<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 01:33:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Fiji Joining the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for&#160;Prosperity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/26/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-fiji-joining-the-indo-pacific-economic-framework-for-prosperity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 02:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54244</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden welcomes Fiji’s decision to join the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF) as a founding member, the 14th&#160;nation and first in the Pacific Islands to do so. IPEF now reflects the full regional diversity of the Indo-Pacific, with members from Northeast and Southeast Asia, South Asia, Oceania, and the Pacific Islands. Across geography,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden welcomes Fiji’s decision to join the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework for Prosperity (IPEF) as a founding member, the 14<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;nation and first in the Pacific Islands to do so. IPEF now reflects the full regional diversity of the Indo-Pacific, with members from Northeast and Southeast Asia, South Asia, Oceania, and the Pacific Islands. Across geography, we are united in our commitment to a free, open, and prosperous Indo-Pacific region. A close partner to the United States and a leader in the region, Fiji will add vital value and perspective to IPEF, including on our efforts to tackle the climate crisis and build a clean economy that creates good paying jobs. The future of the 21st century economy is going to be largely written in the Indo-Pacific, and IPEF will help to drive sustainable growth for all our economies. The United States thanks Prime Minister Bainimarama, and we look forward to deepening our partnership for the benefit of our countries, the Pacific Islands, and the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, May 26,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/26/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-may-26-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[4:10 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hey, good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Okay, I have a few toppers, so please bear with me.&#160; Over the past 15 months, we’ve made tremendous progress in our fight against COVID, with 220 million Americans fully vaccinated and over 100 million people boosted. We’ve also moved quickly to ensure Paxlovid, an oral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>4:10 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hey, good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Okay, I have a few toppers, so please bear with me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the past 15 months, we’ve made tremendous progress in our fight against COVID, with 220 million Americans fully vaccinated and over 100 million people boosted.</p>



<p>We’ve also moved quickly to ensure Paxlovid, an oral antiviral pill that reduces risk of hospitalization and death by almost 90 percent, is widely available.<br><br>Importantly, because of all the work the Biden administration has done on vaccines, boosters, treatments, and more, daily COVID-19 deaths are down by 90 percent from when the President took office, even as infections are rising.<br><br>So the tools that the administration has made widely available to the American people are working to prevent serious illness, to keep people out of the hospital, and to save lives.<br><br>And while COVID isn’t over, it’s critical that Americans know that we now have more tools than ever to protect ourselves.&nbsp; We can now prevent most COVID deaths, and that’s ma- &#8212; that’s major progress.<br><br>To drive further progress, today we announced new federal &#8212; federally supported test-to-treat sites.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, the first of these launches in &#8212; launches in Providence, Rhode Island.&nbsp; In the coming days, we’ll deploy clinical personnel to help transform several of Minnesota’s state-run testing sites into test-to-treat sites.&nbsp; And in the coming weeks, we will work to open more in places like New York and Illinois.<br><br>These build on the more than 2,500 sites we’ve already set up at local pharmacies and community healthcare centers.<br><br>Yesterday afternoon, the Governor of Oklahoma signed into law the most extreme piece of legislation to undo a woman’s fundamental right to make her own reproductive choices since Roe became law.&nbsp; This law will go into effect immediately.<br><br>Not only does this law ban abortion from the moment of fertilization, but it also adopts Texas’s &#8212; Texas plan to allow private citizens to sue their neighbors for providing reproductive healthcare and helping women to exercise their constitutional rights.<br><br>This law is the latest in a growing effort by ultra-MAGA officials across the country to roll back freedoms that should not be taken for granted.&nbsp; Roe has been the law of the land for almost 50 years, and it is under serious threat.<br><br>They are starting with reproductive rights, but the attack on our fundamental rights, including the right to contraception and marriage equality, is growing.&nbsp; And these rights are increasingly at risk.<br><br>The President believes that women have the fundamental right to make their own reproductive health choices, and he and the Vice President and the entire administration are committing to protecting these constitutional rights and fundamental freedoms.<br><br>Today, the Department of Agriculture announced new steps to strengthen food supply chains, increase competition in the meat processing sector, and lower prices for American consumers.<br><br>The Department is making $200 million available to create a new processing capacity expansion program, providing $25 million for workforce training and releasing the first of three planned rules designed to bolster enforcement of the Packers and Stocks&#8212; Stockyards Act which will increase transparency.<br><br>These actions will combat &#8212; combat market dominance by a small number of major meat and poultry processors in key markets, where excessive concentration and control has led to lower prices paid to poultry producers and higher prices by consumers.<br><br>After the severe and sweeping sanctions on the Central Bank of Russia, the Department of Treasury issued General License 9 to provide for an orderly transition so that the bond holders could get paid.<br><br>We’ve announced that we will not be renewing the license.&nbsp;&nbsp;This means that the &#8212; this means that Russia will likely fail to meet its obligation and face default, an enduring sign of their status as a pariah in the global financial system.<br><br>We expect the impact of the U.S. and the global economy to be minimal given Russia has already been isolated financially.&nbsp;<br><br>That being said, Treasury Department continues to monitor and have conversations with the global financial community.<br><br>I have two scheduling updates.<br><br>Next week, the President will welcome Prime Minister of New Zealand to the White House &#8212; another example of our continued commitment to the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; We’ll have more details on this as we get closer.<br><br>And as you all saw, we announced that on Sunday the President and the First Lady will travel to Uvalde to grieve with the community that lost 21 lives in the horrific elementary school shooting.<br><br>We &#8212; we’ll have more to share as we get closer, but while he’s there, the President will meet with the community leaders, religious leaders, and the families of the victim.<br><br>The President and First Lady believe it is important to show their support for the community during this devastating time and to be there for the families of the victims.<br><br>And lastly, on Tuesday, as you all know, the parents of 19 kids did what so many of us parents do every morning: They gave their kids a kiss, told them they loved them, and wished them a good day at school.&nbsp; They figured their kids would spend their day reading, writing, doing math; playing with friends at recess.&nbsp; These kids never came home.<br><br>Some of these parents needed to give DNA samples to be able to identify their own children.&nbsp;&nbsp;These were elementary school kids.&nbsp;&nbsp;They should be losing their first teeth, not losing their lives.&nbsp;&nbsp;They should be at little league, softball, and soccer practices this weekend.&nbsp;&nbsp;These parents should be planning their kid’s summer, not their child’s funeral.</p>



<p>As &#8212; as a parent, it is unfathomable to me that this happened.&nbsp;&nbsp;These kids had their whole lives in front of them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our hearts ache for their families.&nbsp;&nbsp;Our hearts ache for the family and loved ones of the teachers who were killed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Schools should be sanctuaries of learning, not battlefields.&nbsp;&nbsp;And teachers should be there to teach, nurture, prepa- &#8212; and prepare our children for the future, not to be gunned down or asked to sacrifice their own lives for the kids they love.&nbsp;&nbsp;But that is what two heroic teachers did in Uvalde &#8212; killed while trying to protect their students.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m a parent of an elementary school student.&nbsp;&nbsp;I know many of you in this room are as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;We cannot become numb to this.&nbsp;&nbsp;We will not accept this.&nbsp;&nbsp;A grocery store, a church, an elementary school.&nbsp;&nbsp;And this is just in the last few days.&nbsp;&nbsp;It is unacceptable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President said the other night, why are we willing to live with this carnage?&nbsp;&nbsp;Why do we keep letting this happen?&nbsp;&nbsp;Where in God&#8217;s name is our backbone?</p>



<p>So I ask, how is protecting our children a partisan issue?&nbsp;&nbsp;How is preventing innocent people from being slaughtered controversial?</p>



<p>Commonsense gun safety laws work.&nbsp;&nbsp;We know this.&nbsp;&nbsp;They save lives.</p>



<p>As the President said Tuesday night, when the assault weapons ban passed, shootings went down.&nbsp;&nbsp;They tripled after it was lifted.</p>



<p>And let&#8217;s be clear: The public supports this; they are behind this &#8212; even gun owners.&nbsp;&nbsp;Ninety percent of gun owners support universal background checks.&nbsp;&nbsp;Eighty-four percent of Republicans and eighty percent of NRA members support background checks.</p>



<p>As the President said this week, it is time to turn this pain into action.&nbsp;&nbsp;It&#8217;s time for Congress to act.</p>



<p>And with that, Darlene, I will take your question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;Is there any reaction here from &#8212; at the White House to the Senate Republicans blocking the domestic terrorism bill, which was supposed to open the door for some debate and discussion about gun safety, as you were just talking about?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp;So we&#8217;re disappointed that Congress did not move forward with the legislation that would strengthen our response to domestic terror incidents like we saw in Buffalo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need Congress to act on that.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we need Congress to advance commonsense measures that we know will save lives when it comes to gun violence.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;And secondly, the NRA is opening its convention in Houston tomorrow, three days after the massacre in Uvalde.&nbsp;&nbsp;Former President Trump, Texas Governor Abbott, and others are set to speak there.&nbsp;&nbsp;Does the White House think it is appropriate for that convention to move forward?&nbsp;&nbsp;Should it be postponed, cancelled, given the events of the last few days?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp;So it&#8217;s not about the convention.&nbsp;&nbsp;What is inappropriate is that the leadership of the National Rifle Association has proven time and time again that they are contributing to the problem of gun violence, not trying to solve it.</p>



<p>They represent the interests of the gun industry, the gun manufacturers who are marketing weapons of war to young adults.&nbsp;&nbsp;They don&#8217;t represent gun owners who know that we need to take action.&nbsp;&nbsp;And it&#8217;s shameful that the NRA and their allies have stood in the way of every attempt to advance measures that will &#8212; that will &#8212; that we all know will save lives from gun violence, measures that we know would keep weapons off &#8212; of war out of the hands of people who are terrorizing our community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that is what matters, and it is shameful.<br><br>Go ahead, Nancy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Thanks, Karine.&nbsp;&nbsp;Does the President believe that there should be an investigation into the police response to this school shooting?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp;So we&#8217;ve heard of &#8212; (member of the press coughs) &#8212; we&#8217;ve &#8212; need some water?&nbsp;&nbsp;You okay?&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughs.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Just let us know.</p>



<p>The President &#8212; we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve been watching the reporting on this.&nbsp;&nbsp;The President has the utmost respect, as you all know, for the men and women of law enforcement.&nbsp;&nbsp;Just days ago, he honored the memory of the former police officer, Aaron Salter, in Buffalo who was killed bravely while trying to stop the shooter at the supermarket.</p>



<p>I know that right now authorities are working to piece together more details of what happened in Uvalde, so we won&#8217;t prejudge the results from here at this time.</p>



<p>It is al- &#8212; it is always a good idea to look back and try to find any lessons we can learn, especially from trag- &#8212; tragedies like this, so that we can prevent them from moving forward, including law enforcement response.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is the President considering calling on Congress to stay in town to work on this issue instead of going home for a week-long recess?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we have been in close touch with Congress &#8212; even before this shooting and, clearly, what we saw in Buffalo &#8212; about gun reform.&nbsp; This is something that has been a priority from the Pre- &#8212; for the President since day one of his administration.&nbsp; And we also have been in close touch and we really appreciate what Senator Schumer and Speaker Pelosi have been doing.</p>



<p>You know, the President has been very clear that it&#8217;s time to act, it&#8217;s time for Congress to act.&nbsp; The President has long urged Congress to take action to fight gun violence, including by expanding background checks.&nbsp; He supports Leader Schumer&#8217;s plan to bring legislation forward.</p>



<p>They &#8212; the Congress would clearly handle the mechanics of all of this.&nbsp; And, you know, during &#8212; as you all may remember, during the State of the Union, the President asked Congress to pass proven measures to reduce gun violence, pass universal background checks.&nbsp; Why should anyone on &#8212; on the terrorist list be able to purchase a weapon?</p>



<p>Those were what &#8212; is what he said just a couple of months ago.&nbsp; So we have an opportunity to do that right now.&nbsp; And we encourage Congress to act.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, finally, the average age of suspects at school mass shootings is 18.&nbsp; Would the President support raising the age at which someone can buy a gun to 21?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the President was very clear about this just recently when he said that the &#8212; that &#8212; in his remarks, just on Tuesday, that it doesn&#8217;t make sense for an 18-year-old to legally buy an assault weapon.<br><br>And so, he made very clear on Tuesday when he &#8212; after he landed from Asia and had to deal with such a devastating news that happened in Texas.<br><br>Yeah, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; There was a bipartisan group of senators &#8212; nine senators &#8212; that met today.&nbsp; Does the White House have any confidence that this group could reach a meaningful agreement?&nbsp; And does the White House plan to get involved with those negotiations?&nbsp; Would the President bring that group down while they&#8217;re having these talks and meet with them?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you as to any meetings &#8212; upcoming meetings that may be happening at the White House this week or next week or in the coming weeks.<br><br>We really, truly, as I said, leave it to &#8212; the mechanics up to Senator Schumer and Speaker Pelosi.&nbsp; We are confident in &#8212; in that they will &#8212; that Senator Schumer will bring this forward.<br><br>And again, it is time for Congress to act.&nbsp; This is what the President has been calling for since the beginning of his administration, and that&#8217;s what we want to see and that&#8217;s what we encourage Congress to do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Senator Schumer has signaled that they have roughly 10 days to get to a conclusion.&nbsp; Is that a timeline that the White House wants to see?&nbsp; And if at the end of that 10 days there is no agreement, the White House wants to see the Senate move forward on the two House-passed bills?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, we leave the mechanics to Senator Schumer.&nbsp; We want to see action.&nbsp; That is what we&#8217;re calling for.<br><br>And &#8212; but again, we leave it to the leadership &#8212; the Democratic leadership to figure out how they&#8217;re going to move this forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one quick one: Can you give us any sense &#8212; has the President talked to other officials in Texas since Tuesday &#8212; or who he&#8217;s talked to on the phone about what happened down there?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; any calls to preview.&nbsp;<br><br>Clearly, the President is very much &#8212; and the First Lady &#8212; is looking forward to meeting with the families, community leaders when they&#8217;re there on Sunday.<br><br>We have been trying to give the families some time to grieve, as this just happened two days ago.&nbsp; But again, he&#8217;s going to see them on Sunday and have that opportunity to offer comfort.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, are you getting any sense that this time is different, that there&#8217;s a different climate on Capitol Hill that might be inclined to do some &#8212; some things?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this, Steve: You know, we have seen two horrific tragedies in just two weeks.&nbsp; Hours before the shooting, many of the 19 kids who were killed in Texas, Uvalde, were being awarded certificates of the Robb &#8212; of the Robb Elementary’s Honor Roll ceremony as part of the end of the school year.&nbsp; Today would have been their last day of school and &#8212; for the school year.<br><br>In Buffalo, on the same day &#8212; on the same day that this happened just two days ago, 2 of the 10 people who were killed while going to the grocery store on a Sunday, like many of us do, were being buried and honored by their families.&nbsp; I&#8217;m talking about Aaron Salter, the security officer who first responded, and Celestine Chaney, a mother and grandmother of six, were being buried by loved ones right in Buffalo on that same day.<br><br>So, America has more guns than people in this country.&nbsp; If more guns were indeed the solution, we would be the safest country in the world, but we are not.<br><br>And so, the President has been very clear he wants action &#8212; he wants Congress to take action.&nbsp; He wants to turn this pain into action.&nbsp;<br><br>And I hope the Senate, and particularly those who have been unwilling to act in the face of previous tragedies, will act now.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we are hoping and urging Congress to do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President considering some unilateral actions on guns?&nbsp; There are a number of gun safety advocates who are pushing for things like a gun czar or a state of emergency declaration.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on your first part, you know, while we&#8217;ve been calling for Congress to act, and the President has done that since the first couple of days of the White House, he has been waiting, right?&nbsp; We have talked about the things &#8212; the comprehensive approaches that he&#8217;s taken.<br><br>We recently announced how over $10 billion from the Rescue Plan has been spent or committed on ways to fight gun &#8212; gun crime and gun violence.&nbsp; The President wants cities and states to use even more.&nbsp; The department &#8212; the Justice Department issued a tough new rule to stem the flow of ghost guns, which are increasingly being found at the crime scenes and which are the weapons of choice for terrorists and criminals.<br><br>So, the administration &#8212; the administration issued a zero-tolerance policy for gun dealers who willfully sell guns illegally.&nbsp;<br><br>So, this President has done more via executive actions than any other President during their first year of office.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, what we are asking for is for Congress &#8212; we are urging them to take action.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; How does the President view his role in this moment?&nbsp; You know, we talked yesterday about changing a dynamic &#8212; a dynamic that&#8217;s been entrenched for decades now at this point.<br><br>I understand the legislative details are Capitol Hill&#8217;s prerogative.&nbsp; How does he view his role in trying to change that dynamic?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think he &#8212; he views his role has as he has been doing.<br><br>You know, if you think about his remarks on Tuesday, it was &#8212; it was compassion, it was sadness, it &#8212; it was outrage.<br><br>And you heard that from &#8212; from the President of the United States, basically saying “enough is enough.”&nbsp; And this is something that he understands personally.&nbsp; This is a President who has worked on gun violence during his Senate years, as Vice President, and has leadership already from the first couple of days of stepping into this administration.<br><br>So, we have done &#8212; we have done our part.&nbsp; Will there be more executive actions and will we do more?&nbsp; We&#8217;ll look into that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re always looking to do more.&nbsp; But, right now, we need the help of Congress.&nbsp; We need them to step in and to deal with this gun violence that we&#8217;re seeing that&#8217;s tearing up not just families but communities across the country.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You were on &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more quick one.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Yeah, yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You were on Air Force One.&nbsp; Can you talk about the President&#8217;s reaction when he got the news,&nbsp;when more details started to come out over the course of those hours &#8212; those final hours on the flight, and as he prepared for his remarks on Tuesday night, which he echoed on Wednesday?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; As you said, Phil, I was with the President on the plane, on Air Force One, because we were coming back from Asia, and I got to see him right before he delivered the speech.&nbsp;<br><br>Honestly, I will &#8212; would leave the speech to stand for itself.&nbsp; You heard his emotion.&nbsp; You heard what he said very, very clearly.&nbsp; And again, you heard the outrage, which we heard &#8212; which we saw from some of you on TV, from some of you who &#8212; some of your colleagues who are in Texas who were talking to families on the ground, the communities on the ground &#8212; the outrage, the sadness, the grief.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what you heard from this President.&nbsp;<br><br>And, you know, he said a couple of things that I think it&#8217;s important to reiterate, as we &#8212; as we really think about what happened &#8212; is that, you know, there are parents who will never see their child again, parents who will never be the same.&nbsp; And the President said, “To lose a child is like having a piece of your soul ripped away…It’s suffocating.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s never quite the same.&nbsp; And it’s a feeling shared by…their family members, and the community that&#8217;s left behind.”&nbsp;<br><br>So that is the Pres- &#8212; the President’s focus right now.&nbsp; He’s going to go, clearly, on Sunday to offer his comfort, to grieve with the family and the community.&nbsp; But at the same time, he is going to call on Congress to take action because it&#8217;s been too long.&nbsp; And now is the time to act.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two quick things.&nbsp; First, apparently the company that sold the shooter his rifles received a $3 million PPP loan under the last administration.&nbsp; Do you know if there&#8217;s any effort by this administration to claw that money back?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I &#8212; this is the first I’m hearing about this, so I would have to go back to the team and look into it.&nbsp; Do you know the name of the company?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, the name of the company is Daniel Defense &#8212; D-A-N-I-E-L Defense.&nbsp;&nbsp; Apparently, they received a, I think, $3.1 million PPP loan right at the beginning.&nbsp; My colleagues have been writing about it apparently today.&nbsp; But if &#8212; if &#8212; assuming that is confirmed, would the President, do you think, support the idea of trying to claw that money back?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; honestly, Michael, I need to &#8212; to check with the team and just make sure that is actually factual.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But I need to check with the team.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I would appreciate that.&nbsp; And then &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And we’ll get back to on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then just, you know, going back to the question that I&#8217;m sure, you know, everybody has been asking, which is the, sort of “what is the President going to do and can do,” you talk a lot about the outrage.&nbsp; You talk a lot about that he wants Congress to act.&nbsp; You talk a lot about the emotion.&nbsp; I was in this room &#8212; I think a lot of the other people &#8212; a lot of people here were too &#8212; when the President Obama cried at that very podium hours after the Newtown &#8212; Newtown shootings.&nbsp;<br><br>There have been a million shootings since then, lots of expressions of outrage, lots of expressions of wanting the &#8212; wanting Congress to act.&nbsp; They haven&#8217;t.&nbsp;<br><br>I mean, there are people out there &#8212; saw several of them on TV today &#8212; who say this President needs to do more than all of that.&nbsp; This President needs to declare a national emergency.&nbsp; He needs to create task forces.&nbsp; He needs to create, you know, a czar of gun things.&nbsp; He needs to say he&#8217;s not leaving this building, cancel his vacations.&nbsp; Tell Congress &#8212; you know, members from Congress to get in a room and not &#8212; not leave until they &#8212; you know, until they got a solution, and not accept some of the sort of half measures that, you know, are sort of being offered.<br><br>And I guess the question is: Why &#8212; why isn’t he doing of that?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on the public health &#8212; on the emergency, he has already done that.&nbsp; The President has already declared gun violence to be a &#8212; to be a public health epidemic.&nbsp; He has done that already.&nbsp; And he has mobilized our federal departments and agencies, including the Department of Health Services, to respond.&nbsp; So that is &#8212; has been done.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, this is a President, as I&#8217;ve said already, who has been working on gun violence, gun reform &#8212; comprehensive gun reform since he was a senator.&nbsp; And he also was there, as you were talking about &#8212; you know, what President Biden &#8212; I mean, President Obama had to deal with.&nbsp; He was there.&nbsp; He was his partner in that and took on that &#8212; that portfolio of dealing with gun violence.&nbsp; He was there at the table.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But isn’t that more of an indictment than it is a plus to say that the current President has been involved in this for more than &#8212; you know, more than &#8212; you know for decades and it&#8217;s not being fixed?&nbsp; These things are happening over and over again.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But look, Michael, we are frustrated as well.&nbsp; We are angry as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, I said this earlier and I&#8217;ll say it again: This is a President who has done more via executive actions &#8212; this is how much of a priority this is for him, because we&#8217;re a year into his presidency &#8212; more via executive actions than any president in their first year.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But many &#8212; but many of those are not directly related to &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Which is why &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the issues of mass shootings.&nbsp; They &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Which &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; may be directly related &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I hear you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to guns, but &#8212; and that’s important &#8212; I’m not saying &#8212; but &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; they’re not directly related to &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, this is why we&#8217;re calling on Congress to act.&nbsp; The President is doing what &#8212; the President is your &#8212; the President is doing what he can &#8212; right? &#8212; from here, from the White House.&nbsp;<br><br>And now &#8212; and he has said he cannot do this alone.&nbsp; He has been very clear.&nbsp; We &#8212; he understands we need to do more, but Congress also has to act.&nbsp; He has done a comprehensive plan on gun &#8212; on gun violence.&nbsp; We have listed that out.<br><br>Every couple of months, we talk about what he&#8217;s doing, what executive action he&#8217;s taking.&nbsp; And now he is saying, “Congress needs to act.”&nbsp; And &#8212; but he has been saying that for some time.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Kristen.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To the back please?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Give me one second, please.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just &#8212; I want to follow up on this idea, because the President campaigned on a promise to be able to bring Democrats and Republicans together to get the hard things done.&nbsp; Why has he not been able to bring them together to make this a legislative priority to even get a small measure done when it comes to (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think that&#8217;s what Senator Schumer is trying to do.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, but why not do that in the early days of his presidency?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we have been talking to Congress before these two shootings that have been clearly very public and very devastating and horrific in this past two weeks.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing it now.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, we know that this is not easy.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not saying that this is easy.&nbsp; And the President is doing everything that he can to get this done, but we have &#8212; we&#8217;re going to continue to call on Congress to act.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does this now move to the top of his &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It’s a priority.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; legislative priorities, above Build Back Better &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It’s &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; above COVID relief?&nbsp; Does this now need to be the singular focus of &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’ve &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; all of Washington D.C.?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Kristen, I would argue that this has been a top priority from the &#8212; from the time &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the singular focus for the President and lawmakers?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to list out his &#8212; the one, two, or three of priority.&nbsp; What I can tell you is this has been a top priority.&nbsp; Literally, he &#8212; he started working on this the first couple of days he walked into the &#8212; into &#8212; into this office.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you’re getting a lot of questions about the czar.&nbsp; I guess, just to ask more spe- &#8212; to ask in a different way: Former President Obama appointed then-Vice President Biden to take control of this issue.&nbsp; Are there any discussions &#8212; is the President considering tasking his Vice President with trying to get something done on this issue?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, we &#8212; we have Ambassador Susan Rice, who is the President&#8217;s domestic policy advisor, as you all know, and she is coordinating the President&#8217;s whole-of-government approach to reducing gun violence.</p>



<p>She has decades of experience coordinating interagency processes in the federal government.&nbsp; There is no one better at bringing department heads to the table to drive the process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She has a team of 12 staff under the Domestic Policy Council who are working on gun violence reduction, taking an interdisciplinary approach that recognizes that we need all sorts of expertise at the table, from mental health to criminal justice to housing to education, to address the issue.</p>



<p>In addition to the Domestic Policy Council, there&#8217;s the Executive Office of the President, the White House Counsel&#8217;s Office, the Office of the Intergovernmental Affairs, and the Office of Public Engagement.&nbsp; All are playing key roles in gun violence prevention, as do several of the federal agencies, which I&#8217;ve listed out already.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, given everything you just laid out, and the President said yesterday he will use every tool that&#8217;s available, I guess, why hasn&#8217;t he stood up a task force &#8212; an interagency task force on preventing gun violence?&nbsp; He has done it dozens of times on everything from COVID to unionizing since the start of his presidency.&nbsp; There&#8217;s also an outstanding request, I believe, from House Democrats over the past year that he appoint a national director &#8212; I guess a czar, as Kristen said &#8212; and start a task force.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I just &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that something he is going to consider?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just walked through a whole-of-government approach that we&#8217;re taking &#8212; that&#8217;s how important this is &#8212; across departments here at the White House and also with several agencies.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about the DOJ &#8212; Department of Justice.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about HHS.&nbsp; All very much involved here on &#8212; on how we&#8217;re moving forward.</p>



<p>You know &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, I guess, why not make an official interagency task force?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Because we have a whole-of-government approach.&nbsp; We have a whole-of-government approach that I just mentioned, that Ambassador Susan Rice is leading, along with other departments.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and with that whole-of-government approach, we have been able to put forth executive actions at a level that we have not seen from any other presidents.&nbsp; We have been able to deal with this in a comprehensive way.</p>



<p>What we are saying right now is that we need help.&nbsp; We need assistance.&nbsp; The President cannot do this alone.&nbsp; The Congress needs to act.&nbsp; They need to pass legislation so that we can deal with this on a federal level &#8212; legislative level.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last question: Is the President making any &#8212; or is he considering calling or reaching out to the BORTAC agent who was injured in Uvalde while he was protecting students during the shooting?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview or read out for you.&nbsp; As I &#8212; as you know &#8212; as you know, he&#8217;s going to &#8212; on Sunday, he&#8217;s going to be meeting with community leaders, he&#8217;s going to be meeting with victims and family members.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;ll have more to share.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to share at this time.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go to the back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; It’s hard to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would like to ask you a question about the school shooting.&nbsp; But before that, I want to ask you a quick one about the FDA and the baby formula shortage there.&nbsp; It&#8217;s lasted months, and we&#8217;re not just talking about baby formula, either.&nbsp; There are infants, children, and adults with different metabolic disorders who are risking permanent, irreversible damage the longer they go without special formulas that are manufactured at Abbott Nutrition.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m wondering, does the President have confidence in the FDA’s ability to deal with situations like this?&nbsp; And as he&#8217;s been monitoring the situation, does he still have confidence in his FDA director?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes and yes.&nbsp; So the FDA has an important mission, right?&nbsp; It’s to make sure that the infant formula on the shelf isn&#8217;t just available but also that it&#8217;s safe.&nbsp; And as a parent, I understand the frustration, I understand the fear of not mak- &#8212; not knowing if you have safe and healthy food, baby formula in this case, to &#8212; for your kids.</p>



<p>Unlike, you know, Republicans in Congress and the previous administration, the President believes that FDA, and particularly its food division, needs to be well resourced to do its critical work and do regular annual inspection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we have to just take a little bit of &#8212; just give me a second here &#8212; take a step back.</p>



<p>The current shortage exists because Abbott closed, as you &#8212; as you know, a facility in Michigan due to safety concerns from the FDA &#8212; a facility that was a major producer of specialty formula, as you&#8217;re asking me about, right?&nbsp; And so FDA has an obligation to protect the American people, and that&#8217;s what Dr. Califf is going to be doing at the helm.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then the second que- &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; You have a follow-up.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second question.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been having a lot of conversations about specifics when it comes to mass shootings, whether it&#8217;s red flag laws or background checks.&nbsp; Getting down to, though brass tacks, what does the President believe, at this point, is the purpose of the Second Amendment?&nbsp; And does he think that, given some of the tragedies that we&#8217;ve seen, that there should be a discussion about, you know, its ultimate purpose and whether or not it&#8217;s currently in date?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the President has been very clear: What he is calling for is commonsense gun reform.&nbsp; That&#8217;s it.&nbsp; He&#8217;s calling for commonsense gun reform to make sure that if you go to a church, you go to elementary school, you go to a grocery store, that you&#8217;re not gunned down.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what he&#8217;s asking for.</p>



<p>It has &#8212; we&#8217;re not talking about the Second Amendment or &#8212; or doing anything to &#8212; to get rid of the Second Amendment.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about making sure &#8212; 19 &#8212; 19 kids and two teachers died.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the second major mass shooting that has &#8212; has occurred in two weeks.&nbsp; And that &#8212; we&#8217;re not even talking about the crime that we see, the gun violence that we see across the country on a regular basis.</p>



<p>So we have to make sure that we have gun reform.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re calling on Congress to act.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, April.&nbsp; I’m trying to stay in the back.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, I want to ask you about an issue that&#8217;s been in the news nationally and internationally: the grains issue.<br><br>House Foreign &#8212; House Foreign Affairs Committee Chair Greg Meeks is in Europe meeting with world leaders on the issue.&nbsp; He says that&#8217;s all people are really talking about right now, is the grains issue.&nbsp; And as you know, there&#8217;s a blockade of the Black Sea.&nbsp; Russia’s blocked &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, the export.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; there’s a blockade of the Black Sea for the exports of grain, and also India is having problems.&nbsp; So the issue is Russia.</p>



<p>Will this White House look at relenting when it comes to issues of sanctions against Russia to allow the grains to go out?&nbsp; Because, right now, Meeks is saying the issue is starvation, as well as prices in the grocery store.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I th- &#8212; so the question that you&#8217;re asking about, if I&#8217;m getting this right, is, like, Russia is &#8212; has made a proposal to us to &#8212; to allow exports in exchange for lifting the sanctions?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And so, you know, we want to be very, very clear here, because this is very important: This is Russia who is actively blocking the export of food from Ukrainian ports and is increasing world hunger.&nbsp; This is on them.</p>



<p>Russia should immediately cease its war on Ukraine, which is devastating global food security, and allow the free flow of Ukrainian food.</p>



<p>Before Russia attacked Ukraine in February, Ukraine was the world&#8217;s largest export of sunflower oil; the fourth largest export of corn, which is what you&#8217;re asking about, April, with the wheat; and one of the largest exports of wheat, this &#8212; what you&#8217;re asking about.</p>



<p>Now, there are tons of products sitting in se- &#8212; in silos in Ukraine and on ships that are unable to set sail due to Russia&#8217;s naval blockade.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; and to be clear about some- &#8212; something that has been the subject of Russian disinformation: Sanctions from the United States and its allies and its partners are not preventing the export of Ukrainian or Russian agriculture, including food and fertilizer, nor are they preventing the ordinary transactions that are necessary for these exports, such as banking or shipping.</p>



<p>Therefore, even according to the terms of their own apparent proposal that they have presented &#8212; presented us, Russia should immediately allow Ukrainian agricultural exports.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there is no &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; there is no conversation at all about lifting sanctions?&nbsp; You’re saying &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; no?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; There &#8212; there is not.&nbsp; Remember, again, this is Russia’s doing.&nbsp; This is on Russia.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On formula?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All the way back.&nbsp; All the way back.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Nadia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; I have two foreign policy questions.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, a team from the White House is visiting Saudi Arabia, led by Brett McGurk.&nbsp; Is the President still trying to convince the Saudis to increase the production of oil?&nbsp; And is this part of preparation for the President&#8217;s visit to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this time on &#8212; on a &#8212; on a trip or a visit from the President.&nbsp;<br><br>I will confirm that Brett McGurk and Amos Hochstein were in the region to follow up on conversations on a range of &#8212; range of issues, including Iran&#8217;s disab- &#8212; destabilizing activities, ensuring stable global energy supplies, and other regional issues.<br><br>On your question about oil, you know, it’s &#8212; this trip is to review engagement with Saudi Arabia on energy security, as asking for oil is simply wrong &#8212; that’s the way that we see it &#8212; and a misunderstanding of both the complexity of that issue, as well as our multifaceted discussions with the Saudis.</p>



<p>OPEC-Plus will make its own decision as it relates to this, the oil, and as it always has.&nbsp; We are in consultation with all relevant producers about market conditions, including Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have one more, please, on Syria.&nbsp; The head of the Lebanese intelligence chief have met with people at the White House.&nbsp; He told me in an interview that you raised the question of American hostages in Syria held by the Syrian regime.&nbsp; Can you update us on the case on &#8212; specifically on Austin Tice and whether his release is imminent?&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s sensitive because you’re talking to the families.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, this &#8212; it&#8217;s a very sensitive issue.&nbsp; And so, this is not &#8212; it&#8217;s not something that I want to comment from here, so I won&#8217;t.&nbsp; I just can&#8217;t.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to do that just because of &#8212; it’s diplomatic negotiations, and I want to leave it in that space.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>I’ll come back.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the White House detected any mood shift that makes you optimistic after this shooting that something is finally going to happen, that something is finally going to get passed after 19 children were shot down?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, we don&#8217;t have our finger on the pulse of &#8212; on the mood.&nbsp; What we can do is continue to fight for American families, for American communities, as we see the violence that has &#8212; especially the two major &#8212; major tragedies that we&#8217;ve seen these last two weeks &#8212; and call on Congress to act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President, again &#8212; and I&#8217;ve stated this &#8212; he has taken executive actions over this past year and a half, which is more &#8212; again, more than any President has done in its first term.&nbsp; And he cannot do this alone.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, he &#8212; he is going to leave it to Senator Schumer, who is doing the &#8212; going through the mechanics of what that&#8217;s going to look like moving &#8212; moving legislation forward.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we appreciate their efforts.&nbsp; We appreciate his effort.&nbsp; We appreciate the Speaker&#8217;s effort.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to have those conversations, as we have been throughout this past year and a half.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; So, after the President visited with families in Buffalo, he was asked, “What more can you do on guns via executive action?”&nbsp; And he said, quote, “Not much on executive action.”<br><br>As Steve said, there are multiple gun safety groups that disagree with that statement and have pages of &#8212; of executive actions that they think the President can take.&nbsp; Does the President have any plans to meet with gun safety advocates?&nbsp; I know when he was Vice President, he had hundreds of meetings in the EEOB in his office there with groups.&nbsp; Does he plan to meet with them?&nbsp; And if not, why not?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; not at this time.&nbsp;<br><br>I &#8212; you know, I just talked about Susan Rice and her team, the Domestic Policy Council.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve talked about the public engagement team and others, DOJ and also HHS.&nbsp;<br><br>And those teams have been regularly talking to outside experts, outside groups over the course of this past year and a half.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we were able to put forward these executive action, comprehensive effort to deal with gun reform.&nbsp; So, that conversations &#8212; those conversations are going to continue.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you on this one.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) on the meetings, but just in terms of that sentiment where &#8212; where the President says there&#8217;s not much more on executive action that he can do.&nbsp; Does this shooting in Texas change that at all?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think what he is &#8212; I &#8212; just to speak to that: Look, the President has done a lot.&nbsp; He really has.&nbsp; The fact that I&#8217;m able to state this historical fact of how much &#8212; how much he&#8217;s done in his first year and a half.<br><br>But, you know, we&#8217;re always looking at what else we can do.&nbsp; But we have done &#8212; you know, we have done so much.&nbsp; I just read it out &#8212; including stemming the flow of ghost guns, cracking down on gun trafficking, and using the American Rescue Plan funds to invest in keeping officers on the beat to fight gun crime and gun violence.<br><br>And so, we&#8217;re going to continue constantly looking at additional executive action so we can move forward.<br><br>But the President, again, cannot solve this problem alone.&nbsp; He needs Congress to do its job and to act.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On that point: What role do you guys expect Senator McConnell to play on any sort of bipartisan gun legislation?&nbsp; Does the President plan to contact him or speak with him at all?&nbsp; And what are you hoping for from the Senate Minority Leader?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look &#8212; you know, again, we&#8217;re going to leave the mechanics to how this gets done to the leadership &#8212; to the leadership in Congress, Senator Schumer and Speaker Pelosi.<br><br>We have had several conversations before these major shootings that occurred these last two weeks.&nbsp; This is an issue that has been a priority for this President since the moment he walked in &#8212; into this office and, as I mentioned, as a senator, as a Vice President, and now as President.<br><br>So, there&#8217;s an array of issues that we talk to Congress on a regular basis.&nbsp; And again, we&#8217;re going to continue to have those conversations.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the gun issue, just a quick follow-up: Is one of the concerns of the White House that moving ahead with executive actions right now while there are talks in Congress could sink those talks in Congress?&nbsp; Is that why you’re holding &#8212; one of the reasons you might be holding back on moving forward with the executive actions?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; I mean, we’ve been very clear: It’s time for Congress to act.&nbsp; We cannot do this alone.&nbsp; The President cannot do this alone.&nbsp; So, we’re asking Congress to act so we can have federal laws to actually deal with reforming &#8212; reforming &#8212; doing gun reform &#8212; comprehensive gun reform.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Summit of the Americas, President Bolsonaro of Brazil has said he plans to attend now.&nbsp; AMLO, of Mexico, is still making mixed signals.&nbsp; Can you say whether those invitations have now formally gone out to all of those leaders?&nbsp; And are the governments of Venezuela and Cuba and Nicaragua going to be excluded?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re still considering additional invites, and we&#8217;ll share them when &#8212; when it &#8212; we feel it&#8217;s appropriate &#8212; when it&#8217;s final.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s when we&#8217;ll share them.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything right now to share as far as a fi- &#8212; as a list.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one last one.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The CBO came out with a report earlier this week that showed inflation was going to remain above target toward the &#8212; well, going down but still above target to the end of this year and then into next year.&nbsp; I mean, has the White House, sort of, painted too rosy a picture on how quickly inflation is going to go down, given the projections that came out from CBO this week?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, a couple of things.&nbsp; So, as you mentioned, the CBO report came out yesterday.&nbsp; It projects stable, steady economic growth in the year &#8212; in the years ahead, as inflation eases, the deficit falls dramatically this year.<br><br>On the deficit, the CBO projects that our deficit this year will fall by $1.7 trillion, after it fell by $350 billion just last year.&nbsp; That’s after the deficit increased every single year President Trump was in office.&nbsp; And it is a lower deficit for 2022 than the CBO projected before passage of the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; That means that our econo- &#8212; our strong economic recovery, powered by the President’s economic and vaccination policies also improved our nation’s fiscal position and reduced our deficit.<br><br>On growth and inflation, CBO projects the economy to grow by 3.1 percent this year and 2.2 percent next year, with core personal con- &#8212; consumption <s>exemption</s> [expenditures] &#8212; that’s PCE &#8212; inflation falling to 2.3 percent by the end of next year.&nbsp; This is the kind of transition from a historic economic recovery &#8212; again, steady, stable economic growth that works for working families &#8212; that President &#8212; that the President’s policies are designed to bring about.&nbsp;<br><br>So that’s how we’re &#8212; how we’re viewing the CBO report.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, you had something on formula you said?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Can you tell us if there are any more flights planned from &#8212; foreign flights for formula?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to &#8212; to preview at this time.&nbsp; But we will have some more information in the upcoming days.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that because you all are working on it and the details are not there or can we expect more flights?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, definitely, you&#8217;ll expect more flights.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to announce at this time.&nbsp; And, as you know, the second flight landed in Dulles yesterday.&nbsp; The First Lady was there to receive the &#8212; the formula and the &#8212; and the package that landed.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the FDA question: You said &#8212; you brought up the Abbott plant, and it was kind of put on them.&nbsp; But Senator Patty Murray &#8212; today, she told the FDA head that she gives the FDA an “F” on not realizing the warning signs of the crisis.&nbsp; And she also says that they have not given her a plan that she&#8217;s requested about how to stabilize a food safety program.&nbsp; So is there anything the White House can ensure that the FDA has been in response to Senator Murray and those on Capitol Hill?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just first say this &#8212; this is &#8212; they’re hearing &#8212; during the hearing yesterday, Dr. Califf has said, “It’s important we get to the bottom of what happened with the &#8212; with the Sturgis facility and the root of what has caused the issues we’re facing today.”&nbsp; He has designated someone to lead an after-action report.<br><br>But we have to take a step back here and look at the dynamics of what we&#8217;re dealing with: We have fau- &#8212; four companies that make up 98 percent of the market.&nbsp; An industry that’s &#8212; that’s concentrated means more vulnerability to the supply shocks and fewer options for consumption.<br><br>And because of Abbott’s vol- &#8212; voluntary recall, there have been huge disruptions to formula supply of a highly concentrated market.&nbsp; So we have to fix this.<br><br>So, our focus right now is on getting more infant formula supply to families across the country as quickly as possible, as well running a historic agenda to diversify markets and grow the number of companies competing for &#8212; for your business.&nbsp; This is what &#8212; this is what will &#8212; will help avoid situations like this in the future.<br><br>But he has said it is important to get to the bottom of this and has appointed someone to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:53 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with LGBTQI+ Leaders on Reproductive Justice and Civil&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/26/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-lgbtqi-leaders-on-reproductive-justice-and-civil-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 22:55:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54238</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein and White House Deputy Assistant to the President for Racial Justice and Equity Chiraag Bains convened a meeting with national LGBTQI+ leaders on protecting access to reproductive health care and protecting LGBTQI+ civil rights. Advocates discussed the importance of protecting access to abortion for the LGBTQI+&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein and White House Deputy Assistant to the President for Racial Justice and Equity Chiraag Bains convened a meeting with national LGBTQI+ leaders on protecting access to reproductive health care and protecting LGBTQI+ civil rights. Advocates discussed the importance of protecting access to abortion for the LGBTQI+ community, and the need to protect critical and foundational LGBTQI+ civil rights, including marriage equality. Participants also highlighted the importance of the right to reproductive decision-making and privacy, and the importance of reproductive health care for LGBTQI+ people as they start families, and cited fears about the challenges LGBTQI+ families are facing as states pass extreme laws restricting access to critical health care, including reproductive health care and gender-affirming care.</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials highlighted the President’s unwavering commitment to LGBTQI+ civil rights, reproductive rights, and safeguarding LGBTQI+ couples and families.</p>



<p>Participants included representatives from:</p>



<ul><li>Equality Federation</li><li>Family Equality</li><li>Lambda Legal</li><li>Freedom for All Americans</li><li>Human Rights Campaign</li><li>National LGBTQ Task Force</li><li>National Center for Lesbian Rights</li><li>National Center for Transgender Equality</li><li>National Women’s Law Center</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NSC Press Statement on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Phone Call with Croatian Prime Minister Andrej&#160;Plenkovic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/26/nsc-press-statement-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-phone-call-with-croatian-prime-minister-andrej-plenkovic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 20:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54233</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Prime Minister Andrej Plenkovic of Croatia. They underscored their strong commitment to continue supporting Ukraine in response to Russia’s unprovoked military aggression. Mr. Sullivan conveyed U.S. support for Croatia’s efforts to help neighboring countries diversify their energy supplies away from Russian sources, including via the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Prime Minister Andrej Plenkovic of Croatia. They underscored their strong commitment to continue supporting Ukraine in response to Russia’s unprovoked military aggression. Mr. Sullivan conveyed U.S. support for Croatia’s efforts to help neighboring countries diversify their energy supplies away from Russian sources, including via the expansion of the liquefied natural gas (LNG) terminal at Krk. They also exchanged views on stability in the Western Balkans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/26/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-70/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 18:43:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Angela Price Aggeler, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of North Macedonia. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Marie C. Damour, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Angela Price Aggeler, of the District of Columbia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of North Macedonia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Marie C. Damour, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Fiji, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Kiribati, the Republic of Nauru, the Kingdom of Tonga, and Tuvalu.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rosemarie Hidalgo, of the District of Columbia, to be Director of the Violence Against Women Office, Department of Justice, vice Susan B. Carbon.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mark W. Libby, of Massachusetts, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Azerbaijan.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sue Ellen Moore, of Washington, to be a Member of the Marine Mammal Commission for a term expiring May 13, 2023, vice Michael F. Tillman, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gautam A. Rana, of New Jersey, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Slovak Republic.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Andrew J. Read, of North Carolina, to be a Member of the Marine Mammal Commission for a term expiring May 13, 2025, vice Daryl J. Boness, term expired.</p>



<p>     Laura Taylor-Kale, of California, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.  (New Position)</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Announces Launch of First Federally-Supported Test to Treat&#160;Site</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/26/fact-sheet-biden-administration-announces-launch-of-first-federally-supported-test-to-treat-site/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On his first day in office, President Biden mobilized an unprecedented, comprehensive response to the COVID-19 pandemic—standing up a historic vaccination program that has gotten 220 million Americans fully vaccinated and over 100 million people boosted, and investing in other lifesaving tools, including COVID-19 therapeutics. One of the most effective treatments in our nation’s medicine&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On his first day in office, President Biden mobilized an unprecedented, comprehensive response to the COVID-19 pandemic—standing up a historic vaccination program that has gotten 220 million Americans fully vaccinated and over 100 million people boosted, and investing in other lifesaving tools, including COVID-19 therapeutics.<br><br>One of the most effective treatments in our nation’s medicine cabinet is Paxlovid, an oral antiviral pill, which reduces the risk of hospitalization or death by about 90 percent. Since Paxlovid was first authorized in December 2021, the Administration has moved quickly to ensure that these treatments are widely available and that health care providers and patients know about their availability and efficacy. These efforts include a Test-to-Treat initiative to help make it easier for people to quickly access oral antiviral treatments in one convenient location. There are now more than 2,500 Test-to-Treat locations across the country at local pharmacies and community health centers—up from 2,200 a month ago.<br><br>The Administration’s actions to date have resulted in tremendous progress: We have dramatically increased the number of people benefiting from oral antivirals in the last seven weeks, from about 27,000 prescriptions filled each week to more than 182,000 last week—a more than six-fold increase. We have also doubled the number of sites where Paxlovid is available nationally.<br><br>Because of the work the Biden Administration has done on vaccines, boosters, treatments, and more, COVID-19 deaths are down 90 percent from when the President took office—even as cases rise in parts of the country. The tools that the Administration has made widely available to the American people are working to prevent serious illness, to keep people out of the hospital, and to save lives.<br><br>The tools we have now mean that we can prevent most COVID deaths. The Administration remains laser-focused on making sure that these lifesaving tools are widely available to every American who needs them. To that end, today, the Administration is announcing the launch of the first federally-supported Test-to-Treat site, with more planned in the coming weeks.<br><br><strong>Today’s announcement includes:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Launching the first federally-supported Test-to-Treat site in Rhode Island: </strong>Today, Rhode Island will officially launch the nation’s first federally-supported Test-to-Treat site at a clinic in Providence. Federal reimbursement will now allow individuals who test positive for COVID-19 at the clinic to immediately receive an assessment from a medical provider and get oral antiviral treatments—if prescribed—all in one convenient location that serves some of the state’s highest-risk and hardest-hit populations. The clinic also currently offers vaccination, meaning that federal support will help enhance this site into being a true one-stop shop for individuals to protect themselves and their communities from COVID-19.</li><li><strong>Deploying clinical personnel to support state-run Test-to-Treat sites in Minnesota:</strong> In the coming days, the Administration will deploy clinical personnel to support staffing across several of Minnesota’s state-run testing sites, transforming them into Test-to-Treat sites that will co-locate testing, an assessment from a medical provider, and oral antiviral treatments. This direct federal support will allow Minnesota to expand the capacity and reach of Test-to-Treat, making these lifesaving oral antiviral treatments more widely available statewide.</li><li><strong>Launching additional federally-supported Test-to-Treat sites in the coming weeks:</strong> The Administration will open federally-supported Test-to-Treat sites in New York and Illinois in the coming weeks, and is working with other regions like Massachusetts and New York City to enhance existing state-led efforts to increase access to oral antivirals like Paxlovid.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Today’s announcements build on the significant actions the Administration has taken over the past several weeks to increase access to oral antivirals and boost health care provider and patient awareness, including:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Doubling the number of places where oral antivirals are available: </strong>In late April, the Administration acted to make it easier for local pharmacies to order oral antivirals directly from the federal government. As a result, oral antivirals are now available at almost 40,000 convenient locations nationwide—up from roughly 20,000 a month ago. This means nearly 90 percent of Americans now live within 5 miles of a place where they can pick up their prescriptions for oral antivirals, including local pharmacies, hospitals, urgent care centers, community health centers, rural health clinics, Veterans Affairs clinics, and Department of Defense Medical Treatment Facilities.</li><li><strong>Ensuring equitable access to oral antivirals: </strong>In line with the Administration’s unwavering commitment to equity, 40 percent of the pharmacy sites that now have oral antivirals available are located in communities with the highest levels of social vulnerability. To ensure both equitable geographic placement and equitable administration to vulnerable populations, we have also called on all sites dispensing oral antivirals to collect robust demographic data on individuals receiving prescriptions for COVID-19 therapeutics. This demographic data will improve our ability to identify—in real time—any gaps in access and work to promptly alleviate those gaps.</li><li><strong>Expanding the number of Test-to-Treat sites in communities and their reach: </strong>Over the past several weeks, the Administration has worked with its federal pharmacy and community health center partners to expand the footprint of Test-to-Treat sites in communities and to enhance overall patient experience. This means that it is even easier for people to make appointments and to access treatments. There are now more than 2,500 Test-to-Treat locations across the country at local pharmacies and community health centers—up from 2,200 a month ago. These Test-to-Treat sites provide people streamlined access to COVID-19 tests, health care provider visits, and if they need it, prescriptions for oral antivirals. In addition, Americans can now find many health care providers on the <a href="https://covid-19-test-to-treat-locator-dhhs.hub.arcgis.com/">Test-to-Treat locator</a> that supports telehealth visits to determine if oral antivirals are appropriate. Walgreens has made antiviral treatments available in all of its rural and high Social Vulnerability Index (SVI) locations, and CVS and Kroger have added telehealth-based provider visits to help people get a prescription quickly.</li><li><strong>Supporting health care providers with additional guidance: </strong>In the last month, federal health agencies have issued updated guidance to help health care providers stay up to date on the latest science and navigate drug-drug interactions and contraindications. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention has issued two Health Alert Notifications highlighting available COVID-19 treatments, particularly Paxlovid. The National Institutes of Health  has updated its <a href="https://www.covid19treatmentguidelines.nih.gov/therapies/antiviral-therapy/ritonavir-boosted-nirmatrelvir--paxlovid-/">treatment guidelines</a> with more info to help providers understand drug-drug interactions. And, the Food and Drug Administration  issued a <a href="https://www.fda.gov/drugs/news-events-human-drugs/fda-updates-paxlovid-health-care-providers">FAQ</a> and created an <a href="https://www.fda.gov/media/158165/download">eligibility screening checklist</a> to help providers get this treatment to all patients that need it.</li><li><strong>Providing more resources for the immunocompromised:</strong> The Administration continues to prioritize protections for immunocompromised individuals. This includes ensuring that immunocompromised individuals have free and easy access to additional booster shots, and making pre-exposure prophylaxis drugs like Evusheld widely available and free to help those with moderately and severely compromised immune systems mount an adequate immune response to COVID-19. As part of the Administration’s ongoing commitment, we continue to ensure immunocompromised individuals have easy access to the best and latest information on federal websites about vaccines and Evusheld, including highlighting this information on covid.gov. Additionally, the Administration continues to engage provider organizations representing clinicians that care for the majority of immunocompromised patients to make sure that they are doing everything they can to ensure that all patients who would benefit from Evusheld are informed and offered the opportunity to receive the treatment.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris at Signing of Executive Order to Advance Effective, Accountable Policing and Strengthen Public&#160;Safety</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/25/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-at-signing-of-executive-order-to-advance-effective-accountable-policing-and-strengthen-public-safety/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2022 00:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[4:14 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Please have a seat.&#160; Good afternoon. President Joe Biden, members of our Cabinet, members of Congress, community leaders, law enforcement officials: It’s good to be here with all of you &#8212; not under these circumstances, but it is good be with you. And I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>4:14 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Please have a seat.&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br><br>President Joe Biden, members of our Cabinet, members of Congress, community leaders, law enforcement officials: It’s good to be here with all of you &#8212; not under these circumstances, but it is good be with you.<br><br>And I know, of course, that today, following yesterday, that all of our hearts, of course, are with the people of Uvalde, Texas; with the parents, with the children; with all the folks who said goodbye yesterday morning to someone they loved, not knowing that that goodbye would be their last.<br><br>Enough is enough.&nbsp; Enough is enough.<br><br>As the President said last night, we must have the courage to stand up to the gun lobby and pass reasonable gun safety laws.&nbsp;<br><br>We must work together to create an America where everyone feels safe in their community, where children feel safe in their schools.&nbsp; And, of course, that responsibility that we collectively have to ensure that all people feel safe in their community is what brings us together today.<br><br>It is an honor to be joined by the families of George Floyd, Breonna Taylor, and many others.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve met many of you before and many times, and many others I&#8217;m meeting for the first time.<br><br>I&#8217;m moved, as always, by your courage.&nbsp; You have felt so much pain, and you have endured unimaginable grief.&nbsp; You have experienced the anguish of losing someone you love and cherish.&nbsp; And yet, you are here, as you have been throughout the days of your grief, standing selflessly, full of grace and resilience, to speak up, to speak out, often against odds &#8212; great odds &#8212; to fight for a world where no one has to experience what you have been through.<br><br>Your loved ones should be with us today.&nbsp; You should not have to mourn.&nbsp; You should never have had to mourn in order for our nation to feel your pain and to understand what is wrong and to agree that something must be done.<br><br>I know it is a particularly difficult day for the Floyd family.&nbsp; Two years ago today, a brother, a son, a father was taken from you.&nbsp; We will never forget what happened that day.&nbsp; The eyes of the world, literally, were on what happened that day.<br><br>And, collectively, we remain horrified by what we witnessed.&nbsp; And we are here today, in memory of George Floyd and all those we have lost, to take action.&nbsp;<br><br>The law enforcement officers of our nation &#8212; well, they swear an oath to protect and to serve, and the vast majority do so honorably.&nbsp; Yet we know, too often, when there is a use of biased policing and excessive force &#8212; when that occurs, it too often is not met with accountability, denying equal justice not just to individuals but to whole communities and, therefore, to our nation as a whole.<br><br>Trust between law enforcement and the communities they serve is critical to ensuring public safety.&nbsp;<br><br>And as many of you know, this is an issue I have worked on personally since my first days as an elected district attorney and as California&#8217;s Attorney General.<br><br>As a United States senator, I, together with Senator Cory <s>Book</s> [Booker], Congresswoman Karen Bass, introduced legislation to advance much-needed reforms.&nbsp; That legislation would have ensured greater transparency and increased accountability.<br><br>We later named it the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act.&nbsp; And it was passed, because of the strength of the leadership in the House of Representatives, through the House of Representatives.<br><br>However, last fall, Senate Republicans rejected the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act.&nbsp; They walked away from their moral obligation to address what caused millions of Americans to march in the streets: the critical need that a coalition of Americans were demanding, were pleading for, in terms of reform and accountability.<br><br>At the time, President Joe Biden and I, and all of us here, we made clear and we vowed that we would explore every action available to us at the executive level to advance the cause of justice in our nation.&nbsp;<br><br>In a moment, our President will sign an executive order that takes dozens of important actions to advance effective, accountable policing; to strengthen trust between law enforcement and the communities they serve; and to help us fight crime and promote public safety.<br><br>This order will help protect our communities, and it will help keep members of law enforcement safe on the job.<br><br>These actions are a result of input and collaboration from a broad set of partners, many of whom are here today: civil rights leaders; members of Congress, in particular members of the Congressional Black Caucus &#8212; and I see Madam Chair here with us today; leading law enforcement groups; and, of course, the families of the victims.<br><br>We know this executive order will not take away your pain &#8212; your pain &#8212; and the pain of all those families who may not be in this room right now.<br><br>We also know this executive order is no substitute for legislation nor does it accomplish everything we know must be done.&nbsp; But it is a necessary and long-overdue, critical step forward.<br><br>And once again, the President and I call on the United States Senate to pass the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act. And once again, we vow that we will do everything in our power to protect public safety, to support law enforcement, and to address this issue of racial injustice wherever it exists.<br><br>And with that, it is now my great honor to introduce a man who, when he ran for President, was clear in his purpose, which was to bring our nation together, who fights every day to make sure all our communities are safe and that the rights of all people are protected.&nbsp; The President of the United States, Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all.&nbsp; Vice President Harris.<br><br>Before we begin, let me say a few words about what happened in Uvalde, Texas, elementary school.<br><br>Since I spoke last night, the confirmed death toll has tragically climbed, including another teacher and two more &#8212; three more students.<br><br>Jill and I will be traveling to Texas in the coming days to meet with the families and let them know we have a sense &#8212; just a sense of their pain, and hopefully bring some little comfort to the community in shock, in grief, and in trauma.&nbsp; As a nation, I think we all must be there for them.&nbsp; Everyone.<br><br>And we must ask: When in God’s name will we do what needs to be done to, if not completely stop, fundamentally change the amount of the carnage that goes on in this country?<br><br>To state the obvious, like Cory and a lot of other people here, I’m sick and tired &#8212; I&#8217;m just sick and tired of what&#8217;s going on and continues to go on.<br><br>I spent my career, as chairman of the Judiciary Committee and as Vice President, working for commonsense gun reforms &#8212; as I said, as a senator and a Vice President.<br><br>While they clearly will not prevent every tragedy, we know certain ones will have significant impact and have no negative impact on the Second Amendment.&nbsp; The Second Amendment is not absolute.&nbsp; When it was passed, you couldn&#8217;t own a &#8212; you couldn&#8217;t own a cannon, you couldn&#8217;t own certain kinds of weapons.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just &#8212; there&#8217;s always been limitations.<br><br>But guess what?&nbsp; These actions we&#8217;ve taken before, they saved lives.&nbsp; And they can do it again.<br><br>The idea that an 18-year-old can walk into a store and buy weapons of war, designed and marketed to kill, is, I think, just wrong.&nbsp; It just violates common sense.&nbsp; Even the manufacturer &#8212; the inventor of that weapon thought that as well.<br><br>You know, where is the backbone?&nbsp; Where is the courage to stand up to a very powerful lobby?<br><br>But here is one modest step:<br><br>The federal agency that measures and ensures that gun laws are enforced and the Second Amendment is abided by &#8212; the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, the <s>AFT</s> [ATF] &#8212; has not had a Senate confirmation leader for seven years because of these disputes.&nbsp; For seven years, they&#8217;ve been out &#8212; without anyone in charge.<br><br>I nominated a supremely qualified former prosecutor who has broad bipartisan support from law enforcement and the community overall.<br><br>His hearing was held easier today &#8212; earlier today, I should say.&nbsp;<br><br>The Senate should confirm him without delay, without excuse.&nbsp; Send the nomination to my desk.&nbsp; It’s time for action.<br><br>We&#8217;re here today for the same purpose: to come together and say, &#8220;Enough”; to act.&nbsp; We must.</p>



<p>Vice President Harris and members of the Cabinet; members of the Congress; civil rights leaders; law enforcement officers and officials; distinguished guests, especially the families missing a piece of their soul, including the family sitting in front of me and the beautiful young girl who told me, &#8220;My daddy is going to change history.”&nbsp;&nbsp;And he will, honey.&nbsp;&nbsp;He will.&nbsp;&nbsp;They&#8217;ve lost a piece of their soul two years ago as well.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I know events remembering your loved ones, even though they&#8217;re meant with great reverence, are really hard.&nbsp; Everything is coming back as if it was &#8212; happened yesterday.<br><br>But in your own ways, you’ve each &#8212; each of you whose family has been victimized have summoned the courage to find purpose through your pain, to stir justice that&#8217;s been too long dormant, and to give hope while in need of hope yourself.<br><br>That’s why the executive order I&#8217;ll be signing today is so important, in my view.&nbsp; It’s a measure of what we can do together to heal the very soul of this nation; to address the profound fear and trauma, exhaustion that particularly Black Americans have experienced for generations; and to channel that private pain and public outrage into a rare mark of progress for years to come.<br><br>Two summers ago, in the middle of a pandemic, we saw protests across the nation the likes of which you hadn’t seen since the 1960s.<br><br>They unified people of every race and generation. &nbsp;Athletes and sports leagues boycotted and postponed games. &nbsp;Companies and workers proclaimed “Black Lives Matter.” &nbsp;Students staged solidarity walkouts.<br><br>From Europe to the Middle East to Asia to Australia, people saw their own fight for justice and equality in what we were trying to do.&nbsp;<br><br>The message is clear: Enough!&nbsp; Just, “Enough.”&nbsp;<br><br>And, look, almost &#8212; almost a year later &#8212; (applause) &#8212; almost a year later, a jury in Minnesota stepped up and they found a police officer guilty of murdering George Floyd, with officers and even a police chief taking the stand to testify against misconduct of their colleagues.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know any good cop who likes a bad cop.&nbsp;<br><br>But for many people, including many families here, such accountability is all too rare.&nbsp; That’s why I promised as President I would do everything in my power to enact meaningful police reform that is real and lasting.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why I called on Congress to pass the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to send it to my desk.</p>



<p>Some asked why I haven’t done this executive order earlier.&nbsp; If I’d done it, I was worried it would undercut the effort to get the law passed.</p>



<p>This is a call to action based on a basic truth: Public trust, as any cop will tell you, is the foundation of public safety.&nbsp; If they’re not trusted, the population doesn’t contribute, doesn’t cooperate.</p>



<p>Two sides of the same soin [sic] &#8212; coin, inextricably linked.&nbsp; And the principles of fairness and equal justice are at the core of each of them.</p>



<p>For the wheels of justice are propelled by the confidence that people have in their system of justice.&nbsp; Without that confidence, crimes would go unreported.&nbsp; Witness fears come &#8212; don’t &#8212; fear to come forward; cases go unsolved; victims suffer in isolation while perpetrators remain free; and ironically, police are put in greater &#8212; greater danger; justice goes undelivered.&nbsp;<br><br>Without public trust, law enforcement can’t do its job<br>of serving and protecting all of our communities.&nbsp; But as we’ve seen all too often, public trust is frayed and broken, and that undermines public safety.</p>



<p>The families here today and across the country have had to ask why this nation &#8212; why so many Black Americans wake up knowing they could lose their life in the course of just living their life today &#8212; simply jogging, shopping, sleeping at home.&nbsp; Whether they made headlines or not, lost souls gone too soon.</p>



<p>Members of Congress, including many here today &#8212; like Senator Cory Booker and <s>Congressman</s> [Congresswoman] Karen Bass, alongside members of the Congressional Black Caucus, House and Senate Judiciary Committees &#8212; spent countless hours on the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act to find a better answer to that question.</p>



<p>I sincerely thank you all for your tireless efforts.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But they’re not over.</p>



<p>The House passed a strong bill.&nbsp; It failed in the Senate where our Republican colleagues opposed any meaningful reform.</p>



<p>So we got to work on this executive order, which is grounded in key elements of the Justice in Policing Act and reflects inputs of a broad coalition represented here today.</p>



<p>Families courageously shared their perspectives on what happened to their loved ones and what we could do to make sure it doesn’t happen to somebody else.</p>



<p>Civil rights groups and their leaders of every generation who have given their heart and soul to this work provided critical insights and perspectives.</p>



<p>The executive order also benefits from the valuable inputs of law enforcement who put their lines on the li- &#8212; lives on the line every single day to serve.<br><br>Now, let me say there are those who seek to drive a wedge between law enforcement and the people they serve; those who peddle the fiction that public trust and public safety are in opposition to one another.<br><br>We know that’s not true, but it occurs.&nbsp; I believe the vast majority of Americans want the same thing: trust, safety, and accountability.<br><br>The vast majority of law enforcement risk their lives every day to do the right thing.&nbsp; Their families wait for that phone call every time they put on that shield.<br><br>Just yesterday in Uvalde, brave local officers and Border Patrol agents intervened to save as many children as they could.<br><br>Here today, I want to especially thank the International Association of Chiefs of Police, the Fraternal Order of Police, as well as the National Organization of Black Law Enforcement Executives &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the Federal Law Enforcement [Officers] Association, the Police Executive Research Forum, Major City Chiefs Association, and others who stepped up &#8212; stepped up and endorsed what we’re talking about today.<br><br>As divided as this nation can feel, today we’re showing the strength of our unity.&nbsp; It matters.</p>



<p>This executive order is going to deliver the most significant police reform in decades.&nbsp; It applies directly, under law, to only 100,000 federal law enforcement officers &#8212; all the federal law enforcement officers.&nbsp; And though federal incentives and best practices they’re attached to, we expect the order to have significant impact on state and local law enforcement agencies as well.<br><br>Here are the key parts:<br><br>First, the executive order promotes accountability.&nbsp; It creates a new national law enforcement accountability database to track records of misconduct so that an officer can’t hide the misconduct.<br><br>It strengthens the pattern-and-practice investigations to address <s>systematic</s> [systemic] misconduct in some departments.&nbsp; It mandates all federal agents wear and activate body cameras while on patrol.<br><br>Second, the executive order raises standards, bans chokeholds, restricts no-knock warrants, tightens use-of-force policies to emphasize de-escalation and the duty to intervene to stop another officer from using <s>executive</s> [excessive] force, just as occurred &#8212; that didn’t occur, but people testified it didn’t occur in George Floyd’s case.<br><br>And third, the executive order modernizes policing.&nbsp; It calls for a presh [sic] &#8212; a fresh approach to recruit, train, promote, and retain law enforcement that tied to advancing public safety and public trust.<br>Right now, we don’t systematically collect data, for instance, on instances of police use of force.&nbsp; This executive order is going to improve that data collection.</p>



<p>There’s a lot more as well.&nbsp; The bottom line of the executive order includes reforms that have long been talked about but we’re finally implementing at a federal level.&nbsp; And it comes at a critical time.<br><br>By building trust, we can strengthen public safety and we can more effectively fight crime in our communities.&nbsp; And we can do one more thing: We can show what’s possible when we work together.</p>



<p>Look, I know &#8212; I know progress can be slow and frustrating.&nbsp; And there’s a concern that the reckoning on race inspired two years ago is beginning to fade.<br><br>But acting today, we’re showing that our dear friend, the late John Lewis &#8212; Congressman &#8212; wrote in his final words after his final march for justice in July of 2020.&nbsp; He said, “Democracy is not a state.&nbsp; It is an act.”&nbsp; Democracy is not a state, it’s an act &#8212; an affirmative act.&nbsp; And today, we’re acting.<br><br>We’re showing that speaking out matters, being engaged matters, and that the work of our time &#8212; healing the soul of this nation &#8212; is ongoing and unfinished, and requires all of us never to give up, always to keep the faith.<br><br>I’ll close with this:<br><br>Over two years now &#8212; for over two years, we’ve gotten to know one another and pray with one another &#8212; not figuratively, literally.</p>



<p>I promise the Floyd family, among others, that George’s name is not just going to be a hashtag.&nbsp; Your daddy’s name is going to be known for a long time.&nbsp; And that as a nation, we’re going to ensure his legacy and the legacy of so many others remembered today &#8212; it’s not about their death but what we do in their memory that matters.&nbsp; The purpose.<br><br>In just a few mi- &#8212; in just a few moments, I’m going to deliver on that promise when I sign the executive order.<br><br>And Kamala and I will continue, along with our friends in Congress, to get meaningful police reform legislation on my desk as best we can, as quickly as we can, beyond what we’re doing here, affecting states as well, directly.<br><br>On this day, we’re showing the America we know.&nbsp; We’re a great nation because the vast majority of us are good people.&nbsp; And there’s nothing beyond our capacity &#8212; nothing &#8212; when we act together as the <em>United</em> States of America.<br><br>And this is a start &#8212; a new start.&nbsp; May God bless you all, and may God protect our forces.<br><br>And now I’m going to go sign that executive order.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I’m about to sign “Advancing Executive Accountable Policing and Criminal Justice Practices to Enhance Public Trust and Public Safety.”<br><br>And since I only have one pen, you all are going to get a copy of this pen.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I don’t have to do one stroke at a time with each pen.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>(The executive order is signed.)&nbsp; God willing (inaudible).&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>(Gianna Floyd comes up to the stage and sits at the signing desk.)<br><br>You know what she told me when I saw her when she was a little girl two years ago?&nbsp; Seriously, she pulled me aside and she said, “My daddy is going to change the world.”&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Thank you, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>4:43 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Advancing Effective, Accountable Policing and Criminal Justice Practices to Enhance Public Trust and Public&#160;Safety</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/25/executive-order-on-advancing-effective-accountable-policing-and-criminal-justice-practices-to-enhance-public-trust-and-public-safety/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 21:50:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54180</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, I hereby order as follows: Section 1.&#160; Policy.&#160; Our criminal justice system must respect the dignity and rights of all persons and adhere to our fundamental obligation to ensure fair and impartial justice for all.&#160; This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, I hereby order as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; Our criminal justice system must respect the dignity and rights of all persons and adhere to our fundamental obligation to ensure fair and impartial justice for all.&nbsp; This is imperative &#8212; not only to live up to our principles as a Nation, but also to build secure, safe, and healthy communities.&nbsp; Protecting public safety requires close partnerships between law enforcement and the communities it serves.&nbsp; Public safety therefore depends on public trust, and public trust in turn requires that our criminal justice system as a whole embodies fair and equal treatment, transparency, and accountability.</p>



<p>Law enforcement officers are often a person&#8217;s first point of contact with our criminal justice system, and we depend on them to uphold these principles while doing the demanding and often life-threatening work of keeping us safe.&nbsp; We expect them to help prevent and solve crimes and frequently call upon them to respond to social problems outside their expertise and beyond their intended role, diverting attention from their critical public safety mission and increasing the risks of an already dangerous job &#8212; which has led to the deaths of law enforcement officers and civilians alike.&nbsp; The vast majority of law enforcement officers do these difficult jobs with honor and integrity, and they work diligently to uphold the law and preserve the public&#8217;s trust.</p>



<p>Yet, there are places in America today, particularly in Black and Brown communities and other communities of color, where the bonds of trust are frayed or broken. &nbsp;We have collectively mourned following law enforcement encounters that have tragically ended in the loss of life. &nbsp;To heal as a Nation, we must acknowledge that those fatal encounters have disparately impacted Black and Brown people and other people of color. &nbsp;The pain of the families of those who have been killed is magnified when expectations for accountability go unmet, and the echoes of their losses reverberate across generations. &nbsp;More broadly, numerous aspects of our criminal justice system are still shaped by race or ethnicity.&nbsp; It is time that we acknowledge the legacy of systemic racism in our criminal justice system and work together to eliminate the racial disparities that endure to this day.&nbsp; Doing so serves all Americans. </p>



<p>Through this order, my Administration is taking a critical step in what must be part of a larger effort to strengthen our democracy and advance the principles of equality and dignity. &nbsp;While we can make policing safer and more effective by strengthening trust between law enforcement officers and the communities they serve, we must also reform our broader criminal justice system so that it protects and serves all people equally.&nbsp; To be clear, certain obstacles to lasting reform require legislative solutions.&nbsp; In particular, system-wide change requires funding and support that only the Congress can authorize.&nbsp; But my Administration will use its full authority to take action, including through the implementation of this order, to build and sustain fairness and accountability throughout the criminal justice system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The need for such action could not be more urgent.&nbsp; Since early 2020, communities around the country have faced rising rates of violent crime, requiring law enforcement engagement at a time when law enforcement agencies are already confronting the challenges of staffing shortages and low morale. &nbsp;Strengthening community trust is more critical now than ever, as a community&#8217;s cooperation with the police to report crimes and assist investigations is essential for deterring violence and holding perpetrators accountable. &nbsp;Reinforcing the partnership between law enforcement and communities is imperative for combating crime and achieving lasting public safety.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is therefore the policy of my Administration to increase public trust and enhance public safety and security by encouraging equitable and community-oriented policing.&nbsp; We must commit to new practices in law enforcement recruitment, hiring, promotion, and retention, as well as training, oversight, and accountability.&nbsp; Insufficient resources, including those dedicated to support officer wellness &#8212; needed more than ever as officers confront rising crime and the effects of the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic &#8212; jeopardize the law enforcement community&#8217;s ability to build and retain a highly qualified and diverse professional workforce.&nbsp; We must work together to ensure that law enforcement agencies have the resources they need as well as the capacity to attract, hire, and retain the best personnel, including resources to institute screening mechanisms to identify unqualified applicants and to support officers in meeting the stresses and challenges of the job.&nbsp; We must also ensure that law enforcement agencies reflect the communities they serve, protect all community members equally, and offer comprehensive training and development opportunities to line officers and supervisors alike.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Building trust between law enforcement agencies and the communities they are sworn to protect and serve also requires accountability for misconduct and transparency through data collection and public reporting.&nbsp; It requires proactive measures to prevent profiling based on actual or perceived race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity), or disability, including by ensuring that new law enforcement technologies do not exacerbate disparities based on these characteristics.&nbsp; It includes ending discriminatory pretextual stops and offering support for evidence-informed, innovative responses to people with substance use disorders; people with mental health needs; veterans; people with disabilities; vulnerable youth; people who are victims of domestic violence, sexual assault, or trafficking; and people experiencing homelessness or living in poverty.&nbsp; It calls for improving and clarifying standards for police activities such as the execution of search warrants and the use of force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many law enforcement agencies across the country &#8212; including at the Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial level &#8212; have already undertaken important efforts to modernize policing and make our broader criminal justice system more effective and more equitable.&nbsp; Their work has inspired many of the provisions of this order.&nbsp; These agencies &#8212; and the officers who serve within them &#8212; deserve recognition for their leadership and appreciation for setting a standard that others can follow.&nbsp; This order seeks to recognize these key reforms and implement them consistently across Federal law enforcement agencies.&nbsp; Through this order, the Federal Government will also seek to provide State, Tribal, local, and territorial law enforcement agencies with the guidance and support they need to advance their own efforts to strengthen public trust and improve public safety.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is also the policy of my Administration to ensure that conditions of confinement are safe and humane, and that those who are incarcerated are not subjected to unnecessary or excessive uses of force, are free from prolonged segregation, and have access to quality health care, including substance use disorder care and mental health care.&nbsp; We must provide people who are incarcerated with meaningful opportunities for rehabilitation and the tools and support they need to transition successfully back to society.&nbsp; Individuals who have been involved in the criminal justice system face many barriers in transitioning back into society, including limited access to housing, public benefits, health care, trauma-informed services and support, education, nutrition, employment and occupational licensing, credit, the ballot, and other critical opportunities.&nbsp; Lowering barriers to reentry is essential to reducing recidivism and reducing crime.</p>



<p>Finally, no one should be required to serve an excessive prison sentence.&nbsp; When the Congress passed the First Step Act of 2018 (Public Law 115-391), it sought to relieve people from unfair and unduly harsh sentences, including those driven by harsh mandatory minimums and the unjust sentencing disparity between crack and powder cocaine offenses.&nbsp; My Administration will fully implement the First Step Act, including by supporting sentencing reductions in appropriate cases and by allowing eligible incarcerated people to participate in recidivism reduction programming and earn time credits.</p>



<p>With these measures, together we can strengthen public safety and the bonds of trust between law enforcement and the community and build a criminal justice system that respects the dignity and equality of all in America.</p>



<p><u>Sec</u>. 2.&nbsp; Sharing of Federal Best Practices with State, Tribal, Local, and Territorial Law Enforcement Agencies to Enhance Accountability.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;<em>Independent Investigations of In-Custody Deaths</em>. &nbsp;The Attorney General shall issue guidance to State, Tribal, local, and territorial law enforcement agencies (LEAs) regarding best practices for conducting independent criminal investigations of deaths in custody that may involve conduct by law enforcement or prison personnel.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;<em>Improving Training for Investigations into Deprivation of Rights Under Color of Law.&nbsp; </em>The Attorney General shall assess the steps necessary to enhance the Department of Justice&#8217;s (DOJ&#8217;s) capacity to investigate law enforcement deprivation of rights under color of law, including through improving and increasing training of Federal law enforcement officers, their supervisors, and Federal prosecutors on how to investigate and prosecute cases involving the deprivation of rights under color of law pursuant to 18 U.S.C. 242.&nbsp; The Attorney General shall also, as appropriate, provide guidance, technical assistance, and training to State, Tribal, local, and territorial investigators and prosecutors on best practices for investigating and prosecuting civil rights violations under applicable law.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;<em>Pattern or Practice Investigations.</em> &nbsp;The Attorney General shall consider ways in which the DOJ could strengthen communication with State Attorneys General to help identify relevant data, complaints from the public, and other information that may assist the DOJ&#8217;s investigations of patterns or practices of misconduct by law enforcement officers, including prosecutors, pursuant to 34 U.S.C. 12601 and other statutes. &nbsp;The Attorney General shall also develop training and technical assistance for State, local, and territorial officials who have similar investigatory authority.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;<em>Ensuring Timely Investigations.</em> &nbsp;The heads of all Federal LEAs shall assess whether any of their respective agency&#8217;s policies or procedures cause unwarranted delay in investigations of Federal law enforcement officers for incidents involving the use of deadly force or deaths in custody, including delays in interagency jurisdictional determinations and subject and witness interviews, and shall, without abrogating any collective bargaining obligations, make changes as appropriate to ensure the integrity and effectiveness of such investigations. &nbsp;Within 240 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the heads of other executive departments and agencies (agencies) with law enforcement authority shall report to the President what, if any, changes to their respective policies or practices they have made.</p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;<em>Ensuring Thorough Investigations</em>.&nbsp; The Attorney General shall instruct the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) and all United States Attorneys to coordinate closely with the internal oversight bodies of Federal LEAs to ensure that, without abrogating any collective bargaining obligations, for incidents involving the use of deadly force or deaths in custody, initial investigative efforts (including evidence collection and witness interviews) preserve the information required to complete timely administrative investigations as required by the Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2013 (Public Law 113-242) and agency use-of-force guidelines.</p>



<p>(f)&nbsp; <em>Ensuring Timely and Consistent Discipline.</em>&nbsp; The heads of all Federal LEAs shall assess whether any of their respective agency&#8217;s policies or procedures cause unwarranted delay or inconsistent application of discipline for incidents involving the use of deadly force or deaths in custody, and shall, without abrogating any collective bargaining obligations, make changes as appropriate.&nbsp; Within 240 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the heads of other Federal LEAs shall report to the President what, if any, changes to their respective policies or practices they have made.</p>



<p><u>Sec</u>. <u>3</u>.&nbsp; <u>Strengthening Officer Recruitment, Hiring, Promotion, and Retention Practices</u>.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall convene and chair an interagency working group to strengthen Federal law enforcement recruitment, hiring, promotion, and retention practices, with particular attention to promoting an inclusive, diverse, and expert law enforcement workforce, culminating in an action plan to be published within 365 days of the date of this order.&nbsp; The interagency working group shall consist of the heads of Federal LEAs and shall consult with other stakeholders, such as law enforcement organizations. &nbsp;The interagency working group shall, to the extent possible, coordinate on the development of a set of core policies and best practices to be used across all Federal LEAs regarding recruitment, hiring, promotion, and retention, while also identifying any agency-specific unique recruitment, hiring, promotion, and retention challenges. &nbsp;As part of this process, the interagency working group shall:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; assess existing policies and identify and share best practices for recruitment and hiring, including by considering the merits and feasibility of recruiting law enforcement officers who are representative of the communities they are sworn to serve (including recruits who live in or are from these communities) and by considering the recommendations made in the Federal LEAs&#8217; strategic plans required under Executive Order 14035 of June 25, 2021 (Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility in the Federal Workforce);</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; assess existing policies and identify and share best practices for promotion and retention, including by identifying ways to expand mentorship and leadership development opportunities for law enforcement officers;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; develop best practices for ensuring that performance evaluations and promotion decisions for Federal law enforcement officers include an assessment of the officer&#8217;s adherence to agency policies, and that performance evaluations and promotion decisions for supervisors include an assessment of the supervisor&#8217;s effectiveness in addressing misconduct by officers they supervise; and&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp; develop best practices for conducting background investigations and implementing properly validated selection procedures, including vetting mechanisms and ongoing employment screening, that, consistent with the First Amendment and all applicable laws, help avoid the hiring and retention of law enforcement officers who promote unlawful violence, white supremacy, or other bias against persons based on race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity), or disability.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; Within 180 days of the publication of the interagency working group&#8217;s action plan described in subsection (a) of this section, the heads of Federal LEAs shall update and implement their policies and protocols for recruiting, hiring, promotion, and retention, consistent with the core policies and best practices identified and developed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.&nbsp; Such policies and protocols shall include mechanisms for Federal LEAs to regularly assess the effectiveness of their recruitment, hiring, promotion, and retention practices in accomplishing the goals of subsection (a) of this section.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The heads of Federal LEAs shall develop and implement protocols for background investigations and screening mechanisms, consistent with the best practices identified and developed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, for State, Tribal, local, and territorial law enforcement participation in programs or activities over which Federal agencies exercise control, such as joint task forces or international training and technical assistance programs, including programs managed by the Department of State and the Department of Justice.</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall develop guidance regarding best practices for State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs seeking to recruit, hire, promote, and retain highly qualified and service-oriented officers.&nbsp; In developing this guidance, the Attorney General shall consult with State, Tribal, local, and territorial law enforcement, as appropriate, and shall incorporate the best practices identified by the interagency working group established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</p>



<p>Sec. 4.&nbsp; Supporting Officer Wellness. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General shall, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), develop and publish a report on best practices to address law enforcement officer wellness, including support for officers experiencing substance use disorders, mental health issues, or trauma from their duties.&nbsp; This report shall: &nbsp;</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; consider the work undertaken already pursuant to the Law Enforcement Mental Health and Wellness Act of 2017 (Public Law 115-113); and</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; identify existing and needed resources for supporting law enforcement officer wellness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;Upon publication of these best practices, the Attorney General and the heads of all other Federal LEAs shall assess their own practices and policies for Federal officer wellness and develop and implement changes as appropriate.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall, in coordination with the Secretary of HHS and in consultation with multidisciplinary experts and stakeholders, including the National Consortium on Preventing Law Enforcement Suicide and other law enforcement organizations, conduct an assessment of current efforts and available evidence on suicide prevention and present to the President within 180 days of the date of this order evidence-informed recommendations regarding the prevention of death by suicide of law enforcement officers.&nbsp; These recommendations shall also identify methods to encourage submission of data from Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs to the FBI&#8217;s Law Enforcement Suicide Data Collection, in a manner that respects the privacy interests of law enforcement officers and is consistent with applicable law.</p>



<p><u>Sec</u>. <u>5</u>.&nbsp; <u>Establishing a National Law Enforcement Accountability Database</u>.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall, within 240 days of the date of this order, establish the National Law Enforcement Accountability Database (Accountability Database) as a centralized repository of official records documenting instances of law enforcement officer misconduct as well as commendations and awards.&nbsp; The Attorney General shall ensure that the establishment and administration of the Accountability Database is consistent with the Privacy Act of 1974 and all other applicable laws, and respects appropriate due process protections for law enforcement officers included in the Accountability Database. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The Attorney General, in consultation with the heads of other agencies as appropriate, shall take the following actions with respect to the Accountability Database established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;include in the Accountability Database all available information that the Attorney General deems necessary, appropriate, and consistent with law and with considerations of victim confidentiality, concerning misconduct by Federal law enforcement officers relevant to carrying out their official duties;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; include in the Accountability Database, to the maximum extent permitted by law, official records documenting officer misconduct, including, as appropriate: &nbsp;records of criminal convictions; suspension of a law enforcement officer&#8217;s enforcement authorities, such as de-certification; terminations; civil judgments, including amounts (if publicly available), related to official duties; and resignations or retirements while under investigation for serious misconduct or sustained complaints or records of disciplinary action based on findings of serious misconduct; &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; include in the Accountability Database records of officer commendations and awards, as the Attorney General deems appropriate; and</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp; establish appropriate procedures to ensure that the records stored in the Accountability Database are accurate, including by providing officers with sufficient notice and access to their records, as well as a full and fair opportunity to request amendment or removal of any information about themselves from the Accountability Database on the grounds that it is inaccurate or that it is predicated on an official proceeding that lacked appropriate due process protections.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; Requirements for the submission of information to the Accountability Database are as follows:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; the heads of Federal LEAs shall submit the information determined appropriate for inclusion by the Attorney General under subsection (b) of this section on a quarterly basis, beginning no later than 60 days from the establishment of the Accountability Database; and&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the Attorney General shall encourage State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs to contribute to and use the Accountability Database in a manner consistent with subsection (b)(i) of this section and as permitted by law.&nbsp; The Attorney General shall also issue appropriate guidance and technical assistance to further this goal.</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;In establishing the Accountability Database under subsection (a) of this section, the Attorney General shall:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;make use of Federal records from DOJ databases to the maximum extent permitted by law;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; make use of information held by other agencies or entities by entering into agreements with the heads of other agencies or entities, as necessary and appropriate;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; make use of publicly accessible and reliable sources of information, such as court records, as necessary and appropriate; and</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp; make use of information submitted by State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs, as necessary and appropriate.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; The heads of Federal LEAs shall ensure that the Accountability Database established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section is used, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, in the hiring, job assignment, and promotion of law enforcement officers within Federal LEAs, as well as in the screening of State, Tribal, local, and territorial law enforcement officers who participate in programs or activities over which Federal agencies exercise control, such as joint task forces or international training and technical assistance programs, including programs managed by the Department of State and the DOJ.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(f)&nbsp; The Attorney General shall establish procedures for the submission of employment-related inquiries by Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs, and for the provision, upon such a query, of relevant information to the requestor as appropriate.&nbsp; The Attorney General shall develop guidance and provide technical assistance to encourage State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs to integrate use of the Accountability Database established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section into their hiring decisions, consistent with applicable law.</p>



<p>(g) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall ensure that all access to the Accountability Database established pursuant to subsection (a) of this section is consistent with applicable law, and shall also take the following steps related to public access to the Accountability Database:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;publish on at least an annual basis public reports that contain anonymized data from the Accountability Database aggregated by law enforcement agency and by any other factor determined appropriate by the Attorney General, in a manner that does not jeopardize law enforcement officer anonymity due to the size of the agency or other factors; and&nbsp;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; assess the feasibility of what records from the Accountability Database may be accessible to the public and the manner in which any such records may be accessible by the public, taking into account the critical need for public trust, transparency, and accountability, as well as the duty to protect the safety, privacy, and due process rights of law enforcement officers who may be identified in the Accountability Database, including obligations under the Privacy Act of 1974 and any other relevant legal obligations; protection of sensitive law enforcement operations; and victim, witness, and source confidentiality.</p>



<p>(h)&nbsp; The Attorney General shall determine whether additional legislation or appropriation of funds is needed to achieve the full objectives of this section. <a></a></p>



<p>Sec. 6.&nbsp; Improving Use-of-Force Data Collection.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the heads of Federal LEAs shall submit data on a monthly basis to the FBI National Use-of-Force Data Collection (Use-of-Force Database), in accordance with the definitions and categories set forth by the FBI.&nbsp; To the extent not already collected, such data shall include either all deaths of a person due to law enforcement use of force (including deaths in custody incident to an official use of force); all serious bodily injuries of a person due to law enforcement use of force; all discharges of a firearm by law enforcement at or in the direction of a person not otherwise resulting in death or serious bodily injury; or, if applicable, a report for each category that no qualifying incidents occurred and:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; information about the incident, including date, time, and location; the reason for initial contact; the offenses of which the subject was suspected, if any; the charges filed against the suspect by a prosecutor, if any; and the National Incident-Based Reporting System (NIBRS) record or local incident number of the report;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; information about the subject of the use of force, including demographic data by subcategory to the maximum extent possible; types of force used against the subject; resulting injuries or death; and reason for the use of force, including any threat or resistance from, or weapon possessed by, the subject;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; information about the officers involved, including demographic data by subcategory to the maximum extent possible; years of service in law enforcement and employing agency at the time of the incident; and resulting injuries or death; and</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp; such other information as the Attorney General deems appropriate.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The Attorney General, in consultation with the United&nbsp;States Chief Technology Officer, shall work with State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs to identify the obstacles to their participation in the Use-of-Force Database; to reduce the administrative burden of reporting by using existing data collection efforts and improving those LEAs&#8217; experience; and to provide training and technical assistance to those LEAs to encourage and facilitate their regular submission of use-of-force information to the Use-of-Force Database. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall, in a manner that does not reveal the identity of any victim or law enforcement officer, publish quarterly data collected pursuant to subsection (a) of this section and make the data available for research and statistical purposes, in accordance with the standards of data privacy and integrity required by the Office of Management and Budget (OMB).</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall also provide training and technical assistance to encourage State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs to submit information to the Law Enforcement Officers Killed and Assaulted Data Collection program of the FBI&#8217;s Uniform Crime Reporting Program.</p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall publish a report within 120&nbsp;days of the date of this order on the steps the DOJ has taken and plans to take to fully implement the Death in Custody Reporting Act of 2013.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sec. 7.&nbsp; Banning Chokeholds and Carotid Restraints. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The heads of Federal LEAs shall, as soon as practicable, but no later than 90 days from the date of this order, ensure that their respective agencies issue policies with requirements that are equivalent to, or exceed, the requirements of the policy issued by the DOJ on September 13, 2021, which generally prohibits the use of chokeholds and carotid restraints except where the use of deadly force is authorized by law.&nbsp;<a></a></p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The head of every Federal LEA shall incorporate training consistent with this section.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <u>Sec</u>. <u>8</u>.&nbsp; <u>Providing Federal Law Enforcement Officers with Clear Guidance on Use-of-Force Standards</u>.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The heads of Federal LEAs shall, as soon as practicable but no later than 90&nbsp;days from the date of this order, ensure that their respective agencies issue policies with requirements that reflect principles of valuing and preserving human life and that are equivalent to, or exceed, the requirements of the policy issued by the DOJ on May 20, 2022, which establishes standards and obligations for the use of force.</p>



<p><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong>(b) &nbsp;The heads of Federal LEAs shall, within 365 days of the date of this order, incorporate annual, evidence-informed training for their respective law enforcement officers that is consistent with the DOJ&#8217;s use-of-force policy; implement early warning systems or other risk management tools that enable supervisors to identify problematic conduct and appropriate interventions to help prevent avoidable uses of force; and ensure the use of effective mechanisms for holding their law enforcement officers accountable for violating the policies addressed in subsection (a) of this section, consistent with sections 2(f) and 3(a)(iii) of this order.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sec. 9.&nbsp; Providing Anti-Bias Training and Guidance.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and the Attorney General shall develop an evidence-informed training module for law enforcement officers on implicit bias and avoiding improper profiling based on the actual or perceived race, ethnicity, national origin, limited English proficiency, religion, sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity), or disability of individuals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The heads of Federal LEAs shall, to the extent consistent with applicable law, ensure that their law enforcement officers complete such training annually.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The heads of Federal LEAs shall, to the extent consistent with applicable law, establish that effective procedures are in place for receiving, investigating, and responding meaningfully to complaints alleging improper profiling or bias by Federal law enforcement officers. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; Federal agencies that exercise control over joint task forces or international training and technical assistance programs in which State, Tribal, local, and territorial officers participate shall include training on implicit bias and profiling as part of any training program required by the Federal agency for officers participating in the task force or program.</p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;The Attorney General, in collaboration with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the heads of other agencies as appropriate, shall assess the implementation and effects of the DOJ&#8217;s December 2014 Guidance for Federal Law Enforcement Agencies Regarding the Use of Race, Ethnicity, Gender, National Origin, Religion, Sexual Orientation, or Gender Identity; consider whether this guidance should be updated; and report to the President within 180 days of the date of this order as to any changes to this guidance that have been made.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <u>Sec</u>. <u>10</u>. &nbsp;<u>Restricting No-Knock Entries</u>.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The heads of Federal LEAs shall, as soon as practicable, but no later than 60&nbsp;days from the date of this order, ensure that their respective agencies issue policies with requirements that are equivalent to, or exceed, the requirements of the policy issued by the DOJ on September 13, 2021, which limits the use of unannounced entries, often referred to as &#8220;no-knock entries,&#8221; and provides guidance to ensure the safe execution of announced entries.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The heads of Federal LEAs shall maintain records of no-knock entries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The heads of Federal LEAs shall issue annual reports to the President &#8212; and post the reports publicly &#8212; setting forth the number of no-knock entries that occurred pursuant to judicial authorization; the number of no-knock entries that occurred pursuant to exigent circumstances; and disaggregated data by circumstances for no-knock entries in which a law enforcement officer or other person was injured in the course of a no-knock entry.</p>



<p>Sec. 11.&nbsp; Assessing and Addressing the Effect on Communities of Use of Force by Law Enforcement.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The Secretary of HHS shall, within 180 days of the date of this order, conduct a nationwide study of the community effects of use of force by law enforcement officers (whether lawful or unlawful) on physical, mental, and public health, including any disparate impacts on communities of color, and shall publish a public report including these findings.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The Attorney General, the Secretary of HHS, and the Director of OMB shall, within 60&nbsp;days of the completion of the report described in subsection (a) of this section, provide a report to the President outlining what resources are available and what additional resources may be needed to provide widely and freely accessible mental health and social support services for individuals and communities affected by incidents of use of force by law enforcement officers.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Attorney General, in collaboration with the heads of other agencies as appropriate, shall issue guidance for Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs on best practices for planning and conducting law enforcement-community dialogues to improve relations and communication between law enforcement and communities, particularly following incidents involving use of deadly force.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, in collaboration with the heads of other agencies as appropriate, shall issue guidance for Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs, or other entities responsible for providing official notification of deaths in custody, on best practices to promote the timely and appropriate notification of, and support to, family members or emergency contacts of persons who die in correctional or LEA custody, including deaths resulting from the use of force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;After the issuance of the guidance described in subsection (d) of this section, the heads of Federal LEAs shall assess and revise their policies and procedures as necessary to accord with that guidance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 12.&nbsp; Limiting the Transfer or Purchase of Certain Military Equipment by Law Enforcement.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Administrator of General Services shall each review all programs and authorities concerning property transfers to State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs, or property purchases by State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs either with Federal funds or from Federal agencies or contractors, including existing transfer contracts or grants.&nbsp; Within 60 days of the date of this order, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Administrator of General Services shall determine whether, pursuant to this order, such transfers or purchases can, consistent with applicable law, be prohibited beyond existing restrictions and, if so, shall further prohibit any such transfers or purchases, of the following property to the extent not already prohibited:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; firearms of .50 or greater caliber;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; ammunition of .50 or greater caliber;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp;&nbsp; firearm silencers, as defined in 18 U.S.C. 921(a)(24);</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; bayonets;</p>



<p>(v)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; grenade launchers;</p>



<p>(vi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; grenades (including stun and flash-bang);</p>



<p>(vii)&nbsp;&nbsp; explosives (except for explosives and percussion actuated non-electric disruptors used for accredited bomb squads and explosive detection canine training);</p>



<p>(viii)&nbsp; any vehicles that do not have a commercial application, including all tracked and armored vehicles, unless the LEA certifies that the vehicle will be used exclusively for disaster-related emergencies; active shooter scenarios; hostage or other search and rescue operations; or anti-terrorism preparedness, protection, prevention, response, recovery, or relief;</p>



<p>(ix)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; weaponized drones and weapons systems covered by DOD Directive 3000.09 of November 21, 2012, as amended (Autonomy in Weapon Systems);</p>



<p>(x)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; aircraft that are combat-configured or combat-coded, have no established commercial flight application, or have no application for disaster-related emergencies; active shooter scenarios; hostage or other search and rescue operations; or anti-terrorism preparedness, protection, prevention, response, recovery, or relief; and</p>



<p>(xi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; long-range acoustic devices that do not have a commercial application.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; Federal agencies shall review and take all necessary action, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to comply with and implement the recommendations established by the former Law Enforcement Equipment Working Group (LEEWG) pursuant to Executive Order 13688 of January 16, 2015 (Federal Support for Local Law Enforcement Equipment Acquisition), as contained in the LEEWG&#8217;s May 2015 Report (Recommendations Pursuant to Executive Order 13688, Federal Support for Local Law Enforcement Equipment Acquisition), and October 2016 Implementation Update (Recommendations Pursuant to Executive Order 13688, Federal Support for Local Law Enforcement Equipment Acquisition).&nbsp; To the extent that there is any inconsistency between this order and either the LEEWG&#8217;s May 2015 Report or October 2016 Implementation Update, this order shall supersede those documents.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;Prior to transferring any property included in the &#8220;controlled equipment list&#8221; within the October 2016 Implementation Update referenced in subsection (b) of this section, the agencies listed in subsection (a) of this section shall take all necessary action, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to ensure that the recipient State, Tribal, local, or territorial LEA:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; submits to that agency a description of how the recipient expects to use the property and demonstrates that the property will be tracked in an asset management system;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; certifies that if the recipient determines that the property is surplus to its needs, the recipient will return the property;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; certifies that the recipient notified the local community of its request for the property and translated the notification into appropriate languages to inform individuals with limited English proficiency, and certifies that the recipient notified the city council or other local governing body of its intent to request the property and that the request comports with all applicable approval requirements of the local governing body; and</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp; agrees to return the property if the DOJ determines or a Federal, State, Tribal, local, or territorial court enters a final judgment finding that the LEA has engaged in a pattern or practice of civil rights violations.</p>



<p>Sec. 13.&nbsp; Ensuring Appropriate Use of Body-Worn Cameras and Advanced Law Enforcement Technologies.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The heads of Federal LEAs shall take the following actions with respect to body-worn camera (BWC) policies:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As soon as practicable, but no later than 90&nbsp;days from the date of this order, the heads of Federal LEAs shall ensure that their respective agencies issue policies with requirements that are equivalent to, or exceed, the requirements of the policy issued by the DOJ on June 7, 2021, requiring the heads of certain DOJ law enforcement components to develop policies regarding the use of BWC recording equipment.&nbsp; The heads of Federal LEAs shall further identify the resources necessary to fully implement such policies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; For Federal LEAs that regularly conduct patrols or routinely engage with the public in response to emergency calls, the policies issued under subsection (a)(i) of this section shall be designed to ensure that cameras are worn and activated in all appropriate circumstances, including during arrests and searches.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; The heads of Federal LEAs shall ensure that all BWC policies shall be publicly posted and shall be designed to promote transparency and protect the privacy and civil rights of members of the public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;Federal LEAs shall include within the policies developed pursuant to subsection (a)(i) of this section protocols for expedited public release of BWC video footage following incidents involving serious bodily injury or deaths in custody, which shall be consistent with applicable law, including the Privacy Act of 1974, and shall take into account the need to promote transparency and accountability, the duty to protect the privacy rights of persons depicted in the footage, and any need to protect ongoing law enforcement operations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; Within 365 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of HHS and the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), shall conduct a study that assesses the advantages and disadvantages of officer review of BWC footage prior to the completion of initial reports or interviews concerning an incident involving use of force, including an assessment of current scientific research regarding the effects of such review.&nbsp; Within 180 days of the completion of that study, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of HHS, shall publish a report detailing the findings of that study, and shall identify best practices regarding law enforcement officer review of BWC footage.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General shall request the National Academy of Sciences (NAS), through its National Research Council, to enter into a contract to:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; conduct a study of facial recognition technology, other technologies using biometric information, and predictive algorithms, with a particular focus on the use of such technologies and algorithms by law enforcement, that includes an assessment of how such technologies and algorithms are used, and any privacy, civil rights, civil liberties, accuracy, or disparate impact concerns raised by those technologies and algorithms or their manner of use; and</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; publish a report detailing the findings of that study, as well as any recommendations for the use of or for restrictions on facial recognition technologies, other technologies using biometric information, and predictive algorithms by law enforcement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;The Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of OSTP shall jointly lead an interagency process regarding the use by LEAs of facial recognition technology, other technologies using biometric information, and predictive algorithms, as well as data storage and access regarding such technologies, and shall:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; ensure that the interagency process addresses safeguarding privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties, and ensure that any use of such technologies is regularly assessed for accuracy in the specific deployment context; does not have a disparate impact on the basis of race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity), or disability; and is consistent with the policy announced in section 1 of this order;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;coordinate and consult with:</p>



<p>(A) &nbsp;the NAS, including by incorporating and responding to the study described in subsection (d)(i) of this section;</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; the Subcommittee on Artificial Intelligence and Law Enforcement established by section&nbsp;5104(e) of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (Division E of Public Law 116-283); and</p>



<p>(C)&nbsp; law enforcement, civil rights, civil liberties, criminal defense, and data privacy organizations; and&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; within 18 months of the date of this order, publish a report that:</p>



<p>(A) &nbsp;identifies best practices, specifically addressing the concerns identified in subsection&nbsp;(e)(i) of this section;</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; describes any changes made to relevant policies of Federal LEAs; and</p>



<p>(C)&nbsp; recommends guidelines for Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs, as well as technology vendors whose goods or services are procured by the Federal Government, on the use of such technologies, including electronic discovery obligations regarding the accuracy and disparate impact of technologies employed in specific cases.</p>



<p>(f) &nbsp;The heads of Federal LEAs shall review the conclusions of the interagency process described in subsection (e) of this section and, where appropriate, update each of their respective agency&#8217;s policies regarding the use of facial recognition technology, other technologies using biometric information, and predictive algorithms, as well as data storage and access regarding such technologies.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 14.&nbsp; Promoting Comprehensive and Collaborative Responses to Persons in Behavioral or Mental Health Crisis.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General and the Secretary of HHS, in coordination with the heads of other agencies and after consultation with stakeholders, including service providers, nonprofit organizations, and law enforcement organizations, as appropriate, shall assess and issue guidance to State, Tribal, local, and territorial officials on best practices for responding to calls and interacting with persons in behavioral or mental health crisis or persons who have disabilities. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The assessment made under subsection (a) of this section shall draw on existing evidence and include consideration of co-responder models that pair law enforcement with health or social work professionals; alternative responder models, such as mobile crisis response teams for appropriate situations; community-based crisis centers and the facilitation of post-crisis support services, including supported housing, assertive community treatment, and peer support services; the risks associated with administering sedatives and pharmacological agents such as ketamine outside of a hospital setting to subdue individuals in behavioral or mental health crisis (including an assessment of whether the decision to administer such agents should be made only by individuals licensed to prescribe them); and the Federal resources, including Medicaid, that can be used to implement the identified best practices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 15.&nbsp; Supporting Alternatives to Arrest and Incarceration and Enhancing Reentry.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;There is established a Federal Interagency Alternatives and Reentry Committee (Committee), to be chaired by the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; Committee members shall include:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of the Treasury;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Attorney General;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of the Interior;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of Agriculture;</p>



<p>(v)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of Commerce;</p>



<p>(vi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of Labor;</p>



<p>(vii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of HHS;</p>



<p>(viii)&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development;</p>



<p>(ix)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of Transportation;</p>



<p>(x)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of Energy;</p>



<p>(xi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of Education;</p>



<p>(xii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</p>



<p>(xiii)&nbsp;&nbsp; the Secretary of Homeland Security;</p>



<p>(xiv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Director of OMB;</p>



<p>(xv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Administrator of the Small Business Administration;</p>



<p>(xvi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Counsel to the President;</p>



<p>(xvii)&nbsp;&nbsp; the Chief of Staff to the Vice President;</p>



<p>(xviii)&nbsp; the Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers;</p>



<p>(xix)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Director of the National Economic Council;</p>



<p>(xx)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Director of OSTP;</p>



<p>(xxi)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the Director of National Drug Control Policy;</p>



<p>(xxii)&nbsp;&nbsp; the Director of the Office of Personnel Management;</p>



<p>(xxiii)&nbsp; the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service;</p>



<p>(xxiv)&nbsp;&nbsp; the Executive Director of the Gender Policy Council; and</p>



<p>(xxv)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the heads of such other executive departments, agencies, and offices as the Chair may designate or invite.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The Committee shall consult and coordinate with the DOJ Reentry Coordination Council, which was formed in compliance with the requirement of the First Step Act that the Attorney General convene an interagency effort to coordinate on Federal programs, policies, and activities relating to the reentry of individuals returning from incarceration to the community.&nbsp; See sec.&nbsp;505(a) of the First Step Act.&nbsp; The Committee may consult with other agencies; Government officials; outside experts; interested persons; service providers; nonprofit organizations; law enforcement organizations; and State, Tribal, local, and territorial governments, as appropriate.</p>



<p>(d) &nbsp;The Committee shall develop and coordinate implementation of an evidence-informed strategic plan across the Federal Government within 200 days of the date of this order to advance the following goals, with particular attention to reducing racial, ethnic, and other disparities in the Nation&#8217;s criminal justice system:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; safely reducing unnecessary criminal justice interactions, including by advancing alternatives to arrest and incarceration; supporting effective alternative responses to substance use disorders, mental health needs, the needs of veterans and people with disabilities, vulnerable youth, people who are victims of domestic violence, sexual assault, or trafficking, and people experiencing homelessness or living in poverty; expanding the availability of diversion and restorative justice programs consistent with public safety; and recommending effective means of addressing minor traffic and other public order infractions to avoid unnecessarily taxing law enforcement resources;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; supporting rehabilitation during incarceration, such as through educational opportunities, job training, medical and mental health care, trauma-informed care, substance use disorder treatment and recovery support, and continuity of contact with children and other family members; and</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; facilitating reentry into society of people with criminal records, including by providing support to promote success after incarceration; sealing or expunging criminal records, as appropriate; and removing barriers to securing government-issued identification, housing, employment, occupational licenses, education, health insurance and health care, public benefits, access to transportation, and the right to vote.</p>



<p>(e) &nbsp;With respect to the goals described in subsections (d)(i) and (d)(ii) of this section, the Committee&#8217;s strategic plan shall make recommendations for State, Tribal, local, and territorial criminal justice systems.&nbsp; With respect to the goal described in subsection (d)(iii) of this section, the Committee&#8217;s strategic plan shall make recommendations for Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial criminal justice systems, and shall be informed by the Attorney General&#8217;s review conducted pursuant to subsection (f) of this section.&nbsp; Following the 200 days identified in subsection (d) of this section, all agency participants shall continue to participate in, and provide regular updates to, the Committee regarding their progress in achieving the goals described in subsections (d)(i) through (iii) of this section.</p>



<p>(f) &nbsp;Within 150 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General shall submit a report to the President that provides a strategic plan to advance the goals in subsections&nbsp;(d)(ii) and (d)(iii) of this section as they relate to the Federal criminal justice system.&nbsp; In developing that strategic plan, the Attorney General shall, as appropriate, consult with the heads of other relevant agencies to improve the Federal criminal justice system, while safeguarding the DOJ&#8217;s independence and prosecutorial discretion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(g) &nbsp;The Committee and the Attorney General&#8217;s efforts pursuant to this section may incorporate and build upon the report to the Congress issued pursuant to section 505(b) of the First Step Act.&nbsp; The Committee may refer the consideration of specific topics to be separately considered by the DOJ Reentry Coordination Council, with the approval of the Attorney General.</p>



<p>(h) &nbsp;Within 90 days of the date of this order and annually thereafter, and after appropriate consultation with the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, the United States Sentencing Commission, and the Federal Defender Service, the Attorney General shall coordinate with the DOJ Reentry Coordination Council and the DOJ Civil Rights Division to publish a report on the following data, disaggregated by judicial district:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the resources currently available to individuals on probation or supervised release, and the additional resources necessary to ensure that the employment, housing, educational, and reentry needs of offenders are fulfilled; and</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;the number of probationers and supervised releasees revoked, modified, or reinstated for Grade A, B, and C violations, disaggregated by demographic data and the mean and median sentence length for each demographic category.</p>



<p><u>Sec</u>. 16.&nbsp; Supporting Safe Conditions in Prisons and Jails.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;For the duration of the HHS public health emergency declared with respect to COVID-19, the Attorney General shall continue to implement the core public health measures, as appropriate, of masking, distancing, testing, and vaccination in Federal prisons.&nbsp; In addition, the Attorney General shall undertake, as appropriate, the following actions within 120 days of the date of this order:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; updating Federal Bureau of Prisons (BOP) and United States Marshals Service (USMS) procedures and protocols, in consultation with the Secretary of HHS, as appropriate, to facilitate COVID-19 testing of BOP staff and individuals in BOP custody who are asymptomatic or symptomatic and do not have known, suspected, or reported exposure to SARS-CoV-2, the virus that causes COVID-19;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; updating BOP and USMS procedures and protocols, in consultation with the Secretary of HHS, to identify alternatives consistent with public health recommendations to the use of facility-wide lockdowns to prevent the transmission of SARS-CoV-2, or to the use of restrictive housing for detainees and prisoners who have tested positive for SARS-CoV-2 or have known, suspected, or reported exposure;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; identifying the number of individuals who meet the eligibility requirements under the CARES Act (Public Law 116-136), the First Step Act, 18 U.S.C. 3582(c), 18 U.S.C. 3622, and 18 U.S.C. 3624, for release as part of the DOJ&#8217;s efforts to mitigate the impact and spread of COVID-19; and</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp; expanding the sharing and publication of BOP and USMS data, in consultation with the Secretary of HHS, regarding vaccination, testing, infections, and fatalities due to COVID-19 among staff, prisoners, and detainees, in a manner that ensures the thoroughness and accuracy of the data; protects privacy; and disaggregates the data by race, ethnicity, age, sex, disability, and facility, after consulting with the White House COVID-19 Response Team, HHS, and the Equitable Data Working Group established in Executive Order 13985 of January 20, 2021 (Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government), as appropriate.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall take the following actions relating to other conditions of confinement in Federal detention facilities:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; within 180 days of the date of this order, submit a report to the President detailing steps the DOJ has taken, consistent with applicable law, to ensure that restrictive housing in Federal detention facilities is used rarely, applied fairly, and subject to reasonable constraints; to ensure that individuals in DOJ custody are housed in the least restrictive setting necessary for their safety and the safety of staff, other prisoners and detainees, and the public; to house prisoners as close to their families as practicable; and to ensure the DOJ&#8217;s full implementation, at a minimum, of the Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003 (Public Law 108-79) and the recommendations of the DOJ&#8217;s January 2016 Report and Recommendations Concerning the Use of Restrictive Housing; and</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; within 240 days of the date of this order, complete a comprehensive review and transmit a report to the President identifying any planned steps to address conditions of confinement, including steps designed to improve the accessibility and quality of medical care (including behavioral and mental health care), the specific needs of women (including breast and cervical cancer screening, gynecological and reproductive health care, and prenatal and postpartum care), the specific needs of juveniles (including age-appropriate programming), recovery support services (including substance use disorder treatment and trauma-informed care), and the environmental conditions for all individuals in BOP and USMS custody.</p>



<p>Sec. 17.&nbsp; Advancing First Step Act Implementation.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The Attorney General is reviewing and updating as appropriate DOJ regulations, policies, and guidance in order to fully implement the provisions and intent of the First Step Act, and shall continue to do so consistent with the policy announced in section 1 of this order. &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall, in consultation with the Director of OMB, submit a report to the President summarizing:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the rehabilitative purpose for each First Step Act expenditure and proposal for the prior and current fiscal years, detailing the number of available and proposed dedicated programming staff and resources, the use of augmentation among BOP staff, and BOP staffing levels at each facility;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;any additional funding necessary to fully implement the rehabilitative purpose of the First Step Act, ensure dedicated programming staff for all prisoners, and address staffing shortages in all BOP facilities; and &nbsp;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; the following information on the BOP&#8217;s risk assessment tool, Prisoner Assessment Tool Targeting Estimated Risk and Needs (PATTERN):</p>



<p>(A)&nbsp; the number of individuals released early due to Earned Time Credits who were subsequently convicted and sentenced, as defined by United&nbsp;States Sentencing Guideline sec. 4A1.1(a), in the year following their release, disaggregated by their PATTERN risk level category of &#8220;Minimum,&#8221; &#8220;Low,&#8221; &#8220;Medium,&#8221; or &#8220;High&#8221; at time of release;</p>



<p>(B) &nbsp;an assessment of any disparate impact of PATTERN, including the weighting of static and dynamic risk factors and of the statutorily enumerated offenses and prior convictions that render individuals ineligible to earn time credits; and</p>



<p>(C) &nbsp;a strategic plan and timeline to improve PATTERN, including by addressing any disparities and developing a needs-based assessment system.</p>



<p><u>Sec</u>. <u>18</u>. &nbsp;<u>Collecting Comprehensive Criminal Justice Statistics</u>.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The Attorney General, in consultation with the United States Chief Data Scientist and the United States Chief Statistician, shall review the status of State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs transitioning from the Summary Reporting System to the NIBRS in the FBI&#8217;s Uniform Crime Reporting Program, and shall submit a report to the President within 120 days of the date of this order summarizing the status of that transition for State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs and including recommendations to maximize participation in the NIBRS.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; Within 365 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, through the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics, and the Director of OMB, through the United States Chief Statistician, shall jointly submit a report to the President detailing what, if any, steps the agencies will take:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; to improve their current data collections, such as the National Crime Victimization Survey and the Police-Public Contact Survey Supplement, including how to ensure that such data collections are undertaken and published annually, and that they include victimization surveys that measure law enforcement use of force; serious bodily injury or death that occurs in law enforcement encounters; public trust in law enforcement; and actual or perceived bias by demographic subgroups defined by race, ethnicity, and sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity); and</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; to improve the Law Enforcement Management and Administrative Statistics Survey, with a focus on ensuring that such data collections are undertaken and published regularly and measure law enforcement workforce data, use of force, public trust in law enforcement, and actual or perceived bias.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The Equitable Data Working Group established in Executive Order 13985 shall work with the National Science and Technology Council to create a Working Group on Criminal Justice Statistics (Working Group), which shall be composed of representatives of the Domestic Policy Council and the office of the Counsel to the President, the DOJ, OMB, and OSTP, and which shall, as appropriate, consult with representatives of the Federal Defender Services; civil rights, civil liberties, data privacy, and law enforcement organizations; and criminal justice data scientists.</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 365 days of the date of this order, the Working Group and the Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy shall issue a report to the President that assesses current data collection, use, and data transparency practices with respect to law enforcement activities, including calls for service, searches, stops, frisks, seizures, arrests, complaints, law enforcement demographics, and civil asset forfeiture.</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; Within 365 days of the date of this order, the Working Group shall assess practices and policies governing the acquisition, use, and oversight of advanced surveillance and forensic technologies, including commercial cyber intrusion tools, by Federal, State, Tribal, local, and territorial law enforcement, and shall include in the report referenced in subsection (c)(i) of this section recommendations based on this assessment that promote equitable, transparent, accountable, constitutional, and effective law enforcement practices.</p>



<p>Sec. 19.&nbsp; Establishing Accreditation Standards. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;The Attorney General shall develop and implement methods to promote State, Tribal, local, and territorial LEAs seeking accreditation by an authorized, independent credentialing body, including by determining what discretionary grants shall require that the LEA be accredited or be in the process of obtaining accreditation.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;Within 240 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General shall develop and publish standards for determining whether an entity is an authorized, independent credentialing body, including that the entity requires policies that further the policies in sections 3, 4, and 7 through 10 of this order, and encourages participation in comprehensive collection and use of police misconduct and use-of-force-data, such as through the databases provided for in sections 5 and 6 of this order. &nbsp;In developing such standards, the Attorney General shall also consider the recommendations of the Final Report of the President&#8217;s Task Force on 21st Century Policing issued in May 2015.&nbsp; Pending the development of such standards, the Attorney General shall maintain the current requirements related to accreditation.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The Attorney General, in formulating standards for accrediting bodies, shall consult with professional accreditation organizations, law enforcement organizations, civil rights and community-based organizations, civilian oversight and accountability groups, and other appropriate stakeholders. &nbsp;The Attorney General&#8217;s standards shall ensure that, in order to qualify as an authorized, independent credentialing body, the accrediting entity must conduct independent assessments of an LEA&#8217;s compliance with applicable standards as part of the accreditation process and not rely on the LEA&#8217;s self-certification alone.</p>



<p>Sec. 20.&nbsp; Supporting Safe and Effective Policing Through Grantmaking. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the Attorney General, the Secretary of HHS, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall promptly review and exercise their authority, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to award Federal discretionary grants in a manner that supports and promotes the adoption of policies of this order by State, Tribal, local, and territorial governments and LEAs. &nbsp;The Attorney General, the Secretary of HHS, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall also use other incentives outside of grantmaking, such as training and technical assistance, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, to support State, Tribal, local, and territorial governments and LEAs in adopting the policies in this order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;On September 15, 2021, the Associate Attorney General directed a review of the DOJ&#8217;s implementation and administrative enforcement of Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, 42&nbsp;U.S.C. 200d <em>et seq</em>., and of the nondiscrimination provisions of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, 34&nbsp;U.S.C. 10228, in connection with Federal financial assistance the DOJ provides, to ensure that the DOJ is providing sufficient oversight and accountability regarding the activities of its federally funded recipients.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;Within 30 days of the date of this order, and consistent with any other applicable guidance issued by the Attorney General, the head of every other Federal agency that provides grants to State, local, and territorial LEAs shall commence a similar review of its law enforcement-related grantmaking operations and the activities of its grant recipients.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;Within 180 days of the date of this order, the head of each Federal agency that provides grants to State, local, and territorial LEAs shall submit to the Assistant Attorney General for the Civil Rights Division of the DOJ, for review under Executive Order&nbsp;12250 of November 2, 1980 (Leadership and Coordination of Nondiscrimination Laws), a report of its review conducted pursuant to subsection (b)(i) of this section, including its conclusions and recommendations.&nbsp; Within 30 days following such review and clearance from the DOJ pursuant to this subsection, the head of each such agency shall make the conclusions of its review publicly available, as appropriate.</p>



<p>Sec. 21.&nbsp; Definitions.&nbsp; For the purposes of this order:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;&#8220;Federal law enforcement agency&#8221; or &#8220;Federal LEA&#8221; means an organizational unit or subunit of the executive branch that employs officers who are authorized to make arrests and carry firearms, and that is responsible for the prevention, detection, and investigation of crime or the apprehension of alleged offenders. &nbsp;The &#8220;heads of all Federal law enforcement agencies&#8221; means the leaders of those units or subunits.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The term &#8220;sustained complaints or records of disciplinary action&#8221; means an allegation of misconduct that is sustained through a completed official proceeding, such as an internal affairs or department disciplinary process.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;The term &#8220;serious misconduct&#8221; means excessive force, bias, discrimination, obstruction of justice, false reports, false statements under oath, theft, or sexual misconduct.</p>



<p>Sec. 22. &nbsp;Superseding Prior Orders.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Executive Order&nbsp;13809 of August 28, 2017 (Restoring State, Tribal, and Local Law Enforcement&#8217;s Access to Life-Saving Equipment and Resources), is revoked.&nbsp; All agencies are directed, consistent with applicable law, to take prompt action to rescind any rules, regulations, guidelines, or policies implementing Executive&nbsp;Order 13809 that are inconsistent with the provisions of this order.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;Executive Order 13929 of June 16, 2020 (Safe Policing for Safe Communities), is revoked.&nbsp; All agencies are directed, consistent with applicable law, to take prompt action to rescind any rules, regulations, guidelines, or policies implementing Executive Order 13929 that are inconsistent with the provisions of this order.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;To the extent that there are other executive orders that may conflict with or overlap with the provisions in this order, the provisions of this order supersede any prior Executive Order on these subjects.</p>



<p>Sec. 23.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c) &nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                                                                   JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May 25, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by the Press Secretary on Steve Dettelbach’s Confirmation&#160;Hearing</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/25/statement-by-the-press-secretary-on-steve-dettelbachs-confirmation-hearing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 21:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Steve Dettelbach demonstrated today exactly why he has received strong bipartisan support from leading law enforcement groups, mayors, and top former federal prosecutors – and why the Senate should move quickly to confirm him to lead the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives. Dettelbach is a career prosecutor who won unanimous support the last time he was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Steve Dettelbach demonstrated today exactly why he has received strong bipartisan support from leading law enforcement groups, mayors, and top former federal prosecutors – and why the Senate should move quickly to confirm him to lead the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives.</p>



<p>Dettelbach is a career prosecutor who won unanimous support the last time he was before the Senate, and who has spent decades working hand-in-hand with law enforcement – including ATF agents – to prosecute complex cases, take down gangs, and successfully charge hate crimes. He understands the vital importance of redoubling ATF’s work to fight gun violence and domestic terrorism, and he understands deeply, as he said today, that “politics can play no role in law enforcement.”</p>



<p>After being vacant for seven years, it’s never been more important to have a tough, experienced, leader like Steve Dettelbach at the helm of ATF to support the agents risking their lives on the front lines every day to protectthe American people. And as we saw with the tragic shootings in Uvalde and Buffalo – where ATF agents have played a key role in the investigations – and with daily gun violence plaguing too many of our communities, now is the time to provide ATF the leadership it needs to redouble its work to enforce our gun laws and make our communities safer.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to&#160;the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/25/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-69/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 21:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54178</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Rachel Bloomekatz, of Ohio, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Sixth Circuit, vice R. Guy Cole, Jr., retiring. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Thomas E. Brown, of Georgia, to be United States Marshal for the Northern District of Georgia for the term of four years, vice Michael S. Yeager. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Brian&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rachel Bloomekatz, of Ohio, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Sixth Circuit, vice R. Guy Cole, Jr., retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thomas E. Brown, of Georgia, to be United States Marshal for the Northern District of Georgia for the term of four years, vice Michael S. Yeager.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Brian A. Kyes, of Massachusetts, to be United States Marshal for the District of Massachusetts for the term of four years, vice John Gibbons, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stephen D. Lynn, of Georgia, to be United States Marshal for the Middle District of Georgia for the term of four years, vice John Cary Bittick, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Roy W. Minter, Jr., of Georgia, to be United States Marshal for the Southern District of Georgia for the term of four years, vice David L. Lyons, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Florence Y. Pan, of the District of Columbia, to be United States Circuit Judge for the District of Columbia Circuit, vice Ketanji Brown Jackson, elevated.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Doris L. Pryor, of Indiana, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Seventh Circuit, vice David F. Hamilton, retiring.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
