<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:27:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION&#160;SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Thea D. Rozman Kendler, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce, vice Richard Ashooh. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION&nbsp;SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Thea D. Rozman Kendler, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce, vice Richard Ashooh.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Q2 GDP&#160;Data</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-q2-gdp-data/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 16:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s GDP data are further proof of the remarkable progress we’ve made in jump-starting our economy from one of the darkest moments in its history. With today’s numbers, the U.S. economy has now made up the losses of the last 18 months and surpassed the pre-pandemic GDP peak. In doing so, we’ve grown our economy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s GDP data are further proof of the remarkable progress we’ve made in jump-starting our economy from one of the darkest moments in its history. With today’s numbers, the U.S. economy has now made up the losses of the last 18 months and surpassed the pre-pandemic GDP peak. In doing so, we’ve grown our economy the first half of this year at the fastest rate in almost four decades, created three million new jobs, and halved new jobless claims.<br><br>Simply put, because of President Biden’s leadership, America is on the move again. This isn’t an accident: It’s the result of a successful campaign against the virus and an economic policy that has been focused squarely on getting help to the working and middle-class Americans who need it the most – ensuring that we’re rebuilding our economy in a way that puts them first. This wasn’t preordained – in fact, In fact, just one year ago, CBO predicted real GDP would be 3% below its pre-pandemic peak at this time. But, thanks to shots in arms and checks in pockets, we’ve been able to far outstrip that and power a recovery twice as fast as after the last recession.<br><br>That’s the story of this President’s economic plan: taking us from the worst time for our economy in history to one of the best. And we’re seeing signs of that across the economy. More than 600,000 jobs created each month since the President took office, the fastest pace for a new Administration in history. New unemployment claims slashed in half. Independent forecasts of economic growth doubled for 2021.<br><br>We still have work to do to build our economy back better, and we can’t be complacent when too many Americans are still facing the squeeze of economic uncertainty. That’s why the President and his team are going to continue focusing squarely on curbing this virus and getting our communities the economic support they need to thrive. And it’s why the President has put forward a historic, and bipartisan, plan to rebuild our infrastructure and invest in our global competitiveness which cleared an important hurdle last night. And it’s why he’s working with Democrats to deliver on additional support for our middle class that will create a fairer, more sustainable, and stronger economy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Eviction Prevention&#160;Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-biden-harris-administration-eviction-prevention-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For nearly 11 months, the CDC’s eviction moratorium has served as a critical backstop to prevent hard-pressed renters and their families who lost jobs or income due to the COVID-19 pandemic from being evicted for nonpayment of rent. &#160;This moratorium prevented hundreds of thousands of Americans from experiencing the heartbreak, homelessness, and health risks that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For nearly 11 months, the CDC’s eviction moratorium has served as a critical backstop to prevent hard-pressed renters and their families who lost jobs or income due to the COVID-19 pandemic from being evicted for nonpayment of rent. &nbsp;This moratorium prevented hundreds of thousands of Americans from experiencing the heartbreak, homelessness, and health risks that too often emanate from evictions –particularly during a pandemic. The Administration considered it a prudent public health decision when the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) extended the eviction moratorium until July 31<sup>st</sup>.</p>



<p>Given the recent spread of the Delta variant, including among those Americans both most likely to face evictions and lacking vaccinations, President Biden would have strongly supported a decision by the CDC to further extend this eviction moratorium to protect renters at this moment of heightened vulnerability. Unfortunately, the Supreme Court has made clear that this option is no longer available.&nbsp; In June, when CDC extended the eviction moratorium until July 31<sup>st</sup>, the Supreme Court’s ruling stated that “clear and specific congressional authorization (via new legislation) would be necessary for the CDC to extend the moratorium past July 31.”</p>



<p>In light of the Supreme Court’s ruling, the President calls on Congress to extend the eviction moratorium to protect such vulnerable renters and their families without delay. In addition, he has asked the U.S. Departments of Housing and Urban Development, Agriculture, and Veterans Affairs to extend their respective eviction moratoria through the end of September, which will provide continued protection for households living in federally-insured, single-family properties. The President has also asked these and other departments to do everything in their power so that owners and operators of federally-assisted and financed rental housing seek Emergency Rental Assistance to make themselves whole while keeping families in secure and safe housing – before moving toward eviction.</p>



<p>Finally, the President urges states and localities, which long ago received Emergency Rental Assistance – including through the American Rescue Plan – to urgently accelerate their efforts to disburse these funds given the imminent ending of the CDC eviction moratorium. With some cities and states demonstrating their ability to release these funds efficiently to tenants and landlords in need, there can be no excuse for any state or locality not to promptly deploy the resources that Congress appropriated to meet this critical need of so many Americans.</p>



<p>The Administration remains committed to doing everything in its power to keep people safely and securely housed, which is essential to the health, well-being and dignity of all of us.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Immigration&#160;Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/29/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-biden-harris-administration-immigration-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (July 28, 2021) 4:01 P.M. EDT SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Thank you so much, Josh.&#160; Hello, everyone, and welcome.&#160; On behalf of the NSC, I’d like to welcome you to this call on migration strategy. I&#8217;m going to introduce our speakers in a second, but I just want to go over the ground rules.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(July 28, 2021)</p>



<p>4:01 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Josh.&nbsp; Hello, everyone, and welcome.&nbsp; On behalf of the NSC, I’d like to welcome you to this call on migration strategy.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to introduce our speakers in a second, but I just want to go over the ground rules.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s call and the content, as well as the factsheets that we&#8217;ll send out to you later, are on background and embargoed until tomorrow morning at 6:00 a.m. or released by the White House.</p>



<p>For your reference, our speakers today are [senior administration officials].&nbsp; As a reminder, again, our speakers today are going to be referred to as &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;</p>



<p>And with that, I will turn it over to our first senior administration official.&nbsp; Over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Hi, everyone, and good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, we released a factsheet on the Biden administration&#8217;s blueprint for a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system.&nbsp; This administration launched a whole-of-government effort in January to responsibly manage the border and put in place immigration systems that align with our values.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President also sent a bill to Congress that includes a path to citizenship, a proposal to manage the border and address the root causes of migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the blueprint yesterday includes four strategies: One, a humane and well-managed border.  This includes strategic use of the $15 billion a year that <s>CBC</s> [CBP] receives and implementing expedited removal for families who do not express fear of return to their home country. </p>



<p>It includes orderly and fair processing of asylum seekers.&nbsp; This includes allowing asylum officers to adjudicate asylum claims and a dedicated asylum docket.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, what you&#8217;ll hear about today is collaborative migration management with regional partners and addressing the root causes of migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, success in building a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system won&#8217;t come overnight, but we do have a blueprint to get us there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for being on the call.&nbsp; Really appreciate this opportunity to chat.</p>



<p>I want to begin by underscoring a couple of things that [senior administration official] mentioned.&nbsp; You know, when Joe Biden and Kamala Harris came into office on January 20th, they really inherited a broken and dysfunctional system.&nbsp; And you all know the history there, but there were a number of problems that pre-existed the Trump administration, but the Trump administration made them so much worse.&nbsp; And many of the things that we&#8217;re trying to deal with now have been exacerbated by the decisions that were taken then.</p>



<p>Four months ago, in March, when President Biden asked Vice President Harris to take on the root causes &#8212; for her to look at what are the drivers of migration in Central America, and how can we execute diplomacy with these countries, develop assistance with these countries that will get at those primary factors that are causing people to leave their home, and how can we pair that up in an integrated approach, as [senior administration official] has just mentioned, with the other aspects of our approach to migration.</p>



<p>And it really is an integrated approach.&nbsp; You have to work on all aspects of this strategy if we&#8217;re going to be successful over the long term.&nbsp; So, all of them are important.</p>



<p>The root causes piece that the Vice President is working on, in some respects, is the long pole in the tent.&nbsp; It certainly is going to be the longest-term effort, and it is one that needs to work on multiple levels simultaneously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The very first thing that the Vice President did when she took on this account was to deal with the very extreme humanitarian needs in the region.&nbsp; As you all know, there have been devastating hurricanes, COVID, the economic slump that had resulted in destroyed infrastructure, homelessness, food insecurity.</p>



<p>The Vice President put together a package of over $300 million of immediate humanitarian relief.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already disbursed $250 million of that and have brought a lot of really essential relief to people throughout the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time that she was taking that initial action on humanitarian relief, she also worked to lay the framework for extensive engagement. She worked intensively with the Cabinet, Congress, policy experts, civil society, philanthropic foundations, and foreign partners in both the region and around the world.</p>



<p>A couple of things that she produced that I want to highlight for you &#8212; and happy to come back in detail &#8212; but first, the United Nations is going to issue a humanitarian response plan in September.&nbsp; This is a direct result of the work that she and her team have done to &#8212; with all of the U.N. agencies, as well as the U.N. member states.</p>



<p>Second, the Vice President did extensive outreach with our international partners to highlight the needs of this region and to encourage responsible friends and allies to come forward.&nbsp; Many of them have &#8212; to include Japan, South Korea and Israel &#8212; to increase their aid, increase their engagement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe the Japanese foreign minister is in Central America today as we speak.&nbsp; And there are a number of other countries, both within this hemisphere and around the world, who have said that they are eager to help, recognizing the need there.</p>



<p>Third, the Vice President issued a call to action to the private sector, getting some of our most prominent corporations to commit to make investments and also to provide philanthropic support into the region.&nbsp; There was an initial sort of steering group of 12 major corporations.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had over 150 businesses express interest in participating in this very targeted program from private-sector businesses, and we&#8217;re very excited about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She also, as you know, engaged with the region itself, with the leaders in the region.&nbsp; She traveled to Mexico and Guatemala &#8212; as well as visited El Paso &#8212; and issued a number of really important initiatives there on anti-trafficking and anti-smuggling; also talked about a number of &#8212; launched a number of important assistance programs; and delivered very clear messages to the leaders of those governments about what our priorities were and what our expectations were.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m happy to come back to that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, finally, a very important accomplishment of the Vice President is the strategy that we&#8217;re rolling out now.&nbsp; And I will turn it over to my colleague here to talk about the strategy.&nbsp; But just want to note that for this strategy to be successful, we will have to undertake sustained effort, which is both hard work over time, but also a very hardnosed approach to having an impact on the ground for the people of the region who are suffering so badly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, let me turn it over to [senior administration official], who has been working on these issues for many years.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; On the front end, I want to mention, as somebody who worked on this when Vice &#8212; when Vice President Biden was working on it during the Obama-Biden administration, and has had the privilege to also work with the Vice President and her team on this, I want to kind of underscore here that what we&#8217;re talking about here is much more than U.S. assistance package.&nbsp; As [senior administration official] highlighted, we&#8217;re looking at actually building a broader coalition that includes not just the U.S. government and its support, but members of the private sector, the foundations, the international community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in the process of the Vice President&#8217;s leadership and the development of the plan, we did a very thorough study of then-Vice President Biden&#8217;s efforts &#8212; what succeeded, so we could build on it; what areas we needed to actually innovate on and build upon.&nbsp; And that really has informed the development, not just of this strategy, but the Vice President&#8217;s engagement, and as [senior administration official] mentioned, the entire blueprint approach that includes migration.</p>



<p>So I&#8217;ll just go really quickly through the five pillars of the strategy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The first is economic insecurity and inequality.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll run through them quickly and can answer any questions.&nbsp; So the United States is working to promote a strong investment climate in these countries.&nbsp; We want to create jobs so that people want to stay home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The rule of law, transparency, an independent and fair judiciary combating corruption &#8212; all of these elements are strong and vital to that (inaudible) climate.&nbsp; And as the Vice President made clear, economic growth should really be inclusive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A point is &#8212; the point here is that we&#8217;re working with local communities to deepen resilience to the extreme weather events that will only become more common due to climate change, including innovations in climate-smart agricultural practices, all that will be necessary to support economic security.</p>



<p>Pillar number two is combating corruption, strengthening democratic governance, and advancing the rule of law.&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll just say that corruption corrodes the public trust, and as you all saw, there was a (inaudible) administration &#8212; administration-wide national security memorandum where combating corruption is really going to be central to everything that we do, not just in Central America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number three is promoting respect for human rights, labor rights, and a free press.&nbsp; The President and Vice President, I mentioned, were the most &#8212; it&#8217;s going to be the most pro-union administration in modern history.&nbsp; And labor rights is actually something that promotes economic prosperity in these countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our work not just with governments, but I think underscoring our work with civil society is really central to all of this.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s important not to leave out, really, the importance of women and girls, as the Vice President highlighted during her visit to Guatemala, indigenous persons, Afro-descendants, LGBTQI+ persons, and persons with disabilities to make sure that we&#8217;re engaging with all members of society.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number four is countering and preventing violence, extortion, and other crimes perpetrated by criminal gangs, trafficking networks, and other organized criminal organizations.&nbsp; It&#8217;s pretty straightforward, and I would just point out that that&#8217;s why the Vice President launched an anti-smuggling task force in both Mexico and Guatemala, and secured commitments to increase border enforcement in these countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last but not least, combating sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence.&nbsp; Across the region, sexual and gender-based violence significantly hinders the ability of women and girls to participate fully in society and contribute to their families and communities.&nbsp; We know that femicide is something that is rampant in many countries in Central America and that the future prosperity of the region is really one that is invested in the success of women and girls.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s something that has been central to the Vice President&#8217;s approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Women and youth from marginalized communities often face higher levels of violence, especially LGBTQI+ women and girls.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to work with partner governments, civil society organizations, and others to combat violence in the region and to provide protection and services to those who suffer such violence.</p>



<p>So, I’ll turn it over to my colleague.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Great to have a chance to speak with you all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m going to be talking to you about the Collaborative Migration Management Strategy, which is the first of its kind and a companion to the root causes strategy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really premised on this idea that as we&#8217;re seeking to improve the conditions on the ground in Central America and build hope under the leadership of the Vice President, we understand that people will &#8212; there will continue to be a demand to migrate.&nbsp; And so, the CMMS addresses this head on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re not seeking to end migration as part of the fabric of this region.&nbsp; We have so many familial, cultural ties in Central America.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re seeking to change the ways in which people migrate, to provide an alternative to the criminal smuggling and trafficking rings, and to give people access to opportunity and protection through safe legal channels, safe legal pathways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know that people are leaving the north of Central America for a wide variety of reasons, including seeking employment, seeking access to protection for people that are fleeing a lot of the underlying &#8212; the root causes that [senior administration official] mentioned, and then to reunite with family.</p>



<p>So, the goal is to match these legal pathways with these drivers &#8212; these various, distinct drivers of migration.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve been doing a lot of work, a lot of consultation with the people in the region, with civil society actors on the ground, with the governments, trying to deeply understand why people are making the choice to migrate and how can we make sure that we are addressing them in our strategy &#8212; our Collaborative Migration Management Strategy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s a centerpiece of the CMMS that &#8212; is, you know, very ambitiously expanding access to legal pathways, both to the United States and to various other countries.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing a lot of work already to try to bring other countries to the table to multiply the number of legal pathways &#8212; countries like Canada, Costa Rica, Spain, and elsewhere.&nbsp; There&#8217;s actually a lot of momentum on that front, and it&#8217;s very encouraging.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These legal pathways are diverse, as I mentioned.&nbsp; It includes labor pathways; it includes expanding traditional resettlements and other protections pathways.&nbsp; It includes family reunification programs like the Central American Minors Program.&nbsp; That’s just the beginning of that kind of work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then legal pathways is just one piece of the CMMS.&nbsp; I won&#8217;t go through all of them, but you&#8217;ll see them tomorrow when we roll out the plan.&nbsp; There are eight lines of action in total.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, just a few other highlights: You know, we&#8217;re looking to build on a lot of the work that&#8217;s already being done to strengthen asylum throughout the region in countries like Mexico and, again, Costa Rica so that, you know, people have various options where they can access international protection.&nbsp; Also, to strengthen protection mechanisms inside countries of origin for internally displaced persons, IDPs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re looking to connect it to our legal pathways work to stand up migration resource centers &#8212; basically, physical structures where people can go to access this information and to be referred for legal pathways and other services in their countries.&nbsp; And then, we are &#8212; you know, the strategy calls for working with our partner governments in the region to foster secure management of borders and to strengthen regional public messaging on migration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we’re really excited.&nbsp; And again, just to note, this is the first of its kind, and I think we really believe that with the combination of ambitious root causes and migration management strategy that we really and truly have an impact in this region.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We can open it up for questions.&nbsp; As a reminder to our participants, this call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The call contents are embargoed until 6:00 a.m. tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thank you so much.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; A few questions.&nbsp; For [senior administration official], I was hoping you could answer, like, be a little more specific: How much of the $15 billion that was, I guess, for the wall will be redirected?&nbsp; What kind of things will it be redirected for?&nbsp; Are we talking drones, cameras?&nbsp; Does border agents come into that?</p>



<p>I was also hoping you could give an update on ending Title 42 and how will that &#8212; if and when it&#8217;ll be ended, how will it be ended?&nbsp; Will it be done by a phased approach?</p>



<p>And for [senior administration official], I was hoping you could talk a little bit about updates on how we&#8217;ll be supporting prosecutorial efforts in Central America?  Would independent judges and prosecutors &#8212; is this &#8212; are there going to be something like trying to revive something like CICIG?  If you could talk about that as well.  Thank you so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp; I can start.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce on Title 42.&nbsp; As we’ve said in the past, it&#8217;s a public health authority, and that authority rests with the CDC, and so we&#8217;ll continue to defer to them on those decisions.</p>



<p>On the border, the President&#8217;s FY22 budget request, I think, allocated a little over a billion dollars for technology and for ports of entry.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have a number for you in terms of redirection of wall money.&nbsp; I can pull it for you afterwards.&nbsp; But we are prioritizing, as I said, technology and ports of entry.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Great.  Hey, Franco.  Great to hear from you.  Look, you saw the announcement when the Vice President traveled to Guatemala on an anti-corruption task force so &#8212; and you’ll see that actually delivers on a campaign commitment made by the President during the campaign.  The rationale behind that is that organizations like CICIG took years to stand up, and we needed to act very quickly to do a couple things.</p>



<p>Number one, is, there are things that the United States can do in terms of investigations and prosecutions.&nbsp; You know we have officials that (inaudible) to pull visas, and we have the end goal list, which you&#8217;ve seen a lot on.&nbsp; And &#8212; but it also includes working with those judges and prosecutors that are ones that we see are having an active commitment to combatting anti-corruption efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Others are &#8212; as you may have seen after the firing of Mr. Sandoval, the chief of FECI in Guatemala, that we have decided to suspend some assistance to the office of the Prosecutor General.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing some of those programs that we see are advancing these anti-corruption efforts, but others we are freezing.&nbsp; So, those are a whole host of tools on the anti-corruption side.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, I got to underscore here this is something that the Vice President has really made central is that our engagement with the private sector is also an anti-corruption initiative.&nbsp; Because what we&#8217;re trying to do is introduce new private-sector actors who are advocating for creating a transparent and business-friendly environment for investment, and that&#8217;s something that I think provides, like, a profit-proposition to anti-corruption efforts.</p>



<p>So, a lot of this is multifaceted, it’s individual, it’s working with governments, but also trying to go out of government-to-government channel by getting civil society and in the private sector involved.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I have two quick questions.&nbsp; The first one to anyone who can respond.&nbsp; You were talking about the management of the borders.&nbsp; In the case of Mexico, the President Andrés Manuel López Obrador has just announced that he&#8217;s planning to integrate the National Guard under the conduction of the Secretary of Defense of Mexico.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are several reports about human rights abuses of the immigrants by the National Guard of Mexico and also by the members of the Mexican army.&nbsp; Is the Biden administration worried about this change in terms of the National Guard of Mexico guarding the border &#8212; the south border of Mexico and the northern border of Mexico, trying to control the immigration flow, if there&#8217;s will be any complaints about the human rights situation?</p>



<p>And the second question is for [senior administration official].&nbsp; In terms of the increase that were reported by the DHS about the arrest of illegal immigrants in the southern border of the United States, the numbers of Mexicans are going up.&nbsp; The government Mexico says &#8212; said recently that the economy of Mexico is better off than years &#8212; years before.&nbsp; Why do you guys see the reason that Mexicans are trying to cross illegally the northern border of Mexico to be in the United States if Mexico has a better economy now?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll take your first question there regarding Mexico border management.&nbsp; Just to note from the CMMS, you know, our pillar on that is, &#8220;to foster secure and humane management of borders.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, I think we recognize the need to work with governments throughout the region in managing migration and addressing, you know, these irregular movements.&nbsp; But we certainly want to do that in a way that&#8217;s humane and upholds the dignity and the human rights of those who are making the journey.</p>



<p>And so, you know, that includes, for instance, in Mexico, ensuring that people that would be interdicted by the National Guard &#8212; you know, under Mexican law, that they would (inaudible) and have access to asylum in Mexico, through COMAR, their refugee commission.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, when we talk to Mexico and we discuss migration management, we also talked about the importance of access to asylum and protection.&nbsp; So just to note that we view this as some &#8212; the importance of that balance between enforcement and protection.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a &#8212; it is written, explicitly, in our strategy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And, Jesús, hola.&nbsp; Good to &#8212; good to hear from you.&nbsp; So, there are a number of reasons why people choose to leave their homes &#8212; not just Mexico, but Central America and even increasing numbers of migrants from Venezuelan, Haitian, and Cuban origin.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing one of those elements is, of course, that we&#8217;ve all been through a pandemic for the last year-plus, and we&#8217;re still in there.&nbsp; And that there&#8217;s been a pent-up migration demand that we are starting to see.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, frankly, that is one of the reasons why this administration is sharing &#8212; right now, I don&#8217;t have the exact count &#8212; but over 40 million vaccines with the countries of the region to try to be as responsive to a region that has been very hard hit by the impact of the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The other &#8212; just on the &#8212; you know, and I can&#8217;t speak to what President López Obrador&#8217;s characterization of Mexican economy, but I&#8217;ll say that it&#8217;s in our interest for Mexico to prosper.&nbsp; And that, you know, the United States prospers when Mexico prospers and the other way around.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, right now, assessments indicate that the U.S. economy is going to grow at 6.9 percent, at least.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that&#8217;s going to have incredible economic benefits for Mexico.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, GDP growth is one way to measure economic prosperity; inequality and economic opportunity is another one.&nbsp; And those are the conversations that the Vice President is really &#8212; in her meeting with President López Obrador, they talked about not just the trade relationship, but how to make sure that we&#8217;re investing in communities that &#8212; to ensure that we&#8217;re tackling together inequality, investing in Central America, and addressing the root causes of migration through various tools, including economic opportunity.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; My first question is for [senior administration official].&nbsp; (Inaudible) economic insecurity and inequality, can you provide a concrete example of how exactly you plan on addressing that?&nbsp; For example, are you thinking about cash-based transfers?</p>



<p>And then a question for [senior administration official]: In terms of the strategy that you mentioned, how much of that is based on enforcement south of our border?&nbsp; Are you sending more DHS personnel?&nbsp; And how do you anticipate addressing those migrants who have to leave the region, urgently?&nbsp; For example, as you know with asylum seekers, they sometimes have to leave within a 24-hour window, if less.&nbsp; So how does this strategy address those migrants?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, Priscilla, great to hear from you.&nbsp; We can get you specific programs, but I think when we&#8217;re trying to address issues of inequality and economic opportunity, it&#8217;s the whole package.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s not just working on, you know, for example, investing in opportunity for women and girls by promoting entrepreneurship.&nbsp; Others are, obviously, tackling corruption in these countries and engaging with civil society so that we&#8217;re trying to level the playing field so that prosperity is determined not &#8212; not by where you&#8217;re born, but rather your &#8212; your work ethic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so there are a series of programs that we’re undertaking, but it&#8217;s more than just U.S. assistance.&nbsp; It’s making sure that we&#8217;re working closely with the private sector.&nbsp; We&#8217;re actually working with foundations to have a coordinated approach to how we tackle some of these issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But also, frankly, the &#8212; separate from foreign assistance, because no amount of foreign assistance is going to make a difference if these governments actually aren&#8217;t demonstrating political will &#8212; is making some very, sometimes, asks of these governments that may go against their own political interests on matters of corruption, on specific legislation, and a series of things that we&#8217;ve engaged on with all these governments and that are, I think, for us, part of the arrangement that if we&#8217;re going to make an argument for the U.S. taxpayer to support something like this, that the countries of the region are not just contributing their share, but also taking stepping up and advancing necessary reforms. &nbsp;</p>



<p>On the Haiti question, I&#8217;m going to ask my colleague to address just those migrants with an urgent need.&nbsp; So, right now, the &#8212; and you saw that the Special Envoy Dan Foote was announced last week.&nbsp; We went to Haiti a second time for the funeral of Moïse.&nbsp; Our focus is &#8212; is in a couple areas.</p>



<p>Number one is everything we can do to support the investigation.&nbsp; And so, we have, right now, these eight agents, including FBI, DHS, that are doing everything from tracing the weapons, cellphones, and the equipment of those individuals involved in the attack &#8212; in assassination of President Moïse.</p>



<p>And the second one is: What can we do to support Haitians and the Haitian National Police &#8212; their security needs?&nbsp; So, we have a list of requests that they&#8217;ve made.&nbsp; And Special Envoy Foote has &#8212; in the course of the meeting, they just came back &#8212; has been trying to figure out, in terms of the asks and actually needs assessment, what &#8212; you know, what we can actually do to be most responsive so that we&#8217;re supporting Haitian solutions to Haitian challenges, as opposed to, you know, coming as the United States and being prescriptive.</p>



<p>And so that includes the Department of Homeland Security, Homeland Security Investigations.&nbsp; We have the FBI, DEA, (inaudible) DOJ.&nbsp; But also, USAID is very actively engaged.&nbsp; We have a program with the World Food Program and doing an assessment of what more we can actually do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last point on this is that we have &#8212; we are working to expand U.S. aid of $6 million that they&#8217;re investing to expand our vaccination sites from 3 to 10.&nbsp; Right now, we&#8217;re in almost every different department in Haiti, and we&#8217;re working very actively to finalize the distribution of the 500,000 Moderna vaccines.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also looking to see what more we can do to support &#8212; combat the pandemic in Haiti.</p>



<p>And so that, for us, is a kind of broad strategy, and the focus here is also to promote a broad and inclusive dialogue that includes civil society, as we&#8217;re trying to do everything we can to support the Haitian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: &nbsp;Thank you so much.&nbsp; On your question on how do we address people with urgent needs that needs to need access to protection right away, I think you hit on one of the biggest challenges with this.&nbsp; You know, with traditional resettlement, we know that it can often take a few years.&nbsp; And with Central America, frankly, there haven&#8217;t even been enough resettlement slots.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re looking to not only expand the number of refugee admissions to the United States and to other countries, but look at ways in which we can address, sort of, you know, chokepoints in the resettlement process and ways that we can &#8212; you know, while upholding the integrity and the security elements of the program, you know, that we can &#8212; that we can make sure that we&#8217;re able to process people more quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, there&#8217;s the Protection Transfer Arrangement in Costa Rica that is a way that people can be evacuated quickly &#8212; how can we expand that.&nbsp; And then, that&#8217;s, I think, where other countries that neighbor Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador really come in.&nbsp; We can &#8212; if we can expand complementary forms of protection to neighboring countries, I think that also can create an important &#8212; an important way that people can get somewhere safe quickly.&nbsp; So looking at temporary protection &#8212; you know, temporary protection programs that might be possible in Mexico or, you know, other countries in the neighborhood.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we hear you on that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s, I think, a really &#8212; a big challenge, but something that we&#8217;re seeking to try to address wholeheartedly through this strategy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Unfortunately, we&#8217;re out of time, but, again, we want to thank our participants and our speakers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, the ground rules: This call is on background and the contents of the call as well as the factsheet that we&#8217;ll send out later tonight is embargoed until 6:00 a.m. tomorrow or White House release.&nbsp; Our speakers will be referred to as “senior administration officials” for the purpose of the call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you have any additional questions, feel free to email me or email the NSC Press distro at <a href="mailto:DL.NSC.Press@nsc.eop.gov">DL.NSC.Press@nsc.eop.gov</a>.</p>



<p>Thank you all so much.&nbsp; Have a good day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:33 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration in Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-strategy-to-address-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 2, 2021, President Biden signed an Executive Order that called for the development of a Root Causes Strategy. Since March, Vice President Kamala Harris has been leading the Administration’s diplomatic efforts to address the root causes of migration from El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras. &#160;She has worked with bilateral, multilateral, and private sector&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On February 2, 2021, President Biden signed an Executive Order that called for the development of a Root Causes Strategy.<br><br>Since March, Vice President Kamala Harris has been leading the Administration’s diplomatic efforts to address the root causes of migration from El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras. &nbsp;She has worked with bilateral, multilateral, and private sector partners, as well as civil society leaders, to help people from the region find hope at home. &nbsp;This complements work done throughout the U.S. government over the last six months to learn lessons from prior efforts and to consult with a wide range of stakeholders to inform the development of this strategy.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is releasing the Root Causes Strategy—a core component of our Administration’s efforts to establish a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system. &nbsp;This Strategy identifies, prioritizes, and coordinates actions to improve security, governance, human rights, and economic conditions in the region.&nbsp; It integrates various U.S. government tools, including diplomacy, foreign assistance, public diplomacy, and sanctions. &nbsp;<br><br>Implementation of the Strategy will rely on the expertise of a wide range of U.S. departments and agencies, with support from governments in and&nbsp;outside&nbsp;the region, civil society, the private sector, multilateral organizations, international financial institutions, and the U.S. Congress.&nbsp; These partnerships will bolster the impact of the Strategy through informing programmatic interventions, leveraging political will, and mobilizing necessary resources. The U.S. government will coordinate a place-based approach, targeting those areas where migrants are most likely to come from.<br><br>The Strategy is organized into five pillars:</p>



<ul><li>Pillar I:&nbsp; Addressing economic insecurity and inequality;</li><li>Pillar II:&nbsp; Combating corruption, strengthening democratic governance, and advancing the rule of law;</li><li>Pillar III:&nbsp; Promoting respect for human rights, labor rights, and free press;</li><li>Pillar IV:&nbsp; Countering and preventing violence, extortion, and other crimes perpetrated by criminal gangs, trafficking networks, and other organized criminal organizations; and</li><li>Pillar V:&nbsp; Combating sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence. &nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>The Vice President and the Administration have already taken action – notable accomplishments include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Addressing immediate humanitarian needs including vaccines.&nbsp; </strong>On April 26, Vice President Harris announced $310 million in urgent relief to help address the acute factors of migration, including from hurricanes, the pandemic, and drought caused by climate change. &nbsp;To date, we have allocated over $250 million of the total funds, reaching over two million people. &nbsp;We also provided over 10 million COVID vaccine doses to El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.<br></li><li><strong>Countering corruption and democratic backsliding.</strong> &nbsp;Vice President Harris has been direct and unwavering in highlighting the problems of corruption, the need for reforms, and the vital importance of demonstrating commitment to the rule of law, judicial independence, human rights, and a strong civil society—including during her bilateral meeting in Guatemala. &nbsp;Working with the Department of Justice, the Vice President launched an Anticorruption Task Force that will include U.S. prosecutors and law enforcement experts to investigate and prosecute corruption cases with a nexus in the United States and the region.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Addressing security concerns of mutual interest.</strong> &nbsp;Vice President Harris launched Anti-Migrant Smuggling Task Forces in both Mexico and Guatemala and secured commitments to increase border enforcement. &nbsp;She reached an agreement with the Mexican government to restart the high-level dialogue focused on the trafficking of weapons and drugs.<br></li><li><strong>Internationalizing our efforts. &nbsp;</strong>The Vice President has said, “The United States cannot do this work alone.” &nbsp;She has reached out to international partners to highlight the need for increased support for Central America and secured commitments from a number of countries. &nbsp;She successfully encouraged the United Nations to develop a regional Humanitarian Response Plan to mobilize international donor support for the region.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Working with the private sector.&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>On May 27, Vice President Harris launched a&nbsp;<em>Call to Action</em>&nbsp;for the private sector to make new commitments in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to expand economic opportunities.&nbsp; The initial group of 12 companies and organizations committed to helping over 13 million people, offered to provide $750 million in resources, and established a non-profit organization to support economic development efforts in the region – The Partnership for Central America.&nbsp; These initial commitments will provide financial services to small business owners, internet access and digital banking to rural communities, housing for low-income families, and reduced barriers to higher education.&nbsp; Since the&nbsp;launch, over&nbsp;150 companies and organizations&nbsp;have expressed&nbsp;interest in joining the&nbsp;<em>Call to Action</em>.</li></ul>



<p>Full report here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Root-Causes-Strategy.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Root-Causes-Strategy.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Collaborative Migration Management&#160;Strategy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-the-collaborative-migration-management-strategy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25305</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 2, 2021, President Biden signed an Executive Order that called for the development of a Collaborative Migration Management Strategy (Migration Strategy).&#160; Over the last six months, the Administration has consulted with partner governments, Members of Congress and their staff, international organizations, civil society organizations, labor unions, and the private sector to inform its&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On February 2, 2021, President Biden signed an Executive Order that called for the development of a Collaborative Migration Management Strategy (Migration Strategy).&nbsp; Over the last six months, the Administration has consulted with partner governments, Members of Congress and their staff, international organizations, civil society organizations, labor unions, and the private sector to inform its development.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is releasing the Migration Strategy.&nbsp; It is the first U.S. government strategy focused on strengthening cooperative efforts to manage safe, orderly, and humane migration in North and Central America.&nbsp; In line with our Nation’s highest values, the Migration Strategy contributes to a humane and secure approach by improving regional cooperation to manage migration, expanding protection, and enhancing access to lawful pathways for migration.&nbsp; It is driven by the U.S. government’s belief that all individuals should be able to find safety and achieve a stable and dignified life within their own countries.&nbsp; When that is not the case, asylum and other legal migration pathways should be available to those who need them.<br><br>The United States has strong national security, economic, and humanitarian interests in promoting safe, orderly, and humane migration.&nbsp; By enhancing humanitarian support, regional protections, and investing in migration management, the United States will help build a more stable region, strengthen legal pathways for those who must migrate, and reduce irregular migration.<br><br>The Migration Strategy includes the following lines of effort:</p>



<ul><li>Stabilize populations with acute needs</li><li>Expand access to international protection</li><li>Expand access to protection in countries of origin</li><li>Improve and expand temporary labor programs in the region with worker protections</li><li>Assist and reintegrate returned persons</li><li>Foster secure and humane management of borders</li><li>Strengthen regional public messaging on migration</li><li>Expand access to lawful pathways for protection and opportunities to the United States</li></ul>



<p>Implementation of the Migration Strategy will integrate various U.S. government tools, including diplomacy, foreign assistance, public messaging, and U.S. immigration initiatives.&nbsp; It will rely on the expertise of a wide range of U.S. departments and agencies, with support from governments in and&nbsp;outside&nbsp;the region, international organizations, civil society, the private sector, multilateral organizations, international financial institutions, and the U.S. Congress.&nbsp; These partnerships will bolster the impact of the Migration Strategy through informing programmatic interventions, leveraging political will, and mobilizing necessary resources.</p>



<p>Full report here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Collaborative-Migration-Management-Strategy.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Collaborative-Migration-Management-Strategy.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vice President’s Cover Letter: U.S. Strategy for Addressing the Root Causes of Migration in Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/u-s-strategy-for-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 09:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25293</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cover Message from Vice President Kamala Harris In Central America, the root causes of migration run deep—and migration from the region has a direct impact on the United States. For that reason, our nation must consistently engage with the region to address the hardships that cause people to leave Central America and come to our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Cover Message from Vice President Kamala Harris</em></p>



<p>In Central America, the root causes of migration run deep—and migration from the region has a direct impact on the United States. For that reason, our nation must consistently engage with the region to address the hardships that cause people to leave Central America and come to our border.</p>



<p>For decades, our nation has engaged in Central America. Often well intentioned, the engagement has often not been consistent. And over the last few years, the United States significantly pulled back from work in<br>the region.</p>



<p>Under our Administration, President Joe Biden and I have restarted our nation’s engagement in Central America and diplomatic efforts with Central American governments. Our Root Causes Strategy is comprehensive and draws from decades of experience—and is based on four core pieces of evidence.</p>



<p><strong>First, addressing the root causes of migration is critical to our overall immigration effort.</strong></p>



<p>Just after we took office, President Joe Biden outlined our Administration’s vision to reform our immigration system by creating a pathway to citizenship for the nearly 11 million undocumented migrants in our country, modernizing our immigration process, and effectively managing our border.</p>



<p>Shortly after that, the President asked me to lead our nation’s efforts to address the root causes of that migration. That is because migration to our border is also a symptom of much larger issues in the region.</p>



<p><strong>Second, providing relief is not sufficient to stem migration from the region.</strong></p>



<p>The COVID-19 pandemic and extreme weather conditions have indeed exacerbated the root causes of migration—which include corruption, violence, trafficking, and poverty. While our Administration is proud that we have sent millions of vaccine doses and hurricane relief, we know that it is not enough to alleviate suffering in the long term.</p>



<p>The root causes must be addressed both in addition to relief efforts—and apart from these efforts. In everything we do, we must target our efforts in those areas of highest out-migration—and ensure that these programs meet the highest standards of accountability and effectiveness.&nbsp;<strong><br></strong></p>



<p><strong>Third, unless we address all of the root causes, problems will persist.</strong></p>



<p>Recently, I travelled to Guatemala, where one of the largest challenges is corruption. Our Administration knows that, where corruption goes unchecked, people suffer. And so, on that trip, the United States announced that we will launch an Anticorruption Task Force which will include U.S. prosecutors and law enforcement experts who will investigate corruption cases. It is our goal that, in dealing directly with corruption, we will also mitigate the lack of economic and educational opportunities on the ground.</p>



<p><strong>Fourth, and most importantly, the United States cannot do this work alone.</strong></p>



<p>Our Strategy is far-reaching—and focuses on our partnerships with other governments, international institutions, businesses, foundations, and civil society. At this writing, we have already received commitments from the governments of Mexico, Japan, and Korea, and the United Nations, to join the United States in providing relief to the region. Our Administration is also working hand-in-hand with foundations and non-profits to accelerate efforts in Central America.</p>



<p>While, in the past, the private sector has been an underutilized partner, our Administration is calling on U.S. and international businesses to invest in the region – and thus far, 12 have done so. Private sector investment not only boosts economic opportunity, but it also incentivizes regional governments to create the conditions on the ground to attract such investment.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">* * *</p>



<p>Ultimately, our Administration will consistently engage in the region to address the root causes of migration. We will build on what works, and we will pivot away from what does not work. It will not be easy, and progress will not be instantaneous, but we are committed to getting it right. Because we know: The strength and security of the United States depends on the implementation of strategies like this one.</p>



<p>Root Causes Fact Sheet: <a target="_blank" href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25299" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-strategy-to-address-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/</a></p>



<p>Root Causes Report: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Root-Causes-Strategy.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Root-Causes-Strategy.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-28/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 21:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Mark Gitenstein, of Washington, to be Representative of the United States of America to the European Union, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary. &#160; &#160; &#160;Lisa M. Gomez, of New Jersey, to be an Assistant Secretary of Labor, vice Preston Rutledge. &#160; &#160; &#160;Laura&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Mark Gitenstein, of Washington, to be Representative of the United States of America to the European Union, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Lisa M. Gomez, of New Jersey, to be an Assistant Secretary of Labor, vice Preston Rutledge.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Laura S. H. Holgate, of Virginia, to be Representative of the United States of America to the Vienna Office of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Laura S. H. Holgate, of Virginia, to be Representative of the United States of America to the International Atomic Energy Agency, with the rank of Ambassador.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Erik Adrian Hooks, of North Carolina, to be Deputy Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency, Department of Homeland Security, vice Peter Gaynor, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Patricia Mahoney, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Central African Republic.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Julissa Reynoso Pantaleon, of New York, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Spain, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Principality of Andorra.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;William J. Valdez, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security, vice Claire M. Grady.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Peter Hendrick Vrooman, of New York, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Mozambique.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Adrienne Wojciechowski, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Agriculture, vice Kenneth Steven Barbic.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Importance of American&#160;Manufacturing</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/28/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-importance-of-american-manufacturing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mack Lehigh Valley Operations&#160;Macungie, Pennsylvania 1:59 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, I&#8217;m not going to say anything; I just came to drive a truck.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And I&#8217;m not sure which one I want to drive.&#160; That one?&#160; There&#8217;s one back in the corner you can&#8217;t see.&#160; It&#8217;s the biggest damn pick-up truck you ever saw&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Mack Lehigh Valley Operations&nbsp;<br>Macungie, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>1:59 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to say anything; I just came to drive a truck.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not sure which one I want to drive.&nbsp; That one?&nbsp; There&#8217;s one back in the corner you can&#8217;t see.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the biggest damn pick-up truck you ever saw in your life.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I tell you what.&nbsp;<br><br>Please, everybody have a seat.&nbsp; Everybody have a seat.<br><br>Carlo, thank you. &nbsp;And, Carlo, I&#8217;m sorry about your mom. &nbsp;I really am. &nbsp;So many &#8212; so many people. &nbsp;Well over 630,000 Americans have lost their lives because of COVID. &nbsp;And the only thing I&#8217;m going to &#8212; and the press keeps wanting me to talk about COVID, but I’m going to mention this one thing.<br><br>We still have a lot of people not vaccinated.&nbsp; The pandemic we have now is a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; So, please &#8212; please, please, please, if you&#8217;re not vaccinated, protect yourself and the children out there.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important.<br><br>And, Carlo, having been a significant consumer of healthcare myself and my family, I&#8217;ve often said this, and I mean it from the bottom of my heart: Thank your daughter for me.&nbsp; If there are any angels in heaven, they&#8217;re male and female nurses.&nbsp; Not &#8212; that&#8217;s the God&#8217;s truth.&nbsp; Doctors let you live; they make you want to live.&nbsp; Spent a lot of time in ICU, with my son on a table.&nbsp; Tell her, &#8220;Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#8221;&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And I want to thank Congresswoman Wild for the passport into her district.&nbsp; Where are you?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As they say up in Scranton, she&#8217;s bragging on y&#8217;all.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t say &#8220;y&#8217;all&#8221; up there; they say that in Delaware.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You do because you got family from Alabama.<br><br>And you&#8217;ve been a tireless champion for the working men and women of the Lehigh Valley, helping us pass a tax cut for families with children that people are seeing now in their bank accounts, showing up in their bank accounts every month, and working with our administration to expand home care for seniors.&nbsp; We got a generation that&#8217;s a &#8220;sandwich generation&#8221; between the child and a mom or dad needing help.&nbsp; And they need help.&nbsp; Provide better pay for caregivers.<br><br>And I want to particularly thank Bobby Casey &#8212; he&#8217;s a great friend of mine &#8212; who champions this cause in the Senate for eldercare.<br><br>You know, John Mack started this iconic American company in 1890.&nbsp;&nbsp;But things didn’t really didn&#8217;t get off the ground until four years later when he brought his William &#8212; his brother William down from Scranton.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Laughter.)<br><br>So, it goes to show you: If you want to get things moving, bring a guy from Scranton to get it going.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)<br><br>Mind if I take my coat off?&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to take my coat off.<br><br>You know &#8212; and, folks, we’re getting things moving.&nbsp; We really are.&nbsp; You are.<br><br>When I started my campaign for President &#8212; and the Gov is still &#8212; Gov, I didn&#8217;t introduce you.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; No, you&#8217;re the governor of this state, and you&#8217;re one of the best governors in the country.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And you&#8217;re a good friend.<br><br>When &#8212; when I said I was running when I announced my campaign &#8212; and not many people took it seriously &#8212; I said I was running for three reasons: one, to restore the soul of this country &#8212; a sense of decency and honor; but, secondly, to rebuild the backbone of the country: hardworking, middle-class folks who built this country.&nbsp; And I want to point out: Unions built the middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a joke.&nbsp; Unions built the middle class.<br><br>And, by the way, in case you regret anything, I just want you guys and women in union know that if it weren&#8217;t for the UAW in 1972, I never would have won.&nbsp; You think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; We had the largest percentage of union workers of any state in the nation in Delaware back then, including Michigan, because we&#8217;re a small state and we had big plans.&nbsp; But, so &#8212; so, before you get upset, remember, you&#8217;re to blame why I got here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Look, folks, I think a lot of us come from similar backgrounds: moms, dads, brothers, sisters, family.&nbsp; People who get up every day, work hard, raise their families, pay their taxes, serve their communities, and serve their country.<br><br>And that’s why I moved so quickly to pass the American Rescue Plan shortly after I got in &#8212; elected.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because we needed to act quickly and boldly to save jobs, save businesses, and save lives.&nbsp; And we did.<br><br>We added more than 600,000 jobs per month since I&#8217;ve taken office.&nbsp; That&#8217;s over 3 million jobs all told.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It&#8217;s the fastest job growth at this point in any administration on record because of you all.&nbsp;<br><br>We brought this economy back from the brink: checks in people&#8217;s pockets, shots in people&#8217;s arms, tax cuts for working families with children.&nbsp; And we designed our strategy not only to provide a temporary boost, but to lay the foundation for a long-term boom that brings everyone along.<br><br>Because when I arrived in office, we had a long time &#8212; it&#8217;s been a long time since the federal government had worked hard for working people.&nbsp; Things had been great for big corporations, great for the very wealthy, folks at the top.&nbsp; Those 55 major corporations for the past three years paid zero in federal taxes, making over $40 billion.&nbsp; They had no complaints.<br><br>But when I put my hand on that Bible on January 20th and took the Oath of Office, I made a commitment to the American people: We&#8217;re going to change the paradigm so working people could have a fighting chance again to get a good education, to get a good job and a raise, to take care of that elderly parent and afford to take care of their children, and stop losing hours of their lives stuck in traffic because the streets are crumbling, or waiting for slow, spotty Internet to connect them to the world.<br><br>That’s what the economy we’re building is all about.&nbsp; Because given half a chance &#8212; and think about this; I mean this from the bottom of &#8212; given half a chance, ordinary Americans &#8212; the people have never, ever, ever, ever let their country down, just given a half a chance.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp;<br><br>You may have heard that, in Washington &#8212; and I was just on the phone &#8212; it looks like we reached a bipartisan agreement on infrastructure &#8212; a fancy word for bridges, roads &#8212; (applause) &#8212; transit systems, high-speed Internet, clean drinking water, cleaning up and caffing [sic] &#8212; capping the orphan wells, over thousands of them abandoned, and abandoned mines &#8212; and a modern, resilient electric grid to build.<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; A lot of those abandoned wells are leaking methane.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; The same union guys that dug those wells, they can make the same union wage capping those wells.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And I’m working with Democrats and Republicans to get this done, because while there’s a lot we don’t agree on, I believe that we should be able to work together on the few things we do agree on.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s important.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition to the physical infrastructure, I also put forward a thing called Build Back Better plan, with investments that are going to really &#8212; if I said to you, &#8220;You could have the following: We&#8217;re going to be &#8212; build you a lot of new roads and bridges, or I can make sure we&#8217;re going to educate your kids so we&#8217;re the best educated population in the world,&#8221; what do you think would most impact on the growth of America?&nbsp; You’d be the most educated nation in the world.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m insisting that we have universal pre-kindergarten, two years of free community college.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>All the studies show: No matter what background a kid comes from &#8212; whether they&#8217;re a single mom, a single dad who is on what we used to call &#8220;welfare,&#8221; are in trouble, or come from a middle-class household &#8212; the kid who comes from the background that&#8217;s deprived is going to hear, by the time they get to first grade, a million fewer words spoken.&nbsp; A million fewer spoken.&nbsp; What that means is they&#8217;re behind the eight ball from the start.&nbsp; And a lot more.&nbsp;<br><br>But we found out if you put kids in not &#8212; not daycare but in school at age three, four, and five, it increases by 58 percent the chance, no matter what their background, they&#8217;ll make it through high school and qualify to go on to community college.&nbsp;<br><br>Folks, we need more affordable childcare.&nbsp; There are a lot of women not working today because they can&#8217;t get &#8212; go back to their jobs because they have no one to take care of their children; they can&#8217;t afford it.<br><br>I was a single dad for five years when my wife and daughter were killed in an automobile accident, my two little boys were badly banged up.&nbsp; I commuted back and forth to Washington because I couldn&#8217;t dare leave and move to Washington because I didn&#8217;t have my family to help me take care of my kids.&nbsp; I was making a good salary &#8212; $42,000 a year then.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford care &#8212; daycare for my children.<br><br>Eldercare: How many of you know somebody, has a mom or dad that needs help just because they&#8217;re getting older and maybe still has their home but would rather stay in their home, increase their mental state, put them in a position where it&#8217;s better for their health, but you can&#8217;t figure out how to keep mom home alone, how to do it &#8212; or dad?&nbsp; Well, eldercare is a big piece of this.<br><br>Paid leave: We&#8217;re one of the only industrial countries in the world that you don&#8217;t get paid leave if you have a sick son, daughter, mother, father, wife, husband, to have some time to take care of that.<br><br>Bring more people into the workforce, enhance our productivity, raise wages, and bring down the cost for working families.<br><br>You know, I was born up in Scranton, and my dad worked up in Scranton.&nbsp; He was actually from Baltimore, but he worked in Scranton and met my mom (inaudible) dad moved there.&nbsp;<br><br>And when coal died, everything died in the Valley, so he had to leave and look for a new job.&nbsp; My dad used to have an expression when we got down to Wilmington.&nbsp; First thing he did &#8212; he got a job scrubbing the inside of boilers for a thing ca- &#8212; often called “COW” &#8212; the COW corporation.<br><br>We finally got to the place where &#8212; we get to the place after five years we could afford to buy a small house &#8212; actually, six years.&nbsp; My dad used to say, “Remember, Joey, a job is about a lot more than a paycheck.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about your dignity. It&#8217;s about respect.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about your place in the community.”&nbsp; I give my word to what he’d say.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s about being able to look your kid in the eye and say, “Honey, it’s going to be okay,” and mean it.<br><br>Because we know that trickle-down economics has never worked.&nbsp; But when working families do well, everybody does well, including the wealthy.&nbsp; Everybody.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I’m here to talk about a commitment that’s sacred to me and central to our efforts to keep things moving.&nbsp; It’s a straightforward solution: support and grow more American-based companies.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Put more Americans to work in union jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Strengthen American manufacturing and secure critical supply chains.&nbsp; And confront the climate crisis, which is all about jobs.<br><br>I can sum it up in two words: Buy American.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Buy American.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, what most people don&#8217;t know &#8212; no matter how informed they are, most people don&#8217;t know that for literally almost a century, there&#8217;s been a law on the books in America called the Buy America Act.&nbsp; It&#8217;s supposed to make sure that when your government spends your tax dollars in buying goods that they have to be goods that were built, purchased in America.<br><br>But the previous administration didn&#8217;t take it so seriously &#8212; in previous ones, not just the last one.&nbsp; They were quick to say, “You know, we have a lot of money to spend.&nbsp; We got to buy &#8212; the government is going to buy everything from buildings to aircraft carriers to trucks to whatever it is.&nbsp; But we can&#8217;t find an American company that can do it all, so we&#8217;re going to have to issue a waiver.&nbsp; We’ll hire the American company, but that American company is going to have a subsidiary overseas where non-American &#8212; Americans don’t work, where it’s much cheaper, they can make more money, and they’re going to say, “We have to have that as part of the chain of building the product.”<br><br>The result has been tens of billions of dollars didn’t go to jobs and businesses in communities like this one.<br><br>In recent years, “Buy American” has become a hollow promise.&nbsp; But my adma- &#8212; my administration is going to make “Buy American” a reality.&nbsp; And I’m putting the weight of the federal government behind that commitment with Made in &#8212; in the White House itself, we put in a Made in America Office to oversee &#8212; not in an agency, in the White House itself &#8212; to oversee these efforts.<br><br>In my first Cabinet meeting, I told all of the Cabinet members if their agency wants to issue a waiver &#8212; they’re buying forest &#8212; the Forest Department is buying trucks or hoses or whatever they need, okay?&nbsp; They’ve got to buy something that’s &#8212; all of it has been made in America.&nbsp;<br><br>And you can’t give exceptions.&nbsp; Because if you say, “We can’t find one that does &#8212; has…”&nbsp; They get their nozzles overseas because they don’t have anybody here who can make them, et cetera.&nbsp; I said, “If you’re going to give an exception, you got to tell the White House specifically why the exception.”&nbsp;<br><br>If they still want a waiver, they have to post the request on &#8212; publicly so American manufacturers all over the United States &#8212; and businesses &#8212; have a chance to look up now in a new facility and say, “Hey, they’re for companies that make nozzles.&nbsp; They’re looking for companies that make the following whatever.&nbsp; We make that.&nbsp; We make that.”&nbsp; And contact us.&nbsp; Then they can’t take the job overseas.<br><br>And today, we’re going to go further: We’re going to make the biggest enforcement changes to the Buy American Act in 70 years.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, if you manufacture a vehicle &#8212; I expect you guys know about that &#8212; that gets purchased by the federal government, the law says that &#8212; and there’s about 600,000 vehicles the federal government owns, by the way, and replaces and buys &#8212; that “substantially all” of that vehicle &#8212; “substantially all” should be made in America.&nbsp;<br><br>But because of loopholes, over time, you know what “substantially all” means today?&nbsp; If 55 percent of it was made in America, you can go ahead and get all of the rest of it purchased other places.&nbsp; To me, 55 percent is not “substantially all;” it’s barely half.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is actually a double whammy.&nbsp; First, 55 percent is not high enough.&nbsp; And second, contractors don’t have to tell us the total domestic content of their products, they just have to tell us that they hit the threshold.&nbsp; Nobody checking.&nbsp; Well, they got a new sheriff in town.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re going to be checking.&nbsp; No, I’m serious.&nbsp; I am deadly earnest.<br><br>Today, I’m directing the Budget Office to issue a rule to raise the amount of domestic content required to be considered Made in America from 55 percent to 75 percent.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; “Substantially all” is going to mean substantially all.&nbsp;<br><br>And starting with critical products, instead of taking contractors at their word that they hit the threshold, we’re going to start making them give us the details so that we can do more to support American manufacturing.&nbsp;<br><br>We want to be the ones making the innovative parts of every product &#8212; the ones that will support more jobs and more small businesses.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, I had a tour today.&nbsp; A lovely lady showing me in the parts where &#8212; the second stop we made &#8212; she said, “Well, we’re having a little problem.&nbsp; We’re finding we don’t have the computer chips that we need to go into the engines, et cetera.”&nbsp; We basically don’t make them anymore in America.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I got together with a group of 20 Republicans and Democrats.&nbsp; We passed a new piece of legislation providing that South Korea and Taiwan open up plants here in the United States hiring American employees to make those computer chips so we’re not held hostage.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>In case you haven’t noticed, not only you but Ford Motor Company said they’re going to have to stop producing certain vehicles.&nbsp; They couldn’t get the chips.&nbsp; Couldn’t get the wafers.&nbsp;<br><br>And so I’m also directing my Budget Office to create new rules for critical products where we know we need stronger, more resilient domestic supply chains.&nbsp; We’re talking about components like semiconductors, pharmaceutical ingredients, advanced batteries, among other things.<br><br>We saw during the early days of the pandemic that the supply chain disruptions can put Americans’ lives and livelihoods at risk.&nbsp;<br><br>When we needed them most, we were short of protective equipment, we were short on ventilators and other essential health equipment.&nbsp; We couldn’t get the job done.&nbsp; We couldn’t take care of people.&nbsp; We were short on basic equipment.<br><br>I know a lot of you in this factory stepped up to make PPE at the time.&nbsp; That was a noble service, but it’s not a long-term solution.<br><br>Yes, we’ll keep trading with our allies, but we need to have a resilient supply chain of our own so that we’re never again at the mercy of other countries for critical goods ever again.&nbsp; Ever.<br><br>You know exactly what I’m talking about.&nbsp; Right here, you’ve seen production slowdowns.&nbsp; As I’ve said, you’ve had your hours cut because of the shortage of computer chips and semi-conductors.&nbsp;<br><br>These chips are in more than just vehicles; they enable so much of our modern lives &#8212; our smartphones, our televisions, our medical equipment.<br><br>That’s why we’re investing $50 billion to have the best chip manufacturing in the world come and build factories in the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And it passed the Senate, and it’s called the CHIPS Act, and it’s part of my Build Back Better plan.&nbsp; And it is bipartisan, as many Republicans are concerned about it as Democrats.<br><br>It’s not just semiconductors. &nbsp;With this rule, we’ll be able to buy medical products from companies like OraSure that are up &#8212; that are down the road in Bethlehem &#8212; or up the road in Bethlehem, I should say. &nbsp;I’m used to thinking from Scranton.<br><br>Their COVID-19 tests are being made right here, bringing good jobs along with it &#8212; meaning that we’re developing a homegrown capacity to respond to this pandemic and help prepare for the next one.<br><br>And, by the way, when I say “Buy in America,” I mean from all America.&nbsp; You know, we’re going to include communities that have historically been left out of government procurement, when more contracts are going to go Black and brown communities, Native Americans, small businesses, every state and territory, every industry that services and manufactures, and also agriculture.<br><br>Part of the problem is that a lot of companies don’t even know these opportunities exist to be part of this.&nbsp; And we’ve got to &#8212; and we got to know &#8212; I used to have a great friend &#8212; a friend who’s a great friend.&nbsp; He used to play for Providence College back in the days when they had great teams.&nbsp; His name was Pete McLaughlin, and he used to have an expression.&nbsp; And he wasn’t the &#8212; God love him.&nbsp; He passed away &#8212; needed a heart (inaudible).&nbsp;<br><br>But anyway, the point is that what Pete used to say &#8212; and academics weren’t his thing &#8212; he used to say something very streetwise.&nbsp; He said, “Joe, you got to know how to know.”&nbsp; You got to know how to know.&nbsp; You can walk into the Library of Congress, one of the greatest libraries in the world, and if you don’t know how to use the card catalog, figuratively speaking, it’s just all happenstance.&nbsp; You got to know how to know.<br><br>So we started a new manufacturing contracting office in the Small Business Administration to help small- and medium-sized businesses bid on these contracts.&nbsp; And my Department of Commerce is working to help government agencies connect with new domestic suppliers in every state.&nbsp; That’s how we’re going to build a future that’s made in America.<br><br>One more reason this is going to make a big difference:&nbsp; Each year, the federal government purchases more than $600 billion in goods and services<a>.&nbsp; </a>The Congress passes laws for purchasing things, and as President, I get to decide where we spend them and what we purch- &#8212; what &#8212; I mean, I purchase what was called for, but I get to &#8212; and I’m the one who makes the decision &#8212; the administration makes a decision on how to spend that $600 billion.<br><br>If American companies know that we’re going to be buying from them, they’re going to be more inclined to hire and make key investments in the future in their companies, like you’re doing here.<br><br>My Build Back Better plan has incentives for electric vehicle <s>adaptation</s> [adoption], for increasing the amount of clean energy our government buys.&nbsp; And these Buy American rules can help guarantee a reliable market.<br><br>I just saw the work you’re doing on the heavy-duty electric vehicles here, like electric garbage trucks.&nbsp; You know, there are more than 600,000 vehicles in the federal fleet, including the majority of &#8212; the largest portion of which are at the post office.&nbsp;<br><br>As we work to electrify them &#8212; as they run out, electrify them &#8212; we’re going to be making a market for vehicles with electric, supporting both the good jobs being created, as well as innovation we need to electrify our transportation sector and clean up our environment at the same time.<br><br>And we’ll be expanding my Made in America initiative to help cities, towns, and Tribes get a better deal when they buy a “Made in America” product.&nbsp; It helps the towns, the taxpayers, as well as all of you on the floor of this significant place.&nbsp; It really does.<br><br>There are a lot of folks out there who look at how fast and how dramatically the world is changing and world economies are changing.&nbsp; I mean, who would have thought that 20 years ago you’d be making electric garbage trucks here?&nbsp; Seriously, think about it.&nbsp; But they accept it as gospel that working folks aren&#8217;t going to &#8212; aren&#8217;t &#8212; are going to get left behind; they&#8217;re not going to be able to keep up.&nbsp;<br><br>Just the opposite.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the opposite.&nbsp; Hardworking Americans are the ones who are going to make it happen.&nbsp; We got to invest in you.&nbsp; We have the most productive workforce in the world here.&nbsp; Given half a chance, there’s not a single &#8212; single thing you can’t do.<br><br>So, I reject out of hand &#8212; I&#8217;ve been criticized for this for some time &#8212; but I reject out of hand this defeatist view that the forces of automation and globalization mean we can’t have good-paying union jobs in America.<br><br>And right here, on this factory floor, you’re making a product that are fighting climate change.&nbsp; That’s why when I hear &#8220;climate change,&#8221; I think jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>Our manufacturing future, our economic future, our solutions to the climate crisis are all going to be made in America, creating good jobs.&nbsp; This&#8217;s what it means to build back better.&nbsp;<br><br>We came out of this economic crisis &#8212; the worst since the Depression &#8212; stronger than when we went in.<br><br>America is one of the few countries of the world &#8212; when we get smacked and knocked down, we get up, we come back, and we come back better than we were before we got knocked down.&nbsp; Now, I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; Think about the &#8212; you know, the course of history in America.<br>And that’s why, in the American Rescue Plan that we passed shortly after I took office, we’re investing considerable sums that will go to cities and towns looking to build back stronger.<br><br>For example, towns in the southwestern part of this state can now apply for funds to cap those wells that are leaking methane, clean up abandoned coal mines, invest in bringing new employers into abandoned factories, and get help attracting them.<br><br>Let me close with this: Back in 2009, during the so-called &#8220;Great Recession,&#8221; the President asked me to be in charge of managing that piece &#8212; then-President Trump &#8212; excuse me, Freudian slip; that was the last President.&nbsp; He caused &#8212; anyway, that was &#8212; President Obama, when I was Vice President.&nbsp;<br><br>And the American auto industry, you remember, was on the rocks.&nbsp; And a lot of people, including a lot of Democrats, thought it wasn&#8217;t worth investing tra- &#8212; investing in them because the American worker wasn’t that good, and they were blah, blah, blah.<br><br>I remember the heat that I took &#8212; some of you may remember as well &#8212; when I stood up and stepped into the rescue of the American automobile industry.&nbsp; My name was often taken in vain on television shows a lot, because “Why is Biden so committed to the automobile industry?”&nbsp; Well, because the fundamental mistakes that were made weren’t made by the workers; they were made by management.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, a lot of the folks who said we shouldn’t rescue the American auto industry are the same folks who are saying, “We don’t need to buy American.”&nbsp; What those people never realized is, if you give an American worker just a chance &#8212; a fighting chance &#8212; there’s nothing they won’t do.&nbsp; And if you give American companies and communities the chance, there’s nothing they can’t build.&nbsp; Just look around.&nbsp;<br><br>From the steel that raised our cities to these trucks behind me that are going to carry the economy forward, to the workers who are the heart and soul and spine of this nation &#8212;&nbsp;American strength is here.&nbsp; It’s in this region.&nbsp; It’s you.&nbsp; It’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; It’s you.<br><br>And that’s why I’ve told every foreign leader &#8212; and I just got back from Europe meeting with heads of state.&nbsp; One said to me &#8212; I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And he said, “For how long?”&nbsp; A head of state.&nbsp; And I said, “You know, I want to tell you something: It’s never, ever, ever been a good bet to bet against America.&nbsp; We never fail when we decide we’re going to do something.”<br><br>So, today, I’m placing my bet on America.&nbsp; I know you all are going to make sure it pays off because it will pay off with good jobs, long-term employment, the ability for America to, once again, reassert its role as the most powerful economy in the world.&nbsp; And that is as important as the size of our military and as anything else we do.&nbsp; And if we think we’re not in a race, well, guess what?&nbsp; Take a look at China.&nbsp; Take a look at China.&nbsp;<br><br>I spent an awful lot of time with Xi Jinping, President of China &#8212; more than, I’m told, than any other world leader has.&nbsp; And he’s made it really clear he doesn’t think democracies can compete in the 21st century.&nbsp; And I spent over 25 hours alone with him over the period of the last five years &#8212; seven years.<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; Just come back from a conference with Putin.&nbsp; He thinks the same thing.&nbsp; Well, I got news for them: Autocracies will not succeed if we do what we can do as a democracy.&nbsp; Democracies.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you noticed, not a joke, a lot of the rest of the world is hedging their bets whether to move toward autocracy or stay with democracies.<br><br>We have it all, folks.&nbsp; We have everything that we need in this country to &#8212; not only today, but for my grandchildren &#8212; to be in a situation where we’re still the most powerful physically and most powerful economic nation in the world that treats other nations decently and maintains the peace.&nbsp; That’s who we are.&nbsp; That’s America.<br><br>We’re the most unique nation in the history of the world.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; By that I mean: Every other nation was put together based on ethnicity or religion, geography &#8212; but not America.&nbsp; America is the most unique nation in the world, and literally, we’re based on the ide- &#8212; an idea.&nbsp; An idea is what formed America.&nbsp; And the idea was &#8212; and it sounds corny, but it is absolutely true &#8212; no other nation has this as their organizing principle: “We hold these truths to be self-evident that all men and women are created equal…endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights…life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.”&nbsp;<br><br>We believe it.&nbsp; We’ve never accomplished it, but every generation that moved us closer and closer and closer to inclusion.&nbsp; That’s why America’s real power is not in the exercise of a military power, but people follow us because of our example.&nbsp; That’s why the rest of the world follows us.&nbsp;<br><br>It was about time we get back up and reassert who we are.&nbsp; This is the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, and God bless you all.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>2:32 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announced Three Key&#160;Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/president-biden-announced-three-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 20:14:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25257</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles: Jainey Bavishi, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, Department of Commerce Chavonda Jacobs-Young, Nominee for Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics, Department of Agriculture Thea Kendler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Export&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Jainey Bavishi, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, Department of Commerce</li><li>Chavonda Jacobs-Young, Nominee for Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics, Department of Agriculture</li><li>Thea Kendler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Export Administration, Department of Commerce</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Jainey Bavishi, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, Department of Commerce</u></strong></p>



<p>Jainey&nbsp;K.&nbsp;Bavishi&nbsp;serves as the Director of the New York City Mayor’s Office of Climate Resiliency.&nbsp; In this role, she leads a cross-disciplinary&nbsp;team that prepares the city for the impacts of climate change through science-based analysis, policy, program, and project development, and capacity building. During the Obama Administration, Bavishi served as the Associate Director for Climate Preparedness at the White House Council on Environmental Quality and Director of External Affairs and Senior Policy Advisor at the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).&nbsp;&nbsp;Bavishi&nbsp;also served as the Executive Director of R3ADY Asia-Pacific,&nbsp;focused on enhancing disaster risk reduction and resilience in the Asia-Pacific region,&nbsp;based in Honolulu, Hawaii.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Previously, she was the Founding Director of the Equity and Inclusion Campaign, a coalition of community-based leaders in the Gulf Coast region that focused on recovery from Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, Gustav and Ike, at the Louisiana Disaster Recovery Foundation.&nbsp;&nbsp;Bavishi&nbsp;has a Master’s degree in city planning from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology and a Bachelor’s degree in public policy and cultural anthropology from Duke University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Chavonda Jacobs-Young, Nominee for Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics, Department of Agriculture</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Chavonda Jacobs-Young is the Administrator of the USDA Agricultural Research Service and currently serves as the Acting Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics and as Acting USDA Chief Scientist. Dr. Jacobs-Young is the first woman and person of color to lead this agency, which manages an annual budget of $1.82 billion.</p>



<p>During Dr. Jacobs-Young’s distinguished federal career, she has excelled in top-level positions in USDA. She led the Office of National Programs and the Office of International Research as the Agricultural Research Service Associate Administrator for Research Programs. As the founding Director of the Office of the Chief Scientist at USDA, she facilitated the coordination of scientific leadership across federal agencies within USDA, ensuring that the research and scientific information and data produced were held to the highest standards of scientific integrity. As Acting Director for USDA&#8217;s National Institute of Food and Agriculture, she provided leadership and funding for programs that advanced agriculture-related sciences. And as Acting Deputy Under Secretary for Research, Education, and Economics Mission Area, she oversaw Agricultural Research Service, National Institute of Food and Agriculture, National Agriculture Statistics Service, Economic Research Service, and Office of the Chief Scientist.</p>



<p>Dr. Jacobs-Young has also served as a senior policy analyst for agriculture in the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, where she supported the President&#8217;s Science Advisor and others within the Executive Office of the President during the Obama Administration on high priority agricultural scientific issues.</p>



<p>Dr. Jacobs-Young is a native of Augusta, Georgia. She received a B.S. degree in Pulp and Paper Science and Technology from North Carolina State University, where she was a three-time ACC track champion. She earned M.S. and Ph.D. degrees in Wood and Paper Science, also from North Carolina State University, becoming the first African American woman in the country to receive a Ph.D. in this field. She is also a graduate of American University&#8217;s Key Executive Program on Public Policy Implementation. In addition to her career, and community service, Dr. Jacobs-Young is committed to family. This year she will celebrate her 25th wedding anniversary to Arland Young and she is mom to Autumn and Arland, Jr.</p>



<p><strong><u>Thea Kendler, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Export Administration, Department of Commerce</u></strong></p>



<p>Thea Kendler is an experienced federal government attorney whose career focuses on national security and international trade law. As a trial attorney in the Department of Justice’s National Security Division, Counterintelligence and Export Control Section, Ms. Kendler partners with U.S. Attorney’s Offices and federal agents around the country to investigate and prosecute cases primarily involving export controls, economic espionage, and counterintelligence. Ms. Kendler frequently speaks to international audiences on strategic trade controls and conducts training for foreign government officials on best border security law enforcement practices.</p>



<p>Before joining the Justice Department in 2014, Ms. Kendler served as Senior Counsel in the Commerce Department’s Office of Chief Counsel for Industry and Security, providing legal advice on export controls regulations and enforcement to the Bureau of Industry and Security. Earlier in her career, she practiced in the International Trade section of the law firm Akin Gump Strauss Hauer &amp; Feld LLP, where she conducted internal investigations and represented corporate clients in export controls, antidumping and countervailing duty, and Customs proceedings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ms. Kendler graduated from the University of Pennsylvania Law School, where in her third year she received a Foreign Language and Area Studies (FLAS) grant from the U.S. Department of Education to further her Chinese study.&nbsp; Her undergraduate degree is from Princeton University with a concentration in the School of Public and International Affairs and certificates in East Asian Studies and Chinese Culture.&nbsp; While in college, she studied Chinese in Beijing, China, and Japanese in Kanazawa, Japan.&nbsp; Ms. Kendler is admitted to the New York and District of Columbia Bars.&nbsp; She lives in Bethesda, Maryland, with her husband and two children.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
