<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 14:08:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-Harris Administration Announces Comprehensive Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gun Crime and Ensure Public Safety</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden believes that the surge in gun violence that has affected communities across the country over the last year and a half is unacceptable, and his Administration is moving decisively to act with a whole-of-government approach as we enter the summer months when cities typically experience a spike in violence. Today, the Biden-Harris Administration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden believes that the surge in gun violence that has affected communities across the country over the last year and a half is unacceptable, and his Administration is moving decisively to act with a whole-of-government approach as we enter the summer months when cities typically experience a spike in violence.<br><br>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a comprehensive strategy to combat gun violence and other violent crime.&nbsp;This strategy implements preventative measures that are proven to reduce violent crime, and attacks the root causes – including by addressing the flow of firearms used to commit crimes.<br><br>This strategy will use the Rescue Plan’s historic funding levels and clear guidance to help state, local, territorial, and tribal governments get the money they need to put more police officers on the beat – with the resources, training, and accountability they need to engage in effective community policing – in addition to supporting proven Community Violence Intervention programs, summer employment opportunities, and other investments that we know will reduce crime and make our neighborhoods safer.<br><br>The strategy will also address the direct link between gun violence and the rise in violent crime by taking immediate steps to keep guns out of the wrong hands, including by strengthening ATF’s efforts to stem the flow of firearms used in crimes, and by launching multijurisdictional firearms trafficking strike forces to stop illegal gun trafficking across state lines.<br><br>Combined, the Administration’s comprehensive strategy will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Stem the flow of firearms used to commit violence, including by holding rogue firearms dealers accountable for violating federal laws;</strong></li><li><strong>Support local law enforcement with federal tools and resources to help address summer violent crime;</strong></li><li><strong>Invest in evidence-based community violence interventions;</strong></li><li><strong>Expanding summer programming, employment opportunities, and other services and supports for teenagers and young adults; and</strong></li><li><strong>Help formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities.</strong></li></ul>



<p>Now is the time to act. With the secondary consequences of the pandemic and the proliferation of illegal guns over the same period, we have seen increased violence over the past year and a half. <a href="https://cdn.ymaws.com/counciloncj.org/resource/resmgr/covid_commission/Year_End_Crime_Update_Design.pdf">Homicides rose 30%, and gun assaults rose 8% in large cities in 2020.</a> The number of <a href="https://covid19.counciloncj.org/2021/05/21/impact-report-covid-19-and-crime-4/">homicides in the first quarter of 2021</a> was 24% higher than the number of homicides in the first quarter of 2020, and 49% higher than in the first quarter of 2019. Black and brown Americans are <a href="https://efsgv.org/wp-content/uploads/2019CDCdata.pdf">disproportionately harmed</a> by the direct and indirect consequences of gun violence.<br><br>As the President has repeatedly said, we are experiencing an epidemic of gun violence in this country. This violence robs us of loved ones and causes life-altering physical injuries. It causes lasting trauma, with cascading consequences for children, families, and communities. It steals our freedom, our sense of belonging and security, and has ripple effects for our economy.<br><br>The President continues to call on Congress to take action to end this gun violence epidemic. But he knows we cannot afford to wait a single day while lives are being taken, which is why he has already announced a set of initial actions to prevent gun violence – including toughening regulations on ghost guns and moving historically quickly to nominate a permanent ATF Director – in addition to the steps announced today as part of this strategy.<br><br><strong>Stem the Flow of Firearms Used to Commit Violence</strong><br><br>The Biden Administration is taking action to help stem the flow of guns into the hands of those responsible for violence by:<br><br><strong>Establishing zero tolerance for rogue gun dealers that willfully violate the law.</strong> Gun dealers across the country are regulated by federal law that is enforced by the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF). Dealers that fail to comply with their obligations under the law create risks for all of us. Today, the Justice Department is announcing a new policy to underscore zero tolerance for willful violations of the law by federally licensed firearms dealers that put public safety at risk. Absent extraordinary circumstances that would need to be justified to the Director, ATF will seek to revoke the licenses of dealers the first time that they violate federal law by willfully 1) transferring a firearm to a prohibited person, 2) failing to run a required background check, 3) falsifying records, such as a firearms transaction form, 4) failing to respond to an ATF tracing request, or 5) refusing to permit ATF to conduct an inspection in violation of the law.</p>



<p>In addition, ATF will notify every firearms dealer whose license is revoked about how to lawfully transfer any remaining inventory, as well as the potential criminal consequences of continuing to engage in the business of buying and selling guns without a license. The prior Administration stopped this important notification practice that helps deter future unlawful activity.<br><br><strong>Maximizing the efficacy of ATF resources to crack down on rogue gun dealers violating our laws.</strong>&nbsp;The Administration continues to call on Congress to increase funding for ATF to hire additional personnel necessary to increase the number of inspections and enforcement actions taken against dealers in violation of federal law. The President’s FY 22 budget request would allow ATF to add inspectors in every field division around the country. In the meantime, ATF is announcing the following actions to increase the efficacy of its existing, limited resources:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Better coordination with state and local officials with on-the-ground knowledge of which dealers are supplying firearms that show up at crime scenes.</strong> ATF has designated a specific point of contact in every field division for mayors, police chiefs, or other local leaders to report concerns about particular dealers’ compliance with the law. This information may provide valuable leads for ATF investigations and serve as a source of information that helps focus inspection resources on the places that need them most.<br> </li><li><strong>Formalizing the use of data-driven prioritization of inspection resources.</strong> Starting today, ATF will make clear to investigators in every field division—through trainings and guidance—that when identifying inspection priorities they must consider a number of factors related to public safety, including the extent to which firearms sold by the dealer are later used in criminal activity; the time between the sale of a firearm and its use in a crime; the number of recoveries associated with shootings, domestic violence, and other violent offenses; and additional information developed by local law enforcement partners. This data-driven prioritization will allow ATF to target its limited inspection resources to ensure compliance with federal law.</li><li><strong>Equipping states that have their own gun dealer licensing systems with data from ATF inspections.</strong> Sixteen states license or regulate firearms dealers themselves, and their inspection systems can be force multipliers in protecting public safety. Starting next month, ATF will begin sharing inspection data with these states so that officials there can determine whether to take their own steps to shut down dealers that fail to live up to their obligations under state law.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Launching multijurisdictional firearms trafficking strike forces. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration recognizes that the federal government has a critical role to play in coordinating multijurisdictional enforcement efforts to stop the illegal flow of firearms across state lines. Yesterday, the Justice Department announced that it is launching five new law enforcement strike forces focused on addressing significant firearms trafficking corridors that have diverted guns to New York, Chicago, Los Angeles, the Bay Area, and Washington, D.C. These strike forces, which will launch within the next 30 days, will be led by designated United States Attorneys who will coordinate not only with ATF but also with state and local law enforcement partners in places where firearms originate and where they are used to commit crimes. The strike forces will share information and otherwise coordinate their efforts across districts where firearms trafficking schemes cross state or jurisdictional boundaries. As part of this effort, ATF is issuing a best practices guide for law enforcement agencies that will include specific questions that officers should ask unlawful firearm possessors to help identify sources of trafficked crime guns.<br><br><strong>Providing the public with additional data to promote transparency and accountability in enforcement of federally licensed firearms dealer policies. </strong>ATF will publicly post more detailed information about inspection findings and enforcement actions. For the first time, this publicly posted data will be disaggregated to show the number of inspections conducted in each field division, the number of inspections that identified violations, and actions taken by ATF to implement the willful-violation policy discussed above (including any application of the extraordinary circumstances exception). This data will promote transparency and accountability for the enforcement of our existing gun laws.<br><strong>Stemming the proliferation of “ghost guns” and modified firearms.</strong> During the April address in the Rose Garden by the President and Attorney General, the Justice Department announced that it was beginning the rulemaking process to help stop the proliferation of dangerous firearms that are currently circumventing our gun laws. The Justice Department has since issued two proposed rules to follow through on this commitment. First, the Justice Department issued a proposed rule to help address the proliferation of “ghost guns,” which are homemade firearms that are increasingly ending up at crime scenes and often cannot be traced by law enforcement due to the lack of a serial number. Second, the Justice Department issued a proposed rule to make clear when a device marketed as a stabilizing brace effectively turns a pistol into a short-barreled rifle subject to the requirements of the National Firearms Act. Modifying a pistol with an arm brace can make a firearm more stable and accurate while still being concealable.</p>



<p><strong>Convening state legislators and Attorneys General regarding policy strategies to hold gun dealers and manufacturers accountable for their contributions to the flow of crime guns.</strong>&nbsp;The President continues to call on Congress to repeal the Protection of Lawful Commerce in Arms Act (PLCAA), which gives gun dealers and manufacturers special immunity from certain liability for their products. In the meantime, the White House will convene state legislators and Attorneys General to discuss strategies for enacting and employing state liability laws that can be used to hold dealers and manufacturers accountable for improper conduct not covered by PLCAA.</p>



<p>These actions are part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive strategy to reduce gun violence through executive action and legislation. For example, earlier this month the Justice Department issued model state “red flag,” or “extreme risk protection order,” legislation. Extreme risk protection order laws allow family members or law enforcement to petition for a court order temporarily barring people in crisis from accessing firearms if they present a danger to themselves or others. The President urges Congress to pass an appropriate national “red flag” law, as well as legislation incentivizing states to pass their own versions of these laws.<br><br>The President again strongly urges the Senate to ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, and pass the three House-passed, bipartisan pieces of legislation which would strengthen our gun background check system.<br><br><strong>Provide law enforcement the tools and resources needed to tackle gun violence</strong><br><br>As part of the Justice Department’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/attorney-general-merrick-b-garland-announces-new-effort-reduce-violent-crime"><strong>Comprehensive Strategy for Reducing Violent Crime</strong></a>, the Justice Department is committed to supporting law enforcement in local communities in addressing gun violence. In preparation for a possible increase in violence typically seen over the summer months, where needed and appropriate, the Justice Department is providing the following law enforcement support:</p>



<ul><li>The FBI is making available cutting-edge analytical resources to support state and local law enforcement efforts to identify the most violent offenders and most dangerous criminal organizations in communities. The FBI is also deploying agents to assist with enforcement operations targeting these entities. <br> </li><li>Where feasible, the ATF is embedding with local homicide units and expanding the availability of its National Integrated Ballistic Information Network (NIBIN) Correlation Center, which matches ballistics from crime scenes to other ballistic evidence nationwide.<br> </li><li>The DEA is focusing its efforts, in coordination with state, local and Tribal law enforcement, to disrupt the activities of the most violent drug trafficking gangs and egregious drug-trafficking organizations operating in the highest-crime areas.<br> </li><li>The United States Marshals Service, in coordination with state and local authorities, is conducting fugitive sweeps throughout the country focused on individuals subject to state or local warrants for homicide, aggravated assault with a firearm, aggravated robbery, robbery with a firearm, rape or aggravated sexual assault.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Guidance on Using ARP Funds to Reduce Violence.</strong>&nbsp;Today, the&nbsp;<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/SLFRPFAQ.pdf#page=19">Treasury Department</a>&nbsp;is highlighting that communities experiencing a surge in gun violence as a result of the pandemic may use the American Rescue Plan’s $350 billion in state and local funding for purposes such as:</p>



<ul><li>Hiring law enforcement officials – even above pre-pandemic levels – or paying overtime where the funds are directly focused on advancing community policing strategies in those communities experiencing an increase in gun violence associated with the pandemic.</li><li>Additional enforcement efforts to reduce gun violence exacerbated by the pandemic, including prosecuting gun traffickers, rogue dealers, and other parties contributing to the supply of crime guns, as well as collaborative federal/state/local efforts to identify and address gun trafficking channels.</li><li>Investing in technology and equipment to allow law enforcement to more efficiently and effectively respond to the rise in gun violence resulting from the pandemic.</li></ul>



<p>In addition, the Treasury Department is clarifying that any community may use ARP state and local aid for the above strategies and any other public safety programs, up to the level of revenue loss the jurisdiction experienced during the pandemic. And any community may use ARP funds to rehire police officers and other public servants to restore law enforcement and courts to their pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p><strong>Byrne JAG Funds. </strong>Applications for the Justice Department’s FY21 $276 million Byrne Justice Assistance Grant program are open now. Byrne JAG provides critical support to State and territory, local, and Tribal governments across a range of program areas, including crime prevention and education, law enforcement, prosecution, indigent defense, courts, corrections and community corrections, drug treatment and enforcement, technology improvement, crime victim and witness initiatives, and planning and evaluation. Community violence intervention programs are eligible uses of the funding.<br><br>In soliciting grant applications for this program, the Department has emphasized the importance of addressing the backlog of cases created when courts at every level were forced to cancel or scale back proceedings due to COVID-19. It has made clear that funds could be used, for example, to purchase technology that would facilitate virtual outreach and appearances, to enhance case management systems, to build tools to support diversion and alternatives to incarceration as part of the review of backlogged cases, or to retrofit courthouses to mitigate risks to staff. <br><br>The President is also seeking a $300 million increase for the Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS) Hiring program in his recent budget request. These funds will advance community policing and give police the resources they need to keep their communities safe.<br><br><strong>Invest in evidence-based community violence interventions</strong><br><br>Community violence intervention (CVI) programs have been shown to reduce violence by <a href="https://lawcenter.giffords.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/01/Healing-Communities-in-Crisis.pdf">as much as 60%</a>. These programs are effective because they leverage trusted messengers who work directly with individuals most likely to commit gun violence, intervene in conflicts, and connect people to social, health and wellness, and economic services to reduce the likelihood of violence as an answer to conflict.<br><br>Last month, the Treasury Department announced that the American Rescue Plan’s $350 billion in state and local funding can be used to invest in evidence-based community violence interventions. The Department of Education also released guidance clarifying that ARP’s $122 billion in K-12 funds can be used for CVI strategies. To date, the Administration has transferred more than $190 billion of state and local recovery funds and $81 billion in education funds, and additional support is on the way.<br><br>Today, the President is announcing that the Administration will convene and support a CVI Collaborative of 15 jurisdictions that are committing to use a portion of their ARP funding or other public funding to increase investment in their CVI infrastructure, including to anticipate and respond to the potential rise in violence this summer. These jurisdictions include:</p>



<ul><li>Atlanta, GA</li><li>Austin, TX</li><li>Baltimore, MD</li><li>Baton Rouge, LA</li><li>Chicago, IL</li><li>Detroit, MI</li><li>King County, WA</li><li>Los Angeles, CA</li><li>Memphis, TN</li><li>Minneapolis &amp; St. Paul, MN</li><li>Newark, NJ</li><li>Philadelphia, PA</li><li>Rapid City, SD</li><li>St. Louis, MO</li><li>Washington, DC</li></ul>



<p>Over the next 18 months, the Administration will convene meetings with officials from these communities, facilitate peer-to-peer learning, and provide technical assistance. This effort will support both proven and new strategies that reduce gun violence and strengthen community-based infrastructure to enhance public safety for children, families, and communities and to advance equity. A group of philanthropies that have been leaders on this issue will support this collaborative learning network by deploying CVI experts to provide training and technical assistance, identify best practices, integrate proven and innovative public-health approaches, and help local community-based organizations scale CVI efforts this summer and beyond. This group includes:</p>



<ul><li>Arnold Ventures</li><li>The California Endowment</li><li>Annie E. Casey Foundation</li><li>Emerson Collective</li><li>Ford Foundation</li><li>Heising-Simons Foundation</li><li>Joyce Foundation</li><li>W.K. Kellogg Foundation</li><li>Kresge Foundation</li><li>The John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation</li><li>Microsoft Corporation</li><li>Open Society Foundations</li><li>Charles and Lynn Schusterman Family Philanthropies</li></ul>



<p>Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and Director of Intergovernmental Affairs Julie Chavez Rodriguez will convene the first meeting of the CVI Collaborative soon. The President is calling on mayors across the country to follow the lead of these local officials by using their ARP funding or other public funds to launch and strengthen CVI programs in their communities.<br><br>Additionally, the Biden-Harris Administration will convene the first CVI Webinar Series event on June 23. The webinar series will bring together subject matter experts to discuss immediate steps communities and local organizations can take to reduce violence.&nbsp;<br><br>The Administration is continuing to seek a historic $5.2 billion investment in new grant funding for CVI programs through the American Jobs Plan and its FY22 discretionary budget request. The Administration is also executing on its announced changes to 26 programs across five agencies to make federal dollars and technical assistance available to CVI practitioners in the immediate term. For example, this month the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) will publish guidance encouraging jurisdictions to use part of their Community Development Block Grant funds to support CVI efforts needed to combat violence as a result of the coronavirus pandemic. In July and August, the Department of Education will publish guidance explaining that school districts can draw upon the $1.22 billion in Student Support and Academic Enrichment grants and $1.26 billion in 21st Century Community Learning Centers grants to support CVI programs that serve students. This funding will supplement American Rescue Plan funds, providing CVI programs with multiple potential funding streams to expand their work.<br><br><strong>Expand summer programming, employment opportunities, and other services and supports, especially for teenagers and young adults</strong><br><br><strong>American Rescue Plan Funds.</strong>&nbsp;The Administration released guidance from the&nbsp;<a href="https://home.treasury.gov/system/files/136/SLFRPFAQ.pdf#page=19">Department of the Treasury</a>&nbsp;today and from the&nbsp;<a href="https://oese.ed.gov/files/2021/06/21-0130-ARP-Public-Safety-ED-FAQ-06-16-2021.pdf">Department of Education</a>&nbsp;last week explaining how two buckets of American Rescue Plan funding—$350 billion in state and local funding and the $122 billion in school funding—can be used for a variety of public safety strategies. Within the parameters explained in those guidance documents, State and territory, local, and Tribal governments can:</p>



<ul><li>Hire support personnel such as nurses, counselors, and social workers;</li><li>Pay court personnel and operations costs to return to pre-pandemic operation levels;</li><li>Provide and expand employment services, including summer jobs for young people and programs that provide training and work experience for formerly incarcerated persons and other individuals who live in communities most impacted by high levels of violence;</li><li>Provide and expand summer education and enrichment programs, including summer camp;</li><li>Scale up wraparound services—such as housing, medical and mental health care, trauma-informed care, substance use disorder treatment, food assistance, and job placement services—for victims of crime, young people, formerly incarcerated persons, and individuals and households facing economic insecurity due to the pandemic; and</li><li>Establish or expand full-service community schools.</li></ul>



<p>The President urges jurisdictions to use these resources now for strategies to prevent violence.<br><br><strong>Youth Workforce Development Funds.</strong> Young people are disproportionately likely to be involved in gun violence, either as perpetrators or victims. We also know that youth employment programs, including summer jobs programs, can reduce their involvement in violence by as much as <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/metro_2018jan_how-can-summer-jobs-reduce-crime-among-youth-final.pdf">35%</a> or <a href="https://www.ojp.gov/pdffiles1/ojjdp/grants/251101.pdf">45%</a>. The Biden Administration is committed to funding workforce development programs to keep young people safe and give them a path to success.<br><br>On June 10, the Department of Labor awarded $89 million through its YouthBuild program to provide pre-apprenticeship opportunities for young people ages 16-24. 68 grantee organizations will serve more than 5,000 youth in dozens of cities. The young people will split their time between workplace training and the classroom, where they earn their high school diploma or equivalency degree and prepare for postsecondary opportunities. The grants support training and employment in in-demand industries, including construction, healthcare, information technology, manufacturing, logistics, and hospitality. YouthBuild includes a significant wrap-around support system, such as mentoring, trauma-informed care, follow-up education, employment, and personal counseling services.<br><br>The Department of Labor on June 10 also awarded $20 million through its Workforce Pathways for Youth program to expand workforce development activities that serve youth ages 14-21 during “out of school” time (non-school hours). Through these grants, four national grantee organizations will serve approximately 7,000 participants in multiple cities across the country. The organizations will provide career exploration services; work readiness training; career counseling; work experience (internships, summer and year-round employment, pre-apprenticeships, and registered apprenticeships); mentoring; and assistance in placing youth in employment, education, or training.<br><br><strong>Help formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities</strong><br><br>Formerly incarcerated individuals face an uphill climb in landing a job. Many employers are reluctant to hire them out of stigma, fear, or concern that they lack the skills needed for the job. But employment is a key to formerly incarcerated individuals’ successful reentry into their communities. Individuals who secure employment after release have much lower recidivism rates than those who do not. Good, stable jobs promote public safety. That is why the Administration is taking concrete steps to facilitate employment and associated services, such as housing assistance, for people who are formerly incarcerated.<br><br><strong>Investments to help formerly incarcerated individuals find quality jobs. </strong>On June 21, the <a href="https://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/eta/eta20210621">Department of Labor awarded $85.5 million</a> to help formerly incarcerated adults and young people in 28 communities transition out of the criminal justice system and connect with quality jobs. This includes $60 million for Pathway Home projects that will serve approximately 6,000 adults. By enabling services to begin while participants are still incarcerated and continue services post-release, the Pathway Home initiative eliminates the gap between release from incarceration and enrollment into a reentry program. Participants are taught job readiness and job search strategies and receive apprenticeships and occupational training. The Department also awarded $25.5 million in Young Adult Reentry Partnership grants to organizations that will help provide education and training services to young adults between 18-24 who were previously involved with the justice system or who left high school before graduation. The program will serve approximately 3,000 young people, offering accelerated and work-based learning such as registered apprenticeships in high-demand occupations with living wages. Grantees reduce barriers to labor market entry by providing career exploration activities, case management services, legal and other supportive services, and both job preparation and placement. Priority was given to organizations serving communities with high rates of poverty and crime.<br><br><strong>Expanding Federal Hiring of Formerly Incarcerated Persons:</strong> The Office of Personnel Management (OPM) will evaluate the existence of any barriers faced by formerly incarcerated persons in accessing federal employment and consider whether the federal government should take further action as appropriate, including creating a new “Schedule A” excepted service hiring authority for formerly incarcerated persons. This Schedule A hiring authority would allow federal agencies to hire qualified individuals for any job opening through the non-competitive, excepted service hiring process. Schedule A appointments are one-year temporary appointments with good benefits that can be extended for an additional year. Schedule A positions equip people with the skills and experience to become more competitive in the job market. Schedule A hiring authority has previously been created for veterans, people with disabilities, individuals on work release from incarceration, and people hired in direct response to the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic.<br><br><strong>Implementing “ban the box” policy.</strong> OPM will also publish proposed regulations to implement the Fair Chance to Compete for Jobs Act of 2019’s “ban the box” policy. The Fair Chance Act prohibits federal employers and federal contractors in all three branches of government from inquiring into arrest and conviction history until they have made a conditional job offer.<br><br><strong>Hiring Second Chance Act Fellow. </strong>The Department of Justice plans to post an application next month for a formerly incarcerated individual to work at DOJ as a Second Chance Act visiting fellow. This is a unique opportunity to draw on the expertise of a formerly incarcerated person as a policy advocate, legal or social services provider, or academic focusing on the successful reintegration of people returning home to their communities after incarceration. The fellow will develop innovative strategies that build upon and improve DOJ’s investments in reentry and reintegration. <br><br><strong>Leveraging tax credits to incentivize hiring of formerly incarcerated individuals. </strong>The Department of Labor and Department of the Treasury will help employers leverage the Work Opportunity Tax Credit (WOTC), which includes incentivizes to hire formerly incarcerated individuals. Under WOTC, employers can receive up to a $2,400 credit against federal income taxes for hiring a person within one year of their conviction or release from prison for a felony offense. The Departments of Labor and Treasury will encourage employers to take up this opportunity to hire formerly incarcerated individuals. Specifically, within 90 days, the Departments will issue guidance, provide technical assistance to state workforce agencies, and release materials on ways employers can leverage this tax credit and other resources, such as the Federal Bonding Program and the American Rescue Plan’s Employee Retention Credit (ERC). For example, a small business that hires someone who was released in the last twelve months and employs them through the second half of the year could qualify for a credit of up to $16,400 per worker by claiming both the WOTC and the ERC. The Department of the Treasury will also revise online materials to make it easier to claim the tax credit.<br><br><strong>Addressing the housing needs of returning citizens. </strong>Today, HUD Secretary Marcia L. Fudge is issuing a <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/PA/documents/SOHUD_reentry_housing_letter.pdf">letter</a> outlining actions that HUD is taking to improve public safety by addressing the housing needs of returning citizens, including through the recently awarded 70,000 emergency housing vouchers funded by the American Rescue Plan. The letter clarifies that returning citizens that are at-risk of homelessness are among the eligible populations for these emergency housing vouchers and encourages public housing authorities and their Continuum of Care partners to ensure that eligible returning citizens are given consideration for these vouchers. The letter also discusses additional steps that HUD is taking to improve access to housing for returning citizens and people with criminal records.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/22/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-42/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  12:35 P.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&#160; We&#8217;re joined by Drs. Fauci, Walensky, and Murthy, who I will turn to in a few moments. First, today, I want to report on the progress we are making in our fight to end the pandemic, specifically as it relates to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference </p>



<p>12:35 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&nbsp; We&#8217;re joined by Drs. Fauci, Walensky, and Murthy, who I will turn to in a few moments.<br><br>First, today, I want to report on the progress we are making in our fight to end the pandemic, specifically as it relates to the President’s goals for July 4th.<br><br>In March, on the one-year anniversary of the start of the pandemic and less than two months after taking office, President Biden provided Americans an update on the whole-of-government effort he was mobilizing to defeat the virus and set what, at the time, seemed like an audacious goal for the country: independence from COVID-19 by July 4th.<br><br>The President was clear about what achieving this very ambitious goal would require.&nbsp; First, we needed to build on the work we began on January 20th, taking additional bold steps to make vaccines even more accessible to all Americans and to further accelerate the pace of vaccinations.<br><br>And second, we needed “every American to do their part.”&nbsp; He said, quote, “If we do all this, if we do our part, if we do this together, by July the 4th, there’s a good chance you, your families, and friends will be able to get together in your backyard or in your neighborhood and have a cookout and celebrate Independence Day.”&nbsp; He said that this would not mean large events with lots of people together, but rather with small groups of close friends and family.&nbsp;<br><br>Just three months later, look at where we are.&nbsp; We have succeeded beyond our highest expectations.&nbsp; Instead of just small, backyard gatherings, America is getting ready for a truly historic Fourth of July, with large celebrations planned in communities across the country.<br><br>Here at the White House, we will be celebrating our independence from the virus with over 1,000 people on the White House lawn &#8212; 1,000 of our nation’s military and frontline workers celebrating how far we have come as a country in such a short period of time.&nbsp;<br><br>And here’s why we are able to do so: Since the President took office, COVID-19 cases and deaths are down by over 90 percent.&nbsp; Nearly every state is open for most activities, and the economy is rebounding strongly.<br><br>Importantly, today I am announcing exciting news.&nbsp; We have already met the President’s 70 percent goal for all U.S. adults 30 and older.&nbsp; That’s right: For those ages 30 and above, 70 percent have at least one shot.<br><br>We got here because the President treated this as a wartime effort; built a whole-of-government response to defeat the pandemic; and mobilized state and local governments, the private and non-profit sectors, and asked every American to join this fight.<br><br>In the past 150 days, we went from not having enough supply to securing supply &#8212; enough supply to vaccinate all Americans and making every adult eligible for vaccinations months ahead of expectations.<br><br>We went from not having enough places to get vaccinated to more than 81,000 convenient vaccination sites.&nbsp; In fact, today, 90 percent of Americans live within five miles of a vaccine site.&nbsp; Tens of thousands of sites offer walk-in vaccinations, and thousands are open 24 hours a day on Fridays in June.<br><br>And Americans have new tools to find the most convenient vaccination sites and free transportation to get to and from sites.<br><br>We have built an unparalleled, first-of-its-kind, nationwide vaccination program.&nbsp; And as a result, we have successfully executed the most complex, logistical task: administering 300 million shots in just 150 days.<br><br>To put that into perspective, at the pace the U.S. was vaccinating before the President took office, it would have taken 336 days &#8212; almost a year &#8212; to get 300 million shots in arms.&nbsp;<br><br>Instead of hitting the major milestone of 300 million shots in June, we would have hit it in December &#8212; six months from now.&nbsp; And America would have looked a lot different than it does today.&nbsp; We would have lost more lives; more people would have gotten sick; and many of our businesses, restaurants, and schools would still be closed.<br><br>The President understood that we did not have a day to waste, and we have moved at an unprecedented speed.&nbsp;<br><br>Importantly, Americans have responded to the President’s call.&nbsp; More than 175 million Americans have rolled up their sleeves and gotten at least one shot, and over 150 million Americans are now fully vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>As a result, we are close to achieving two aspirational goals we set for July 4th. &nbsp;The first goal was related to the percentage of adults who have at least one shot by July 4th.&nbsp; We asked Americans, state and local governments, and the private sector to help get to 70 percent of all adults with at least one shot by July 4th.&nbsp; Sixteen states and the District of Columbia have already met this goal.&nbsp;<br><br>And let’s remember, when the President took office, we were at approximately 5 percent of adults with one shot.&nbsp; So, in just five months, we have been racing from 5 percent to 70 percent.<br><br>So, how are we doing?&nbsp; Today, I want to drill down on the numbers that show where we have made the most progress and where we have more work to do.<br><br>We set 70 percent of adults as our aspirational target, and we have met or exceeded it for most of the adult population.&nbsp; This is a remarkable achievement.<br><br>When we began our vaccination campaign, we prioritized the most vulnerable.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s clear from the numbers that this strategy has worked.&nbsp; Looking at Americans 65 and older &#8212; our most at-risk group &#8212; we have more than 87 percent with at least one shot.&nbsp; Again, 87 percent of seniors, who tragically accounted for about 80 percent of COVID deaths, have gotten at least one shot.&nbsp; And today, nearly 80 percent of people 65 and older are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; That’s lifesaving progress.<br><br>For Americans who are 40 years old and over, 75 percent have received at least one shot.&nbsp; For Americans 30 and older, we have met the President’s goal of at least one shot.&nbsp; That’s right: We have met the President’s 70 percent goal for all U.S. adults 30 and over.<br><br>And based on today’s estimates, we&#8217;re on track to hit the 70 percent target for those age 27 and over once the data for the July 4th holiday weekend is fully in.&nbsp;<br><br>So, as to our goal of 70 percent for all adults, we’re going to hit it for adults 27 and older.&nbsp; This is amazing progress and has our country returning to normal much sooner than anyone could have predicted.&nbsp;<br><br>Where the country has more work to do is particularly with 18- to 26-year-olds.&nbsp; The reality is: Many younger Americans have felt like COVID-19 is not something that impacts them and they&#8217;ve been less eager to get the shot.<br><br>However, with the Delta variant now spreading across the country and infecting younger people worldwide, it&#8217;s more important than ever that they get vaccinated.<br><br>We are working with state and local leaders to reach them.&nbsp; We think it&#8217;ll take a few extra weeks to get to 70 percent of all adults with at least one shot, with the 18- to 26-years-olds factored in.<br><br>So, to recap: With respect to the first goal of getting at least one shot to 70 percent of American adults, already we&#8217;re at almost 90 percent for 65 and older, over 75 percent for 40 and older, and 70 percent for 30 and older.<br><br>We will meet the 70 percent goal for ages 27 and older by end of July 4th weekend, with a few extra weeks needed for the 18- to 26-year-olds to get vaccinated.<br><br>Now, everyone involved in this effort knows, and the President has said repeatedly: Our work does not stop on July 4th or at 70 percent.&nbsp; But we used this aspirational goal to drive progress in a very short period of time.&nbsp; It has taken a huge collective effort, and we have made significant progress.<br><br>The second aspirational goal we set was to have 160 million Americans fully vaccinated by July 4th.&nbsp; For context, only 3 million Americans were fully vaccinated when the President came into office. &nbsp;<br><br>In just five months, we&#8217;ve grown that number from 3 million to over 150 million fully vaccinated Americans.&nbsp; That represents more than 56 percent of the adult population.&nbsp; This is important progress across the country.&nbsp; And we will hit 160 million Americans fully vaccinated no later than mid-July.&nbsp;<br><br>Throughout the last five months, the President has set goals to rally the American people behind defeating this virus, with the most important and most ambitious being to celebrate our independence from the virus on July 4th &#8212; for America to look like America again.&nbsp; And thanks the President&#8217;s whole-of-government effort and the American people stepping up to do their part, we are there.&nbsp;<br><br>The virus is in retreat in communities across the country.&nbsp; We are entering a summer of joy, a summer of freedom.&nbsp; This is cause for celebration, and that&#8217;s exactly what Americans will be able to do on July 4th: celebrate independence from the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>But we&#8217;re not done, because for all the progress we&#8217;ve made as a nation, individuals who are still unvaccinated are still at risk.&nbsp; We are not leaving anyone behind in our response.&nbsp; And we will continue to put equity at the center of everything we do, to focus on helping at-risk and hard-hit communities drive up vaccination rates.&nbsp;<br><br>We want every American in every community to be protected and free from fear of the virus.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;ll keep working to vaccinate more Americans across the summer and into the fall.&nbsp; As I said, we are not stopping at 70 percent, and we&#8217;re not stopping on July 4th.&nbsp;<br><br>And as we push to get more Americans vaccinated, we&#8217;re also focused on leading the efforts to vaccinate the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a position to do so because of our success here at home and because we&#8217;ve secured enough supply &#8212; more than enough supply for all Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>In the last week alone, we have shipped millions of surplus U.S doses overseas, including to our neighbors in Mexico and Canada, as well as Taiwan.&nbsp; In total, we&#8217;ve already committed to sharing 580 million doses, and we expect to continue to commit more and more to the world over the summer months as we help lead the fight to end the pandemic across the globe.&nbsp;<br><br>Now to say more about why the progress we are making here at home matters, let me turn it over to Dr. Fauci.&nbsp;<br><br>Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Jeff.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to just spend a few minutes now recapitulating what Jeff said about where we are, where we want to be, and how we get there, and what the obstacles are.&nbsp;<br><br>And can I have the first slide.<br><br>As Jeff has said, our aspirational goal for July 4th was 70 percent of the adult population receiving at least one dose, but that is not the goal line, nor is it the endgame.&nbsp; The endgame is to go well beyond that, beyond July 4th, into the summer and beyond, with the ultimate goal of crushing the outbreak completely in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, what are one of the main obstacles for that?&nbsp; Obviously, it&#8217;s under-vaccinated people and under-vaccinated regions of the country, particularly among the young and, as Jeff said, particularly among individuals 18 to 26 &#8212; although any age of an unvaccinated person is someone we need to get vaccinated as we concentrate on the younger.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>If you take a look, for example &#8212; can I have the next slide, please.&nbsp; There are 16 states, plus the District of Columbia, have vaccinated greater than 70 percent; 4 U.S. states vaccinated less than 50.&nbsp; And so between them, you have 30 states between 50 and more than 70 percent.&nbsp; And those are the individuals that we need to concentrate on.&nbsp;<br><br>But let&#8217;s take a look at what the challenge is. &nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>If you look at the growing threat of what we&#8217;re all concerned about: the Delta variant.&nbsp; What do we know about that variant?&nbsp; The transmissibility is unquestionably greater than the wild-type SARS-CoV-2, as well as the Alpha variant.&nbsp; It is associated with an increased disease severity, as reflected by hospitalization risk, compared to Alpha.&nbsp; And in lab tests, associated with modest decreased neutralization by sera from previously infected and vaccinated individuals.&nbsp; But efficacy, as I&#8217;ll get to in a moment, is something that has held up.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>Let&#8217;s take a look at the UK, because we have followed the UK in so many respects, with regard to the B117 Alpha.&nbsp; But look at what&#8217;s happened to the UK from February to June &#8212; i.e., this month.&nbsp; The gray shading was the B117 &#8212; the Alpha.&nbsp; Look at how the Delta &#8212; in red &#8212; completely began to dominate the isolates throughout the UK, to the point where it&#8217;s well over 95 percent now.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Among whom is this taking place?&nbsp; The Imperial College of London did a study in over 100,000 homes, and looked and found that youth were driving the UK surge, with a fivefold higher positivity among children 5 to 12 and young adults 18 to 24, versus people older than 65 years old.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>Look at what&#8217;s happening in the United States.&nbsp; We seem, as was the case with B117 &#8212; we seem to be following the pattern with the Delta variant, with a doubling time of about two weeks if you look from the May 8th with 1.2, to 2.7, to 9.9, and as of a couple of days ago, 20.6 percent of the isolates are Delta.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>Here is now some of the good news and one of our tools.&nbsp; The effectiveness of the vaccines &#8212; in this case, two weeks after the second dose of Pfizer-BioNTech &#8212; was 88 percent effective against the Delta and 93 percent effective against the Alpha when you&#8217;re dealing with symptomatic disease.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>When you look at hospitalizations, again, both the Pfizer-BioNTech and the Oxford-AstraZeneca are between 92 and 96 percent effective against hospitalizations.&nbsp;<br><br>You put all of these things together, and you come to what we would call a &#8220;self-evident conclusion.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>Next and last slide.<br><br>Similar to the situation in the UK, the Delta variant is currently the greatest threat in the U.S. to our attempt to eliminate COVID-19.&nbsp; Good news: Our vaccines are effective against the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>Conclusion: We have the tools, so let&#8217;s use them and crush the outbreak.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ll hand it now over to Dr. Walensky.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; And good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp; Yesterday, CDC reported 9,816 new cases of COVID-19, and our seven-day average is about 10,350 cases per day.&nbsp; This represents a decrease of nearly 18 percent from the prior seven-day average and is the lowest seven-day average since March 25th, 2020.<br><br>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 1,790 per day, a decrease of about 14 percent from the prior seven-day period.<br><br>And the seven-day average of daily deaths have also declined to 273 per day.&nbsp;<br><br>These numbers demonstrate the extraordinary progress we&#8217;ve made against a formidable foe.&nbsp; Thanks to our vaccination programs, we are seeing a dramatic decline in deaths, hospitalization, and cases.&nbsp; And we will continue to vaccinate people across the summer months.<br><br>COVID-19 vaccines are available for everyone ages 12 and up.&nbsp; They are nearly 100 percent effective against severe disease and death, meaning nearly every death due to COVID-19 is particularly tragic because nearly every death, especially among adults, due to COVID-19 is, at this point, entirely preventable.&nbsp;<br><br>This new virus forced too many of our families to accept death as an outcome for too many of our loved ones, but now this should not be the case.&nbsp; As more Americans have rolled up their sleeves to get vaccinated, we have chipped away at the ability of the COVID-19 virus to cause more illness and more suffering.&nbsp; As I&#8217;ve often said, this virus is an opportunist.&nbsp; As long as there are those who are not vaccinated, COVID-19 will remain a threat.&nbsp;<br><br>CDC continues to follow the prevalence of the Delta variant of COVID-19, as you&#8217;ve just heard.&nbsp; In the last two weeks, the prevalence of cases resulting from the Delta variant has doubled to just over 20 percent, as Dr. Fauci just showed.<br><br>This variant represents nearly half of all infections in HHS Regions 7 and 8.&nbsp; This is concerning but expected, knowing what we do about how efficiently this variant spreads and by what we saw in the United Kingdom with this variant.&nbsp;<br><br>We know our vaccines work against this variant.&nbsp; However, this variant represents a set of mutations that could lead to future mutations that evade our vaccine.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s more important than ever to get vaccinated now, to stop the chain of infection, the chain of mutations that could lead to a more dangerous variant.&nbsp;<br><br>While not everyone with COVID-19 may require hospitalization at the time of their infection, one of the unfortunate outcomes from COVID-19 is something known as &#8220;post-COVID conditions&#8221; or &#8220;long COVID.&#8221;&nbsp; Post-COVID conditions are an umbrella term for the wide range of physical and mental health problems that occur four or more weeks after being infected with COVID-19.&nbsp; Current research suggests that up to 20 percent of people are reporting post-COVID condition symptoms, but additional research is needed and is ongoing with funding from NIH and CDC.&nbsp;<br><br>Even people who did not have symptoms when they were infected can have post-COVID conditions.&nbsp; Symptoms may vary and may include fatigue, brain fog, headache, loss of smell or taste, dizziness on standing, heart palpitations, chest pain, difficulty breathing, cough, joint or muscle pain, depression and anxiety and insomnia.&nbsp; These symptoms can persist for weeks or months after first being infected with the virus that causes COVID-19, or appear weeks after infection.&nbsp; For some people, they can be severely debilitating.&nbsp;<br><br>A recent study published in MMWR found that two out of three adults who had COVID-19 and were not hospitalized for their initial illness went on to have at least one outpatient visit for symptoms &#8212; such as chest or throat pain, shortness of breath, fatigue, and cough &#8212; one to six months after they were initially diagnosed with COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>The study also found that more than one in three patients had to be referred to a specialist, such as doctors that specialize in pulmonology, neurology, cardiology, and behavioral or mental health.&nbsp; In other words, even patients who were not hospitalized for COVID-19 infection were commonly referred for additional evaluation for COVID-19-related symptoms and conditions after their initial illness.&nbsp; We have seen post-COVID conditions in people of all ages, and this makes it even more important for anyone who is eligible to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>There are many benefits of vaccination, including preventing serious illness &#8212; illness and death, but also the kind of long-term effects associated with post-COVID conditions.&nbsp;<br><br>I invite you to visit the CDC website to review new information to help healthcare professionals in evaluating caring for patients with post-COVID conditions.&nbsp; CDC is continuing to work to identify how common these longer-term effects are, who is the most likely to get them, and whether symptoms eventually resolve.&nbsp;<br><br>Multi-year studies are also on their &#8212; underway that will help us better understand post-COVID conditions and understand how to treat patients with these longer-term effects.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, all.&nbsp; And now, I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Murthy.<br><br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Well thank you so much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; As you &#8212; Jeff laid out for us, we&#8217;ve made remarkable progress in the last six months to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; And our work isn&#8217;t done yet, especially among young adults, 18- to 29-year-olds.&nbsp; Today, I want to talk about what we&#8217;ve been doing to increase our efforts to connect with them, and to ensure that they know that they can and should get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>First, we focused on connecting directly with students in this age group through the COVID-19 College Challenge that was launched for the Month of Action.&nbsp; Colleges and Universities are now taking part in a pledge to commit to take action to get their students and communities vaccinated.&nbsp; Over 700 colleges and universities have already signed the pledge.&nbsp;<br><br>And last week, we launched this Student Community Corps, where students participate in biweekly calls to learn best practices and hear from their peers about how they can talk to friends, family members, and other community members about getting vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Second, we&#8217;ve also partnered with companies nationwide who are offering incentives for young people.&nbsp; This includes major sports leagues, which are offering discounts and ticket giveaways; Spotify, which has launched a sweepstakes giveaway for tickets to independent music venues.&nbsp; It includes stores that are now offering free items when a customer shows their vaccination cards.&nbsp; And, as of today, Walgreens is giving every person who comes in to get a vaccine between now and July 4th a $25 gift card.<br><br>Third, we also know that misinformation continues to be rampant on many online platforms that young people visit, which is why we&#8217;re meeting them there with accurate information through trusted messengers about the COVID-19 vaccine.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve launched media campaigns to reach different communities with this &#8212; within this age group, including our Digital Day of Action, which reached more than 280 million people across Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram, plus the celebrity PSAs on more than 850 radio stations.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve organized Instagram Lives with influencers and a YouTube townhall where influencers and creators are in conversation with public figures and doctors, including those of us on this press conference and President Biden.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;re also meeting gamers where they are.&nbsp; Riot Games has been airing Vaccine.gov PSAs on their E-game livestreams, and is working on other ways to connect with young people on video game platforms.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition to all of this, we are asking all young people to have conversations with friends and family members, encouraging their communities to get vaccinated and actually helping them then get to a vaccination site, which you can do more easily than ever before, given how many sites we have and how easy it is to find them at Vaccines.gov, or by texting your ZIP Code to GETVAX or to VACUNA.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, when we look back at our history as a country, it&#8217;s clear that so many of our most meaningful movements for change have been led by young people, whether it&#8217;s the Civil Rights Movement or our original fight for independence in America.&nbsp;<br><br>And this generation of young adults has shown, time and time again, their incredible energy and power to drive change.&nbsp; Today, they have the power to get vaccinated, to help their family and friends get vaccinated, and to help protect our nation.&nbsp; I believe they will rise to the challenge, and we will be there to work with them and to support them at every step of the way.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll turn it back over to Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Wonderful.&nbsp; Thank you, Doctors.&nbsp; Now let&#8217;s open it up for a few questions.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; We only have time for a few questions today.&nbsp; But first, we&#8217;re going to go to Sharon LaFraniere, New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Sorry, I had to unmute.&nbsp; So I&#8217;d like to ask what will happen this winter if there continues to be a solid 20 to 30 percent of the adults who refuse to get vaccinated?&nbsp; Could there be a renewed surge?&nbsp; Could we even get back up to like 1,000 daily deaths?&nbsp; Or are those days behind us?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; If there is a persistence of a recalcitrant group that doesn&#8217;t get vaccinated, there will be local type of regional spikes and outbreaks.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t foresee what we refer to a surge as we have known it, namely the three major surges that we&#8217;ve experienced over the past year and a half.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t think, even under those circumstances, that you&#8217;re going to see things like 1,000 deaths a day.&nbsp; I think that is a bit much.&nbsp; But there is a danger &#8212; a real danger &#8212; that if there is a persistence of a recalcitrance to getting vaccinated, that you could see localized surges, which is the reason why I want to emphasize what all four of us have said: All of that is totally and completely avoidable by getting vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the very fact that you bring up the question, which means there&#8217;s a reality that that could happen, should hopefully stimulate people to appreciate that they have, within their own wherewithal, to prevent that from happening to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; And I would just add: With 70 percent of people over 30 already with at least one dose; with 54 percent of Americans &#8212; adult Americans &#8212; fully vaccinated, we have a very strong platform to build off of.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to vaccinate millions and millions more Americans across the coming months.&nbsp;<br><br>Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Kaitlan, CNN.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; Since we&#8217;re not going to hit this goal now of 70 percent with one shot by July 4th, can you say when you do expect to hit that goal?<br><br>And then, secondly, I noticed there&#8217;s been a lot of focus on the milestones that they&#8217;ve hit so far.&nbsp; Should we expect any new goals on vaccinations going forward from the administration?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, Kaitlan, just to summarize where we are: We&#8217;re already at people ov- &#8212; 30 and over, we&#8217;re at 70 percent.&nbsp; By July 4th, we&#8217;ll be over 70 percent for 27 and over.&nbsp; And within a few weeks, we will be over 70 percent &#8212; 70 percent or over for the whole adult population.&nbsp; And then we&#8217;re going to continue to drive across the summer and into the early fall to vaccinate more and more people.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ll leave it to the President to set an additional goal.&nbsp; He&#8217;s our goal-setter, and he&#8217;s done a great job at setting aspirational and ambitious goals that have really driven our success.&nbsp;<br><br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; If I could just add one thing to this and &#8212; thinking of it as just as we do in medicine when we&#8217;re taking care of patients, you know, you pay attention to numbers &#8212; like (inaudible) values and other numbers that are important &#8212; but the most important thing at the end of the day is: How&#8217;s the patient doing?&nbsp; How are they feeling?&nbsp; What can they do?<br><br>And similarly, when we think about this effort, the most important goal that we&#8217;re focused on is: What can people in our country do as a result of this vaccination effort?&nbsp; And there, I think what&#8217;s been encouraging to me and so many of us is that we have actually exceeded where we thought we would be.&nbsp;<br><br>We thought people would be able to get together, have barbecues again if they were vaccinated.&nbsp; We are finding now, given the progress we&#8217;ve made thanks to the hard work of people all over this country, that we can not only do that, but if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you can be part of large gatherings.&nbsp; You can participate in so much more of life that we have missed out on over the last year.&nbsp;<br><br>So I think it&#8217;s just important to keep in mind that the most important metric at the end of the day is: What are we able to do in our lives?&nbsp; How much of &#8220;normal&#8221; have we been able to recapture?<br><br>And I think what we are seeing now is that we have exceeded our expectations.&nbsp; That we&#8217;ve just got to keep going because, until everybody is under that umbrella of protection, until everyone has their way of life back, we&#8217;re not going to stop in our vaccination effort.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Murthy, I couldn&#8217;t agree more. &nbsp;We are going to have a Fourth of July celebration which is beyond everyone&#8217;s highest expectations.&nbsp;<br><br>Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s got to Nancy Cordes at CBS.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; I&#8217;d love to hear from any of you about how you came up with the 70 percent goal in the first place.&nbsp; What led you to that particular number?&nbsp; And what do you think is the main thing that kept you from getting over that finish line?&nbsp; Did you assume that young people would get vaccinated in larger numbers than they have?&nbsp; That would be great.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, we did that as a team, relying very heavily or exclusively on the docs and scientists &#8212; many of whom are on this call.&nbsp;<br><br>Dr. Fauci, why don&#8217;t I turn it to you as to the 70 percent and where we are relative to Fourth of July and where we&#8217;re headed.&nbsp;<br><br>Dr. Fauci.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; As some of you may remember, when we were talking about this concept of herd immunity and I repetitively said, &#8220;We don&#8217;t know what that number is, but you can make a reasonable intelligent estimate that it&#8217;s somewhere between 70 and 85 percent.&#8221;&nbsp; Because, remember, herd immunity is a combination of individuals who are vaccinated and individuals who are protected from &#8212; because of prior infection.&nbsp;<br><br>The lower number of that was 70.&nbsp; It seemed like a reasonable number to do.&nbsp; It was empiric.&nbsp; I mean, there was no mathematical certainty to it, but I think most &#8212; not &#8220;I think&#8221; &#8212; I know that most of us agreed that that was quite a reasonable number.<br><br>You did say something that&#8217;s interesting.&nbsp; You said &#8220;reached the goal line.&#8221;&nbsp; That&#8217;s not the goal line; that&#8217;s the aspirational goal.&nbsp; The goal line is to completely crush this outbreak, and that&#8217;s the endgame that I showed on my first slide.&nbsp;<br><br>So no one should think that when we reach this 70 percent across the country that we&#8217;re done.&nbsp; We are not done until we completely crush this outbreak.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; And maybe just to emphasize the importance of the second dose.&nbsp; So, the 70 percent is the first-dose benchmark, but we also want people to get the second dose for their two-dose vaccines.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; One more question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp; Zeke, AP.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; For those four states that haven&#8217;t even reached 50 percent of their &#8212; of their adult population yet, vaccinated: Is the White House looking at a different approach to those states?&nbsp; Is there &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve heard those governors, saying they&#8217;re not &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s a personal choice for folks who are not quite &#8212; you know, is there a &#8212; should we expect to see a different strategy from you all going forward?<br><br>And then, secondly, after July 4th, a lot of these incentive programs run out.&nbsp; To Dr. Walensky&#8217;s comment that, sort of, every COVID death at this point is preventable, at a &#8212; you know, is the White House going to phase out its promotional campaign to drive people to vaccinate &#8212; vaccinations if at this point, you know, you&#8217;re throwing a lot of, you know &#8212; million &#8212; you know, the chance of winning the lottery at folks, and they&#8217;re still not getting vaccinated.&nbsp; Is that all going to go away and &#8212; if this is obviously people&#8217;s personal choices?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Zeke, this is &#8212; this intensity that you&#8217;ve witnessed across the last five months is going to continue for the foreseeable future until all Americans can get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>So we will continue to meet people where they are &#8212; mobile clinics, doctors&#8217; offices, pharmacies.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll continue to make it even easier and more convenient for people to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>People have questions about the vaccines, and we want to make sure that we&#8217;re ask- &#8212; answering those questions, addressing those questions at the local level &#8212; through doctors, through faith leaders, through trusted messengers at the local level.&nbsp;<br><br>So we&#8217;re not &#8212; we&#8217;re not slowing down at all.&nbsp; If anything, we&#8217;re speeding up, as Dr. Fauci has talked about, until we crush this disease.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to do everything we can to get as many Americans vaccinated as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>Dr. Murthy, anything to add there?<br><br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s exactly right, Jeff.&nbsp; And, Zeke, our approach and what we&#8217;ve learned over these past, you know, many months is that we have to go more and more and more local as this vaccination effort proceeds.&nbsp; It is through the one-on-one conversations, it&#8217;s through making access even easier and readily available to people that we&#8217;re going to reach more folks.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;ll continue to support states and local counties and city health officials in their effort to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to let up.&nbsp; I know July 4th has been an important deadline, but this continues long after July 4th.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going anywhere.&nbsp; That&#8217;s for sure. &nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining the briefing, and we&#8217;ll look forward to seeing you at the next one.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>1:11 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/COVID-Press-Briefing_22June2021_for-transcript.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/COVID-Press-Briefing_22June2021_for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Kamala Harris on the For the People Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/statement-by-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-the-for-the-people-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 23:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When we cast a ballot, we not only decide our leaders. We determine our future. The right to vote is fundamental. It gives Americans a voice in what happens in our nation—whether that is in our economy or our national security, our education system or our healthcare system. When more people have a voice, our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>When we cast a ballot, we not only decide our leaders. We determine our future.<br><br>The right to vote is fundamental. It gives Americans a voice in what happens in our nation—whether that is in our economy or our national security, our education system or our healthcare system. When more people have a voice, our democracy becomes more representative, and our nation becomes stronger.<br><br>Today, across our nation, we are witnessing unprecedented attacks on voting rights. There are unjust bills in dozens of state legislatures that would limit early voting and vote by mail and otherwise make it harder for the American people to vote. Make no mistake: While these attacks are meant to silence some Americans, the impact is felt by all Americans.<br><br>At this critical moment, the United States Senate had a critical opportunity to make voting more accessible nationwide. The For The People Act has the broad support of the American people. Yet, as Senate Democrats united around the legislation, this afternoon, Senate Republicans voted against advancing it.<br><br>The President and I are undeterred, and I know the American people are as well. Like generations before, we will not give up, we will not give in, and we will continue the fight to strengthen the right to vote. We will fortify and expand the nationwide coalition on voting rights, and promote voter engagement and registration nationwide. We will lift up leaders in the states who are working to stop anti-voter legislation, and work with leaders in Congress to advance federal legislation that will strengthen voting rights.<br><br>I want to be clear that our Administration remains determined to work with Congress to pass the For The People Act, and we will keep working with Congress to pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act.<br><br>Here is the bottom line: Our democracy is stronger when everyone participates—and it is weaker when people are denied meaningful access to participation. And that is why the right to vote is neither Democratic nor Republican. The right to vote is an American right.<br><br>It is our duty, at every opportunity, to protect and strengthen the right to vote.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the For the People Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-for-the-people-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 23:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21657</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Democrats in Congress unanimously came together to protect the sacred right to vote. In supporting the For the People Act and defending the rights of voters, they stood united for democracy. They stood against the ongoing assault of voter suppression that represents a Jim Crow era in the 21st Century. Unfortunately, a Democratic stand&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Democrats in Congress unanimously came together to protect the sacred right to vote.</p>



<p>In supporting the For the People Act and defending the rights of voters, they stood united for democracy. They stood against the ongoing assault of voter suppression that represents a Jim Crow era in the 21st Century.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, a Democratic stand to protect our democracy met a solid Republican wall of opposition. Senate Republicans opposed even a debate—even considering—legislation to protect the right to vote and our democracy.</p>



<p>It was the suppression of a bill to end voter suppression—another attack on voting rights that is sadly not unprecedented.</p>



<p>The creed “We Shall Overcome” is a longtime mainstay of the Civil Rights Movement. By coming together, Democrats took the next step forward in this continuous struggle—not just on Capitol Hill, but across the country—and a step forward to honor all those who came before us, people of all races and ages, who sacrificed and died to protect this sacred right.</p>



<p>I’ll&nbsp;have more to say on this next week. But let me be clear. This fight is far from over—far from over. I’ve been engaged in this work my whole career, and we are going to be ramping up our efforts to overcome again—for the people, for our very democracy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with FEMA and Emergency Preparedness Team on Extreme Weather Preparation and Response Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-fema-and-emergency-preparedness-team-on-extreme-weather-preparation-and-response-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 22:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21647</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met today with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, FEMA Acting Associate Administrator for Response and Recovery David Bibo, and other members of his emergency preparedness team to discuss FEMA’s ongoing efforts to prevent, prepare for and respond to extreme weather events, including hurricanes, tornadoes, extreme heat, and wildfires, as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met today with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, FEMA Acting Associate Administrator for Response and Recovery David Bibo, and other members of his emergency preparedness team to discuss FEMA’s ongoing efforts to prevent, prepare for and respond to extreme weather events, including hurricanes, tornadoes, extreme heat, and wildfires, as well as how to expedite delivery of support to communities in need of Federal help.</p>



<p>The President emphasized the importance of ensuring that the Federal government is prepared to respond quickly to a range of extreme weather scenarios and to support Americans when disasters strike.&nbsp;The President and his team also discussed how to enable communities across our country to build greater resilience in the face of extreme weather, which has been exacerbated by climate change.&nbsp;The President thanked FEMA and other frontline agencies for all they have done to respond to COVID-19 and help vaccinate Americans, and for their support in response to this year’s brutal winter storms and early fire season.</p>



<p>Next week, President Biden will convene Cabinet officials, Governors from Western States, and private sector partners to discuss the devastating intersection of drought, heat, and wildfires in the Western United States, and strengthening prevention, preparedness and response efforts this season.&nbsp;The 2020 wildfire season alone burned over 10 million acres across the United States, resulting in the loss of dozens of lives and tens of billions of dollars in economic damage.&nbsp;Next week’s meeting hosted by the President will focus on how departments and agencies across the Federal Government, in close coordination with State and local governments and the private sector, can most effectively enhance public safety and deliver assistance to our people in times of urgent need.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, June 22, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/22/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-june-22-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 21:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21641</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:13 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; So, I know some of you are going to have to leave for the pool call, which is absolutely fine.&#160; We will also keep you honest on when the President is getting ready to speak.&#160; So there are a couple of mechanics.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:13 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, I know some of you are going to have to leave for the pool call, which is absolutely fine.&nbsp; We will also keep you honest on when the President is getting ready to speak.&nbsp; So there are a couple of mechanics.&nbsp; Chris is going to be our special helper on this front today.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, a couple of items at the top.&nbsp; As you may have seen, today, the FAA &#8212; the Federal Aviation Administrator &#8212; Administration &#8212; announced it will award $8 billion in airport rescue grants from the American Rescue Plan to keep airport workers employed, construction projects going, provide rent relief to in-terminal concession companies, and help U.S. airports recover from the impacts of COVID-19.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks to the President&#8217;s successful vaccination program, America is on the move again.&nbsp; There are over three times more Americans traveling through airports now than at any time last year, and this funding will help airports ramp up operations, keep travelers safe, and workers employed.&nbsp; Hundreds of airports across the country will receive this funding, thanks to the American Rescue Plan, including airports in Philadelphia; Charleston, West Virginia; Anchorage, Alaska; Raleigh-Durham, North Carolina; Portland, Maine; and Portland, Oregon.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last item for the top: It&#8217;s the first official week of summer, as you all know, and the onset of peak wildfire season.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already &#8212; we&#8217;re already experiencing extreme heat in the West, several large wildland fires, and we&#8217;ve had three named Atlantic storms &#8212; including Tropical Storm Claudette, which led to the tragic loss of life in Alabama this past weekend.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It was important to the President to meet with the FEMA Administrator and members of the Emergency Preparedness team, including the Homeland Security Advisor, to discuss the federal government&#8217;s ongoing preparedness and response efforts, as well as how FEMA supports communities in need.&nbsp; Hence, that&#8217;s what he will be doing this afternoon.<br>&nbsp;<br>Josh, why don&#8217;t you kick us off.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two subject areas.&nbsp; First, with regard to voting rights, President Biden described his 2020 campaign as a battle for the soul of America. &nbsp;What does the administration think is more important for the soul: upholding the tradition of the filibuster or getting the voting rights agenda through?&nbsp; If you had to make the choice, what is that choice?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t see it through that prism, which won&#8217;t surprise you.&nbsp; I will say that, first, the President believes that expanding access to voting, making it easier for people to vote should be a fundamental right for the American public across the country.&nbsp; And it will be a fight of his presidency long past today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I will also note &#8212; since you gave me the opportunity &#8212; that this has been a fight that he has been battling through the course of his career.&nbsp; When he was in the Senate, he fought for an extension of the Voting Rights Act.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it&#8217;s something that he, of course, talked about on the campaign trail, and he will continue to use the bully pulpit but also every lever in government to continue to advocate for moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, the President is going to meet with the FEMA Administrator this afternoon.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re seeing a lot of extreme weather and climate events.&nbsp; Researchers have an event at Columbia University this week to look at moving people out of harm&#8217;s way in order to mitigate the effects of extreme weather.&nbsp; Does this administration believe that more people need to leave the areas adversely affected by climate change in order to address the issue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a really interesting question, Josh.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if they&#8217;ll be talking about that during the President&#8217;s briefing this afternoon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note that, while it&#8217;s traditional for Presidents to get briefings on hurricanes and preparedness for hurricanes, it was important to him and to our team to also get a briefing on wildfires and the impacts, and also to take steps that are &#8212; to prepare for that and the impacts on local communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Whether that means moving people from their homes &#8212; it&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll have to see what comes out of the briefing today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On COVID and missing the 70 percent deadline: As this White House sees it, what went wrong?&nbsp; What happened there?&nbsp; Was the goal too high, the number just not attainable?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t see it exactly like something went wrong.&nbsp; How we see it is: We set a bold, ambitious goal &#8212; something the President has done from the very beginning &#8212; and we are expected to meet that goal just a couple of weeks after July 4th.&nbsp; And, in fact, at this point, as of today, we&#8217;re going to be already at that point for people who are 30 years of age and older.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we also know, though &#8212; and we&#8217;ve learned this as we&#8217;ve been working to get the pandemic under control, take on this herculean task where there is no playbook &#8212; is that there are demographic groups and sometimes populations where it&#8217;s more difficult to reach.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that and we&#8217;ve talked about that as it related to &#8212; early on, to hesitancy we were seeing in communities of color or some more conservative communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve seen it&#8217;s been a great deal more difficult to get &#8212; to get young people between the ages of 18 and 26 vaccinated than adults who are older than that.&nbsp; Hence, we are redoubling our efforts to ensure we are targeting, we are focusing on, we are making the vaccine more accessible for those age groups.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, we are on &#8212; we are already meeting the goal of vaccinating with one dose 70 percent of Americans 30 years of age and older.&nbsp; And we are working toward meeting it for all adults as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just quickly, if I can follow up on voting rights here.&nbsp; Yesterday, you said that there&#8217;s more work to be done &#8212; among that is including engaging state legislatures.&nbsp; But the problems, as Democrats at least see it, is not problems in blue states &#8212; state legislatures; it&#8217;s Republican-controlled states where many of these decisions are already being made.&nbsp; So what leverage do you actually have?&nbsp; And what, realistically, do you think you can accomplish in some of these red states?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think the point we&#8217;ve been making is that it&#8217;s, in part, a federal approach that is needed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think it&#8217;s important to remember why we&#8217;re at this point: State legislatures, as you referenced, across the country are passing a wave of anti-voter laws based on the same repeatedly disproven lies that led to an assault on our nation&#8217;s Capitol.&nbsp; They are putting these laws in place because they did not like the outcome and they&#8217;ve continued to perpetuate a lie about the outcome of the election.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What the President and what the Vice President will do is engage with voting rights groups; engage with legislatures who are supportive of expanding access to voting around the country &#8212; yes, there are &#8212; even in red states, there are many Democratic legislators or legislators who want to expand that access; empower them, work with them, support them in these efforts; and continue to fight to get legislation across the finish line on the federal level.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So this fight is not over.&nbsp; No matter the outcome today, it is going to continue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, you mentioned the bully pulpit on the voting issue.&nbsp; Jamaal Bowman, a congressman, said earlier today, the President needs to be a lot more &#8220;vocal,&#8221; a lot more &#8220;out in front&#8221; on the issue.&nbsp; Do you guys believe the President has elevated this issue enough, given the seriousness that you frame it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would suggest that &#8212; that isn&#8217;t a &#8212; that is a fight &#8212; that those words are a fight against the wrong opponent.&nbsp; The President is passionate about this issue.&nbsp; He has been passionate through the course of his time in public office.&nbsp; You know, again, securing a 25-year extension of the Voting Rights Act &#8212; when, I would note, Strom Thurmond chaired the committee.&nbsp; So that was quite a time to live through.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he&#8217;s absolutely revolted by the wave of anti-voter laws based on the same repeatedly disproven lies that led to our assault &#8212; an assault on our nation&#8217;s Capitol, as I know the congressman and many others are as well.&nbsp; We share their passion.&nbsp; We share the desire to fight these efforts.&nbsp; We share the desire to fight against efforts by many Republicans to suppress the vote around the country.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean that that fight will always be easy, but he is going to stand by them in this effort.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would note that it&#8217;s not that he has &#8212; you know, it is not just about private phone calls &#8212; he&#8217;s certainly done a number of those &#8212; and private meetings &#8212; as he did with Senator Manchin yesterday to convey to him the importance to him, personally, of moving this to a debate on the floor about this important piece of legislation.&nbsp; The President has also &#8212; gave a speech in Tulsa, Oklahoma, where he gave a passionate &#8212; made a passionate case for the importance of voting rights.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also has taken action, including empowering a number of nominees at the apart- &#8212; at the Department of Justice who have been leading advocates for voting rights, pushing for their confirmation to get through.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Department of Justice also just announced a few weeks ago that they are doubling their support and their financial support for enforcement of important voting laws around the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he signed a historic executive action, just several weeks ago, that puts in place a number of protections to ensure that people have the ability to vote.&nbsp; I would say that&#8217;s hardly being silent.&nbsp; That&#8217;s hardly sitting on the backbench.&nbsp; And we are &#8212; he will be standing with advocates in this fight for the foreseeable future.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; This White House is very good at setting ambitious but achievable goals.&nbsp; Did the White House believe that 70 percent was achievable when you set it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, there&#8217;s no record &#8212; there&#8217;s no playbook for this.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no record to look back and say, &#8220;These were the &#8212; these were the goals that were achieved 5 years ago or 10 years ago,&#8221; because we&#8217;re dealing with a historic pandemic.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s view is that we should set bold, ambitious goals and do everything we pas- &#8212; possibly can to achieve them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And in our view, we have &#8212; part of our objective was to return the country to normal, for people to enjoy backyard barbecues, which people across the country &#8212; millions of people will be.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have 1,000 people on the South Lawn here at the White House &#8212; frontline workers, men and women who are serving &#8212; also enjoying life back to normal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we also are honest about where we need to continue to redouble our efforts.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s among people who are 18 to 26.&nbsp; That is a small &#8212; relatively small demographic of the country, but one where there needs to be continued work.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to use every tool at our disposal to push for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what is the game plan for getting young people vaccinated in greater numbers?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me give you a couple of examples of what we&#8217;re working on.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just Dr. Fauci on TikTok, though that is happening.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, Dr. Fauci has done several Q&amp;As with TikTok and Instagram influencers to answer questions, to meet people where they are, including young people, give them information they need.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>CDC&#8217;s COVID Vaccine Chat on WhatsApp is now live to help Spanish-speaking young adults get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re working with the private sector as well.&nbsp; As you all know, Microsoft is giving away Xboxes at Boys &amp; Girls Clubs.&nbsp; The College Challenge is rallying university students across the country.&nbsp; Walgreens is giving out $25 to anyone who gets vaccinated there before July 4th.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These are just a couple of examples of some of the approaches we&#8217;re taking.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll build on that from there.&nbsp; What we&#8217;ve all &#8212; what we&#8217;ll also note is that we&#8217;re seeing the same challenges that we&#8217;ve seen in other groups, which is that access and making it as easy as possible is the name of the game.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, continuing to re- &#8212; to support our pharmacy program, to support our mobile vaccination units, to make this &#8212; the vaccine as accessible to young people.&nbsp; They lead busy lives; we want this to be just a &#8212; just a box they can check on their weekend to-do list.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up on Phil&#8217;s question.&nbsp; You very ably went through the President&#8217;s history on voting rights and related issues, and you&#8217;ve laid out all the times he&#8217;s spoken about it. But this lectern is available to him today.&nbsp; We have not heard him talk about it.&nbsp; He has the biggest megaphone in the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Aside from the Tulsa speech, just a few weeks ago?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m talking about when the vote is happening &#8212; using the President&#8217;s time.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, clearly, the President is choosing not to do that now.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Where is the President on this issue on a day when they&#8217;re voting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, that the President has spoke &#8212; spoken passionately about his commitment to expanding access to voting rights a number of times, and you will hear him speak about this again.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You certainly will hear us.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll put out a statement from him at the conclusion of the vote today.&nbsp; And I expect you&#8217;ll hear from &#8212; more from him in the coming days as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On another subject, with COVID: Former FDA Commissioner Scott Gottlieb is among the voices saying he&#8217;s concerned that children who are not yet eligible to be vaccinated could be drivers of the variant, especially with school coming back and camps and all of that.&nbsp; What specifically does the administration feel needs to be done to address that issue for those not yet even eligible to be vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, as a parent of a couple kids myself who are not yet eligible to be vaccinated, I think the challenge is we need to be vigilant and abide by the CDC guidelines.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not always easy to do, and we know that.&nbsp; And that means, you know, being mindful of social distancing, being mindful of where mask wearing should be essential to keep your kids protected and keep other kids protected.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Certainly, we can&#8217;t expedite the work of the FDA.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the gold standard in science, and we want them to abide by whatever timeline works for them.&nbsp; But it does mean &#8212; which again, is challenging &#8212; abiding by the guidelines for children and those who are not yet eligible until we get to that point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You said, yesterday, the President feels a lot &#8212; a great deal of the crime we&#8217;re seeing is a result of gun violence, but the stats show it&#8217;s not just gun crimes.&nbsp; So why does the President think there&#8217;s been a 30 percent increase in car thefts in D.C., 47 percent increase in robbery in New York City, or a 98 percent increase in rapes in Atlanta?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think, if you look at a number of cities across the country, it is actually driven by gun violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>Take St. Louis: In 2021, 96 percent of homicides where the instrument is known were committed using a firearm.&nbsp; In New York City, from March 2020 to March 2021, shooting incidents have jumped 77 percent.&nbsp; The city recorded more than 1,500 shootings in 2020; 97 percent more than 777 in 2019.&nbsp; There are major cities across the country where gun violence is absolutely the driver, where it is absolutely increasing.&nbsp; And that will be a central part of what he&#8217;ll talk about when he delivers his remarks tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And given everything that is going on &#8212; with guns, without guns &#8212; does the President still think that this is the best time to end cash bail?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think I have a &#8212; any new position on that for you, but I&#8217;m happy to check and see if there&#8217;s anything more to report.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So his stated position from his website, which is, basically, end cash bail &#8212; he wants to lead a national effort to end cash bail and reform the pretrial system.&nbsp; That stands?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a new position for you, but I&#8217;m happy to check for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, for people who are watching who might be worried about a rise in crime, what does the President think is a deterrent to committing a crime if there&#8217;s no cash bail in place?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me give you just a sense to the degree I can, because we&#8217;re still finalizing the specifics.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s been, one, an increase in violent crime over the last 18 months; it&#8217;s not just over the last few months.&nbsp; And actually, if you look statistically back, it&#8217;s more over the last five years or so.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So there&#8217;s an initial set of actions the President has announced to date to address gun violence.&nbsp; Back in April, strengthening regulations on ghost guns; stabilizing braces that make firearms more legal [sic] &#8212; lethal; investing money in community violence intervention programs &#8212; an investment that he thinks can be quite effective.&nbsp; He&#8217;s talked about, for decades &#8212; and I think you&#8217;ll hear him talk about more tomorrow &#8212; supporting additional funding for community policing through his budget request, and helping state and local governments keep co- &#8212; cops on the beat.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, yes, we believe that a central driver of violence is gun violence and is the use of guns.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing that statistically in a lot of areas.&nbsp; But he also believes that we need to ensure that state and local governments keep cops on the beat, that we&#8217;re supporting community policing, and that&#8217;s a key part of it as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just the last one.&nbsp; You just said, again, you guys want to &#8220;keep cops on the beat,&#8221; but there are reports that big cities are having a very difficult time recruiting officers right now.&nbsp; And there are many other reports that morale is at an all-time low in big police departments.&nbsp; So why does the President think that there&#8217;s low morale with police officers on the beat?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re the right entity to give an assessment of that.&nbsp; I&#8217;d certainly look to the police departments to give that assessment.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I would say to you is that the President has never supported defunding the police.&nbsp; He&#8217;s always supported community policing programs.&nbsp; He&#8217;s supported giving funding to &#8212; to states and localities around the country, including through his American Rescue Plan, because he thinks there is an essential role to play for community policing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Andrea.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I want to ask you about infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, there was the meeting earlier today.&nbsp; Can you give us a little &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s still going on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s still going on.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As far as I know.&nbsp; When I came out here, yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And are you hopeful that you&#8217;ll be able to invite those senators to the White House for a meeting with the President?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will see.&nbsp; As we do every day in democracy in action happening here, we assess what the right next step is.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as I noted yesterday, the President is encouraged by the ongoing talks and discussions that are continuing with Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve sent some &#8212; he&#8217;s asked some members of his senior team &#8212; as you noted, Steve Ricchetti, Louisa Terrell &#8212; to go up to Capitol Hill and meet with a group of bipartisan senators.&nbsp; And once they conclude that meeting, I expect we&#8217;ll assess what the next steps are.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;re getting a lot of criticism already about the paring down of the very ambitious infrastructure proposals.&nbsp; Things that are falling away are things that you&#8217;ve said are top priorities, whether it&#8217;s climate, the care economy.&nbsp; I mean, how do you &#8212; how do you anticipate dealing with and solving those priorities, spending issues, if you get to a compromise now that is, in fact, a slimmed down version of what you initially planned?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s a budget reconciliation process that&#8217;s just getting underway, which we expect to be a vehicle to move a number of the President&#8217;s bold ideas forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you a question about Amazon as well?&nbsp; So the FTC is going to look at the Amazon-MGM merger.&nbsp; There&#8217;s growing criticism about the antitrust legislation that&#8217;s being put forth on the Hill.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Are you &#8212; what is your perspective about whether there is, sort of, fundamental reform needed to ensure that large companies don&#8217;t get too big?&nbsp; Do you see this as, sort of, an inflection point?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve seen companies, including Amazon, really profit enormously from the pandemic and during the pandemic, and there have been warnings even from international financial institutions.&nbsp; So do you see that there&#8217;s something sort of fundamental needed now to check the growth?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m going to be in a position to speak to it from here.&nbsp; There are legal components of this.&nbsp; I can see if there&#8217;s more we can &#8212; we can give back to you on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on the Amazon FTC review: Do you &#8212; can you just confirm any details of that review?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going be able to confirm or speak to that specifically from here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President&#8217;s remarks tomorrow, just to follow up on policing and crime &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; will that detail any efforts on police reform?&nbsp; Or is that kind of unilaterally focused on crime prevention?&nbsp; And why or why not?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, there&#8217;s ongoing negotiations, as you know, on police reform.&nbsp; And the President would love to have a bill on his desk that he could sign into law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve seen progress being made, we&#8217;ve heard progress being made, and those discussions are ongoing.&nbsp; So I would expect that his &#8212; his remarks tomorrow will build on &#8212; will build on a number of the announcements that have already touched on that he&#8217;s made in the recent months, making guns &#8212; putting in place safety measures to make our streets safer, preventing the use of guns in violent crime across the country, ensuring that we can have more cops on the beat to protect communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He, obviously, is a big advocate for the benefit of community policing so we&#8217;ll build on that foundation and lay out a comprehensive strategy to address violent crime and gun violence as the &#8212; as we enter the summer months.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some advocates &#8212; criminal justice advocates have raised concern that potentially having the President raise alarm about, you know, a trend of rising crime &#8212; this crime uptick in American cities &#8212; could actually undercut efforts on police reform, especially since legislation is still being discussed, you know, in Congress.&nbsp; So is that a concern for the White House at all?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The White House has said that, you know, the administration wants to give members of Congress space to negotiate police reform, but that potentially raising alarm of this crime uptick could hurt those efforts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that the negotiations are happening between Senator Booker, Senator Scott, key &#8212; Congressman Bass.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think they&#8217;ve expressed that particular concern.&nbsp; If there&#8217;s a named person who is expressing this concern, I&#8217;m happy to speak to that.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s &#8212; those negotiations are ongoing.&nbsp; We keep them abreast of our work.<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, I think, in communities across the country who advocate and support police reform, they don&#8217;t see it as a mutually exclusive issue; neither does the President.&nbsp; We need &#8212; police reform is long outdated.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s also important to take steps to &#8212; to put in place gun safety measures, to take any &#8212; use at any lever he can as President to do exactly that, and to ensure there is appropriate funding and resources needed to ensure there&#8217;s community policing in communities across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more on FEMA &#8212; the FEMA meeting.&nbsp; Given that meeting happened today, FEMA is still involved in setting up shelters at the border.&nbsp; Since we&#8217;re going into hurricane season, as you said, is there a deadline on when FEMA will be pulled out of that process of assisting at the border?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to assess for FEMA.&nbsp; Obviously, they&#8217;ll make that assessment in coordination with the leadership at the Department of Homeland Security, but I don’t have anything to preview on the timeline for that.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been a key resource.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. &nbsp;Going back to the 70 percent goal, the CDC data says that there are 13 states that are falling way short of that 70 percent; they&#8217;re less than 55 percent.&nbsp; Four states are below 50 percent.&nbsp; Should those states get more of a focus right now and not the nationwide number, as the administration plans their strategy to get vaccinations up?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; we&#8217;re not not focusing on those states.&nbsp; I would say that, one, it&#8217;s important to note that when we give the statistics &#8212; including 87 percent of all seniors, 75 percent of people age 40 and over, 70 percent of those age 30 and over &#8212; they&#8217;re from red states and blue states and purple states, or whatever color the state may be.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our focus, from the beginning, has been continuing to redouble our efforts among demographics and groups where we need extra assistance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have taken steps to put in place 24-hour pharmacies, walk-up sites, mobile clinics, free rides.&nbsp; We have vaccines at barber shops, baseball games, NASCAR races.&nbsp; Even over the last &#8220;Month of Action,&#8221; which we&#8217;ve been doing across the country, we&#8217;ve had 15,000 events.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve attempted 1.4 million contacts or reached about 500,000 people.&nbsp; And there are thousands of volunteers in 50 states across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Ultimately, it&#8217;s going to be up to individuals to decide if they want to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there something more, though?&nbsp; You went through all of those incentives, and specifically tying those to that age group &#8212; that younger age group.&nbsp; But if there&#8217;s something that&#8217;s regional about this &#8212; if it&#8217;s Alabama, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Wyoming that are those states below 50 percent, is there something that the administration can do to get those numbers up?&nbsp; Or at this point, is this governors and states that should be doing this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s always been a partnership, and it will continue to be a partnership moving forward.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s also up to individuals to make the decision to get vaccinated.&nbsp; And what we can do from the federal government, of course, is to make it as accessible as possible; make sure we have the supply &#8212; we&#8217;ve done that long ago; make sure there are thousands and thousands of sites, vaccinators, opportunities for people to get vaccinated; incentivize it across the country. &nbsp;That&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;ve done.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note: We&#8217;re not going to stop implementing these programs on July 5th.&nbsp; We will continue to implement them as we work to get more people in the country vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, April.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I want to hit two topics: voting rights, as well as crime.<br>&nbsp;<br>You keep bringing up former President George W. Bush, in 2006, when he &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I do?&nbsp; I keep bringing him up?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you bought him up &#8212; you brought the extension up.&nbsp; You brought the extension up of voting rights, and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What &#8212; I think that happened long before (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;&nbsp; Right, but you brought it up as to &#8212; it was extended for 25 years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t bring up George W. Bush, but, go ahead, you can bring him up.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, I&#8217;m bringing him up.<br>&nbsp;<br>As someone who was here when he did it &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; he was a Republican who did it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s one of his pieces that he likes to tout when he talks about efforts in the Black community.&nbsp; What&#8217;s different with Republicans then and Republicans now when it comes to voting rights?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What&#8217;s different?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, April, what &#8212; what should raise some questions for Americans across the country is: Why would anyone want to make it more difficult to vote?&nbsp; Why wouldn&#8217;t we want to make it more accessible?&nbsp; What are they so afraid of?&nbsp; And maybe they&#8217;re more afraid now of what it would mean to have more people voting across the country than they were back then.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll have to ask them that question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, secondly, on crime: What&#8217;s different now as you&#8217;re trying to push this effort on community policing, as well as guns?&nbsp; What&#8217;s different now?&nbsp; What do you think will have the teeth to change the tide that hasn&#8217;t been changed before?&nbsp; In the coming years (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Different now &#8212; do you mean different from a different period of time &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; or different from &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, you know, community policing was in place during the Clinton years; it was taken away.&nbsp; There was conversation about it in many years prior.&nbsp; And now, you&#8217;re bringing it back again.&nbsp; So you’re bringing the issue back again.&nbsp; What teeth do you believe that will have?&nbsp; And do you believe that that could become a reality again?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, I understand different police departments can do what they want.&nbsp; But you’re trying to make an overall sweeping push for police departments across the nation to make this difference.&nbsp; What’s different now that will make this tide change?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say one difference now is that it&#8217;s become a politically charged issue, when it wasn&#8217;t historically.&nbsp; And if you look back, Community Oriented Policing Services, you know, historically had been supported by liberal Democrats; Democrats; civil rights groups, including the NAACP, and &#8212; over the course of time.&nbsp; And that has always been the case.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say we&#8217;re not suggesting &#8212; the President isn&#8217;t suggesting it&#8217;s the silver bullet.&nbsp; A central part of his remarks and his &#8212; his announcement tomorrow will be about addressing gun violence, which he thinks is a significant driver in violence in our communities and cities across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, as you know, April, there are laws that were in place: the Assault Weapons Ban, others that are no longer in place.&nbsp; There are also additional guns &#8212; ghost guns and others that were not a reality just a few years ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are some laws he&#8217;d like to go back to and some that he&#8217;ll continue to work to update.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, again, what&#8217;s different now?&nbsp; I mean, you&#8217;ve got the powerful NRA.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got Republicans who &#8212; anytime you touch anything about guns, they feel like you&#8217;re taking their rights away.&nbsp; What&#8217;s different now?&nbsp; Where do you think the tide will turn on this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Are you asking me about, like, the politics of now or the &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The politics and, you know, this moment in time.&nbsp; Why do you believe that you have a chance to make a dent when you didn&#8217;t &#8212; when Democrats didn&#8217;t have to do &#8212; have it before?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would just say here&#8217;s how the President sees this: There&#8217;s been rising crime in cities for the last 18 months, if not before that.&nbsp; Yes, there needs to be reforms of police systems across the country; the President is a firm believer in that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But there are also steps he can take, as President of the United States, to help address and hopefully reduce that crime.&nbsp; A big part of that, in his view, is putting in place gun safety measures, using &#8212; even as Congress is not moving forward currently &#8212; using the bully pulpit, but also using levers at his disposal as President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess I’ll take another shot &#8212; stab at that, to use a phrase.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; What&#8217;s different for Joe Biden?&nbsp; Thirty years ago, he was chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, wrote a crime bill, addressed this issue.&nbsp; What has he learned since then?&nbsp; And what can we look, tomorrow, that might be the same or different?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, on the campaign: The President said that some parts of the bill worked and some areas did not work.&nbsp; There are also steps he took as senator when he introduced or supported legislation, I should say, to address the disparities in gun senten- &#8212; in drug sentencing laws.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s taken some specific actions over time in areas where he don&#8217;t &#8212;&nbsp; doesn&#8217;t think worked as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are some components of that legislation he supported at the time, including the 10-year ban on assault weapons; including the support for &#8212; for the Violence Against Women Act; and including the support for community policing programs that he has been a longtime advocate for.&nbsp; And I think you will see continuity in terms of his support for those initiatives moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said that he aims to build on the announcements he&#8217;s made.&nbsp; Is there anything we can expect to hear tomorrow that we haven&#8217;t heard before?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Stay tuned.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t tell you everything, otherwise you won&#8217;t come tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the President&#8217;s meeting with the chairman of the Federal Reserve yesterday: Did the President bring up interest rates or express his view on the direction of interest rates at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As you well know, that is the purview of the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve put out their own projections, as you know, about what it looks like moving forward.&nbsp; The topic and the focus of the meeting was exactly as it was outlined in our &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he did not bring up interest rates at all?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just have no more to read out for you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on the infrastructure negotiations, do you know &#8212; has White House put anything new on the table as far as payfors?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say we&#8217;ve put a lot of different options on payfors on the table.&nbsp; And our view is there&#8217;s a fundamental question right now: Are &#8212; are Dem- &#8212; are Republicans, members of Congress, do they believe that rich people should have to pay the taxes they owe?&nbsp; Or should we increase the cost of travelers who are just trying to make it to work?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s the basic question here.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll see if they can make progress on that exact point.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say who the stakeholders will &#8212; who will be at the White House tomorrow for this crime meeting?&nbsp; Can you say who&#8217;s coming?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The announcement tomorrow?&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have it in front of me, but we can venture to get it to you after the briefing.&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And this is sort of a pullback question, but why now exactly?&nbsp; Is it just because crime rates are up and the stats are out?&nbsp; Or why is this the week, of all the weeks, that the President has decided to focus on crime?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First, I would say that he&#8217;s made a number of announcements over the past several months on gun violence, on putting in place gun safety measures.&nbsp; He&#8217;s made &#8212; announced in his budget his support for community policing and providing funding.&nbsp; Maybe we haven&#8217;t drawn that clear through-line for all of you, but this is a continuation of that, in his view.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Labeling it a speech about crime is certainly different than a speech about gun safety or it &#8212; this is &#8212; this is a different focus.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A central part of it will be on gun violence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m just going to continue this &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; crime spree, if you will.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A lot of analogies here that might be threatening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My colleague, Zolan, had brought up that there are activists who are very concerned that the President&#8217;s decision to highlight crime right now could undercut some of the negotiations on the Hill for police reform.&nbsp; You&#8217;d asked for the names of some of them.&nbsp; The Tampa Dream Defenders is one, the Justice Action Network is another &#8212; just so we, sort of, have that covered.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But can you address how the President is going to sort of walk that line between expressing his concern about crime without undercutting these efforts that, as you point out, have been under- &#8212; you know, have been underway for a while.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, what I was trying to get at &#8212; but thanks for bringing up the question again &#8212; is that there are negotiators that are continuing to make progress on the Hill.&nbsp; And the President supports and stands by a lot of these groups in their support and advocacy for long-overdue police reform.&nbsp; He believes that, supports it, wants to sign a bill into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>He does not feel that they are conflicting.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think you&#8217;ve heard from any of the negotiators on the Hill that they feel they are conflicting either.&nbsp; So that was the point I was trying to make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And communities across the country where they are seeing &#8212; if you&#8217;re living in St. Louis and 96 percent of homicides were done where &#8212; we know the instrument &#8212; were done using a firearm, you do want to hear more about what the President of the United States is going to do to address that.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re living in New York City, you do want to hear more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And nationwide, you know, Everytown put out some information that there were 30 &#8212; more &#8212; 30 &#8212; 3,900 additional firearm deaths and 9,278 additional firearm injuries in 2020 compared to 2019.&nbsp; That&#8217;s impacting people&#8217;s lives, people&#8217;s communities, people&#8217;s families, people&#8217;s neighbors.&nbsp; Of course they want to hear more, and he wants to share more with the American public about what he&#8217;s going to do about it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just on COVID: Just given that, you know, the country did not reach this goal of 70 percent of adults being &#8212; getting one shot, is there anything that the country cannot do?&nbsp; Is there any sort of &#8212; I mean, that was always the, sort of, benchmark for getting back to normalcy.&nbsp; And since we didn&#8217;t get there, are there things that the country cannot do because we haven&#8217;t actually achieved the goal that we were supposed to?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say it&#8217;s a goal we, here, set in the White House.&nbsp; I’m &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything you’d recommend the country not do, given that the goal was not reached?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this was always going to be community to community, right?&nbsp; When the President set this goal back in March, it was always meant to be a incentive and a driver for people to see what the benefit would be of getting vaccinated.&nbsp; And at the time, what the President said is, “If you are vaccinated, your neighbors are vaccinated, you can all have a backyard barbecue.”&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing that times about 100 by hosting 1,000 people here at the White House.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, if you&#8217;re in a community where you&#8217;re at 80 percent vaccination rate, my bet is the community is pretty closely back to normal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If you&#8217;re not in a com- &#8212; if you&#8217;re a community with a much lower vaccination rate, obviously, you&#8217;re going to make your own choices, but you&#8217;re not operating in a community where it should be back to normal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it&#8217;s always going &#8212; was always going to be local, was always going to be based on what the decisions are made, community to community &#8212; but not nationwide, no.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really dependent on where you&#8217;re living.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, because the President is in Washington, D.C., and they have got &#8212; we have got &#8212; Washington, D.C., has gone beyond their 70 percent goal, it&#8217;s okay to do (inaudible).&nbsp; It&#8217;s okay to have 1,000 people in Washington, D.C., at an event because Washington, D.C., has surpassed the 70 percent, but somewhere where it&#8217;s a 50 percent vaccination rate perhaps &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Communities are going to make their own decision.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing ever magical through science about 70 percent.&nbsp; 70 percent was a bold, ambitious goal we set to continue to drive to get more people vaccinated across the country.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not as if, if you&#8217;re 67 percent in a community, you&#8217;re at a different level of safety than 71 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>Communities are going to make their own decisions.&nbsp; And I think, at &#8212; a fundamental fact is that if you&#8217;re vaccinated, if your neighbors are vaccinated, then you&#8217;re safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; One quick &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I&#8217;m going to (inaudible) here.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Chris.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thanks.&nbsp; Can you respond to &#8212; at least a couple Republican senators and one today said that &#8212; want to have talked about signing on to this bipartisan talks right now on the Jobs Plan, that that would essentially stop momentum or stop you guys from being able to do reconciliation.&nbsp; Can you respond to that idea that they&#8217;re basically cooperating so that you can&#8217;t do the second half of your plan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s how the process works, fundamentally.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it will not stop the White House from enacting and Democrats from &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, if you just &#8212; if we just go to our episode of “How a Bill Becomes a Law,” there&#8217;s a budget reconciliation process led by the budget chairman; it&#8217;s proceeding.&nbsp; It needs a certain number of votes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s different from the number of votes that are needed for other pieces of legislation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That piece of legislat- &#8212; the budget reconciliation process is proceeding.&nbsp; There&#8217;ll be discussions.&nbsp; There may even be disagreements among people within the Democratic Party about what should be included in there or not.&nbsp; There needs to be 50 votes to move that forward.&nbsp; But that process is continuing and proceeding.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But stopping the momentum for it, as well as taking the amount of time that these talks are taking that it &#8212; realistically, that it could gum up the works to get this &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; How would it gum up the works?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, this is their &#8212; this is their plan, their hope of a strategy.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sounds like they have some more explaining to do about what they mean.&nbsp; Or maybe they need to go to “How a Bill Becomes a Law,” &#8220;How Reconciliation Works.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;ll suggest that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Senator Sanders could &#8212; he could come to the Republican caucus and teach them.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll offer him.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One on foreign affairs, please?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, we have to wrap it up because I think the President is about to speak.&nbsp; But thanks so much everyone.&nbsp; Sorry it was a little short today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>1:48 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before a Meeting with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell and Homeland Security Advisor and Deputy National Security Advisor Dr. Elizabeth Sherwood-Randall</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/22/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-meeting-with-fema-administrator-deanne-criswell-and-homeland-security-advisor-and-deputy-national-security-advisor-dr-elizabeth-sherwood-randall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 21:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 2:06 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, our FEMA Director &#8212; Administrator is here today.&#160; We&#8217;re going to talk about was the sever- &#8212; severe weather patterns we&#8217;re facing which keeps &#8212; likely increase every year.&#160; And I want to make sure that we&#8217;re in a position to be able to help Americans all across&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>2:06 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, our FEMA Director &#8212; Administrator is here today.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to talk about was the sever- &#8212; severe weather patterns we&#8217;re facing which keeps &#8212; likely increase every year.&nbsp; And I want to make sure that we&#8217;re in a position to be able to help Americans all across the country and in all our jurisdictions as these severe weather incidents increase.<br>&nbsp;<br>The last few days alone, we&#8217;ve seen droughts and wildfires in the West, and we&#8217;ve seen tornadoes in Illinois, flooding in the South and the Mid-Atlantic.&nbsp; And extreme weather doesn&#8217;t confine itself, as you all know, to state lines.&nbsp; These crises require proactive federal responses.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just not just the states responding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I know that &#8212; that your team, Administrator, is going to raise &#8212; be faced with a lot of challenges this year, more than most.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not that you&#8217;re not used to it, but it&#8217;s going to &#8212; this time, it&#8217;s the whole country.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve already stepped up this year to help vaccinate the American people and respond to the (inaudible), but now we have to respond to these brutal storms &#8212; and more severe storms and fires that extend into longer seasons throughout the year.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to bring every resource to bear to be prepared to respond and to help people recover, but it&#8217;s a big job.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;re making sure FEMA and other frontline agencies have what they need to continue getting the job done.&nbsp; And I insist on being ready for whatever comes our way.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what this is all about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re here today about.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll be hosting a meeting next week with Western governors and FEMA and the Cabinet members to prepare for heat, drought, and wildfires in the West.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I want to thank everybody for being here today.&nbsp; And let me just say one other thing.&nbsp; You know, I was talking with my staff a moment ago in the office about wildfires.&nbsp; And &#8212; and, you know, the thing I know a little bit about is the fire service.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there&#8217;s an old expression: God made man, and then he made a few firefighters.&nbsp; They are &#8212; they have the higher incidence of severe injuries than police officers do.&nbsp; They are incredibly, incredibly brave, what they do: They run to the fire.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I just realized &#8212; I didn&#8217;t realize this, I have to admit &#8212; that federal firefighters get paid $13 an hour.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to end in my administration.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a ridiculously low salary to pay federal firefighters.&nbsp; Not that many federal firefighters, but &#8212; and they &#8212; and I know you use all the resources, including state and local firefighters.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, any rate, that&#8217;s we&#8217;re going to talk about today.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be brought up to date on what we can expect this season.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And many of you have covered what&#8217;s already happened.&nbsp; And the droughts in the West is just astounding, when you take a look at it.&nbsp; Fires have already started, and flooding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re in for a tough season, but I think we&#8217;ve got to be prepared and have every resource available to make sure we&#8217;re there for the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you all so very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, on voting rights, is this end?&nbsp; Is it over?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>2:10 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Three Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/president-biden-announces-three-key-nominations-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 20:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles: David Uhlmann, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Enforcement and Compliance Assurance, Environmental Protection Agency Celeste Wallander, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Security Affairs, Department of Defense David Prouty, Nominee for Member of the National&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following three individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>David Uhlmann, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Enforcement and Compliance Assurance, Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Celeste Wallander, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Security Affairs, Department of Defense</li><li>David Prouty, Nominee for Member of the National Labor Relations Board</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>David Uhlmann, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Enforcement and Compliance Assurance, Environmental Protection Agency</u></strong></p>



<p>David M. Uhlmann is an internationally recognized expert on environmental law, leading authority on criminal enforcement of the environmental laws in the United States, and highly-regarded advocate for environmental stewardship and corporate sustainability programs. He is currently the Jeffrey F. Liss Professor from Practice and the director of the Environmental Law and Policy Program at the University of Michigan Law School. Professor Uhlmann previously served for 17 years as a federal prosecutor, including seven years as the Chief of the Environmental Crimes Section at the United States Department of Justice. In that role, he led prosecution of environmental and wildlife crimes nationwide, coordinated national legislative, policy, and training initiatives regarding criminal enforcement, and chaired the Justice Department&#8217;s Environmental Crimes Policy Committee. He earned a reputation for prosecuting polluters aggressively and fairly, presided over expansion of the environmental crimes program, and strengthened relationships with the Environmental Protection Agency, the Coast Guard, and other law enforcement partners. His work as lead prosecutor in <em>United States v. Elias</em>, a tragic knowing endangerment case that left a 20-year-old worker severely and permanently brain-damaged, is chronicled in <em>The Cyanide Canary</em>. He received numerous Justice Department and EPA awards for his precedent-setting prosecutions, including the first environmental justice criminal trial.</p>



<p>Professor Uhlmann is a fellow in the American College of Environmental Lawyers, which invited him to join their Board of Regents earlier this year. Professor Uhlmann was named a “Conservation Hero” by the Michigan League of Conservation Voters and selected by the University of Michigan to be a Distinguished Faculty Fellow in Sustainability. Professor&nbsp;Uhlmann received a J.D. from Yale Law School and a B.A. in history and political science with high honors from Swarthmore College. Following law school, he clerked for U.S. District Court Judge Marvin H. Shoob in Atlanta, Georgia. He is married to Virginia Murphy, a professor in the Residential College at the University of Michigan. They have three adult children and two grandchildren, all of whom love hiking in the northern Maine woods.</p>



<p><strong><u>Celeste Wallander, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for International Security Affairs, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Celeste Wallander is President and CEO of the U.S.-Russia Foundation. She served as Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Russia/Central Asia on the National Security Council (2013-2017), as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Russia/Ukraine/Eurasia (2009 to July 2012), professor at American University (2009-2013), visiting professor at Georgetown University (2006-2008), Director for Russia/Eurasia at the Center for Strategic and International Studies (2001-2006), Senior Fellow at the Council on Foreign Relations (2000- 2001), and professor of Government at Harvard (1989-2000).&nbsp; She is the author of over 80 publications on European and Eurasian security issues, focused on Russian foreign and defense strategy. She received her Ph.D. (1990), M.Phil. (1986) and M.A. (1985) degrees from Yale University, and her B.A. (1983 – summa cum laude) from Northwestern University.&nbsp; She is a member of the Council on Foreign Relations, the Atlantic Council of the United States, and the International Institute for Strategic Studies.</p>



<p><strong><u>David Prouty, Nominee for Member of the National Labor Relations Board</u></strong></p>



<p>David Prouty is General Counsel of Service Employee International Union (SEIU) Local 32BJ, the largest labor union for property service workers in the country with over 175,000 members. He served as General Counsel of the Major League Baseball Players Association (MLBPA) from 2013 – 2017 and as Chief Labor Counsel of the MLBPA from 2008 – 2013. Prior to June 2008, Mr. Prouty was General Counsel of UNITE HERE, the union formed by the 2004 merger of UNITE (the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees) with HERE (the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees International Union), and was General Counsel of UNITE from 2001 &#8211; 2004. Before serving as General Counsel of UNITE and UNITE HERE, Mr. Prouty was Southern Regional Counsel for UNITE and its predecessor union, the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU), for fifteen years and litigated many of the union’s landmark organizing cases including <em>Fieldcrest Cannon, S. Lichtenberg, Tultex </em>and<em> Kmart</em>.  He is a Fellow of the College of Labor and Employment Lawyers; was the Union Co-Chair of the American Bar Association’s Committee on Practice and Procedure Under the National Labor Relations Act from 2007 – 2010; was a member of the National Labor Relations Board’s Union Advisory Panel from 1997 to 1998; and is a member of the Peggy Browning Fund’s Advisory Board. Mr. Prouty graduated from Walter Johnson High School in Bethesda, Maryland in 1976; received his AB <em>magna cum laude</em> from Bowdoin College in Brunswick, Maine in 1980; worked as a researcher and organizer for the American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME) from 1980 to 1983; and received his JD <em>cum laude</em> from Harvard Law School in 1986.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/22/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 18:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21615</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION&#160;SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Carlton Waterhouse, of Virginia, to be Assistant Administrator, Office of Solid Waste, Environmental Protection Agency, vice Peter C. Wright. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION&nbsp;SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Carlton Waterhouse, of Virginia, to be Assistant Administrator, Office of Solid Waste, Environmental Protection Agency, vice Peter C. Wright.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Roundtable with LGBTQ+ Advocates on the Equality Act and Achieving Full Equality for LGBTQ+ Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/21/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-lgbtq-advocates-on-the-equality-act-and-achieving-full-equality-for-lgbtq-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 01:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond, and Executive Director of the Gender Policy Council Jen Klein hosted a roundtable in the Roosevelt Room with LGBTQ+ leaders who are coordinating the national movement to pass the Equality Act. Advocates shared their perspectives on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond, and Executive Director of the Gender Policy Council Jen Klein hosted a roundtable in the Roosevelt Room with LGBTQ+ leaders who are coordinating the national movement to pass the Equality Act. Advocates shared their perspectives on the urgency and importance of Congress extending long overdue civil rights protections to LGBTQ+ Americans by passing the Equality Act and shared the efforts their organizations are undertaking to get the bill to the President’s desk.</p>



<p>During the meeting, LGBTQ+ advocates and leaders also briefed senior White House officials on the alarming increase in anti-LGBTQ+ legislation in state legislatures across the country, in particular legislation that targets transgender children. They discussed the detrimental impacts these bills are having on the health, safety, and well-being of children and families across the United States.</p>



<p>Senior White House officials expressed their gratitude for the participants’ leadership and impactful advocacy. They reiterated the President’s strong commitment to achieving full equality for every LGBTQ+ American and his calls for the Senate to quickly pass the Equality Act. Finally, they underscored that the President has the backs of LGBTQ+ Americans, especially transgender youth.</p>



<p>Participants in today’s roundtable included:</p>



<ul><li>Alphonso David, President, Human Rights Campaign</li><li>Fatima Goss Graves, President and CEO, National Women’s Law Center</li><li>Fran Hutchins, Executive Director, Equality Federation</li><li>Mara Keisling, Executive Director, National Center for Transgender Equality</li><li>Kasey Suffredini, CEO and National Campaign Director, Freedom for All Americans</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
