<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 22:04:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Massachusetts Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/18/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-massachusetts-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 22:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts and ordered Federal assistance to supplement Commonwealth, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by the severe winter storm and snowstorm from January 28 to January 29, 2022. Federal funding is available to Commonwealth, tribal, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts and ordered Federal assistance to supplement Commonwealth, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by the severe winter storm and snowstorm from January 28 to January 29, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to Commonwealth, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storm and snowstorm in the counties of Bristol, Norfolk, Plymouth, and Suffolk, including the Mashpee Wampanoag Tribe.</p>



<p>In addition, Federal funding is available to the Commonwealth, tribal, and eligible local governments on a cost-sharing basis for snow assistance for a continuous 48-hour period during or proximate to the incident period in the counties of Bristol, Norfolk, Plymouth, and Suffolk, including the Mashpee Wampanoag Tribe.</p>



<p>Lastly, Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures in all areas within the Commonwealth of Massachusetts.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named William F. Roy as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the Commonwealth and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the 2022 White&#160;House Easter Egg&#160;Roll</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/18/remarks-by-president-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-2022-white-house-easter-egg-roll/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 16:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 10:13 A.M. EDT THE FIRST LADY:  Good morning, and welcome to the Easter Egg Roll!  (Applause.)  The President and I are so excited that you are here.  As your First Lady and as a teacher, I’ve seen again and again that learning doesn’t only happen in a classroom.  There are so many fun opportunities to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>10:13 A.M. EDT<br> <br>THE FIRST LADY:  Good morning, and welcome to the Easter Egg Roll!  (Applause.)  The President and I are so excited that you are here. <br> <br>As your First Lady and as a teacher, I’ve seen again and again that learning doesn’t only happen in a classroom.  There are so many fun opportunities to learn around us every day.  And that’s especially true here at the White House. <br> <br>For generations, Presidents and First Ladies and kids, just like you, celebrated the Easter Egg Roll together &#8212; racing and making crafts, reading books, and, of course, meeting the Easter Bunny.  (Applause.) <br> <br>Education never stops.  The determined spirit of education is what we wanted to honor in this Easter Egg Roll.  So, we turned the South Lawn into a school community.<br> <br>Today, we hope you learn that re- &#8212; we help you learn by going to the reading nook, roll some eggs, and, most of all, have fun.<br> <br>Welcome to your house, the People&#8217;s House.  Happy Easter!<br> <br>Now, please welcome my husband, our President, Joe Biden.  (Applause.) <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  My job is to keep it from raining &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; for another two minutes. <br> <br>Jill and I are excited to have you at the White House.  The &#8212; we weren&#8217;t able to host this Easter Egg Roll last year because of the pandemic.  But this year &#8212; this year, we&#8217;re finally getting together again, and it&#8217;s so special.  It means &#8212; it means so much to see and hear the children and all the families show up to be here today.<br> <br>The joy, the laughter, and the occasional &#8212; at least with my young grandson, who’s only two &#8212; the occasional, “There&#8217;s the Easter Bunny.”  (Laughs.)  A little startled sometimes. <br> <br>But the joy and the laughter is something that has been a wonderful tradition here at the White House for a long, long time.<br> <br>I especially want to thank the White House Associat- &#8212; Historical Association, the National Park Service, and America&#8217;s Egg Board for all their hard work to make this day possible.  Let’s give them a round of applause.  (Applause.) <br> <br>To all of you, have fun today and welcome to the White House.  Welcome to your house.  Welcome to the South Lawn.<br> <br>Thank you and happy, happy Easter.  (Applause.)  All right.<br> <br>10:17 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: This Tax Day, the President Is Fighting to Reward Work, Not Wealth, While Republicans Want to Increase Taxes on the Middle&#160;Class</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/18/fact-sheet-this-tax-day-the-president-is-fighting-to-reward-work-not-wealth-while-republicans-want-to-increase-taxes-on-the-middle-class/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This Tax Day, the difference in approach between the President and Congressional Republicans couldn’t be clearer.&#160; The President is fighting for tax cuts for the middle class and to ensure that the super wealthy and large corporations pay their fair share, while Congressional Republicans, led by Senator Scott, are proposing big tax increases on middle-class&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This Tax Day, the difference in approach between the President and Congressional Republicans couldn’t be clearer.&nbsp; The President is fighting for tax cuts for the middle class and to ensure that the super wealthy and large corporations pay their fair share, while Congressional Republicans, led by Senator Scott, are proposing big tax increases on middle-class families.</p>



<p>President Biden’s plan would give tax relief to tens of millions of families—continuing the tax relief families are seeing this Tax Day—and he’d apply new minimum taxes on billionaires and large corporations to make sure they’re paying their fair share.&nbsp; He wouldn’t raise taxes by a penny on anyone making less than $400,000.</p>



<p>In contrast, Congressional Republicans would continue the big handouts they’ve given to the richest Americans and largest corporations and implement a Middle-Class Tax Increase. Congressional Republicans’ plan will increase middle-class families’ taxes an average of nearly <a href="https://www.taxpolicycenter.org/model-estimates/minimum-federal-individual-income-tax-february-2022/t22-0002-enact-minimum-federal">$1,500</a> this year alone and take $100 billion out of the hands of middle-class families each year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not only that – but the Republican plan would eliminate Social Security and Medicare. The President believes we have a sacred commitment to our nation’s seniors, while the Republican plan puts that at risk.</p>



<p><strong>The President’s Tax Plan Ensures That Corporations and Billionaires Pay Their Fair Share and Delivers Tax Relief to Middle-Class Families</strong></p>



<p>In recent years, both billionaires and the largest corporations have paid an average tax rate of just 8 percent.&nbsp; That’s less than what a teacher and firefighter can pay.&nbsp; The President’s plan would fix that, and give middle-class families the tax relief they deserve.</p>



<p>President Biden is calling on Congress to pass legislation requiring the wealthiest American households to pay a minimum of 20 percent on all of their income, including unrealized investment income that currently is untaxed.&nbsp; The richest Americans could no longer do what they can now—and often pay no tax whatsoever or very little tax on their income and too often escape paying income tax forever. The tax will apply only to the top one-one hundredth of one percent (0.01%) of American households &#8212; those worth over $100 million, and over half of hundreds of billions raised would come from households worth more than $1 billion.</p>



<p>The President has also proposed repealing the 2017 Republican tax giveaways for the wealthiest Americans by restoring the top income tax rate for those making more than $400,000.</p>



<p>The President believes that profitable corporations shouldn’t pay a lower tax bill than a middle-class family, and shouldn’t be able to avoid taxes by shipping jobs and profits overseas. The President is championing a 15 percent corporate minimum tax here and around the world to ensure that no large profitable corporation gets away with paying $0 in taxes and reversing the massive 2017 Republican tax cuts, by increasing the corporate tax rate to 28 percent.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, the President is fighting for continued middle-class tax relief, especially as the middle class and working people deal with global inflation.&nbsp; Because of the American Rescue Plan, millions of middle-class families are receiving well deserved tax cuts through the Child Tax Credit, the Earned Income Tax Credit, Affordable Care Act Premium Tax Credits, and the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit.&nbsp; Families are benefitting from these tax cuts right now as they file their taxes on this Tax Day.&nbsp; The President is proposing extending that tax relief because he believes that middle-class families already pay enough in taxes.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Republican Middle-Class Tax Increase and Threat to Social Security and Medicare</strong></p>



<p>After delivering almost $2 trillion in tax cuts for the wealthiest Americans and largest corporations with their 2017 tax law, Congressional Republicans, led by Senator Rick Scott, are following up by proposing $100 billion per year in tax <em>increases</em> on middle-class families. &nbsp;According to independent analysis, around 75 million American families—96 percent of them making less than $100,000—would pay an average of <a href="https://www.taxpolicycenter.org/model-estimates/minimum-federal-individual-income-tax-february-2022/t22-0002-enact-minimum-federal">$1,480 more in taxes each year</a>.&nbsp; The Republican plan doesn’t raise a single penny in taxes from the wealthiest Americans or profitable corporations.</p>



<p>These tax increases would mean:</p>



<ul><li>24 million families of seniors making less than $100,000 per year would face tax increases.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Another 24 million families with kids making less than $100,000 per year would face tax increases.</li></ul>



<p>In 2017 the Republicans delivered an average tax cut of over <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/new-tax-law-is-fundamentally-flawed-and-will-require-basic-restructuring?msclkid=fa754cd4bb3a11ec90b7bafcd074bdb7">$250,000</a> a year to families in the top .1%; now they want working families to pay $100 billion <em>more</em> in taxes each year. &nbsp;Republicans complain that middle-class Americans don’t have “skin in the game” and don’t pay enough in taxes.&nbsp; But the truth is that middle-class Americans are the back bone of our economy, pay plenty in federal, state, and local taxes, and in many cases pay a higher rate than the super-wealthy. &nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s not just that – the Republican plan calls for expiring all laws, including Social Security and Medicare, after 5 years.&nbsp; That means Social Security and Medicare would be eliminated, unless Congress could enact them again.&nbsp; That’s wrong.&nbsp; The President believes these programs are sacred commitments.&nbsp; They should be strengthened – not threatened.</p>



<p><strong>The Choice Is Clear</strong> This Tax Day, it’s a clear choice.&nbsp; And the President is going to continue fighting for middle-class tax relief and to make sure the richest Americans and largest corporations don’t pay a lower rate than middle-class families.&nbsp; And he will fight against the Republican plan to raise taxes on middle-class families and to threaten the future of Social Security and Medicare, while continuing giant hand outs to very top and the largest corporations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement Between the United&#160;States, Belize, Germany, Indonesia, and Senegal on the Announcement of the Second Global COVID-&#8288;19&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/18/joint-statement-between-the-united-states-belize-germany-indonesia-and-senegal-on-the-announcement-of-the-second-global-covid-19-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51338</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States as first COVID Summit Chair, Belize, as CARICOM Chair; Germany, holding the G7 Presidency; Indonesia, holding the G20 Presidency; and Senegal as African Union Chair, are pleased to announce we will co-host the second Global COVID-19 Summit, which will be held virtually on May 12, 2022.&#160;The Summit will redouble our collective efforts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States as first COVID Summit Chair, Belize, as CARICOM Chair; Germany, holding the G7 Presidency; Indonesia, holding the G20 Presidency; and Senegal as African Union Chair, are pleased to announce we will co-host the second Global COVID-19 Summit, which will be held virtually on May 12, 2022.&nbsp;The Summit will redouble our collective efforts to end the acute phase of the COVID-19 pandemic and prepare for future health threats.<br>&nbsp;<br>This Summit follows the first <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/24/global-covid-19-summit-ending-the-pandemic-and-building-back-better/">Global COVID-19 Summit</a> convened by the United States on September 22, 2021.&nbsp;In advance of the May 12 Summit, we are calling on world leaders, members of civil society, non-governmental organizations, philanthropists, and the private sector to make new commitments and bring solutions to <a href="https://twitter.com/i/status/1441202427609305097">vaccinate the world, save lives now, and build better health security</a> &#8212; for everyone, everywhere.<br>&nbsp;<br>The emergence and spread of new variants, like Omicron, have reinforced the need for a strategy aimed at controlling COVID-19 worldwide. Together, we can mitigate the impact of COVID-19 and protect those at the highest risk with vaccinations, testing, and treatments, actions to minimize disruption to routine health services, and through support for the ACT-Accelerator multilateral mechanism.&nbsp;We know we must prepare now to build, sustain, and finance the global capacity we need, not only for emerging COVID-19 variants, but also future health crises.&nbsp;To help achieve these goals, we urge all countries and stakeholders to pledge to take urgent actions to create the systems we need to end the acute phase of COVID-19, save lives, and build better health security and health systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Summit will build on the themes and commitments made at the first Summit and will place an emphasis on supporting locally-led solutions to both immediate and long-term challenges, including:</p>



<ul><li>Getting shots into arms;</li><li>Deploying tests and treatments, especially for the highest-risk populations;</li><li>Expanding and protecting the health workforce and minimizing disruptions to routine and essential health services;</li><li>Enhancing access to medical countermeasures, including research and development and scaling and diversifying local and regional manufacturing; and</li><li>Generating sustainable financing for pandemic preparedness, health security, and health systems&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>We look forward to another successful Summit to continue the international effort in the fight against COVID-19 and to advance global pandemic preparedness.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on Senior Administration Travel to Hawaii, Fiji, Papua New Guinea, and the Solomon&#160;Islands</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/18/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-senior-administration-travel-to-hawaii-fiji-papua-new-guinea-and-the-solomon-islands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell and Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink will lead a delegation of U.S. government officials to three Pacific Island nations: Fiji, Papua New Guinea, and the Solomon Islands. The delegation—which will include representatives from the National Security Council, the Department&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell and Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink will lead a delegation of U.S. government officials to three Pacific Island nations: Fiji, Papua New Guinea, and the Solomon Islands. The delegation—which will include representatives from the National Security Council, the Department of State, the Department of Defense, and the United States Agency for International Development—will seek to further deepen our enduring ties with the region and to advance a free, open, and resilient Indo-Pacific. In Hawaii, the delegation will consult with senior military officials and regional partners at United States Indo-Pacific Command. In Fiji, Papua New Guinea, and the Solomon Islands, the delegation will meet with senior government officials to ensure our partnerships deliver prosperity, security, and peace across the Pacific Islands and the Indo-Pacific. They will also meet with representatives of the Pacific Islands Forum, a critical driver of regional action, to discuss issues of importance to the Pacific as a whole. The trip builds on Secretary Antony Blinken’s travel in February to the region, during which the Administration released the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/U.S.-Indo-Pacific-Strategy.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Indo-Pacific Strategy of the United States</a> and furthered our shared commitment to democracy and prosperity in the Pacific.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on&#160;Easter</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/17/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-easter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 13:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I join fellow Christians around the world in celebrating Easter Sunday — a day of joy and hope, of renewal and rebirth. Once again, Holy Week has taken us on a journey from sorrow to salvation. As we reflect today on Christ’s Resurrection, we are reminded that with faith, hope, and love —&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I join fellow Christians around the world in celebrating Easter Sunday — a day of joy and hope, of renewal and rebirth.</p>



<p>Once again, Holy Week has taken us on a journey from sorrow to salvation. As we reflect today on Christ’s Resurrection, we are reminded that with faith, hope, and love — even death can be defeated.</p>



<p>And, as we emerge from this pandemic, we are grateful that so many are able to celebrate this day of joy and renewal with services and family gatherings in person and together again. But we know this Holy Day falls on heavy hearts for those who have lost loved ones and those among us living in the dark shadow of war, persecution, and poverty.</p>



<p>On this day and each day, we pray for them, and for peace, freedom, and the basic dignity and respect for all of God’s children. As we look ahead with His blessing, may we share a common hope for the future, reaffirm love and compassion for one another, and cherish the blessing of the dawn of new possibilities.</p>



<p>From our family to yours, we wish you hope, health, joy, and the peace of God, which passes all understanding.</p>



<p>Happy Easter and may God bless and keep you.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on U.S.-ASEAN Special&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/16/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-u-s-asean-special-summit-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden will host the Leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) in Washington, DC&#160;on May 12&#160;and 13 for a U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit. The Special Summit will demonstrate the United States’ enduring commitment to ASEAN, recognizing its central role in delivering sustainable solutions to the region’s most pressing challenges, and commemorate 45 years&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden will host the Leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) in Washington, DC&nbsp;on May 12&nbsp;and 13 for a U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit.</p>



<p>The Special Summit will demonstrate the United States’ enduring commitment to ASEAN, recognizing its central role in delivering sustainable solutions to the region’s most pressing challenges, and commemorate 45 years of U.S.-ASEAN relations. It will build on President Biden’s participation in the October 2021 U.S.-ASEAN Summit, where the President announced $102 million in new initiatives to expand our engagement with ASEAN on COVID-19 recovery and health security, fighting the climate crisis, stimulating broad-based economic growth, promoting gender equality, and deepening people-to-people ties.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is a top priority for the Biden-Harris Administration to serve as a strong, reliable partner in Southeast Asia. Our shared aspirations for the region will continue to underpin our common commitment to advance an Indo-Pacific that is free and open, secure, connected, and resilient.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Call with Ray Chambers of the Partnership for Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-call-with-ray-chambers-of-the-partnership-for-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 20:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51322</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today Vice President Kamala Harris spoke to Ray Chambers, Vice Chair of the Partnership for Central America and World Health Organization Global Ambassador, about the ongoing work to address the root causes of migration from Central America. The Vice President provided an update on progress in implementation of the Administration’s Root Causes Strategy, including marshalling&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">Today Vice President Kamala Harris spoke to Ray Chambers, Vice Chair of the Partnership for Central America and World Health Organization Global Ambassador, about the ongoing work to address the root causes of migration from Central America. The Vice President provided an update on progress in implementation of the Administration’s Root Causes Strategy, including marshalling private sector investment in the region through the Vice President’s “Call to Action,” which has generated more than $1.2 billion in private sector commitments to create new jobs and opportunities for people in the region. Mr. Chambers provided an update on the Partnership’s progress in implementing economic development programs with private sector partners, and he shared recommendations to spur additional investment that benefits people in the U.S. and in Central America. The Vice President thanked Mr. Chambers for his leadership as Vice Chair of the Partnership. They discussed next steps to build on the progress achieved since the Vice President launched the “Call to Action” last year.<br> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The President and Vice President release their 2021 tax&#160;returns</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2022/04/15/the-president-and-vice-president-release-their-2021-tax-returns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Disclosures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the President and First Lady released their 2021 federal income tax return. With this release, the President has shared a total of 24 years of tax returns with the American public, once again demonstrating his commitment to being transparent with the American people about the finances of the commander in chief.&#160; The President and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the President and First Lady released their 2021 federal income tax return. With this release, the President has shared a total of 24 years of tax returns with the American public, once again demonstrating his commitment to being transparent with the American people about the finances of the commander in chief.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President and First Lady filed their income tax return jointly and reported federal adjusted gross income of $610,702. They paid $150,439 in federal income tax, and their 2021 effective federal income tax rate is 24.6 percent.</p>



<p>The President and First Lady also reported contributions of $17,394 to 10 different charities. The largest gift to charity was $5,000 to the Beau Biden Foundation, a public charity dedicated to ensuring that all children are free from the threat of abuse.</p>



<p>The President and First Lady also released their Delaware income tax return and reported paying $30,765 in Delaware income tax, and the First Lady released her Virginia income tax return and reported paying $2,721 in Virginia income tax.</p>



<p>View the President and First Lady’s tax returns <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-15-POTUS-Redacted-2021-Federal-and-State-Returns.pdf">here</a>.</p>



<p>The Vice President and the Second Gentleman also released their 2021 federal income tax return, as well as state income tax returns for California, New York and the District of Columbia. Including today’s release, the Vice President has published 18 years of tax returns.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Vice President and the Second Gentleman reported federal adjusted gross income of $1,655,563. They paid $523,371 in federal income tax, amounting to a 2021 effective federal income tax rate of 31.6 percent. They also paid $120,517 in California income tax, $2,044 in New York income tax, and Mr. Emhoff paid $54,441 in District of Columbia income tax. They contributed $22,100 to charity in 2021.</p>



<p>View the Vice President and Second Gentleman’s tax returns <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/2022-04-15-VPOTUS-Redacted-2021-Federal-and-State-Returns.pdf">here</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/15/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-11/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Richard Lee Buangan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Mongolia Rachna Sachdeva Korhonen, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mali Rebecca Haffajee, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Planning and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Richard Lee Buangan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Mongolia</li><li>Rachna Sachdeva Korhonen, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mali</li><li>Rebecca Haffajee, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Jaime Areizaga-Soto, Nominee for Chair of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, Department of Veterans Affairs</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Richard Lee Buangan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Mongolia</u></strong></p>



<p>Richard Lee Buangan, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of Global Public Affairs at the State Department. Prior to that, Buangan served as Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs, and as the Executive Assistant to the Secretary of State. Earlier in his career, Buangan was assigned as Managing Director for International Media in the Bureau of Public Affairs, as the Public Affairs Officer of the then-U.S. Consulate General, Jerusalem, and as Deputy Press Attaché and then as Embassy Spokesperson of the U.S. Embassy in Beijing, China. Buangan also served as a staff officer in the Executive Secretariat of the Department of State, and held overseas assignments in Paris, France and Abidjan, Côte d’Ivoire.</p>



<p>Buangan earned a Bachelor of Arts degree from Saint Edward’s University, Austin, Texas. He is the recipient of multiple performance awards from the State Department. He speaks Mandarin Chinese, French, and Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rachna Sachdeva Korhonen, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mali</u></strong></p>



<p>Rachna Korhonen is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Counselor. She currently serves as a Deputy Assistant Secretary and the Executive Director of the combined Executive Offices of the State Department’s Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs and the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs. Previously, Korhonen was the Consul General and Principal Officer of the U.S. Consulate in Dharan, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia. She also led the Management Section of the U.S. Embassy in Colombo, Sri Lanka and, in Washington, served as a Special Assistant to the Under Secretary for Management. Among her other assignments, Korhonen was the Supervisory General Services Officer and Senior Human Resources Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Riyadh, Saudi Arabia, and the Political Chief of the Provincial Reconstruction Team in Kirkuk, Iraq.&nbsp; She also had assignments at the U.S. Embassy in Kuwait and at the U.S. Consulate General in Mumbai, India.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Korhonen earned her B.S. from Empire State College. She speaks Hindi, French, Finnish, and Arabic.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rebecca Haffajee, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Rebecca Haffajee was appointed as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation at the Department of Health and Human Services and has been serving as the Acting Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation since March 2021. Before joining the federal government, Haffajee was a policy researcher at the RAND Corporation, and an assistant professor of health management and policy at the University of Michigan School of Public Health. Prior to these roles, Haffajee practiced health care law at Ropes &amp; Gray LLP, where she advised domestic health care providers on regulatory compliance and reimbursement matters, and she was a law fellow at the O’Neill Institute for National and Global Health Law at Georgetown University. Haffajee’s work combines detailed legal analyses with empirical investigations of the relationships between policy and health. Her main research interests are behavioral health, drug policy, health equity, and public health law and policy. Her work has been covered by major news media outlets and published in health journals, including in the New England Journal of Medicine, Journal of the American Medical Association, Annals of Internal Medicine, and Health Affairs.</p>



<p>Haffajee received her Ph.D. in Health Policy (concentrating in evaluative sciences and statistics) from Harvard University, J.D. from Harvard Law School, and M.P.H. from the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health. She attended Duke University for her undergraduate degree. She grew up in Massachusetts, where she now lives with her husband and two children.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Jaime Areizaga-Soto, Nominee for Chair of the Board of Veterans’ Appeals, Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Jaime Areizaga-Soto, an attorney, public servant, and Army JAG Brigadier General, is currently mobilized to active duty as the Principal Deputy General Counsel of the National Guard Bureau (NGB), a joint activity of the Department of Defense (DOD). In that role, he works closely with the General Counsel in advising the senior leadership of NGB, in leading an office of over 100 attorneys, and in coordinating among the Air Force, the Army, and the 54 National Guards. From 2014 until earlier this year, Areizaga-Soto served as the Deputy Secretary for Veterans and Defense Affairs of Virginia, where he advised Governors McAuliffe and Northam on matters related to the 730,000 Virginia veterans and military families, and in ensuring an excellent relationship with DOD’s thirty large installations across the Commonwealth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Areizaga-Soto practiced international law for twelve years, focusing on cross-border infrastructure project finance. He served as a White House Fellow assigned to the Treasury Department, and as the Senior Attorney Advisor at USAID’s Office of the General Counsel. Areizaga-Soto grew up in Puerto Rico and graduated from Georgetown University’s School of Foreign Service. He holds a law degree from Stanford Law School, a Masters in Latin American Studies from Stanford University, a Masters in Security and Defense from the Inter-American Defense College in Ft. McNair, and a Mágister from the National Academy of Political and Strategic Studies (ANEPE) of Chile. He is a member of the Virginia, District of Columbia, New York, Maryland, and U.S. Supreme Court Bars; is fluent in Spanish, Portuguese, and French; and has basic knowledge of Italian.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
