<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 20:37:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>March 2021 Visitor Log Records Posted</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2021/06/29/march-2021-visitor-log-records-posted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22441</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House released visitor log records generated in March 2021. This set includes 1215 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 2679. These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House released visitor log records generated in March 2021. This set includes 1215 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 2679.</p>



<p>These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.</p>



<p>To learn more about the policy, read our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/">voluntary disclosure policy</a>. To view visitor log records, view our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/">disclosure page</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate Consistent with the War Powers Resolution (Public Law 93-148)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/29/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-and-the-president-pro-tempore-of-the-senate-consistent-with-the-war-powers-resolution-public-law-93-148/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 18:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Mr. President:) At my direction, on June 27, 2021, United States forces conducted targeted strikes against facilities at two locations in Syria and one location in Iraq near the Iraq-Syria border.  These facilities were used by Iran-backed militia groups that have been involved in a series of unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Mr. President:)<br><br>At my direction, on June 27, 2021, United States forces conducted targeted strikes against facilities at two locations in Syria and one location in Iraq near the Iraq-Syria border.  These facilities were used by Iran-backed militia groups that have been involved in a series of unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) and rocket attacks against United States personnel and facilities in Iraq.  These militia attacks have escalated in recent months.  Recent rocket attacks have included ones on Balad Air Base on April 4, April 18, and May 3, 2021; the Baghdad Diplomatic Support Center near the Baghdad International Airport on May 2, 2021; and Al‑Asad Air Base on May 4 and May 24, 2021.  Recent UAV attacks have included ones on United States facilities in Erbil on April 14, 2021; Al-Asad Air Base on May 8, 2021; Bashur Air Base on May 10, 2021; and United States facilities near the Baghdad International Airport on June 9, 2021.  These attacks have injured and threatened the lives of United States and Coalition personnel.  Additional UAV attacks have been attempted. <br><br>I directed the June 27 strikes in order to protect and defend the safety of our personnel, to degrade and disrupt the ongoing series of attacks against the United States and our partners, and to deter the Islamic Republic of Iran and Iran-backed militia groups from conducting or supporting further attacks on United States personnel and facilities.  In support of these aims, the targeted strikes were directed at facilities used by groups involved in these ongoing attacks for weapons storage, command, logistics, and UAV operations.<br><br>I directed this discrete military action consistent with my responsibility to protect United States citizens both at home and abroad and in furtherance of United States national security and foreign policy interests, pursuant to my constitutional authority to conduct United States foreign relations and as Commander in Chief and Chief Executive.  The United States took this necessary and proportionate action consistent with international law, and in the exercise of the United States&#8217; inherent right of self-defense as reflected in Article 51 of the United Nations Charter.  The United States stands ready to take further action, as necessary and appropriate, to address further threats or attacks. <br><br>I am providing this report as part of my efforts to keep the Congress fully informed, consistent with the War Powers Resolution (Public Law 93-148).  Additional information is provided in a classified annex.  I appreciate the support of the Congress in this action.       </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"> Sincerely,<br><br>                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki En Route La Crosse, WI</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/29/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-en-route-la-crosse-wi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 18:33:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:27 A.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; Good morning.&#160; Welcome to our trip to La Crosse, Wisconsin.&#160;&#160;President Biden is traveling today to make the case directly to the American people that the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework is a major step forward for our country and the largest infrastructure investment in nearly a century.&#160; It will grow&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:27 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Welcome to our trip to La Crosse, Wisconsin.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden is traveling today to make the case directly to the American people that the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework is a major step forward for our country and the largest infrastructure investment in nearly a century.&nbsp; It will grow our economy, create good-paying jobs, and position America to compete with the world and win the 21st century.<br>&nbsp;<br>A couple of Wisconsin specifics: Nearly half of &#8212; nearly half of Milwaukee’s 160,000 water service lines are made of lead, and the plan’s investments in water infrastructure will replace them all.<br>&nbsp;<br>The infrastructure deal will also, as you know, help make broadband access a reality for people across the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There’s 82,000 Wisconsin children who didn’t have access to reliable Internet in the midst of a year of remote schooling.&nbsp; This will help change that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It will also help address the bridges and roads, of course, across Wisconsin that need rebuilding as a core part of the Infrastructure Framework.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The place we’re going today &#8212; the place where the President will deliver his remarks &#8212; is the La Crosse Municipal Transit Utility, which was rewarded &#8212; awarded a federal grant in 2018 to purchase two electric buses, charging stations, and related infrastructure. &nbsp;This is part of a broader strategy of the City of La Crosse to achieve a goal of 100 percent renewable energy by 2050.<br>&nbsp;<br>Oh, and just a little full-circle note for all of you: The buses are being manufactured by Proterra, whose Greenville, South Carolina, facility the President visited back in April.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I also wanted to note that, yesterday, the House took an important step in advancing the vision the President laid out with the American Jobs Plan for growing the economy for all workers by advancing two bipartisan bills: the National Science Foundation for the Future Act and the Department of Energy Science for the Future Act.<br>&nbsp;<br>He was pleased to see the Senate pass crucially important investments in our domestic strength through the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act with massive bipartisan support, and he’s heartened to see the House pass bipartisan investments in science and R&amp;D.<br>&nbsp;<br>Another update on our doses going overseas: We are proud to announce that 2.5 million doses of the Moderna vaccine will begin to ship to Bangladesh today.&nbsp; And we expect we may have more announcements today, as well, for additional shipments.<br>&nbsp;<br>You may have also seen our announcement &#8212; short announcement &#8212; that the President and the First Lady will be traveling to Surfside, Florida.&nbsp; Let me give you a little bit more detail about what they’re planning to do there.&nbsp; They want to thank the heroic first responders, search-and-rescue teams, and everyone who has been working tirelessly around the clock, and meet with the families who have been forced to endure this terrible tragedy &#8212; waiting in anguish and heartbreak for word of their loved ones &#8212; to offer them comfort as search-and- rescue efforts continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>And they want to make sure that state and local officials have the resources and support they need under the emergency declaration approved by the President for Miami-Dade, Florida.<br>&nbsp;<br>The visit is being, of course, closely coordinated with officials on the ground to ensure it does not draw any critical local resources from the ongoing search-and-rescue operations or have any negative operational impact.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, obviously, I know you’re going to ask about meetings with local officials; we don’t have any updates &#8212; any details on that quite yet.&nbsp; If any develop while we’re on our trip today, we’ll make sure those are available to all of you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two-question subject areas.&nbsp; First, Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The top general in Afghanistan said the escalating violence could lead to a deadly civil war.&nbsp; Does the administration have any concerns about that possibility, given the withdrawals? &nbsp;And what will it do to minimize that possibility?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would note that the President met with the leaders of Afghanistan just last Friday, and he reiterated our commitment to working with them on not just humanitarian assistance, but security assistance and our commitment to continue to have a presence on the ground, which we vowed to do in the beginning, and we will &#8212; we remain committed to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll also note that the decision that the President made to withdraw troops from Afghanistan, it is consistent with his view over the last 20 years about the war.&nbsp; But he also made that decision because it was made clear, given the timeline set by the prior administration, that if we did not withdraw our troops, U.S. men and women would be facing fire on the ground.&nbsp; And that was not something, as the Commander-in-Chief, that he felt was acceptable, and hence we are on this timeline we’re on by September.<br>&nbsp;<br>There has been assessments out there, as you know, by the intelligence community and others.&nbsp; I would refer to them on those assessments of the situation on the ground.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, Tucker Carlson said that the NSA is spying on him.&nbsp; Is the administration aware of any espionage or listening efforts on U.S. citizens by the NSA, and is Tucker Carlson one of them?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the NSA, as I think you’re well aware &#8212; I’m not sure everyone is aware &#8212; everyone on this plane is aware, I should say &#8212; is an entity that focuses on foreign threats and individuals who are trying &#8212; attempting to do us harm on foreign soil.&nbsp; So, that is the &#8212; their purview.&nbsp; But beyond that, I would point you to the intelligence community.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on infrastructure: So, Leader McConnell said he was satisfied that the President has de-linked the reconciliation package and the bipartisan agreement, but Speaker Pelosi said this morning that the House isn&#8217;t going to vote on the bipartisan bill until the Senate passes that reconciliation package.&nbsp; So the question is: Is the White House urging her to publicly de-link those two issues like the President did over the weekend?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our focus is on doing &#8212; the President&#8217;s focus is on doing exactly what he&#8217;s doing today and what leaders in Congress asked him to do, which is to go out to the public and make clear the benefits of this package to the American people, whether it&#8217;s on roads and railways and bridges, or components of the package that there&#8217;s less known about, including making broadband available; making sure we&#8217;re doing environmental remediation, something that would help lower-income communities quite a bit; making public transit available.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s exactly what they expect him to do, what they want him to do, and what the President is going to spend his time doing.&nbsp; He looks forward to and is eager to sign both bills into law, and he will leave it to leaders in Congress to determine the order and the sequencing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there&#8217;s no message coming from the White House to Speaker Pelosi to publicly “de-link,” quote unquote, those two issues?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President made clear that he is going to work his heart out getting both bills across the finish line, and that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to do, and work closely with leaders in Congress to get that done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you describe the ongoing outreach to progressives today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, to what extent is the White House worried about the idea that all the Democrats in the House won&#8217;t be a “yes” on the reconciliation bill and the compromise (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Let me give you a rundown of some outreach.&nbsp; It will include progressives but other outreach as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have been &#8212; the White House was in touch with all Democratic chiefs of staff in both chambers yesterday.&nbsp; The White House also had calls with over 60 Democratic and Republican members, chiefs of staff and staff directors in both chambers.&nbsp; This included calls with a diverse &#8212; diverse range of ideologies ranging from members of the Congressional Progressive Caucus to members of the Problem Solvers Caucus.&nbsp;<br>We hosted a call today with all the Democratic &#8212; we are hosting a call today, I should say &#8212; with all of the Democratic Senate communications directors on the package.&nbsp; And today, Steve Ricchetti, Louisa Terrell, and Shuwanza Goff will meet with a range of progressives to moderates within the Democratic House Caucus, as well as Republicans.</p>



<p>In terms of progressive groups &#8212; which is a little beyond this but I think of interest to all of you &#8212; senior White House staffers addressed over 100 progressives groups through a call organized by Build Back Together, focused on the historic progressive wins in the bipartisan framework, including with respect to job creation; climate and clean energy; removing all lead water pipes &#8212; something there isn&#8217;t a lot of information out there on, which we&#8217;re trying to make sure people understand the details of; and connecting all communities to broadband.</p>



<p>We also, separately, addressed 60 additional groups yesterday on a call convened by a different outside organization.</p>



<p>Point being, we have every senior member of the White House working to communicate directly with the public, with groups, with members of Congress about the components of this package and our continued commitment to also get the reconciliation package across the finish line.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does that say about the fact that this Democratic White House has to do that kind of outreach to members of its own party?&nbsp; I mean, is the President in any way disappointed by the fact that he has to engage this way with fellow Democrats?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President sees that as his job and, by association, all of our jobs.&nbsp; And part of what his objective is, at this point, is to move beyond &#8212; and all of our objectives &#8212; move beyond the process.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an important component of it, but make sure we are clearly articulating what the benefits are of these packages, why they can help people, how they can help people in the country, and that&#8217;s something we&#8217;re going to do in partnership with members around the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, Bernie Sanders was on NPR this morning talking about the fact that this infrastructure bill doesn&#8217;t include, you know, enough for climate.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve said that there are climate provisions in there, but, you know, what do you say to Bernie Sanders when he gets on, you know, national radio and says that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, we say to Senator Sanders: You&#8217;re an important partner, and we look forward to continuing to work with you to get this and the reconciliation package across the finish line.</p>



<p>What we also have been conveying is this &#8212; the President sees this bipartisan package on climate as a down payment.&nbsp; It has a number of key important priorities for anybody who is focused on addressing the climate crisis, including the President, included in it.&nbsp; And that includes environmental remediation.&nbsp; It includes an enormous investment in electric vehicles, electric buses &#8212; something that will not only help communities across the country, you know, better move around, but it will also help our climate.&nbsp; And he is also committed to continuing to work to get more in the bi- &#8212; in the reconciliation package, something that Senator Sanders is certainly running point and leading on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess my other question has to do with the reconciliation package.&nbsp; To what degree, given the amount of effort you&#8217;re having to put into getting the compromise through &#8212; the infrastructure package through &#8212; has there any &#8212; has any real work been done on looking at what you can put into a reconciliation package and win support for?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, how far is this &#8212; you know, is this effort underway?&nbsp; And who&#8217;s leading that initiative?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Senator Sanders is leading that initiative, of course, in the Senate.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) say?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say White House leaders &#8212; the same White House leaders: Steve Ricchetti, Louisa Terrell, others who are &#8212; Shalanda Young, obviously, as our &#8212; as our Acting OMB Director.&nbsp; They have already had meetings.&nbsp; They had a meeting &#8212; I think, last week, we announced &#8212; on the Hill to discuss the next steps and the paths forward.&nbsp; They will have continued meetings over the coming weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have a Jobs Cabinet.&nbsp; We also have a Families Cabinet of members of our &#8212; of our administration who we expect to also be out there communicating about the huge benefits of the Families Plan &#8212; something that will be central to the President&#8217;s push in the reconciliation package as well as his budget that he&#8217;s also put forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also fully recognize that we&#8217;re at the early stages of this process, and I think anybody on the Hill will tell you that.&nbsp; And there are important discussions that need to happen between a range of Democrats about priorities, what can be in the package, and what they would support.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ll, of course, be engaged in that, but those need to also happen among senators.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s your best guess for timing, in terms of getting &#8212; you know, what &#8212; what&#8217;s your goal, your target to get this legislation passed &#8212; both?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that Leader Schumer has conveyed that he wants to have both packages on the floor in July, and that&#8217;s probably the next step.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And tomorrow, you&#8217;ll be meeting with the western governors.&nbsp; So the President will be meeting with the western governors.&nbsp; He met with the FEMA Administrator recently and talked about increasing pay for firefighters and just raising awareness about wildfires.&nbsp; Do you have any specific proposals that you&#8217;re going to be unveiling in terms of how to address this problem?&nbsp; There&#8217;s so many wildfires already.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re absolutely right.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s commitment to making sure we&#8217;re being partners &#8212; that the administration and he, personally, is a partner to governors who are looking ahead to a growing wildfire season &#8212; rising heat, rising temperatures in the West &#8212; you know, that&#8217;s something that&#8217;s been important to him personally.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He already had a briefing from FEMA over the last couple of weeks.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you yet.&nbsp; We will see if, by the end of the day, we do, in advance of tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on COVID, is the White House having pause on plans to reopen to Canada and Europe because of the Delta strain?&nbsp; Has &#8212; is the &#8212; you know, because it&#8217;s causing some disruption like everywhere, as far away as Australia.&nbsp; Is that, like, getting into the &#8212; putting a fly in the ointment for whatever plans there were to reopen?&nbsp; And when are you going to reopen Canada and Europe?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As you know, there&#8217;s working groups that are under discussion &#8212; having discussions between our officials and officials in Europe and other countries about what that path forward looks like.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any updates on those groups.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there&#8217;s no pro- &#8212; there&#8217;s no progress on &#8212; like, (inaudible) Canada?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I didn’t &#8212; I didn&#8217;t actually say that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I said: We continue to evaluate, through these working groups, what the criteria should be and when it would be safe to reopen.&nbsp; We are working &#8212; we’re guided by our public health officials, but I don&#8217;t have any updates on the timeline at this point.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Jen, I just &#8212; just related to that, is there any update on the mask policy and so on for the barbecue on Sunday?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, the &#8212; sorry, say that one more time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; At the White House barbecue on Sunday &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the July the 4th barbecue &#8212; have you &#8212; what are the rules going to be for masks and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; vaccine and so on?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s been guidance that has been provided, which may be updated.&nbsp; But to all attendees that include the &#8212; the guidance that they should be &#8212; they should get tested one through three days in advance of coming to the event.&nbsp; If they are vaccinated, of course, they can abide by the public health guidelines that does not require mask wearing.&nbsp; If they have not been vaccinated, they should wear a mask.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you talk about the strategy of going to Wisconsin today?&nbsp; Why aren’t we heading to West Virginia or Arizona or some other place where you might be targeting a lawmaker?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Wisconsin is a place where there &#8212; where the people of the state would hugely benefit from the components of the bipartisan infrastructure package.&nbsp; I mentioned a couple of them at the top, including broadband access &#8212; something that more than 80,000 kids across Wisconsin didn&#8217;t have access to, even while they were getting &#8212; attending school from home.&nbsp; There are bridges across the state that need repair, roads that need repair &#8212; also something that would be beneficial.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to a &#8212; the location we&#8217;re going to, where the President is going to be delivering his remarks, is an interesting example.&nbsp; They purchased two electric vehicles because of an electric &#8212; because of a federal grant &#8212; electric buses, I should say.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that&#8217;s going to help the City of La Crosse get to a more &#8212; a &#8212; to become a city that is &#8212; can be a model for how you should move to a more climate-friendly approach to transit.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is a place where we felt we could highlight the benefits, talk directly to the Ame- &#8212; American people, people of Wisconsin about why this bipartisan package is a good deal for the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, does the President believe that Americans who live in coastal high rises are safe right now?&nbsp; Or is there anything that &#8212; more that he wants to see being done?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, one, the President supports an investigation.&nbsp; I conveyed this yesterday.&nbsp; And I actually didn&#8217;t give the specifics on who would oversee the investigation, so let me just give that to you right now.&nbsp; One second.&nbsp; I have it right in here somewhere.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; So the National Institute of Standards and Technology &#8212; NIST &#8212; is authorized to investigate building failures.&nbsp; Their authorities are modeled after those of the National Transportation Safety Board &#8212; the NTSB &#8212; for investigating transportation accidents.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They have announced they sent a team of six scientists and engineers to collect firsthand information on the towers &#8212; the Champlain Towers South collapse that will be used to determine if an investigation or study will be conducted.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, obviously, that would be something the President would support, and certainly we would look to that &#8212; if that&#8217;s a decision made &#8212; to learn how we can help protect infrastructure across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And any reaction to that letter that went out to the residents of the building?&nbsp; We found &#8212; CNN found, in April, that it was warning the occupants of basically the worst possible outcome, which happened.&nbsp; Any &#8212; any reaction?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, clearly, we are providing every resource we can from the federal government &#8212; not just to help with the search-and-rescue operations, but to be a part of any effort to determine if an investigation should happen moving forward.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the President supports, and that&#8217;s a way we can be constructive from the federal government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, there&#8217;s a report in Politico that suggests that your administration is looking at reversing some of the deportations that happened during the Trump administration.&nbsp; Can you talk about that and maybe whether there&#8217;s any limit to it or how you&#8217;re going through that process?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; I&#8217;d have to talk to our immigration team about that.&nbsp; I have not seen that report, but I will check in with them about it and get you an answer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Jen, going back to what we were talking about earlier with infrastructure and Senator McConnell: Senator McConnell, yesterday, claimed he&#8217;s still sort of undecided on whether to vote for this package.&nbsp; Does the White House think getting him to vote for this is a realistic goal?&nbsp; Do you view him as a partner in passing this or as someone who&#8217;s more trying to tank the deal?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I would say that the President would welcome the support from any Republican and Democrat for a bipartisan package that&#8217;s broadly supported by the American people, because the American people don&#8217;t think &#8212; including people in his home state of Kentucky &#8212; that rebuilding roads and railways and bridges is a partisan issue.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not.&nbsp; Neither is making sure people have access to broadband or clean drinking water.<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s the case the President will continue to make. &nbsp;We’ll lead the &#8212; leave the vote counting and the whip counting to leaders in Congress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But does the President view McConnell as an ally in trying to get this passed or as someone we need to get past in order to pass it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President and members of the administration will engage with a range of leaders and officials in Congress, including Leader McCon- &#8212; including Senator McConnell.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The German finance minister is coming this week to visit Janet Yellen, and there&#8217;s these OECD tax talks.&nbsp; As you know, this was a subject at the G7.&nbsp; Are you confident that you&#8217;ll &#8212; that the U.S. will be able to prevail with that digital &#8212; you know, with the &#8212; with its view of a global minimum corporate tax of 15 percent?&nbsp; And do you have any, kind of, updates for us as we&#8217;re heading into the G20 process too?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Beginning of an exciting season: the G20 season.&nbsp; I will say I would certainly leave it to the Department of Treasury for any previews of the Secretary&#8217;s meeting, but I would remind you &#8212; and you were on the trip with us &#8212; that it was, in part, because of U.S. leadership that we got agreement on the global minimum tax at the G7 &#8212; an important step forward and something we knew that there would be continued work that would be required to be done to get that across the finish line.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would leave it to them for any update on that, as Secretary Yellen is running point and leading that effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On housing finance, you had the Supreme Court ruling recently, but we saw, in the Miami condo tower, condos were selling &#8212; they were listed for sale between $600- and $700,000.&nbsp; Does this administration plan to do anything about the shortage of home construction and housing finance to make sure that people can find homes where they can afford and know that their investments will be safe?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Are you asking me about the infrastructure or the cost of housing?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The cost of housing but, more importantly, the absence of supply and the absence of new construction.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I would say, first, on the &#8212; we certainly recognize that the absence of certain materials, as you all know, including lumber, has led to price increases in the housing market.&nbsp; And we have been focused on working through our supply chain team that is leading this effort to make sure we are addressing challenges in the supply chain, gaps in the supply chain to make sure that those materials are more readily available.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, yes, we are doing &#8212; we are taking a number of steps as an administration, across the board, to address housing.&nbsp; As you know, there&#8217;s been a one-month extension &#8212; I know this wasn&#8217;t what you were asking, but just an example &#8212; of the eviction moratorium and the foreclosure moratorium.&nbsp; That will help some people in the country stay in their homes for a period of time.&nbsp; That was always meant to be temporary.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also are working to see &#8212; to determine how we can address these supply chain issues that have led to increases, because as you know, Josh, from covering this quite closely, the fact that there are not new builds is also raising the prices of houses that have been around for some time, so we&#8217;re seeing kind of a ricocheting effect here.&nbsp; But that is part of our objective.&nbsp; And some of the materials that are &#8212; is being worked through by our economic team.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this trip, Jen &#8212; so, obviously, President Biden won Wisconsin in 2020, but the area we&#8217;re going to today was more in favor of Donald Trump.&nbsp; I know the next election is a long way off, but does the White House believe winning or getting higher margins in rural areas is important for the President&#8217;s reelection?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that what should be noted is that under President Biden&#8217;s leadership, the economy is starting to come back again, and communities across the country &#8212; whether they&#8217;re blue or red parts of the country &#8212; are seeing the benefits of that.&nbsp; And it is &#8212; it should be noted that a range of members of Congress who may be facing reelections are eager to have the President travel to parts of their districts and parts of their &#8212; and their states because of his work on an economic agenda that works for all people, whether they live in red states or blue states or purple states and whomever they may have voted for the last time around.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just ask on the supply chain stuff?&nbsp; You talked yesterday about Taiwan.&nbsp; You talked yesterday about Taiwan.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there&#8217;s this critical meeting today on this sort of, you know, trade council with Taiwan.&nbsp; Is there any suggestion at all that the U.S. decision to provide as many vaccine doses as were provided to Taiwan is in some way a quid pro quo to get access to semiconductors from Taiwan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There should not be that suggestion.&nbsp; I will note that they were being cut off from access to vaccines.&nbsp; So that was a factor.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, Senator Wyden has what he&#8217;s calling the &#8220;Press Act.&#8221; &nbsp;It has to do with the idea that Justice Department &#8212; the Justice Department is subpoenaing reporters&#8217; business records.&nbsp; Does the White House have a position that it&#8217;s ready to take on that?&nbsp; I know the President has obviously spoken out about how wrong it is that the Justice Department might go after reporters&#8217; records.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, the President has been pretty clear about what he feels the tactics should not be as it relates to reporters and members of the media. &nbsp;And that is aligned with his long respect for the freedom of press and the freedom of media.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d have to look into this.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a piece of legislation.&nbsp; I&#8217;d have to look into the specifics of the piece of legislation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>11:49 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Memorandum for the Secretary of State on Expo 2027 Minnesota &#8211; Healthy People, Healthy Planet: Wellness and Well-Being for All</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/29/a-memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-state-on-expo-2027-minnesota-healthy-people-healthy-planet-wellness-and-well-being-for-all/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 16:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In accordance with Public Law 91-269, I have approved the recommendation for Federal recognition of the proposed &#8220;Expo 2027 Minnesota &#8211; Healthy People, Healthy Planet:&#160; Wellness and Well-Being for All,&#8221; finding that such recognition will be in the national interest. Accordingly, I am requesting you to notify the Bureau of International Expositions of my actions.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In accordance with Public Law 91-269, I have approved the recommendation for Federal recognition of the proposed &#8220;Expo 2027 Minnesota &#8211; Healthy People, Healthy Planet:&nbsp; Wellness and Well-Being for All,&#8221; finding that such recognition will be in the national interest.<br><br>Accordingly, I am requesting you to notify the Bureau of International Expositions of my actions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Memorandum for the Secretary of Commerce on Expo 2027 Minnesota &#8211; Healthy People, Healthy Planet: Wellness and Well-Being for All</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/29/a-memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-commerce-on-expo-2027-minnesota-healthy-people-healthy-planet-wellness-and-well-being-for-all/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 16:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have reviewed the reports and recommendations presented to me by you and the Secretary of State that recognition be given to the proposed &#8220;Expo 2027 Minnesota &#8211; Healthy People, Healthy Planet:&#160; Wellness and Well-Being for All,&#8221; and find that such recognition will be in the national interest. I approve granting Federal recognition to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I have reviewed the reports and recommendations presented to me by you and the Secretary of State that recognition be given to the proposed &#8220;Expo 2027 Minnesota &#8211; Healthy People, Healthy Planet:&nbsp; Wellness and Well-Being for All,&#8221; and find that such recognition will be in the national interest.<br><br>I approve granting Federal recognition to the proposed Exposition.<br><br>On that basis, please advise the appropriate agencies and organizations that official recognition is hereby granted.<br><br>I would also appreciate your taking the appropriate steps to notify the Congress of this action, in accordance with section&nbsp;2(c) of Public Law 91-269.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before Marine One Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/29/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The South Lawn 10:05 A.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Are you going to Florida?&#160;&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Yes, I hope so.&#160; That&#8217;s &#8212;&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; What&#8217;s &#8212; how soon?&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Unless I &#8212; as soon as we can.&#160; Maybe as early as Thursday.&#160;&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Dr. Biden going to Tokyo, Mr. President?&#160; Jill Biden going to Tokyo, Mr. President?&#160;&#160;&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Am I going &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The South Lawn</p>



<p>10:05 A.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to Florida?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, I hope so.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s &#8212; how soon?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Unless I &#8212; as soon as we can.&nbsp; Maybe as early as Thursday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Dr. Biden going to Tokyo, Mr. President?&nbsp; Jill Biden going to Tokyo, Mr. President?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Am I going &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Your wife, Dr. Biden, going to Tokyo next month?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re trying to work that out now.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>10:06 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in a Virtual Fundraising Reception for the Democratic National Committee</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/29/remarks-by-president-biden-in-a-virtual-fundraising-reception-for-the-democratic-national-party/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via TeleconferenceThe Residence (June 28, 2021) 6:59 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Reid, thank you.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you for hosting this event and for your generous support.&#160; I might note that &#8212; I was saying to you when I got to speak to you a few minutes earlier that, you know, you haven’t&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>The Residence</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(June 28, 2021)</p>



<p>6:59 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Reid, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you for hosting this event and for your generous support.&nbsp; I might note that &#8212; I was saying to you when I got to speak to you a few minutes earlier that, you know, you haven’t even &#8212; we haven’t even sat down with each other.&nbsp; You know, anybody who contributed and raised as much funds as you did, everybody expects to be knocking on my door for &#8212; you never asked me for a single thing.&nbsp; You’ve raised an enormous amount of money, and you said, “The reason why we haven’t gotten together, Mr. President, is because we didn’t want to distract you.&nbsp; We want you to keep going.”&nbsp; And I’m like &#8212; I really mean it.&nbsp; I hope everybody understands that about almost all of you on this call.&nbsp; And I want to thank you for your incredible support.<br><br>And, Jaime, I think that Leader Clyburn was correct: You’re the right choice for this job.&nbsp; You’ve been doing outstanding leadership.&nbsp; And let me just say that you’re part of something special.&nbsp; We’re bound together in one of the most consequential campaigns in the history of this country.&nbsp; It really was a battle for the soul of America.<br><br>And I just got back, by the way, from Europe after being there for, I guess, 13 days.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I forget how many days.&nbsp; And I met for five days with the G7 nations.&nbsp; I also &#8212; and then there were four others that were there &#8212; India, Australia.&nbsp; And I won&#8217;t go through all the detail; it’d be too boring for you.&nbsp; And then I went to a NATO meeting with all the &#8212; all the NATO representatives there and the heads of state.&nbsp; And then I went to meet with Putin.&nbsp; Actually, in between, I did the EU.<br><br>And here&#8217;s the bottom line: I &#8212; I think &#8212; I know you all understood it: the incredible damage done to us, internationally, by the last outfit that sat in this seat.&nbsp; And I have to say, sitting here tonight, I&#8217;ve lived through what we&#8217;ve lived through.&nbsp; We know just how important it was.&nbsp; It turns out it was even more important than I thought it was.<br><br>Think about the last 150 days: The American Rescue Plan delivered shots in the arms.&nbsp; And, by the way, we are in a position where we&#8217;re getting close to making sure that 70 percent of all the people in America will have been fully vaccinated, or at least get one shot by the &#8212; by Independence Day.&nbsp; We&#8217;re way ahead.&nbsp; No one thought we could ever do that.<br><br>And I&#8217;m in the process of being able to announce very shortly that we&#8217;re going to generate &#8212; half a billion doses we&#8217;re going to give away between &#8212; after taking care of every single American.&nbsp; Half a billion doses give away to the poorest countries in the world.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what you do when you want to really help and influence people around the world.<br><br>And we put &#8212; and &#8212; but beyond that, they &#8212; you know, the act put shots in arms and checks in pockets for hundreds of millions of Americans who are on the edge.&nbsp; It’s keeping food on the table, a roof over their heads.&nbsp; And maybe the thing I&#8217;m proudest of is it’s putting us back on track to cut child poverty in half.&nbsp;<br><br>A hundred and fifty million Americans are fully vaccinated now.&nbsp; The fastest job growth in the first four months, I&#8217;m told &#8212; not because of me, but because of all of you &#8212; of any previous presidency.&nbsp; Projected economic growth at nearly 7 percent &#8212; the highest in four decades.<br><br>And just last week, I announced a bipartisan agreement in the Senate asking to make one of the biggest investments ever in infrastructure, ever &#8212; rebuilding our roads and bridges; delivering high-speed Internet to every American family, rural and as well as in urban areas; delivering every clean water, getting rid of those lead pipes to every American; building a more resilient power grid; installing electric vehicle charging stations &#8212; over half a million of them.&nbsp; This is the largest investment in public transit ever and the largest investment in rail since the creation of Amtrak 50 years ago.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about creating millions of good-paying jobs, and it&#8217;s about our economic competitiveness.<br><br>You all know better than I, because you’re all successful people, that we’re in a race in the 21st century to &#8212; who&#8217;s going to have a strongest economy in the 21st century.&nbsp; And the rest of the world is not waiting around.&nbsp; We have more to do, and we have to move fast and move quickly.<br><br>This is a &#8212; and this agreement, this infrastructure bill that &#8212; you know, it signals in the world that we can function, we can deliver.&nbsp; We can do significant things and show that America is back.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the message I delivered and received during the trip in Europe.&nbsp; I announced that America is going to help vaccinate the world, because that&#8217;s who we are.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we can do.<br><br>I also rallied our European allies to holding China to the same rules of the road in a global economy in the 21st century.&nbsp;<br></p>



<p>I made clear to President Putin and Russia that the relationship between America and Russia should be stable and predictable.  We should be able to cooperate where we have our interests, on nuclear non-proliferation and climate change.  And where we have differences, I made it clear to President Putin that I understand why &#8212; we have to understand what exists, and whether it&#8217;s on cyberattacks or interference in our <s>economy</s> [elections], I will respond.  I will respond.  And I know we’ll respond to specific kinds of actions that harm U.S. interests.<br><br>The bottom line of all this at home and abroad: We&#8217;re proving that our democracy can deliver for the people when autocrats are betting we can&#8217;t. <br><br>But we&#8217;ve got a lot more to do.  As we invest in our physical infrastructure, we also have to invest in our human infrastructure, the so-called Biden Family Plan bill.  We&#8217;re going to move on the American Family Plan that will deliver childcare, paid leave, universal pre-K, two years of community college, and so much more.<br><br>And I will take the case to the American people on the need to protect the sacred right to vote.  It’s under assault in ways that I haven&#8217;t seen in my entire career, and that&#8217;s what got me involved in the first place.  It&#8217;s about who gets to vote and whether the vote counts.  And we have a system that does both with integrity and independence.  But the Republicans want to do what no political party has ever tried to do: get to decide if your vote counts.  It&#8217;s outrageous.  We&#8217;re going to fight like hell to make sure that doesn&#8217;t happen. <br><br>There’s so much to say on all of these subjects.  I’m sorry (inaudible) such shorthand. <br><br>But to work &#8212; the work has not been easy, and I&#8217;m going to need all of you to help do that work.  The DNC is going to need you, because here&#8217;s the deal: We won in 2020 as a unified party, and we need to stay unified and keep doing the big consequential things.<br><br>If we make the right decisions in the next four &#8212; (inaudible) years, in 50 years, people will look back and say this was the moment that America won the future.  But we can&#8217;t do it without you.  And it&#8217;s not hyperbole to suggest what I said &#8212; that America won the future.<br><br>So, look, there&#8217;s so much more to say, but the bottom line is that there&#8217;s so much at stake.  But I promise you &#8212; I promise you, I&#8217;ve heard from almost every major world leader &#8212; I&#8217;ve heard from every major world leader: We can do this.  So we can, in the process, be helping the rest of the world by doing well for ourselves.<br><br>May God bless America, and may God protect our troops.  And I look forward to meeting you all in a virtual photo line, which I guess is going to begin very shortly.<br><br>7:08 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe Biden’s Meeting on Voting Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/29/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-meeting-on-voting-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 12:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met yesterday with White House Senior Advisors and outside experts to discuss voting rights in America. The President and this group discussed anti-voter legislation that has been proposed or recently passed by state legislatures, legislation pending before Congress, and recent actions taken by the Department of Justice to protect the right to vote. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met yesterday with White House Senior Advisors and outside experts to discuss voting rights in America. The President and this group discussed anti-voter legislation that has been proposed or recently passed by state legislatures, legislation pending before Congress, and recent actions taken by the Department of Justice to protect the right to vote. The President and his staff highlighted ways that the Administration will continue working with Congress to pass critical legislation and ramp up engagement with the American people on voting rights. The President also reiterated his unwavering determination to win the fight to protect the sacred right to vote in free and fair elections.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting with President Reuven Rivlin of Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/28/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-with-president-reuven-rivlin-of-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 02:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr.&#160;met today with President Reuven Rivlin of Israel to honor President Rivlin as he approaches the conclusion of his term and to demonstrate the enduring strength of the U.S.-Israel partnership.&#160; President Biden conveyed his unwavering support for Israel’s security and his commitment to deepening the cooperation between the two countries across&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr.&nbsp;met today with President Reuven Rivlin of Israel to honor President Rivlin as he approaches the conclusion of his term and to demonstrate the enduring strength of the U.S.-Israel partnership.&nbsp; President Biden conveyed his unwavering support for Israel’s security and his commitment to deepening the cooperation between the two countries across all fields.&nbsp; The leaders discussed the many challenges facing the region, including the threat posed by Iran.&nbsp; The President emphasized that under his administration, Iran will never get a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; He also assured President Rivlin that the United States remains determined to counter Iran’s malign activity and support for terrorist proxies, which have destabilizing consequences for the region.<br><br>The leaders also consulted on opportunities to enhance peace and stability in the Middle East and beyond.&nbsp; In that regard, the President expressed his strong support for the normalization of relations between Israel and other countries in the Arab and Muslim world.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The leaders also discussed recent developments in Gaza and the West Bank and the President emphasized the importance of Israel taking steps to ensure calm, stability, and to support greater economic opportunities for the Palestinian people.&nbsp; President Biden affirmed his view that a negotiated two-state solution remains the best avenue to achieving a lasting peace.&nbsp; The leaders discussed the importance of enhancing efforts to strengthen moderate voices and promote the cause of coexistence while weakening extremists who advocate for hatred and violence.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The President warmly extended an invitation for Prime Minister Naftali Bennett to meet with him soon at the White House and reaffirmed that this administration looks forward to close collaboration with the new Israeli government on the many important issues on the bilateral agenda.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on House Passage of the National Science Foundation for the Future Act and the Department of Energy Science for the Future Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/28/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-house-passage-of-the-national-science-foundation-for-the-future-act-and-the-department-of-energy-science-for-the-future-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In March, I outlined my vision for how we can grow our economy for all workers through the American Jobs Plan, and today the House took an important step in moving that forward by advancing two bipartisan bills. Led by Chairwoman Eddie Bernice Johnson and Ranking Member Frank Lucas, the National Science Foundation for the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In March, I outlined my vision for how we can grow our economy for all workers through the American Jobs Plan, and today the House took an important step in moving that forward by advancing two bipartisan bills. Led by Chairwoman Eddie Bernice Johnson and Ranking Member Frank Lucas, the National Science Foundation for the Future Act and the Department of Energy Science for the Future Act will make vital investments in R&amp;D, science, and our economic competitiveness, and re-affirm the role of science in helping us solve major challenges like the climate crisis.</p>



<p>Manufacturing, and the innovation fueling it, are the backbone of the American economy, and they’re powered by the American workers and unions who help build our middle-class and the strongest, most dynamic economy in the world. But decades of neglect and disinvestment have left us at a competitive disadvantage as countries across the globe, like China, have poured money and focus into new technologies and industries, leaving us at real risk of being left behind.</p>



<p>We need historic—once in a generation—investments in our competitiveness that support R&amp;D, innovation, our semiconductor industry, and advanced manufacturing to grow our economy and create good-paying middle-class jobs in every corner of America. By rebuilding those domestic sources of strength, we can out-compete China and the rest of the world for years to come.</p>



<p>I was pleased to see the Senate pass crucially important investments in our domestic strength through the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act with massive bipartisan support, and I’m heartened today to see the House pass similar bipartisan investments in R&amp;D and science tonight. These pieces of legislation—and the agreement reached on the infrastructure framework last week—show the American people, and the world, that we’re capable of coming together as a country and setting aside our differences to make transformational investments that will strengthen us both at home and abroad. My Administration looks forward to continuing to work with the House and the Senate in producing a final bill I can sign.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
