<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 22:13:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Bilateral Meeting between President Joe&#160;Biden and Micheál Martin, Taoiseach of&#160;Ireland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/13/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-bilateral-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-micheal-martin-taoiseach-of-ireland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49039</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On March 17, President Joe Biden will host Micheál Martin, Taoiseach of Ireland, for a bilateral meeting and Shamrock presentation at the White House, continuing a longstanding St. Patrick’s Day tradition. The leaders will reaffirm the close and historic partnership between the United States and Ireland and the extraordinary bonds between our people. They will discuss&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On March 17, President Joe Biden will host Micheál Martin, Taoiseach of Ireland, for a bilateral meeting and Shamrock presentation at the White House, continuing a longstanding St. Patrick’s Day tradition. The leaders will reaffirm the close and historic partnership between the United States and Ireland and the extraordinary bonds between our people. They will discuss their countries’ contributions to the international effort to support the people of Ukraine and to impose costs on Russia for its unprovoked and unjustified war. They will also talk about a range of global issues and shared priorities, including combatting the COVID-19 pandemic worldwide, strengthening global health security, tackling the climate crisis, and working together on the United Nations Security Council. In addition, they will discuss their continued support for the Good Friday Agreement (also known as the Belfast Agreement). Vice President Kamala Harris will host the Taoiseach for a breakfast at the Naval Observatory on March 17.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Senior Administration Travel to&#160;Rome</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/13/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-senior-administration-travel-to-rome/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49036</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and officials from the National Security Council and State Department will be in Rome. Sullivan will meet with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi as part of our ongoing efforts to maintain open lines of communication between&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and officials from the National Security Council and State Department will be in Rome. Sullivan will meet with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi as part of our ongoing efforts to maintain open lines of communication between the United States and the People’s Republic of China (PRC). The two sides will discuss ongoing efforts to manage the competition between our two countries and discuss the impact of Russia’s war against Ukraine on regional and global security. Sullivan will also meet with Luigi Mattiolo, Diplomatic Advisor to the Italian Prime Minister to continue coordinating a strong, united international response to President Putin’s war of choice. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the DNC Winter&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/12/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-dnc-winter-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 19:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Washington HiltonWashington, D.C. 12:41 P.M. EST THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone!  (Applause.)  Good afternoon, Democrats!  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Please, have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon. Jaime, thank you for those kind words and for your continuous leadership.  You’ve done such an outstanding job. And on behalf of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The Washington Hilton<br><em>Washington, D.C.</em></em></p>



<p>12:41 P.M. EST<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone!  (Applause.)  Good afternoon, Democrats!  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Please, have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.<br><br>Jaime, thank you for those kind words and for your continuous leadership.  You’ve done such an outstanding job.<br><br>And on behalf of the first Second Gentleman of the United States and myself &#8212; (applause) &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I want to say thank you to everybody in this room.  It is wonderful to see this group of friends in person.  <br><br>This, of course, is the first time that we have been able to get together in person since the President and I were inaugurated.  And I can just feel the energy in the room, which, of course, is reflective of the extraordinary dedication, commitment, and work that each of you have been doing over the course of the last couple of years, which presented, of course, many challenges because of the pandemic. <br><br>But for so many of you, this is part of a lifetime of commitment to extraordinary work on behalf of so many people in our country.  So thank you all.  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you.<br><br>And thank you for the work that you did to get us into the White House &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and to win control of the Senate, and to keep control of the House!  (Applause.) <br><br>You all did that work.  And, you know, sometimes you make it look easy, but it&#8217;s not.  It&#8217;s hard work.  It&#8217;s difficult work.  It&#8217;s around-the-clock work.  It&#8217;s work that requires great sacrifice in terms of the other commitments in your lives.<br><br>And you do this work on behalf of people sometimes that you meet, on behalf of people that you don&#8217;t meet.  You do this work on behalf of people that may never know your names, may never know my name, but will be forever impacted and, to our mission, uplifted because of the work of the people in this room.</p>



<p><br>And so when I think about where we are, based on the work that has already happened to get us here, I know it has been hard work and good work.  <br><br>I also want to give a special shout-out to the Californians in the room &#8212; (applause) &#8212; because how could I not.<br><br>But to everyone: Thank you again.<br><br>So I just returned this morning from Poland and Romania.  And I&#8217;ll tell you that everything that you were watching on television I know makes you understand and feel the importance of this moment on many levels. </p>



<p><br>When I was meeting with our allies, I emphasized that the greatest strength that we share is unity, especially at this moment, as we stand together in defense of democracy and stand together in defense of each other.  (Applause.)<br><br>And that unity and &#8212; to our collective resolve has been strengthened, of course, since Russians’ reinvasion of Ukraine and Putin&#8217;s war.<br><br>Russia&#8217;s invasion threatens not just Ukraine&#8217;s democracy, it threatens democracy and security across Europe.  And by extension, when democracy is threatened anywhere, it threatens us all.  And the ocean that separates us will not leave us untouched by this aggression.<br><br>So I will say what I know we all say, and I will say over and over again: The United States stands firmly with the Ukrainian people [and] in defense of the NATO Alliance.  (Applause.) <br><br>And I&#8217;ll tell you, while I was &#8212; while I was there these last couple of days, I met with the presidents of both nations, and I &#8212; and I met with refugees from Ukraine, some of who are Ukrainian citizens, others who were students studying in Ukraine from other countries.<br><br>And, you know, they feel very alone, of course, because of the experience they&#8217;ve been having.  One of them was a 22-year-old student from Morocco who fled by himself, doesn&#8217;t know anybody.<br><br>And because of the experience they&#8217;ve had, they&#8217;ve, of course, not been in a room like this among the population, the multitude of people who support them.  And I told them &#8212; and so what you did to stand and applaud them in this point means a lot.  I told them people around the world stand with them, and they are not alone.<br><br>When I was there, I met with a group of American troops who are there with a group of troops from Poland, working together, training together &#8212; attempting to understand each other&#8217;s language, but yet speaking the same language &#8212; in their fight for what is important about this moment.<br><br>So, again, I thank you all.<br><br>Days before I traveled to Poland, with many of you, I was in Selma to commemorate the 57th anniversary &#8212; (applause) &#8212; of the march across the Edmund Pettus Bridge, that historic place which is a stark reminder that we must always remain vigilant to safeguard freedom and democracy.  Because we all know, in this room, neither is assured without our vigilance.  And defending democracy, then, takes all of us.<br><br>As I said last week about the great Congressman John Lewis &#8212; (applause) &#8212; this fight for democracy, for freedom, for equality, for justice requires of all of us, like John Lewis modeled &#8212; it requires from all of us a clarity of purpose and a determination and diligence to always keep our eye on the ball, understanding that in this fight for democracy, we must appreciate its character and nature. <br><br>We must understand that when we have a democracy that reflects its values by treating people with a sense of equality and fairness and justice, we can see, when it works, it possesses great strengths. </p>



<p><br>And we must always remember the duality of a democracy in that, yes, there is strength.  But a democracy by its nature is also fragile, meaning it will only be intact if we fight for it and never take it for granted and be vigilant with a sense of clarity every day.  (Applause.)<br><br>And that&#8217;s what we in this room stand for &#8212; all of us fighting and marching and pushing forward together to reach our ideals in the constant effort to create a more perfect union. <br><br>You know, when the President and I took office, our country was facing the aftermath of a reckless president, the COVID-19 pandemic, and questions about America&#8217;s leadership on the world stage.  We had a plan to get America back on track with the support of the American people and the leaders in this room.<br><br>We knew, all of us, our election should herald a change in direction, not just a change in management.  And President Biden and I, then, with your help and leadership, chartered a new course for our nation&#8217;s future.  And we rebuilt relationships with our allies.  And the results of that effort are clear as we stand together in this unified rebuke of Russia.<br><br>The President and I also proposed, with your leadership, with your help, the American Rescue Plan &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to fight through the impact of COVID.  And since that plan was enacted last year, we went from 2 million people vaccinated to over 215 million vaccinated in our country.  (Applause.)<br><br>Businesses are back open, and 99 percent of our schools are no longer remote.  We went from 60,000 jobs created each month to 678,000 jobs created last month &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and over 7 million total jobs created since we took office.<br><br>Unemployment is down 3.8 percent.  Black unemployment is at an all-time low, and Hispanic unemployment has fallen by historic amounts.  (Applause.)<br><br>The Child Tax Credit cut childhood poverty for the children &#8212; the children &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Latino children, Black children, poor children, Appalachian children &#8212; by 40 percent.  (Applause.) <br><br>Because of your work, and with your help, we passed a once-in-a-generation infrastructure law.  (Applause.)  And it will create more jobs, it will rebuild communities.  I&#8217;m sorry, it will create more jobs, including good union jobs.  (Applause.)  That&#8217;s right.  That&#8217;s right.  Because we&#8217;re clear on who helped build the middle class of America.  We&#8217;re clear on that.<br><br>So, yes, it will create more jobs, it’ll rebuild communities and do so much more to help America&#8217;s families.<br><br>For example, just last week, we announced nearly one and a half billion dollars in grants to help cities and towns electrify their fleet of public buses, build infrastructure to support their fleet, and train workers. <br><br>Thank you, again, for all of the apprenticeships run by our unions that are training these workers &#8212; (applause) &#8212; with extraordinary skills to actually do the work.<br><br>And think about it on the issue of public transit: So, this will make public transit more reliable, more affordable, and more efficient.  So imagine, if you will, a mother or a father trying to get out of the house during the week, in the morning, trying to get the kids to school and get to work. <br><br>And then imagine for that parent, one of them kids don&#8217;t want to put on their shoes.  Familiar experience.  And so that parent misses the bus by just a few minutes.  If the bus only comes by once an hour, those kids are going to be late for school, mom or dad is going to be late for work.<br><br>And that might mean having their pay docked or potentially even losing their job. <br><br>Public transit: Working people in America, in so many places in our country, rely on it for all of their essential needs.  This is about to change with an investment of billion dollars &#8212; in billions of dollars in public transit.<br>So when we look at this issue, it is one of many. <br><br>But we&#8217;re not going to stop there, and we didn&#8217;t stop there.  More than 70 percent of the judicial nominees we have appointed are women.  (Applause.)  More than 70 percent. <br><br>And, of course, the President recently nominated Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson to the United States Supreme Court.  (Applause.)<br><br>And I&#8217;ll share with you guys &#8212; going off script &#8212; I’ll share with you guys: So, the President and I were there at the White House for the day of the &#8212; of the &#8212; that he announced his nomination, and many of you may have watched it on television.  And so we were in the back before we went out.  And before we walked out, I just looked at our President and I said, “You’re again making history.  You&#8217;re again making history.”  Think about that. <br><br>You know, when we &#8212; when we look at the job we have in the coming months, and people will look at all of us as leaders and they&#8217;ll say, “Well, why should I vote?  Why does it matter?”  There&#8217;s so much we have to talk about.  We have collectively, on many levels, achieved historic feats.  And let&#8217;s be proud of that &#8212; knowing, of course, that there is still more to do.  Let&#8217;s be proud of that.  Be proud of that.  (Applause.)<br><br>And so, on the issue of Judge Jackson, she will make an outstanding and extraordinary jurist.  And if confirmed, of course, she will be the first Black woman on the highest court in the land.  (Applause.) <br><br>And &#8212; don&#8217;t let this be lost in terms of this point in history: And for the first time in history, four women will sit on the United States Supreme Court at the same time.  (Applause.)  How about that?  How about that? <br><br>So there&#8217;s a whole long list I could go through, but you all know it.  And, you know, I know you&#8217;ve been meeting for a couple days, so I&#8217;m not going to do that to you.  But I will say that, together, we have accomplished so much.  And, of course, yes, there is more to do.<br><br>As the President laid out in his State of the Union, it&#8217;s time to bring down costs &#8212; the cost of living &#8212; even more.  It is time to create more union jobs.  It is time to ensure that everyone has an opportunity to succeed.  It is time to defend our democracy and be vigilant in its defense, and to safeguard our planet for generations to come.  It is time to do so much more.<br><br>And over the past year, I have traveled our country, talking with many leaders including those from, of course, this room, those from the Latino community, the Black community, AAPI community, LGBTQ+ community, the disability community, all around our country.<br><br>And we have talked about many of the issues that I know over the last couple of days this group has addressed.  We have talked about one of the most urgent issues as well, in terms of how the clock is ticking on a purposeful attack against our democracy being waged in states around our country.  And that is on the attack on the freedom to vote. <br><br>And we have talked about what we must do, us as leaders, all of us, understanding the intentions that are at play, which are to make it more difficult for people to vote &#8212; certain populations in particular &#8212; with an expectation that if you make it more difficult, then people won&#8217;t vote.<br><br>We have discussed together our frustrations and fears.  We&#8217;ve talked about the rights that we fought so hard to win and how they could be lost. <br><br>But I will say, as we talked about last week in Selma: We must fight on, because we know all of our rights and all of our progress depends on the freedom to vote &#8212; workers’ rights, women&#8217;s rights, immigrant rights, LGBTQ rights.<br><br>All of the rights that we hold so dear flow from the right to vote.<br><br>So the DNC, of course, has taken on a role of leadership on this issue, as well as all the others, and in this fight making substantial investments &#8212; and thank you &#8212; in organizing, in strengthening state party infrastructure and protecting voters.<br><br>Last summer, I was proud to announce that the DNC would invest $25 million in its I Will Vote initiative to make voting more accessible and to fight back against Republicans’ unprecedented voter suppression efforts. <br><br>As the tiebreaking vote in the Senate &#8212; I am the President of the Senate &#8212; I know, as you do &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I know, as you do, that protecting our majorities on Capitol Hill is critical.  And that is why President Biden announced that the DNC will transfer $15 million to the DCCC and the DSCC.  (Applause.)<br><br>So, the work ahead is not going to be easy.  Everybody knows that.  That&#8217;s why you all are here, knowing the work that must be done, knowing it&#8217;s not going to be easy, but knowing we are under one roof together, in solidarity, in our commitment to seeing this through.<br><br>I know, and I believe we know, when we show what we have accomplished just in a year, and when we show it as because the American people voted, I believe we will meet the moment again.  But that is our task.  Our task is to show people that, in many ways, they got what they ordered.  Right?  (Applause.)  They said this is what they wanted.  They stood in line.  They took time from work.  It was difficult.  And a lot of what they demanded, they got. <br><br>And so let&#8217;s get out there, as we do, and remind them of that.  Because we know that they will show up again and they will say, “Yes, we want better jobs at higher wages.”  They will say yes to extending the Child Tax Credit.  They will say, “Yes, we must fight climate change.”  They will say, “Yes, I wanted and got and want more diversity on the Court.”  They will say, “Yes, we must fight to protect reproductive rights.”  (Applause.) <br><br>We have faith in what they want and how much they want it and what they are prepared to do to get it.<br>So our job is the job of just supporting the people, supporting their voices, supporting their will and desire of what their government has a responsibility to deliver to uplift our nation and to strengthen it.  That&#8217;s at the core of the work we do.<br><br>When we fight for social justice, when we fight for equal rights, when we fight for all that is on our list of priorities, that&#8217;s our mission: to strengthen our nation &#8212; so that when I go overseas, when the President goes overseas, when you talk to folks, and we say, “America is a beacon, it is a model,” that we can actually back that up.  That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing.  (Applause.)  That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing. <br><br>We are, as Democrats, continuing to own the responsibility that comes with being a role model, which is, as a democracy, to take care of its people &#8212; to see them, to hear them, and to be reflective of their priorities and their needs.<br><br>So, DNC, we will keep working the phones, and we will keep registering the voters, and we will keep getting the souls to the polls.  (Applause.)  And we will keep doing all that is necessary to fight for the best of who we are.<br><br>Thank you, DNC.  (Applause.)  Thank you for your leadership.  Thank you all.<br><br>END                 1:05 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/12/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 15:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49028</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961         By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America,&#160;including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate to the Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961        </p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America,&nbsp;including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $200 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris to U.S. and Polish&#160;Troops</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/11/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-to-u-s-and-polish-troops/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 23:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49023</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Warsaw Chopin International AirportWarsaw, Poland THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Good morning, good morning.  So it was very important for the President of the United States and me to be here on the ground to say hello and to say thank you to all of you for your service, for your sacrifice, for your dedication,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Warsaw Chopin International Airport<br><em>Warsaw, Poland</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Good morning, good morning.  So it was very important for the President of the United States and me to be here on the ground to say hello and to say thank you to all of you for your service, for your sacrifice, for your dedication, for your patriotism.<br><br>You know, I’ll just say that I start every morning reading what we call the Presidential Daily Brief, which is generated by our intelligence community, and where I read about hotspots around the world and, in the case of the United States, threats to our national security.  (Inaudible).<br><br>Then I got into the Oval Office and I sit down with the President and the Secretary of Defense and the Joint Chiefs, the Chairman.  And we talk about you guys, and how proud we are and your service. <br><br>We talked about the fact that Poland joined NATO in 1999.  And since 2014, the United States made a commitment to our friends in Poland to support you.  And that’s when we first sent troops on a rotational basis, averaging about 5,000, and then over the course of the last couple of months, another 4,700 to stand with you in the alliance that is the NATO Alliance. <br><br>I&#8217;ve said in many places, I will say again today, that part of being in the NATO Alliance means that we have a motto which we (inaudible): An attack against one is an attack against all.  And the United States takes that commitment very seriously.  It is part of the reason I am here.<br><br>In this moment of Russian aggression and Putin’s war, we take seriously our commitment to defend, if necessary, every inch of NATO territory.  So that is why I&#8217;m here, to reinforce and reaffirm that commitment.  But these men and women are on the ground to see it through as necessary. <br><br>I was with President Duda yesterday, and we spoke of this collaboration, this partnership, this friendship and what it means to our two nations, and what it symbolizes for us as nations that are grounded and founded in certain principles, including the importance of sovereignty and territorial integrity.  And that&#8217;s what&#8217;s at stake as much as anything in terms of Russia&#8217;s reinvasion of Ukraine. <br><br>So, we stand as partners.  We work together.  We train together.  We form friendships that are based on solidarity, mutual values, and shared principles. <br><br>All of you took an oath to protect and defend your country.  You have each decided to live a life of service, doing some of the most important work any individual could ever do, which is prepare to sacrifice for the sake of your nation.  That is some of the most noble work any human being (inaudible). <br><br>So, before I got on that plane, I wanted to come by and tell you all &#8212; all of you &#8212; thank you.  When we are in those rooms making decisions, it is you we have in mind, knowing that when we stand firm, we can back it up with you &#8212; some of the best fighting forces in the world.  So thank you all &#8212; all of you.  Thank you all. <br><br>And with that, I want to meet every one of you.  So let’s do that.   </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.J. Res.&#160;75</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/bill-signed-h-j-res-75/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 23:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49014</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On&#160;Friday,&#160;March&#160;11, 2022, the President signed into law: H.J.Res. 75, the &#8220;Extension of Continuing Appropriations Act, 2022,&#8221; which provides fiscal year 2022 appropriations to Federal agencies through March 15, 2022, for continuing projects and activities of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On&nbsp;Friday,&nbsp;March&nbsp;11, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.J.Res. 75, the &#8220;Extension of Continuing Appropriations Act, 2022,&#8221; which provides fiscal year 2022 appropriations to Federal agencies through March 15, 2022, for continuing projects and activities of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Tennessee Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-tennessee-disaster-declaration-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 23:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Tennessee and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm from February 3 to February 4, 2022. Federal funding is available to state and eligible local governments and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Tennessee and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm from February 3 to February 4, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to state and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storm in the counties of Crockett, Fayette, Haywood, Lauderdale, Shelby, Tipton, and Weakley.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Myra M. Shird as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the House Democratic Caucus Issues&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/11/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-house-democratic-caucus-issues-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 22:18:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hilton Philadelphia at Penn&#8217;s LandingPhiladelphia, Pennsylvania 12:41 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Please.&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Please, sit down.&#160; Please.&#160; I&#8217;ve been to enough Senate caucuses and Democratic retreats to know that when the last speaker is up, you want to get the hell out of here &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; no matter&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Hilton Philadelphia at Penn&#8217;s Landing<br>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>12:41 P.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Please.&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Please, sit down.&nbsp; Please.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been to enough Senate caucuses and Democratic retreats to know that when the last speaker is up, you want to get the hell out of here &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; no matter who it is.&nbsp; But thank you.<br><br>Look, folks, let me begin by saying that when I ran &#8212; and a lot of you helped me; a lot of good people ran &#8212; I made it clear I was running for three reasons, and &#8212; because I had no intention of running for office again when I left the vice presidency.&nbsp; But when I saw those folks come out of those fields down in Charlottesville, carrying torches and singing Nazi slogans and carrying swastikas, and white supremacists, I decided to get engaged.&nbsp;<br><br>The point is this: I had a message, which I didn&#8217;t consult with anybody about generating, to begin with, which was not viewed as being very saleable.&nbsp; The first was that I thought it was essential to literally restore the soul of this country &#8212; a sense of decency and honor, a sense of &#8212; a sense that you could trust one another &#8212; just restore the soul of the country, because what we were seeing was not who we are.&nbsp; And among some of our Republicans, what they&#8217;re saying is still not who we are.</p>



<p>The second thing I wanted to do that has been the essence of my whole career, from the time I ran 20 miles from here &#8212; a 29-year-old kid for the Senate &#8212; was that I wanted to rebuild the backbone of the country.&nbsp; And the backbone of the country is the working class and middle class.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so sick and tired of trickle-down.&nbsp; When the middle class does well, the poor have a way up and the wealthy do just fine.&nbsp; They do just fine.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And third thing, which a lot of you didn&#8217;t like &#8212; I know &#8212; I thought we had to unify the country, because, ultimately, we are a democracy.&nbsp; And there needs to be &#8212; for it to work, there has to be consensus.&nbsp; In a consensus, you got to get a majority.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve not been able to do that for a lot of the important things.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have to continue to maintain our majority.&nbsp;<br><br>This off-year election, in my view, may be the most important off-year election in modern history.&nbsp; Because we know what happens: We know the fundamental change that shifts if we lose the House and the Senate.&nbsp; The only thing I&#8217;ll have then is a veto pen.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, folks, I want to thank Nancy for the introduction, for your friendship all these years, Nance.&nbsp; And, Paul, thank you as well.&nbsp;<br><br>And I want to thank &#8212; the extraordinary job you’ve done delivering the omnibus, just like you delivered so many critical pieces of legislation last year.<br><br>And Hakeem and Steny and Jim and Emanuel Cleaver and Pete, Congresswoman Katherine Clark and all of you out there: Let me first say that &#8212; I want to say thank you &#8212; thank you for the support you’ve provided Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I was on the phone today for a better part of an hour with &#8212; with Zelenskyy, who I speak to almost daily.&nbsp; The people of Ukraine have demonstrated a remarkable source of bravery and courage.&nbsp; But the security assistance that you’ve provided has been absolutely critical &#8212; critical in their defense.&nbsp;<br><br>Second, I want to thank you for showing a unified front to the world.&nbsp; When Putin unleashed his assault, he thought he could divide NATO.&nbsp; He thought he could literally divide this country, the West &#8212; the United States &#8212; in terms of the parties.&nbsp; I know a former ambassador knows that out there.&nbsp; He thought he could divide Democrats and Republicans at home.&nbsp; But he failed.&nbsp; He failed.&nbsp;<br><br>For months, the United States has worked tirelessly to keep our Allies and partners together.&nbsp; As our former ambassador &#8212; who you see on television a lot, thank God &#8212; will tell you I&#8217;ve spent literally hours and hours and hours and hours keeping the Alliance together &#8212; the EU, NATO, and all of our allies, including our Asian allies.&nbsp;<br><br>As a result, we&#8217;ve been able to ramp up our economic pressure on Putin and further isolate Russia on the global stage.<br><br>This morning, along with the G7 nations &#8212; in Germany, Canada, France, Italy, Japan, and the United Kingdom &#8212; we moved &#8212; which I know you wanted to do initially &#8212; and Nancy, I drove her crazy &#8212; on most-favored-nation status &#8212; as we call it in the United States, “permanent normal trade relations” &#8212; and eliminate them.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>But, folks, I know I&#8217;ve occasionally frustrated you, but more important than us moving when we want to is making sure all of NATO is together &#8212; is together.&nbsp; They have different vulnerabilities than we do.&nbsp; Just like in the oil embargo, a lot of them could not &#8212; the only way I was &#8212; it took, I think, you know, weeks to work out.&nbsp; I said, “We&#8217;re going to block oil &#8212; Russian oil energy and energy.”&nbsp;<br><br>We consume 15 percent of it; they rely totally on it.&nbsp; Without Russian oil, they&#8217;re going to find themselves in a position where they get choked off in a way that far exceeds anything we do &#8212; anything we do.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So it took a long time sitting with my counterparts and saying, “Look, we&#8217;re going to block oil, but I&#8217;m not going to ask you to do it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to say to you, ‘You do what you can.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to explain why it&#8217;s not rational for you to do the same thing.&nbsp; In the meantime, we&#8217;re going to help you get energy through liquefied natural gas and a whole range of other things.’”<br><br>The point is: Revoking PNTR for Russia has made it harder for Russia to do business with the United States.&nbsp; But in doing it with unison with our Allies that, kept together, make up half the global economy &#8212; half of it &#8212; is a crushing blow to Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>Along with our partners and Allies, we&#8217;ve stepped up pressure on corrupt Russian billionaires.&nbsp; We&#8217;re increasing &#8212; we&#8217;re increasing coordination among the G7 countries and &#8212; to target, capture the ill-begotten gains &#8212; the yachts.&nbsp; You see some of these yachts &#8212; 450 feet long.&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; Hundreds of millions of dollars in value. &nbsp;Their luxury apartments.&nbsp;<br><br>The totality of our economic sanctions and export controls are crushing &#8212; crushing the Russian economy.&nbsp; The ruble has lost &#8212; and I know many of you know this in detail &#8212; lost more than half its value.&nbsp; You know what the value of a ruble is versus a dollar?&nbsp; You need 200 rubles to equal 1 dollar today &#8212; 200.&nbsp;<br><br>The Moscow stock exchange is closed for a simple reason.&nbsp;&nbsp;I get asked, “Well, why is it closed?”&nbsp; Because &#8212; for the last two weeks &#8212; because the moment it opens, it will be disbanded.&nbsp; You hear me?&nbsp; It will blow up.</p>



<p>Credit-rating agencies have downgraded Russia’s government to “junk” status &#8212; “junk” status.&nbsp; And the list of private businesses and international corporations leaving Russia is growing day by day by day.<br><br>I want to be clear though: We’re going to make sure Ukraine has the weapons to defend themselves from invading Russian force.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we will send money and food aid to save Euro- &#8212; Ukrainian lives.<br><br>We’re going to welcome Ukrainian refugees with open arms if, in fact, they come all the way here.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And as we provide &#8212; as we provide this support to Ukraine, we’re going to continue to stand together with our allies in Europe and send an unmistakable message that we will defend every inch of NATO territory –- every single inch &#8212; with a united, galvanized NATO.&nbsp; One movement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why I’ve moved over 12,000 American forces along the borders with Russia &#8212; Latvia, Estonia, Lithuania, Romania, et cetera &#8212; because they move once.&nbsp; Granted, if we respond, it is World War Three, but we have a sacred obligation on NATO territory &#8212; a sacred obligation &#8212; Article 5.&nbsp; And we will not &#8212; although we will not fight the third World War in Ukraine.&nbsp; Putin’s war against Ukraine is never going to be a victory.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><s>Democrats</s>&nbsp;[Democracies] are rising to meet the moment, relying &#8212; rallying the world on the side of peace and security.&nbsp; We are showing a strength, and we’ll never falter.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, look, the idea &#8212; the idea that we’re going to send in offensive equipment and have planes and tanks and trains going in with American pilots and American crews, just understand &#8212; and don’t kid yourself, no matter what you all say &#8212; that’s called “World War Three.”&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; Let’s get it straight here, guys.&nbsp; That old expression &#8212; “Don’t kid a kidder.”<br><br>Now, I’d like to speak to our broader purpose here today to remind everybody where we were a year ago, where we’ve gotten since, the direction we’re headed in.&nbsp; And all of you know that today is&nbsp;the anniversary, as Nancy said, since we passed the American Rescue Plan within the first month in office, thank God.&nbsp; Thank God you did it.</p>



<p>Was it anybody’s thought we’re going to pass a bill that’s 1 trillion 900 billion dollars?&nbsp; We’re going to do that?&nbsp; Yeah, you did it.&nbsp; I asked, and you did it.<br><br>Few pieces of legislation &#8212; no hyperbole &#8212; in American history have done more to lift this country out of a crisis than what you did.<br><br>It took about 2 million Americans before I was &#8212; before I was sworn in &#8212; 2 million Americans had been vaccinated.<br><br>Today, because of the efforts you’ve &#8212; what you’ve voted for, we have more than 215 million Americans fully vaccinated.<br><br>You all remember the lines of cars &#8212; you remember?&nbsp; Nice-looking cars, stretched for hours and hours to (inaudible) just to get a box of food.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; Stretching those miles and miles no longer is happening.&nbsp; That box of food is not only in the table &#8212; in the trunk.&nbsp; Because of that law, 41 million people put food on their table and are putting it on the table who wouldn’t have been able to.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Because of that law, we helped to keep a roof over 4 million people’s heads who were about to be evicted.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we gave families what my dad used to call “just a little breathing room.”&nbsp; Just a little bit of breathing room<em>.</em></p>



<p>Because we took action, we created &#8212; we created&nbsp;6.7 million jobs last year &#8212; more than any other time in American history.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we haven’t stopped.&nbsp; Last month, we created over 7- &#8212; 678,000 jobs in February to get us well over 7 million jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Unemployment is down [to] 3.8 percent.&nbsp; The economy grew 5.7 percent &#8212; the best economic growth in the last four decades.&nbsp; And the leading financial firm on Wall Street, Moody’s, estimates that because of the Rescue Plan, 4 million more jobs were created, unemployment is 2 percent lower than it would have been and &#8212; had we failed to act.&nbsp; And it didn’t cause the inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look,&nbsp;there’s more to the story than that.&nbsp; Many of you remember when we went through the last financial crisis in 2008.&nbsp; I had the dubious distinction of the President standing before all of you and said, “And Sheriff Joe is going take care of the Recovery Act.”&nbsp; (Laughter.) &nbsp;Well, guess what?&nbsp; The economy recovered, but underneath the recovery, just like the re- &#8212; like every other recovery in our history, there was a lot of pain &#8212; a lot of pain.<br><br>Republicans in Congress refused to give President Obama the additional Recovery funds he asked for.&nbsp; And the truth is, a lot of folks never got back on their feet.&nbsp; A whole lot of young people saw their futures dimmed, diminished.&nbsp; They didn’t get back on track.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what’s &#8212; economists called the “economic scarring” that occurred as a consequence of that recession: the chronic pain when an economy comes back but some of the folks who were left behind were left behind almost permanently, trapped in long-term unemployment, evictions and foreclosures.<br><br>Study after study showed that when you’re stuck in that cycle, it has the worst impact on your emotional health and that of your children and your family members that you can imagine.&nbsp; And that’s serious.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So when I came to office in the midst of this crisis, I was determined not to let that happen.&nbsp; Together, we made the choice to ask for all that we needed, to leave nobody behind, to minimize the pain and the hopelessness and the despair that so many had just lost their jobs, lost everything through no fault of their own.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And look what happened.&nbsp; It isn’t just that the unemployment rate has dropped at a record pace.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’ve also seen the biggest drop in long-term unemployment ever recorded in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Nearly 2.5 million Americans have got to break out of that cycle of long-term unemployment.<br><br>We’ve seen the most significant drop in Black and Hispanic unemployment ever recorded.&nbsp; Black [un]employment fell by more than 30 percent.&nbsp; Hispanic fell &#8212; Hispanic employment &#8212; unemployment fell by 9 percent to 4.4 percent.<br><br>We’ve seen the lowest child poverty rate ever recorded &#8212; 40 percent decline in child poverty.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>The lowest num- &#8212; the lower number of harm forcl- &#8212; home foreclosures ever recorded, down to less than a third of what they were we were before the pandemic.<br><br>Record low credit card delinquencies because families had money in their pockets.<br><br>The list goes on.&nbsp; We’ve got a long way to go, though.&nbsp; I’m not saying we’re over; we’re just getting going.&nbsp; And a lot of work to do.&nbsp; But never forget what we’ve accomplished together so far.</p>



<p>And, by the way, the American people just trying to stay above water don’t understand this.&nbsp; You tell them what the American Recovery Act was, and they look at you like, “What<br>are you talking about?”&nbsp; Understandably.&nbsp; They’re like my family: mom, dad, four kids, grandpop living in the house in a three-bedroom split-level home.&nbsp; Just every single day figuring out how you put enough food on the table even when things are okay.<br><br>Well &#8212; and on this one anniversary of the American Rescue Plan, let&#8217;s be clear: We did it alone, without one single, solitary Republican vote.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>The American economy was flat on its back.&nbsp; It was the Democrats &#8212; it was you that brought us back.&nbsp; And you didn&#8217;t stop there.&nbsp; You invested in America.<br><br>In fact, you passed the biggest investment of rebuilding the nation in history.&nbsp; Now, it&#8217;s true we got some Republicans friends &#8212; to help on their for &#8212; on the Recovery &#8212; on &#8212; excuse me, on the Infrastructure Act.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re talking how many in the House &#8212; 12, 13, 14, or something?&nbsp; Whatever it was.<br><br>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; Thirteen!<br><br>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; Thirteen.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thirteen.&nbsp; I mean, come on.&nbsp; I mean, I was happy for them, don’t get me wrong.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And then every one of them got attacked.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, have &#8212; but have you noticed that every new bridge, every trench dug put in the &#8212; to take out lead pipes, every trench dug, there&#8217;s a Republican standing there saying, “This is a great thing.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Wonderful.&nbsp; We did it.&nbsp; Even Mitch McConnell, for God&#8217;s sake.<br><br>You know, as we say in my outfit, “Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.&nbsp; There has been so much since our last confession.”<br><br>Look, the simple fact is: This Infrastructure Bill is going to transform America.&nbsp; I mean, not figuratively, literally transform America.&nbsp; And it’s already starting.&nbsp;<br><br>Instead of having “Infrastructure Week,” we have an “Infrastructure Decade” we voted for.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We got 4,000 projects all across the country, including 1,500 bridges in disrepair that are starting to be repaired this year.&nbsp; This year.&nbsp; People back home need to know what’s happening.<br><br>By the way, where&#8217;s my Pittsburgh group?&nbsp; Where are you?&nbsp; They&#8217;re in Pittsburgh.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Anyway, I just out &#8212; was out in Pittsburgh.&nbsp; That &#8212; that bridge &#8212; you saw that bridge; it was devastating.&nbsp; I stood there about that bridge that had gone down an hour before I got there.&nbsp; Over a hundred-foot fall.&nbsp; Only a couple folks on that bridge.&nbsp; And if it had been two hours later, school buses would have been filled, children would have died.&nbsp; I mean, it was &#8212; you saw the pictures in the paper.&nbsp; You ought to stand there and lean over and look at it.<br><br>Look, we need to tell the American people this law is going to create millions of jobs rebuilding roads and bridges, airports and ports, Internet, and a whole range of other things.&nbsp; Because that&#8217;s what it’s going to do.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s why &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get into it right now, but that&#8217;s where we have to make sure we have our education system up and running so we can produce the kind of workers we need, et cetera.<br><br>But it&#8217;s going to start to get rid of the poisonous lead pipes as well so our kids and families can drink clean water.&nbsp; There&#8217;s 10 million homes with lead pipes in America.&nbsp; And some of you on the Health Committee know the incredible studies done on the impact of lead on the brain of children and children&#8217;s development.&nbsp; Four hundred thousand schools.<br><br>We’re going to invest $65 billion to deliver affordable high-speed Internet everywhere in America: urban, suburban, Tribal, city.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, we can&#8217;t be &#8212; this is the United States of America.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t be the country where for a mom to get her kid on the Internet to be able to do their homework has to pull into a McDonald&#8217;s parking lot.&nbsp; I mean, for real, that’s what was happening.&nbsp;<br><br>This law is going to put an end to all of that.&nbsp; It’s going to put people in a much different position to be able to determine their own &#8212; their own judgments about when to sell their cattle, when they should &#8212; I just &#8212; just &#8212; we’re going to change things.&nbsp;<br><br>But look, we all know that despite the progress we’ve made, families are still struggling.&nbsp; They’re struggling with higher prices.<br><br>As I said, I grew up in a family &#8212; when the price of gas went up, everybody felt it.&nbsp; You talked about it.&nbsp; It mattered.&nbsp; It mattered.<br><br>But let&#8217;s be absolutely clear about why prices are so high right now.&nbsp; They’re very high for two reasons, notwithstanding what the Republicans say: COVID, number one.&nbsp; What happened was, the glo- &#8212; the way the global economy works: If a factory in Taiwan makes computer chips shuts down because of COVID, it causes a ripple effect that can slow down the manufacturing in Detroit, which it did.&nbsp; One hitch can hold up everything.<br><br>Because of the pandemic, we’ve had disruptions in our supply chain materials and important materials.<br><br>At the same time, the strength and speed of our economic recovery and families making more money still kept up.&nbsp; So here you had an unusual situation that, during a pandemic, people had money to spend.&nbsp; But what they didn’t do is they didn’t want &#8212; they didn’t want to go to restaurants.&nbsp; They didn’t want to go out and go on vacations.&nbsp; They didn’t spend money on leisure activities.&nbsp; So they wanted to spend it on other things &#8212; on hard goods, home improvements, televisions, additions to their homes &#8212; the very products that slowed down by disruptions in the supply chain, because there weren’t people cutting two-by-fours.&nbsp; Because of COVID, they were shut down.&nbsp;<br><br>I could go on a list.&nbsp; You all know this.&nbsp; I’m preaching to the choir here.&nbsp;<br><br>So what happened?&nbsp; Prices went up exponentially.&nbsp;<br><br>Just take a look at automobiles last year.&nbsp; One third of all the inflation in America last year was because of the price of automobiles.&nbsp; People had the money to buy automobiles, finally.&nbsp; But because the companies couldn’t get semiconductors, they couldn’t make the automobiles.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The result: The price of automobiles skyrocketed.&nbsp;<br><br>And used cars &#8212; the reason used cars went up is because when the &#8212; when the COVID hit and the leisure industry shut down, the rental cars sold all their stock.&nbsp; So people were in real trouble.&nbsp;<br><br>The second big reason for inflation is Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; From the moment he put his over 150,000 troops on the Ukrainian border, the price of gasoline&nbsp;<s>in</s>&nbsp;[since] January went up 75 cents.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Then Putin began amassing troops along the border.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; The world took notice.&nbsp; And those of you who work in the business know that the market anticipated and pricing went up more.&nbsp; And then Putin invaded.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Make no mistake, inflation is largely the fault of Putin.&nbsp; I love &#8212; you know, the Republicans are saying it’s “Biden&#8217;s gas pipeline.”&nbsp; “Biden said he&#8217;s going to stop the Keystone Pipeline…” &#8212; and I did &#8212; “…and that&#8217;s the reason prices went up.”</p>



<p>Folks, let&#8217;s get something straight here: The Keystone Pipeline was two years away.&nbsp; It had been 2 percent finished.&nbsp; Give me a break.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Give me a break.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Headline fact checker in the New York Times: “Republicans Wrongly Blame Biden for Rising Gas Prices.”&nbsp; And it goes on to explain why gas prices are so high.</p>



<p>Washington Post op-ed by &#8212; by Dana Milbank, “Opinion: Biden Heeded Republicans’ Plea to Ban Russian Oil.&nbsp; They Pounced.”&nbsp; And it goes on to talk about why it’s got &#8212; don’t let anybody tell you anything you did supporting the idea that we block Russian oil coming into the country, which is g- &#8212; and I said at the time prices are going to go up for gasoline.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t anything we did.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, you&#8217;re in a situation right now where if you take a look, the idea can we &#8212; “can we pump more oil?”&nbsp; There are now &#8212; now five &#8212; there are 172 gas and oil rigs running.&nbsp; Now we have &#8212; there were 519 in operation before this all began.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But guess what?&nbsp; They have over 7,000 permits to dig oil if they want.&nbsp; Why aren&#8217;t they out pumping oil?&nbsp; Why aren’t they out pumping oil?&nbsp; Because they&#8217;ve said and they’re very clear &#8212; Wall Street bankers have made it very clear &#8212; not a joke, check it out.&nbsp; And I recommend these two articles to you, just as a little bit of a primer.&nbsp; You probably already know it.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>What&#8217;s happened?&nbsp; Well, the oil companies and executives, they don&#8217;t want to pump more oil, although they have every capacity to do so.&nbsp; Nothing is slowing them up from doing it if they want to.</p>



<p>Why?&nbsp; Rather than spend the profits on the increased price of gasoline, they would rather take those profits and buy back stock &#8212; buy back their own stock, rather than take that money and invest it in pumping new oil.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>So don&#8217;t tell me gas prices rose because I&#8217;ve slowed down the American energy production.&nbsp; In my first year in office, American production grew by 9.7 million barrels a day to 11.6 million while we still made a major, major effort to deal with global warming and changing the way in which we shift to renewable &#8212; renewable energy.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And don&#8217;t tell me gas prices rose because of the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; The San Francisco Reserve &#8212; Federal Reserve analyzed this and other outfits confirm: The Rescue Plan contributed to 0.3 percent of inflation &#8212; 0.3 inflation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re the facts.&nbsp; Democrats didn&#8217;t cause this problem.&nbsp; Vladimir Putin did.<br><br>And we&#8217;re &#8212; and we are working on it to fix it.&nbsp; Because of the work we did, this country is vaccinated and start building the economy from the bottom up in the middle out. Something incredible is happening.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re seeing a manufacturing revival I don&#8217;t think even those of you from the Midwest thought would occur.&nbsp; The pride that comes from stamping products “Made in America.”&nbsp; Intel came to see me &#8212; the CEO.&nbsp; He said he wants to invest $20 billion to build factories in eastern Ohio &#8212; manufacture computer chips, semiconductors that will power the world and everyday lives, smartphones, intel, technology that doesn&#8217;t exist today.<br><br>And they&#8217;re prepared to increase their investment from $20 billion now to $100 billion now, as soon as you get final passage of the innovation bill headed to conference now.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This bill will invest another $200 billion to make us competitive, including $52 billion in computer chips.&nbsp; We invented these damn things.&nbsp; We, the United States &#8212; everybody forgets &#8212; we invented the computer chip, in going to the moon.&nbsp; And we have made &#8212; every single, solitary part of modernizing the technology in a computer chip has been American made.<br><br>But we stopped making them in America, and now we&#8217;re going to make them again.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to help bring down the price of automobiles, appliances, and so much more.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s not just Intel.&nbsp; Take a look at what Ford and General Motors did.&nbsp; Ford committed $11 billion to build electric vehicles in America &#8212; its biggest investment ever.&nbsp; General Motors committed $7 billion to build electric vo- &#8212; vehicles.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember when General Motors &#8212; Mary Barra &#8212; was suing California &#8212; suing California because there&#8217;s a higher standard &#8212; mileage standard?&nbsp; I talked to her.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not saying she changed because of me.&nbsp; I talked to her.&nbsp; She came to &#8212; called me and said she’s no &#8212; she’s going to drop her suit and that she&#8217;s going to commit that 50 percent of all General Motors vehicles by the year 2030 are going to be electric vehicles.&nbsp; And everybody started following suit.<br><br>Just a few years ago, companies might have built these factories elsewhere, but now they&#8217;re building them in America.&nbsp; We’re coming back.&nbsp; We’re coming back stronger than ever before.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, one of the things I&#8217;ve done &#8212; you know, I didn&#8217;t know &#8212; maybe you all knew it; I didn&#8217;t know when I was in the Senate; I should have &#8212; that there&#8217;s law in the books.&nbsp; It&#8217;s called “Build America.”&nbsp; You&#8217;re allowed to insist I get to spend, as your President &#8212; allocate spending of $600 billion &#8212; everything from the decks of aircraft carriers to a whole range of fleet of automobile, all the things we spend money on in the government.<br><br>Well, the law says that the President of the United States can say all those products have to be made in America.<br><br>Well, what happened?&nbsp; Initially, we just got really lax &#8212; Democrats and Republicans, I might add &#8212; and said, “Here&#8217;s the deal: If it has 55 percent American-made product and 45 is from foreign sources, that&#8217;s okay.”&nbsp; Not in my book.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So I just signed an executive order saying it&#8217;s got to be a minimum of 75 percent to start; it&#8217;s going to go up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And I think it’s the third executive order I signed that no &#8212; no department can give a waiver for a non-American-made product in any American product we&#8217;re buying without my permission, without coming to the White House to determine whether or not that&#8217;s justified.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And know what&#8217;s happening now?&nbsp; A lot of minority businesses, small businesses getting in on the deal.&nbsp; It gets posted &#8212; there’s an office in the White House &#8212; that says, “This is a product being built.&nbsp; We can’t find &#8212; we can’t find contractors for this. &nbsp;We’re an American product.&nbsp; Here’s what we need.”&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; It’s increasing the number of small businesses.</p>



<p>We also know there’s no one &#8212; no one way to increase the standard of living.&nbsp; Putin’s gas tax has pushed prices up higher; it’ll take American manufacturing to bring prices of cars down.&nbsp; But in the meantime, we can save people money in a big way by reducing the cost of childcare, of insulin, of caring for mom and dad and their energy bills.&nbsp; Because that’s another way to fundamentally impact on inflation for a family.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it gets down to what&#8217;s the total amount of money you have to spend to meet your basic needs.&nbsp; So guess what?&nbsp; If you &#8212; instead of the 200,000 folks with kids with Type 1 diabetes, if instead of spending an average of six- &#8212; $647 a month for that insulin, as high as $1,000, you&#8217;re only paying $35, and you&#8217;ve saved a hell of a lot of money.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Think about &#8212; think about your parents, particularly single parents, particularly women out there &#8212; the cost of childcare.&nbsp; Look, when I got here, as Nancy and some of you know, I had lost my family with an automobile accident.&nbsp; I got a call saying my wife was dead and my daughter was dead and my two boys were very badly injured.&nbsp; And I hadn&#8217;t been sworn in yet.</p>



<p>And make a long &#8212; an awful lot of help from a lot of senators saying, “Come and stay just six months.&nbsp; Help us organize.”&nbsp; Boy, was I stupid.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Six months.&nbsp; But they saved my sanity.</p>



<p>And so I came.&nbsp; And everybody says, “God, that &#8212; ain’t that Joe Biden a wonderful guy?&nbsp; He commuted every single day, roughly 300 miles a day, four hours a day, just to be home with his kids.”</p>



<p>It&#8217;s true, I did.&nbsp; I tried to hit over 2 million-some miles on Amtrak.&nbsp; But here&#8217;s the deal: I did it because I could not afford childcare.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t even begin to think of it.&nbsp; And I was making &#8212; I was making, at that time, as a United States senator &#8212; I was making more money than I made before.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford it.<br><br>So I think it&#8217;s &#8212; anybody making 100,000 bucks a year &#8212; single person &#8212; or $120,000 as a family should have childcare capped at 7 percent of their income.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Period.<br>We can do that.&nbsp; That’ll cut the cost of childcare in half.&nbsp; And a family is paying 14 grand a year in San Francisco, Philadelphia &#8212; all the big cities of the country &#8212; for just one child.&nbsp; And look, that extra 7,000 bucks in their pocket will make a difference in what they can do.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s so much we can do.&nbsp; Let me be clear: None of this is going to increase inflation.</p>



<p>Seventeen Nobel laureates spontaneously, a month and a half ago, wrote to me &#8212; seventeen Nobel laureates in the economic &#8211;in economics wrote me a long paper saying this will have &#8212; this will help ease inflationary pressures over time &#8212; not increase it.&nbsp; Ease.&nbsp; And we can do this without raising one single penny on taxes on anybody making less than 400 grand a year.</p>



<p>Let me say that again, be crystal clear: No one making less than $400,000 a year will pay a single additional penny in tax for all these things that were in the &#8212; in the Build Back Better plan.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have to do this.&nbsp; We have to do this.&nbsp; We have to ask &#8212; easy: Ask the biggest &#8212; those of the biggest corporations who pay very little to raise their hand.&nbsp; Everybody in here, raise your hand if you think the existing tax structure is remotely fair.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not being so- &#8212; I could do this at a Republican meeting, privately &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and they&#8217;d say that &#8212; no one would raise their hand.</p>



<p>But look, we have &#8212; in 2020, 55 of the biggest corporations in America &#8212; the Fortune 500 &#8212; paid zero in taxes and they made $40 billion in profit.&nbsp; Forty billion.</p>



<p>You know it, I know it, the American people know it: It just isn&#8217;t right.</p>



<p>Look, I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; This isn&#8217;t about punishing anybody.&nbsp; I love Bernie, and I really do.&nbsp; He&#8217;s a great friend.&nbsp; But I &#8212; I&#8217;m not Bernie.</p>



<p>If you can make a billion dollars, make a b- &#8212; for God&#8217;s sake, pay your fair share for &#8212; damn it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Right now.</p>



<p>But why are teachers and firefighters paying a higher percentage of taxes than billionaires and corporations, which is literally true?&nbsp; Literally true.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And we can fix this.&nbsp; We can raise the standard of living for hardworking people without raising taxes, without raising inflation, and without raising the deficit.&nbsp;<br>And for all those folks out there that like to tack us for, you know &#8212; let me remind them: Last year, because of what you all did, we reduced the deficit by $360 billion &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we, the Democrats &#8212; while the economy grew.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re on track right now &#8212; I’m on track to be the first President in history to lower the deficit by over $1 trillion in one year.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>So, I’m sick of this stuff.&nbsp; We have to talk about it because the American people think the reason for inflation is the government is spending more money.&nbsp; Simply not true.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t think we need any lectures from our friends on the other side about fiscal responsibility, for God’s sake.&nbsp; Look, we have an ambitious agenda.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s go get it done.&nbsp; That includes standing up for and not giving an inch on core Democratic values.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re going to continue to stand up to meet the great challenges of our time: voting rights, climate change, gun violence, criminal justice, immigration, and so much more.&nbsp;<br><br>Coming out of the State of the Union &#8212; why I think we&#8217;re in a strong position &#8212; we have a record to be proud of, an agenda that will lower costs for American families and lift this nation up, and a message that resonates.&nbsp; We&#8217;re building a better America, a fairer America, a more decent America.&nbsp; A country that&#8217;s been through a lot these past few years.&nbsp;<br><br>And I mean what I said &#8212; I meant what I said at the State of the Union: We&#8217;re stronger today than we were a year ago.&nbsp; And we will be stronger next year than we are today.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve long said &#8212; and I mean this sincerely.&nbsp; I’m not &#8212; I’ve spent a lot of time with Xi Jinping.&nbsp; Over 36 hours of private meetings with him.&nbsp; He asked me &#8212; we were in the Tibetan Plateau and he asked me if I could define America for him.&nbsp; Just me and a simultaneous interpreter, him and an interpreter.&nbsp; And, by the way, I turned all my notes over.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)<br><br>But seriously, he said, “Can you define America for me?”&nbsp; He&#8217;s a tough guy.&nbsp; And I said, “I can.”&nbsp; And I said, “In one word.”&nbsp; And he looked at me.&nbsp; I said, “Possibilities.”&nbsp;<br><br>We’re the only nation in the world &#8212; it’s the reason why we’re looked at as sometimes being arrogant.&nbsp; We think anything is possible.&nbsp; Anything is possible if we act together.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, we&#8217;ve taken every crisis we ever faced and turned it into an opportunity.&nbsp; Think of one that hadn&#8217;t that way.&nbsp; Whatever the crisis was, we&#8217;ve come out of it better than we were in before it occurred, every single time.&nbsp; But we’ve got to stick together.&nbsp; We got to stick together.&nbsp; We can do this again.&nbsp; We can do it.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, I &#8212; I&#8217;m going to get going.&nbsp; I shouldn’t &#8212; I&#8217;ll stop here.&nbsp; I know you all have questions, and I’m supposed &#8212; anyway, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll be back here for questions.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>1:18 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Virginia Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-virginia-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 22:16:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Virginia and ordered Federal assistance to supplement Commonwealth, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and snowstorm from January 2 to January 3, 2022. Federal funding also is available to Commonwealth, tribal,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the Commonwealth of Virginia and ordered Federal assistance to supplement Commonwealth, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by a severe winter storm and snowstorm from January 2 to January 3, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding also is available to Commonwealth, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storm and snowstorm in the counties of Albemarle, Amelia, Appomattox, Bedford, Buckingham, Caroline, Charlotte, Culpeper, Cumberland, Essex, Fauquier, Fluvanna, Goochland, Greene, Hanover, King George, King William, Louisa, Madison, Nelson, Orange, Powhatan, Prince Edward, Rappahannock, Spotsylvania, Stafford, and Westmoreland Counties and the independent city of Fredericksburg.</p>



<p>In addition, Federal funding is available to the Commonwealth, tribal, and eligible local governments on a cost-sharing basis for snow assistance for a continuous 48-hour period during or proximate to the incident period in the counties of King George and Stafford.</p>



<p>Lastly, Federal funding is available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures for all areas within the Commonwealth of Virginia.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Gerard M. Stolar as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.</p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the Commonwealth and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>November 2021 Visitor Log Records&#160;Posted</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2022/03/11/november-2021-visitor-log-records-posted/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 22:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Disclosures]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House released visitor log records generated in November 2021. This set includes 4608 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 25932. These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House released visitor log records generated in November 2021. This set includes 4608 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 25932.</p>



<p>These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.</p>



<p>To learn more about the policy, read our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/">voluntary disclosure policy</a>. To view visitor log records, view our <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/">disclosure page</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
