<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 15:17:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the Occasion of&#160;Eid al-Adha</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/09/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-occasion-of-eid-al-adha-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 15:16:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I send our warmest greetings to Muslims across the United States and around the world celebrating Eid al-Adha. The Eid traditions and Hajj rituals that commemorate the devotion of Abraham and his son to God are an opportunity for Muslims to renew their faith, and a reminder of the common roots of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I send our warmest greetings to Muslims across the United States and around the world celebrating Eid al-Adha. The Eid traditions and Hajj rituals that commemorate the devotion of Abraham and his son to God are an opportunity for Muslims to renew their faith, and a reminder of the common roots of the world’s great Abrahamic religions. And the act of sharing the sacrifice with those less fortunate in service of God mirrors our common commitment to work together to meet the challenges of our world today.<br><br>While COVID-19 restrictions remain, Muslims draped in white will be able to gather from around the world for the first time in two years to perform the Hajj. It’s a symbol of the progress we have made in fighting this pandemic and of all work we must still do to strengthen our recovery. Let us all take this opportunity to renew our shared commitment to work for peace, care for the vulnerable, and pursue greater equality and opportunity for all people.<br> <br>Here in the United States, Muslim Americans are leading on the frontlines, together with members of all faith communities, to assist those suffering from hunger and conflict, at home and abroad. To all those celebrating, Jill and I wish you and your loved ones a joyous holiday filled with community, celebration, compassion, and service. Eid Mubarak and Hajj Mabroor! </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Commemorating the 75th Anniversary of the Central Intelligence&#160;Agency</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/08/remarks-by-president-biden-commemorating-the-75th-anniversary-of-the-central-intelligence-agency/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 03:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57043</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[George Bush Center for IntelligenceLangley, Virginia 3:57 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; It’s so good to be back.&#160; This is my third time standing before these stars to speak and &#8212; in my life in public &#8212; my time in public office.&#160; And &#8212; and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">George Bush Center for Intelligence<br>Langley, Virginia</p>



<p>3:57 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; It’s so good to be back.&nbsp; This is my third time standing before these stars to speak and &#8212; in my life in public &#8212; my time in public office.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it’s a great honor.<br><br>I was saying to some of the folks &#8212; and Avril has heard me say this before, along with Bill &#8212; that I’ve been involved with your agency for &#8212; not 75 years, but &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; but I hate to admit it, 52 years.&nbsp; (Makes the sign of the cross.)&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I know it’s hard to say.<br><br>At any rate, but, you know, there was a time when there were questions raised about the agency in the so-called Church Committee way back in the early ‘70s.&nbsp; And that’s when they set up intelligence committees in the United States Senate &#8212; although I know you doubt that: intelligence in the Senate &#8212; but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; I’m joking &#8212; and the House of Representatives.<br><br>And I was appointed to that committee by a great man &#8212; straight as an arrow &#8212; named Mike Mansfield, the senator from Montana.&nbsp; They called him “Iron Mike.”<br><br>And he &#8212; I think &#8212; I’m not positive, but I think the next-youngest person on the committee was, I think, 28 or 29 years older than I was.<br><br>So I’ve been doing &#8212; I’ve been watching from that day on and been deeply involved either as a member of the Intelligence Committee or the Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee or doing national security issues as Vice President and to today.&nbsp; And you’re an incredible group of people &#8212; incredible group of people.<br><br>Before I re- &#8212; move to my specific remarks I want to talk about today, I’d like to say just a very few words about the horrific, shocking killing of my friend, Japanese Prime Minister Abe.&nbsp;<br><br>I became acquainted with him when I was Vice President.&nbsp; I hosted him.&nbsp; He hosted me in Japan.&nbsp; And I just stopped by the Japanese Embassy to see the Ambassador and sign the <s>consolence</s> [condolence] book &#8212; the consol- &#8212; <s>consolence</s> [condolence] book for the Japanese people.&nbsp;<br><br>I knew him well.&nbsp; We worked together closely for years, and we spoke and consulted with one other when I served as Vice President.&nbsp;<br><br>And he &#8212; he was deeply committed to strengthening the alliance and friendship between the United States and Japan and pursuing an open and free Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp;<br><br>And service to his country and his people was in his bones.&nbsp; Even after he stepped down from public office, his focus on his health, he stayed engaged and he cared deeply.&nbsp; And I hold him in great respect.&nbsp;<br><br>This attack was &#8212; has had a profound impact on the psyche of the Japanese people.&nbsp; This is &#8212; this is a different &#8212; a different culture.&nbsp; They’re not used to &#8212; as, unfortunately, we are.&nbsp; Here in the United States, we know how deep the wounds of gun violence go for communities that are affected.&nbsp; And this assassination is a tragedy that all the people of Japan are feeling.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I’m keeping his wife and family in my prayers.&nbsp; And the United States is standing in solidarity with our ally Japan with confidence in the strength of Japan’s democracy as they approach their elections on Sunday.&nbsp;<br><br>Director Burns, [Deputy] Director Cohen, I’m honored to be here, standing in front of this hallowed wall to honor 75 years of this proud institution and so many faithful public servants.&nbsp;<br><br>And Director Haines, thank you for being here today as well.&nbsp; For 75 years, our nation’s intelligence professionals have worked unceasingly and sacrificed willingly to make our country safer.&nbsp; And that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; That’s a simple, straightforward fact.<br><br>And as we celebrate the history of this agency, we will never forget those who have laid down their lives in service to this nation.&nbsp; A hundred and thirty-nine stars behind me &#8212; two added just this year &#8212; each a patriot whose sacrifice we’re going to always honor and whose legacies live on in each of you as you continue their work.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, so often, you have to keep your identities secret, sometimes even in death, that we don’t get the chance to thank you enough for all that you do.&nbsp; You have to keep it secret, so many of you.&nbsp;<br><br>You ask for no recognition or personal acclaim, knowing that the quiet bravery of the women and men of this agency echoes loudly around the world &#8212; and I assure you it does, around the world &#8212; in lives saved, in crises averted, in truths revealed, in decisions of the 75 years of American presidents made better because of the insights you’ve provided.&nbsp; And again, that’s not exaggeration.<br><br>In the years between leaving office as Vice President and winning the nomination for President, the thing I missed most &#8212; and I mean this sincerely; I was a professor at the University of Pennsylvania &#8212; but I missed &#8212; you’re going to think I’m nuts, but I missed waking up every morning and getting &#8212; seeing the PDB.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>No, seriously.&nbsp; Every single morning except from the time I was 26 years old &#8212; 27 years old &#8212; I mean 37 years old until I left the vice presidency &#8212; every morning, I got up and I knew what was happening around the world and in detail and, in many cases, in sharp relief.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s indispensable to me as I face some of the dec- &#8212; the difficult decisions to have the best possible information provided by the most capable, reliable intelligence community in the world.&nbsp; And again, not hyperbole, you are clearly the best in the whole world.&nbsp;<br><br>It was thanks to the incredible work of our intelligence professionals that we were able to forewarn the world what Vladimir Putin was planning in Ukraine.&nbsp; We saw what he was doing.&nbsp; You saw it &#8212; the forces he was amassing, the plans he was making.&nbsp;<br><br>Exposing Putin’s playbook punched a gigantic hole in the pretense and discredited his lies about what we were doing in Ukraine.<br><br>Without revealing sources and methods, that’s been critical to our ability to rally our Allies and partners around the world &#8212; again, not an exaggeration &#8212; to keep them united.<br><br>I imagine, General, you wondered whether we could.&nbsp; Many thought we &#8212; could we keep NATO alive?&nbsp; Could we keep it completely coherent and together?<br><br>And, by the way, I’ve spent well over 135 hours doing just that on almost a daily basis.&nbsp; Because Putin counted on &#8212; counted on the ability to break up NATO and to break our resolve.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This organization changed dramatically since President Truman signed this into law &#8212; the National Security Act of 1947, which created the CIA.&nbsp; Wars have been fought, peace negotiated, new countries formed.&nbsp; Technology has empowered more people, but it also emboldened many to abuse that power that’s our wol- &#8212; our world smaller than it’s ever been.<br><br>And along the way, you’ve evolved to anticipate and respond to emerging threats from the earliest days of the Cold War to our fight against terrorism, to equipping ourselves for the competition ahead with China and meeting the transnational challenges that are reshaping the world, like emerging technologies, changing climate, and the spread of pandemics.&nbsp; You’re sort of the key to all of it.<br><br>Every step &#8212; every step, that 16-pointed compass star you walk across every morning when you come to work has guided your path.&nbsp; And a reminder of your ultimate mission: to bring together the intelligence and data from around the world so that those of us who direct American foreign policy can do everything in our power &#8212; everything in our power to keep the American people safe, because that’s what it’s all about.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We turn to you with the big questions, the hardest questions.&nbsp; And we count on you to give your best, unvarnished assessment of where we are.&nbsp; And I emphasize “unvarnished.”&nbsp; That doesn’t mean I expect to always get it 100 percent right.&nbsp; But it does mean that I expect you to tell me the truth no matter what.&nbsp; No matter what.&nbsp;<br><br>I expect each of you to honor the democratic values and ideals that form the core of our nation’s strength.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re the most unique nation in the history of the world.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the only nation in the world based on an idea &#8212; not ethnicity, not geography, not religion.&nbsp; “We hold these truths to be self-evident…”&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never lived up to it, but we&#8217;ve never walked away from it.<br><br>And one of the ways to guarantee that doesn&#8217;t happen is the unvarnished truth.&nbsp;<br><br>Because, in this week when we celebrate our nation’s independence, we remember that America is strongest when we lead not just by the example of our power, but the power of our example.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why most nations follow us: the power of our example.&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, although much of your work you do is going to remain unseen by necessity to protect you and your families and to safeguard the sources and methods, where possible we have to seek to balance secrecy with transparency, to shine a light on atrocities, and prevent plots or threats or acts of aggression before they happen.&nbsp; Because the greatest value of our intelligence collection is the good we do with it.<br><br>As we celebrate 75 years of this agency, I know you’re also honoring the trailblazers who helped make this institution what it is &#8212; the women and the men who changed the game or set the standard for intelligence profession.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, it’s an important reminder, just like these stars behind me &#8212; that’s what sets this agency apart &#8212; has always been &#8212; what sets you apart are the people.&nbsp; That’s what sets you apart.<br><br>And just like the work of every part of our government, our intelligence is more robust when we tap the full strength of our diversity as a nation.&nbsp;<br><br>When I first stood here, years ago, I looked out, there weren&#8217;t nearly as much diversity as there is today &#8212; women, people of color, men.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, that’s something “Wild Bill” Donovan knew when he created the Office of Strategic Services to collect intelligence to help us win World War Two.&nbsp;<br><br>And if diversity was essential to intelligence work in the ‘40s, its mission is critical today.&nbsp; If everyone brings the same ideas, the same experiences, the same skillsets to work, it will leave some pretty big blind spots in our security.<br><br>I also know that your work can be incredibly demanding.&nbsp; For the last 20 years, we’ve asked you to keep a relentless pace, serving in the face of physical dangers and daunting challenges.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So let me just close by saying: Your health &#8212; your physical health and wellbeing are critically important to me and to your leadership here at the CIA.&nbsp; And as your President and your number-one consumer of your work, I have the greatest respect for you and for the sacrifices you and your families make for the country.&nbsp;&nbsp;Not just you.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s an expression &#8212; <s>Keats</s> [Milton] said, &#8220;They also serve who only stand and wait.&#8221;&nbsp; Think of your families, all the sacrifices they&#8217;ve made.&nbsp;<br><br>I know that you will continue to honor and uphold the highest traditions of the CIA and the highest values of this nation for the next 75 years and beyond.&nbsp; You will continue to serve as the bedrock of our national security as well as our national strength.&nbsp;<br><br>So, thank you for all that you do.&nbsp; May God protect you all and the work that keeps this nation safe from harm.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you. (Applause.)<br><br>4:11 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with State Legislators on Reproductive Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-state-legislators-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 01:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, July 8, 2022, Vice President Kamala Harris convened state legislative leaders from Indiana, Florida, South Dakota, Nebraska, and Montana who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights. All five states have Republican-controlled state legislatures and Republican governors, and may soon call special sessions to pass abortion bans. The convening follows meetings about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, July 8, 2022, Vice President Kamala Harris convened state legislative leaders from Indiana, Florida, South Dakota, Nebraska, and Montana who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights. All five states have Republican-controlled state legislatures and Republican governors, and may soon call special sessions to pass abortion bans. The convening follows meetings about reproductive rights that the Vice President has held with health care providers, faith leaders, constitutional law and privacy experts, advocates, and Attorneys General.<br>&nbsp;<br>During the meeting, the Vice President discussed actions the Administration is taking to defend abortion rights, including the President’s signing of the Executive Order Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care Services. The Vice President reiterated the Administration’s commitment to partnering with elected leaders at the local, state, and federal level to protect reproductive health care access.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The state legislative leaders shared what is happening in their states as extremist legislators are fighting to further limit reproductive health care access following the Supreme Court overruling <em>Roe v. Wade. </em>They discussed the importance of patient privacy and spoke out against government inference in decisions that should be made between a woman and her doctor. They also shared concerns about other rights that are being attacked on the state level, including voting rights and LGBTQI+ rights. The Vice President and the state leaders reaffirmed their commitment to working together to protect reproductive rights and freedoms for all women, no matter where they live.<br>&nbsp;<br>State legislative leaders included:</p>



<ul><li>Indiana House Minority Leader Representative Phil GiaQuinta</li><li>Florida incoming House Democratic Leader Representative Fentrice Driskell</li><li>South Dakota&nbsp;House Minority Whip Erin Healy</li><li>Nebraska Senator Patty Pansing Brooks</li><li>Montana Senator Diane Sands</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WHAT THEY ARE SAYING: President&#160;Biden Signs Executive Order to Protect Access to Reproductive Healthcare&#160;Services</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/what-they-are-saying-president-biden-signs-executive-order-to-protect-access-to-reproductive-healthcare-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57037</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two weeks ago, the Supreme Court issued a decision that overturned&#160;Roe v. Wade&#160;and eliminated a woman’s Constitutional right to choose.&#160; This decision expressly took away a right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to make her own reproductive health care decisions, free from government interference.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Two weeks ago, the Supreme Court issued a decision that overturned&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade&nbsp;</em>and eliminated a woman’s Constitutional right to choose.&nbsp; This decision expressly took away a right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to make her own reproductive health care decisions, free from government interference. Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order Protecting Access to Reproductive Health Care Services.<br><br>This Executive Order builds on the actions his Administration has already taken to defend reproductive rights by:</p>



<ul><li>Safeguarding access to reproductive health care services, including abortion and contraception;</li><li>Protecting the privacy of patients and their access to accurate information;</li><li>Promoting the safety and security of patients, providers, and clinics; and</li><li>Coordinating the implementation of Federal efforts to protect reproductive rights and access to health care.</li></ul>



<p><em>See below for what they are saying:</em><br><br><strong><em><u>Elected Officials</u></em></strong><br><br><strong><em>Members of Congress &#8211; Senators</em></strong><br><br><strong>Sen. Debbie Stabenow: </strong>“Thank you @POTUS for using your executive powers to do everything you can to protect our freedom to make our own reproductive health decisions. Ultimately, protecting our freedom will be decided at the ballot box. Until then, we need to do everything we can to limit the harm the Supreme Court decision is causing for women and families across our country. This Executive Order will: &#8211; Safeguard access to reproductive health care &#8211; Protect patient privacy &amp; access to accurate information &#8211; Promote patients, providers, &amp; clinics safety &amp; security &#8211; Coordinate Federal efforts to protect reproductive rights &amp; access to health care” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenStabenow/status/1545450223685828609">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Patty Murray: </strong>“After leading the charge in urging @POTUS to act boldly to protect abortion access, I&#8217;m glad to see him take further action today even with limited executive authority. These steps are good &amp; important, but the post-Roe health care crisis is urgent. This fight is far from over.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/PattyMurray/status/1545444536163368960">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Tom Carper: </strong>“In the wake of a disastrous SCOTUS decision, we need an all-of-government approach to protect women’s access to reproductive health care. @POTUS’s action will help women get the care they need. But we in Congress need to do more—far more—to protect this constitutional right.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenatorCarper/status/1545501000978649089">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Chris Coons:</strong> “Glad to see decisive action from @POTUS to protect access to reproductive health care. The American people have a right to privacy and bodily autonomy, and these steps will help safeguard women’s health from gov&#8217;t overreach. The fight continues to protect the right to choose.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/ChrisCoons/status/1545443195286323200">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Elizabeth Warren: </strong>“@POTUS&#8217; executive order will help Americans receive the reproductive health care they need. I urged the Biden administration to expand access to medication abortion, protect patient privacy, and safeguard interstate travel for care. Today&#8217;s actions are important first steps. The Administration should continue to explore every available option to protect access to abortion care. The overwhelming majority of Americans oppose this extremist Supreme Court’s decision to overturn Roe v. Wade, and we must use every tool possible to address this emergency.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenWarren/status/1545448006946029574">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Cortez Masto:</strong> “Today, @POTUS heeded my call to take executive action to safeguard access to reproductive care and protect women’s data privacy. While these steps are important, more needs to be done to protect reproductive freedom, and I’ll keep fighting for women and their families.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenCortezMasto/status/1545415758192054272">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Cory Booker</strong>: “This is an important step for safeguarding reproductive rights. We need to deploy every tool available to ensure Americans can continue to access the health care they need.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenBooker/status/1545470413840449544">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Tammy Baldwin</strong>: “The Executive Order from @POTUS takes positive and important steps to protect access to reproductive health care services. Now, we all need to keep pushing forward to take back the rights and freedoms Republicans have taken away from women.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenatorBaldwin/status/1545461075470082049">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Tammy Duckworth: </strong>“Since the Supreme Court cruelly overturned Roe, people across the country have been crying out for action. I’m glad @POTUS answered my call for an EO and took this first step to reaffirm the right to choose for every American. Now it’s time Congress acts to codify this right.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenDuckworth/status/1545473050099032064">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Diane Feinstein: </strong>“I&#8217;m glad President Biden has heeded the call of Senate Democrats to issue an executive order to help protect access to abortion. Now Congress must take decisive action to codify reproductive rights by passing the Women’s Health Protection Act.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenFeinstein/status/1545445167787827201">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Maggie Hassan: </strong>“By overturning Roe, the Supreme Court took away a woman’s autonomy and ability to make her own health care decisions. The administration’s actions announced today are welcome steps to mitigate the impact of this decision. We also know that in the aftermath of the decision, Mitch McConnell and anti-choice extremists’ ultimate objective is to ban abortion nationwide — we must hold the line against this and keep fighting to protect a woman’s fundamental freedom.” [<a href="https://www.hassan.senate.gov/news/press-releases/senator-hassan-statement-on-administrations-executive-order-following-the-supreme-courts-roe-decision">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. John Hickenlooper: </strong>“Thank you @POTUS for taking steps to protect women and their doctors.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenatorHick/status/1545466663771901954">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Senator Ben Ray Lujan: </strong>“I’m grateful that @POTUS has taken federal action to protect women’s healthcare decisions post Roe overturn. But the Senate still needs to take action to codify Roe into law. And that means abolishing the filibuster. We have to act now.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenatorLujan/status/1545471811441369088">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Ed Markey: </strong>“.@POTUS&#8217;s actions, including directing the FTC to safeguard the privacy of individuals seeking an abortion, are an important step in the fight to protect essential abortion rights. Now, Congress must go further to abolish the filibuster and codify Roe.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenMarkey/status/1545464010719563785">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Alex Padilla: </strong>“This is a necessary step toward protecting reproductive rights across the country. The fight is far from over — I’ll continue to work with the Biden administration to ensure people have access to safe abortion care nationwide.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenAlexPadilla/status/1545490690435678209">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Gary Peters: </strong>“This is welcome action from @POTUS – but there’s no question the fight to protect critical health care for women is far from over. It’s clear Republicans want to impose further bans to abortion access and more cruel restrictions at every level of government—even in cases of rape, incest and when the life of the mother is at risk. Congress must step up – and I will always fight in the Senate to ensure access to vital health care and to keep the government from interfering in a woman’s right to make health care decisions with her doctor.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenGaryPeters/status/1545458472036274176">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Jacky Rosen: </strong>“In the wake of Roe v. Wade being overturned, a group of my colleagues and I urged @POTUS to take action to protect a woman&#8217;s right to choose. Today&#8217;s Executive Order is welcome news, and we will keep pushing for action in every way we can to protect reproductive rights.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenJackyRosen/status/1545460431686455300">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Jeanne Shaheen:</strong> “These are important steps to help preserve access to abortion &amp; repro services in the wake of the devastating Roe reversal. Decisions around health &amp; bodily autonomy belong to patients – not jurists or politicians. I’ll keep fighting to secure access to life-saving health care.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenatorShaheen/status/1545457683360370690?s=20&amp;t=sduMHttlkjVMC2AKgtoHmA">Tweet</a>, 7/8/2022]<br><br><strong>Sen. Tina Smith: </strong>“Let’s be clear: extremist Republicans gutted Americans’ reproductive freedoms, but Democrats are fighting to restore them. These are critical steps that will help protect abortion access.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenTinaSmith/status/1545464600505860096">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Reverend Raphael Warnock: </strong>“After pushing the @WhiteHouse to protect women’s reproductive health, I’m glad @POTUS is listening to the American people &amp; taking much-needed action. But we have more to do.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenatorWarnock/status/1545485322968088576">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Sen. Sheldon Whitehouse: </strong>“I’m glad to see President Biden sign an executive order to bolster reproductive rights as women face the dangerous consequences of the Supreme Court’s extreme decision to overturn Roe. We must keep fighting by every means we can.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/SenWhitehouse/status/1545449997101039617">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong><em>Members of Congress – House Members</em></strong><br><br><strong>Speaker Nancy Pelosi</strong>: “President Biden’s executive order today helps advance Democrats’ fight to defend Americans’ health freedom from all-out assault by right-wing extremists.&nbsp; This action will take steps to uphold a woman’s right to make her own health decisions: protecting access to FDA-approved medication abortion, strengthening enforcement of the Affordable Care Act’s contraceptive protections and defending the legal rights of both patients and providers. “Our pro-choice Democratic House Majority continues to prepare additional legislative action to respond to the Supreme Court’s appalling decision to rip away women’s reproductive rights.&nbsp; Next week, we will again pass the Women’s Health Protection Act: landmark legislation enshrining the protections of Roe v. Wade into federal law.&nbsp; We will also pass legislation addressing the GOP’s disturbing threats to restrict Americans’ freedom to travel — reaffirming the Constitutional right to seek care freely and voluntarily throughout the country. “We have a sacred, fundamental duty to expand freedom in America, not to roll back fundamental rights.&nbsp; While Republicans seek to criminalize reproductive health care nationwide, House Democrats will never relent in our fight to defend freedom for women and for every American.” [<a href="https://www.speaker.gov/newsroom/7822-1">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>House Majority Leader Steny Hoyer</strong>: “Today’s executive order shows that the American people have a President who takes swift action to protect women’s reproductive choice.&nbsp; While this executive order is important and will help women access reproductive health care where they need it and maintain privacy, in truth there is very little that the President can do on his own to address the dangers posed by the Supreme Court’s ruling in&nbsp;<em>Dobbs v. Jackson</em>.&nbsp; It is up to Congress to take meaningful action by enacting laws that guarantee reproductive freedom in all states and territories of our union.&nbsp; That’s what the House did when we passed the Women’s Health Protection Act last year &#8211; and we will do so again next week with an updated version of that bill. I will also bring to the House Floor next week the Ensuring Access to Abortion Act, to make it possible and safe for women needing abortion care to travel to states where it is accessible.&nbsp; I urge the Senate to act without delay and join the House in taking action to protect women’s reproductive choice in the wake of the extremist and precedent-ignoring&nbsp;<em>Dobbs v. Jackson</em>&nbsp;ruling.” [<a href="https://www.majorityleader.gov/content/hoyer-statement-president-bidens-executive-order-protecting-reproductive-freedom#:~:text=Hoyer%20(MD)%20released%20the%20following,to%20protect%20women's%20reproductive%20choice.">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Katherine Clark</strong>: “As Congress works to protect abortion long-term, @POTUS is protecting patients right now. Today&#8217;s EO will: -Safeguard access to reproductive health care -Protect the safety &amp; privacy of patients, providers &amp; clinics -Coordinate federal efforts to protect abortion”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepKClark/status/1545435403012157441">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Carolyn B.&nbsp; Maloney</strong>: “In this critical moment, I applaud President Biden for issuing today’s Executive Order, which protects abortion access and underscores Democrats’ commitment to fighting back against the anti-abortion and anti-freedom agenda being pursued by Republican-appointed members of the Supreme Court.&nbsp; I am proud that the Executive Order advances efforts that the Oversight Committee has championed, including expanding access to medication abortion and protecting access to contraceptives. “Next week, my Committee is holding a hearing to tell the story of what overturning Roe means for people across America—especially the most vulnerable among us.&nbsp; I’ve spent years in Congress advocating for equitable access to reproductive health care, and the Oversight Committee will not stop fighting until everyone can access the care they need when they need it.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://oversight.house.gov/news/press-releases/chairwoman-maloney-applauds-president-biden-s-executive-order-protecting-access">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Jerry Nadler: </strong>“We must do everything in our power to ensure that all Americans can safely access abortion care. I applaud @POTUS for taking crucial steps to protect abortion access, ensure patient privacy, and defend those providing abortion services.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepJerryNadler/status/1545466065332969472">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Mark Takano</strong>: “By signing this executive order, President Biden has taken a significant step in defending reproductive rights and protecting access to safe and legal abortion, but this is only the beginning. Congress must codify Roe.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepMarkTakano/status/1545499099599818752">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Pete Aguilar</strong>: “President Biden’s Executive Order will: ✅Protect access to medication abortion ✅Ensure emergency medical care ✅Protect access to birth control I support @POTUS’s efforts to protect reproductive rights. It’s time for the Senate to do their job and codify Roe v. Wade into law.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepPeteAguilar/status/1545449893921267714">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Adam Smith: </strong>“Today @POTUS announced actions he&#8217;s taking to protect access to reproductive health care in the wake of the Supreme Court&#8217;s dangerous decision to overturn Roe v. Wade. The President directed @SecBecerra to protect access to medication abortion, ensure emergency medical care, protect access to contraception, and unite lawyers across the country to defend the rights of people seeking reproductive health care in areas that have banned abortion. The Executive Order will also protect consumer privacy, personal data, and sensitive health information and importantly will advance the safety of providers and clinics who are courageously providing essential reproductive health care services in the face of heightened risk. These actions are a step in the right direction, but they are not enough on their own. We must codify Roe v. Wade into law, and to do so, we must be willing to scrap the filibuster &#8211; our freedoms are so much more important than Senate procedure.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepAdamSmith/status/1545465464410853376">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Kathy Castor</strong>: “Thank you @POTUS for taking action today to protect reproductive decisions through executive action since Senate Republicans refuse to act.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/USRepKCastor/status/1545499252939423744">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Raul M. Grijalva:</strong> “I support this executive order and once again call on my Senate colleagues to stand with the majority of Americans in protecting abortion rights now!” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepRaulGrijalva/status/1545460997426651136">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Judy Chu</strong>: “This is a step forward as we continue to navigate a post-Roe world—however, with Republicans working endlessly to pave a way for a federal abortion ban, this is not enough. Congress must take immediate action to enshrine abortion rights into law.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepJudyChu/status/1545457261564379139">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Lois Frankel:</strong> “In the face of the biggest dismantling of women’s rights in half a century, I commend and thank President Biden for his commitment to protecting reproductive freedom and access to abortion,” said Rep. Frankel. “The President’s order will protect the right to travel freely, safeguard patients&#8217; privacy, promote the safety and security of patients, providers, and clinics, and the ability to obtain approved medication. It is a critical step in fighting back to ensure everyone has the freedom to make decisions about their own reproductive health, regardless of their income or zip code.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://frankel.house.gov/news/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=3504">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Colin Allred</strong>: “We must do all we can to protect abortion access for Texas women. @POTUS’ executive order directing @HHSGov to protect reproductive health services is a good step, and I&#8217;ll keep fighting in Congress to ensure Texas women can get the health care they need.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepColinAllred/status/1545475684272848898">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Cindy Axne</strong>: “While I&#8217;m pleased to see @POTUS taking action to protect access to abortion and other reproductive health care services, there&#8217;s much more to be done. We need to meet this moment and codify Roe v. Wade.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepCindyAxne/status/1545455989297713154">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Ami Bera</strong>: “The actions taken today by @POTUS are an important step in defending reproductive health care in the wake of the Supreme Court’s decision to overturn Roe. Now, the Senate must pass the Women’s Health Protection Act to codify reproductive rights.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepBera/status/1545467589387747330">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Lisa Blunt Rochester</strong>: “@POTUS is right –&nbsp; the extremist Supreme Court does not know the power American women hold. We will turn out and we will continue to fight back against attacks on women&#8217;s reproductive rights.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepLBR/status/1545445351070597121">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Shontel Brown</strong>: “Now more than ever, it is essential that we support and protect women’s safety and privacy— especially those coming from our most vulnerable communities —with access to safe resources and reliable information. This executive order from @POTUS is crucial.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepShontelBrown/status/1545455922184593410">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Cori Bush</strong>: “I&#8217;m glad @POTUS heeded our call for executive action to protect reproductive freedom, including expanding access to medication abortion, family planning, emergency care, and contraception, and a commitment to protecting the right to travel. These are important first steps. There is so much more that the President and Congress can and must do right now, starting with declaring a public health emergency, preempting state law to protect access to FDA-approved medication abortion pills, and eliminating the filibuster to codify Roe.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepCori/status/1545491650964750336">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Cheri Bustos</strong>: “Everyone should have the freedom to decide what is best for themselves and their families. I applaud @POTUS for taking this step in safeguarding access to reproductive care services to protect ALL Americans.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepCheri/status/1545500722438995968">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Salud Carbajal</strong>: “Thank you @POTUS for taking action today to protect access to reproductive health care. I will continue fighting in Congress to #CodifyRoe and protect women&#8217;s fundamental and Constitutional rights, including patient privacy &amp; safe access to contraception.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepCarbajal/status/1545496385038041088">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Sean Casten</strong>: “Thank you, @POTUS, for signing an executive order to protect access to reproductive health care. This will give immediate relief to women who are disproportionately harmed by the SCOTUS decision. Now, the Senate must legislatively enshrine abortion rights.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepCasten/status/1545497956207534080">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Yvette Clarke</strong>: “Thank you, Mr. President. And now, we must codify Roe — so no woman ever knows these awful fears again.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepYvetteClarke/status/1545442398368571392">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Emanuel Cleaver: </strong>“Recent polling shows that the majority of Americans disapprove of the overturning of Roe v. Wade. I am proud to see @POTUS take necessary action to protect reproductive freedom and the fundamental right to bodily autonomy. The days following SCOTUS&#8217; harrowing decision not only turned back the clock on women&#8217;s rights, it set us on a trajectory that has monumental implications for many Americans. POTUS&#8217; executive action aims to protect access to critical aspects of healthcare and privacy. Reproductive rights are human rights that we must fight to protect and preserve, which is why we must codify Roe v. Wade into federal law.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/repcleaver/status/1545484791008661505">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Steve Cohen: </strong>“President Biden is signing an Executive Order designed to safeguard access to abortion and protect women from states trying to criminalize their health care. It’s an important step, but the Senate must end the filibuster to protect the right to abortion.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepCohen/status/1545443554717306880">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Diana DeGette:</strong> “These are important steps to help millions of women, but there is still so much more that needs to be done. We need the Senate to act. They need to end the filibuster and make Roe v. Wade the law of our land once again. And they need to do it today!”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepDianaDeGette/status/1545446377513259015">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Mark DeSaulnier: </strong>“Thank you @POTUS for taking these critical first steps to protect abortion access. Now we need a Senate that will act to protect reproductive freedom the way Democrats in the House already have.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepDeSaulnier/status/1545491815855431690">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Mike Doyle</strong>: “I support @POTUS&#8217;s executive order directing @HHSGov to protect women&#8217;s access to contraception, patient privacy, &amp; emergency care. These steps support a woman&#8217;s right to choose &amp; fight against extreme abortion restrictions.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/USRepMikeDoyle/status/1545419897467019265">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Veronica Escobar: </strong>“Abortion is healthcare. This executive order is a step toward a future where everyone—no matter who they are and where they’re from—is free to make the personal health decisions that are best for themselves, their lives, and their families, without political interference.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepEscobar/status/1545457417798012928">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Adriano Espaillat:</strong> “I commend @POTUS for taking action to protect abortion &amp; contraception access which @CongresswomanSC, &amp; I called for in H.Res.1218 along with more than 50 colleagues. We must continue to fight for reproductive freedom in the U.S. #AbortionIsHealthcare #ReproductiveRights”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepEspaillat/status/1545439515073994752">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Bill Foster</strong>: “I applaud @potus for taking aggressive action to protect access to reproductive health care and abortion rights. Now, the Senate needs to take up the House-passed Women&#8217;s Health Protection Act.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepBillFoster/status/1545455840391569410">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Ruben Gallego</strong>: “Today @POTUS announced an Executive Order to protect the rights of women. The Order: 💊Protects access to medication abortion and contraception 🏥Protects the right to emergency care ⚕️Protects privacy and health information Now the Senate must act to codify Roe v. Wade.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepRubenGallego/status/1545473189890990081">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Sylvia Garcia:</strong> “While Republicans want to control women and their personal decisions with a draconian nationwide ban on abortion, @POTUS is fighting to expand and protect access to reproductive health care with his executive order. Thank you for standing alongside women, President Biden.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepSylviaGarcia/status/1545447876549033985">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Brian Higgins</strong>: “Today @POTUS will sign an Executive Order that protects safe &amp; secure reproductive care for millions of people in our country. After SCOTUS dismantled the important precedent set by Roe v Wade, we must continue fighting to defend reproductive rights for all.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepBrianHiggins/status/1545427439316254722">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Jared Huffman: </strong>“I’m happy to see this announcement from @POTUS, but our work is far from over. Reproductive health care—and countless other rights—are under attack from the alt-right SCOTUS, and we must do everything in our power to fight back.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepHuffman/status/1545455907517202435">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Sara Jacobs: </strong>I&#8217;m encouraged by @POTUS&#8217; Executive Order to protect reproductive privacy. Now it&#8217;s time for Congress to act. We MUST pass legislation that protects access to reproductive health care without putting our most personal and sensitive data at risk. We must pass the #MyBodyMyDataAct [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepSaraJacobs/status/1545454975484153856">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Pramila Jayapal:</strong> “Thank you @POTUS for working to protect the rights of pregnant people across this country. Now it&#8217;s time for the Senate to step up and act to codify Roe.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepJayapal/status/1545456428693032961">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Mondaire Jones</strong>: “In the wake of this rogue Supreme Court waging war on the right to an abortion, I&#8217;m proud to see @POTUS tap into the fight to protect abortion care. Congress must take action. We need to codify Roe.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepMondaire/status/1545450353503752193">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Ro Khanna</strong>: &#8220;.@POTUS&#8217;s Executive Order to protect reproductive health care &amp; abortion is an important step in fighting back against the attacks by six extremist Supreme Court justices on the rights of women. Now, let&#8217;s abolish the filibuster to codify Roe &amp; pass my SCOTUS term limits bill.&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepRoKhanna/status/1545453318507560961">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Raja Krishnamoorthi:</strong> “I’m glad to see @POTUS is taking action to protect access to reproductive care and medication, but my colleagues and I in Congress must do more to defend reproductive freedom.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/CongressmanRaja/status/1545483134724186113">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Ann McLane Kuster:</strong> “I appreciate @POTUS taking steps to protect access to abortion &amp; reproductive health care in the wake of SCOTUS’s egregious ruling overturning Roe. Congress must put the protections enshrined by Roe into law &amp; ensure women can access the care they need.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepAnnieKuster/status/1545500225980317697">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Andy Levin: </strong>“I&#8217;m pleased to see @POTUS stepping up to protect access to abortion. We cannot stop until we ensure every single person who needs or wants an abortion has the right to do so.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepMikeLevin/status/1545474954262679555">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Mike Levin:</strong> “Everyone deserves to decide what to do with their body and get the care they need. Today, @POTUS signed an Executive Order protecting access to vital reproductive health care services and the right to privacy.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepMikeLevin/status/1545474954262679555">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Tom Malinowski</strong>: “Since SCOTUS&#8217; decision, GOP governors and state legislatures have been imposing extreme laws, banning a woman’s right to choose. @POTUS&#8217; executive order upholds an American&#8217;s right to make their own health decisions, without political interference.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/KathyManningNC/status/1545490036392693762">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Betty McCollum:</strong> “POTUS signed an executive order today safeguarding access to medication abortion &amp; Plan B, protecting data privacy, &amp; coordinating federal efforts to protect reproductive rights. More is needed – we must #CodifyRoe – but I’m glad to see @POTUS taking action to stand up for women.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/BettyMcCollum04/status/1545456341950537729?s=20&amp;t=sduMHttlkjVMC2AKgtoHmA">Tweet</a>, 7/8/2022]<br><br><strong>Rep. Donald McEachin:</strong> “I am grateful for @POTUS&#8217;s efforts to safeguard reproductive health care in the wake of the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision overturning Roe. This is a meaningful step, but our work is not done. The Senate needs to take immediate action on the Women&#8217;s Health Protection Act.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepMcEachin/status/1545453966892449792">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Chellie Pingree:</strong> &#8220;@HouseDemocrats did their job to codify Roe by passing the #WHPA. @POTUS&#8217;s Executive Order today was urgently needed, but next, we must: Abolish the filibuster Expand the Court End partisan gerrymandering And eliminate the undemocratic electoral college”&nbsp;&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/chelliepingree/status/1545444649468313601">Tweet,</a> 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Ayanna Pressley</strong>: “These much-needed actions will help folks get the abortion care they need. TY @POTUS for heeding our calls to expand access to medication abortion &amp; support those traveling for care. Now let&#8217;s build on this &amp; declare a public health emergency. Everything must be on the table.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepPressley/status/1545475200178954243">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Deborah Ross:</strong> “President Biden is right. We will fight these extreme attacks on our rights, and we will use every tool at our disposal to safeguard access to abortion. I&#8217;m glad @POTUS is taking action to protect women and health care providers. We can &amp; must do more.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepDeborahRoss/status/1545468065802080256">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Haley Stevens: </strong>“Thank you, @POTUS for taking steps to protect abortion access. Now Congress must act. It’s time to #EndTheFilibuster and enshrine the right to abortion care into law.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepHaleyStevens/status/1545456344349696003">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. David Trone</strong>: “We must ensure that women have the right to make personal decisions about their own health care and futures. Thank you @POTUS, for taking this crucial step toward protecting reproductive freedom across the nation. Let&#8217;s keep fighting.”&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepDavidTrone/status/1545472898965688320">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Rep. Marc Veasey:</strong> “Thank you, @POTUS, for signing an executive order to protect reproductive freedoms. Congress must follow your lead by codifying Roe v. Wade to protect essential health care and the right to choose.”&nbsp; [Tweet, <a href="https://twitter.com/RepVeasey/status/1545473343809355777">7.8.22</a>]<br><br><strong>Rep. Nikema Williams:</strong> “Today, @POTUS signed an executive order preserving access to abortion and contraception, defending patient privacy &amp; protecting clinic safety – all immediate priorities for women who are disproportionately harmed by tearing down abortion rights. It&#8217;s time for the Senate to step up and pass the Women&#8217;s Health Protection Act to protect equal access to safe, legal abortion for EVERYONE in EVERY ZIP code.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/RepNikema/status/1545443210381725697">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong><em>Governors</em></strong><br><br><strong>California Governor Newsom: </strong>“Thank you @POTUS&nbsp; for fighting to protect the right to choose!” [<a href="https://twitter.com/CAgovernor/status/1545462105444196352?s=20&amp;t=ymuBbBr0H1IQ8mJ6pT16SA">Tweet</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong>Illinois Governor JB Pritzker</strong>: “Thank you @POTUS for taking this action to protect women’s rights. We must do everything to protect access to reproductive health, the right to privacy, and the freedom of all.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/GovPritzker/status/1545519497951559680?s=20&amp;t=ymuBbBr0H1IQ8mJ6pT16SA">Tweet</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong>New Jersey Governor Phil Murphy:</strong> “President Biden’s action today builds upon the work we continue to do in New Jersey to ensure and secure every woman’s access to abortion and reproductive health care services. The President is correct that Congress must act to codify the rights protected for fifty years by Roe in federal law, but absent that action it is up to the states to protect women through our laws and the federal government, as it can through this order, to ensure access and privacy. New Jersey has enshrined the right to seek an abortion in state law, and I just signed new laws to protect any woman who comes to our state seeking abortion care, and also her doctor, from punitive actions by her home state. I am proud to have President Biden standing shoulder-to-shoulder with us in this fight.” <a href="https://twitter.com/GovMurphy/status/1545471651952967684">[Press Release</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong>New Jersey Lt. Governor Sheila Oliver:</strong> &#8220;Thank you <a href="https://twitter.com/GovMurphy/">@GovMurphy</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/">@POTUS</a> for working together to help ensure women have access to reproductive health in America.&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/LtGovOliver/status/1545500311258890240">Tweet</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong>North Carolina Governor Roy Cooper:</strong> “President Biden’s Executive Order is another strong step in the effort to protect access to reproductive health care across the country. Here in North Carolina, I will never back down when women’s health is on the line. – RC” [<a href="https://twitter.com/NC_Governor/status/1545479959812009985">Tweet</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong>Pennsylvania Governor Tom Wolf: </strong>&#8220;Thank you <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/">@POTUS</a> for prioritizing the health and safety of women and birthing people. I will continue to veto any attacks on reproductive health care that reach my desk here in Pennsylvania.&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/GovernorTomWolf/status/1545442583752712193">Tweet</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong>Washington Governor Jay Inslee</strong>: “Every action to protect abortion access matters. Thanks to @POTUS for keeping the offense going. Congress and states must do their part too.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/GovInslee/status/1545474904274792448?s=20&amp;t=ymuBbBr0H1IQ8mJ6pT16SA">Tweet</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong><em>Mayors</em></strong><br><br><strong>Denver Mayor Michael B. Hancock:</strong> &#8220;I applaud the @POTUS executive order protecting access to reproductive healthcare services for all.&#8221;&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/MayorHancock/status/1545441536380268544">Tweet</a>, 7/8/2022]<br><br><strong>New York City Mayor Eric Adams:</strong> &#8220;Thank you, @POTUS! Reproductive rights are under assault and we need to use every tool at our disposal to fight back. Now, it’s time for Congress to codify the right to access an abortion into federal law.&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/NYCMayor/status/1545464813286981639">Tweet,</a> 7/8/2022]<br><br><strong>Oakland Mayor Libby Schaaf:</strong> &#8220;Thank you President @JoeBiden and @VP @KamalaHarris for taking action to support reproductive rights after the terrible Supreme Court decision. These executive orders will make a difference to women and girls in need of health care.&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/LibbySchaaf/status/1545448525290299395">Tweet</a>, 7/8/2022]<br><br><strong>Philadelphia Mayor Jim Kenney: </strong>&#8220;Thankful that @POTUS is taking steps to protect access to reproductive health care services. SCOTUS’s ruling will disproportionately affect people of color, low-income residents, and rural Americans. This fight is not over. Get involved here in Philly: <a href="https://t.co/CvCYakI6HG">https://t.co/CvCYakI6HG</a>.&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/PhillyMayor/status/1545450129720745989">Tweet</a>, 7/8/2022]<br><br><strong>Richmond Mayor Levar Stoney: </strong>&#8220;Earlier this week, <a href="https://twitter.com/CityRichmondVA/">@CityRichmondVA</a> declared that we support the right to abortion in VA. Today, <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/">@POTUS</a> declared that abortion will be protected nationwide &#8211; no matter where you live. We stand with <a href="https://twitter.com/POTUS/">@POTUS</a> to provide safe and affordable reproductive healthcare in Richmond!&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/LevarStoney/status/1545470744959893504">Tweet</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong>Tucson Mayor Regina Romero:</strong> &#8220;Thank you @POTUS for fighting to protect women&#8217;s Constitutional right to bodily autonomy. Among its safeguards, today&#8217;s executive action protects: ✅Access to medication abortion ✅Access to contraception ✅Patient health information [<a href="https://twitter.com/TucsonRomero/status/1545453626881179648">Tweet</a>, 7/8/2022]<br><br><strong>New York City Mayor Eric Adams:</strong> &#8220;Thank you, @POTUS! Reproductive rights are under assault and we need to use every tool at our disposal to fight back. Now, it’s time for Congress to codify the right to access an abortion into federal law.&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/NYCMayor/status/1545464813286981639">Tweet,</a> 7/8/2022]<br><br><strong>Tom Cochran, CEO and Executive Director of U.S. Conference of Mayors:&nbsp; </strong>“America’s mayors applaud the efforts by President Biden and the Executive Branch to protect access to reproductive health care services in the wake of the devastating Supreme Court decision in <em>Dobbs</em>. Today’s Executive Order will also protect patient privacy and access to accurate information and promote the safety and security of patients, providers, and clinics. We further appreciate the Attorney General’s pledge on June 24 that the Justice Department will work tirelessly to protect and advance reproductive freedom. Just last month the Conference of Mayors adopted <a href="https://www.usmayors.org/the-conference/resolutions/?category=a0F4N00000QhBoyUAF&amp;meeting=90th%20Annual%20Meeting">policy</a> registering the organization’s support for a woman’s constitutional right to choose and calling on Congress to swiftly pass legislation to codify that right. We will do everything we can to help to make that happen but appreciate in the meantime the importance of this Executive Order and the support it provides to women across the country.” [<a href="https://www.usmayors.org/2022/07/08/statement-by-u-s-conference-of-mayors-on-president-bidens-executive-order-protecting-access-to-reproductive-health-care-services/">Press Release</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong>African American Mayor’s Association:</strong> &#8220;The burden and the harms of restrictions to abortion access falls disproportionately on Black communities. America&#8217;s Black mayors are working to meet this moment and ensure all of our communities have access to the reproductive health care that they need. <a href="https://t.co/F2ge1KMXqK">rb.gy/zx0bd0&#8243;</a> [<a href="https://twitter.com/OurMayors/status/1545483542729203712">Tweet</a>, 7/8/22]<br><br><strong><em>State Constitutional Officers</em></strong><br><br><strong>Minnesota Attorney General Keith Ellison:</strong> “Thank you, President Biden. Despite what 6 people on the Supreme Court say, the vast majority of Americans want the freedom to control their own bodies and their most personal choices protected. This is what protecting Americans looks like.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/AGEllison/status/1545453326225080323?s=20&amp;t=sduMHttlkjVMC2AKgtoHmA">Tweet</a>, 7/8/2022]<br><br><strong><em><u>Advocacy Organizations and Advocates</u></em></strong><br><br><strong><em>Women’s Rights Leaders</em></strong><br><br><strong>Hillary Clinton: </strong>“Make no mistake: Banning abortion puts lives at risk. Thank you, @POTUS, for taking these crucial steps to protect our most fundamental rights and access to health care.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/HillaryClinton/status/1545479819848196096">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Mini Timmaraju, President, NARAL Pro-Choice America:</strong> “All across the country, from governor&#8217;s mansions to state legislatures, pro-choice Democrats are stepping up to the plate to defend our fundamental freedom to make our own decisions about our families and futures while extremist MAGA Republicans prepare a federal abortion ban and anti-choice state officials are enforcing extreme bans on abortion state by state. President Biden’s executive order to safeguard access to reproductive healthcare, including abortion care, is an important first step in restoring the rights taken from millions of Americans by the Supreme Court. We’re encouraged by the Biden-Harris administration’s work to defend abortion rights and access, and look forward to continuing partnership with the administration to make good on its commitment to championing reproductive freedom.These actions come in the aftermath of the anti-choice supermajority on the Supreme Court overturning Roe v. Wade in its ruling in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization. This cruel decision opened the door for extremist state lawmakers to enforce extreme bans on abortion. Roughly half of the states in the country are at risk of banning abortion, and thus far, 11 states have bans in place and many more are rushing to do the same. The people hurt most by these bans and restrictions are those who already face barriers to accessing abortion care—including women; Black, Indigenous, and other people of color; those working to make ends meet; the LGBTQ+ community; immigrants; young people; those living in rural communities; and people with disabilities. [<a href="https://www.prochoiceamerica.org/2022/07/08/naral-pro-choice-america-applauds-biden-adminstrations-executive-order-protecting-reproductive-freedom/">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]<br><br><strong>Fatima Goss Graves, President and CEO, National Women&#8217;s Law Center: </strong>“We commend the President for making it clear that the full weight of the government will be brought to bear on the legal and public health crisis unfolding across our country. We expect them to move forward with the speed and intensity demanded by this Executive Order, and look forward to concrete initiatives that help people get the care they need. This crisis is here because of a decades-long strategy where extremist politicians took over our courts, restricted our right to vote, and gerrymandered their districts in order to deny us economic security, equality, and freedom. Undoing these injustices will take efforts by all of us, including using the full force of the federal government.” [<a href="https://nwlc.org/press-release/nwlc-reacts-to-president-bidens-executive-order-on-abortion/">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong>Jacqueline Ayers, Senior Vice President of Policy, Organizing and Campaigns, Planned Parenthood Federation of America: </strong>“We’re in a national health care crisis and need officials at every level of government to do everything within their authority to fight for access to abortion. Amid the Supreme Court stripping Americans of their constitutional right to abortion after nearly 50 years, we need an urgent and robust response to ensure people get the essential health care they need. Planned Parenthood is encouraged the administration is reaffirming its commitment to abortion access and looks forward to working toward implementation&nbsp; of these and other strategies to address this crisis.” [<a href="https://www.plannedparenthood.org/about-us/newsroom/press-releases/planned-parenthood-federation-of-america-responds-to-bidens-executive-order-on-abortion-rights">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong>Amanda Brown Lierman, Executive Director, Supermajority: </strong>“We applaud President Biden for stepping up to the moment and safeguarding our access to reproductive care. This Executive Order shows the Biden Administration is willing to fight for women while our rights are under attack. “The Supreme Court’s decision to overturn Roe v. Wade put the lives of millions of people, especially women of color, in danger. The decision pushed us into a new era where my three young daughters have fewer rights than I or their grandmother had. “While this Executive Order is not the only solution to this arcane and restrictive ruling, it is a critical step towards safeguarding our ability to choose. But we must continue to work until our lives are safe and our bodies are respected.&nbsp; “We cannot stop until Congress enshrines the right to safe, legal abortion care into law. Our freedom should not be gambled for political gain. Women –– as the majority bloc of voters –– have to show up to the ballot boxes and keep our elected leaders accountable. We will not stop organizing, voting, or protesting until our reproductive freedoms are permanently safe.” [<a href="https://supermajority.com/press/supermajority-supports-president-bidens-executive-order-protecting-access-to-reproductive-health-care-services/">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong><em>Healthcare Organizations</em></strong><br><br><strong>Dr. Jack Resneck, President, American Medical Association: </strong>&#8220;Across the country, since the Supreme Court’s egregious decision to overturn <em>Roe v. Wade</em>, physicians have been placed in an impossible situation – straining to meet our ethical duties to place patient health and wellbeing first, while attempting to comply with vague, restrictive, complex, and conflicting state laws that interfere in the practice of medicine and jeopardize the health of patients. The AMA applauds today’s executive order from the Biden Administration exploring pathways to protect access to reproductive health care services and provide guidance to physicians. For physicians and patients alike, this is a frightening and fraught time, with new, unprecedented concerns about data privacy, access to contraception, and even when to begin lifesaving care. Our hope is that these first steps announced today are clarifying and effective as we continue the critical work necessary to ensuring access to comprehensive reproductive health care.&#8221; [Statement, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong>Dr. Maureen Phipps, CEO, American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists:</strong> &#8220;As the nation&#8217;s leading organization representing women&#8217;s health care professionals, ACOG, our volunteer leadership, our members, and our staff have been working around the clock to provide resources and support for obstetrician-gynecologists, their patients, and their practice. We appreciate that the administration is taking steps to support clinicians, including protecting access to necessary medications; ensuring legal protections for clinicians who provide out-of-state abortion care; and issuing new guidance on EMTALA and HIPAA to support and protect clinicians, health care professionals, and patients.&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp; [<a href="https://twitter.com/acog/status/1545494437425561603">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong>Dr. Rachel Villanueva, President, National Medical Association</strong>: &#8220;We strongly support the Biden administration’s executive order to protect access to reproductive health services, including abortion and contraception. Today’s decision from the White House will protect patients’ bodily autonomy, uphold the relationship between doctors and patients, and strengthen privacy rights for everyone. As doctors, we are encouraged by these developments, especially on the heels of the Supreme Court’s decision to overturn Roe which undermines our ability to provide safe, private health care to all of our patients. Unfortunately, the Supreme Court’s decision to strip away the freedom of individuals to make deeply personal health care decisions has far-reaching and devastating consequences that the President alone cannot address, particularly for people of color. The National Medical Association urges the Senate to pass the Women’s Health Protection Act, and codify reproductive freedom for all.” [<a href="https://www.nmanet.org/news/610813/National-Medical-Association-Reacts-to-Bidens-Executive-Order-Defending-Reproductive-Health-Care.htm">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong>American Medical Women’s Association</strong>: “The American Medical Women’s Association (AMWA) supports key provisions in the Executive Order announced today by President Biden. In particular, AMWA upholds the commitment to safeguard reproductive rights, specifically to:</p>



<ul><li>Protect access to FDA-approved medication abortion</li><li>Ensure that patients are able to receive emergency medical care afforded under the law</li><li>Enable interstate travel to attain abortion care and maintain access to contraception</li><li>Protect the privacy of an individual’s health information, including reproductive health information</li></ul>



<p>The Executive Order addresses the need to protect digital health privacy so that sensitive individual health information is not sold to data brokers. AMWA supports all efforts aimed at protecting personal medical privacy as a cornerstone of the invaluable physician-patient relationship.&nbsp;As with most medical decisions, reproductive health matters, including abortion, are complex and nuanced, necessitating considerations by the patient in consultation with their physician without legislative interference.&nbsp;AMWA supports efforts to provide better protective measures that assure physicians are able to practice evidence-based medicine and deliver the most appropriate and necessary care possible. AMWA commends the efforts announced today by the White House as important steps toward securing physicians’ ability to deliver reproductive-related care without fear of legal repercussions. And, to support patients’ rights to receive desired and necessary reproductive medical care.&nbsp;AMWA champions these measures that uphold our mission to assure that quality healthcare, including abortion, is accessible and available to all.” [<a href="https://www.amwa-doc.org/news/amwa-endorses-presidents-order-reproductive-rights/">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong>Oregon Health and Science University</strong>: &#8220;Thank you President Biden for signing this Executive Order aimed at defending access to reproductive health care services. Abortion is health care.&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/ohsunews/status/1545464873986928640?s=21&amp;t=TlZI4qYDu6NQqjSTQNtwgw">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong><em>Faith</em></strong><br><br><strong>National Council of Jewish Women: &#8220;</strong>We thank @POTUS for the exec. order to create an Interagency Task Force on Reproductive Healthcare Access, signaling dedication to protecting &amp; expanding access to abortion care, incl. medication abortion, &amp; contraception, while protecting patient privacy.&#8221; &nbsp;[<a href="https://twitter.com/NCJW/status/1545495282426826753">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]<br><strong>Religious Action Center of Reform Judaism: </strong>&#8220;We welcome President Biden&#8217;s executive order, which will protect access to medication abortion &amp; contraception; protect privacy of patients; ensure emergency care; promote safety of patients, providers, &amp; clinics; &amp; form an interagency reproductive healthcare access task force. Jewish tradition teaches that providing health care is an obligation for both the doctor and for all of society. Ensuring access to care for all requires the Administration to use the full scope of executive powers. These comprehensive measures are key to reach that goal.&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/TheRAC/status/1545433386851991553">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong>Dr. Serene Jones, President, Union Theological Seminary</strong>: &#8220;Union welcomes the safeguards the Biden administration is putting in place to protect the reproductive wellbeing of all women, transgender and non-binary people. As some states work to criminalize abortion, it is essential that our federal government protect those rights, which is consistent with what the Christian faith, the Bible and the teachings of many faith traditions support. The Bible never explicitly discusses abortion. What it does consistently tell us is that human beings are moral agents, fully capable of making their own decisions. It also tells us that we should protect and love each other. And so Union thanks the Biden administration for advancing the very Christian value of protecting and loving each other. We hope that this will also spur Congress to action on codifying reproductive rights into law.” [<a href="https://utsnyc.edu/protecting-access-to-reproductive-health-care-services/">Statement</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong>American Muslim Health Professionals</strong>: &#8220;ALL women must have equitable access to quality &amp; safe reproductive healthcare services &amp; we applaud the President’s executive order today to ensure this.&#8221; [<a href="https://twitter.com/MuslimHealth/status/1545493243588009984">Tweet</a>, 7.8.22]</p>



<p><strong><em>Union Leaders<br></em></strong><br><strong>Randi Weingarten, President, AFT</strong>: “From combating disinformation to protecting access to things like medication abortion and contraception, the Biden administration is taking the necessary steps forward. It’s time for the Senate to do their part and protect reproductive freedoms.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/rweingarten/status/1545478196585455616?s=21&amp;t=jPXA8Wbf__rybfIqIu4wYA">Tweet</a>, 07/08/22]</p>



<p><strong>Liz Shuler, President, AFL-CIO</strong>: “Thank you @POTUS for taking action to protect access to critical reproductive care for millions of working people. Everyone deserves autonomy &amp; equity over their own health care.” [<a href="https://twitter.com/LizShuler/status/1545449238024314881">Tweet</a>, 07/08/22]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese, and Prime Minister Narendra Modi Mourning Former Prime Minister&#160;Abe</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/statement-by-president-joe-biden-prime-minister-anthony-albanese-and-prime-minister-narendra-modi-mourning-former-prime-minister-abe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57034</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the leaders of Australia, India, and the United States, are shocked at the tragic assassination of former Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe. Prime Minister Abe was a transformative leader for Japan and for Japanese relations with each one of our countries. He also played a formative role in the founding of the Quad partnership,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We, the leaders of Australia, India, and the United States, are shocked at the tragic assassination of former Japanese Prime Minister Shinzo Abe. Prime Minister Abe was a transformative leader for Japan and for Japanese relations with each one of our countries. He also played a formative role in the founding of the Quad partnership, and worked tirelessly to advance a shared vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific. Our hearts are with the people of Japan — and Prime Minister Kishida— in this moment of grief. We will honor Prime Minister Abe’s memory by redoubling our work towards a peaceful and prosperous region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Kishida of&#160;Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-kishida-of-japan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 23:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden called Prime Minister Kishida of Japan today to express his outrage, sadness and deep condolences on the tragic and violent shooting death of former Prime Minister Abe Shinzo. The President underscored that he and the American people stand with the Prime Minister and the people of Japan in their time of mourning. The President noted&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden called Prime Minister Kishida of Japan today to express his outrage, sadness and deep condolences on the tragic and violent shooting death of former Prime Minister Abe Shinzo. The President underscored that he and the American people stand with the Prime Minister and the people of Japan in their time of mourning. The President noted the importance of Prime Minister Abe’s enduring legacy with his vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific and the establishment of the QUAD meetings of Japan, the United States, Australia and India. The President noted our unwavering confidence in the strength of Japan’s democracy and the two leaders discussed how Abe Shinzo’s legacy will live on as we continue the important task of defending peace and democracy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What They Are Reading in the States:  President&#160;Biden’s Actions to Protect Worker Pensions, Create Jobs &#038; Honor America’s&#160;Heroes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/08/what-they-are-reading-in-the-states-president-bidens-actions-to-protect-worker-pensions-create-jobs-honor-americas-heroes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 22:47:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Local news outlets across the country are highlighting President Biden’s actions to strengthen families’ retirement savings, create good-paying jobs through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and honor extraordinary Americans who embody the soul of our nation. Following his trip to Cleveland, Ohio, newspapers and broadcast outlets across the Buckeye state covered President Biden’s announcement of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Local news outlets across the country are highlighting President Biden’s actions to strengthen families’ retirement savings, create good-paying jobs through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and honor extraordinary Americans who embody the soul of our nation.<br><br>Following his trip to Cleveland, Ohio, newspapers and broadcast outlets across the Buckeye state covered President Biden’s announcement of the American Rescue Plan’s Special Financial Assistance program. This initiative will protect two to three million workers and retirees from facing dramatic cuts to their pensions, and it will reverse previous cuts to their pensions.<br><br>Americans nationwide also witnessed President Biden present the Presidential Medal of Freedom – our Nation’s highest civilian honor – to individuals who represent the best of America because of their exemplary contributions to the prosperity, values, or security of the United States and world.  <br><br>And from Long Island to Los Angeles, travelers are reading about how President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is building better airports, investing nearly $1 billion across 85 airports to improve customer experiences, move more goods through the economy to lower prices, and enhance U.S. competitiveness.<br><br><em>See below for a sampling of the local news coverage:</em><br><br><strong><em>President Biden Highlights Actions to Protect Worker and Retiree Pensions in Cleveland, OH </em></strong><br><img loading="lazy" height="330" width="500" src="https://mcusercontent.com/c97630621baff8c44fe607661/images/55bdc323-4ddc-7cb4-10f9-83ba8070a68b.jpg"></p>



<ul><li>&nbsp;<strong>Associated Press: </strong><a href="https://apnews.com/article/biden-ohio-donald-trump-cleveland-bdef01e8e39628951433ea0f984e4133"><strong>Biden in Ohio spotlights effort to rescue union pensions</strong></a></li><li><strong>Cleveland.com: </strong><a href="https://www.cleveland.com/news/2022/07/joe-biden-in-cleveland-visit-touts-pension-fix-while-knocking-gop-lawmakers-on-economy.html"><strong>Joe Biden in Cleveland visit touts pension fix while knocking GOP lawmakers on economy</strong></a></li><li><strong>Ohio Capital Journal: </strong><a href="https://ohiocapitaljournal.com/2022/07/07/biden-touts-pension-rescue-economic-agenda-in-cleveland/"><strong>Biden touts pension rescue, economic agenda in Cleveland</strong></a></li></ul>



<p><strong><em>President Biden Awards the Medal of Freedom to American Heroes</em></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://mcusercontent.com/c97630621baff8c44fe607661/images/6bcf88ad-3093-6c2c-963b-5faae1ef00a0.jpg" alt="" /></figure>



<ul><li><strong>AL.com: </strong><a href="https://www.al.com/news/2022/07/wilma-vaught-ua-grad-who-shattered-military-glass-ceilings-among-3-medal-of-freedom-honorees-with-alabama-ties.html"><strong>Wilma Vaught, UA grad who shattered military glass ceilings, among 3 Medal of Freedom honorees with Alabama ties</strong></a></li><li><strong>Alabama News Network: </strong><a href="https://www.alabamanews.net/2022/07/07/attorney-fred-gray-receives-presidential-medal-of-freedom/"><strong>Attorney Fred Gray Receives Presidential Medal Of Freedom</strong></a></li><li><strong>Casper Star Tribune: </strong><a href="https://trib.com/news/state-and-regional/govt-and-politics/former-sen-al-simpson-receives-presidential-medal-of-freedom/article_a7d02168-fe2f-11ec-ad63-8f097c03d01a.html"><strong>Former Sen. Al Simpson receives Presidential Medal of Freedom</strong></a></li><li><strong>Houston Public Media: </strong><a href="https://www.houstonpublicmedia.org/articles/news/national/2022/07/07/428286/biden-awards-medal-of-freedom-to-springs-simone-biles-16-others-at-ceremony/"><strong>Biden awards Medal of Freedom to Spring’s Simone Biles, 16 others at ceremony</strong></a></li><li><strong>Nashville NPR: </strong><a href="https://wpln.org/post/diane-nash-says-she-shares-her-presidential-medal-of-freedom-with-everyone-who-sacrificed-so-much-for-the-cause/"><strong>Diane Nash says she shares her Presidential Medal of Freedom with everyone who ‘sacrificed so much for the cause’</strong></a></li><li><strong>Record Searchlight: </strong><a href="https://www.redding.com/story/news/2022/07/07/biden-medal-of-freedom-denzel-washington-simone-biles-megan-rapinoe-steve-jobs-john-mccain/10007800002/"><strong>Biden awards Medal of Freedom to Palo Cedro’s Megan Rapinoe, 16 others</strong></a></li><li><strong>The Tennessean: </strong><a href="https://www.tennessean.com/story/news/local/2022/07/07/nashville-civil-rights-icons-diane-nash-fred-gray-awarded-medal-freedom/7823472001/"><strong>Civil rights icons Diane Nash, Fred Gray awarded Medal of Freedom by President Joe Biden</strong></a></li><li><strong>Tucson Sentinel: </strong><a><strong>Biden: Medal of Freedom recipients Giffords, McCain &amp; others are ‘soul of our nation’</strong></a></li><li><strong>ABC Los Angeles:&nbsp; </strong><a href="https://abc7.com/long-beach-sister-simone-campbell-medal-of-freedom-joe-biden/12027363/"><strong>Long Beach native, longtime social justice lobbyist Sister Simone Campbell receives Medal of Freedom</strong></a></li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Biden-Harris Administration Announces Historic Airport Infrastructure Funding</em></strong></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://mcusercontent.com/c97630621baff8c44fe607661/images/f1adf141-567c-e4f3-c78c-96afe7aa2cea.jpg" alt="" /></figure>



<ul><li><strong>Atlanta Journal Constitution: </strong><a href="https://www.ajc.com/news/atlanta-airport-blog/atlanta-airport-gets-40m-from-feds-for-concourse-d-expansion/ZEFT3YFJBJHU5J5GX2AOIJOHZI/"><strong>Atlanta airport gets $40M from feds for Concourse D expansion</strong></a></li><li><strong>Dallas Morning News: </strong><a href="https://www.dallasnews.com/business/airlines/2022/07/07/dfw-airport-lands-35-million-for-new-zero-carbon-power-plant/"><strong>DFW Airport lands $35 million for new zero-carbon power plant</strong></a></li><li><strong>Houston Chronicle: </strong><a href="https://www.houstonchronicle.com/news/houston-texas/transportation/article/Bush-Hobby-airports-receive-combined-43-6-17288705.php"><strong>Houston&#8217;s Bush, Hobby airports to receive $43.6 million for terminal upgrades</strong></a></li><li><strong>Washington Post: </strong><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/transportation/2022/07/07/dulles-airport-new-concourse/"><strong>Plan for 14-gate Dulles concourse gets boost from infrastructure law</strong></a></li><li><strong>Arkansas Democrat Gazette: </strong><a href="https://www.arkansasonline.com/news/2022/jul/07/airports-in-northwest-arkansas-texarkana-to-get-18m-for-terminal-improvements/"><strong>Airports in Northwest Arkansas, Texarkana to get $18M for terminal improvements</strong></a></li><li><strong>Los Angeles Times: </strong><a href="https://www.latimes.com/california/story/2022-07-07/at-lax-buttigieg-announces-california-airports-get-100-million"><strong>California airports get $100 million to upgrade terminals and roads, Buttigieg announces</strong></a></li><li><strong>Orlando Business Journal:</strong><a href="https://www.bizjournals.com/orlando/news/2022/07/07/florida-biden-orlando-international-airport-grant.html"> <strong>Orlando International Airport was one of 85 U.S. airports to get a federal grant this month to help expand capacity and improve access.</strong></a></li><li><strong>Times West Virginia: </strong><a href="https://www.timeswv.com/news/local_news/ncwv-airport-receives-15m-windfall-from-usdot-for-new-terminal-project/article_100a2b30-fe2f-11ec-9175-8faea5be113a.html"><strong>NCWV Airport receives $15M windfall from USDOT for new terminal project</strong></a></li><li><strong>YourValley: </strong><a href="https://yourvalley.net/stories/14m-coming-to-phoenix-mesa-gateway-airport-from-infrastructure-law,315116"><strong>$14M coming to Phoenix-Mesa Gateway Airport from infrastructure law</strong></a></li><li><strong>Spectrum (Austin, TX): </strong><a href="https://spectrumlocalnews.com/tx/austin/news/2022/07/08/austin-airport-breaks-another-record-as-it-s-set-to-receive--15m-for-expansion"><strong>Austin airport breaks another record as it&#8217;s set to receive $15M for expansion</strong></a></li><li><strong>WAFF (NBC Huntsville, AL): </strong><a href="https://www.waff.com/2022/07/08/huntsville-international-airport-receiving-10-million-grant/"><strong>Huntsville International Airport receiving $10 million grant</strong></a></li><li><strong>ABC Los Angeles: </strong><a href="https://abc7.com/lax-infrastructure-grant-pete-buttigieg-biden-administration/12028962/"><strong>LAX awarded $50 million grant under Biden infrastructure plan</strong></a></li><li><strong>Douglas County Sentinel: </strong><a href="https://www.douglascountysentinel.com/news/local/atlanta-airport-s-concourse-d-slated-for-upgrades/article_9b2da018-f6bc-578b-874b-bfe368fc406e.html"><strong>Atlanta airport&#8217;s Concourse D slated for upgrades</strong></a></li><li><strong>Georgia Public Broadcasting: </strong><a href="https://www.gpb.org/news/2022/07/07/federal-funding-supports-hartsfield-jackson-airport-upgrades"><strong>Federal funding supports Hartsfield-Jackson Airport upgrades</strong></a></li><li><strong>Times-Republican: </strong><a href="https://www.timesrepublican.com/news/todays-news/2022/07/iowa-airports-receive-27-million-in-grants-from-federal-government/"><strong>Iowa airports receive $27 million in grants from federal government</strong></a></li><li><strong>WAFB (CBS Baton Rouge, LA): </strong><a href="https://www.wafb.com/2022/07/07/baton-rouge-metro-airport-set-receive-52m-infrastructure-law-funding/"><strong>Baton Rouge Metro Airport set to receive $5.2M in infrastructure law funding</strong></a></li><li><strong>WABI (NBC Bangor, ME): </strong><a href="https://www.wabi.tv/2022/07/07/bangor-international-airport-getting-142-million-expansion-renovations/"><strong>Bangor International Airport getting $14.2 million for expansion, renovations</strong></a></li><li><strong>KDUZ (Hutchinson, MN): </strong><a href="https://kduz.com/2022/07/08/local-airport-among-4-in-mn-to-get-federals-funds/"><strong>Local Airport Among 4 in MN to Get Federal Funds</strong></a></li><li><strong>Nebraska Public Media: </strong><a href="https://nebraskapublicmedia.org/en/news/news-articles/lincoln-and-omaha-airports-receive-federal-funding-for-renovations/"><strong>Lincoln and Omaha Airports Receive Federal Funding for Renovations</strong></a></li><li><strong>WMUR (ABC Manchester, NH): </strong><a href="https://www.wmur.com/article/manchester-boston-regional-airport-4-million-improve-terminals-7722/40551021"><strong>Manchester-Boston Regional Airport receives $4.1 million in funding to improve terminals</strong></a></li><li><strong>Long Island Business News: </strong><a href="https://libn.com/2022/07/08/macarthur-airport-to-get-14-11m-from-faa/?ep=1"><strong>MacArthur Airport to get $14.11M from FAA</strong></a></li><li><strong>WXPI (NBC Pittsburgh, PA): </strong><a href="https://www.wpxi.com/news/business/pittsburgh-international-airport-lands-20m-its-new-terminal-project-part-federal-infrastr/2LFO3TDHCBAHDKYKFSIVVIAKYI/"><strong>Pittsburgh airport lands $20M for its new terminal project as part of federal infrastructure law</strong></a></li><li><strong>KFOX (Fox El Paso, TX): </strong><a href="https://kfoxtv.com/news/local/el-paso-international-airport-awarded-5-million-from-infrastructure-law"><strong>El Paso International Airport awarded $5 million from infrastructure law</strong></a></li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris During Roundtable Discussion with State Legislators on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/08/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-during-roundtable-discussion-with-state-legislators-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 22:46:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57026</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial OfficeEisenhower Executive Office Building THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon.  I want to welcome and thank these extraordinary leaders, who are based in various states but who are also national leaders, for coming together so we could have this conversation about, I think, one of the most challenging and troubling issues of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President&#8217;s Ceremonial Office<br><em>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon.  I want to welcome and thank these extraordinary leaders, who are based in various states but who are also national leaders, for coming together so we could have this conversation about, I think, one of the most challenging and troubling issues of the day.<br> <br>Last month, as we all know &#8212; actually, just weeks ago, the Supreme Court of the United States did something that is &#8212; before then was unthinkable and unprecedented, which is the United States Supreme Court took a constitutional right that had previously been recognized &#8212; took it from the women of America and with great consequence, as we know. <br> <br>This is not a law school debate.  This is not an intellectual discussion and debate.  This is real in the way that it is currently and will impact the women and the girls of America in a very direct way. <br> <br>It goes without saying that I think we share a belief that women should be able to make decisions about their own bodies without interference from their government; that she should be able to make a decision about whether or not to have an abortion in the privacy of a safe place where she will make that decision &#8212; be it with her pastor, her priest, her rabbi, her family, a physician &#8212; but not requiring permission from her government.<br> <br>So, this is about that.  This is also, for so many reasons that are integral to what is at stake, a healthcare crisis in America, I would offer.<br> <br>We have heard recent examples of what this means for a girl as young as 10 years old, who endured an act of violence &#8212; I say as a former prosecutor who specialized in child sexual assault &#8212; and who then has to endure a system that clearly is not in its current design with these laws in place, designed in a way that is about keeping her in mind in terms of what will give her a safe place in a way that she can address and those around her who care about her can address her needs.<br> <br>When we look at this issue, we know that it affects our country at every level, in each and every region.  We also know that the federal government and we, our administration, recognizes the power and the importance and the responsibility we have to partner with elected leaders in local, state, and at the federal level.  And so that&#8217;s why I&#8217;ve asked you all to come and join us today, so we can have a conversation about what&#8217;s happening in your states.<br> <br>I do want to emphasize though, back to the point of the 10-year-old girl that we&#8217;ve been hearing so much about: We have, I believe, 12 states in our country that, right now, will not even allow an exception in their ban on abortion &#8212; will not even allow an exception for rape or incest.<br> <br>We have in our country states that are criminalizing healthcare professionals for doing what they believe is in the best interest, in the public health interest of their community.<br> <br>And so, again, we take these issues quite seriously, understanding the ramifications and the injustice that is playing out associated with this issue.<br> <br>So, I also believe that this is just the beginning.  When we &#8212; most of us have read the opinion and the concurring opinion.  As I&#8217;ve said before, Justice Thomas said the quiet part out loud, which is that also at risk is the right for individuals to make the most intimate decisions that they can make about what I call &#8220;heart and home&#8221; when it comes to issues like contraception, same-sex marriage.<br> <br>And so, there is a lot at stake.  We cannot wait for Congress to act.  Congress must act.  But also, we cannot wait for Congress to act, which is why the President, Joe Biden, this morning, earlier today issued executive orders around what we will do at the federal level to ensure that women are not impeded in terms of their right to interstate travel and also that they will have access to the medication that they need, which, by the way, the FDA approved, I believe, over 20 years ago.<br> <br>So, with that, there&#8217;s a lot at stake.  We are working together.  We will continue to work together.<br> <br>And, with that, I&#8217;m going to invite a discussion for the leaders around the table.  And I&#8217;ll start to my left with Representative GiaQuinta from the great state of Indiana.<br> <br>                        END                4:07 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine&#160;Jean-Pierre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/08/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:57 P.M.&#160;EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Okay.&#160; And Happy Friday to everyone.&#160; Just a quick note, because we wanted to make sure we had a briefing today, but the President, as you know, has a very tight schedule.&#160; Today he&#8217;s going to be heading to the CIA, so&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:57 P.M.&nbsp;EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And Happy Friday to everyone.&nbsp; Just a quick note, because we wanted to make sure we had a briefing today, but the President, as you know, has a very tight schedule.&nbsp;<br><br>Today he&#8217;s going to be heading to the CIA, so this is going to be a short briefing, so apologies at the top.&nbsp; But again, we wanted to make sure you guys all had an opportunity to ask your questions.<br><br>So joining us today is Jen Klein, the Director of the White House Gender Policy Council, which was established by President Biden at the start of this administration.&nbsp; This is her second time in the Briefing Room, some of you might remember.<br><br>By creating the Gender Policy Council, President Biden fulfilled a campaign promise to create a White House team backed by the whole of government for defending women&#8217;s rights and advancing equality.&nbsp;<br><br>When the draft decision of Dobbs was leaked this spring, Jen Klein and the Gender Policy Council, along with other senior officials here at the White House, put every policy action on the table and evaluated them through an intensive process to determine which were the strongest and the most meaningful.<br><br>With that, Jen, I’ll let you take it away.<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, Karine, for having me today.&nbsp; As you said, when the final decision was issued, the President took immediate action under his executive authority to defend reproductive rights.&nbsp; And just now, as you know, he signed an executive order which builds on those actions.<br><br>So just to talk a little bit about what&#8217;s in this executive order: It safeguards access to reproductive health services, building on steps HHS has already taken to ensure that medication abortion and contraception, including emergency contraception and long-acting contraception, are as widely available as possible, as well as the Attorney General&#8217;s commitment to fight any attack by a state or local official who attempts to interfere with women exercising their constitutional right to travel out of state for medical care.<br><br>It also protects the privacy of patients and their access to accurate information, building on steps that HHS Office of Civil Rights has already begun to take to ensure that doctors and medical providers and plans know that, with limited exceptions, they&#8217;re not required and, in many cases, they&#8217;re not even permitted to disclose patients’ private information.<br><br>It also promotes the safety and security of patients, providers, and clinics &#8212; the physical safety and security.&nbsp; And finally, it coordinates the implementation of federal efforts to protect reproductive rights and access to healthcare.<br><br>As Karine said, my team, working really with colleagues all across the White House and around the administration, has been working around the clock since the draft decision was leaked in May.&nbsp; And we are going to continue to evaluate all options and steps that we can take.&nbsp;<br><br>So, as Karine said, I know we&#8217;re short on time.&nbsp; So, with that, I&#8217;ll just be open to take your questions.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Aamer.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, ma’am, Senator Marco Rubio is demanding the federal government &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; not provide sick leave to federal employees.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; If I &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you respect the Hyde Amendment?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Medicaid Admin- &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will this administration respect the Hyde Amendment?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Medicaid Administrator said that the Biden administration was considering having Medicaid pay for travel for people.&nbsp; And with some of the instances that the President just highlighted in his speech just now, that seems like something that would be very useful right away.&nbsp; Just wondering, why isn&#8217;t that included in this tranche of action?<br><br>And then secondly, if you could just broadly speak: There&#8217;s been some frustration with abortion rights supporters that this administration is not moving fast enough.&nbsp; Some of this stuff seems like it could have been done on day one, considering you knew the leak and what was coming.<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; So, on your first question on Medicaid, you know, as you heard from the President the day of the decision and again today as part of this executive order, we are very focused on protecting that right to travel.&nbsp;<br><br>The Attorney General issued an extremely strong statement, again, on the day of the decision, and has continued to be vigilant so that no woman, no person who is seeking a medical service in a state where it is legal is prevented from doing that.<br><br>We&#8217;re also looking at all options to figure out how to best effectuate that right to travel.<br><br>On your second question more broadly, I sort of take issue with the premise of the question, because I think, first of all, what the President did on day one, which was really significant, was to take immediate action, as I said, to ensure that medication abortion is available and accessible.&nbsp;<br><br>Fifty-four percent of abortions in this country are through Medicaid [sic] abortion &#8212; medica- &#8212; medication abortion, excuse me.&nbsp; So that is a hugely significant thing to make sure that people have accurate information about medication abortion and have the right to take it.<br><br>You know, a sort of falsity that is already out there is that it&#8217;s illegal everywhere in the country.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re, in this executive order, taking further action to make sure that the FDA has the support they need to go through their scientific process and that people have the information they need to access and get this vital critical medication, as well as contraception, which, you know, as we noted, the Supreme Court put on the table already.<br><br>The other thing I would say is, you know, the leaked decision was two weeks ago.&nbsp; So in addition to the immediate actions that the administration took, Secretary of Health and Human Services Becerra took a series of actions while the President was away in Europe.&nbsp; When he came back, his first public event was meeting with nine Democratic governors, who really are in the frontlines, to talk to them about what we could do best to help them and what they are doing on their own to actually ensure reproductive rights and health in their states.<br><br>And then the last thing I would say &#8212; and, you know, you heard the President say it &#8212; is: You can&#8217;t solve by executive action what the Supreme Court has done.&nbsp; The Supreme Court has taken away a constitutional right that was precedent for nearly 50 years.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think we all need to be mindful &#8212; he is very mindful, we are all very mindful &#8212; that that can&#8217;t be solved by executive action alone and that the best and fastest way to fix that is by codifying Roe, restoring Roe by legislation.&nbsp; But that doesn&#8217;t mean we won&#8217;t be taking the actions he took today and more as we consider best actions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is there a disconnect there?&nbsp; Because there is frustration.&nbsp; There is no doubt there&#8217;s a lot of frustration, and some of the frustration is undoubtedly &#8212; through anybody in this room that’s spoken to a voter or an American that supports abortion rights &#8212; that there is frustration with the administration.&nbsp; So is there a disconnect in what&#8217;s happening and their ability to message it?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; Well, I would say that, you know, first of all, if you look at what NARAL and Planned Parenthood said today about the actions that we’re taking, they’ve both called it, you know, important steps.<br><br>And I&#8217;ve been in constant contact with stakeholders across lots of different constituencies and lots of different coalitions, from women&#8217;s rights to reproductive rights and justice, civil rights, community, businesses, medical providers, I mean, the American Medical Associa- &#8212; Association and the ACOG and &#8212; American College of Obstetrics and Gynecology.&nbsp; Very supportive of the actions we&#8217;re taking to protect providers’ rights and responsibilities to offer the services that they are legally allowed to provide, and to make sure that their responsibilities but also protect them in this time where, you know, what we are experiencing already but will continue to experience is serious legal chaos.<br><br>So I think we are taking strong action.&nbsp; And again, we&#8217;re going to continue to look for where we can take the most significant actions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does this administration &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Michael.&nbsp; Michael.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; respect the Hyde Amendment, ma’am?&nbsp; Simple question.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Michael.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s a real simple question.&nbsp; Do you respect the Hyde Amendment or no?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Michael, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can’t answer that question?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Michael.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, so I’m a little still confused about what the actual &#8212; the order actually does.&nbsp; It says here that it directs Mr. Becerra to develop a report identifying potential actions; to consider updates to guidances; to &#8212; it directs the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission to consider actions; it asks Mr. Becerra to consider actions about protecting information; it talks about protecting the &#8212; you know, the sort of safety of people, but it doesn&#8217;t say how.<br><br>I mean, how is this &#8212; how is any of this actually doing the things that you say it&#8217;s doing, or isn&#8217;t it just repeating what the President said two weeks ago that he wanted to do but has already, both he and &#8212; he and Mr. Becerra have both said their, sort of, hands are tied?&nbsp; I think Mr. Becerra’s comment was that there is no silver bullet here.&nbsp; So, I mean, what is it actually going to do tomorrow?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; There are &#8212; there are many new things in here, so let me &#8212; let me walk through a few of them.<br><br>First of all, on privacy: You know, what we are seeing is already an assault on people&#8217;s privacy.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s sort of two things in the executive order to address that.&nbsp; The first is through the Federal Trade Commission.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it doesn’t actually do anything.&nbsp; It says it asks the Federal Trade Commissioner to consider actions, right?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So the Federal Trade &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What actions &#8212; what actions do you want him to do?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; The Federal Trade Commission is obviously an independent agency, so the President can&#8217;t compel them, which is why, you know, the exe- &#8212; the words of the executive order are “to consider.”&nbsp;<br><br>But what I believe the Federal Trade Commission is looking to do is to ensure that people&#8217;s private health information is not sold by data brokers, that when somebody goes on and does a Google search to find an abortion clinic, that that information is not made publicly available.<br><br>They have to make their &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How are they &#8212; how are they going to do that?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; They have to make &#8212; they have to make their own enforcement decisions, and obviously, neither nor &#8212; certainly not me, but the President can&#8217;t compel them to bring any sort of enforcement action.&nbsp; But they can clarify their policy, and that&#8217;s what this executive order asks them to do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you guys know what policies you would like them to clarify?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; Just what I said: that &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I mean, specifically?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; They&#8217;re the experts, and so they will make a determination and then release a policy statement, I believe, that will ensure that people&#8217;s private, sensitive health information is protected on the Internet, that people have access to accurate information.<br><br>This is &#8212; this is what they will be able to do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And the second piece is the HHS Secretary &#8212; that&#8217;s not &#8212; he’s not an independent agent.&nbsp; So why &#8212; why are you just directing him to consider actions?&nbsp; And what actions do you want him to consider?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; So, what the executive order asks the Secretary to do is come back within 30 days with a plan.&nbsp; So part of this, as you are noting, are things the President has talked about and what &#8212; and what the Secretary has already started to work on.&nbsp;<br><br>And what this asks for is a very deliberate plan and process to make sure that medication abortion is available; to support the FDA in their determination &#8212; their scientific determination about this medic- &#8212; critical medication, which, by the way, has been safe and legal for 20 years; and to take other steps.&nbsp;<br><br>So, to take one other example, emergency medical care.&nbsp; We need to make sure that when somebody walks into an emergency room and they&#8217;re pregnant, that they are getting the care that they need and that they are not being turned away because &#8212; either because a provider doesn&#8217;t know that they&#8217;re legally required or able to give them that care.&nbsp;<br><br>So there is guidance that the secretary can issue and the Secretary will issue to make clear what kind of treatment somebody needs to be &#8212; needs to receive when they walk into an emergency room.&nbsp;<br><br>Same thing for pharmacists.&nbsp; You know, again, back to the notion of legal chaos, pharmacists don&#8217;t know whether they can dispense mifepristone, the drug which is medication abortion &#8212; which, by the way, is used in miscarriages, which are 1 in 10 pregnancies.&nbsp;<br><br>So again, the Secretary can take action, through guidance from the Department of Health and Human Services specifically, to make clear to pharmacists, again, what their responsibilities are but also what their rights are as pharmacists so that they are not putting themselves in jeopardy.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; The White House says this executive action will expand access to medication abortion.&nbsp; How, specifically, will the administration do that?&nbsp; What concrete steps will be taken?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re looking for the Secretary to come back to us with.&nbsp; I mean, the two things immediately is &#8212; is what I&#8217;ve noted, which is that the FDA is in a process right now, and they need to continue to do their process.&nbsp; And again, they are independent, they&#8217;re making their own scientific judgment, but to do &#8212; to extend permanently what they did in April.&nbsp;<br><br>So, in April, what they did was they said that medication abortion should be available by telehealth, and it should be able to be &#8212; to be mailed.&nbsp;<br><br>And currently, they&#8217;re going through a scientific process.&nbsp; And we can&#8217;t interfere with that process, but the Secretary can support them in any way that he needs to.&nbsp;<br><br>And the other thing is we, you know, launched a website, ReproductiveRights.gov, and there will be many other ways to communicate &#8212; again, as I said, both, you know, critical medications like medication abortion, but also contraception, which is at risk.&nbsp;<br><br>Emergency contraception is at risk in states across the country now, partly because there are states that are &#8212; are passing laws that say that fertilization &#8212; that fertilization begins &#8212; that pregnancy begins at fertilization, and that puts a drug like emergency contraception at risk.&nbsp; And we need to clarify for people what is and isn&#8217;t available to them.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just to &#8212; just to follow up really quickly here.&nbsp; Is this sort of like a wait-and-see approach here for the American people?&nbsp; The White House says that this executive action will be expanding access to medication abortion, but right now, there&#8217;s no details, no concrete steps until the Department of Health and Human Services releases that in 30 days?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; The Secretary &#8212; I mean, I know it feels frustrating because we&#8217;re taking action and then asking for more action.&nbsp; But the Secretary is already taking action.&nbsp; The website is already launched.&nbsp; The Attorney General has already made a statement that we will be vigilant about protecting people&#8217;s right to travel and also to look at the question about whether mifepristone should be available and how it can be available, because the FDA has already spoken, 20 years ago, that this is a safe and effective drug.&nbsp;<br><br>And at the same time, what we&#8217;ve asked for is, you know, continued vigilance and an ongoing process and ongoing work to make sure that that is really happening.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, as I said, this is not going to be solved by one day&#8217;s action.&nbsp; So the &#8212; you know, the strong statement at the outset; all the work we&#8217;ve done, both before the decision and after the decision; and then, you know, we will come back.&nbsp; And you know, the report from the Secretary is just one step in the process.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; They moved the gather time, so we got to go.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, again, the Hyde Amendment &#8212; will you answer my question?&nbsp; Really simple. &nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Phil.&nbsp; And then (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The idea of a public health emergency has been something some advocates have pressed for.&nbsp; My understanding is it’s not off the table but that the consideration may give a window into the complexities that you guys are trying to deal with right now.&nbsp; Can you explain, kind of, the approach as it pertains to that specific item?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, as you said, we&#8217;re really looking at everything.&nbsp; And it is definitely not off the table, as are many other options.&nbsp;<br><br>When we looked at the public health emergency, we learned a couple things.&nbsp; One is that it doesn&#8217;t free very many resources.&nbsp; It&#8217;s what&#8217;s in the public health emergency fund, and there&#8217;s very little money &#8212; tens of thousands of dollars in it.&nbsp; So that didn&#8217;t seem like a great option.&nbsp; And it also doesn&#8217;t release a significant amount of legal authority.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s why we haven&#8217;t taken that action yet.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, ma’am, pro-life Americans &#8212; one question.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sir, you’re being rude.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Pro-life Americans &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sir, you’re being rude to your colleagues.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All the questions you’re taking are pro-abortion.&nbsp; So let me ask you this question.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Excuse me &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Senator Marco Rubio &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Caitlin.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; is demanding &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the federal government not provide sick leave to federal employees who travel to get abortions.&nbsp; Should &#8212; he says that would violate the Hyde Amendment.&nbsp; So, what’s your response to it?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sir, take a seat in the back.&nbsp; You’re being rude to your colleagues and our guest.<br><br>Go ahead, Caitlin.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m not (inaudible).&nbsp; I can stand right here and ask my questions (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sir, please.&nbsp; Please.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I can ask my question.&nbsp; She doesn’t want to answer it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President, earlier today, encouraged people to go out and vote, and essentially said, “If you want to change the rights for women, you have to show up at the ballot box.”&nbsp;<br><br>Does that suggest that, with this order, the President has reached the limit of what he can do unilaterally?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; No, it does not.&nbsp; It means it&#8217;s an important step that we&#8217;re taking today.&nbsp; And we will continue to look at all options on the table that are legally appropriate.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have another question about privacy.&nbsp; Is the White House encouraging people in states where abortion is going to be illegal to not use different apps &#8212; period-tracking apps, Google searches on fertility, those kinds of things?&nbsp; Is the White House directing people to stop using those apps?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t say we&#8217;re directing people.&nbsp; But I think people should be really careful about that.&nbsp; And one of the things that HHS did just last week was &#8212; as part of this website and also made public in other ways &#8212; is literal instructions, practical instructions of how to delete certain apps that are on your phone so that if you want to protect yourself, you have the ability to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, sorry, quickly on the abortion pill: Is the President, is the administration directing the FDA to loosen restrictions on the abortion pill?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; The President can&#8217;t direct the FDA.&nbsp; The FDA has to go through their process.&nbsp; But &#8212; and they are in the middle of a process not to loosen restrictions but to clarify what the restrictions are and who can dispense and who can prescribe mifepristone.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Two questions left.&nbsp; Jeff and then &#8212; go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give &#8212; right here.&nbsp; Oh, and also, earlier you said the leaked decision came out two weeks ago.&nbsp; You probably meant six weeks.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; Sorry, yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The actual one was two weeks ago.<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; The actual decision.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of what other options are on the table now that this executive order has been signed?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to preview our process.&nbsp; But all the things that you&#8217;ve heard about that have been suggested by advocates, by members of Congress &#8212; literally every single one of those things we have run down and either decided was not a viable option at the moment or are continuing to run down.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one question about the pill.&nbsp; Is this White House studying or is the administration studying making it easier for people to get that pill without a prescription?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; Again, the FDA has to go through their process.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s currently not only not &#8212; it is not available without a prescription.&nbsp; And &#8212; and, in fact, there are part of these &#8212; the guidance that FDA has already issued is pretty specific about it.&nbsp;<br><br>So I can&#8217;t answer a question about what they might consider in the future.&nbsp; But I would say: At present time, it is &#8212; it is a pretty regulated medication.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; One of the executive actions announced today was creating a task force.&nbsp; Why wasn’t that created after the Dobbs decision was leaked to help prepare?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve been &#8212; you know, a number of us have called it a task force, a war room.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been meeting literally every day for weeks, far before the &#8212; not only the decision, but the leaked decision, to think about all of the options that we could put in place to respond.&nbsp;<br><br>So this just formalizes the interagency work that&#8217;s been going on between the Department of Justice, the Department of Health and Human Services &#8212; really all of the agencies and across the White House.&nbsp;<br><br>And the reason, actually, we decided to formalize it and also to make clear that it will also be available as a way to communicate and coordinate with states was when the President met with the governors, they specifically asked for it.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things that was really interesting to us is that when we&#8217;ve been meeting with state attorneys general, state legislators, and as well when the President met with the governors &#8212; and, by the way, the Vice President has had a number of meetings, as have I, with all of those different state officials.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things that has come to the front is the avail &#8212; is the importance of connecting them to each other, creating a network so that they can learn from each other.&nbsp; So, you know, states that are looking at laws to prevent extradition of providers who are providing a legal service in the state of, you know, where they &#8212; where they reside, it became really clear that this was something that was very much needed.&nbsp; So we decided to make it part of this order.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one clarifying question on the public health emergency.&nbsp; So, if &#8212; would you say that you &#8212; the White House believes it has the authority to declare the public health emergency to preserve broad access to abortion services?<br><br>MS. KLEIN:&nbsp; The Secretary of Health and Human Services has to declare a public health emergency.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not a question of legal authority that &#8212; he has the authority to do that at any time.&nbsp; The question is, “What authority does he gain by declaring a public health emergency?”<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you take any questions from a pro-life American audience at all?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No?&nbsp; You’ll just walk away?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, I have a question.&nbsp; Does the President have a reaction to the passing of the former Angolan President, Eduardo dos Santos?&nbsp; I noticed that you just had your reaction to the passing of &#8212; to the death of the Japanese prime minister.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let me &#8212; let me just get started, and then I&#8217;ll &#8212; I’ll come back to you.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; Let me just get started with the &#8212; with the briefing.&nbsp;<br><br>We don&#8217;t have a lot of time.&nbsp; As we know, the President is going to be leaving for CIA pretty sho- &#8212; pretty soon, and we&#8217;re going to gather very shortly.&nbsp;<br><br>But I do want to take a point of privilege and acknowledge Angela Perez, who is going to be leaving us.&nbsp; We have many big things to celebrate today, but you leaving and getting a promotion to the Department of Commerce as Deputy Press Secretary.&nbsp;<br><br>Angela has been with us from the beginning.&nbsp; She is what we call an “OG Biden person.”&nbsp; She was with us on the campaign.&nbsp; And her tell &#8212; intelligence, her follow through, and humor had been a gift to all of her colleagues here at the White House.&nbsp; I know some of you have experienced her humor in this very room.&nbsp;<br><br>And we are going to be incredibly sad to see you go.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also going to be cheering you on as you do &#8212; go and do really amazing and great things.&nbsp; And as I said, today is her last day.&nbsp; And we love you, Angela.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for all that you do.&nbsp;<br><br>All right, Aamer, why don’t you kick us off?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; One question.&nbsp; I understand we’re tight on time.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Shireen Abu Akleh’s family sent President Biden a letter in which they noted their “sense of betrayal” with the State Department’s report on her killing.&nbsp; It was a very scathing letter.&nbsp;<br><br>Will the President meet with the family?&nbsp; Will he bring up the case with Israeli officials next week?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I haven&#8217;t seen the letter as yet.&nbsp; I have heard about the letter; I just haven&#8217;t had a sens- &#8212; a chance to read it.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President&#8217;s travel and what he&#8217;ll be doing on his travel in the Middle East.&nbsp;<br><br>But I can assure you that he has been closely monitoring the developments of the investigation into Shireen’s killing.&nbsp; You have heard us talk about it many times right here at this podium.&nbsp;<br><br>Senior American officials also continue to be in touch with Abu Akleh family.&nbsp; And we hear their concerns.&nbsp; We feel their pain.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t even &#8212; we can&#8217;t even imagine what they must be going through.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to imagine.&nbsp;<br><br>We continue to urge cooperation between Israel and the Palestinian Authority on next steps.&nbsp; And we &#8212; and we definitely continue to urge accountability.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as far as the gather: Is the briefing going to continue?&nbsp; And &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go for &#8212; I&#8217;ll go a little bit longer for folks who stay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Should people gather and leave at 1:20?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I bel- &#8212; they should if they want to &#8212; if they want to catch &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; the President at the CIA.&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll continue.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Jeff.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one quick one before we leave?&nbsp; Can you give us an update on the President&#8217;s thinking on tariffs and lifting tariffs in China?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so we don&#8217;t have anything, clearly, right now, at this time on &#8212; on the &#8212; on the tariff decision.&nbsp; The President, as I&#8217;ve said many times, is considering all options.&nbsp; This is an important decision that the President is making on behalf of the American public.&nbsp;<br><br>As soon as we &#8212; as soon as we have something, we will we will share that.<br><br>Go ahead, Caitlin.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some Democratic senators have praised the President&#8217;s executive order today but say that he should be doing more.&nbsp; What else is the White House planning on doing?&nbsp; And does the President believe that he can do any more on this issue?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the President &#8212; you heard him speak very passionately today.&nbsp; He is going to continue to do everything that he can &#8212; the legal authority that he has &#8212; to continue to work and make sure that we &#8212; that we look at all options to protect women, to protect women&#8217;s rights, and their freedoms.&nbsp; So it doesn&#8217;t end today.&nbsp;<br><br>It be- &#8212; it be- &#8212; you know, all of this kind of began on the day that decision was &#8212; the Dobbs decision was made.&nbsp;<br><br>But he&#8217;s been also very clear &#8212; like I said, you heard him today: The way to &#8212; to really address this is for people to make sure that their voices are heard at the ballot box.&nbsp; That is what he is calling for.&nbsp; That is what we are &#8212; we are asking our fellow Americans to make sure that they speak up and get their voices heard.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But does that &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does that suggest that he believes that he doesn&#8217;t have any more legal authority to act on this issue?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, he said he&#8217;s going to &#8212; he has &#8212; we have continued to say he&#8217;s going to look at every option that he has.&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, here&#8217;s what we saw &#8212; right? &#8212; we heard him say that what &#8212; the SCOTUS decision was not driven by the Constitution.&nbsp; It was driven by political and extreme raw political power.&nbsp; A decision that was made &#8212; he disagrees with that decision.&nbsp; He thinks it&#8217;s extreme.&nbsp; We have to be sure, and we continue &#8212;<br><br>He wants to be straight with the American people.&nbsp; And if you look at what&#8217;s going to happen across the board; if you look at what Republicans &#8212; national Republicans are saying: They&#8217;re asking or going to go for a national ban.&nbsp;<br><br>So our work now is &#8212; he&#8217;s going to &#8212; again, continue to do the work that he can from here.&nbsp; But also, you know, call on Congress to act.&nbsp; If they cannot, we have to make sure that people&#8217;s voices are heard at the ballot box.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just quickly, has he ruled out the sanctioning of federal lands for abortion?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, we are &#8212; we&#8217;re looking at all options.&nbsp; Everything is on the table.&nbsp; We have talked about how, you know, while this is a &#8212; a idea that comes from a good place, it is definitely a difficult thing to protect the provider or to protect any &#8212; any woman who is on federal land, once they leave.&nbsp; It puts them in a legal &#8212; kind of an illegal bind.&nbsp; So it is something that we have to think about when we have those discussions.&nbsp;<br><br>But again, everything is on the table.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to do everything that he can from whatever legal authority that he has to make sure that we continue to protect women&#8217;s rights and also the freedom of women.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In many ways, the President&#8217;s rhetoric today was almost declaring war on the Court.&nbsp; He talked about galvanizing women voters, especially, to act.&nbsp; But he said some things that are kind of unusual for a President who is an institutionalist, when you&#8217;re talking about a co-equal branch of government.&nbsp;<br><br>Is it the President&#8217;s view that the Court is not apolitical any longer?&nbsp; Is it his view that it is, in fact, motivated by politics in all matters or just the Dobbs decision?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll say this: The President respects the institution.&nbsp; He respects the Court.&nbsp; What he doesn&#8217;t &#8212; what he believes was unconstitutional, and spoke to this &#8212; to this this morning &#8212; to this morning and also prior, is their decision.&nbsp; He believes the decision that this Court has made is extreme and it is beyond the pale.&nbsp;<br><br>We are talking about, as you know, you know, a constitutional right that was around for almost 50 years.&nbsp; And so, when you think about that &#8212; when you think about what was done two weeks ago, the President wants to speak very clearly and loudly about what we saw and how this will have an effect, as we know, on women&#8217;s rights and women&#8217;s freedom.&nbsp; And beyond that &#8212; it&#8217;s going to go beyond that when you think about privacy, when you think about contraception, when you think what else that &#8212; what else extreme Republicans &#8212; Republicans that he has called the “Ultra” &#8212; the “Ultra-MAGA” of the Republican wing is planning to do.<br><br>But the reality is: In order to have pro-choice senators, pro-choice House members, we have to make sure that folks have their voices heard at the ballot box.&nbsp; And that is what he&#8217;s going to continue to call on to make sure that they exercise their rights as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it his view that the Court is now a politicized body or not an independent judicial panel?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, he believes that this was done by a war of political power.&nbsp; You heard him say that today, that this decision was not a constitutional decision.&nbsp; It was beyond extreme.&nbsp; It will &#8212; you know, it will hurt people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; It will upend, you know, people&#8217;s &#8212; you know, people&#8217;s everyday decision on their own body and what they can decide what they &#8212; what they need to take care of their health and how they want to grow their family.&nbsp; And so that is incredibly important as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, this decision was incredibly extreme.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to &#8212; he’s called that out.&nbsp; He&#8217;s talked about that very emphatically, as you heard him today.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but we have to also do our part.&nbsp; We have to do everything that we can to codify Roe into law.&nbsp; And the only way to do that is to make sure that Congress acts.<br><br>I’m going to &#8212; go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Governor Abbott in Texas issued an executive order today calling on the National Guard and officials there to apprehend undocumented immigrants.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m wondering if the administration is planning any legal response, and if you&#8217;ll prohibit the National Guard from participating?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: The immigration enforcement is a federal authority, and states should not be mandating it &#8212; meddling in it.&nbsp; That is just &#8212; especially governor of Te- &#8212; the Texas governor, Abbott, who has a track record of causing chaos and confusion at the border.&nbsp;<br><br>So I would refer you to DOJ on any legal matter.&nbsp; But again, this is an &#8212; immigration enfortment [sic] &#8212; enforcement is a federal authority.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; TPS for Venezuelans is up for renewal next week.&nbsp; Do you have any sense of how the President is planning to proceed there?&nbsp; And if he&#8217;s not going to renew it, what has &#8212; what the circumstances have changed?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President&#8217;s decision on TPS.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything for you at this time to preview.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one last one.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve discussed multiple times that the only way to, sort of, restore Roe is through legislative action and electing more Democrats, which I think is undeniably true based on the, sort of, math.&nbsp;<br><br>But in the period, you know, before the ruling was issued, there was an effort by some Republican senators to pass a sort of scaled-down bill.&nbsp; We heard the President today talk passionately about a case &#8212; a reported case of a rape survivor that had to go across state lines.&nbsp;<br><br>Is the administration at all interested in engaging with Republicans on a smaller (inaudible) bill that might protect rape victims’, incest victims’ right &#8212; you know, health of the mother &#8212; less than Roe &#8212; undeniably less than, you know, you and abortion activists want, but more than exists after the ruling?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything to share right now about what we would do that&#8217;s less than Roe.&nbsp; The President&#8217;s priority right now is to make sure we codify Roe. And that is what is going to bring back the rights of women and the freedoms that women have.&nbsp;<br><br>And, you know, we have to take what the Court did very seriously, even what&nbsp;<s>Judge</s>&nbsp;[Justice] Thomas said about privacy and contraception and marriage.&nbsp; That is something that we have to be &#8212; should be ready for.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the President laid out what he has in the past two week &#8212; two weeks &#8212; whether it is the two executive authorities that he took on the day that the decision was made on Dobbs, which is making sure that the FDA provided approved medication to its full extent, because that is so incredibly important for women who are looking to have abortion; and also making sure that women who decide to travel across states have the protection; and everything else that he talked about today &#8212; the privacy component, protecting clinics.<br><br>And so that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to continue to do.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to see what other legal authorities that he haves &#8212; he has to move forward and protect &#8212; to protect those rights.&nbsp;<br><br>But the way that we truly get back those freedoms, that constitutional right that people &#8212; the American public had for almost 50 years is we have to codify Roe into law.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President mentioned that he&#8217;s going to stop by the Japanese embassy today to sign a condolence book.&nbsp; Anything else you can share about how the administration is going to respond to this assassination?&nbsp; Any consideration of the President or Vice President traveling for the funeral?&nbsp; Anything like that at this point in time?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything to share on the funeral travel.&nbsp; I believe &#8212; I believe that they haven&#8217;t set a date yet for the former prime minister.&nbsp; The President mentioned that he tried to give a call to the Prime Minister of &#8212; Kishida, the current Prime Minister, obviously, to offer up his condolences.&nbsp;<br><br>You all saw the President&#8217;s statement from this morning, where he is deeply saddened and outraged that his friend and former Prime Minister Abe was shot and killed.&nbsp; We send our deepest condolences to former prime minister and his family and all those who loved him.&nbsp; The President and the American pu- &#8212; the American people stand with the people of Japan in their time of mourning.&nbsp; We have unwavering confidence in the strength of Japanese democracy and firmly believe that the former Prime Minister&#8217;s legacy will live on.<br><br>For &#8212; as far as travel or funeral arrangements, I believe those have not been set, and I just don&#8217;t have anything to share at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One follow-up on that question, Karine.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; You can follow up.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would the administration be open to the possibility of including President Trump as part of the presidential delegation that goes to the funeral?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, as far as I know, a funeral date has not been scheduled.&nbsp; I would &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They&#8217;re doing this July 12, so that would be the same day that the President is traveling.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; again, I don&#8217;t have anything to share with you on his travel at this time.&nbsp; But I would refer you to President Trump on his own plans.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to that from here.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; You’ve talked a little bit about privacy today.&nbsp; Does the President think it&#8217;s appropriate for abortion rights protesters to intimidate Supreme Court justices when they&#8217;re out to eat, like Brett Kavanaugh, who had to sneak out of a steakhouse last night?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We have been pretty clear on this, the President has been very clear, that we condemn any intimidation of judges in this specific question here.&nbsp; We have condemned that.&nbsp; We have signed &#8212; he has assigned a piece of legislation making sure that they have the protection that they need.&nbsp; And so we &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you never said, “Don’t go to their houses.”&nbsp; So as long as they&#8217;re peaceful, would you say, “Don&#8217;t go to a restaurant that a Supreme Court justice is at”?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is we condemn any intimidation when it comes to judges.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been &#8212; the President has talked about this, and we have put out statements in his name and many, many times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there are circumstances that it’s okay if protesters know that if a justice is out to eat at a restaurant, that pro- &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that they can go and protest as long as they are what you consider peaceful?&nbsp; That&#8217;s okay?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we have said that we want to see peaceful protests.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we have said.&nbsp; We want to see the pe- &#8212; the protests be peaceful.&nbsp; But when it comes to intimidation, that is something that we have condemned.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So where&#8217;s the line?&nbsp; If these protesters can go to a justice’s house and they can go to a restaurant, where is it that you don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s appropriate for a group of protesters to go?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Where is &#8212; I just laid out.&nbsp; You asked me about intimidation.&nbsp; We condemn intimidation.&nbsp; We condemn any violence.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been very clear that is &#8212; it is like clear &#8212; it is a clear definition of what violence is and what intimidation is.&nbsp; Peaceful protest &#8212; people should be allowed to be &#8212; to be able to do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In a restaurant?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; If it&#8217;s outside of a restaurant, if it&#8217;s peaceful, for sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Really?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Peaceful protest.&nbsp; Where is &#8212; you were &#8212; your first question to me was “intimidation” &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So these justices &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; and violence.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; because protesters do not agree with an opinion that they signed on to, have no right to privacy, is what you&#8217;re saying?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But, Peter, this is &#8212; this is &#8212; people have the right &#8212; this is what a democracy is.&nbsp; People have the right &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do people have a right to privacy?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Of course, people have a right to privacy, but people also have a right to be able to protest peacefully.&nbsp; Peacefully.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that safe?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It&#8217;s the intimidation and the violence that we condemn.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is &#8212; is that safe?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Peter &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Isn’t that creating a potential really bad situation when there are people &#8212; even if they&#8217;re being peaceful at the time, they&#8217;re angry.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why they would be there, right?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Peter, we have condemned any intimidation and violence.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you just said it’s okay if they go to a restaurant.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I said peaceful protest should be allowed.&nbsp; We do &#8212; we do commen- &#8212; condemn intimidation &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s not &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; and we condemn any violence at any &#8212; whatever &#8212; every ty- &#8212; whatever type of violence.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been very clear on that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So President Biden &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And the President has signed &#8212; the President has signed legislation that was passed bipart- &#8212; in a bipartisan way in Congress to make sure that the judges have the protection that they need.&nbsp; We &#8212; this administration &#8212; has provided U.S. Marshals, through the DOJ, to make sure that these judges are protected.&nbsp; So we have shown how we want to make sure that intimidation and violence is not the way to go.&nbsp; It is not the way to have a political discourse.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m done here, Peter.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Mexican President will be here next week.&nbsp; I want to get from you what President Biden expects out of that.&nbsp; And secondly, if you can respond to the criticism from the Mexican President over the spying charges against Julian Assange.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll speak to the &#8212; to the AMLO meeting &#8212; is what you&#8217;re speaking to.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, the President and the First Lady look forward to welcoming the President of Mexico and the First Lady here to Washington next week.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be a bilateral visit, as we&#8217;ve spoken about before.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ll have an opportunity to carry &#8212; to work on the summit &#8212; to carry out the work of the Summit of the Americas forward.&nbsp; That was the summit that happened in Los Angeles not too long ago, just a few short weeks ago.<br><br>They will discuss a broad and deep agenda, including joint efforts on migration, food security, and economic opportunity.&nbsp; And so the President looks forward to having that conversation, and he&#8217;s going to welcome them next week.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you &#8212; could you address that second part?&nbsp; The president made some very critical comments about tearing down the Statue of Liberty, you know, if the U.S. proceeds with that &#8212; he&#8217;s offered asylum there.&nbsp; Which &#8212; what&#8217;s the administration&#8217;s response?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we see &#8212; we see AMLO, the President of Mexico, as a partner.&nbsp; We are &#8212; they are welcomed here next week.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have a bilateral meeting.&nbsp; There will be many conversations that will be had.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to leave it as that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just follow up on one last question?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah, sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s been reported that the President is considering giving a speech after the January 6th hearings are completed.&nbsp; Can you &#8212; can you discuss that with us?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the &#8212; what would be the intent of that?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I cannot confirm a speech that the President &#8212; the President may or may not be having.&nbsp; That is not &#8212; right now we are letting the January 6th Committee hearing go and do their &#8212; do their jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has &#8212; as he has said many times and we have said many times, thinks it&#8217;s &#8212; their work is important.&nbsp; Is it a &#8212; it is an independent process that they are &#8212; a bipartisan, independent process that they&#8217;re running.&nbsp;<br><br>And we believe &#8212; as the hearings are going on, we believe it&#8217;s important for the American people to see exactly what happened on that day.&nbsp; January 6th was a dark day for our democracy.&nbsp; It was an attack on our law enforcement.&nbsp; And so we wanted &#8212; we want to respect their process, and we&#8217;re just not going to comment on that while it&#8217;s going on.&nbsp;<br><br>I do not have a speech to confirm for you at this time.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The White House has taken credit for the recent drop in gas prices.&nbsp; Do you believe that the administration&#8217;s moves are more responsible for that drop than, say, changing consumer behavior and the fact that some recession jitters also seem to be pushing oil prices under $100 a barrel?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you heard from the President today, he &#8212; we saw the gas prices go down for 25 consecutive days and about 25 cents.&nbsp;<br><br>While we understand that that is not enough, and we understand that people are still going through a lot &#8212; a lot of pain and with the &#8212; with the cost of gas prices &#8212; we know what it means for families.&nbsp;<br><br>But we do believe that the President has really taken this on these last several months: when it comes to Strategic Petroleum Reserve and that historic 1 million barrels a day; when it comes to the homegrown biofuels, the ethanol 15, that the President has called on.&nbsp; Remember that is only available in the wintertime; we made that available during the summer.&nbsp; And all of those &#8212; all of the work that the President has done has helped to blunt the price increase.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, remember this price increase is due to Putin&#8217;s &#8212; Putin&#8217;s tax hikes, Putin&#8217;s war &#8212; a brutal war on Ukraine.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we have seen the increase of gas prices.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have seen the increase &#8212; food.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, the President is going to continue to do the work.&nbsp; We know we need to do more.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he asked for the gas tax holiday, which we &#8212; is something that we&#8217;re calling on Congress to do, something that&#8217;s very, very easy to do that&#8217;s going to give some &#8212; a little bit more relief to the American public.&nbsp;<br><br>But, again, we are happy to see the decrease of gas prices.&nbsp; But we know we need to do more.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hold on, I &#8212; go ahead, Phil.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t seen you in a while.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; The President shared that tragic story, moments ago, about the 10-year-old girl who had to travel across state lines to receive an abortion.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering, has the White House confirmed that local law enforcement knows the identity of this 10-year-old victim?&nbsp; And has the President directed the DOJ to do everything it can to prosecute the abuser and protect her?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: Anything to do with the DOJ that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a legal component, I would refer you to DO- &#8212; to DOJ.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have more to share on the identity of this young woman or the question that you just asked me.&nbsp;<br><br>The President spoke to that &#8212; a young woman &#8212; just to show how extreme the decision on &#8212; the Dobbs decision was and just how extreme it is now for American public, the American families when there is no exception at all.&nbsp; When you have such a young girl who has to carry out the child of a rapist, that is unacceptable.&nbsp; You heard that from him directly.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is why he is calling for action.&nbsp; This is why he&#8217;s trying to do everything that he can from his legal authority that he has.&nbsp; And so, he&#8217;s going to continue to do that work.&nbsp;<br><br>But again, it is &#8212; we have to make sure Congress acts.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; But is he taking any steps to protect her?&nbsp; Or does he expect that, you know, law enforcement will?&nbsp; I know he cited her in the speech, and I know that he wants some of these larger reforms, he wants Congress to act.&nbsp; But, I mean, this little one certainly seems to be (inaudible).<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think what the President is calling on and what he has laid out is to protect girls and women like her and beyond &#8212; right? &#8212; who do not have the rights and the freedom.&nbsp; That is why he&#8217;s calling for the action that I just laid out for Congress.&nbsp;<br><br>That is why he is using his legal authority and making &#8212; and made an announcement on the executive authority &#8212; the executive action today.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, he&#8217;s going to continue to do that work.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to do everything that he can to protect young people who are like this young girl.<br><br>But at the same time, he&#8217;s going to call it out and use his bully pulpit to make it clear of what is happening out there is unacceptable.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a very, very quick follow-up.&nbsp; I asked on Tuesday about the releases from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; Were there any conversations before that release about making certain that that oil &#8212; the million barrels a day &#8212; stayed domestic?&nbsp; I mean, was the administration aware that, you know, some of that oil could end up going overseas?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So when it comes to the oil, it is something that oil companies decide what &#8212; you know, we cannot control what oil companies do with their oil.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I would ask &#8212; you should ask the oil companies about where they are sending the oil they purchase and why.&nbsp; That is not something that we can answer from here.&nbsp;<br><br>The Department of Energy can&#8217;t dictate what oil companies do with the oil they purchase or where they ship it to sell.&nbsp; That is something, again, that the oil company decides on.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, I would refer you to Department of Energy on that question.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; We got to go.&nbsp; Okay, go ahead, Phil.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just real quick.&nbsp; The President has been so sharp in his denunciations of this Court &#8212; of this Court&#8217;s majority &#8212; a majority that &#8212; nobody is going anywhere anytime soon.&nbsp; If he&#8217;s so sharply opposed to what they&#8217;ve done, why doesn’t he support any changes to this Court or this Court&#8217;s majority?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, because the President believes the best way to use our political capital is to make sure that we do everything that we can to get Congress to act; to make sure that we do everything we can to get pro-choice Democrats in the Senate, pro-choice Democrats in the House; to really codify Roe into law.&nbsp; That is the fastest way, the best way that we can get this done.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he&#8217;s calling on the American people to go to the ballot box and get their voices heard.&nbsp; And that is the best way that we can get that done.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; Simon, I owe &#8212; I owe you a question.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; The former President of Angola, Eduardo dos Santos, died today at the age of 79.&nbsp; Does the President have any reaction or any plans to call President João Lourenço?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any calls to preview at this time.&nbsp; Clearly, it is sad to hear that news.&nbsp; And, you know, our sympathies and condolences go out to the family.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have a call to preview at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The second question: I know in the past few weeks you&#8217;ve had questions on abortion, on inflation &#8212; everything that goes wrong with the President.&nbsp; Is there anything &#8212; or can you list a few things that are going right for this President at this moment?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I would point you to the jobs numbers today.&nbsp; We saw 375,000 jobs in this pa- &#8212; in the past month.&nbsp; While we understand what the American public is going through at this time, that is a good sign.&nbsp; That is a good sign for the economy.&nbsp;<br><br>And we also saw that unemployment rate is &#8212; it remains at 3.6.&nbsp;<br><br>And in &#8212; also, in those numbers, we saw that we are &#8212; we have created &#8212; we are back to the pre-pandemic job numbers when it comes to the private sector, which is incredibly important.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve added jobs.&nbsp; We saw 1 million jobs added in this past quarter.&nbsp;<br><br>All of those things are very important as we talk about moving this historic economic recovery into tran- &#8212; into a transition so that we can really truly deal with inflation.<br><br>And so I think these numbers &#8212; and you heard the President talk about that.&nbsp; He listed all of the &#8212; all of the items that I just listed in &#8212; at the top of his speech.&nbsp;<br><br>And one more thing that someone just asked me as well is: We saw gas prices drop by 25 cents this past two weeks.&nbsp; That is also important.<br><br>We understand there&#8217;s more work to be done.&nbsp; But a lot of that that we are seeing is because of the work that this President has done.&nbsp; When you look at the jobs number &#8212; is because of this &#8212; the work that this President has done.&nbsp; When you think about the American Rescue Plan, how it turned the economy back on &#8212; all of those things are incredibly important.<br><br>But again, we have more work to do, and we will continue to do that work on behalf of the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, guys.<br><br>1:47 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/08/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 21:31:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57019</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section&nbsp;506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $400&nbsp;million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
