<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 13:33:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Executive Order on Promoting Competition in the American Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The economy is booming under President Biden’s leadership. The economy has gained more than three million jobs since the President took office—the most jobs created in the first five months of any presidency in modern history. Today, the President is building on this economic momentum by signing an Executive Order to promote competition in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The economy is booming under President Biden’s leadership. The economy has gained more than three million jobs since the President took office—the most jobs created in the first five months of any presidency in modern history. Today, the President is building on this economic momentum by signing an Executive Order to promote competition in the American economy, which will lower prices for families, increase wages for workers, and promote innovation and even faster economic growth.</p>



<p>For decades, corporate consolidation has been accelerating. In&nbsp;<a href="https://poseidon01.ssrn.com/delivery.php?ID=409065022090123092012067078086115107100012095020070029025083079086096073094098075085122016002103042099002113082005024090123021051037093012023080067090015110022015049069087098078117019024125021127031003020126124121120123113125029089025105027005103097&amp;EXT=pdf&amp;INDEX=TRUE">over 75%</a>&nbsp;of U.S. industries, a smaller number of large companies now control more of the business than they did twenty years ago. This is true across healthcare, financial services, agriculture and more.</p>



<p>That lack of competition drives up prices for consumers. As fewer large players have controlled more of the market, mark-ups (charges over cost)&nbsp;<a href="https://www.janeeckhout.com/wp-content/uploads/RMP.pdf">have tripled</a>. &nbsp;Families are paying higher prices for necessities—things like prescription drugs, hearing aids, and internet service.</p>



<p>Barriers to competition are also driving down wages for workers. When there are only a few employers in town, workers have less opportunity to bargain for a higher wage and to demand dignity and respect in the workplace. In fact, research shows that industry consolidation is decreasing advertised wages by&nbsp;<a href="http://jhr.uwpress.org/content/early/2020/05/04/jhr.monopsony.1218-9914R1.full.pdf+html">as much as 17%</a>.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/noncompete-agreements/">Tens of millions</a>&nbsp;of Americans—including those working in construction and retail—are required to sign non-compete agreements as a condition of getting a job, which makes it harder for them to switch to better-paying options.<br><br>In total, higher prices and lower wages caused by lack of competition are now estimated to cost the median American household&nbsp;<a href="https://www.economicliberties.us/our-work/confronting-americas-concentration-crisis-a-ledger-of-harms-and-framework-for-advancing-economic-liberty-for-all/">$5,000 per year</a>.</p>



<p>Inadequate competition holds back economic growth and innovation. The rate of&nbsp;<a href="https://eig.org/dynamism">new business formation</a>&nbsp;has fallen by almost 50% since the 1970s as large businesses make it harder for Americans with good ideas to break into markets. There are&nbsp;<a href="https://ilsr.org/wp-content/uploads/downloads/2016/08/MonopolyPower-SmallBusiness.pdf">fewer opportunities</a>&nbsp;for existing small and independent businesses to access markets and earn a fair return. &nbsp;Economists find that as competition declines,&nbsp;<a href="https://one.oecd.org/document/DAF/COMP/WD(2018)67/en/pdf">productivity growth</a>&nbsp;slows,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w23583/w23583.pdf">business investment and innovation decline</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://research.chicagobooth.edu/~/media/5872FBEB104245909B8F0AE8A84486C9.pdf">income</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.oecd.org/daf/competition/Inequality-hidden-cost-market-power-2017.pdf">wealth</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://rooseveltinstitute.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/RI_Racial-Rules-of-Corporate-Power_Issue-brief_201911-1.pdf">racial inequality</a>&nbsp;widen.</p>



<p>When past presidents faced similar threats from growing corporate power, they took bold action. In the early 1900s, Teddy Roosevelt’s Administration broke up the trusts controlling the economy—Standard Oil, J.P. Morgan’s railroads, and others—giving the little guy a fighting chance. In the late 1930s, FDR’s Administration supercharged antitrust enforcement, increasing more than eightfold the number of cases brought in just two years—enforcement actions that saved consumers&nbsp;<a href="https://lawecommons.luc.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?referer=&amp;httpsredir=1&amp;article=1494&amp;context=facpubs">billions</a>&nbsp;in today’s dollars and helped unleash decades of sustained, inclusive economic growth.</p>



<p>Today President Biden is taking decisive action to reduce the trend of corporate consolidation, increase competition, and deliver concrete benefits to America’s consumers, workers, farmers, and small businesses.&nbsp;<strong>Today’s historic Executive Order established a whole-of-government effort to promote competition in the American economy.&nbsp;</strong>The Order<strong>&nbsp;includes 72 initiatives by more than a dozen federal agencies to promptly tackle some of the most pressing competition problems across our economy.&nbsp;</strong>Once implemented, these initiatives will result in concrete improvements to people’s lives.</p>



<p>Among other things, they will:</p>



<ul><li>Make it easier to change jobs and help raise wages by banning or limiting non-compete agreements and unnecessary, cumbersome occupational licensing requirements that impede economic mobility.</li><li>Lower prescription drug prices by supporting state and tribal programs that will import safe and cheaper drugs from Canada.</li><li>Save Americans with hearing loss thousands of dollars by allowing hearing aids to be sold over the counter at drug stores.</li><li>Save Americans money on their internet bills by banning excessive early termination fees, requiring clear disclosure of plan costs to facilitate comparison shopping, and ending landlord exclusivity arrangements that stick tenants with only a single internet option.</li><li>Make it easier for people to get refunds from airlines and to comparison shop for flights by requiring clear upfront disclosure of add-on fees.</li><li>Make it easier and cheaper to repair items you own by limiting manufacturers from barring self-repairs or third-party repairs of their products.</li><li>Make it easier and cheaper to switch banks by requiring banks to allow customers to take their financial transaction data with them to a competitor.</li><li>Empower family farmers and increase their incomes by strengthening the Department of Agriculture’s tools to stop the abusive practices of some meat processors.</li><li>Increase opportunities for small businesses by directing all federal agencies to promote greater competition through their procurement and spending decisions.</li></ul>



<p><strong>The Order also encourages the leading antitrust agencies to focus enforcement efforts on problems in key markets and coordinates other agencies’ ongoing response to corporate consolidation.&nbsp;</strong>The Order:</p>



<ul><li>Calls on the leading antitrust agencies, the Department of Justice (DOJ) and Federal Trade Commission (FTC), to&nbsp;<strong>enforce the antitrust laws vigorously</strong>&nbsp;and recognizes that the law allows them to&nbsp;<strong>challenge prior bad mergers</strong>&nbsp;that past Administrations did not previously challenge.</li><li>Announces a policy that enforcement should focus in particular on&nbsp;<strong>labor markets, agricultural markets, healthcare markets (which includes prescription drugs, hospital consolidation, and insurance)</strong>,&nbsp;<strong>and the tech sector.</strong></li><li>Establishes a&nbsp;<strong>White House Competition Council, led by the Director of the National Economic Council,&nbsp;</strong>to monitor progress on finalizing the initiatives in the Order and to coordinate the federal government’s response to the rising power of large corporations in the economy.</li></ul>



<p>A more detailed summary of the key actions in the Order is provided below:</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Labor Market</u><span style="text-decoration: underline">s</span></strong></p>



<p>Competition in labor markets empowers workers to demand higher wages and greater dignity and respect in the workplace. One way companies stifle competition is with non-compete clauses. Roughly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/half-of-u-s-businesses-ask-employees-to-sign-noncompete-agreements-and-half-of-them-are-low-wage-workers/">half</a>&nbsp;of private-sector businesses require at least some employees to enter non-compete agreements, affecting some&nbsp;<a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/noncompete-agreements/">36 to 60 million</a>&nbsp;workers.</p>



<p>Overly burdensome occupational licensing requirements that impede worker mobility and suppress wages also restrict competition. Today, almost <a href="https://www.ftc.gov/system/files/documents/reports/options-enhance-occupational-license-portability/license_portability_policy_paper_0.pdf">30%</a> of jobs in the United States require a license, up from less than 5% in the 1950s. <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/Portals/1/Documents/employ/Occu-Licensing-2nd-Edition_v02_web.pdf">Fewer than 5%</a> of occupations that require licensing in at least one state are treated consistently across all 50 states. That locks some people out of jobs, and it makes it harder for people to move between states—particularly burdening military spouses, <a href="https://download.militaryonesource.mil/12038/MOS/Reports/military-spouse-licensure-report-2019.pdf">34%</a> of whom work in a field requiring a license and are subject to military-directed moves every few years.</p>



<p>Workers may also be harmed by existing&nbsp;<a href="https://www.justice.gov/atr/file/903511/download">guidance</a>&nbsp;provided by the Department of Justice and Federal Trade Commission to Human Resource personnel that&nbsp;<a href="https://www.booker.senate.gov/news/press/booker-warren-question-doj-ftc-on-policy-allowing-employers-to-share-compensation-data">allows</a>&nbsp;third parties to make wage data available to employers—and not to workers—in certain circumstances without triggering antitrust scrutiny. This may be used to collaborate to suppress wages and benefits.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the FTC to&nbsp;<strong>ban or limit non-compete agreements</strong>.</li><li>Encourages the FTC to&nbsp;<strong>ban unnecessary occupational licensing restrictions that impede economic mobility</strong>.</li><li>Encourages the FTC and DOJ to strengthen antitrust guidance to&nbsp;<strong>prevent employers from collaborating to suppress wages</strong>&nbsp;<strong>or reduce benefits&nbsp;</strong>by sharing wage and benefit information with one another.</li></ul>



<p>These actions complement the President’s call for Congress to pass the Protecting the Right to Organize (PRO) Act to ensure workers have a free and fair choice to join a union and to collectively bargain. Unions are critical to empowering workers to bargain with their employers for better jobs and to creating an economy that works for everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Healthcare</u></strong></p>



<p>The proposed Order tackles&nbsp;four&nbsp;areas where lack of competition in healthcare increases prices and reduces access to quality care.</p>



<p><strong><em><u>Prescription Drugs</u></em>:</strong> Americans pay more than <a href="https://www.rand.org/news/press/2021/01/28.html">2.5 times </a>as much for the same prescription drugs as peer countries, and <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/pdf-report/Comparing-Insulin-Prices">sometimes much more</a>. Price increases continue to <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/democracy/reports/2019/08/30/473911/big-pharma-reaps-profits-hurting-everyday-americans/">far surpass inflation</a>. As a result, nearly one in four Americans report difficulties paying for medication, and nearly one in three Americans <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/press-release/poll-nearly-1-in-4-americans-taking-prescription-drugs-say-its-difficult-to-afford-medicines-including-larger-shares-with-low-incomes/">report</a> not taking their medications as prescribed. </p>



<p>These high prices are in part the result of lack of competition among drug manufacturers. The largest pharmaceutical companies are able to wield their market power to reap average annual profits of&nbsp;<a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-18-40.pdf">15-20%,</a>&nbsp;as compared to average annual profits of 4-9% for the largest non-drug companies.</p>



<p>One strategy that drug manufacturers have used to avoid competing is “pay for delay” agreements, in which brand-name drug manufacturers pay generic manufacturers to stay out of the market. That has raised drug prices&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/media-resources/mergers-competition/pay-delay">by $3.5 billion per year</a>, and&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28964/w28964.pdf?utm_campaign=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_medium=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_source=PANTHEON_STRIPPED">research also shows</a>&nbsp;that “pay for delay” and similar deals between generic and brand name manufacturers reduce innovation—reducing new drug trials and R&amp;D expenditures.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs the Food and Drug Administration to&nbsp;<strong>work with states and tribes to safely import&nbsp;prescription drugs from Canada</strong>, pursuant to the Medicare Modernization Act of 2003.</li><li>Directs the Health and Human Services Administration (HHS) to increase&nbsp;<strong>support for generic and biosimilar drugs</strong>, which provide low-cost options for patients.</li><li>Directs HHS to issue&nbsp;<strong>a comprehensive plan within 45 days to combat high prescription drug prices and price gouging</strong>.&nbsp;</li><li>Encourages the FTC to&nbsp;<strong>ban “</strong><a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28964/w28964.pdf?utm_campaign=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_medium=PANTHEON_STRIPPED&amp;amp%3Butm_source=PANTHEON_STRIPPED"><strong>pay for delay</strong></a><strong>” and similar agreements by rule.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Hearing Aids</u></em>:</strong> Hearing aids are so expensive that only <a href="https://hearinghealthfoundation.org/blogs/why-so-many-cant-afford-to-hear-better">14%</a> of the approximately <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nceh/hearing_loss/public_health_scientific_info.html">48 million Americans </a>with hearing loss use them. On average, they cost more than <a href="https://www.consumerreports.org/hearing-aids/best-and-worst-hearing-aid-brands-and-retailers/">$5,000 </a>per pair, and those costs are often not covered by health insurance. A major driver of the expense is that consumers must get them from a doctor or a specialist, even though <a href="https://www.nap.edu/download/23446">experts agree</a> that medical evaluation is not necessary. Rather, this requirement serves only as red tape and a barrier to more companies selling hearing aids. The four largest hearing aid manufacturers now control <a href="http://concentrationcrisis.openmarketsinstitute.org/industry/hearing-aid-manufacturing/">84%</a> of the market. <br>In 2017, Congress passed a bipartisan proposal to allow hearing aids to be sold over the counter. However, the Trump Administration Food and Drug Administration failed to issue the necessary rules that would actually allow hearing aids to be sold over the counter, leaving millions of Americans without low-cost options.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs&nbsp;HHS&nbsp;to consider issuing&nbsp;<strong>proposed rules within 120 days for&nbsp;allowing hearing aids to be sold over the counter.</strong>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Hospitals</u></em>:</strong> Hospital consolidation has left many areas, <a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-21-93">especially rural communities</a>, without good options for convenient and affordable healthcare service. Thanks to unchecked mergers, the ten largest healthcare systems now control a <a href="https://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/insights/industry/health-care/hospital-mergers-acquisition-trends.html">quarter</a> of the market. Since 2010, <a href="https://www.shepscenter.unc.edu/programs-projects/rural-health/rural-hospital-closures/">139</a> rural hospitals have shuttered, including a high of 19 last year, in the middle of a healthcare crisis. Research shows that hospitals in consolidated markets charge <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/issue-brief/what-we-know-about-provider-consolidation/">far higher prices</a> than hospitals in markets with several competitors.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Underscores that hospital mergers can be harmful</strong> to patients and encourages the Justice Department and FTC to review and revise their merger guidelines to ensure patients are not harmed by such mergers.</li><li>Directs HHS to <strong>support existing hospital price transparency rules and to finish implementing bipartisan federal legislation to address surprise hospital billing</strong>.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Health Insurance</u></em>:</strong> Consolidation in the health insurance industry has meant that many consumers have <a href="https://www.kff.org/private-insurance/issue-brief/insurer-participation-on-the-aca-marketplaces-2014-2021/">little choice</a> when it comes to selecting insurers. And even when there is some choice, comparison shopping is hard because plans offered on the exchanges are complicated—with different services covered or different deductibles.<br><br><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs HHS to&nbsp;<strong>standardize plan options in the National Health Insurance Marketplace so people can comparison shop</strong>&nbsp;more easily.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Transportation</u></strong></p>



<p>In the transportation sector, multiple industries are now dominated by large corporations—air travel, rail, and shipping.</p>



<p><strong>Airlines:&nbsp;</strong>The top four commercial airlines control nearly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/250577/domestic-market-share-of-leading-us-airlines/">two-thirds</a>&nbsp;of the domestic market. Reduced competition contributes to increasing fees like baggage and cancellation fees. These fees are often&nbsp;<a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/american-delta-united-all-raise-checked-baggage-fees-2018-9">raised in lockstep</a>, demonstrating a lack of meaningful competitive pressure, and are&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/travel/which-airlines-have-the-best-and-worst-fees">often hidden</a>&nbsp;from consumers at the point of purchase. The top ten airlines collected&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aviationpros.com/airlines/press-release/21115541/with-travel-season-ahead-senator-markey-and-reps-cohen-and-garcia-reintroduce-legislation-to-stop-rising-airline-fees">$35.2 billion</a>&nbsp;in ancillary fees in 2018, up from just $1.2 billion in 2007. Inadequate competition also reduces incentives to provide good service. For example, the Department of Transportation (DOT) estimates that airlines were late delivering&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/sites/dot.gov/files/2020-02/February%202020%20ATCR.pdf">at least</a>&nbsp;2.3 million checked bags in 2019.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs the DOT to consider issuing<strong> clear rules requiring the refund of fees when baggage is delayed or when service isn’t actually provided</strong>—like when the plane’s WiFi or in-flight entertainment system is broken.</li><li>Directs the DOT to consider issuing <strong>rules that require baggage, change, and cancellation fees to be clearly disclosed</strong> to the customer.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Rail</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;In 1980, there were&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ams.usda.gov/sites/default/files/media/Railroad%20Concentration%2C%20Market%20Shares%2C%20and%20Rates.pdf">33 “Class I” freight railroads</a>, compared to just seven today, and four major rail companies now dominate their respective geographic regions. Freight railroads that own the tracks can privilege their own freight traffic—making it harder for passenger trains to have on-time service—and can overcharge other companies’ freight cars.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the Surface Transportation Board to&nbsp;<strong>require railroad track owners to provide rights of way to passenger rail&nbsp;</strong>and to strengthen their obligations to&nbsp;<strong>treat other freight companies fairly</strong>.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Shipping</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;In maritime shipping, the global marketplace has rapidly consolidated. In 2000, the largest 10 shipping companies controlled&nbsp;<a href="https://www.joc.com/maritime-news/container-lines/new-oligopoly-container-shipping_20190704.html">12%</a>&nbsp;of the market. Today, it is more than 80%, leaving domestic manufacturers who need to export goods at these large foreign companies’ mercy. This has let powerful container shippers charge exporters exorbitant fees for time their freight was sitting waiting to be loaded or unloaded. These fees, called “detention and demurrage charges,” can add up to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.joc.com/regulation-policy/us-detention-demurrage-probes-initial-focus-carriers-terminals_20180402.html">hundreds of thousands</a>&nbsp;of dollars.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the Federal Maritime Commission to&nbsp;<strong>ensure vigorous enforcement against shippers charging American exporters exorbitant charges</strong>.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Agriculture</span></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Over the past few decades, key agricultural markets have become more concentrated and less competitive. The markets for seeds, equipment, feed, and fertilizer are now dominated by just a few large companies, meaning family farmers and ranchers now have to pay more for these <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/economy/reports/2019/05/07/469385/fair-deal-farmers/">inputs</a>. For example, just <a href="https://civileats.com/2019/01/11/the-sobering-details-behind-the-latest-seed-monopoly-chart/">four companies</a> control most of the world’s seeds, and corn seed prices have gone up as much as <a href="https://www.agri-pulse.com/ext/resources/pdfs/m/e/r/p/t/Merger_Paper_Full_manuscript.pdf">30</a>% annually.</p>



<p>Consolidation also limits farmers’ and ranchers’ options for selling their products. That means they get&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/23/business/beef-prices.html">less</a>&nbsp;when they sell their produce and meat—even as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/meat-price-spreads/">prices rise</a>&nbsp;at the grocery store. For example,&nbsp;four large meat-packing companies dominate over&nbsp;<a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/economy/reports/2019/05/07/469385/fair-deal-farmers/">80</a>% of the beef market and, over the last five years, farmers’ share of the price of beef has dropped by more than a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/meat-price-spreads/">quarter</a>—from 51.5% to 37.3%—while the price of beef has risen.</p>



<p>Overall, farmers’ and ranchers’ share of each dollar spent on food has been <a href="https://data.ers.usda.gov/reports.aspx?ID=17885&amp;reportPath=/FoodDollar/Real">declining </a>for decades. In short, family farmers and ranchers are getting less, consumers are paying more, and the big conglomerates in the middle are taking the difference.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the law designed to combat these abuses—the Packers and Stockyards Act—was systematically weakened by the Trump Administration Department of Agriculture (USDA).</p>



<p>American farmers and ranchers are also getting squeezed by foreign corporations importing meat from overseas with labels that mislead customers about its origin. Under current labeling rules, meat can be labeled “Product of USA” if it is only processed here—including when meat is raised overseas and then merely processed into cuts of meat here. For example,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2019-05-23/most-grass-fed-beef-labeled-product-of-u-s-a-is-imported">most grass-fed beef labeled “Product of USA”</a>&nbsp;is actually imported. That makes it hard or impossible for consumers to know where their food comes from and to choose to support American farmers and ranchers.</p>



<p>Corporate consolidation even affects farmers’ ability to repair their own equipment or to use independent repair shops. Powerful equipment manufacturers—such as tractor manufacturers—use proprietary repair tools, software, and diagnostics to prevent third-parties from performing repairs. For example, when certain tractors detect a failure, they cease to operate until a dealer unlocks them. That forcers farmers to pay dealer rates for repairs that they could have made themselves, or that an independent repair shop could have done more cheaply.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Directs USDA to consider issuing <strong>new rules under the Packers and Stockyards Act making it easier for farmers to bring and win claims, stopping chicken processors from exploiting and underpaying chicken farmers, and adopting anti-retaliation protections</strong> for farmers who speak out about bad practices.</li><li>Directs USDA to consider issuing <strong>new rules defining when meat can bear “Product of USA” labels, so that consumers have accurate, transparent labels that enable them to choose products made here.</strong></li><li>Directs USDA to develop a plan to <strong>increase opportunities for farmers to access markets and receive a fair return, including supporting alternative food distribution systems like farmers markets and developing standards and labels</strong> so that consumers can choose to buy products that treat farmers fairly.</li><li>Encourages the FTC to <strong>limit powerful equipment manufacturers from restricting people’s ability to use independent repair shops or do DIY repairs—such as when tractor companies block farmers from repairing their own tractors</strong>.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Internet Service</u></strong></p>



<p>The Order tackles four issues that limit competition, raise prices, and reduce choices for internet service.</p>



<p><strong><em><u>Lack of competition among broadband providers</u></em>: </strong>More than<a href="https://broadbandmap.fcc.gov/#/area-summary?version=jun2020&amp;type=nation&amp;geoid=0&amp;tech=acfw&amp;speed=25_3&amp;vlat=38.09830512359795&amp;vlon=-97.57983008590088&amp;vzoom=2.779496173169071">200 million</a> U.S. residents live in an area with only one or two reliable high-speed internet providers, leading to prices as much as <a href="https://poseidon01.ssrn.com/delivery.php?ID=153105123123122096085069108028083069015084039027010010113122030072017096030080000111022041026045103029042116102105092074116105009011053002088124092068090068124020088055017094105076107024069120007103094103025106024007073088080121124071098084103125111021&amp;EXT=pdf&amp;INDEX=TRUE"><em>five times higher</em></a> in these markets than in markets with more options. A related problem is landlords and internet service providers entering <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/oti/reports/cost-connectivity-2020/us-policy-recommendations/">exclusivity deals or collusive arrangements</a> that leave tenants with only one option. This impacts low-income and marginalized neighborhoods, because landlord-ISP arrangements can effectively block out broadband infrastructure expansion by new providers.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President encourages the FCC to:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Prevent ISPs from making deals with landlords that limit tenants’ choices.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong>Lack of price transparency</strong>: Even where consumers have options, comparison shopping is hard. According to the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), actual prices paid for broadband services can be <a href="https://docs.fcc.gov/public/attachments/DOC-338708A1.pdf">40%</a> higher than advertised. During the Obama-Biden Administration, the FCC began <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/oti/press-releases/oti-applauds-bill-to-create-a-broadband-nutrition-label/">developing</a> a “Broadband Nutrition Label”—a simple label that provides basic information about the internet service offered so people can compare options. The Trump Administration FCC abandoned those plans.<br><strong>In the Order, the President encourages the FCC to:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Revive the “</strong><a href="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6286175/BroadbandLabel.0.jpg"><strong>Broadband Nutrition Label</strong></a><strong>”</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>require providers to report prices and subscription rates</strong>&nbsp;to the FCC.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>High termination fees</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;If a consumer does find a better internet service deal, they may be unable to actually switch because of high early termination fees—on average nearly&nbsp;<a href="https://www.newamerica.org/oti/reports/cost-connectivity-2020/focus-on-the-fees/">$200</a>—charged by internet providers.<br><strong>In the Order, the President encourages the FCC to:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Limit excessive early termination fees.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Companies discriminatorily slowing down internet access</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;Big providers can use their power to discriminatorily block or slow down online services. The Obama-Biden Administration’s FCC adopted “Net Neutrality” rules that required these companies to treat all internet services equally, but this was&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/11/technology/net-neutrality-repeal.html">undone</a>&nbsp;in 2017.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President encourages the FCC to:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Restore Net Neutrality rules</strong>&nbsp;undone by the prior administration.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Technology</u></strong></p>



<p>The Order tackles three areas in which dominant tech firms are undermining competition and reducing innovation:</p>



<p><strong><em><u>Big Tech platforms purchasing would-be competitors</u></em>:</strong>&nbsp;Over the past ten years, the largest tech platforms have acquired hundreds of companies—including alleged “<a href="https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3241707">killer acquisitions</a>” meant to shut down a potential competitive threat. Too often, federal agencies have not blocked, conditioned, or, in some cases, meaningfully examined these acquisitions.<br><br><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Announces an Administration policy of&nbsp;<strong>greater scrutiny of mergers</strong>, especially by dominant internet platforms, with particular attention to the acquisition of nascent competitors, serial mergers, the accumulation of data, competition by “free” products, and the effect on user privacy.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Big Tech platforms gathering too much personal information</u></em></strong><strong>:&nbsp;</strong>Many of the large platforms’ business models have depended on the accumulation of extraordinarily amounts of sensitive personal information and related data.<br><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the FTC to establish&nbsp;<strong>rules on surveillance and the accumulation of data.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Big Tech platforms unfairly competing with small businesses</u></em></strong><strong>:&nbsp;</strong>The large platforms’ power gives them unfair opportunities to get a leg up on the small businesses that rely on them to reach customers. For example, companies that run&nbsp;<a href="https://judiciary.house.gov/uploadedfiles/competition_in_digital_markets.pdf?utm_campaign=4493-519">dominant online retail marketplaces</a>&nbsp;can see how small businesses’ products sell and then use the data to launch their own competing products. Because they run the platform, they can also display their own copycat products more prominently than the small businesses’ products.<br><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the FTC to establish&nbsp;<strong>rules barring unfair methods of competition on internet marketplaces.</strong></li></ul>



<p><strong><em><u>Cell phone manufacturers and others blocking out independent repair shops</u></em></strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp;Tech and other companies impose restrictions on self and third-party repairs, making repairs&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vox.com/the-goods/2019/7/3/18761691/right-to-repair-computers-phones-car-mechanics-apple">more costly and time-consuming</a>, such as by&nbsp;<a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/ypkqxw/do-you-know-anything-about-apples-authorized-service-provider-program">restricting</a>&nbsp;the distribution of parts, diagnostics, and repair tools.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages the FTC to issue&nbsp;<strong>rules against anticompetitive restrictions on using independent repair shops or doing DIY repairs</strong>&nbsp;of your own devices and equipment.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>Banking and Consumer Finance</u></strong></p>



<p>Over the past two decades, the United States has lost 70% of the banks it once had, with around&nbsp;<a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/USNUM">10,000</a>&nbsp;bank closures. Communities of color are disproportionately affected, with&nbsp;<a href="https://ncrc.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/05/NCRC_Branch_Deserts_Research_Memo_050517_2.pdf">25%</a>&nbsp;of all rural closures in majority-minority census tracts. Many of these closures are the&nbsp;<a href="https://pubs.aeaweb.org/doi/pdfplus/10.1257/app.20170543">product</a>&nbsp;of mergers and acquisitions. Though subject to federal review, federal agencies have not formally denied a bank merger application in more than&nbsp;<a href="https://digitalcommons.law.yale.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1557&amp;context=yjreg">15 years</a>.<br><br>Excessive consolidation raises costs for consumers, restricts credit for small businesses, and harms low-income communities. Branch closures can reduce the amount of small business lending by about&nbsp;<a href="http://faculty.haas.berkeley.edu/hqn/nguyen_aej_201901.pdf">10%</a>&nbsp;and leads to&nbsp;<a href="https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/full/10.1111/j.1540-6261.2006.00847.x">higher interest rates</a>. Even where a customer has multiple options, it is hard to switch banks partly because customers cannot easily take their financial transaction history data to a new bank. That increases the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/economy/reports/2021/02/26/496444/switching-responsible-banking/">cost</a>&nbsp;of the new bank extending you credit.</p>



<p><strong>In the Order, the President:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Encourages DOJ and the agencies responsible for banking (the Federal Reserve, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency) to&nbsp;<strong>update guidelines on banking mergers to provide more robust scrutiny</strong>&nbsp;<strong>of mergers</strong>.</li><li>Encourages the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) to issue&nbsp;<strong>rules allowing customers to download their banking data</strong>&nbsp;and take it with them.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting With Leaders from Legacy Black Civil Rights Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/08/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-leaders-from-legacy-black-civil-rights-organizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 01:20:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23491</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden and Vice President Harris met today with leaders from legacy Black civil rights organizations. The group discussed the wave of anti-voter legislation that has recently passed or is pending in state legislatures across the country and the path forward to protect the right to vote. The group also discussed steps the Administration recently&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris met today with leaders from legacy Black civil rights organizations. The group discussed the wave of anti-voter legislation that has recently passed or is pending in state legislatures across the country and the path forward to protect the right to vote. The group also discussed steps the Administration recently announced to address the rise in gun violence and the status of the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act that is currently being negotiated in the Senate. The President and Vice President reiterated that they will continue to push for Congress to pass critical legislation that protects the right to vote and combats subversion of the election process, while continuing to utilize all existing authorities in an all-of-government effort to ensure full voter participation and elections that reflect the will of the people.<br><br>The civil rights leaders provided an update on the work their organizations are doing, both nationally and in the states, to protect the right to vote. They also provided the President and Vice President with their ideas on ways to engage the public on civil rights issues.<br><br>The meeting participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Melanie Campbell, President and CEO of the National Coalition on Black Civic Participation</li><li>Dr. Johnnetta Cole, National Chair and President of the National Council of Negro Women</li><li>Wade Henderson, Interim President of the Leadership Conference on Civil and Human</li><li>Damon Hewitt, President and Executive Director of the Lawyers’ Committee for Civil Rights Under Law</li><li>Sherrilyn Ifill, President and Director-Counsel of the NAACP Legal Defense Fund</li><li>Derrick Johnson, President and CEO of the NAACP (virtual)</li><li>Marc Morial, President and CEO of the National Urban League</li><li>Reverend Al Sharpton, President of the National Action Network</li></ul>



<p>From the White House:</p>



<ul><li>Danielle Conley, Deputy Counsel to the President</li><li>Tina Flournoy, Assistant to the President and Chief of Staff to the Vice President</li><li>Catherine Lhamon, Deputy Assistant to the President for Racial Justice and Equity</li><li>Dana Remus, Assistant to the President and White House Counsel</li><li>Susan Rice, Assistant to the President and Domestic Policy Advisor</li><li>Cedric Richmond, Assistant to the President and Senior Advisor and Director of the Office of Public Engagement</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/08/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-44/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 22:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:05 A.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Today, before I turn to Dr. Walensky, Dr. Fauci, and Dr. Nunez-Smith, I want to start by talking about why our vaccination program is so critical. All along, we have said that by getting fully vaccinated, Americans protect themselves, their loved ones, and their communities.&#160; Already,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:05 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Today, before I turn to Dr. Walensky, Dr. Fauci, and Dr. Nunez-Smith, I want to start by talking about why our vaccination program is so critical.</p>



<p>All along, we have said that by getting fully vaccinated, Americans protect themselves, their loved ones, and their communities.&nbsp; Already, in just over five months, thanks to our whole-of-government effort and the hard work of local leaders in communities across the country, more than 182 Americans &#8212; 182 million Americans have taken action and rolled up their sleeves to get a shot, and nearly 160 million Americans have gotten fully vaccinated.</p>



<p>Just yesterday, we got a powerful reminder about what&#8217;s at stake in our vaccination effort from a new report by experts from the Yale School of Public Health.&nbsp; The study states the vaccination campaign markedly curbed the U.S. pandemic and concludes the pace at which we have vaccinated the country has saved more than 100,000 American lives and prevented up to 450,000 hospitalizations.&nbsp; This is further evidence that our whole-of-government strategy is working and has prevented significant further tragedy and disruption to Americans&#8217; lives and livelihoods.&nbsp;</p>



<p>More than two out of three adults have at least one shot.&nbsp; As a country, we&#8217;re closer than ever to ending this pandemic and getting back to normal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the sad reality is that, despite our progress, we&#8217;re still losing people to this virus &#8212; which is especially tragic given, at this point, it is unnecessary and preventable.&nbsp; Virtually all COVID-19 hospitalizations and deaths in the United States are now occurring among unvaccinated individuals.&nbsp; And to be clear, there will likely continue to be an increase in cases among unvaccinated Americans and in communities with low vaccination rates, particularly given the spread of the more transmissible Delta variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time, we&#8217;ve already fully vaccinated nearly 80 percent of seniors &#8212; those 65 and older and those most at risk.&nbsp; So, despite a potential increase in the number of cases, there will likely be fewer hospitalizations and deaths.&nbsp; The bottom line is there&#8217;s simply no reason that anyone 12 and older should be severely impacted by this virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So our focus is on reaching those who have still not made the choice to protect themselves, their loved ones, and their communities.&nbsp; Over the last six months, we&#8217;ve seen vaccine confidence increase steadily from 34 percent to 68 percent.&nbsp; That is because we&#8217;ve worked hard to get the word out about the safety and efficacy of the vaccines, and because so many Americans have stepped up, gotten their shot, and done their part.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, we know that most people who are not yet vaccinated still have to make up their mind.&nbsp; As such, each person in this phase will take longer to reach, but that makes them no less important.&nbsp; And the spread of the Delta variant, which poses a particular threat to our young people, only strengthens our resolve to reach everyone.</p>



<p>Our job is to keep doing all we can to reach Americans where they are, to answer their questions, and to make it as easy as possible for them to get a shot as soon as they are ready.&nbsp; And our goal is simple: Get more and more Americans fully vaccinated.</p>



<p>As the science makes crystal clear, individuals who are fully vaccinated have a very high degree of protection and those who are not fully vaccinated are not protected.&nbsp; So every individual that we vaccinate is a step forward.&nbsp; And across the summer months, we&#8217;ll vaccinate millions more individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President said, we do this by going community by community, neighborhood by neighborhood, person by person; by partnering with local leaders, governors, mayors, doctors, school administrators, employers, faith leaders, and community organizers &#8212; leaders that people know and trust.&nbsp; One shot at a time.&nbsp; One person at a time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the good news is we know this local, community-by-community approach works.&nbsp; In June, we focused much of this work in places with some of the lowest vaccination rates.&nbsp; We worked with local organizations in these communities to make sure people knew where to get a vaccine and how effective the vaccines are against COVID-19.&nbsp; We focused much of this work in states including Alabama, Arizona, Florida, Georgia, and Texas &#8212; states with some of the lowest vaccination rates.</p>



<p>Across June, vaccination rates in these states grew faster than the overall national vaccination rate.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to stay at it and continue to make progress.&nbsp; We will get vaccines to more and more family doctors so Americans can get a shot at their doctor&#8217;s office.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Across the last few months, we&#8217;ve already nearly doubled the number of medical practices receiving vaccine, with tens of thousands of family doctors now administering shots.&nbsp; We will build on this progress and work with pediatricians and other healthcare providers who serve younger people to push to get younger people vaccinated as they see their doctors for back-to- school checkups or get physicals for fall sports.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will also intensify our efforts to bring vaccines to where many people spend the most time during the week: at workplaces and on school campuses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time we work with communities to get more shots and arms, we’re also mobilizing COVID-19 surge response teams to provide additional support to states in dealing with outbreaks among the unvaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The COVID-19 surge response teams have begun working with several states to identify and support the state-specific or county-specific needs.&nbsp; This includes states such as Missouri, Nevada, Illinois, and Arkansas.&nbsp; These efforts include providing expert support from the CDC on outbreak investigations; working with local health officials on getting more treatments for people with COVID; and helping states increase vaccine confidence, answer questions, and expand access to vaccinations and testing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the days and weeks ahead, we will continue to make sure states have access to the specific federal resources and capabilities they need to fight the virus.&nbsp; And as always, we will continue to keep equity at the center of everything we do, because every person in every community matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In closing, America is coming back.&nbsp; Millions are safely living a more normal life.&nbsp; And we have a huge swath of the country vaccinated.&nbsp; We have moved from getting Americans vaccinated at a speed and scale never seen before, to focusing on reaching each individual who remains unvaccinated to ensure they are protected as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We push forward with a singular focus: Every shot matters; every individual that we vaccinate is progress.&nbsp; It&#8217;s another life protected, another community that is safer, and another step toward putting this pandemic behind us that has sadly taken more than 600,000 lives here at home and a total of 4 million lives around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, let me hand it over to Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp; Yesterday, CDC reported a little over 14,000 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is about 13,900 cases per day.&nbsp; And this represents an increase in cases, of nearly 11 percent, from the prior seven-day average.</p>



<p>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 2,000 per day.&nbsp; This also represents an increase of about 7 percent from the prior seven-day average.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the seven-day average of daily deaths is about 184 per day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These numbers and what we are seeing across the country reveal two truths about the current state of the pandemic.&nbsp; On the one hand, we have seen the successes of our vaccination program over the last eight months, with cases, hospitalizations, and deaths far lower than the peaks we saw in January.&nbsp; And yet, on the other hand, we are starting to see some new and concerning trends.&nbsp; Simply put, in areas of low vaccination coverage, cases and hospitalizations are up.</p>



<p>Further, we are seeing some small clusters and larger outbreaks of COVID-19 in locations such as camps and community events where proper hard-learned prevention strategies are not enforced and the virus is readily able to thrive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the Delta variant is spreading rapidly throughout the country.&nbsp; This week, the Delta variant is estimated to be the most prevalent variant in the United States, representing over 50 percent of sequenced samples across the country, up from 26 percent from the week ending June 19.</p>



<p>And in some parts of the country, the percentage is even higher.&nbsp; For example, in parts of the Midwest and Upper Mountain states, CDC’s early sequence data suggests the Delta variant accounts for approximately 80 percent of cases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although we expected the Delta variant to become the dominant strain in the United States, this rapid rise is troubling.&nbsp; We know that the Delta variant has increased transmissibility, and it is currently surging in pockets of the country with low vaccination rates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also know that our authorized vaccines prevent severe disease, hospitalization, and death from the Delta variant, and results &#8212; these results have been observed not just here in the United States, but in other countries as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, widespread vaccination is what will truly turn the corner on this pandemic.&nbsp; Please know if you are not vaccinated, you remain susceptible, especially from the transmit &#8212; transmissible Delta variant and are particularly at risk for severe illness and death.</p>



<p>I want to share with you my concerns about what we&#8217;re seeing across the country in areas of low vaccination coverage and in counties with increasing case rates.&nbsp; As shown on the left map in blue, there are 173 counties in the United States that have case rates of greater than or equal to 100 cases per 100,000 people over the last seven days.&nbsp; On the right side of this slide, shown in purple, are the counties in the U.S. that have both vaccine coverage less than 40 percent and cases of greater than or equal to 100 per 100,000 people over the last several days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of the 173 counties with the highest case rates, the vast majority &#8212; 93 percent &#8212; have less than 40 percent vaccination of their residents.&nbsp; These counties are where more than 9 million Americans live and work, and are the locations in the country where we are seeing the increased hospitalizations and deaths among unvaccinated individuals.&nbsp; Many of these counties are also the same locations where the Delta variant represents the large majority of circulating virus.&nbsp; Low vaccination rates in these counties coupled with high case rates and lax mitigation policies that do not protect those who are unvaccinated from disease will certainly and sadly lead to more unnecessary suffering, hospitalizations, and potentially death.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Indeed, as I stated last week, preliminary data from several states over the last few months suggests that 99.5 percent of deaths from COVID-19 in the United States were in unvaccinated people.&nbsp; Those deaths were preventable with a simple, safe shot.</p>



<p>COVID-19 vaccines are free and available to everyone age 12 and up.&nbsp; Vaccinating &#8212; vaccination is our leading public health strategy to stop the Delta variant and bring case rates down in these counties.</p>



<p>We are seeing that communities and counties that have high vaccine coverage and low case rates are getting back to normal.&nbsp; Turning the corner on this pandemic, getting back to normal, and stopping the Delta variant requires all of us to do our part and to get vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; As you heard from Dr. Walensky, the Delta variant is assuming more and more dominance in this country, particularly in those areas of low vaccination.&nbsp; So the logical question one asks: Is that the vaccines that our &#8212; they are &#8212; that we are using, how effective are they against the various aspects of disease associated with a Delta variant?&nbsp;</p>



<p>If I could have the first slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, let&#8217;s take a look at the mRNA vaccines, which are two out of the three vaccines that are used in this country &#8212; and mRNA, overwhelmingly, used the most among vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The real-world setting, as shown here if you ask, cases protected against &#8212; the Scotland study &#8212; showing that two doses of Pfizer are about 79 percent protective.&nbsp; Symptomatic disease &#8212; a study from England &#8212; again, two doses of Pfizer: 88 percent.&nbsp; And hospitalizations &#8212; again, in England &#8212; two doses: 96 percent real-world effectiveness.&nbsp; You can make a quite reasonable assumption that data that are applicable to Pfizer are also applicable to Moderna.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then the next slide, please.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The question is &#8212; I&#8217;ve just spoken about the mRNA vaccines: What about the J&amp;J vaccines?&nbsp; There&#8217;s indirect and direct evidence for effectiveness of J&amp;J against the Delta variant.&nbsp; Because if you look at a comparison between the J&amp;J and the Oxford-AstraZeneca, or the AZ vaccine &#8212; because they use similar adenovirus vectors.&nbsp; We have clinical data with AZ in real-world effectiveness.&nbsp; And as you can see, when you look at infection versus symptomatic versus the important number on the bottom of the slide &#8212; 92 percent effective against hospitalization from the Delta variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there&#8217;s also other types of data, namely looking at the antibodies that are induced by vaccination with J&amp;J.&nbsp; A recent study that came out a few days ago, looked at the blood studies from individuals vaccinated with the typical single dose of J&amp;J vaccine.&nbsp; And it covered the Delta variants and other variants really, effectively, quite well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a similar, related paper, when you look at the durability of the humoral and cellular immunity using the J&amp;J vaccine &#8212; again, against the Delta and other variants &#8212; again, shows not only good protection projected by the antibody test, but also a good durability of that protection out to eight months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what&#8217;s the bottom line of all of this?&nbsp; We&#8217;ve heard about the threat from Dr. Walensky about the increasing in infections.&nbsp; The question is: If you get vaccinated, are you protected?&nbsp; And the answer is &#8212;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As shown on this study &#8212; or this story from the New York Times, the world is understandably worried about the Delta virus variant, but studies showed, as I&#8217;ve showed you on the previous against it.&nbsp; The only conclusion one can reasonably come to from looking at what I&#8217;ve told you over the last few minutes is: Please get vaccinated.&nbsp; It will protect you against the surging of the Delta variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me now hand it over to Dr. Nunez-Smith.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. NUNEZ-SMITH:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Very glad to be here with you today to provide an update on equity and the progress we&#8217;re making vaccinating communities that have been hit the hardest by the pandemic, with a focus today on communities of color.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So when we consider the data that we have on race and ethnicity &#8212; and, of course, we have to acknowledge there are still notable data gaps and some caveats remain &#8212; but still, the data indicate the majority of individuals receiving vaccines over the past two weeks identified as people of color.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, more specifically, 12 percent of individuals getting their first shot these past two weeks have identified as Black.&nbsp; That&#8217;s roughly equivalent in terms of the group&#8217;s representation in the general U.S. population.</p>



<p>Latinos make up 17 percent of the total U.S. population, and over these past two weeks have accounted for 34 percent of individuals getting their first shot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we do see progress, and particularly so when we look at the federal vaccination channels, and those were set up in the very first few weeks of the administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, at our community health centers, more than 75 percent of people vaccinated at those locations are people of color.&nbsp; Nearly two thirds of those vaccinated at dialysis centers are people of color.&nbsp; And over the past two weeks, 58 percent of doses administered at pharmacies have been to people of color.&nbsp; And over 50 percent of vaccines administered at the federally run vaccination centers went to people of color.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But despite this progress, we still have more work to do.&nbsp; And as the President said on Tuesday: This summer, the work &#8212; it&#8217;s going to be hyperlocal, person by person to help folks get vaccinated.&nbsp; And each one of us is worth the effort.&nbsp; And every vaccination is a victory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we will continue to make vaccination easy and convenient.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to address structural barriers, both to accessing accurate information, as well as accessing vaccination resources, meeting people where they are, especially younger folks.</p>



<p>So you&#8217;ll see more mobile units in neighborhoods across the country and at summer gatherings.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue to work with employers on paid time off, and to provide on-site vaccination opportunities.&nbsp; And, of course, we&#8217;ll continue to lift up best and promising practices, finding innovative ways to bring vaccinations to people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One example: On Mondays and Fridays, the Chicago Transit Authority is partnering with the Chicago Department of Public Health to implement pop-up COVID-19 vaccination station clinics.&nbsp; The Chicago Transit Authority has retrofitted buses that will make stops along the L Line stations to administer vaccines where rates have been lower.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, we&#8217;re pleased to announce that four of the nation&#8217;s largest childcare providers &#8212; that&#8217;s Bright Horizons, KinderCare, Learning Care Group, and the YMCA &#8212; have agreed to continue providing free drop-in childcare for parents and caregivers getting vaccinated through Labor Day, which is September 6th &#8212; extended from their initial commitment, which was through the Fourth of July.&nbsp; So, thank you to all of our partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, of course, we&#8217;re going to keep partnering with community faith-based organizations all across the country.&nbsp; Those partners are trusted and trustworthy.&nbsp; And so whether that&#8217;s a house of worship, a barber shop, a medical practice, or a local community center, working together to build vaccine confidence and increase access.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And importantly, we have to continue to get the message out to remind everyone vaccination is free; government-issued ID is not required; proof of insurance is not required; and we will always, always commit to maintaining data privacy.&nbsp; And last but certainly not least, we&#8217;ll continue to strengthen the data environment to inform equity interventions and commit to prioritizing long-term health equity policies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, communities are the experts in what they need, all the time.&nbsp; So partnership and collaboration &#8212; that&#8217;s how we&#8217;ll get through this together.&nbsp; And thank you so much to everyone on the ground, showing up every day to advance equity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I&#8217;ll turn things back over to you, Jeff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, thank you, doctors.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s open it up for a few questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; And we are very limited on questions and timing today, so please keep it to one question.&nbsp; First let&#8217;s go to Yamiche at PBS.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much for taking my question.&nbsp; This one &#8212; if I can go to Dr. Fauci &#8212; I&#8217;m wondering if you could talk a little bit more about mask wearing.&nbsp; You said that you would possibly wear a mask if you were in a community with low vaccination rates.&nbsp; And is there any sort of thinking that we might have to go back to wearing masks indoors in the fall if things get even worse?&nbsp; And it&#8217;s for vaccinated people, of course.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah, so let me clarify that.&nbsp; When I was asked a question about wearing masks when you are vaccinated &#8212; and the question that was “If you would go to a place with a high degree of viral dynamics and a very low level of vaccine, what you might do?” &nbsp;And I underscored “might.”&nbsp; And that is the discretion that people have, even if you are vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, if you are an elderly person or if you have a person with an underlying disease, you might want to go the extra mile of protection of wearing a mask if you are indoors in an environment with a high degree of infection in the community and a low level of vaccination.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That is not a mask recommendation; that&#8217;s just for consideration of each individual has their own level of the risk that they would like to take.&nbsp; And there are many individuals who would feel &#8212; because of age, or because of an underlying condition &#8212; that they might want to wear a mask.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Having said that, let me emphasize that if you are vaccinated, you have a very high degree of protection and therefore you do not need to wear a mask.&nbsp; So I wanted to make sure I clarified what I had said and what was interpreted with what I had said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Alice Park at Time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just wanted to follow up on that and ask: Can we take from that then &#8212; and this is for both Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci &#8212; that &#8212; are we going to be looking at going the way of the UK and start leaving it up to individual people to decide how and when to wear masks, and how and when to continue practicing social distancing and other mitigation measures?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci and then Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; You know, Alice, it really is consistent with what I had just said.&nbsp; I mean, you look for what the general recommendation is from the CDC &#8212; and I&#8217;ll let Dr. Walensky comment that in a moment &#8212; the general recommendation is that you have a high degree of protection, and if you are vaccinated, you do not need to wear a mask indoors or outdoors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The point about individual discretion: We, of course, leave it up to individuals to make an evaluation of the level of risk.&nbsp; Some people are very, very risk averse, and they say, “Even though you&#8217;re telling me that I have a high degree of protection, for myself, I would opt…” &#8212; for any of the number of reasons: the two that I gave a moment ago, age or underlying condition; or just a great degree of risk aversion.</p>



<p>You have the option of making your personal choice of whether or not you would like to wear a mask indoors in an area where there&#8217;s a high degree of viral dynamics and a low degree of vaccination.</p>



<p>But, Rochelle, why don&#8217;t you comment further.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, I don&#8217;t have a lot to add except to say that we do know that you are protected, if you are vaccinated, from hospitalization, severe disease, and death.&nbsp; Data in our country and numerous other countries have demonstrated that.</p>



<p>I want to emphasize, however, that if you are not vaccinated &#8212; first, you should go get vaccinated.&nbsp; But second, until you are fully vaccinated, you&#8217;re definitively not protected from disease that is around you, and in those situations, we would absolutely continue &#8212; suggest continuing to wear a mask.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Josh Wingrove, Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, can you follow a little bit up on the map you showed?&nbsp; It looked like, in particular, the hotspot in sort of southern &#8212; southwestern &#8212; western Missouri and northern Arkansas. Do you have any sense of what has been driving this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And broadly, Jeff, can you speak a little bit to the question about when borders would reopen and how you will make that determination on travelers from the European Union or other countries where vaccination levels are rising?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Josh.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; You pointed to some areas we&#8217;re following closely both because of their low vaccination rates, as well as because we&#8217;re seeing increasing cases there and in other areas around the country, which is why I thought those two maps were very informative.</p>



<p>In those areas, again, we&#8217;ve demonstrated high rates of disease, lower rates of vaccination.&nbsp; We are really encouraging people who are not vaccinated yet will get vaccinated and wear a mask until you do.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good.&nbsp; And, Josh, on international travel, you know, we&#8217;ve made, as we just discussed, significant progress on the pandemic, and we’ll continue to put public health first when making decisions about borders and international travel.&nbsp; Any decisions about reopening international travel will be guided by our public health and medical experts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have any specific update for you on any reopening plans.&nbsp; We must remain vigilant, particularly given the spread of the Delta variant, and we&#8217;ll reopen when the health and medical experts believe it’s safe to do so.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Anne Flaherty, ABC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; One clarification on the Delta variant.&nbsp; Can you say how accurate you think the 51 percent estimate is and if that&#8217;s a possible undercount?&nbsp; And then, also, Jeff, if you could respond to the Missouri governor saying he doesn&#8217;t want government officials going door to door pushing the vaccine and he&#8217;s ordered his health department to ensure that that doesn&#8217;t happen.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; What I can tell you is, over time, we get an increasing number of sequences that we continue to sequence and then update our estimate.&nbsp; So this 51 percent is an estimate of about the first 600 sequences.&nbsp; It has some uncertainty around it, but that&#8217;s our best estimate at this point.&nbsp; And in fact, generally, we think that those are relatively stable as we get more &#8212; more sequences over time, and we will continue to update those.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good.&nbsp; On the door-to-door &#8212; you know, as we&#8217;ve said from the beginning, all of the studies, all of our experiences &#8212; the best people to talk about vaccinations with those who have questions are local trusted messengers: doctors, faith leaders, community leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as part of our efforts, trusted messengers may go door to door &#8212; these very doctors, faith leaders, and community leaders that people look to for this type of advice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as we talked about earlier, we&#8217;ve seen movement by going person by person, community by community in states where neighbors have contacted neighbors.&nbsp; This is important work that&#8217;s leading to more vaccinations, and it&#8217;s done by people who care about the health of their family, friends, and neighbors.</p>



<p>So, I would say: For those individuals, organizations that are feeding misinformation and trying to mischaracterize this type of trusted-messenger work, I believe you are doing a disservice to the country and to the doctors, the faith leaders, community leaders, and others who are working to get people vaccinated, save lives, and help end this pandemic.</p>



<p>Why don&#8217;t we do one more question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Kaitlan Collins, CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; Jeff, could you weigh in on the Olympics and the &#8212; given the new state of emergency?&nbsp; You know, should the First Lady still go?&nbsp; And what is your perspective of this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, secondly, should vaccinated people be getting tested on a regular basis to know if they are breakthrough cra- &#8212; case, if they&#8217;re carrying the Delta variant or any other variant, for that matter?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Let me actually turn to Dr. Fauci on the Olympics and Dr. Walensky on your second question.</p>



<p>Dr. Fauci?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, Kaitlan, I mean, obviously, as we always do, we leave the situation of the kinds of restrictions that are going to be put on people coming to the Olympics to the local authorities who know best of what&#8217;s going on.</p>



<p>With regard to the athletes themselves, the protocols that are in place to protect them are really quite strict and stringent.&nbsp; Many of them &#8212; maybe the majority of them, I think &#8212; are going to be vaccinated.&nbsp; But the care that&#8217;s being taken to avoid the spread there is really something that I think is really quite impressive, from what I have heard about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The question about the First Lady going there: I mean, I think that&#8217;s going to be up to the First Lady.&nbsp; I believe that there&#8217;s no reason, right now, given the situation, that &#8212; the protocol to protect her health, I think, will be also rather stringent, so I don&#8217;t have a concern about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the final choice of what she’d do, obviously, is up to her.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, the testing question.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you, Kaitlan.&nbsp; Our current guidance for fully vaccinated people is that if you have symptoms that could suggest COVID-19, that you should absolutely get a test.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t see any reason currently to test for those who are asymptomatic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what I do want to emphasize is: Those symptoms that could potentially suggest COVID-19 &#8212; runny nose, sore throat, cough &#8212; are typical of upper respiratory symptoms that people may just ignore and &#8212; as not being COVID-19.&nbsp; So what I would say is: If you have those upper respiratory symptoms and you&#8217;ve been vaccinated, you should absolutely get a COVID-19 test.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, everybody.&nbsp; We look forward to seeing you at next week&#8217;s briefing.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:37 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_8July2021.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_8July2021.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the Drawdown of U.S. Forces in Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/08/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-drawdown-of-u-s-forces-in-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room  2:09 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Earlier today, I was briefed by our senior military and national security leaders on the status of the drawdown of U.S. forces and allied forces in Afghanistan.    When I announced our drawdown in April, I said we would be out by September, and we’re on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room </p>



<p>2:09 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Earlier today, I was briefed by our senior military and national security leaders on the status of the drawdown of U.S. forces and allied forces in Afghanistan.   <br><br>When I announced our drawdown in April, I said we would be out by September, and we’re on track to meet that target.<br><br>Our military mission in Afghanistan will conclude on August 31st.  The drawdown is proceeding in a secure and orderly way, prioritizing the safety of our troops as they depart.  <br><br>Our military commanders advised me that once I made the decision to end the war, we needed to move swiftly to conduct the main elements of the drawdown.  And in this context, speed is safety. <br><br>And thanks to the way in which we have managed our withdrawal, no one &#8212; no one U.S. forces or any forces have &#8212; have been lost.  Conducting our drawdown differently would have certainly come with a increased risk of safety to our personnel.   <br><br>To me, those risks were unacceptable.  And there was never any doubt that our military would perform this task efficiently and with the highest level of professionalism.  That’s what they do.  And the same is true of our NATO Allies and partners who have supported &#8212; we are supporting, and supporting us as well, as they conclude their retrograde.   <br><br>I want to be clear: The U.S. military mission in Afghanistan continues through the end of August.  We remain &#8212; we retain personnel and capacities in the country, and we maintain some authority &#8212; excuse me, the same authority under which we’ve been operating for some time.<br><br>As I said in April, the United States did what we went to do in Afghanistan: to get the terrorists who attacked us on 9/11 and to deliver justice to Osama Bin Laden, and to degrade the terrorist threat to keep Afghanistan from becoming a base from which attacks could be continued against the United States.  We achieved those objectives.  That’s why we went.<br><br>We did not go to Afghanistan to nation-build.  And it’s the right and the responsibility of the Afghan people alone to decide their future and how they want to run their country.   <br><br>Together, with our NATO Allies and partners, we have trained and equipped over three hu- &#8212; nearly 300,000 current serving members of the military &#8212; of the Afghan National Security Force, and many beyond that who are no longer serving.  Add to that, hundreds of thousands more Afghan National Defense and Security Forces trained over the last two decades.<br><br>We provided our Afghan partners with all the tools &#8212; let me emphasize: all the tools, training, and equipment of any modern military.  We provided advanced weaponry.  And we’re going to continue to provide funding and equipment.   And we’ll ensure they have the capacity to maintain their air force.<br><br>But most critically, as I stressed in my meeting just two weeks ago with President Ghani and Chairman Abdullah, Afghan leaders have to come together and drive toward a future that the Afghan people want and they deserve.<br><br>In our meeting, I also assured Ghani that U.S. support for the people of Afghanistan will endure.  We will continue to provide civilian and humanitarian assistance, including speaking out for the rights of women and girls.<br><br>I intend to maintain our diplomatic <s>presedence</s> [presence] in Afghanistan, and we are coordinating closely with our international partners in order to continue to secure the international airport. <br><br>And we’re going to engage in a determined diplomacy to pursue peace and a peace agreement that will end this senseless violence. <br><br>I’ve asked Secretary of State Blinken and our Special Representative for Afghanistan Reconciliation to work vigorously with the parties in Afghanistan, as well as the regional and international stakeholders to support a negotiated solution.   <br><br>To be clear &#8212; to be clear: Countries in the region have an essential role to play in supporting a peaceful settlement.   We’ll work with them, and they should help step up their efforts as well.   <br><br>We’re going to continue to work for the release of detained Americans, including Mark &#8212; excuse me &#8212; Fre&#8211; Frerichs &#8212; I want to pronounce the name correctly; I mis- &#8212; I misspoke &#8212; so that he can return to his family safely.<br><br>We’re also going to continue to make sure that we take on the Afghan nationals who work side-by-side with U.S. forces, including interpreters and translators &#8212; since we’re no longer going to have military there after this; we’re not going to need them and they have no jobs &#8212; who are also going to be vital to our efforts so they &#8212; and they’ve been very vital &#8212; and so their families are not exposed to danger as well.<br><br>We’ve already dramatically accelerated the procedure time for Special Immigrant Visas to bring them to the United States.   <br><br>Since I was inaugurated on January 20th, we’ve already approved 2,500 Special Immigrant Visas to come to the United States.  Up to now, fewer than half have exercised their right to do that.  Half have gotten on aircraft and com &#8212; commercial flights and come, and the other half believe they want to stay &#8212; at least thus far.<br><br>We’re working closely with Congress to change the authorization legislation so that we can streamline the process of approving those visas.  And those who have stood up for the operation to physically relocate thousands of Afghans and their families before the U.S. military mission concludes so that, if they choose, they can wait safely outside of Afghanistan while their U.S. visas are being processed.<br><br>The operation has identified U.S. facilities outside of the continental United States, as well as in third countries, to host our Afghan allies, if they ch- &#8212; if they so choose.  And, starting this month, we’re going to begin to re- &#8212; re- &#8212; reloc- &#8212; we’re going to begin relocation flights for Afghanistan SIV applicants and their families who choose to leave.   <br><br>We have a point person in the White House and at the State Department-led task force coordinating all these efforts. <br><br>But our message to those women and men is clear: There is a home for you in the United States if you so choose, and we will stand with you just as you stood with us.<br><br>When I made the decision to end the U.S. military involvement in Afghanistan, I judged that it was not in the national interest of the United States of America to continue fighting this war indefinitely.  I made the decision with clear eyes, and I am briefed daily on the battlefield updates. <br><br>But for those who have argued that we should stay just six more months or just one more year, I ask them to consider the lessons of recent history. <br><br>In 2011, the NATO Allies and partners agreed that we would end our combat mission in 2014.  In 2014, some argued, &#8220;One more year.&#8221;  So we kept fighting, and we kept taking casualties.  In 2015, the same.  And on and on.<br><br>Nearly 20 years of experience has shown us that the current security situation only confirms that “just one more year” of fighting in Afghanistan is not a solution but a recipe for being there indefinitely.   <br><br>It’s up to Afghans to make the decision about the future of their country.<br><br>Others are more direct.  Their argument is that we should stay with the Afghan &#8212; in Afghanistan indefinitely.  In doing so, they point to the fact that we &#8212; we have not taken losses in this last year, so they claim that the cost of just maintaining the status quo is minimal.<br><br>But that ignores the reality and the facts that already presented on the ground in Afghanistan when I took office: The Taliban was at its strongest mil- &#8212; is at its strongest militarily since 2001.<br><br>The number of U.S. forces in Afghanistan had been reduced to a bare minimum.  And the United States, in the last administration, made an agreement that the &#8212; with the Taliban to remove all our forces by May 1 of this past &#8212; of this year.  That’s what I inherited.  That agreement was the reason the Taliban had ceased major attacks against U.S. forces. <br><br>If, in April, I had instead announced that the United States was going to back &#8212; going back on that agreement made by the last administration &#8212; [that] the United States and allied forces would remain in Afghanistan for the foreseeable future &#8212; the Taliban would have again begun to target our forces.<br><br>The status quo was not an option.  Staying would have meant<br>U.S. troops taking casualties; American men and women back in the middle of a civil war.  And we would have run the risk of having to send more troops back into Afghanistan to defend our remaining troops.<br><br>Once that agreement with the Taliban had been made, staying with a bare minimum force was no longer possible.<br><br>So let me ask those who wanted us to stay: How many more &#8212; how many thousands more of America’s daughters and sons are you willing to risk?  How long would you have them stay?<br><br>Already we have members of our military whose parents fought in Afghanistan 20 years ago.  Would you send their children and their grandchildren as well?  Would you send your own son or daughter?<br><br>After 20 years &#8212; a trillion dollars spent training and equipping hundreds of thousands of Afghan National Security and Defense Forces, 2,448 Americans killed, 20,722 more wounded, and untold thousands coming home with unseen trauma to their mental health &#8212; I will not send another generation of Americans to war in Afghanistan with no reasonable expectation of achieving a different outcome.<br><br>The United States cannot afford to remain tethered to policies creating a response to a world as it was 20 years ago.  We need to meet the threats where they are today.<br><br>Today, the terrorist threat has metastasized beyond Afghanistan.  So, we are repositioning our resources and adapting our counterterrorism posture to meet the threats where they are now significantly higher: in South Asia, the Middle East, and Africa.<br><br>But make no mistake: Our military and intelligence leaders are confident they have the capabilities to protect the homeland and our interests from any resurgent terrorist challenge emerging or emanating from Afghanistan. <br><br>We are developing a counterterrorism over-the-horizon capability that will allow us to keep our eyes firmly fixed on any direct threats to the United States in the region, and act quickly and decisively if needed.<br><br>And we also need to focus on shoring up America’s core strengths to meet the strategic competition with China and other nations that is really going to determine &#8212; determine our future. <br><br>We have to defeat COVID-19 at home and around the world, make sure we’re better prepared for the next pandemic or biological threat. <br><br>We need to establish international norms for cyberspace and the use of emergenc- &#8212; emerging technologies.<br><br>We need to take concerted action to fight existential threats of climate change.<br><br>And we will be more formidable to our adversaries and competitors over the long run if we fight the battles of the next 20 years, not the last 20 years.<br><br>Finally, I want to recognize the incredible sacrifice and dedication that the U.S. military and civilian personnel, serving alongside our Allies and partners, have made over the last two decades in Afghanistan. <br><br>I want to honor the significance of what they&#8217;ve accomplished and the great personal risk they encountered and the incredible cost to their families: pursuing the terrorist threat in some of the most unforgiving terrain on the planet &#8212; and I&#8217;ve been almost throughout that entire country; ensuring there hasn’t been another attack on the homeland from Afghanistan for the last 20 years; taking out Bin Laden.<br><br>I want to thank you all for your service and the dedication to the mission so many of you have given, and to the sacrifices that you and your families have made over the long course of this war. <br><br>We&#8217;ll never forget those who gave the last full measure of devotion for their country in Afghanistan, nor those whose lives have been immeasurably altered by wounds sustained in service to their country.<br><br>We&#8217;re ending America’s longest war, but we&#8217;ll always, always honor the bravery of the American patriots who served in it.<br><br>May God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.  Thank you.<br><br>Q    Mr. President &#8212; do you trust the Taliban, Mr. President?<br><br>Q    Is a Taliban takeover of Afghanistan now inevitable?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, it is not.<br><br>Q    Why?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Because you &#8212; the Afghan troops have 300,000 well-equipped &#8212; as well-equipped as any army in the world &#8212; and an air force against something like 75,000 Taliban.  It is not inevitable.<br><br>Q    Do you trust the Taliban, Mr. President?  Do you trust the Taliban, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  You &#8212; is that a serious question?<br><br>Q    It is absolutely a serious question.  Do you trust the Taliban? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, I do not.<br><br>Q    Do you trust handing over the country to the Taliban?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, I do not trust the Taliban. <br><br>Q    So why are you handing the country over?<br><br>Q    Mr. President, is the U.S. responsible for the deaths of Afghans after you leave the country?<br><br>Q    Mr. President, will you amplify that question, please?  Will you amplify your answer, please &#8212; why you don’t trust the Taliban?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  It’s a &#8212; it’s a silly question.  Do I trust the Taliban?  No.  But I trust the capacity of the Afghan military, who is better trained, better equipped, and more re- &#8212; more competent in terms of conducting war. <br><br>Yes, ma&#8217;am.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  Given the amount of money that has been spent and the number of lives that have been lost, in your view, with making this decision, were the last 20 years worth it?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  You know my record.  I can tell by the way you asked the question.<br><br>I opposed permanently having American forces in Afghanistan.  I argued, from the beginning, as you may recall &#8212; it came to light after the administration was over, last &#8212; our administration &#8212; no nation has ever unified Afghanistan.  No nation.  Empires have gone there and not done it.<br><br>The focus we had &#8212; and I strongly support it &#8212; and you may remember I physically went to Afghanistan.  I was up in that pass where Osama bin Laden was &#8212; allegedly escaped or &#8212; out of harm&#8217;s way.<br><br>We went for two reasons: one, to bring Osama bin Laden to the gates of hell, as I said at the time.  The second reason was to eliminate al Qaeda’s capacity to deal with more attacks on the United States from that territory.  We accomplished both of those objectives &#8212; period.<br><br>That&#8217;s what I believed, from the beginning, why we should be and why we should have gone to Afghanistan.  That job had been over for some time.  And that&#8217;s why I believe that this is the right decision and, quite frankly, overdue.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, has the civilian government hailed the people of Afghanistan?<br><br>Q    Mr. President, thank you very much.  Your own intelligence community has assessed that the Afghan government will likely collapse.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  That is not true. <br><br>Q    Is it &#8212; can you please clarify what they have told you about whether that will happen or not? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  That is not true.  They did not &#8212; they didn&#8217;t &#8212; did not reach that conclusion. <br><br>Q    So what is the level of confidence that they have that it will not collapse? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The Afghan government and leadership has to come together.  They clearly have the capacity to sustain the government in place.  The question is: Will they generate the kind of cohesion to do it?  It&#8217;s not a question of whether they have the capacity.  They have the capacity.  They have the forces.  They have the equipment.  The question is: Will they do it? <br><br>And I want to make clear what I made clear to Ghani: that we are not going just sus- &#8212; walk away and not sustain their ability to maintain that force.  We are.  We&#8217;re going to also work to make sure we help them in terms of everything from food necessities and other things in &#8212; in the region.  But &#8212; but, there&#8217;s not a conclusion that, in fact, they cannot defeat the Taliban. <br><br>I believe the only way there&#8217;s going to be &#8212; this is now Joe Biden, not the intelligence community &#8212; the only way there&#8217;s ultimately going to be peace and security in Afghanistan is that they work out a modus vivendi with the Taliban and they make a judgment as to how they can make peace. <br><br>And the likelihood there&#8217;s going to be one unified government in Afghanistan controlling the whole country is highly unlikely.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, thank you.  But we have talked to your own top general in Afghanistan, General Scott Miller.  He told ABC News the conditions are so concerning at this point that it could result in a civil war.  So, if Kabul falls to the Taliban, what will the United States do about it?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Look, you&#8217;ve said two things &#8212; one, that if it could result in a civil war &#8212; that&#8217;s different than the Taliban succeeding, number one.  Number two, the question of what will be done is going to be implicated &#8212; is going to implicate the entire region as well.  There&#8217;s a number of countries who have a grave concern about what&#8217;s going to happen in Afghanistan relative to their security. <br><br>The question is: How much of a threat to the United States of America and to our allies is whatever results in terms of a government or an agreement?  That&#8217;s when that judgement will be made. <br><br>Q    Mr. President, some Vietnamese veterans see echoes of their experience in this withdrawal in Afghanistan.  Do you see any parallels between this withdrawal and what happened in Vietnam, with some people feeling &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  None whatsoever.  Zero.  What you had is &#8212; you had entire brigades breaking through the gates of our embassy &#8212; six, if I&#8217;m not mistaken. <br><br>The Taliban is not the south &#8212; the North Vietnamese army. They&#8217;re not &#8212; they&#8217;re not remotely comparable in terms of capability.  There&#8217;s going to be no circumstance where you see people being lifted off the roof of a embassy in the &#8212; of the United States from Afghanistan.  It is not at all comparable. <br><br>Q    And, Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>Q    Mr. President, can I &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ll take him and then I&#8217;ll &#8212; and then I&#8217;ll go &#8212; I&#8217;ll go to the other side.  Hang on a second.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, how serious was the corruption among the Afghanistan government to this mission failing there?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, first of all, the mission hasn&#8217;t failed, yet.  There is in Afghanistan &#8212; in all parties, there&#8217;s been corruption.  The question is, can there be an agreement on unity of purpose?  What is the objective? <br><br>For example, it started off &#8212; there were going to be negotiations between the Taliban and the Afghan National Security Forces and the Afghan government.  That &#8212; that of &#8212; it didn&#8217;t come to &#8212; it didn&#8217;t come to fruition. <br><br>So the question now is, where do they go from here?  That &#8212; the jury is still out.  But the likelihood there&#8217;s going to be the Taliban overrunning everything and owning the whole country is highly unlikely. <br><br>Yes, ma&#8217;am.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, will the United States be responsible for the loss of Afghan civilian lives that could happen after a &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  No.<br><br>Q    &#8212; military exit?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, no, no.  It&#8217;s up to the people of Afghanistan to decide on what government they want, not us to impose the government on them.  No country has ever been able to do that. <br><br>Keep in mind, as a student of history, as I&#8217;m sure you are, never has Afghanistan been a united country, not in all of its history.  Not in all of its history.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, if this isn&#8217;t a &#8220;mission accomplished&#8221; moment, what is it, in your view?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, there&#8217;s no &#8220;mission accomplished.&#8221; <br><br>Q    How would you describe it?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The mission was accomplished in that we get &#8212; got Osama bin Laden, and terrorism is not emanating from that part of the world.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, if &#8220;speed is safety,&#8221; as you just said in your remarks, are you satisfied with the timeline of relocating Afghan nationals?  Is it happening quickly enough to your satisfaction, if it may not happen until next month, at the end?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, much of it has already happened.  There’s already been people &#8212; about a thousand people have gotten on aircraft and come home &#8212; come to the United States already on commercial aircraft.  So, as I said, there&#8217;s over 2,500 people that as &#8212; from January to now, have gotten those visas.  And only half decided that they wanted to leave. <br><br>The point is that I think the whole process has to be speeded up, period, in terms of being able to get these visas.<br><br>Q    Why can&#8217;t the U.S. evacuate these Afghan translators to the United States to await their visa processing as some immigrants at the southern border have been allowed to do?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Because the law doesn&#8217;t allow that to happen.  And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re asking the Congress to consider changing the law. <br><br>But in the meantime, we can guarantee their safety, if they wish to leave, by taking them to third countries and/or, while the wait is taking place, to come to &#8212; to &#8212; and hopefully, while they&#8217;re waiting there, to be able to bring them back to the United States, if that&#8217;s what they choose to do.<br><br>Q    And what do you make &#8212; and what do you make, sir, of the Taliban being in Russia today?<br><br>Q    Mr. President, I&#8217;m from Afghanistan.  I am Afghan (inaudible) woman.  Any message &#8212; good message for Afghan women in future?  Because they have achievement &#8212; they are really concerned about their achievement. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  They are very concerned, with good reason. <br><br>Q    Yes.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  When I was in Afghanistan &#8212; I&#8217;ve been there a number of times &#8212; I remember being in a school outside and &#8212; and, by the way, the schools in Afghanistan are not fundamentally unlike schools in the West Coast, where they have, you know, a &#8212; an area in the middle that is sort of like &#8212; it looks like a playground and single-story buildings connected around it. <br><br>And I remember saying to &#8212; speaking to a group of young women &#8212; I guess they were roughly &#8212; don&#8217;t hold me to this &#8212; they look like they&#8217;d be 14, 15 years old.  And they&#8217;re in school, and there&#8217;s a tiered classroom with single light bulbs hanging from the ceiling, as I know you know. <br><br>And I said, &#8220;You know, the United States came here to make sure that we got this terrorist, Osama bin Laden, and that terrorists didn&#8217;t amass again to &#8212; to go after our country.  And then we&#8217;re going to have to leave.&#8221;  And a young woman said, &#8220;You can&#8217;t leave.  You can&#8217;t leave.&#8221;  It was &#8212; it was heartbreaking.  &#8220;You can&#8217;t leave,&#8221; she said.  &#8220;I want to be a doctor.  I want to be a doctor.  I want to be a doctor.  If you leave, I&#8217;ll never be able to be a doctor.&#8221;  Well, that&#8217;s why we spent so much time and money training the Afghan Security Forces to do the work of defending that.  If every work &#8212;<br><br>Well, anyway &#8212; so, yes, I&#8217;m aware. <br><br>I&#8217;m going to take one more question.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, have you spoken with any Taliban officials about the withdrawal?<br><br>Q    (Inaudible) the Taliban being in Russia today &#8212; the Taliban &#8212;<br><br>Q    Mr. &#8212; Mr. President, I &#8212; thank you.  I wanted to ask: With the benefit of hindsight, you’ve spoken to the fact that the Taliban are sort of at their militarily strongest point that you&#8217;ve seen in 20 years.  How do you feel personally about that, with the benefit of hindsight and all of the dollars and investments and American troops that were sent there?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Relative to the training and capacity of the ANSF and the training of the federal police, they&#8217;re not even close in terms of their capacity. <br><br>I was making the point &#8212; the point was that here we were; I was &#8212; the argument is, &#8220;Well, we could stay because no one was dying.  No Americans are being shot.  So why leave?&#8221;  Once the agreement was made by the last administration that we were going to leave by May 1st, it was very clear that a Taliban that had always been a problem was even a more sophisticated problem than they were than before.  Not more sophisticated than the ANSF, the government.  More than they were.<br><br>The point being that it would have increased the prospect that they would have been able to take more lives of Americans if they decided we weren&#8217;t going to go after them.  That was the point I was making. <br><br>Thank you all so very much.  Thank you.<br><br>2:34 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 8, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/08/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-8-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 21:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:42 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone. Q    Hello. MS. PSAKI:  Happy Thursday.  (Laughter.)  Is it Thursday? Q    (Inaudible) “Happy Birthday”? MS. PSAKI:  I said, &#8220;Happy Thursday.&#8221;  Well, I was going to say &#8212; I did hear it was Steve Holland&#8217;s 29th birthday.  (Laughter.)  So, happy 29th birthday.  I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:42 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.<br><br>Q    Hello.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Happy Thursday.  (Laughter.)  Is it Thursday?<br><br>Q    (Inaudible) “Happy Birthday”?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I said, &#8220;Happy Thursday.&#8221;  Well, I was going to say &#8212; I did hear it was Steve Holland&#8217;s 29th birthday.  (Laughter.)  So, happy 29th birthday.  I am a terrible singer, but I am willing to lead a song here if you are all game.  (Laughter.)<br><br>Q    Is this a good day to ask for an interview with the President?  (Laughter.) <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  It may be.  It may be.<br><br>Q    You got to at least give him the first question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Who&#8217;s with me?  Someone here has a good voice.<br><br>(&#8220;Happy Birthday&#8221; is sung to Steve Holland.)  (Applause.)<br><br>All right.  I will also note: Brian Karem, excellent voice.  I don&#8217;t know what you do with that, but that&#8217;s one thing I learned today.  (Laughter.)<br><br>Okay, a couple of items for you.  Today, as you all know, the President and Vice President will meet with Black leaders from top civil rights organizations.  We are about to put out the list of these names if they are not already in your inbox.  But that is happening this afternoon.  We&#8217;ll have a readout.  We also expect a number of them will go out to the stakeout after the meeting.<br><br>Later today, Vice President Harris will also deliver remarks at Howard University on how the Democratic National Committee is expanding their “I Will Vote” campaign, for which the DNC can give you additional specifics.<br><br>As the President has been emphatic since taking of- &#8212; before taking office, our constitutional rights are on the line because state legislatures have forced through a wave of anti-voter laws based on the same repeatedly disproven lies that led to an assault on our nation’s Capitol in one of the darkest days in the history of American democracy. <br><br>So the meeting today, the Vice President&#8217;s event are a part of our ongoing effort to elevate this issue, to work with every lever of the federal government.<br><br>I also wanted to note, as you may have noticed, we&#8217;ve been doing kind of a daily announcement about our competition executive order.  So the new announcement that went out today will &#8212; focuses on saving American businesses money on shipping costs.  In turn, that will lower prices for American consumers.<br><br>A lot of American companies rely on railroads to ship their goods domestically and ocean carriers to ship their goods internationally.  Both of these industries have grown more concentrated over time.  Many freight routes are monopolized because they’re served by a single railroad.  Three foreign-owned shipping alliances now control more than 80 percent of the market.  I did not know that.  I&#8217;m learning something new every day with the competition EOs, which I appreciate.<br><br>That concentration has contributed to a spike in shipping costs and fees during the pandemic.  For example, the index price to ship one container has gone up eightfold.  And shipping container companies have charged companies massive fees while their goods sit at ports.<br><br>So, this executive order takes several steps to address these problems.  On international shipping, the executive order calls on the Federal Maritime Commission to crack down on unjust and unreasonable fees and work with the Justice Department to investigate and punish anticompetitive conduct.</p>



<p>And on domestic freight railroad, the executive order urges the Surface Transportation Board to allow more shippers &#8212; allow shippers to more easily challenge inflated rates when there is no competition between routes.<br><br>Finally, today we also have more doses that are going out to the world.&nbsp; We will ship 500,000 doses of the Pfizer vaccine to Uruguay and 1.4 million doses of Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine to Afghanistan. In the coming days, we will complete the entire 3 million shipment of J&amp;J doses to Afghanistan &#8212; something the President will also mention in his remarks today.</p>



<p>Zeke, why don&#8217;t you kick us off.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Yesterday, the President said he would know more today about what he would do in response to Russian ransomware attacks on U.S. entities.&nbsp; What does he plan on doing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, Zeke, I think what he intended to convey is that he&#8217;s continuing to be updated by his team on a regular and near-daily basis.&nbsp; And certainly, when they have new information to provide, they provide that to him.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we are continuing to gather details on if this incident occurred with the knowledge or approval of the Russian government.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re really digging into at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And while the intelligence community has not yet attributed the attack and we still don&#8217;t have new information on the attribution as of today, the cyber community &#8212; security community agrees that the criminal group, REvil, that we&#8217;ve talked about a bit in here, operates out of Russia with affiliates around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve been in touch at a high level, as you all know, with Russian &#8212; high-level Russian authorities &#8212; counterparts, I should say &#8212; regarding this incident.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve continued to send a clear message: If the Russian government cannot or will not act against criminal actors residing in Russia, we will act.</p>



<p>In terms of what we will do, I&#8217;m not in a position, of course, to discuss operations.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not in our interest to preview those.&nbsp; But the President sent a clear message to President Putin; we&#8217;re continuing to send that clear message in our engagements as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, on Afghanistan, on the SIV process, any updates on the administration&#8217;s efforts to find a third country to host processing of those visas, as well as can you confirm the administration is adding additional staff to help vet those applicants?&nbsp; And how long will that take, and how is the administration going to address security concerns among those who are applying for visas here?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, one of the areas the President will talk about in his remarks this afternoon is certainly ensuring that we are taking care of Afghan nationals who worked side by side with U.S. forces, and the SIV applicants, as you noted, including interpreters and translators.<br><br>So we have already dramatically accelerated the processing time for Special Immigrant Visas to bring them to the United States.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working closely with Congress &#8212; we&#8217;re continuing to work closely with Congress to change the authorizing legislation so that we can streamline the process for approving visas, even when they are in a third country.&nbsp; And we have stood up an operation to physically relocate thousands of these Afghans and their families before the U.S. military mission concludes so that they can wait safely outside of Afghanistan.</p>



<p>That operation has identified U.S. facilities outside of the continental United States, as well as third countries.&nbsp; Because of security reasons, we&#8217;re not going to outline in detail at this point where those are.&nbsp; But I can confirm that we will be conducting flights of our Afghan allies to these locations in August, so, of course, in advance of the timeline of bringing our troops home.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, we&#8217;re going to hear from the President later, but is it an acceptable outcome to the President if Kabul were to fall to the Taliban?&nbsp; I mean, that&#8217;s widely been predicted by experts, including in the U.S. mil- &#8212; in the U.S. government as a potential outcome here of the U.S. withdrawal.&nbsp; Is that an acceptable outcome to the President?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, Zeke, let me say what &#8212; the reason the President is speaking to all of you and the American public today is because he views this as an opportunity to once again communicate to the American people the security challenges he inherited in Afghanistan and affirm why he made the decision he made in April to withdraw our troops and end our involvement in the war.<br><br>And the question fundamentally facing him was: After 20 years, was he going to commit more American troops to a civil war in Afghanistan?&nbsp; And if we look back 20 years ago, which many people in this room covered when Steve was 9 years old &#8212; I&#8217;ll just &#8212; by math &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; we &#8212; we did what we wanted to do, which was we got the terrorists who attacked us on 9/11, we delivered justice to Osama bin Laden, we degraded al Qaeda&#8217;s capacity to the point they did not present an active threat to our homeland.<br><br>He made the decision after a clear-eyed assessment, in part because he’s never seen there to be a military end to this war, and also because, as we came into office, we had an agreed-to timeline.&nbsp; After May 1st, the uptick in violence was coming this summer; the status quo was not sustainable.&nbsp;<br><br>And we are still continuing to support diplomatically &#8212; through security assistance, humanitarian assistance &#8212; the ongoing efforts in Afghanistan, including a political negotiation process that&#8217;s ongoing that we expect the ambassador to continue to return to.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we have always anticipated, Zeke &#8212; and the President was very clear about this when he made his speech in April &#8212; that there would be an uptick in violence, that there would be an uptick in turmoil on the ground.&nbsp; We knew that, and we knew the security situation would become more difficult.&nbsp;<br><br>But he made the decision in part because, if you look back at recent history: In 2011, the NATO Allies and partners agreed that we would end our combat mission by 2014.&nbsp; In 2014, some argued for more &#8212; for one more year.&nbsp; So we kept fighting, kept taking casualties.&nbsp;<br><br>If we did not make the decision we did, there would have been severe consequences.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he made it.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe it&#8217;s still &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead, Steve.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe it&#8217;s still possible that the Afghan Security Forces can repel the Taliban?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly, under &#8212; as we expected, the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces are now under real pressure, and that was certainly a part of the discussion the President had with Afghan leaders just two weeks ago.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to provide funding and ensure they have capacity to maintain the Air Force.<br><br>And I would remind you that even since we were &#8212; since we engaged, together with our NATO Allies and partners, we have trained and equipped nearly 300,000 currently-serving members of the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces.<br><br>And one of the clear messages that the President sent directly in the meeting he had and he will continue to convey is that it is now time for them to be in the lead.&nbsp; They are in the lead as we pull our troops back, and we will continue to support them with security assistance and ongoing training.&nbsp; And we have &#8212; continue to have the authorities that we&#8217;ve long had through our withdrawal later this summer.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, separately, do you have an update on Haiti &#8212; the search for the killers of the president there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a &#8212; an extensive update, I will say, Steve.&nbsp; We continue to be engaged; of course, in touch through a range of channels, but we don&#8217;t have updates at this point.<br><br>The Haitian authorities are, of course, leading the investigation, which is, of course, in its early stages.&nbsp; We&#8217;re ready and willing to support Haitian authorities, but we&#8217;re going to let the investigation play out.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow-up on Haiti, please.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, April.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is this administration doing, in the midst of this assassination, to stand up the Haitian democracy in the midst of this?&nbsp; What is this administration doing?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that it is still &#8212; it is our view and we continue to call for elections to happen this year.&nbsp; And we believe they should proceed.&nbsp;<br><br>We know that free and fair elections will facilitate a peaceful transfer of power to a newly elected President, and we certainly continue to support Haiti&#8217;s democratic institutions.&nbsp; We will call on all political parties, civil society, and stakeholders to work together in the wake of the tragedy and echo acting &#8212; the acting prime minister&#8217;s call for calm.<br><br>We have not re- &#8212; offi- &#8212; received an official request for assistance, a formal request, but we stand ready to receive that when it comes in.<br><br>I&#8217;ve got to move on, April, because we have limited time.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Jeff.&nbsp;&nbsp;Go ahead, Jeff.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Is this speech this afternoon by the President considered the final word by the White House, at least, as America&#8217;s longest war draws down?&nbsp; Or does the President plan to mark this in some other way when all of the troops are out?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Jeff, I would say that we &#8212; we are &#8212; the President will continue to update the American people, as Commander-in-Chief, why he&#8217;s making choices to &#8212; that are in our national security interests.&nbsp; Today is an example of that.&nbsp; And today is an opportunity to communicate again why he made the decision he made and communicate again why it&#8217;s in our interests.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I&#8217;m not going to rule out when &#8212; if he will or won’t speak on Afghanistan in the future.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of plans for the end &#8212; for our men and women coming back, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview, but we don&#8217;t &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to have a “Mission Accomplished” moment in this regard.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a 20-year war that has not been won militarily.&nbsp;<br><br>We are proud of the men and women who have served &#8212; incredibly grateful.&nbsp; The President will note that in his remarks today &#8212; how grateful he is for their service and the families who have sacrificed over the last 20 years.&nbsp; And we will continue to press for a political outcome and a political solution.&nbsp;<br><br>But beyond that, I think we&#8217;re going to continue to look for ways to communicate why we make the choices we make.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned “Mission Accomplished.”&nbsp; Has this mission not been accomplished?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, we did exactly what we wanted to do.&nbsp; What I was referring to, Jeff, is we&#8217;re not having a moment of celebration.&nbsp; We&#8217;re having a moment where we feel is in our national security interests to bring our men and women serving home.&nbsp; And we feel it&#8217;s in our national security interests for Afghan forces to be in the lead.&nbsp;<br><br>We did exactly what we intended to do, and certainly that is something, thanks to the leadership of our military, we have achieved.&nbsp; However, there is not benefit, in our view, in continuing to fight this war militarily.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; If the military withdrawal is 90 percent complete at this point, why wait until August to finish that?&nbsp; Is there an effort to stall because of this situation &#8212; because of the conditions that are worsening?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, Rachel, that that is under the purview of the Department of Defense, and they&#8217;re doing &#8212; bringing our troops home in a way that is &#8212; keeps them safe.&nbsp; We have not had a single casualty, as I &#8212; as, I think, everyone has noted, and we will continue to keep that as our priority.&nbsp;<br><br>But in terms of the operational timeline, speed is safety, but we also want to manage our withdrawal in a way that protects our service members, makes sure that we are conducting our drawdown in a way that keeps that as the top priority.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a quick follow-up: Is the administration considering granting visas to vulnerable women in the region, including prominent activists, politicians, or journalists?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We maintain a range of contingencies and plan for a range of operational options, but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview on that front.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, thank you.&nbsp; If it turns out that the Afghan forces are not equipped and the Taliban has a complete takeover, would the President consider sending U.S. troops back into Afghanistan?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into a hypothetical.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I had a question on something you briefly mentioned yesterday.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said he would deliver a message to Putin, which he already did last month.&nbsp; So, when he said that yesterday, did he mean he has a new message for Putin?&nbsp; And under what circumstances will he deliver that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think, in the context of the Q&amp;A, he meant, “I&#8217;m not going to provide to you an update of the briefing I just received.”&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he said he had a message to deliver.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But that was the context of how he answered that question.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Jacqui.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On ransomware, in terms of the Kaseya hack, does the administration consider this to be an escalation, given that it didn&#8217;t attack one entity but hundreds of entities?&nbsp; And does the U.S. consider it to be critical infrastructure in any way, given how it hampered transactions for grocery stores and that kind of thing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, I would say, critical infrastructure, broadly speaking, would perhaps take out an entire se- &#8212; economic sector in the country.&nbsp; But that doesn&#8217;t mean we don&#8217;t take every cyberattack, every ransom attack incredibly seriously.<br><br>And as it relates to the impact here &#8212; or how we&#8217;re evaluating it, I should say &#8212; there has been an escalation of ransomware attacks over the course of the last several years.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a growing &#8212; an escalating problem that even predates President Biden.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not just the United States; it&#8217;s something that&#8217;s happening around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we know it&#8217;s not going to be turned off with a light switch.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not an up and down.&nbsp; We know that this needs to be ongoing engagement, and we&#8217;ll have to assess, over 6 months and 12 months, what our success looks like.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s how we&#8217;re looking at our impact as it relates to the cyber threats.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in the conversation with Russia about, you know, enforcing this red line that the President drew at the summit, what concrete asks have we made of Russia in terms of cracking down on actors that are within that state and clearly are attacking our companies here?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I would say the President hasn&#8217;t minced words.&nbsp; And should he speak with President Putin again &#8212; to Weijia’s question &#8212; he will convey the same message, which is: We &#8212; if you do not take action to crack down on criminal actors in your country, even if the government didn&#8217;t know, we will.&nbsp; We reserve that option too.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; continues to be his clear message.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a timeline, though, on that?&nbsp; Is &#8212; have we given Russia, you know, two weeks to do something?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to preview that for you all.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to go to the meeting yesterday between the Chicago mayor &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and the President.&nbsp; Can you talk at all about the request that she made of the administration in order to crack down on crime in that city?&nbsp; There was a report that she requested federal support.&nbsp; Did that involve troop presence in any way?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any summary of the conversation in that regard.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s something they&#8217;ve read out from their ends.&nbsp;<br><br>From our end, what the President conveyed to Mayor Lightfoot is that he will continue to work with her, in partnership, and work with cities around the country to address the rise of cri- &#8212; of violence and, specifically, the rise of gun violence was &#8212; is predominantly the driver in Chicago.&nbsp;<br><br>He also reiterated that, as the Department of Justice had announced just a few weeks ago, Chicago is one of the cities that will be a beneficiary of these groups that will go and help them &#8212; help directly crack down on combating drug violence and drug traffic- &#8212; I mean, sorry, gun violence and gun trafficking &#8212; something that we&#8217;re doing in about a half a dozen cities across the country.&nbsp; And he also reiterated his continued efforts at the federal level to crack down on the illegal passing of guns.<br><br>So there has been a great deal of funding that has been provided already to the city of Chicago &#8212; Cook County, specifically &#8212; and certainly some of that can be used to address crime as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How is the DOJ’s strike force going to specifically interrupt the networks that are trafficking these guns?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They&#8217;re work &#8212; going to work directly with the city.&nbsp; They&#8217;re doing them &#8212; we&#8217;re doing these strike forces in about five cities around the country, and they want to work directly with them to use legal authorities to crack down on illegal gun trafficking and work in partnership with law enforcement authorities in the cities and add that additional heft and &#8212; and resources.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, is there any push to, you know, fund more efforts to equip police departments?&nbsp; There&#8217;s &#8212; you know, the White House position was that Republicans defunded police. Obviously, the Biden administration has talked a lot about the budget proposal for the COPS program, but there&#8217;s been some pressure that the administration hasn&#8217;t vocally enough talked about this spike in crime.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say the President gave an entire speech on it and will continue to speak about what he&#8217;s doing.&nbsp; A big driver of the rise in crime is gun violence &#8212; a personal passion of his for decades.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say that there are a number of components &#8212; I know you referenced the budget &#8212; but the President called &#8212; called for a $300 million increase in funding for the COPS program.&nbsp; That&#8217;s up from two hun- &#8212; from $237 million in the last budget passed by President Trump to $537 million.&nbsp; And he also calls for an increase of $753 million over 2021 levels to federal law enforcement agencies.&nbsp; It includes ATF &#8212; the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives.&nbsp; It also includes a $10.2 billion &#8212; an increase of $465 million over 2021 &#8212; enacted for the FBI.<br><br>Go ahead, Steve.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, back on Haiti, just for a second, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you in a position to describe or detail some of the assistance the U.S. is standing ready to offer Haiti if asked?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we have to wait to see what their formal request is.&nbsp; And we stand ready to respond rapidly to whatever they &#8212; their needs are on the ground, but they&#8217;re the best equipped to assess that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you describe how the President views security and stability in Haiti vis-à-vis American interests today?&nbsp; I mean, I ask that because there&#8217;s a clip of the President in 1994, when he was a senator, comparing the situation in Haiti to the then-ongoing Bosnian War, in which he said something to the effect of &#8212; you know, he called it a godawful thing to say, but he said, “Haiti could sink into the Caribbean Sea or rise 300 feet in the air, and it wouldn&#8217;t matter to American interests.”&nbsp; Does he stand by that view today, or has he changed his view on Haiti?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say: First, the fact that he is now sitting as President of the United States &#8212; he issued a statement in his voice yesterday about the horrific killing of the President &#8212; and he has made clear to the administration and administration officials that we are &#8212; stand ready to assist in any way they need, whether it&#8217;s in the investigation or other federal assistance we can offer from here &#8212; sends you a clear message about his care and concern for the people of Haiti.<br><br>Go ahead, Kelly.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The administration and the President has, in some way, included in the calculus on Afghanistan the American public&#8217;s view that it&#8217;s time to bring U.S. forces home.&nbsp; Is the President believing that the American people would be satisfied with Kabul falling, with the threat to women and children there, and with some ill-defined numbers about how many of the Afghan interpreters, translators, support are able to be removed safely from the country? &nbsp;Does the President feel the American people factored those risks into that judgement about bringing troops home?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think at the end of the day, Kelly, the President feels that the American people elected him to serve as Commander-in-Chief, make decisions that are in our national interests.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean they&#8217;re always easy, and it doesn&#8217;t mean there aren&#8217;t drawbacks to the decisions that he makes.&nbsp; But he is not going to ask another generation of kids to go and serve in Afghanistan in a war that he does not feel can be won militarily, and that is the core driver of his decision here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On REvil, quickly: You mentioned that it&#8217;s now the assessment of the administration that they were responsible and that part of their criminal enterprise is working outside of Russia.&nbsp; You mentioned that the U.S. is in touch with high-level Russian entities.&nbsp; Is there also outreach to specific locations where our cyber resources know their actors are at work?&nbsp; Is that happening as well?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I used that context because I think it&#8217;s important for people to understand that even though the cybersecurity community has assessed it was REvil, we know they operate in different parts of the world.&nbsp; So even as we&#8217;re directing and we&#8217;re having a conversation largely about Russia&#8217;s knowledge, we &#8212; as we assess and before we make an official assessment by the United States government, we look at that.<br><br>But, certainly, as concerns arise, we&#8217;d certainly be in touch with countries as relevant.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Of course, yeah.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, thanks.&nbsp; On voting rights, the Supreme Court has upheld the voting laws in Arizona.&nbsp; Democrats don&#8217;t have the votes to pass the latest voting rights bill.&nbsp; What specifically can the President and the White House do to increase voting access without filibuster reform?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that, one, there are a number of announcements being made by the Democratic National Committee today &#8212; which is most appropriate for them to address &#8212; that the Vice President will be elevating.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;ve also seen that we&#8217;ve taken steps from our Department of Justice to use legal action, where relevant and where legal &#8212; where the law allows for, to push back on and take action in states where it is &#8212; where legislation is making it more difficult or where laws are making it more difficult for people to vote.&nbsp;<br><br>We also believe very much that empowering and engaging activists and creating grassroots movements &#8212; something that the Vice President is continuing to play a very prominent and prevalent role in doing &#8212; is also a part of how we&#8217;re going to work to fight legislation and fight actions to suppress voters around the country.&nbsp;<br><br>So, certainly, the President would love to sign a piece of voting rights legislation into law.&nbsp; He is &#8212; looks forward to doing that.&nbsp; But he also knows that there are a number of levers from the federal government that we should continue to use, and he&#8217;s not waiting to have the legislation on his desk.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on the Olympics.&nbsp; You know, fans have been banned from attending the Summer Games.&nbsp; Is it your assessment this is still safe for U.S. athletes?&nbsp; And has there been a determination on whether the First Lady will be attending?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, well, I would say the President supports the Tokyo Olympic Games and the public health measures necessary to protect athletes, staff, and spectators.&nbsp; He has pride in the U.S. athletes who have trained for the Tokyo Games and will be competing in the best traditions of the Olympic spirit.&nbsp;<br><br>The government of Japan has stressed that public health remains a central priority as they host the Games &#8212; or they prepare to host the Games.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve stayed in close contact with the Japanese government throughout the planning process and on related public health measures.&nbsp;<br><br>So we&#8217;re well aware of the careful preparations, including the public health measures necessary to protect athletes, staff, and spectators that the government and international committee has undertaken, which is why, as we&#8217;ve said, we support the Games moving forward.<br><br>In terms of the First Lady, we&#8217;re still assessing the feasibility of the First Lady attending.&nbsp; And our advance team arrives in Tokyo later this week.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you clarify one point, please?&nbsp; Just one &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on Afghanistan.&nbsp; And I guess it&#8217;s off of Kelly&#8217;s question.&nbsp; But you said that you all met many times and there was a decision process in drawing down the &#8212; our presence in Afghanistan.&nbsp; Yes?&nbsp; That&#8217;s the &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That we met many times?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure what you mean by that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, that &#8212; well, you have discussed this; there is a plan in place.&nbsp; So, the question naturally is whether or not, at the end of the day, you&#8217;re accepting the fact or the possibility that the Taliban could indeed take over Afghanistan?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Brian, I, again, will refer you to intelligence assessments and the fact that the President asked for a cleared-eye assessment &#8212; a clear-eyed assessment at the beginning of this process.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And what I can convey to you clearly is why he made the decision.&nbsp; That&#8217;s also what he&#8217;ll be delivering an entire speech on &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; just this afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>Okay, we got to go on.&nbsp; Go ahead, Mike.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Again, Afghanistan.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You and I and a lot of the people in this room will remember early 2009, when the Vice President, you know, expressed his &#8212; his opposition to the way that that war was being conducted and his efforts to try to pull back then.&nbsp; He largely hasn&#8217;t changed his position over the time &#8212; if anything, gotten more opposed to it.<br><br>I guess, at the end of the day, does the President think this war was worth it?&nbsp; And will he tell the American people that today, whether he &#8212; what he thinks about the worth of having conducted this two-decade war?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what you can hear &#8212; what you&#8217;ll hear the President talk about today is one, of course, that he is proud of the men and women who served, and he is grateful to the sacrifices that have been made over the last 20 years.<br><br>He will also reiterate, as I&#8217;ve talked about a little bit, the fact that he believes the United States did what we went to Afghanistan to do: get the terrorists attacked &#8212; who attacked us on 9/11, deliver justice to Osama bin Laden, root out the terrorist threat so that Afghanistan can never be used as a base from which to attack the United States and our allies.<br><br>And he also will talk about what he&#8217;s done &#8212; what we&#8217;ve done, as a country, to help prepare and assist and provide security assistance and humanitarian assistance to the military in Afghanistan, but also to the people of Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br><br>But we&#8217;ll &#8212; what you&#8217;ll also hear him say &#8212; which I think is important for the American people to hear &#8212; is that there would have been significant consequences had we chosen not to bring our troops home.&nbsp;<br><br>In April, if he had instead announced that the U.S. &#8212; the United States was going back on this agreement made &#8212; the U.S. and allied forces remaining in Afghanistan for the foreseeable future &#8212; the Taliban would have begun to target our forces.&nbsp; The status quo was not an option.&nbsp; Those are difficult decisions you make as Commander-in-Chief.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you are right.&nbsp; His view has been, for a decade or more consistently, that he does not feel this is a military &#8212; a war that can be won militarily.&nbsp;<br><br>He does still believe and support the people of Afghanistan, the future of the government of Afghanistan.&nbsp; He supports a political process &#8212; something that our ambassador is continuing to engage in.&nbsp; And he will continue to provide and advocate for providing &#8212; and he could make this decision as President &#8212; humanitarian and security assistance to the people there.&nbsp;<br><br>So it&#8217;s &#8212; this is not a speech that is going to give a grade.&nbsp; This is a speech that&#8217;s going to explain clearly to the American people why he made the decision, what the consequences would have been, what assistance we&#8217;re going to continue to provide, how we&#8217;re going to help the brave interpreters and translators who served alongside our forces, and also what the counterterrorism factors are here, including the changing threat from Afghanistan, but including the need to take our CT resources &#8212; counterterrorism resources &#8212; and put them in parts of the world where we have the largest threat.&nbsp;<br><br>That is no longer Afghanistan.&nbsp; That is other parts of the world, whether it is, Syria, Yemen, Somalia, North Africa.&nbsp; That is where al Qaeda and ISIS is greater, and that&#8217;s where, as Commander-in-Chief, he needs to put our resources.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; but fair to say he &#8212; fair to say that he thinks this should have been done a decade ago?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think his view has &#8212; is well publicly known.&nbsp; But again, he has made the decision because he is now President and he assessed what is in our national security interests.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, shifting gears to a different topic: A USA Today investigation published yesterday revealed that the FBI played a role in locating Princess Latifa of Dubai just before a yacht was raided in the Indian Ocean in 2018.&nbsp; The capture of the princess has outraged human rights activists, given the accounts that she was trying to flee her father&#8217;s oppressive rule.&nbsp;<br><br>Two questions: Was the FBI assistance appropriate?&nbsp; And does it raise concerns that the assistance, even if provided unwittingly, forced Latifa&#8217;s return to the family she sought to flee?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand your question.&nbsp; I&#8217;m certainly &#8212; I&#8217;m just not going to have anything to offer you from here, so I&#8217;d refer you to the FBI.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one other question.&nbsp; Multiple media outlets, including Politico and ABC, reported yesterday that the White House is seeking to have bi- &#8212; have the bipartisan infrastructure plan on the Senate floor as early as next week.&nbsp; Can you confirm that timeline as being the one sought by the White House right now?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, as Leader Schumer has said, he wants to move on both the bipartisan plan and the budget reconciliation resolution &#8212; or we&#8217;re now calling the Build Back Better plan &#8212; during the upcoming July/August Senate session.&nbsp;<br><br>So our understanding is that the process could begin as early as the week of July 19th, given that committees are still finalizing legislative text for both the budget resolution and the bipartisan bill.&nbsp; We, of course, support and would like to see it move forward as quickly as possible, but it would be a mistake to think of July 19th as anything more than the opening of a window, not a deadline.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; One, Al Sharpton said earlier this morning that he and other civil rights leaders would press President Biden to do more than just put boots on the ground for voting rights &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that he’d pushed for a legislative solution and one that works through or around the filibuster.&nbsp; What does the President plan to say in response?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well &#8212; well, we&#8217;ll wait for the meeting to take place and then they&#8217;ll come out to the stakeout.&nbsp;<br><br>But I will tell you the President agrees that a federal legislation is an important part of protecting voting rights and people&#8217;s right to vote, which is a fundamental right in this country.&nbsp; He agrees with that.&nbsp;<br><br>He also believes there&#8217;s a range of levers that can be used from the federal government concurrently and that he&#8217;s not going to wait either, even as federal legislation &#8212; even as we&#8217;re determining what the path forward looks like.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll see how the meeting goes, and certainly that will be the &#8212; a central topic.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House wonder that &#8212; worry that elevating voting rights to a Democratic issue &#8212; a Democratic platform issue will give Republicans more fodder to make partisan attacks against voting rights?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I could piggyback off Michael’s question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the benefit of hindsight, does the President feel that the war with Afghanistan was worth it?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I think it&#8217;s important for people to know &#8212; understand that as President of the United States, he&#8217;s not here to give grades.&nbsp; He&#8217;s here to provide context to the American people on why he made the decision he made to bring men and women home from serving; why it&#8217;s in our national interest, our counterterrorism interest, and the interest of our &#8212; of our positions around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>I understand why you all are asking the question, but I think this issue, the complexity of this issue over 20 years deserves more context than that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one quick follow-up.&nbsp; Will there or are there consequences for the Taliban in terms of just the encroachments that they have been making in the country?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Consequences from the United States?&nbsp; Well, I would say that right now what we&#8217;re supporting is a political process and one where we are hopeful that that can move forward to have a more lasting solution and bring peace and prosperity to the country over the long term.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so that means engaging with the Taliban as sort of (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, we have an ambassador who is engaging &#8212; or playing a role in these negotiations.&nbsp; Ultimately, it&#8217;s, of course, between the Afghans and members of the Taliban, but we are engaged and supportive of those political &#8212; that political process.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead, Nancy.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thanks.&nbsp; Shortly after the company DiDi was listed on the New York Stock Exchange, China blocked the app, resulting in it plummeting in value and American investors losing money.&nbsp; Does this concern the President?&nbsp; And more broadly, does the President agree that regulators should block companies that do not adhere to U.S. auditing regulations from IPOs?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to speak &#8212; comment on this specific company from here or speak to actions that could be taken independently by the SEC.&nbsp;<br><br>Broadly, the U.S. will continue to ensure we remain the destination of choice for investors and companies seeking investments around the world, and always protecting Americans’ data and our national security.&nbsp;<br><br>We do think it&#8217;s essential that all companies that list in the U.S. adhere to high standards of transparency and disclosure, and welcome companies that meet those standards.&nbsp;<br><br>But beyond that, I&#8217;m not going to have additional &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more question, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Nancy.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On COVID: When will the White House make a decision on reopening travel to certain nations?&nbsp; And what will it be based on?&nbsp; Will it be based on vaccine thresholds, or is there a certain country that you want to open travel to first?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, Nancy, there are working groups that are currently engaged and in touch about the criteria that will need to be met in order to reopen.&nbsp; We certainly understand and know that this is a point of frustration for a lot of people around the world, including people who are separated from their family members.&nbsp; And we put these working groups together so they could work together directly to assess what the criteria should be on when the travel can be reopened.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the United States now recognizing Claude Joseph as the leader of Haiti?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We recognize the democratic institutions of Haiti, and we are going to continue to work with them directly.&nbsp; But we have long call- &#8212; we have been calling for elections this year, and we support those proceeding.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think that those elections should be delayed from September?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We believe they should proceed this year.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President reached out to the interim prime minister?&nbsp; Has he reached out or does he plan to reach out?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any calls that &#8212; he has not reached out.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any calls to preview for you, no.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Rachel.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President’s reference to door-to-door campaigns for vaccines sparked kind of a backlash.&nbsp; You know, Missouri’s governor is saying he doesn&#8217;t want that.&nbsp; The Republican lawmakers saying, basically, “Stay off our lawns.”&nbsp; Can you say who is doing the door knocking and where?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me first say that this has been ongoing since April, and the best people to talk about vaccinations are local, trusted messengers: doctors, faith leaders, community leaders &#8212;<br><br>Do you have something, April, you want to share with the group?&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>So, those are the people who are the trusted messengers around the country.&nbsp; And we believe that we need to empower these individuals to continue to work in communities to make sure people know that these vaccines are safe, that they can save lives.&nbsp; And so these are grassroots voices across the country.&nbsp;<br><br>They are not members of the government.&nbsp; They are not federal government employees.&nbsp; They are volunteers.&nbsp; They are clergy.&nbsp; They are trusted voices in communities who are playing this role and door knocking.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is one of the tactics that we&#8217;ve used over the last couple of months, but we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; so, it&#8217;s not the only factor &#8212; but I would say that we&#8217;ve seen, in some states &#8212; Alabama: the adult vaccination rate increased by 3.9 percent; 149,000 additional adults got their first dose in June.</p>



<p>In Florida, the adult vaccination rate increased by 4.4 &#8212; 4.4 percent.&nbsp; In Georgia, the adult vaccination rate increased by 3.5 percent.&nbsp;<br><br>So, in our view, this is a &#8212; this is a way to engage and empower local activists, trusted members of the community.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the follow-up would be: Is it working? &nbsp;And who are &#8212; who are these volunteers reaching other than, say, shut-ins?&nbsp; Because people don&#8217;t even have to get off their couches to see who&#8217;s at their door these days.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s fair &#8212; depending on the technology in your house, I guess, I suppose.&nbsp; But I think what&#8217;s important for people to know &#8212; and I appreciate you asking the question &#8212; is that the federal government does not have a database of who&#8217;s been vaccinated.&nbsp; That is not our role.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t maintain a database along those lines, and we have no plans to.<br><br>We do know where there are rates of vaccination across the country, and we know &#8212; as I just listed in some of the data &#8212; that there are tactics that are powerful and impactful.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I will say, the thing that is a bit frustrating to us is that when &#8212; when people are critical of these tactics, it&#8217;s really a disservice to the country and to the doctors, faith leaders, community leaders, and others who are working to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; This is about saving lives and ending this pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was that me?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead, Yamiche.&nbsp; Yeah, go ahead.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; And then I’ll go to you, right in front of her.&nbsp; Go ahead, Yamiche.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So my &#8212; I have two questions.&nbsp; The first is: You’ve said over and over again that the United States believes elections should happen in Haiti this year.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; People in Haiti are so scared they can&#8217;t leave their homes; they can&#8217;t go to the grocery store.&nbsp; How does the United States think elections can happen when people are too afraid to even go to their front doors?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Yamiche, first, we understand and see the trauma that obviously the horrific killing of just thirty- &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s happening for months.&nbsp; So, yes?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand that.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t say anything otherwise.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m saying what&#8217;s happened over the last 36 hours.&nbsp; We, again, stand ready to provide support, provide assistance in any way that is formally requested by the government there.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re &#8212; we’re looking forward to hearing from them on what they would request and how we can help them through this period of time.&nbsp; And we called for an election this year &#8212; or we&#8217;re continuing to call for one because we feel that supporting democratic institutions, the democratic process, is something that would be in the interest of the people of Haiti.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re advocating for it.&nbsp;<br><br>We stand by to provide assistance, to provide help in any way possible, as we long have, even before yesterday.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the people of Haiti, including human rights activists, clergy members on the ground, they&#8217;ve been saying over and over again for months now that elections aren&#8217;t possible.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve talked to people specifically who say that they&#8217;re disappointed in the President’s stance on Haiti, that they see him as continuing failed policies that go back to his predecessor, former President Trump.&nbsp;<br><br>What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s response to Haitians who say they are disappointed in him and they don&#8217;t think that he&#8217;s really listening to their cries, which are saying that elections cannot happen?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that the message to the people of Haiti is: We stand with you.&nbsp; We want to provide assistance, whether that is assistance requested by the government or assistance that is needed for the people of the country to prosper in the future.&nbsp; And that is the President&#8217;s view.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have to keep going.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, right now, on Haiti &#8212; right now &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll come back to you, I apologize.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, right now there are two politicians who are claiming, in Haiti, the role of prime minister: Claude Joseph and Ariel Henry.&nbsp; How does the U.S. think that this impasse should be resolved?&nbsp; And are you worried that it could lead to further instability?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, we continue to support Haiti&#8217;s democratic institutions.&nbsp; And we have been in touch with the acting prime minister, and we echo his call for calm.&nbsp; But I would again reiterate that&#8217;s one of the reasons we have called for elections this year, and we believe that they should proceed.&nbsp;<br><br>Of course, we are worried about and closely monitoring the security situation, the stability in Haiti, and understand that &#8212; even before yesterday, but certainly as a result of yesterday &#8212; that is even more of a concern for the people who are living in the country.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But right now, you are not backing any one of the two?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are calling &#8212; we support the institutions, and we are continuing to call for elections this year.<br><br>Go ahead, Monica.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on voting rights: The President indicated he may tour the nation and talk about that, give a major speech on the topic.&nbsp; That hasn&#8217;t happened yet.&nbsp; Should we expect it still to take place?&nbsp; Or what can you tell us about that?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, that the President felt it was important to meet directly with civil rights leaders and talk to them about how we can work together to continue to push for federal legislation, continue to use every lever in the federal government to make voting more accessible across the country.&nbsp;But certainly, he conveyed he wants to speak to the country about voting rights and how he&#8217;s going to address it moving forward.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have any scheduling updates for you today, but he certainly plans to continue &#8212; continues to plan to do that, I should say.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s still the plan.&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, I’m sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead, go ahead.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; There are hurt feelings among government officials in Taipei after the White House COVID team posted and then deleted a tweet that had an image of Taiwan&#8217;s flag along those of other nations getting vaccine doses from the United States.&nbsp; Was this tweet a mistake in the first place?&nbsp; And if not, then why was the tweet deleted?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, this was an honest mistake that was made by the team handling graphics and social media, and should not in any way be viewed as a shift in official U.S. policy.&nbsp; When we recognized the mistake, we removed the tweet.&nbsp; So we did exactly as you said.<br><br>We remain committed to our One-China Policy based on the Taiwan Relations Act, the three joint communiqués, and the six assurances.<br><br>Go ahead, in the middle.&nbsp; Go ahead, Eugene.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; It seems pretty clear on &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And you just got engaged, I think.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I did.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Random aside.&nbsp; But congratulations.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; We’re just a lot of news you can use in here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It seems pretty clear that, on voting rights, a legislative fix isn&#8217;t going to happen, right?&nbsp; Like, the Republicans have made it clear they&#8217;re probably not going to get on board; you&#8217;re not going to get 10 votes.&nbsp; And the President has talked about being open to filibuster reform if it&#8217;s used, kind of, too much.&nbsp; And, I guess, advocates keep asking us to ask you guys: What does that look like?&nbsp; Is there a time period?&nbsp; Because we&#8217;re &#8212; they feel like they&#8217;re running out of time, that they&#8217;re not seeing a lot of urgency on the President’s part.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say the President is meeting with civil rights leaders today because he feels there is urgency on determining how we can most effectively work together to move voting rights forward &#8212; access to voting rights, I guess I should say, forward.&nbsp;<br><br>And he&#8217;s an optimist by nature; otherwise, he wouldn&#8217;t be President of the United States.&nbsp; So he continues to believe that there should be a pathway forward for federal legislation.&nbsp; He did say, as you just quoted, he has made comments in that regard.&nbsp; And certainly obstruction and the fact that there is an unwillingness to move forward in making voting more accessible to people across the country is something that he&#8217;s mindful of and he believes and has said &#8212; and we have said before &#8212; could change the conversation in the Senate.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ll see what happens, but he will continue to press for federal legislation moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) one more.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, yeah, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ve talked to Reverend Sharpton quite a bit, and one thing that he is really interested in seeing and hearing from the President is a carve-out for voting rights and police reform for the filibuster.&nbsp; Is that something that the White House is going to be pushing for?&nbsp; Is the President calling Joe Manchin and other holdouts on filibuster reform?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President&#8217;s position hasn&#8217;t changed.&nbsp; We certainly understand the position of Reverend Sharpton and others.&nbsp; And the President, though, shares their desire, commitment, interest in moving forward on voting rights legislation and moving forward on initiatives across the country that can help make voting more accessible to people across the country.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure they will have a robust discussion today.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question about the executive order &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on non-compete mandates.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Businesses use those mandates because it helps protect their investment in employees; it also helps protect their intellectual property.&nbsp; So will there be any kind of carve-out or anything in this executive order to protect businesses?&nbsp; And what is the White House message to businesses that are concerned about this executive order?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m happy to follow up with our team and see if there&#8217;s anything specifically to your very good question.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say that the overarching objective with the executive order is to make sure the President is encouraging competition in industries around the country.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t sound right to most people that there are three shipping companies that are dominating the market, and upping and increasing costs for suppliers, small businesses, people across the country.&nbsp; That doesn&#8217;t sound right or fair, because it isn&#8217;t.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what the President is trying to address.<br><br>In terms of the specific carve-out you&#8217;re asking about, I&#8217;m happy to ask our team if there&#8217;s anything more.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just on voting rights: Vice President Harris, as we speak, is announcing a $25 million expansion of the DNC’s &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; “I Will Vote” initiative.&nbsp; This is just one of the examples that voter &#8212; that Democratic committees are launching in terms of voter protection.&nbsp; Can you speak about the White House&#8217;s collaboration with these committees on the strategy?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I referred specifically to the DNC because it&#8217;s most appropriate for them.&nbsp; I know the Vice President is making this speech to &#8212; but to outline the specific details given they’re the political arm here, so they can get into all the specific details.<br><br>But it&#8217;s just an example of how every lever of the Democratic Party and the federal government is working and looking for ways that we can make voting more accessible around the country.&nbsp; But they&#8217;d be the most appropriate entity to outline details.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is the White House specifically involved?&nbsp; Were they aware of this strategy?&nbsp; I mean, what was the collaboration between the two?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, we&#8217;re aware of it.&nbsp; But again, they&#8217;re the political arm, so they&#8217;re the most appropriate body to outline details.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Jen.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about the global tax negotiations.&nbsp; I know that Secretary Yellen is supposed to be in Italy tomorrow about it.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can the White House credibly guarantee to its counterparties in that agreement that you can get something through the Senate and the U.S. will actually be able to enact the legislation that the deal requires?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s something we&#8217;ve proposed and we&#8217;re going to continue to press on.&nbsp; And this agreement wouldn&#8217;t be the case &#8212; wouldn&#8217;t be happening without the leadership of the United States, of Secretary Yellen and others in the government.&nbsp; So certainly, it is very much our desire, our interest, and our commitment to deliver on that promise.&nbsp;<br><br>I think you&#8217;re going to have to gather in a moment here.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; One more.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; You may have seen yesterday the former President filed a class-action lawsuit against three social media companies, and one of the targets as part of that lawsuit is Section 230 of the Communications Decency Act.&nbsp; He would like to see that particular aspect of the law ruled unconstitutional.<br><br>In January of last year, Joe Biden, when he was running for President, spoke to the New York Times, and he said Section 230 should be revoked &#8212; revoked immediately.&nbsp; Does he stand by the comments that he made to the New York Times last year?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not spoken with him about Section 230.&nbsp; I remember those comments, and I remember the New York Times article.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to venture to do exactly that.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say that, as it relates to these lawsuits, it&#8217;s certainly a decision for the platforms to make.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s safe to say that the President spends a lot less time obsessing over social media than the former President.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, thank you, everyone.&nbsp; Happy birthday, Steve!<br><br>1:29 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework Creates Economic Opportunities for Rural America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/08/fact-sheet-bipartisan-infrastructure-framework-creates-economic-opportunities-for-rural-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 20:43:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, despite the fact that rural and Tribal communities across the country are asset-rich, they make up a disproportionate number of persistent poverty communities. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests in rural and Tribal communities, creating jobs in rural America and wealth that stays in rural America. The Framework delivers 100% broadband coverage, rebuilds crumbling infrastructure&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, despite the fact that rural and Tribal communities across the country are asset-rich, they make up a disproportionate number of persistent poverty communities. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests in rural and Tribal communities, creating jobs in rural America and wealth that stays in rural America. The Framework delivers 100% broadband coverage, rebuilds crumbling infrastructure like roads and bridges, eliminates lead pipes and service lines, builds resilience to climate change and extreme weather events, and puts Americans to work cleaning up pollution that has impacted fossil fuel communities in rural America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to being the largest-long term investment in our infrastructure in nearly a century – four times the infrastructure investment in the 2009 Recovery Act – the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework is a generational investment in rural America.</p>



<p>Investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework to strengthen and create jobs in rural communities include:</p>



<p><strong>Provide high speed internet to every home. </strong>More than 35 percent of rural Americans and Tribal communities lack wired access to broadband at acceptable speeds. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Frameworkinvests $65 billion, including through USDA rural broadband programs, to make high-speed internet available to all Americans, bring down high-speed internet prices across the board, and provide technical assistance to communities seeking to expand broadband. With the 1936 Rural Electrification Act, the Federal government made a historic investment in bringing electricity to nearly every home and farm in America, and millions of families and our economy reaped the benefits. Broadband internet is the new electricity. It is necessary for Americans to do their jobs, to accelerate precision agriculture, to participate equally in school learning and health care, and to stay connected.<br><br><strong>Ensure clean drinking water in every home. </strong>Across the country, including in rural and Tribal communities, pipes and treatment plants are aging and polluted drinking water endanger public health. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests $55 billion in clean drinking water. It will replace 100 percent of the nation’s lead pipes and service lines, benefiting up to 10 million American households and 400,000 schools and child care centers. The Framework invests in water infrastructure across America, including in Tribal Nations and disadvantaged communities that need it most.</p>



<p><strong>Fix Rural Roads and Bridges. </strong>As part of a $110 billion investment to repair America’s crumbling infrastructure, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests in fixing 10,000 off-system bridges, many in rural areas, that provide critical linkages for communities to economic opportunity.</p>



<p><strong>Build Drought, Fire and Flood Resilience. </strong>Last year, the United States faced 22 extreme weather and climate-related disaster events with losses over $1 billion – a cumulative price tag of nearly $100 billion. These included damaging floods, fires, and wind storms across rural America. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests $52 billion to help communities build resilience to wildfires and floods through investments in forest management and upgrades to critical infrastructure &#8212; such as elevating buildings, roads, and bridges, hardening physical infrastructure, and winterizing the power grid. And, it will fund state and local infrastructure improvements and emergency response strategies, such as planning grants to support the development of evacuation routes or upgrades community shelters.</p>



<p>The Framework also helps Western farmers, ranchers, Tribes, families, and communities better prepare for future droughts. It invests in ecosystem restoration, such as the restoration of wetlands that can reduce flood risk for communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Plug Orphan Wells, Clean Up Abandoned Mines, and Remediate Idle Rural Property. </strong>In rural and Tribal communities around the country, former industrial and energy sites are now idle and sources of blight and pollution. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework provides the full American Jobs Plan funding level &#8212; $21 billion – to create good-paying union jobs plugging orphan oil and gas wells, cleaning up abandoned mines, and remediating Brownfield and Superfund sites in rural areas and on Tribal lands. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework will create jobs and build wealth in communities across the country that powered our economic growth for decades and have been affected most by the impacts of climate change and pollution, including rural communities and communities of color.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Connect Rural Communities Through Rail. </strong>U.S. passenger rail lags behind the rest of the world in reliability, speed, and coverage. China already has 22,000 miles of high-speed rail, and is planning to double that by 2035. The lack of rail options affects rural communities in particular. This the largest investment in passenger rail since the creation of Amtrak 50 years ago. The Framework invests $66 billion in passenger and freight rail, including to bring world-class rail service to areas outside the northeast and mid-Atlantic.</p>



<p><strong>Build and Upgrade Airports, Ports, and Waterways in Rural America. </strong>While the United States pioneered the modern aviation industry, today, U.S. airports lag far behind and many rural airports need repair.&nbsp; Only 9 percent of roads outside ports are in good or very good condition and the American Society of Civil Engineers gives America’s Inland Waterways infrastructure a D+. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework meets this challenge by investing $16.3 billion in port infrastructure and $25 billion in airports to address repair and maintenance backlogs, reduce congestion and emissions near ports and airports, and drive electrification and other low-carbon technologies. Modern, resilient, and sustainable port, airport, and freight infrastructure will help American farmers and ranchers sell their goods around the nation and world by removing bottlenecks and expediting commerce and reduce the environmental impact on neighboring communities.</p>



<p><strong>Build Electric Transmission Infrastructure in Rural America. </strong>Power outages cost the U.S. economy up to $70 billion annually. For example, the recent Texas power outages caused estimated losses of up to $90 billion for the state. At times, rural communities can be without power for days during these outages. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework meets this challenge by making the single largest investment in transmission in American history.&nbsp; It creates a Grid Development Authority at the Department of Energy to enable a national, clean energy power grid and funds to support activities that reduce the impacts to the electric grid and communities from extreme weather, wildfire, and natural disasters. It deploys long distance, high voltage transmission to enhance reliability and resilience, lower costs, and integrate the highest value clean energy resources. It invests in research and development for advanced transmission and electricity distribution technologies, and smart grid technologies that deliver flexibility and resilience. And, it invests more than $22 billion in demonstration projects and research hubs for next generation technologies like advanced nuclear reactors, carbon capture for industrial plants, and green hydrogen.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joe Biden Appoints Nine Members to President’s Council of Governors</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/08/president-joe-biden-appoints-nine-members-to-presidents-council-of-governors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 19:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden appointed nine governors as members of the Council of Governors for two-year terms. The bipartisan Council of Governors serves as the lead forum to strengthen partnerships between the Federal government and State governments to better protect our nation from threats to our homeland security and all types of hazards. The Council focuses&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden appointed nine governors as members of the Council of Governors for two-year terms. The bipartisan Council of Governors serves as the lead forum to strengthen partnerships between the Federal government and State governments to better protect our nation from threats to our homeland security and all types of hazards. The Council focuses on matters of homeland security; homeland defense; civil support; synchronization and integration of state and Federal military activities in the United States; and other matters of mutual interest, including those involving the National Guard. Federal-state cooperation is critical to protecting communities given the evolving challenges and threats facing our country, which range from extreme weather to domestic and international terrorism to a global pandemic. The Council of Governors will closely coordinate with the Biden-Harris administration to bolster preparedness, resilience and response on behalf of all Americans in times of need.<br><br>The Council includes leaders across the Federal government: the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security, the Deputy Assistant to the President for Intergovernmental Affairs, the Commander of U.S. Northern Command, the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Homeland Defense and Global Security, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, and the Chief of the National Guard Bureau. Other key Federal officials such as the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) are regular participants.<br><br><strong>President’s Council of Governors:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Minnesota Governor Tim Walz, Co-Chair</li><li>Ohio Governor Mike DeWine, Co-Chair</li><li>Delaware Governor John Carney</li><li>Louisiana Governor John Bel Edwards</li><li>Michigan Governor Gretchen Whitmer</li><li>Oregon Governor Kate Brown</li><li>Utah Governor Spencer Cox</li><li>Vermont Governor Phil Scott</li><li>Wyoming Governor Mark Gordon</li></ul>



<p>The nine Governors will join Tennessee Governor Bill Lee on the council. Governor Lee’s term expires in 2022.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Transnational Criminal Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/07/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-transnational-criminal-organizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:59:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations declared in Executive Order 13581 of July&nbsp;24, 2011, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13863 of March 15, 2019, is to continue in effect beyond July 24, 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The activities of significant transnational criminal organizations have reached such scope and gravity that they threaten the stability of international political and economic systems.&nbsp; Such organizations are becoming increasingly sophisticated and dangerous to the United States; they are increasingly entrenched in the operations of foreign governments and the international financial system, thereby weakening democratic institutions, degrading the rule of law, and undermining economic markets.&nbsp; These organizations facilitate and aggravate violent civil conflicts and increasingly facilitate the activities of other dangerous persons.</p>



<p>The activities of significant transnational criminal organizations continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.  For these reasons, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations declared in Executive Order 13581, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13863.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Transnational Criminal Organizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/07/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-transnational-criminal-organizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 24, 2011, by Executive Order 13581, the President declared a national emergency with respect to transnational criminal organizations pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 24, 2011, by Executive Order 13581, the President declared a national emergency with respect to transnational criminal organizations pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States constituted by the activities of significant transnational criminal organizations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On March 15, 2019, by Executive Order 13863, the President took additional steps to deal with the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations in view of the evolution of these organizations as well as the increasing sophistication of their activities, which threaten international political and economic systems and pose a direct threat to the safety and welfare of the United States and its citizens, and given the ability of these organizations to derive revenue through widespread illegal conduct, including acts of violence and abuse that exhibit a wanton disregard for human life as well as many other crimes enriching and empowering these organizations.</p>



<p>The activities of significant transnational criminal organizations continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of&nbsp;the United States.&nbsp; For these reasons, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13581 of July 24, 2011, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13863 of March&nbsp;15, 2019, must continue in effect beyond July 24, 2021.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1&nbsp;year the national emergency with respect to significant transnational criminal organizations declared in Executive Order 13581.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>July 7, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Hong Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/07/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-hong-kong/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 22:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.  In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the situation in Hong Kong declared in Executive Order 13936 of July 14, 2020, is to continue in effect beyond July 14, 2021. <br><br>The situation with respect to Hong Kong, including recent actions taken by the People&#8217;s Republic of China to fundamentally undermine Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat, which has its source in substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13936 with respect to the situation in Hong Kong. <br>                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,<br><br>JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
