<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 19:45:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by National Economic Council Director Brian Deese on One Year of Action and Progress on America’s Supply&#160;Chains</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/statement-by-national-economic-council-director-brian-deese-on-one-year-of-action-and-progress-on-americas-supply-chains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even as we engage and respond forcefully to the crisis unfolding in Ukraine, we are focused on the crucial work of advancing economic progress at home. Today, we received news confirming the strength and resilience of the American economy: GDP increased 7 percent in the fourth quarter of 2021 and the four-week average of weekly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Even as we engage and respond forcefully to the crisis unfolding in Ukraine, we are focused on the crucial work of advancing economic progress at home. Today, we received news confirming the strength and resilience of the American economy: GDP increased 7 percent in the fourth quarter of 2021 and the four-week average of weekly unemployment claims fell. &nbsp;A year ago, President Biden signed &nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/24/executive-order-on-americas-supply-chains/">Executive Order 14017</a> on <em>America’s Supply Chains, </em>launching <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Capstone-Report-Biden.pdf">a historic year of action and progress</a> to strengthen the resilience, security, and sustainability of America’s supply chains. These actions are contributing to a historic recovery in American manufacturing and industrial strength, helping to rebuild our supply chains here at home and make more here in America.</p>



<p>As the President has said: we have more work to do, to bring back manufacturing to the United States, to make things more affordable for consumers, and to strengthen the resilience of our supply chains. But we are making critical progress. The six industrial base reports released today are an important milestone, laying a strong foundation <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/the-biden-harris-plan-to-revitalize-american-manufacturing-and-secure-critical-supply-chains-in-2022/">upon which we can rebuild</a> America’s global leadership in technological development and manufacturing, and create new jobs and new businesses in communities across America.</p>



<p>To secure America’s supply chains and ensure the United States remains the most productive and innovative nation in the world, President Biden is urging Congress to pass a final version of comprehensive competitiveness legislation, building on USICA and the COMPETES Act.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Joined by Allies and Partners, the United&#160;States Imposes Devastating Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/fact-sheet-joined-by-allies-and-partners-the-united-states-imposes-devastating-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 19:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47800</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Russia to Face Massive Costs from its Isolation from the Global Financial and Trade System and Cutting-Edge Technology Today, the United States, along with Allies and partners, is imposing severe and immediate economic costs on Russia in response to Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine. Today’s actions include sweeping financial sanctions and stringent export controls&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em> Russia to Face Massive Costs from its Isolation from the Global Financial and Trade System and Cutting-Edge Technology</em></p>



<p>Today, the United States, along with Allies and partners, is imposing severe and immediate economic costs on Russia in response to Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine. Today’s actions include sweeping financial sanctions and stringent export controls that will have profound impact on Russia’s economy, financial system, and access to cutting-edge technology. The sanctions measures impose severe costs on Russia’s largest financial institutions and will further isolate Russia from the global financial system. With today’s financial sanctions, we have now targeted all ten of Russia’s largest financial institutions, including the imposition of full blocking and correspondent and payable-through account sanctions, and debt and equity restrictions, on institutions holding nearly 80% of Russian banking sector assets. The unprecedented export control measures will cut off more than half of Russia’s high-tech imports, restricting Russia’s access to vital technological inputs, atrophying its industrial base, and undercutting Russia’s strategic ambitions to exert influence on the world stage. The impact of these measures will be significantly magnified due to historical multilateral cooperation with a wide range of Allies and partners who are mirroring our actions, inhibiting Putin’s ambition to diversify Russia’s brittle, one-dimensional economy. The scale of Putin’s aggression and the threat it poses to the international order require a resolute response, and we will continue imposing severe costs if he does not change course.</p>



<p>Putin’s threatening actions and now his unprovoked aggression toward Ukraine are being met with an unprecedented level of multilateral cooperation. The United States welcomes the commitments by Australia, Canada, the European Union, Japan, and the United Kingdom that they will also take similarly forceful actions to hold Russia accountable – demonstrating the strength of our partnerships and deepening the impact on Russia more than any action we could have taken alone. This follows our joint action earlier this week to impose a first tranche of severe sanctions on Russia.</p>



<p>As a result of Putin’s war of choice, Russia will face immediate and intense pressure on its economy, and massive costs from its isolation from the global financial system, global trade, and cutting-edge technology. This includes cutting off Russia’s largest bank from the U.S. financial system – a significant blow to its ability to function and process global trade. It also includes full blocking sanctions on Russia’s second largest bank – freezing any of its assets touching the U.S. financial system. &nbsp;Russia’s ability to access global markets, attract investment, and utilize the U.S. dollar will be devastated.</p>



<p>Russia’s economy has already faced intensified pressure in recent weeks; just today its stock market sunk to its lowest level in four and a half years, and the ruble weakened beyond its weakest daily settlement price on record – before additional sanctions were even imposed. With these new stringent measures, these pressures will further accumulate and suppress Russia’s economic growth, increase its borrowing costs, raise inflation, intensify capital outflows, and erode its industrial base. The United States and our Allies and partners are unified and will continue to impose costs, forcing Putin to look to other countries that cannot replicate the financial and technology strengths of Western markets.<br>Today, the United States carried out the following actions:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Severing the connection to the U.S. financial system for Russia’s largest financial institution, Sberbank</strong>, including 25 subsidiaries, by imposing correspondent and payable-through account sanctions. This action will restrict Sberbank’s access to transactions made in the dollar. Sberbank is the largest bank in Russia, holds nearly one-third of the overall Russian banking sector’s assets, is heavily connected to the global financial system, and is systemically critical to the Russian financial system.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Full blocking sanctions on Russia’s second largest financial institution, VTB Bank (VTB)</strong>, including 20 subsidiaries. This action will freeze any of VTB’s assets touching the U.S financial system and prohibit U.S. persons from dealing with them. VTB holds nearly one-fifth of the overall Russian banking sector’s assets, is heavily exposed to the U.S. and western financial systems, and is systemically critical to the Russian financial system.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Full blocking sanctions on three other major Russian financial institutions</strong>: Bank Otkritie, Sovcombank OJSC, and Novikombank- and 34 subsidiaries. These sanctions freeze any of these institutions’ assets touching the U.S financial system and prohibit U.S. persons from dealing with them. These financial institutions play a significant a role in the Russian economy.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>New debt and equity restrictions on thirteen of the most critical major Russian enterprises and entities.&nbsp;</strong>This includes restrictions on all transactions in, provision of financing for, and other dealings in new debt of greater than 14 days maturity and new equity issued by thirteen Russian state-owned enterprises and entities:&nbsp; Sberbank, AlfaBank, Credit Bank of Moscow, Gazprombank, Russian Agricultural Bank, Gazprom, Gazprom Neft, Transneft, Rostelecom, RusHydro, Alrosa, Sovcomflot, and Russian Railways. These entities, including companies critical to the Russian economy with estimated assets of nearly $1.4 trillion, will not be able to raise money through the U.S. market — a key source of capital and revenue generation, which limits the Kremlin’s ability to raise money for its activity.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Additional full blocking sanctions on Russian elites and their family members: Sergei Ivanov (and his son, Sergei), Andrey Patrushev (and his son Nikolai), Igor Sechin (and his son Ivan), Andrey Puchkov, Yuriy Solviev (and two real estate companies he owns), Galina Ulyutina, and Alexander Vedyakhin.</strong>&nbsp;This action includes individuals who have enriched themselves at the expense of the Russian state, and have elevated their family members into some of the highest position of powers in the country. It also includes financial figures who sit atop Russia’s largest financial institutions and are responsible for providing the resources necessary to support Putin’s invasion of Ukraine. This action follows up on yesterday’s action targeting Russian elites and their family members and cuts them off from the U.S. financial system, freezes any assets they hold in the United States and blocks their travel to the United States.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Costs on Belarus for supporting a further invasion of Ukraine</strong>&nbsp;by sanctioning 24 Belarusian individuals and entities, including targeting Belarus’ military and financial capabilities by sanctioning two significant Belarusian state-owned banks, nine defense firms, and seven regime-connected official and elites. We call on Belarus to withdraw its support for Russian aggression in Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Sweeping restrictions on Russia’s military to strike a blow to Putin’s military and strategic ambitions. &nbsp;</strong>This includes measures against military end users, including the Russian Ministry of Defense<strong>.</strong>&nbsp;Exports of nearly all U.S. items and items produced in foreign countries using certain U.S.-origin software, technology, or equipment will be restricted to targeted military end users. These comprehensive restrictions apply to the Russian Ministry of Defense, including the Armed Forces of Russia, wherever located.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Russia-wide restrictions to choke off Russia’s import of technological goods critical to a diversified economy and Putin’s ability to project power.&nbsp;</strong>This includes Russia-wide denial of exports of sensitive technology, primarily targeting the Russian defense, aviation, and maritime sectors to cut off Russia’s access to cutting-edge technology<strong>.</strong>&nbsp;In addition to sweeping restrictions on the Russian-defense sector, the United States government will impose Russia-wide restrictions on sensitive U.S. technologies produced in foreign countries using U.S.-origin software, technology, or equipment. This includes Russia-wide restrictions on semiconductors, telecommunication, encryption security, lasers, sensors, navigation, avionics and maritime technologies. These severe and sustained controls will cut off Russia’s access to cutting edge technology.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Historical multilateral cooperation that serves as a force multiplier in restricting more than $50 billion in key inputs to Russia- impacting far more than that in Russia’s production.&nbsp;</strong>As a result of this multilateral coordination, we will provide an exemption for other countries that adopt equally stringent measures. Countries that adopt substantially similar export restrictions are exempted from new U.S. licensing requirements for items produced in their countries. The European Union, Australia, Japan, Canada, New Zealand and the United Kingdom, have already communicated their plans for parallel actions. This unprecedented coordination significantly expands the scope of restrictions on Russia. Further engagement with Allies and partners will continue to maximize the impact on Russia’s military capabilities.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with G7&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-bidens-meeting-with-g7-leaders-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 18:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President and G7 Leaders reaffirmed their resolve to respond swiftly to President Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified attack on Ukraine and expressed their solidarity with the people of Ukraine. The Leaders built on their months-long coordination and agreed to move forward on devastating packages of sanctions and other economic measures to hold Russia to account.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President and G7 Leaders reaffirmed their resolve to respond swiftly to President Putin’s unprovoked and unjustified attack on Ukraine and expressed their solidarity with the people of Ukraine. The Leaders built on their months-long coordination and agreed to move forward on devastating packages of sanctions and other economic measures to hold Russia to account. The G7 makes up the world’s leading democracies and 50% of the world’s economy—and the costs the G7 will impose together on Russia will be unprecedented. As a result of Putin’s choices, Russia will now face immediate and intense pressure on its economy and massive costs from its isolation from the global financial system, global trade, and cutting-edge technology. The Leaders also agreed to intensify ongoing efforts to mitigate any spillover effects from Russia’s actions and to secure stability in global energy markets. President Biden conveyed his thanks to German Chancellor Olaf Scholz for bringing all the Leaders together in this critical moment.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Biden-&#8288;Harris Plan to Revitalize American Manufacturing and Secure Critical Supply Chains in&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/the-biden-harris-plan-to-revitalize-american-manufacturing-and-secure-critical-supply-chains-in-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 14:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47774</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Release of Historic Industrial Base Reports by Seven Federal Agencies Caps Off a Year of Action Fortifying America’s Supply Chains One year ago, President Biden signed Executive Order 14017 directing an all-of-government approach to assessing vulnerabilities in – and strengthening the resilience of – the United States’ critical supply chains. Within six months of taking&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Release of Historic Industrial Base Reports by Seven Federal Agencies Caps Off a Year of Action Fortifying America’s Supply Chains</em></p>



<p>One year ago, President Biden signed <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/24/executive-order-on-americas-supply-chains/">Executive Order 14017</a> directing an all-of-government approach to assessing vulnerabilities in – and strengthening the resilience of – the United States’ critical supply chains. Within six months of taking office, the Administration completed a comprehensive review of the supply chains for four critical products, identified solutions to secure those supply chains against a wide range of risks and vulnerabilities, and established a first-of-its-kind Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force (SCDTF)&nbsp;&nbsp;to address the challenges arising from a pandemic-affected economic recovery.<br><br>These actions are contributing to a historic recovery in American manufacturing and industrial strength. During President Biden’s first year in office, the economy added 367,000 manufacturing jobs – the most in nearly 30 years – manufacturing as a share of U.S. Gross Domestic Product (GDP) returned to pre-pandemic levels, and companies have announced major new investments in American manufacturing. American ports also moved a record amount of cargo, and inflation-adjusted retail inventories – excluding autos – surged 5 percent in 2021 compared to the previous year, ensuring retailers’ shelves were fully stocked for a record-breaking holiday season. The progress made rebuilding American supply chains contributed to the fastest job growth in history, the fastest economic growth in nearly 40 years, and a faster recovery than every other country in the G7.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Today, on the one-year anniversary of President Biden’s executive order, seven cabinet agencies published reports identifying key weaknesses in some of the nation’s most crucial supply chains, and devising multi-year strategies to address those weaknesses. The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Capstone-Report-Biden.pdf">White House also published a capstone report</a> that provides an overview of the key actions the Biden-Harris Administration has taken over the past year to reduce the vulnerability of U.S. supply chains across a range of key sectors. And in the coming months, a number of federal departments and agencies, including the Department of Commerce and the Department of Labor (DOL), will host regional summits that will bring together stakeholders to discuss opportunities to align regional economic development strategies with the national supply chain strategy.<br><br>Links to agency reports:</p>



<ul><li><a href="https://media.defense.gov/2022/Feb/24/2002944158/-1/-1/1/DOD-EO-14017-REPORT-SECURING-DEFENSE-CRITICAL-SUPPLY-CHAINS.PDF">Department of Defense</a></li><li><a href="https://www.dhs.gov/publication/assessment-critical-supply-chains-supporting-us-ict-industry">Department of Homeland Security</a></li><li><a href="https://www.commerce.gov/sites/default/files/2022-02/Assessment-Critical-Supply-Chains-Supporting-US-ICT-Industry.pdf">Department of Commerce</a></li><li><a href="https://www.energy.gov/policy/securing-americas-clean-energy-supply-chain">Department of Energy</a></li><li><a href="https://www.ams.usda.gov/supply-chain">Department of Agriculture</a></li><li><a href="https://www.transportation.gov/supplychains">Department of Transportation</a></li><li><a href="https://aspr.hhs.gov/MCM/IBx/2022Report/Pages/default.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Department of Health and Human Services</a></li></ul>



<p>Building on the conclusions outlined in these reports, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing additional, concrete actions it will take this year to build long-term resilience across critical supply chains and formally institutionalize supply chain resilience throughout the Federal government. Central to this effort is implementing the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law (BIL), which is our nation’s most significant investment ever in modernizing the transportation systems on which our supply chains depend. Looking forward, with the historic investments included in the landmark America Creating Opportunities for Manufacturing, Pre-Eminence in Technology, and Economic Strength (COMPETES) Act, the United States Innovation and Competition Act (USICA), and President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda, these actions will strengthen our supply chains, grow domestic manufacturing, enhance our domestic workforce with a focus on good, union jobs, and help us outcompete China and the rest of the world. Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration will:<br><br><strong>Put the U.S. Economy on a Path Towards Long-Term Resilience Across Critical Supply Chains:<br></strong>Since his first day in office, President Biden has focused on an industrial strategy to address near-term disruptions linked to the global pandemic, revitalize our manufacturing base, strengthen critical supply chains, and position U.S. workers and businesses to compete and lead globally in the 21st century. To date, the SCDTF’s whole-of-government actions have contributed to a more than 70 percent decline in long-dwelling containers cluttering the docks at our two largest ports. Over $600 million in American Rescue Plan (ARP) resources have already been announced to strengthen the port workforce and improve facility efficiency at ports nationwide, from California and Florida to Massachusetts and Louisiana. These actions have also produced new supply chain partnerships between the automobile and semiconductor industries. And, they have helped secure $1 billion in ARP funding to expand meat processing capacity to promote competition and reduce prices for consumers. Because of the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to domestic industrial revitalization, American companies are also betting on the United States again. In just the last year, companies have announced nearly $200 billion in investments for semiconductor, electric vehicle, and battery manufacturing in the United States. But there is more work to do to build long-term resilience. In addition to working with Congress to enact the historic, bipartisan COMPETES/USICA legislation and the President’s Build Back Better Agenda, the Biden-Harris Administration will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Propose a new domestic manufacturing initiative through the Export-Import Bank to strengthen U.S. manufacturing exports. </strong>Too many American manufacturers – especially small- and medium-sized ones– struggle to obtain the financing they need to expand their operations and compete for global sales. As the official export credit agency of the United States, the Export-Import Bank (EXIM) is well positioned to address this issue, supporting jobs in America along the way. This Spring, EXIM’s board will vote on a new domestic initiative, including providing financing priority to environmentally beneficial, small business, and transformational export area transactions, including semiconductors, biotech and biomedical products, renewable energy, and energy storage. This initiative will help America win the future by revitalizing American manufacturing, improving the resiliency of our supply chains, and leveling the playing field for American companies competing in overseas markets.<br></li><li><strong>Expand access to capital for small manufacturers. </strong>Even before the COVID-19 pandemic, too many small businesses struggled to access the capital needed to grow and compete. Through new and existing programs at the Department of the Treasury and the Small Business Administration (SBA), the Biden-Harris Administration will unlock tens of billions of dollars for small manufacturers. Specifically, $10 billion in ARP funds deployed by the Treasury Department under the new and improved State Small Business Credit Initiative (SSBCI) will be leveraged into more than $70 billion in additional lending and investment for small businesses, including small manufacturers. Nearly a quarter of funding from the last round of SSBCI supported manufacturing companies. &nbsp;To ensure small manufacturers can access this program, the Treasury Department will convene state, local, territorial, and Tribal governments this Spring to share ideas and highlight best practices, building to a roundtable of elected officials and other stakeholders later this year to highlight accomplishments. SBA will also promote and prioritize licenses for Small Business Investment Companies (SBICs) committed to providing capital to domestic small business manufacturers. SBIC fund managers have financed over $14 billion in manufacturing-related businesses over the last decade, representing 24 percent of total dollars invested through the program during that period.<br></li><li><strong>Advance the technological leadership of both small and large manufacturers. </strong>U.S. technological leadership remains critical to building greater long-term resilience and global competitiveness, including innovations in manufacturing. The Administration will host a series of roundtables with the 16 Manufacturing USA institutes focused on scaling innovative technologies, promoting sector-based regional workforce initiatives, partnering with unions, and supporting small- and medium-sized suppliers, to develop specific proposals for how the institutes can strengthen our supply chains. SBA will also host the inaugural America’s Seed Fund Start-up Expo to support Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) awardees seeking to access resources and assistance they need to help them commercialize and manufacture innovative technologies addressing critical supply chain challenges. Additionally, SBA will establish a committee of industry leaders to advise on transformative inventions and innovations from U.S.-based startups and established small businesses, as well as vulnerabilities in commercializing and financing domestic innovation.<br></li><li><strong>Leverage the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to move critical goods from ships to shelves faster and more affordably. </strong>Outdated infrastructure and the COVID-19 pandemic have strained the capacity of the entire goods movement supply chain, resulting in unprecedented snarls in global freight and logistics supply chains. Recognizing the importance of port investments for U.S. competitiveness, President Biden’s BIL is the single largest Federal investment in our ports in U.S. history. The Department of Transportation (DOT) is announcing the opening of the $450 million Port Infrastructure Development Grant program, the first and only Federal grant program wholly dedicated to investments in port infrastructure. In the coming weeks, DOT will also release notices of funding opportunity for the BIL’s INFRA, MEGA, CRISI, and grade crossing grant programs, which will fund a diverse set of transportation infrastructure projects of regional and national significance, including those that support the movement of freight and improve supply chain resilience. And, DOT will develop and issue revised State Freight Plan Guidance that incorporates updated requirements from BIL and requires consideration of cargo flows, the impacts of e-commerce, and supply chain resilience in directing BIL funding.<br></li><li><strong>Invest in sustainable domestic production and processing of critical minerals</strong>. From rare earths in our electric motors and generators to the carbon fiber used for airplanes, the United States must ensure we are not dependent on foreign or single sources for critical minerals. To that end, this week the Biden-Harris Administration <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/fact-sheet-securing-a-made-in-america-supply-chain-for-critical-minerals/">announced plans</a> that will expand domestic rare earth processing; strengthen the National Defense Stockpile; <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-launches-interagency-working-group-mining-reform">update mining regulations</a> to ensure sustainable and responsible practices; and issue recommendations for <a href="https://www.doi.gov/sites/doi.gov/files/biden-harris-administration-fundamental-principles-for-domestic-mining-reform.pdf">comprehensive reform</a> of outdated mining laws. Through the BIL, the Department of Energy (DOE) will also demonstrate the feasibility of a full-scale integrated rare earth element extraction and separation facility and refinery from mine waste. Today, as part of the Mining Innovations for Negative Emissions Resources (MINER) Program, DOE is also releasing a $44 million funding opportunity to provide commercial-ready technologies that give the United States a net-zero or net negative emissions pathway toward increased domestic supplies of copper, nickel, lithium, cobalt, rare earth elements, and other critical elements required for a clean energy transition.&nbsp; These and other efforts to secure a reliable, sustainable, and diverse supply of critical minerals and materials will help the United States meet its climate goals while creating good paying jobs and boosting U.S. competitiveness.<br></li><li><strong>Leverage the American Rescue Plan to jumpstart a more competitive, innovative, and resilient meat and poultry supply chain. </strong>Over the last few decades, the meat and poultry processing sector has become dominated by a handful of large companies that control most of the business and most of the opportunities—raising prices and decreasing options for American families, while also squeezing out small businesses and entrepreneurs.&nbsp; To increase competition and create more options for producers and consumers, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) is taking the next steps outlined in its <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/03/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-action-plan-for-a-fairer-more-competitive-and-more-resilient-meat-and-poultry-supply-chain/">comprehensive action plan</a> to create a more diverse and resilient supply chain, supporting farmers, ranchers, and workers alike. This action plan includes dedicating $1 billion in American Rescue Plan funds to expand independent processing capacity. At a press conference this morning, USDA will announce the opening of applications for the first tranche of grants for new processing capacity and detail a partnership with DOL’s Goods Jobs Initiative to support the food processing workforce. &nbsp;In the weeks ahead, USDA will also announce $10 million in technical assistance funding to establish an initial network, with additional efforts to follow, for a total of $25 million for technical assistance. Through that partnership, the agencies will improve workers’ access to information about their rights, engage with employers to improve job quality and workforce pathways, support workforce development such as Registered Apprenticeships, and provide technical assistance on grants, contracts, and other investments intended to improve job quality.&nbsp;<br></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Institutionalize Supply Chain Resilience Throughout the Federal Government:</u></strong><br>Supply chain resilience must become a lasting focus for businesses and governments alike. In addition to the SCDTF, which has broken down silos and coordinated collaboration between agencies to respond to supply chain disruptions, the Administration has begun to formally institutionalize supply chain resilience throughout the Federal government. Earlier this month, DOE announced an internal realignment to effectively deploy more than $60 billion in BIL funding for clean energy infrastructure and deployment. The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) announced a new dedicated public health industrial base expansion and supply chain management office. And, as highlighted above, DOT will now work with states to include supply chain resilience in their State Freight Plans, so that state-led infrastructure planning and investments bolster the resilience of the entire goods movement chain – across ports, trucking, rail, and warehousing. To build on this progress, the Administration is announcing new actions to institutionalize supply chain resilience throughout the Federal government. Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Bolster the American manufacturing of critical goods through new reforms under the Buy American Act. </strong>President Biden believes that when the U.S. government spends Federal dollars, it should buy American-made products. During his first week in office he issued Executive Order 14005 to close loopholes and raise standards in the Buy American rules that govern Federal contracts. The White House Office of Management and Budget will soon issue a new Buy American rule that will create a new category of critical products that will be eligible for enhanced price preferences. By allowing the Federal government to pay an additional premium for critical domestic-made products and components essential to the Administration’s supply chain resiliency strategy, the new rule will create a steady source of demand that will help catalyze domestic production and bolster thin supply chains. Once implemented, American manufacturers will have an easier time securing the government contracts they need to expand their operations and create good-paying jobs.<br></li><li><strong>Fully establish a Defense Production Act Investment Program to build and expand the health resources industrial base. </strong>The United States remains critically dependent on imports for a range of key pharmaceutical products and active pharmaceutical ingredients—the primary ingredients of generic drugs. During the pandemic, HHS established a Defense Production Act (DPA) office to ensure supply chain scarcity and shortages did not impede national efforts to combat COVID-19. Now, HHS will fully establish a DPA Title III Program to provide loans, grants, and other financing to build and expand the health resources industrial base. This program will ensure timely availability of essential domestic industrial resources; establish the necessary authorities and mechanisms to leverage the proposed Supply Chain Resilience and Crisis Response Office for management of the Public Health Industrial Base; support extended long-term contracts, on-hand inventory, and vendor-managed inventory; and ensure sufficient manufacturing capacity.<br></li><li><strong>Bolster clean energy manufacturing through implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. </strong>As part of the first ever Energy Sector Industrial Base strategy<em>, America’s Strategy to Secure the Supply Chain for a Robust Clean Energy Transition</em>, DOE is executing dozens of lines of work to accelerate domestic clean energy manufacturing. These include creating a new Manufacturing and Energy Supply Chains Office to strengthen and secure the energy supply chains needed to modernize the nation’s energy infrastructure and support the clean energy transition. Amongst many other activities, DOE is establishing four Regional Clean Hydrogen Hubs and supporting the electric-vehicle battery materials supply chain. And today, as part of the Mining Innovations for Negative Emissions Resource Recovery (MINER) Program, DOE is releasing a $44 million funding opportunity to provide commercial-ready technologies that give the United States a net-zero or net negative emissions pathway toward increased domestic supplies of copper, nickel, lithium, cobalt, rare earth elements, and other critical elements required for a clean energy transition.<br></li><li><strong>Restore U.S. global leadership on supply chains. </strong>&nbsp;President Biden is committed to working with U.S. trading partners to address the immediate supply chain challenges from this unprecedented economic recovery and building long-term supply chain resilience for the future. Later this year, the Biden-Harris Administration will host a Ministerial-level Summit on Global Supply Chain Resilience to address near-term bottlenecks and tackle long-term challenges, building on the Summit on Global Supply Chain Resilience that President Biden held in October with the European Union and over a dozen like-minded countries. The Biden-Harris Administration will also partner with North American trading partners to prepare for future crises and mitigate resulting supply chain disruptions. Through the U.S.-Mexico High-Level Economic Dialogue, the United States and Mexico will establish a joint list of critical sectors involved in cross-border supply chains and create procedures to maintain continuity of supply chains in the event of times of crisis. The Competitiveness Committee of the U.S.-Mexico-Canada Agreement will also work to define essential industries and effective approaches for supply chains, including through information-sharing activities, providing advice and recommendations, identifying priority projects and policies, and designating a contact point for these efforts. And, as agreed to at the North American Leaders Summit in November, the United States, Mexico, and Canada will hold a trilateral supply chain coordination meeting by Summer 2022 to explore trilateral opportunities on supply chains based on results from the bilateral supply chain working groups.</li></ul>



<p>There is still more to be done. To build on these investments and spur more private-sector investment in the United States, the President is committed to passing comprehensive competitiveness legislation like the COMPETES/USICA bills put forward in the House and the Senate to strengthen our supply chains, grow domestic manufacturing, and help us outcompete China and the rest of the world. This legislation, combined with the critical investments included in the Build Back Better Act, will help to deliver on the President’s mission to expand the productive capacity of our economy and lower costs for families.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Phone Call with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-phone-call-with-president-volodymyr-zelenskyy-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 05:09:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Zelenskyy reached out to me tonight and we just finished speaking. I condemned this unprovoked and unjustified attack by Russian military forces. I briefed him on the steps we are taking to rally international condemnation, including tonight at the United Nations Security Council. He asked me to call on the leaders of the world to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Zelenskyy reached out to me tonight and we just finished speaking. I condemned this unprovoked and unjustified attack by Russian military forces. I briefed him on the steps we are taking to rally international condemnation, including tonight at the United Nations Security Council. He asked me to call on the leaders of the world to speak out clearly against President Putin’s flagrant aggression, and to stand with the people of Ukraine. Tomorrow, I will be meeting with the Leaders of the G7, and the United States and our Allies and partners will be imposing severe sanctions on Russia. We will continue to provide support and assistance to Ukraine and the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Russia’s Unprovoked and Unjustified Attack on&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/23/statement-by-president-biden-on-russias-unprovoked-and-unjustified-attack-on-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 03:24:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The prayers of the entire world are with the people of Ukraine tonight as they suffer an unprovoked and unjustified attack by Russian military forces. President Putin has chosen a premeditated war that will bring a catastrophic loss of life and human suffering. Russia alone is responsible for the death and destruction this attack will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The prayers of the entire world are with the people of Ukraine tonight as they suffer an unprovoked and unjustified attack by Russian military forces. President Putin has chosen a premeditated war that will bring a catastrophic loss of life and human suffering. Russia alone is responsible for the death and destruction this attack will bring, and the United States and its Allies and partners will respond in a united and decisive way. The world will hold Russia accountable.</p>



<p>I will be monitoring the situation from the White House this evening and will continue to get regular updates from my national security team. Tomorrow, I will meet with my G7 counterparts in the morning and then speak to the American people to announce the further consequences the United States and our Allies and partners will impose on Russia for this needless act of aggression against Ukraine and global peace and security. We will also coordinate with our NATO Allies to ensure a strong, united response that deters any aggression against the Alliance. Tonight, Jill and I are praying for the brave and proud people of Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before a Meeting with the National Black Caucus of State&#160;Legislators</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/23/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-a-meeting-with-the-national-black-caucus-of-state-legislators/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 02:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47760</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President’s Ceremonial OfficeEisenhower Executive Office 5:00 P.M. EST THE VICE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m meeting this afternoon with the National Black Caucus of State Legislators.  I have met with them before.  They are extraordinary leaders in their states and national leaders.  And we have many important topics to discuss.  But before I address what we will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President’s Ceremonial Office<br><em>Eisenhower Executive Office</em></em></p>



<p>5:00 P.M. EST<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m meeting this afternoon with the National Black Caucus of State Legislators.  I have met with them before.  They are extraordinary leaders in their states and national leaders.  And we have many important topics to discuss. <br><br>But before I address what we will discuss this afternoon, I want to thank President Billy Mitchell for your leadership, and President-Elect Laura Hall.  It is my great honor to be with you and to do the work that I know we will continue to do together.<br><br>As I said when I addressed your annual leadership council, you all are on the ground doing extraordinary work during very difficult times, in particular over the last two years, and you continue to persevere and to show us what we are capable of when we know what is possible.<br><br>I do want to take a moment to address two key issues that I know are at top of mind for &#8212; for many people: That&#8217;s the issue of Ukraine and also the Supreme Court. <br><br>On the issue of Ukraine, as we know, we have imposed significant costs in response to Russia&#8217;s reinvasion of Ukraine.  And we are working closely with our Allies and our partners in that regard.<br><br>The threat of a full-scale attack on Ukraine remains.  And so we will remain vigilant in watching what is happening there and in close coordination with our Allies and our partners around the world. <br><br>If Russia goes further, we will impose more costs, which will continue to be swift and severe.<br><br>On the issue of the Supreme Court of the United States, the President of the United States will announce soon a most eminently qualified, extraordinary lawyer and jurist who will have a record of excellence and who will happen to be a Black woman to be the next justice on the United States Supreme Court.  And she will be, without any question &#8212; (applause) &#8212; without any question, she will be the first, but not the last.<br><br>So, with that, let me say to this august group of leaders that I fully appreciate &#8212; the President sends his greetings &#8212; for all the work that you do every day.<br><br>One of the areas that I know you are focused on and have been is the issue of voting rights.  And so that&#8217;s a subject that I&#8217;ll address briefly, and then we can discuss about in more detail. <br><br>As we know, we are, at this moment, faced with probably an unprecedented fight to preserve and protect the right for all people who are eligible to vote to be able to vote unencumbered. <br><br>We are also looking at an unprecedented assault on the freedom to vote in our country.  In many of your states, we have seen legislation that has been passed or is attempted to be passed that will have as its, I believe, direct intention the goal of making it more difficult for people to vote &#8212; with the hope and expectation that when it is more difficult for people to vote, people won&#8217;t vote.<br><br>So, it is our collective responsibility to do everything we can to ensure that those laws are not passed and that we speak using the full voice given to us through the bully pulpit we have to let folks know that they have a right and that we will fight for that right for all eligible voters to be able to vote.<br><br>We, of course, here in Washington, D.C., have fought &#8211;through our administration and along with many of the leaders here &#8212; to pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act and the Freedom to Vote Act. <br><br>Sadly and unfortunately, there were not the majority of legislators who had the ability to pass that legislation present to weigh in.  But we are not going to give up, because we fully realize that if we are to comprehensively address this issue, we need federal legislation.<br><br>That being said, there is still work to do at the state level, and that is where your leadership kicks in, in a very fundamental and a very important way. <br><br>And so, I look forward to our conversation and the work we will do together. <br><br>I will tell you as a point of privilege, last night I was speaking with the president of the National Baptist Association, the convention, Reverend Jerry Young.  And Reverend Young said to me, “Well, you know, I&#8217;ve got a saying.”  He said &#8212; and I told him that I was going to share with you what he said.  And his saying is, “No vote, no voice, your choice.”  (Laughter.)<br><br>And that is a message that he is sharing through the National Baptist Convention and through his role of leadership.  And I shared with him that &#8212; that some of us may echo that &#8212; that same message.  <br><br>But with that, I want to thank again the National Black Caucus of State Legislators for your work, for this visit, and for the work we will continue to do together.  <br><br>So, thank you and welcome.  Thank you.  Thank you.<br><br>5:06 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 23,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/23/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-23-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 01:23:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:33 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Wednesday.&#160; Are we Wednesday?&#160; Yes.&#160; Okay.&#160; We have a graphic here today because it&#8217;s been awhile since we&#8217;ve had a graphic, so I wanted to deliver on that.&#160; So, as you all know, we announced our first tranche of sanctions in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:33 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Wednesday.&nbsp; Are we Wednesday?&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We have a graphic here today because it&#8217;s been awhile since we&#8217;ve had a graphic, so I wanted to deliver on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as you all know, we announced our first tranche of sanctions in less &#8212; less than a day after the beginning of the invasion, with Allies and partners from the European Union, the United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, and Australia.</p>



<p>And what I &#8212; we wanted to provide to all of you today is an overview of what we&#8217;re seeing as an impact on the Russian economy.&nbsp; Obviously, the bite of these sanctions has not taken place yet, so this is largely in anticipation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let me just go through a couple of these points:</p>



<p>Borrowing costs for the Russian government has spiked to almost 11 percent &#8212; highest since 2015.</p>



<p>Foreign investors are fleeing Russia.</p>



<p>The Ruble is trading at its weakest level since November 2020 &#8212; one of the weakest currencies in the world.</p>



<p>In response to inflation risk, the Russian Central Bank has hiked rates eight times in the past year to 9.5 percent.</p>



<p>And Bloomberg reported &#8212; just going to cite Bloomberg there &#8212; that “The fortunes of Russia’s super-rich have tumbled $32 billion this year, with the escalating conflict in Ukraine poised to make that wealth destruction much larger.”</p>



<p>So, as I started off saying, this is before the bite even takes place.  And this is just after the beginning.  I mean, we&#8217;ve only had, obviously, a first tranche here.  But it&#8217;s &#8212; this is a vicious feedback loop that will get more severe if Putin doesn’t <s>escalate</s> [deescalate]. </p>



<p>So, as he&#8217;s looking at the impact on his own economy, on his rich and wealthy oligarch friends, and on the people of Russia, these are the facts, regardless of what you&#8217;re hearing from the Kremlin, about the impact.</p>



<p>Also, I just wanted to note, because I know that we put out these sanctions when a lot was happening yesterday &#8212; just wanted to give you a little bit more detail of them.&nbsp; Obviously, you, hopefully, have seen the announcement and the statement from the President about Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; We can come back to that, but that is an additional step today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, on banks and the announcement we made yesterday, what we did was we used our most powerful sanctions tool to target two major state-owned Russian banks for the first time; that is the significance.&nbsp; These banks can no longer &#8212; what it means is they can no longer make any transactions with the United States or Europe, and their assets in the financial system will be frozen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They are the glorified piggybanks &#8212; some of the glorified piggybanks for the Kremlin, including one of them which is a key financial institution where &#8212; where support &#8212; military finances has been held.&nbsp; And this will have a significant impact on Russian leadership and the inner circle because they&#8217;re state-owned control &#8212; banks controlled by them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also were clear yesterday &#8212; but again, there was a lot going on, so I just wanted to touch on this &#8212; on this lightly &#8212; that no financial institution is safe.&nbsp; And the authority that was announced yesterday means that we can expand this to other financial institutions in Russia.&nbsp; And we have every capability and capacity to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, we made an announcement about sovereign debt.&nbsp; And essentially, this means &#8212; I know there&#8217;s been a lot of &#8212; some commentary out there &#8212; some from Russia, of course &#8212; that they have a rainy-day fund.&nbsp; A rainy-day fund is limited.&nbsp; A rainy-day funds mean you can only tap into it until the rainy-day fund is done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ability to purchase sovereign debt means that you can gain access to additional funding.&nbsp; And what we are essentially doing is cutting off their ability to &#8212; to tap into that from the United States and Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, on elites, what is significant about this &#8212; and somebody asked me this question about what&#8217;s different.&nbsp; So, some of the people who were sanctioned yesterday are repeat people that we have sanctioned in the past.&nbsp; But the additional step we took was that we sanctioned family members, because what we&#8217;ve seen in terms of tactics that they&#8217;ve used in the past, is they have moved &#8212; they&#8217;re very sophisticated, some of these oligarchs; no surprise &#8212; they&#8217;ve moved money around to children, to family members so they could still have access to it.&nbsp; And we wanted to reduce the likelihood of that.&nbsp; So that is an additional step we took.&nbsp; So I just wanted to cover that.</p>



<p>One other note: Today also marks 100 days since the President signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; Time flies.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also day 400 of the administration.&nbsp; In the past 100 days, we&#8217;ve hit the ground running, rolling out nearly $100 billion worth of programs and funding to state and local governments.</p>



<p>This funding will help rebuild crumbling road and bridges, replace lead pipes, help provide high-speed Internet to every family in America, and produce concrete results that change people’s lives for the better.</p>



<p>To continue this momentum, today, the Department of Transportation announced nearly $450 million available to strengthen port infrastructure and supply chain resiliency.&nbsp; And, obviously, there is more to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Chris, your first day in the AP seat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Welcome to the front of the room.&nbsp; No pressure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; So a few questions about Ukraine.&nbsp; First, you talked about the impact of the economy on Russia.&nbsp; Ukraine is also feeling a lot of economic pain right now.&nbsp; What more is the White House prepared to do to shore up their economy, provide them with financial assistance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have provided them an extensive amount of financial assistance, including recently announcing $1 billion in sovereign &#8212; I mean in loan guarantees.&nbsp; And that is something we are open to building upon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we are going to continue to assess what the impact is on the Ukrainian economy, what is needed on the ground.&nbsp; That applies to both access to &#8212; to, you know, economic assistance, as well as humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I don&#8217;t have anything to announce today, but we will continue to be a large provider and supporter of financial and economic assistance to Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A new AP poll found that only 26 percent of Americans want the U.S. to play a major role in this &#8212; in this crisis.&nbsp; Given that this could increase costs on Americans &#8212; gas prices, other economic ripples &#8212; has the White House done enough to prepare Americans for what the U.S. role could be and what impact it could be on their lives?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this is very important to the President personally.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why he gave remarks &#8212; delivered the remarks he did last week and why he has spoken several times to provide updates to the American people over the last couple of days.</p>



<p>Two pieces I would note that I think are very important as Americans are tuning in and learning more about this conf- &#8212; this potential conflict &#8212; this conflict that&#8217;s underway, I guess I should say, between Russia and Ukraine:</p>



<p>One, the President has no intention of sending U.S. military or U.S. troops to fight in Ukraine.&nbsp; It is hard to know &#8212; because I don&#8217;t think it was in your poll &#8212; how people assess what &#8220;major involvement&#8221; means.&nbsp; But that has not changed in terms of the President&#8217;s view and his approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second is he is going to do everything he can to reduce the impact on energy costs for the American people.&nbsp; And that means engaging closely with partners around the world.&nbsp; It means considering a range of options that are all on the table to reduce the market &#8212; the impact on the oil markets, and that is what would impact energy costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the last thing I would say is that the President and the White House &#8212; you know, we make national security decisions based on what&#8217;s best for our country&#8217;s national security, not on the latest polling.&nbsp; And if you step back, what, hopefully, the American people will see and have seen is that while Russia has sought to divide our allies and the American people, the President has sought to revitalize our partnerships and alliances and unite our country.&nbsp; He&#8217;s standing up for our national security interests and bedrock democratic values against the aggression of a dictator threatening to further invade a sovereign country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why he&#8217;s doing what he&#8217;s doing.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re less focused on the politics of Ukraine and more focused on preventing a war.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The other question &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; I have was: Yesterday, the administration said the goal of the sanctions is to “prevent and deter” a wider invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; If Russia does attack, as U.S. officials are warning that they&#8217;re imminently prepared to do, does that mean that strategy has failed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say as we look at it, we&#8217;re focused on accomplishing two things.&nbsp; One is implementing serious costs for the actions that have already been taken &#8212; so, the actions in the Donbas.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve taken steps beyond what we did in 2014, which, obviously, I just outlined at the beginning of the briefing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, yes, deterrence is part of our objective.&nbsp; If he goes further, we will go further.&nbsp; We have a range of tools at our disposal.&nbsp; I mentioned some of the potential financial step &#8212; or steps we could take that could impact financial institutions. &nbsp;That is &#8212; is very significant and could have a very significant impact, but we have far more options beyond that, including export controls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what export control steps would mean &#8212; you know, Russia &#8212; as President Putin looks to the future of Russia, there is a lot of access to different industries, technologies that he needs and would rely on in order for the economy to grow and flourish in the future, whether it&#8217;s AI, whether it&#8217;s other technological sectors, biotech, semiconductors &#8212; a term we&#8217;ve used a lot in here.&nbsp; And what this would do, would essentially cut off access to that; that would also be a significant step.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, point is: We have more steps we can take, and we&#8217;re going to continue to apply those if he escalates.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Given the possibility of an attack seems particularly high today, can you walk us through how the President is spending his day, how his security team is spending the day, if they&#8217;re doing anything in these &#8212; what could be these final hours before an attack, if that&#8217;s the case?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen the reporting on this.&nbsp; But let me &#8212; let me be very clear: We have been saying for days that Russian military forces are in an attack position; that has not changed.&nbsp; They are capable of operationalizing at any point in time.&nbsp; We are in constant contact with the Ukrainians about their positioning, about their capacity and capabilities.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not predicting a day, a moment, or an hour.&nbsp; That has been our assessment and the &#8212; what we&#8217;ve been communicating with the Ukrainians for some time now.</p>



<p>Let me tell you, though, something else that we&#8217;re also seeing or assessing right now: We believe &#8212; obviously, we&#8217;ve laid out a game plan that we believe that President Putin has been implementing over the course of the last several weeks, if not longer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s clear &#8212; and what our assessment is, is that President Putin did not expect the United States to have the level of information that we have, did not expect us to put out this amount of information that we have put out, did not expect the global community to be as unified, including in the &#8212; how unified the global community was in putting out the sanctions yesterday.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re seeing now &#8212; our assessment is that he is improvising, adapting, and we’re having to respond and adapt his own actions to &#8212; as we are even &#8212; as we are responding to him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we don&#8217;t have a new assessment.&nbsp; I will tell you that what the President is doing is what he has been doing for several days now, which is continuing to meet and engage with his national security team.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, he had a PDB this morning, and he will receive regular updates from his team.&nbsp; He will continue to engaze [sic] clo- &#8212; engage closely with partners and Allies, some things that he &#8212; something that he has been doing for several days now.&nbsp; But that is cont- &#8212; the continuation of what our engagement has been.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, given that we could be looking at an imminent attack, is there anything this White House, this President believes he can do to stop it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; what I &#8212; I think what&#8217;s important to note here is we have been saying &#8220;imminent&#8221; for days now.&nbsp; And what I&#8217;m conveying to you is that we&#8217;re also seeing adjustments by President Putin or the need to adapt in response to what our actions and what our response has been.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what the President has been doing has cont- &#8212; has been continuing to work with partners and Allies to ensure we remain united, to leave the door open to diplomacy, but to make very clear to President Putin and to our partners around the world that there will be significant consequences beyond what we have done already should he invade further.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, what&#8217;s the next trigger point for new sanctions?&nbsp; Obviously, yesterday&#8217;s was the start of the invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does Putin have to do next to see another wave?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to give you a detailed, &#8220;If he does this, we will do that.&#8221;&nbsp; I would only just reiterate what I said a little bit earlier, which is that we have the specific authority, based on the announcement made yesterday, to take additional steps as it relates to financial institutions in Russia.&nbsp; There&#8217;s additional enormous financial institutions &#8212; the two largest banks, for example &#8212; which were not a part of the announcement made &#8212; we made yesterday.&nbsp; There&#8217;s additional steps we&#8217;ve expressed an openness to, including taking steps as it relates to export controls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this &#8212; these are assessments we will continue to make internally.&nbsp; And we have a range of tools that we are prepared to &#8212; steps we are prepared to take should he further escalate.</p>



<p>Q    On Monday, when President Putin made clear that he was sending troops into those two breakaway regions, the White House initially said that does not constitute an invasion because Russia already has troops there; this is just &#8220;more overt.&#8221;  The next day, President Biden came out and said, “This is the start of invasion.”  What happened overnight?  What changed to lead to that change in rhetoric?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I talked about this a little bit yesterday, but what we looked at and what we assessed were a range of steps.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not, obviously, going to get into military assessments or movements today, just like I didn&#8217;t yesterday.&nbsp; But we looked at a couple of steps, including President Putin taking steps, as it relates to the Duma, to ask for authority to take additional military action beyond that region.&nbsp; We looked at his recognition.&nbsp; We looked at the position &#8212; positioning of troops and military.&nbsp; And we looked at the range of steps over that period of time to assess and make that decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would also note that our Deputy National Security Advisor was on TV conveying that that morning as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And just lastly on this: The President of Russia, President Putin, said on Monday that he felt the West was going to impose sanctions basically regardless of what they did.&nbsp; Given that, you&#8217;re obviously trying and effectively putting a lot of pain on the Russian economy.&nbsp; Do you think these sanctions will actually be a deterrent?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think that is a decision for President Putin to make.&nbsp; I mean, there are statements he has conveyed, in terms of what he wants to achieve here, right?&nbsp; The division of NATO; the opposite is happening.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; He wanted to see Nord Stream 2 move forward &#8212; a key prize for him; that is obviously not happening.&nbsp; He wants to have a flourishing economy for the Russian people; just even without the bite of our sanctions, that is clearly not happening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is an assessment he&#8217;s going to have to make, and we expect he’ll hear from people around him who are being impacted and other people in Russia about the impact of these sanctions.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House share the assessment of the Australian Prime Minister today that an attack is likely within 24 hours?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give an additional timeline to it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been saying it could happen at any time.&nbsp; And they are in attack position for some time now, but I&#8217;m not going to give you an additional day, hour, moment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, just to follow up on that, you have been saying that it&#8217;s imminent for some time.&nbsp; You guys stopped for a little bit &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and then you went back to it.&nbsp; Has there been a new warning to the Ukrainians in the last 24 hours or so?&nbsp; Because it seems that CNN and others are reporting that they have shared new intelligence about the threat of just how quickly an attack could happen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t know what that&#8217;s based on.&nbsp; We have been conveying &#8212; in close touch with the Ukrainians, we have been conveying that they are capable of operationalizing at any time.&nbsp; That has been the case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note that, obviously, our preference would be that President Putin doesn&#8217;t further invade.&nbsp; And as I said a few minutes ago, what we&#8217;re also assessing is that he has had to adjust, adapt to the strength of the unity of the global community, to what our reaction has been.&nbsp; And he has been forced to need to respond and adapt his own actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will see.&nbsp; We still very much anticipate and predict that he will invade further.&nbsp; But, again, we&#8217;re also seeing an impact on how he&#8217;s behaving.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on Nord Stream 2: Last month, the White House opposed an effort on Capitol Hill to put sanctions on this pipeline.&nbsp; Last year, of course, President Biden waived the sanctions on that.&nbsp; And now, today, he is imposing the sanctions on it, which is a pretty big shift.&nbsp; So, can you just explain the changes &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don’t &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and where you stand on that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t see it as a shift at all.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never supported the pipeline.&nbsp; It was 98 percent built when the President took office.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve always spoken out against the pipeline.&nbsp; The question was: What was the most effective step in order to have the result that we have now over the last 24 hours?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there were calls by some in Congress to do preemptive sanctions on &#8212; or earlier sanctions &#8212; or take earlier steps, I should say, on Nord Stream 2.&nbsp; We disagreed with that strategy.&nbsp; We worked through a diplomatic path with the Germans.&nbsp; You saw the German Chancellor make the announcement yesterday, and the announcement today was complementary to that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the change is just because you were waiting on the Germans to take the first step here.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, actually, it was that we felt a diplomatic approach would be the most effective pro- &#8212; approach, and we have succeeded in our efforts.&nbsp; And we didn&#8217;t think the alternative approach was the right one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My last question: A French official recently told the Wall Street Journal that during his last visit, the French President found Putin was &#8220;more rigid, isolated, and had basically gone into a sort of ideological and security-minded drift.&#8221;&nbsp; The President recently spent about an hour on the phone with him.&nbsp; Obviously, he knows Putin pretty well.&nbsp; I wonder if he has seen a change in the Russian leader.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any personal observations by President Biden about President Putin to read out.&nbsp; But I think we all watched, including the President, the speech &#8212; or read it &#8212; from the other night and saw a leader who was outlining a case for a war to his public &#8212; one that was based on revisionist history.&nbsp; And whether that&#8217;s based on isolation or not, we&#8217;ll leave that to others to assess.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; So you’ve said many times today that you &#8212; that there is not a new assessment.&nbsp; But yesterday, the President clearly chose his words carefully when he said the world was watching the start of an invasion, which is very different from the U.S. warning today that a full-scale Russian invasion is imminent.&nbsp; So, are you saying that nothing has changed between when we heard from the President yesterday and today?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m saying I don’t have &#8212; we have been saying for days that there has been &#8212; that they are prepared to launch a full-scale invasion.&nbsp; We saw the beginning of that yesterday.&nbsp; So, nothing has changed in that assessment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about the figure of 80 percent of Russian troops are now in the forward attack position?&nbsp; Was that also the case yesterday?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to be in a position to give you move- &#8212; troop assessments or movements.&nbsp; But as I said just a few minutes ago, we &#8212; they are in an attack position.&nbsp; That remains the case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then to follow up on something I asked Daleep yesterday, he said that the administration would not give a timeframe for when Americans might feel the impact of this conflict.&nbsp; Why not?&nbsp; I mean, the President has said we need to be honest about the cost of fighting for democracy.&nbsp; Can you share anything about a timeframe, a range?&nbsp; Should people be saving money?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, Weijia, there&#8217;s been a little confusion about this because, one, the announ- &#8212; the sanctions that we announced yesterday will not have an impact on the American people.&nbsp; They will have an impact on the Russian elite, on financial institutions, on individuals who are trying to use those institutions to engage in &#8212; with Western banks, including President Putin and his inner circle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re seeing in the market is an anticipation of a further invasion by President Putin.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re trying to do and focus on is take every step we can, working around the world with our counterparts and partners, to minimize the impact on the global energy market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re working on.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working on minimizing that, but there is not an impact from the sanctions we&#8217;ve announced on the American public.&nbsp; It really depends, in part, on what President Putin does in many regards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, is one of those options looking at releasing more oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is certainly an option on the table.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Peter.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Following up on Weijia’s question &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A lot of focus on the economic pain in Russia, potentially, from these sanctions, but what about the economic pain here?&nbsp; The Russians are saying they think gas prices in Europe are going to double.&nbsp; How high could they get here?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, again, Peter, as I said to Weijia, I mean, some of this depends on what President Putin does.&nbsp; So as he&#8217;s suggesting what the impact will be around the world, it&#8217;s all based on what his actions are, just to be very clear about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What the President is focused on and is working on is taking every step we can to communicate with, coordinate with, engage with big global suppliers around the world to minimize the impact on the energy markets.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But even without all this going on, gas in California is almost $5 a gallon.&nbsp; Should people across the country expect to see that kind of a number when they go to gas up their car &#8212; $5, $6?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I think as you heard the President say last week, standing up for our values is not without cost.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re trying to do is minimize that cost.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have a prediction of it right now because we&#8217;re trying to minimize the impact on the global energy markets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Something that you said &#8212; two different things that you&#8217;ve said so far today: You said you think right now Putin is improvising and adapting.&nbsp; But you&#8217;ve also said that you very much anticipate and predict that he&#8217;s going to invade further.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, which is it: Is he adapting, or is he still invading?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Think big here, Peter.&nbsp; He can still be preparing to invade &#8212; which we&#8217;ve said, and that continues to be the case &#8212; while making adaptations on when, if, how to, what his strategy is.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing. &nbsp;Both are true.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; so if that&#8217;s what you&#8217;re seeing &#8212; he announced sanctions yesterday &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did any Russian military units turn around and head back towards Russia?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to get into assessments from here of movements of any military.&nbsp; But also, what we&#8217;re trying to do is prevent a war, prevent devastation on the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re already seeing the impact on the economy in Russia.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to make clear that there are much &#8212; that as &#8212; if he continues to escalate, we will as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as we wait to see if or how Russia might retaliate against the U.S., the FBI is reportedly warning businesses about cybersecurity risks.&nbsp; So why did you say there is no current threat as it relates to cyber here?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is no current threat as it relates to cyber here.&nbsp; The FBI and all of the agencies in the government always provide regular updates on what businesses and entities should do to prepare for the potential for. &nbsp;There is still no immediate specific threat.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But on Friday, the Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber came in here to say, “We don&#8217;t have the level of cyber resilience that we wish.”&nbsp; Why would somebody come to the White House briefing room and talk about that if there is no threat?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because we anticipate that there could be continuing threats in the future, and what we need private sector companies to do is harden their cybersecurity capabilities now.&nbsp; Now is the time to do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, finally, the State Department spokesman today said you guys are doing everything you reasonably can to prevent human rights abuses, atrocities, and potential war crimes in Ukraine.&nbsp; How can you say that if all that you&#8217;re announcing is financial punishment?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That isn&#8217;t all we&#8217;re announcing.&nbsp; We have provided a range of assistance to Ukraine &#8212; humanitarian assistance, security assistance &#8212; the most of any year in history.&nbsp; We will continue to build on all of this assistance.&nbsp; We are plussing-up support for our partners and Allies in the region to ensure they know we have our ba- &#8212; their backs and we are abiding by our NATO obligations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we continue to also provide &#8212; I think what he was referring to is a range of public information as well &#8212; to make clear what the intentions are of the Russians, to call them out for the type of actions we could see them taking in the future.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, if I can ask you about Nord Stream 2 to have a little better understanding of this right now.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen the sanctions.&nbsp; Can you say declaratively that this pipeline will never be operational, that this is effectively dead?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; not only did the Chancellor of Germany announce it&#8217;s not moving forward, we also announced additional sanctions today.&nbsp; And it is not moving forward right now, no.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So would you say &#8212; but just for clarity, you say it&#8217;s not moving forward right now.&nbsp; But there have been some concern among some critics that though he did announce the suspension, that, at a later date, that Chancellor Scholz could say, “Yes, we are going to begin the process again.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, when you say “right now,” that means right now; that doesn&#8217;t mean for perpetuity?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s currently dead at the bottom of the sea, Peter.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of where we are in the process.&nbsp; It is not happening.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not moving forward.&nbsp; It hasn&#8217;t been operational for some time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that is where it stands.&nbsp; And this is all the result of diplomatic engagement and leadership by the President and his engagement with Chancellor Scholz.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me ask you about some other security issues as best you&#8217;re able to detail.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s some things you can&#8217;t discuss.&nbsp; So, without detailing specifics that you can&#8217;t discuss, what role is the U.S. playing in securing President Zelenskyy’s safety?&nbsp; And does the U.S. bear some responsibility in making sure that he is safe?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;m not going to detail our conversations or engagements about security with the President of Ukraine, who remains in Kyiv and is continuing to lead the country.<br><br>Q    Do we bear some responsibility, though, for making sure &#8212; without detailing what you&#8217;re doing, do we bear some responsibility for making sure that he is safe?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  We are going to continue to engage with him privately.  I&#8217;m not going to detail or speak to it further from here.<br><br>Q    If I could ask you just a last quick question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br><br>Q    Is there any circumstance &#8212; obviously, we&#8217;re focusing so much on Ukraine, as evidenced by these questions.  Is there any circumstance in which the President would hold his announcement of a Supreme Court pick after February?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  No. <br><br>Q    Declaratively, it&#8217;ll happen before then. <br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Yes.<br><br>Q    Has he made a decision yet?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have any updates on that. <br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since it&#8217;s been asked a few different times, but just to clarify: You and other officials have said that the purpose of withholding additional and harsher sanctions is so that they have a deterrent effect.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But at the same time, you&#8217;re saying that a broader invasion is likely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So how are both of those true, if the idea is that they would have a deterrent effect?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re trying to prevent that from happening, and we are making very clear what &#8212; how impactful and serious what we&#8217;re considering, in terms of additional sanctions, could be.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And are &#8212; is inflation playing a role at all in deciding, you know, what gets sanctioned, what &#8212; how you&#8217;re thinking about the sanctions package?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Inflation in the United States, I assume you&#8217;re referring to?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Global inflation.<br><br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Look, I think we look at a range of factors.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll use the energy markets as an example, because I know that was a question that was asked yesterday.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good one.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, as we look at what sectors we&#8217;re going to sanction, one of the factors we look at is what can have the biggest impact, of course, on Russian leadership, people around President Putin, on the Russian economy.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re trying to minimize is what impact there&#8217;s going to be on the United States and global markets, in a lot of ways.&nbsp;<br><br>And if you look at energy &#8212; the energy sector as an example, sanctioning them further could also mean that President Putin and people around him get richer.<br><br>So we look at a range of factors and, certainly, the impact on the global economy is a factor as we consider options.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If Russia does launch a full-scale invasion of Ukraine, should we expect to hear from the President, as we have in the last few days?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would expect you would, yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And he would address the nation in some televised fashion?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would expect you would hear from the President, as you have.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, can you explain a little bit more for people who are trying to follow this continuing situation with Russia and Ukraine, why would the U.S. not directly sanction Putin at this time?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It remains an option on the table.&nbsp; What I would say to people who are trying to understand why is that sanctions are designed to &#8212; we&#8217;ve always designed them to increase, be escalatory.&nbsp; That would be an escalatory step, as would be sanctioning the largest banks &#8212; the very largest banks and additional components of the financial sector, as would taking export control steps be.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s a range of escalatory steps we have as options.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned the sanctions on oligarchs at the top, and the President was a little unclear in his wording yesterday.&nbsp; He said that sanctions on Russian elites wouldn&#8217;t start until today; that was crossed out in the transcript to yesterday.&nbsp; The reason I&#8217;m asking is, as part of the, sort of, first tranche &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; of sanctions, are we going to see more elites sanctioned, or would that only happen if Russia takes additional escalatory steps?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can check if there are additional ones.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not tracking additional ones that we&#8217;re holding for a rollout.&nbsp;<br><br>I will note, on your first part of your question, that for the elites &#8212; individuals, if they were to have used their fi- &#8212; their bank card, I guess, to make a financial transaction, it wouldn&#8217;t have been working yesterday.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There was a cyberattack on Ukrainian government websites today.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know the NSC has already said that it was sort of similar to the one that we saw on Ukrainian banks earlier and would be in keeping with what you expect from Russia.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m wondering if, at this point, you&#8217;ve made a definitive determination if Russia was responsible, and, if so, if you have any sort of retaliation &#8212; or response to that announcement.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, we have not &#8212; we have not attributed today&#8217;s activity yet.&nbsp; That would be very fast &#8212; even fast for us, as fast as last week was.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We do consider it, as I think some of my NSC colleagues said, to be consistent with the type of activity Russia would carry out in a bid to destabilize Ukraine.&nbsp; It&#8217;s consistent with what we saw last week, where we attributed similar incidents to the Russian government.&nbsp; And we, of course, consider these further incidents to be consistent with a type of activity we&#8217;ve seen Russia take over the course of time.<br><br>We are in conversation with Ukraine regarding the cyber-related needs, including as recently as today.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to move with urgency to assess the nature and extent of this, what steps needs to be taken, and, therefore, our response.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then the President has got a meeting &#8212; a virtual meeting with the G7 tomorrow morning.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Obviously, I think the topic is going to be Ukraine &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but I was wondering if you could put any meat on the bone, in terms of what the President is trying to &#8212; what his objective is in that &#8212; in that meeting on what he’s looking to accomplish.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one of the steps the President has been focused on is ensuring that we are coordinated with key allies and partners around the world, and certainly the G7 is an important entity to remain very closely engaged with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The G7 is 50 percent of the world&#8217;s economy and joined us &#8212; all of them &#8212; in this first tranche of sanctions announced yesterday.&nbsp;<br><br>The President isn&#8217;t a believer that this level of coordination happens by accident; it happens through a lot of work and in close engagement.&nbsp; We&#8217;re obviously at a pivotal point in this &#8212; in this process, and so he felt tomorrow was a time to discuss with them what we&#8217;re seeing, what it looks like, what&#8217;s next, and engage in this format.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, a couple of questions.&nbsp; On this first tranche of sanctions, have what&#8217;s going to be announced in that first batch been announced, or will we see more things today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The first tranche has been announced.&nbsp; And, obviously, the Nord Stream 2 announcement today is an additional part of that.&nbsp; I can certainly check if there&#8217;s anything additional coming at this point beyond for the first tranche &#8212; not that I am aware of, but I will check and make sure that&#8217;s correct.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, when you all talk about this first tranche of sanctions, can you give us a sense of, like, how many tranches &#8212; if that’s the right word &#8212; are in this toolbox that you have to apply?&nbsp; You know, how many sets of sanctions are we talking about?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand the question.&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard for me to give that assessment.&nbsp; It really depends on what escalatory actions President Putin takes.&nbsp; If he goes further, we will go further.&nbsp; What that looks like, I can&#8217;t outline for you at this point in time.<br><br>I gave you the sense, a little bit, of what some additional options are &#8212; right? &#8212; export controls; sanctioning additional financial institutions, larger financial institutions.&nbsp; Those are all on the table, as are other options.<br><br>But in terms of what the breakdown of tranches would look like, I can’t outline that from &#8212; for you at this point from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And in terms of the cyberattack, which you just were asked about, does &#8212; will the U.S. or could we expect the U.S. to have some sort of retaliatory behavior towards Russia in response to this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We always reserve that option and, obviously, we haven&#8217;t made an attribution for this recent DDoS attack.&nbsp; As we go through the process of doing that, we&#8217;ll certainly consider what actions could be taken as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask one final question, actually, on the JCPOA?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There have been reports that the U.S., Iran is reaching, closing in on some sort of deal.&nbsp; Would you all confirm that that is an accurate assessment &#8212; that you are inching towards a potential deal this week?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what we&#8217;re seeing is there is significant progress being made, and we are close to a possible deal.&nbsp; But there are a number of very difficult issues that remain unresolved.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s very little time remaining to reach a deal given the pace of Iran&#8217;s nuclear advances.&nbsp;<br><br>Also, I would note that typically the most difficult components &#8212; the last mile &#8212; is where it &#8212; where there is the most difficult conversations and negotiations.&nbsp;<br><br>So, yes, significant progress and we are close.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s a lot that still needs to be worked out.&nbsp;<br><br>It is true that Iran &#8212; we believe if Iran shows seriousness, we can and should reach an understanding on mutual return to full implementation of the JCPOA within &#8212; potentially within days.&nbsp; But there is still more work that needs to be done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you all are optimistic or &#8212; I mean, that’s a mixed (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are &#8212; we are encouraged by the significant progress, but, having been through a few of these, I would note that, often, the most difficult negotiations happen in the &#8212; in the last portion.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Zolan.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So, following up on the Nord Stream, just &#8212; I&#8217;m wondering if anything happened. I understand you were saying that there was an intent to want to do this in a coordinated way with the Germans and, obviously, they made their action yesterday.&nbsp; But was there anything else that happened on the ground in Ukraine yesterday that warranted the sanction happening today rather than yesterday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, it &#8212; but it&#8217;s part of our first tranche of sanctions, so we would see it as a part of what was rolled out yesterday.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, you were also telling &#8212; I think you told Kaitlan that you wanted this approach with Germany rather than an alternative.&nbsp; Just looking at, you know, the President last year said, in Cincinnati, that construction is already kind of going at this point.&nbsp; I believe the exact quote &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, 90 percent of it.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; He was saying 90 percent.&nbsp; So why is this a better way, a more effective way than issuing sanctions unilaterally and then possibly pressuring the Germans to take action themselves?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it hasn&#8217;t been operational, which is an important component, right?&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like oil has been flowing through Nord Stream 2, which is a very important component here.&nbsp; And we made the assessment &#8212; others can have different assessments &#8212; that this would be the way to achieve the outcome that we&#8217;ve now achieved.&nbsp; Others can have different assessments.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no proof or evidence that their approach would have worked.&nbsp; Ours has worked.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; More so the question was: Why would not issuing sanctions last year, earlier &#8212; why wouldn&#8217;t have that been effective?&nbsp; Why is this approach &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because we felt working in coordination with our German counterparts through a diplomatic process would be the most effective way to approach it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then a pivot &#8212; just two more.&nbsp; Can you outline what exactly Doug Jones has been doing in terms of the SCOTUS process, who he&#8217;s been talking to on the Hill?<br><br>Lastly, the March 18th mask mandate for travel, just &#8212; is the administration considering extending that or is that seen as an expiration date?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; On the first, I&#8217;m sure once there is an announcement to be made, we will have more detail about all of the engagements that have led up to it.&nbsp; But certainly, Senator Jones is playing an integral role engaging with senators, engaging with different stakeholders and individuals who want to &#8212; to give their view on where this should head.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll have more details once an announcement is made.<br><br>As it relates to the March 18th timeline, the CDC is in the process of reviewing their mask guidelines and their mask guidance.&nbsp; We will let them make any announcements on that.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to predict at this point about March 18th and the &#8212; and where that stands on planes.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Earlier during today&#8217;s briefing, you said it&#8217;s the U.S.’s assessment that President Putin did not expect the U.S. to have this level of information that we have, did not expect us to put out the amount of information that we put out, and did not expect the global community to be as unified as it is.&nbsp; What have you seen from Putin&#8217;s actions, from Russia&#8217;s actions that have led to that conclusion, that assessment?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think why I was conveying that is because what we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; and I don&#8217;t think I can give much more detail than that, other than to say what we&#8217;ve seen is him adjusting and adapting some of his actions and needing to respond to what our actions are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve obviously been making a &#8212; assessing that he is prepared to operationalize at any time.&nbsp; That has not changed.&nbsp; But, you know, we are also watching closely what he does.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what&#8217;s your response &#8212; the administration&#8217;s response to lawmakers from both sides of the aisle who say President Biden still hasn&#8217;t gone far enough with sanctions?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Representative Adam Schiff yesterday said, quote, “…the administration must go further.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, Senator Graham called the administration&#8217;s initial response “inadequate,” and he said, “Let&#8217;s quickly up our game.”<br><br>So what is the strategy behind holding back some of these larger sanction possibilities that you&#8217;ve talked about?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our strategy has been start high, which is certainly what we did.&nbsp; We did not sanction a major bank or financial institution back in 2014.&nbsp; This is a farther step than that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I noted a little bit earlier, we also sanctioned not just oligarchs but also family members around them to cut off their ability to preserve their funding and financing.&nbsp; And our approach and our strategy has been to preserve a range of sanctions and options that we can also escalate to, should we need to.</p>



<p>Obviously, our preference is that President Putin deescalates.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if Russia does invade further &#8212; as, you know, there are indications that it could &#8212; does that mean that those sanctions imposed yesterday, imposed today were a failure?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, part of them were a cost.&nbsp; Part of them is an effort to prevent a war.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing that not alone but in coordination with our partners and Allies around the world.&nbsp; That is the way to do it.&nbsp; That is the strong way to do it.&nbsp; That is the effective way to do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There may be others who have different points of view.&nbsp; They&#8217;re welcome.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a free country.&nbsp; They can have those points of view.</p>



<p>But our approach has been, to date, to respond with strong sanctions, to start high and build from there.&nbsp; And that is what we will continue to do if he escalates.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, lastly, on the Supreme Court nomination process, can you confirm that the interviews are now finished ahead of an announcement before the end of the month?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to confirm any details about the process.&nbsp; I would note that we are five days away from the end of February, if my math is correct.&nbsp; The interviews are typically late stage in the process.&nbsp; So, we are getting close to an announcement.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I want to ask about food prices.&nbsp; But, first, a quick question about Ukraine.&nbsp; Just a short while ago, separatists in eastern Ukraine formally asked President Putin for military help.&nbsp; Is that a signal that the U.S. expects a broader invasion is about to begin?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think as we&#8217;ve said from the beginning, there are going to be a range of false-flag operations that we have expected to and laid out the playbook to see.&nbsp; This is an example of it.&nbsp; That is suggesting that they feel under threat.&nbsp; By whom &#8212; the Ukrainians that the Russians are threatening to attack?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;ll continue to call out what we see as false-flag operations or efforts to spread disinformation about what the actual status is on the ground.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Americans, they just experienced their most expensive Thanksgiving.&nbsp; This conflict will likely drive up food prices, grocery prices.&nbsp; What does the White House minimizing the impact of even higher grocery prices actually look like?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;ve ever minimized the higher impact of the costs of food.&nbsp; I would note &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) but you’re going to minimize the impact.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would note &#8212; let me finish.&nbsp; Factually, I think the price of a turkey just a couple of months ago was about $1 more, if we just look back at the facts of what was actually happening at the time.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve talked a bit in here about our concerns about meat conglomerates jacking up the prices &#8212; if people go into the store and they try to buy a pound or two pounds of meat &#8212; what we&#8217;re seeing as the impact of not enough competition in the industry.</p>



<p>But the President has repeatedly expressed concern about costs for the American people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the reasons he continues to press for steps with Congress that will lower significant costs on people&#8217;s budgets, whether it&#8217;s childcare, healthcare, eldercare, whatever it may be.&nbsp; That is a central part of his economic agenda.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve said and the President has said several times that, you know &#8212; to Americans &#8212; that the U.S. is not sending the military into Ukraine, not going to war with Russia.&nbsp; And I just wanted to ask, given that your warning of a full-fledged invasion with potential attacks on Kyiv, how the administration is as confident as it is that that won&#8217;t become necessary at some point, that there won&#8217;t be any need down the road for military engagement with Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is not a decision the President is going to make.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Based on?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are not going to be in a war with Russia or putting military troops on the ground in Ukraine fighting Russia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, ultimately, if Vladimir Putin takes all of Ukraine, that&#8217;s a situation that the administration is not &#8212; going to condemn, obviously; going to punish, economically &#8212; but that&#8217;s not something that will be engaged militarily.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that is several steps down the road.&nbsp; But what I will tell you is the President has been crystal clear and consistent: He is not sending U.S. troops to fight in Ukraine.&nbsp; That has not changed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has there been any discussion on the strategy of saying that, though, so publicly and potentially giving Putin an indication that the U.S. and NATO Allies are willing to cede that sphere of influence outside of NATO boundaries to him?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I don’t know how many more times I can say it: There&#8217;s no scenario &#8212; the President is not sending U.S. troops to fight in Ukraine against Russia.&nbsp; We are taking a range of other steps, as you&#8217;ve touched on, but, I would say, they&#8217;re quite significant.</p>



<p>Not only are we the largest provider of security assistance, humanitarian assistance, and economic assistance to Ukraine, but we have also taken significant steps to plus up not only our NATO forces and our force posture but the force posture of our partners in Eastern Europe to make sure they know we have their backs and support them.</p>



<p>We will continue to plus this all up.&nbsp; But the President is not sending U.S. troops to fight in Ukraine.&nbsp; That hasn&#8217;t changed.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp;&nbsp;This is a little bit related to Eli&#8217;s&nbsp;question.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s very clear what Russian escalation could be, right?&nbsp; Go from today to, you know, the whole of Ukraine, or bombarding Kyiv, or &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of things along the way.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve laid out all sorts of different sanctions that are being considered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what is the arc &#8212; because it&#8217;s very clear what the Russian arc could be, right?&nbsp; It could ultimately go to whatever, you know, occupying the whole of Ukraine.&nbsp; What is the arc of the U.S. response?&nbsp; Like what&#8217;s &#8212; what&#8217;s the equivalent to, you know, smashing Kyiv to pieces?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to outline &#8220;if this, then that&#8221; from here.&nbsp; And I &#8212; unless you know something the rest of us don&#8217;t know, I don&#8217;t know that anyone knows exactly what the next step will be.</p>



<p>As much as we&#8217;re preparing, we&#8217;re seeing them positioning their military forces for attack.&nbsp; Obviously, until they further invade, they haven&#8217;t further invaded, right?&nbsp; If they do and take escalatory steps, we will take escalatory steps.&nbsp; What those look like will depend a lot on what the actions are.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And one other question, please.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got the G7 virtual meeting tomorrow.&nbsp; The President has made a lot of outreach to allies, obviously.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is any consideration whatsoever being given to some kind of last-ditch outreach to the Russians, either from the President or him encouraging the Europeans to have another go at it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ve talked about this a little bit yesterday.&nbsp; I mean, a couple of days ago, obviously, the President made clear &#8212; or we made clear on his behalf that if they didn&#8217;t invade, that he was open to ha- &#8212; engaging with President Putin, and that would follow a meeting or engagement between our Secretary of State and Foreign Minister Lavrov.</p>



<p>Obviously, we&#8217;re in a different point at this point in time, and it doesn&#8217;t feel appropriate or the right step to have those diplomatic engagements right now.&nbsp; We will always leave the door open.&nbsp; If they de-escalate, we will certainly proceed with diplomatic engagement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, no, we&#8217;re not considering a meeting with President Putin or engagement with him right now.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, I have a question on Mexico but, first, on Ukraine &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the sanctions on Nord Stream AG, can you confirm that they will only affect gas from and not the four European companies that are shareholders of the consortium?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we put out an extensive statement on this, as well as some details.&nbsp; I can &#8212; let me see if I can just outline it all from you &#8212; from here, and we can get that to you after the briefing as well.</p>



<p>What was your other question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, on Mexico, the President of Mexico said today that the U.S. isn&#8217;t well informed about violence against journalists in Mexico and the recent impunity for those crimes.&nbsp; Are you worried that he&#8217;s downplaying the risks that journalists face in that country?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, we&#8217;ve seen, factually, the threats that have been posed to journalists in Mexico.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen the threats, we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; and that is a concern that I think the Secretary of State was expressing on behalf of the United States about those abuses.&nbsp; So, I think he was speaking to facts we&#8217;ve seen on the ground.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Jen.&nbsp; A couple of domestic questions for you.&nbsp; First, does the White House have any reaction to the order from Texas Governor Abbott calling for prosecutions of parents who move forward with gender-affirming treatments for their kids?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I spoke a little bit, unfortunately, to another law that we saw moving in Florida just last week.&nbsp; And &#8212; but let me reiterate some of the points I made then.</p>



<p>There are efforts in some states &#8212; not just Texas, but also Florida and unfortunately others &#8212; designed to target and attack the kids who need support the most: LGBTQI+ students who are already vulnerable to bullying and violence just for being themselves.</p>



<p>This isn&#8217;t an isolated action, as is evidenced by multiple states pursuing this.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing Republican leaders take actions to regulate what students can or cannot read, what they can or cannot learn, and, most troubling, who they can or cannot be.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve heard the President &#8212; he also, I think, put out a tweet or &#8212; I think &#8212; or a statement to the Florida law.&nbsp; And I would say we have the same concerns about these type of actions we&#8217;re seeing in Texas.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in Florida, Governor DeSantis&#8217;s administration is moving forward with the rule targeting shelters that house unaccompanied minors.&nbsp; Does the Biden administration have any contingency plans for the unaccompanied minors who may be affected by that rule, in terms of their</p>



<p>housing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think this is an important thing to call &#8212; to call out here, because what we&#8217;re talking about here is, one, it&#8217;s our view &#8212; it&#8217;s our responsibility, I should say, as an administration to responsibly and safely care for unaccompanied children.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about minor kids here.</p>



<p>So HHS is currently examining all legal options available at its disposal to ensure that our shelters continue to provide services to the unaccompanied minor &#8212; minors in our care.</p>



<p>I would remind you all that there have been kids in Florida in these facilities since 2005 &#8212; I mean, these facilities have been open for 17 years now, being overseen by the Office of Refugee Resettlement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re obviously looking at legal options here.&nbsp; But I also would say this is &#8212; you know, really flies in the face of what should be a moral view of anyone that taking &#8212; caring for &#8212; the safe care for unaccompanied children should be a part of what we all want to be active participants in.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; So, the Justice Department today announced that they are ending the Trump administration&#8217;s 2018 China Initiative and replacing it with a broader approach towards, you know, more countries &#8212; Russia, Iran, North Korea.</p>



<p>I know that Justice officials have spoken about this, but if you can elaborate from this podium the reasoning behind that, and especially in addressing the complaints of discrimination from Asian Americans.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to dig further into this, Patsy.&nbsp; I&#8217;d really point you to the Department of Justice.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure we have more to add from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just on the global pandemic response, can you confirm the amount of funding that the administration has requested from Congress?&nbsp; We&#8217;re hearing this number of $5 billion that activists say is not nearly enough to help vaccinate the world, as well as to stop new variants from, you know, attacking the U.S. as well.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t &#8212; well, I don&#8217;t have any specific numbers; we&#8217;re still in conversation with the Hill at this point about funding and funding needs, both domestically and internationally.</p>



<p>We want to continue to be the provider of not just vaccines but vaccine know-how and assistance to the global community.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t believe that COVI- &#8212; that the pandemic sees borders.&nbsp; And we know that in order to continue to get it under control, we need to be the leader in the world on this effort.&nbsp; But numbers are still being discussed with the Hill, so I don&#8217;t have any more specifics, unfortunately.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just really quickly on Ukraine: Are you, at this point, urging Americans to leave Russia?&nbsp; I know that &#8212; I think, two days ago the embassy in Moscow is issuing an advisory saying &#8212; for Americans to have evacuation plans that do not rely on government assistance.&nbsp; But are you actually telling Americans in Russia to leave Russia right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The State Department makes those assessments and recommendations, and they update them regularly, so I&#8217;d point to them for any updates.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; A few on Ukraine.&nbsp; First, the Kremlin has vowed countersanctions in response to the U.S.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve not seen what those will look like, but it sounds like the U.S. has quite a bit of intelligence, so I&#8217;m wondering if you have any view on what the nature of those countersanctions could be, what impact they could have on consumers, and how the administration could offset that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve seen those threats or those reports, but I don&#8217;t have anything to provide or assess from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, yesterday, President Biden said, “Nothing in Putin’s lengthy remarks indicated any interest in pursuing real dialogue on European security in the year 2022.”<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If that’s the case, what do you see as the endgame here?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, our hope is that Putin will decide to de-escalate: that he will feel the threat of the sanctions, what the impact will be on the Russian economy, on the Russian people, on the people who surround him &#8212; they are meant to have a deterrent impact; that he will feel the weight of being a pariah in the global community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It does not mean &#8212; we have never closed the door to diplomacy, and the President didn&#8217;t have that intention of conveying that yesterday either.&nbsp; And, certainly, if it is an appropriate time, he will engage with President Putin again.&nbsp; But now is not the appropriate time, where he&#8217;s continuing to invade a sovereign country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, finally, the administration is working on putting its budget together.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How much humanitarian assistance for Ukraine is the administration prepared to support?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re going to &#8212; and it&#8217;s hard for me to give you a number right now, because we&#8217;re going to continue to assess the needs on the &#8212; on the ground.&nbsp; And we certainly are prepared for the potential for there to be major humanitarian &#8212; continued humanitarian needs on the ground.&nbsp; Obviously, those existed &#8212; have existed since back to 2014.</p>



<p>But we want to continue to be the largest provider of humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; This is something we will continue to discuss with colleagues in Congress as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thanks everyone.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll do this again tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Supreme Court, Jen?&nbsp; Supreme Court, real fast, Jen?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, ma&#8217;am.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And going back to what Peter asked &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This &#8212; this small window &#8212; and in the midst of this window, you have a lot going on with foreign policy.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It means you guys have a lot going on, too.&nbsp; All of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; How about that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that said, how is the President feeling in the midst of all this as it relates to this impending nomination &#8212; this historic nomination that he&#8217;s getting ready for make?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And tell me more about what you mean, &#8220;How is he feeling?&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How is he feeling?&nbsp; I mean, he&#8217;s got all of this going on &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; with Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; And then he&#8217;s got this historic nomination of the first Black woman to potentially sit on the U.S. Supreme Court.&nbsp; It&#8217;s history being made in the midst of looking at sanctions and other things that are happening overseas.&nbsp; How&#8217;s he feeling about this piece over here?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, I mean, I think the President is looking forward to announcing a historic, eminently qualified Black woman to serve on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; He has &#8212; feels there&#8217;s tremendous honor in that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He takes the role that every President has in selecting and nominating someone to the Supreme Court very seriously.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he has been spending time not just studying bios, but also reviewing cases and engaging very closely with an internal team on this process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But he is very much looking forward to making this announcement and getting this individual confirmed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How many nominees has he met with thus far?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into further detail on that.&nbsp; I expect once he makes an announcement, we&#8217;ll have more details to share.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the administration has been fervrent &#8212; fervor &#8212; fervent &#8212; I can&#8217;t even get the word out &#8212; saying that they will &#8212; that you all will fight against anyone who tries to mar or ruin the reputation of any of these nominees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are you willing to do in this fight to keep their reputations that they walked into this process with?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a good question, April.&nbsp; I think what we mean by that is: There are a range of eminently qualified Black women whose names have been out there as potential nominees &#8212; all of these women would make tremendous additions to the Supreme Court &#8212; and we have also seen efforts to mar their reputations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we mean by that is we are going to fight back &#8212; even before, obviously, the President has made a decision or made an announcement &#8212; against efforts to tar any of their reputations.&nbsp; That means defending them publicly, standing up for them, providing information to &#8212; to, you know, debunk any information that&#8217;s being put out about them that&#8217;s inaccurate.&nbsp; And hopefully they all feel that we have &#8212; we have delivered on that promise.&nbsp; But that has been important to the President from the beginning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp; See you tomorrow or whenever.</p>



<p>4:27 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Nord Stream&#160;2</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/23/statement-by-president-biden-on-nord-stream-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 18:55:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since Russia began deploying troops to the Ukrainian border, the United States has worked closely with our Allies and partners to deliver a strong, unified response. As I said when I met with Chancellor Scholz earlier this month, Germany has been a leader in that effort, and we have closely coordinated our efforts to stop&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since Russia began deploying troops to the Ukrainian border, the United States has worked closely with our Allies and partners to deliver a strong, unified response. As I said when I met with Chancellor Scholz earlier this month, Germany has been a leader in that effort, and we have closely coordinated our efforts to stop the Nord Stream 2 pipeline if Russia further invaded Ukraine.</p>



<p>Yesterday, after further close consultations between our two governments, Germany announced that it would halt certification of the pipeline. Today, I have directed my administration to impose sanctions on Nord Stream 2 AG and its corporate officers. These steps are another piece of our initial tranche of sanctions in response to Russia’s actions in Ukraine. As I have made clear, we will not hesitate to take further steps if Russia continues to escalate.</p>



<p>Through his actions, President Putin has provided the world with an overwhelming incentive to move away from Russian gas and to other forms of energy. I want to thank Chancellor Scholz for his close partnership and continued dedication to holding Russia accountable for its actions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-⁠Harris Administration Delivering Results 100 Days into Infrastructure&#160;Implementation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/23/fact-sheet-biden-%e2%81%a0harris-administration-delivering-results-100-days-into-infrastructure-implementation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 18:47:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since President Biden signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law 100 days ago, the Biden-Harris Administration has made major progress implementing the largest long-term investment in America’s infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century. The historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will rebuild crumbling road and bridges, replace lead pipes, help provide high-speed internet to every family in America,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since President Biden signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law 100 days ago, the Biden-Harris Administration has made major progress implementing the largest long-term investment in America’s infrastructure and competitiveness in nearly a century.</p>



<p>The historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will rebuild crumbling road and bridges, replace lead pipes, help provide high-speed internet to every family in America, and produce concrete results that change people’s lives for the better. By reaching all communities all across the country – including rural communities and historically underserved populations – these investments will position the United States to win the 21st century.</p>



<p>Upon signing the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, President Biden signed an Executive Order establishing an Infrastructure Implementation Task Force that has now met nine times to ensure that the Administration is delivering results to the American people.<br>The Administration has demonstrated early and often how we will work as one team with one mission: to build a better America while creating good-paying job opportunities for American workers, ensuring products are Made in America and strengthening supply chains, advancing racial equity, and strengthening the nation’s resilience to climate change.</p>



<p>Since the bill signing, implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law has been the focus of more than 60 presidential and cabinet visits to communities across America. The President, Vice President, and Cabinet have traveled the country to showcase how the Administration is building a better America and how the law benefits communities in every corner of the country.<br><strong><br>Resources for States, Territories, Tribes, &amp; Local Governments<br></strong><br>In January, the White House released the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.build.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>first edition of its Bipartisan Infrastructure Law guidebook</strong></a>&nbsp;to help state, local, Tribal and territorial governments unlock the benefits from the historic investments in our nation’s infrastructure. The guidebook is a central repository on the law and contains the most comprehensive information to date on the more than 375 programs included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;Along with its accompanying information online, states, territories, Tribes and local governments now have information on funding opportunities, who to contact, and how to get ready to rebuild. Future phases of the guidebook will update dates, key timelines for program implementation, best practices, case studies, and links to key resources developed by the White House and partners. In recent weeks, the Administration has launched an <strong>“Infrastructure School”</strong> webinar series to go more in depth into each of the guidebook’s 12 chapters and allow communities the opportunity to ask questions to the agency experts, overseeing implementation of key programs.</p>



<p>Given that over 90 percent of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding will be implemented by non-federal partners, the White House has requested <a href="https://www.ibtta.org/sites/default/files/documents/Advocacy/GA053-Mitch%20Landrieu%20Letter%20to%20Governors%202022-0104.pdf">Governors</a>&nbsp;and local leaders take a series of preparatory actions, including appointing infrastructure coordinators to manage the flow of funds to their states. The Administration has also released a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BIL-Factsheet-Local-Competitive-Funding.pdf">fact sheet</a> on some of the largest sources of competitive funding, particularly for local governments. Senior Advisor and Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator Mitch Landrieu has shared these resources during meetings with the National Governors Association, U.S. Conference of Mayors, National League of Cities, National Association of Counties, and hundreds of tribes through Tribal Consultations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While many funding streams in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law specifically set aside funds for underserved communities, the White House Infrastructure Implementation Team has also been engaging states, local governments, Tribal governments, territories, federal agencies, philanthropy, and others to leverage all available resources to quickly deliver the necessary technical assistance and capacity to underserved communities.</p>



<p><strong>Good Stewards of Taxpayer Dollars</strong><br>As outlined in the President’s executive order, agencies must prioritize “investing public dollars efficiently and equitably, working to avoid waste, and focusing on measurable outcomes for the American people.” To support effective agency implementation, transparency, and appropriate oversight, key Biden-Harris Administration officials have met with the Inspectors General for agencies with major Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding and leaders of the Government Accountability Office (GAO). Going forward, the Administration will work with agency IGs and GAO to share data and effective practices so that program planning, design, execution, and financial management, as well as data, tracking, and reporting, support transparency and help ensure taxpayer dollars are spent well.</p>



<p><strong>Delivering On Time, On Task, On Budget</strong><br>Nearly $100 billion has been announced to states, territories, Tribes and local governments from formula and competitive programs for roads and highways, bridges, ports, airports, and water systems. Another nearly $50 billion in RFIs and notices of funding availability have been released. The Administration has also unveiled new offices and action plans that will ensure these investments are implemented wisely and well.</p>



<p><em>Transportation</em></p>



<ul><li>The U.S. Department of Transportation (USDOT) and Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) announced $52.5 billion in Federal Highway Apportionment for fiscal year 2022 the largest in decades for all 50 states and DC. The law invests $350 billion in highway programs over the next 5 years.<br></li><li>USDOT and FHWA announced&nbsp;over $27 billion in funding to replace, repair, and rehabilitate bridges&nbsp;across the country to all 50 states, D.C., Puerto Rico, and Tribal governments over the next five years.<br></li><li>USDOT and the Department of Energy (DOE) <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/president-biden-doe-and-dot-announce-5-billion-over-five-years-national-ev-charging">announced nearly $5 billion</a> that will be made available over the next 5 years under the new National Electric Vehicle Infrastructure (NEVI) Formula Program and released guidance to states, available on driveleectric.gov on how to strategically deploy EV charging infrastructure to create an interconnected national electric vehicle charging network.<br></li><li>The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) at USDOT announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/faa-announces-first-year-airport-funding-amounts-bipartisan-infrastructure-law">$3 billion for 3,075 airports</a> across the country that can use investments to upgrade critical infrastructure.<br></li><li>&nbsp;FAA announced a $1 billion notice of funding opportunity to <a href="https://www.faa.gov/newsroom/application-process-opens-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-funds-build-safe-sustainable-and">modernize airport terminals</a> across the country. The law invests $25 billion dollars in three FAA programs over the next 5 years.<br></li><li>The Federal Transit Authority (FTA) at USDOT <a href="https://www.transit.dot.gov/about/news/president-bidens-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-delivers-billions-transit-funding-through">announced $4.7 billion</a> in partial year funding to transit agencies, states, and Tribal governments to support public transportation – and public transportation jobs – throughout the country. In total, the new investments and reauthorization in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal provide $89.9 billion in guaranteed funding for public transit over the next five years — the largest Federal investment in public transit in history.<br></li><li>USDOT released a $1.5 billion notice of funding opportunity for its&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/us-secretary-transportation-buttigieg-announces-nearly-1-billion-grant-awards">Rebuilding American Infrastructure with Sustainability and Equity (RAISE) grant programs</a>, building off a $1 billion series of awards made to 90 major projects across 47 states in December 2021. Funding under the law allows USDOT to invest $7.5 billion dollars over the next 4 years in this program.<br></li><li>The Maritime Administration (MARAD) at USDOT announced a $450 million notice of funding opportunity for the <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/us-transportation-secretary-pete-buttigieg-announces-over-241-million-grants-americas">Port Infrastructure Development Program grants</a>&nbsp;to improve ports and strengthen the nation’s supply chains, building off of $230 million of awards in December 2021. The Ports Infrastructure Development Program will invest $2.25 billion over the next 10 years in our nation’s critical port infrastructure.<br></li><li>The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) at USDOT&nbsp;announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/nhtsa-announces-260-million-grants-highway-safety-programs-made-possible-bipartisan">$260 million in highway safety&nbsp;grants</a> to reduce traffic crashes. The law provides NHTSA with over 4 billion dollars over the next 4 years to improve the safety of our roadways.<br></li><li>Vice President Harris announced an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-electric-vehicle-charging-action-plan/">EV Charging Action Plan</a>&nbsp;to achieve the President’s goal of building a national network of 500,000 electric vehicle chargers. USDOT and DOE also formed a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/doe-and-dot-launch-joint-effort-build-out-nationwide-electric-vehicle-charging">Joint Office of Energy &amp; Transportation&nbsp;</a>focused on building out the national network of EV chargers.<br></li><li>USDOT announced <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/president-biden-and-us-department-transportation-announce-12-billion-highways-rural">$1.2 billion for highways in rural Appalachia</a> for the Appalachian Development Highway System (ADHS) toward the timely completion of designated corridors in 11 states in the Appalachian region. The total amount that will be available to the states in Fiscal Year 2022 is $246 million.</li></ul>



<p><em>Climate, Energy &amp; the Environment</em></p>



<ul><li>The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (USACE) announced <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/19/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-historic-investment-to-americas-port-and-waterway-infrastructure/">&nbsp;$14 Billion</a> to strengthen supply chains, improve waterways, and bolster climate resilience in fiscal year 2022 for over 500 projects across 52 states and territories using Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds and other appropriations.<br></li><li>Vice President Harris announced a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-lead-pipe-and-paint-action-plan/">Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan</a>&nbsp;to accelerate Bipartisan Infrastructure Law investments to replace all of the nation’s lead pipes in the next decade and expand access to clean drinking water.<br></li><li>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) announced $7.4 billion in funding for states to upgrade America’s aging water infrastructure, sewerage systems, pipes and service lines, and more through their State Revolving Fund (SRF) programs. This is the first of five years of supplemental funding to the SRFs. EPA Administrator Michael S. Regan The Department also issued a letter to Governors outlining the key priorities for water investments, including targeting resources to disadvantaged communities, making rapid progress on lead-free water for all, and tackling dangerous chemicals such as PFAS. The law provides nearly $44 billion to EPA’s State Revolving Funds programs.<br></li><li>The Department of the Interior (DOI) launched a new $4.7 billion program to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-releases-implementation-guidance-states-infrastructure-law-efforts">cap</a>&nbsp;<a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-releases-implementation-guidance-states-infrastructure-law-efforts">and plug orphaned oil and gas wells</a>&nbsp;in order to reduce methane emissions and create jobs over the next decade. The first $1.15 billion in funding is now available to 26 states to create jobs cleaning up orphaned oil and gas wells across the country.<br></li><li>DOI announced <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-administration-announces-nearly-725-million-create-good-paying-union-jobs">nearly $725 million</a> in Fiscal Year 22 funding for 22 states and the Navajo Nation to create good-paying union jobs and catalyze economic opportunity by reclaiming abandoned mine lands (AML). The program will help communities eliminate dangerous environmental conditions and pollution caused by past coal mining. The law reauthorized the existing program and provided nearly $11.3 billion to be allocated evenly over the next 15 years.<br></li><li>EPA announced&nbsp;$1 billion&nbsp;to initiate cleanup and clear the backlog of 49 previously unfunded Superfund sites and accelerate cleanup at dozens of other sites across the country. Until this historic investment, many of these were part of a backlog of hazardous waste sites awaiting funding. These funds will help communities living near many of the most serious uncontrolled or abandoned releases of contamination finally get the protections they deserve.<br></li><li>DOI announced <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/tribes-receive-17-billion-president-bidens-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-fulfill">$1.7 billion to fulfill Indian Waters Rights Settlements</a>, which will help deliver long-promised water resources to Tribes, certainty to all their non-Indian neighbors, and a solid foundation for future economic development for entire communities dependent on common water resources.<br></li><li>EPA announced <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/president-biden-epa-announce-1-billion-investment-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-will">$1 billion for the Great Lakes Restoration Initiative</a>, including $200 million in FY2022, to accelerate progress in the clean-up and restoration of the Great Lakes’ most environmentally degraded sites, securing clean water and a better environment for millions of Americans in the Great Lakes region.<br></li><li>EPA <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-highlights-historic-106-million-investment-water-infrastructure-benefitting-long">announced $106 million</a> over a five-year period going to the Long Island Sound Study Program to significantly improve Long Island Sound’s environmental health, climate resilience, and economic vitality.<br></li><li>DOE established $9.5 billion in <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-establishes-bipartisan-infrastructure-laws-95-billion-clean-hydrogen-initiatives">Clean Hydrogen Initiatives</a> to help decarbonize industry and the transportation sectors. The Department announced two Requests for Information (RFI) to collect feedback from stakeholders to inform the implementation and design of the Regional Hydrogen Hub and the Electrolysis and Clean Hydrogen Manufacturing and Recycling Programs.<br></li><li>DOE released <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-launches-140-million-program-develop-americas-first-kind-critical-minerals-refinery">a Request for Information (RFI) on the design, construction, and operation</a> of a new $140 million facility to demonstrate the commercial feasibility of a full-scale rare earth element (REE) and critical minerals (CM) extraction and separation refinery using unconventional resources.<br></li><li>DOI announced over $167 million will go towards a new facility for the <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-colorado-leaders-announce-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-funding">U.S. Geological Survey</a>, which is working on critical energy and mineral programs.<br></li><li>The Department of Health and Human Services announced the <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2022/01/25/president-bidens-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-directs-100-million-lower-heating-cooling-bills.html">release of $100 million</a> to help families pay their outstanding heating and cooling bills. This funding comes on top of investment in the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program (LIHEAP) through the American Rescue Plan and the Continuing Resolution most recently passed by Congress, and is the first installment of the five-year, $500 million investment in the program provided from President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br></li><li>The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service announced a <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-announces-over-15-billion-support-state-wildlife-conservation-and">record $1.5 billion</a> in annual funding from excise taxes on guns, ammunition, and archery sales through the Wildlife and Sport Fish Restoration (WSFR) Program to support state and local outdoor recreational opportunities, and wildlife and habitat conservation efforts. The WSFR Program contains two funding sources: the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund, which was reauthorized as part of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and the Wildlife Restoration Program.&nbsp;<br></li><li>DOE <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-establishes-6-billion-program-preserve-americas-clean-nuclear-energy-infrastructure">released a Notice of Intent (NOI) and Request for Information (RFI)</a> on the implementation of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s $6 billion Civil Nuclear Credit Program. The nuclear credit program supports the continued operation of U.S. nuclear reactors, the nation’s largest source of clean power.<br></li><li>DOE issued two notices of intent to <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-administration-doe-invest-3-billion-strengthen-us-supply-chain-advanced-batteries">provide $3 billion to boost production of the advanced batteries</a> that are critical to rapidly growing clean energy industries of the future, including electric vehicles and energy storage.<br></li><li>DOI’s Bureau of Reclamation announced application periods for hundreds of millions of BIL funding opportunities for water infrastructure, some of which are still open. Funding for the maintenance of aging infrastructure, and water recycling and desalination projects have been advertised, with more on the way during the rest of 2022.<br></li><li>DOE announced an <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-optimizes-structure-implement-62-billion-clean-energy-investments-bipartisan">organizational realignment</a> to ensure is has the structure needed to effectively implement the clean energy investments in President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the Energy Act of 2020. A newly created Under Secretary for Infrastructure will focus on deploying clean infrastructure—supporting DOE’s ongoing work to achieve carbon-free electricity in the U.S. by 2035 and a net zero economy by 2050.<br></li><li>DOE &nbsp;established the new&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-establishes-new-office-clean-energy-demonstrations-under-bipartisan-infrastructure-law">Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations,</a>&nbsp;which will oversee $20 billion of infrastructure funding to scale up clean energy, create new, good-paying jobs for American families and workers, and reduce pollution while benefiting underserved communities.<br></li><li>DOE launched a new&nbsp;Building a Better Grid&nbsp;initiative to accelerate the deployment of new transition lines, enabled by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. As part of this initiative, Office of Electricity at DOE released a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.energy.gov/sites/default/files/2022-01/Transmission%20NOI%20final%20for%20web_1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">notice of intent</a>&nbsp;to inform the design and implementation of this historic investment.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><em>High-Speed Internet</em></p>



<ul><li>The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) began accepting applications for the $1.15 billion <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2021/11/24/usda-begins-accepting-applications-115-billion-loans-and-grants">ReConnect rural broadband program</a> for loans and grants to state, local or territory governments, corporations, Native American Tribes and limited liability companies and cooperative organizations to help people in rural areas get access to high-speed internet, which will be boosted by the infrastructure law.<br></li><li>The  Department of Commerce (DOC) announced the <a href="https://broadbandusa.ntia.doc.gov/resources/grant-programs/tribal-broadband-connectivity-program">three sets of grants</a> for the <a href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2021/11/department-commerces-ntia-awards-first-grants-tribal-groups-seeking">Tribal Broadband Connectivity Program</a>, totaling <a href="https://www.commerce.gov/news/press-releases/2021/12/commerce-awards-42-million-expand-broadband-tribal-communities-arizona">$3.85 million</a>, which is receiving additional funding through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br></li><li>The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) launched the Affordable Connectivity Program providing broadband subsidies of up to $30/month for low-income households (up to $75/month for households on Tribal Lands) and up to $100 towards the purchase of a desktop, laptop or tablet computer. Vice President Harris announced earlier this month the program has enrolled more than 10 million households in affordable, high speed internet plans.<br></li><li>The National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) at the DOC hosted a series of  <a href="https://broadbandusa.ntia.doc.gov/news/latest-news/broadband-grant-programs-public-virtual-listening-sessions">broadband</a> <a href="https://broadbandusa.ntia.doc.gov/news/latest-news/broadband-grant-programs-public-virtual-listening-sessions">listening sessions</a>  to inform how the Administration implements several of the historic broadband program funded by the infrastructure law.<br></li><li>The NTIA also <a href="/www.ntia.gov/other-publication/2022/request-comment-broadband-programs-bipartisan-infrastructure-law%3c">published a request for comment</a> seeking public input on the design and implementation of the Broadband Equity, Access and Deployment Program, the Middle-Mile Broadband Infrastructure Program, and the Digital Equity Planning Grant Program which together will distribute more than $45 billion in broadband funding.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
