<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 01:20:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the Oklahoma Abortion&#160;Bill</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-oklahoma-abortion-bill/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 01:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President believes that women have the fundamental right to make their own reproductive health choices.&#160;Roe has been the law of the land for almost 50 years, and basic fairness and the stability of our law demand that it not be overturned.&#160; Today’s action by the Oklahoma legislature is the most extreme effort to&#160;undo&#160;these fundamental&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President believes that women have the fundamental right to make their own reproductive health choices.&nbsp;<em>Roe </em>has been the law of the land for almost 50 years, and basic fairness and the stability of our law demand that it not be overturned.&nbsp; Today’s action by the Oklahoma legislature is the most extreme effort to&nbsp;undo&nbsp;these fundamental rights we have seen to date.&nbsp; In addition, it adopts Texas’ absurd plan to allow private citizens to sue their neighbors for&nbsp;providing reproductive health care and helping women to exercise&nbsp;their constitutional rights.</p>



<p>This is part of a growing effort by ultra MAGA officials across the country to roll back the freedoms we should not take for granted in this country.&nbsp; They are starting with reproductive rights, but the American people need to know that other fundamental rights, including the right to contraception and marriage equality, are at risk.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>The President is committed to standing up for these constitutional rights, and for protecting Americans’ fundamental freedoms.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden in&#160;Ecuador</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/19/remarks-by-first-lady-jill-biden-in-ecuador/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 23:06:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53634</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carondelet PalaceQuito, Ecuador 2:21 P.M. ECT FIRST LADY BIDEN:  Thank you, María de Lourdes, for that very kind introduction. Mr. President, Madam First Lady, María Mercedes, Foreign Minister Holguín, and Ambassador Baki, Ministers of State, and to you, the people of Ecuador: Here, at the center of the world, there is so much to fill&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Carondelet Palace<br>Quito, Ecuador</p>



<p>2:21 P.M. ECT</p>



<p>FIRST LADY BIDEN:  Thank you, María de Lourdes, for that very kind introduction.<br><br>Mr. President, Madam First Lady, María Mercedes, Foreign Minister Holguín, and Ambassador Baki, Ministers of State, and to you, the people of Ecuador:<br><br>Here, at the center of the world, there is so much to fill us with awe: the majestic Andes, the volcanos like fire gods waiting to awaken.  From the Galapagos to the Amazon, the story of our very origins on Earth.  The breathtaking coast and the history that dusts every stone and brick that lines the streets of Quito. <br><br>And no less spectacular is the heart of the Ecuadorian people.  Thank you for your warm hospitality and welcome.<br><br>I am honored to be here in this beautiful capital today.  And on behalf of my husband and the people of the United States: <em>Buenas tardes</em>.  (Applause.) <br><br>Ambassador Fitzpatrick, you and Silvana are doing great work here.  And our U.S. Embassy team represents the United States with excellence every day.  Thank you to both of you.  (Applause.)<br><br>Two hundred years ago next week, you won independence from Spain right here in Quito, at the Battle of Pichincha.</p>



<p>And since then, you’ve built a democracy that is able to withstand the tides of time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, you have a President and a First Lady who serve the people.</p>



<p>President Lasso is carving his place in your history by reaching out to those who have often been ignored or left behind, by listening to those who have faced inequality and discrimination and poverty and finding solutions for their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As he said in his inaugural address, “I have not come to satisfy the hatred of a few, but to satisfy the hunger of many.”&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Thank you, President Lasso, for leading with courage and conviction.<br><br>And, Madam First Lady, today I saw your heart through your work to serve children of Ecuador’s most vulnerable.&nbsp; And may God bless you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Ecuador, the progress you’ve made here is a light to your neighbors.&nbsp; And your illumination can bring a more equitable and sustainable future in this corner of the world.<br><br>But alone, you can only do so much.&nbsp; Any one of us can only do so much.&nbsp; So that’s what I’d like to talk to you about today: how when we work together, we can make our nations and our world stronger.<br><br>A little over a week ago, in a small school on the other side of the world, I sat with Ukrainian mothers, with tears permanently in &#8212; on the edges of their eyes, as if they could barely contain their sadness.<br><br>While they wore brave faces, they grasped their children’s hand or touched their children’s hair, unable to bear to lose the physical connection for even a moment.<br><br>The mothers I met there told me about the violence; the days and days without food, harbored in basements, no sunlight.&nbsp; They never wanted to leave their homes, but what else could they do?</p>



<p>Perhaps you’re wondering why I am telling you about mothers who are almost 7,000 miles away.&nbsp; After all, there are desperate parents all around this world.<br><br>I met them just two days ago in Buffalo, New York, in my own country &#8212; a mother and a father weeping over the daughter whose life was stolen in a hateful gun massacre.&nbsp;<br><br>I met Syrian mothers in Jordan who told me that they couldn’t protect their daughters from the soldiers who came to abuse them.</p>



<p>I met a mother in a Kenyan refugee camp who told me of leaving her child’s lifeless body behind in the sand because she only had the strength to carry one of her two children.<br><br>And I will meet the children of Venezuelan parents later today when your First Lady and I visit students whose families have fled their homes.<br><br>It&#8217;s tempting to believe that other people’s problems are theirs to solve alone.&nbsp; What does a terrified mother in Ukraine matter to someone who is oceans away?&nbsp; What does a hungry child in Ecuador matter to a family in New York?&nbsp; What does inequality in the United States matter to young people right here in Quito?</p>



<p>But they do matter.&nbsp; Injustice and corruption, poverty and pollution, disease and despair &#8212; they aren’t contained by any borders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If we’ve learned anything from the COVID-19 pandemic, from these last few years of sickness and sorrow, it’s how one deadly virus can move through the world, how hunger and violence are woven together, how a war in Europe can ripple through stock markets and supermarkets here, how the loss of trees in your Amazon can take a piece of the future from all of us.&nbsp;<br><br>But we’ve seen something else in the past few years as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’ve seen how kindness can spread through something as simple as wearing a mask.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’ve seen calls for injustice [justice] echoing through the streets of cities near and far.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’ve seen countries rise up against tyrants and offer shelter to their neighbors.&nbsp;&nbsp;Unexpected acts of kindness that speak to our very humanity.<br><br>Yes, we are connected, especially in the Americas.&nbsp; If one nation is vulnerable to authorit- &#8212; authoritarianism or a health crisis or poverty, it won’t be long before those same problems reach us all.<br><br>But when nations here in South America embrace democracy, you become the living proof that governments can deliver for the people that they represent, inspiring others to follow your lead.</p>



<p>When parents in every hemisphere don’t have to worry about how they will have to feed their children or hide them from violence, when they can work in their home countries and build their communities, their children can learn and grow and become the leaders and the innovators that we need.<br><br>My husband, Joe, has always said that politics is personal, and that’s why he’s worked so hard to build relationships throughout the world and here in Ecuador.</p>



<p>You know Joe, and I hope that you know that he cares deeply about you.&nbsp; And I do too.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I’m here today.<br><br>The United States is committed to Ecuador.&nbsp; Together &#8212; (applause) &#8212; thank you.&nbsp; Together, we vaccinated your people, and we’re working &#8212; working on strengthening your healthcare system.&nbsp; Together, we’ve trained and mentored entrepreneurs and small businesses, especially those run by women.<br><br>And together, we’ve worked to preserve Ecuador’s precious environment, help more students go to college.&nbsp; And together, we will defend your government from cyberattacks.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And it’s not just Ecuador.&nbsp; The United States, like you, is investing throughout this region.&nbsp; And, like you, we are committed to building rela- &#8212; lasting relationships.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, I will head to Panama and then Costa Rica &#8212; two other critical democracies.&nbsp; From visiting schools and meeting students, to learning about health systems and how they’re serving patients, I’m going to see things that are making lives better.<br><br>And, in June, Joe and I are excited to invite leaders and their spouses to Los Angeles, California, for the Summit of the Americas.</p>



<p>At the summit, our leaders have an ambitious agenda to come together on things like achieving an equitable and sustainable future, building health and pandemic resilience, and strengthening democratic government [governance].<br><br>But let &#8212; today, let me say this: The United States stands with you, the people of Ecuador &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and everyone who believes in education and health, democracy and justice, and working together to build a stronger world for us all.<br><br>There are moments that transcend words; it is often the language of motherhood: A deep ache that just runs down the slope of her shoulders that says, “My child is in danger, and I don’t know what to do.”&nbsp; Or the shift of a jaw, set in determination &#8212; a small shadow that tells the world, “There is nothing &#8212; nothing &#8212; I wouldn’t do to keep my children safe.”<br><br>Sometimes it’s a sigh that resonates from a place I know well, somewhere hidden inside of all parents, where we keep memories of first steps and the sweet, familiar scent of your child resting in your arms.&nbsp; Or it’s a smile that has seen the hard edges of the world but bends towards hope.</p>



<p>No one needs to translate that strength, that yearning, that love.<br><br>Every terrified mother or father, every hungry child, every hopeful student and hardworking person who dreams of a better world, they’re not just “other people.”&nbsp; The threads of their lives are tied to ours, no matter how far apart we are.<br><br>No one can heal the world’s wounds alone &#8212; not the United States, not Ecuador.&nbsp; But we can be the arms of welcome and the hands of kindness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can stand shoulder-to-shoulder and lift each other when we fall.&nbsp; We can and we will.&nbsp; And we will build a better world together.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Thank you, and may God bless you.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>END                    2:35 P.M. ECT</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden Administration Approves First Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/biden-administration-approves-first-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 22:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53629</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Department of Defense (DOD) is sourcing the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)’s request for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé S.A. formula from Zurich, Switzerland to Plainfield, Indiana. DOD is actively working the request to identify commercial aircraft. The Operation Fly Formula shipments will transport the equivalent of up to 1.5 million 8-ounce&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Department of Defense (DOD) is sourcing the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)’s request for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé S.A. formula from Zurich, Switzerland to Plainfield, Indiana. DOD is actively working the request to identify commercial aircraft.</p>



<p>The Operation Fly Formula shipments will transport the equivalent of up to 1.5 million 8-ounce bottles of three formulas—Alfamino® Infant, Alfamino® Junior, and Gerber Good Start® Extensive HA—all of which are hypoallergenic formulas for children with cow’s milk protein allergy. These formulas have been prioritized because they serve a critical medical purpose and are in short supply in the United States because of the Abbott Sturgis plant closure. These shipments will include approximately 246 pallets.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, USDA and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) are authorized to use DOD-contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. In addition, President Biden has directed his Administration to take a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to reopen Abbott Nutrition’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance to allow major formula manufacturers to safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Alfamino.png" alt="" class="wp-image-53631" width="356" height="207" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Alfamino.png 820w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Alfamino.png?resize=615,357 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Alfamino.png?resize=768,446 768w" sizes="(max-width: 356px) 100vw, 356px" /><figcaption>Photo credit: Nestlé S.A.</figcaption></figure></div>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Gerber.png" alt="" class="wp-image-53632" width="128" height="190" /><figcaption>Photo credit: Nestlé S.A.</figcaption></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on FTC Vote to Protect Children’s&#160;Privacy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/statement-from-president-biden-on-ftc-vote-to-protect-childrens-privacy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 20:12:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53626</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the State of the Union I said that it is time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children and demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children.  I want to commend the Federal Trade Commission for unanimously taking a big step in that direction today.    When children and parents access&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In the State of the Union I said that it is time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children and demand tech companies stop collecting personal data on our children.  I want to commend the Federal Trade Commission for unanimously taking a big step in that direction today.    When children and parents access online educational products, they shouldn’t be forced to accept tracking and surveillance to do so.   The FTC is making it clear that such requirements would violate the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, and that the agency will be cracking down on companies that persist in exploiting our children to make money.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Regional Appointments for USDA, EPA, and&#160;HHS</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/president-biden-announces-key-regional-appointments-for-usda-epa-and-hhs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and Department of Health and Human Services (HHS): Joy Kono, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Hawaii Maria Herrera, USDA State Director, Rural Development, California&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and Department of Health and Human Services (HHS):</p>



<ul><li>Joy Kono, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Hawaii</li><li>Maria Herrera, USDA State Director, Rural Development, California</li><li>Casey Sixkiller, EPA Regional Administrator, Region 10</li><li>Joseph Palm, HHS Regional Director, Region 7</li></ul>



<p>These regional appointees will be critical to the President’s efforts to rebuild communities most impacted by the pandemic, the economic recovery, and climate change. They bring deep expertise in their issue areas as well as critical relationships with federal, state, tribal, and local leaders. And, consistent with the President’s commitment to building an administration that looks like America, these regional appointees represent the diversity of America and the communities they serve.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE (USDA)</u></strong></p>



<p>The USDA’s Farm Service Agency implements agricultural policy, administers credit and loan programs, and manages conservation, commodity, disaster, and farm marketing programs in each U.S. State. Its mission is to equitably serve all farmers, ranchers, and agricultural partners through the delivery of effective, efficient agricultural programs for all Americans. State Executive Directors oversee this work, ensuring the needs of local constituents are met and that USDA resources are distributed equitably and fairly.</p>



<p>USDA’s Rural Development mission area is committed to helping improve the economy and quality of life in rural America. State Directors lead offices that offer grants, loans, and loan guarantees to help create jobs and support economic development and essential services.</p>



<p><strong><u>Joy Kono, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Hawaii</u></strong></p>



<p>Joy Kono has over 30 years of managerial and administrative experience in support programs, along with a first-hand understanding of the challenging and diverse agricultural industry of Hawaii. Kono comes from a rural community on the island of Kauai, where her family farmed a variety of vegetables and livestock, ranging from chickens, pigs, and cattle, to truck crops and leafy greens. Kono began work on the farm at 12 years old, spending her college summers working on a ranch. As a dedicated farm family on Kauai, they were awarded Hawaii Farm Bureau’s Farm Family of the Year.</p>



<p>Kono earned a Bachelor’s degree in Agriculture Economics from the University of Hawaii at Manoa and then obtained a Master’s degree in Agribusiness from Santa Clara University.</p>



<p>Kono worked for Kamehameha Schools for the last 20 years; her current position oversees four teams that process over 30,000 applications annually for various programs. Appointed as Senior Director of Education Support Services in 2015, Kono has administered numerous programs that provides crucial support across the state of Hawaii to families and students that apply for over $30 million in aid each year. Kono is currently the board chair for the Hawaii Commission for National and Community Services and has served on the Agriculture Leadership Foundation of Hawaii Board and the Hawaii Farm Bureau Board.</p>



<p><strong><u>Maria Herrera, USDA State Director, Rural Development, California</u></strong></p>



<p>Maria Gallegos Herrera<a> </a>is a proud daughter of farmworker parents who grew up in the rural agricultural communities in the heart of California’s San Joaquin Valley. She joined the Office of Governor Gavin Newsom in 2019 as the Central California Deputy Regional Director of External Affairs and in July of 2021 was promoted to Central California Regional Director.</p>



<p>Herrera previously served as a Community Development Manager at Self-Help Enterprises, a nationally recognized community development organization dedicated to working with low-income families to build and sustain healthy communities. She previously held positions at the Community Water Center and the California Department of Food and Agriculture. Throughout her career, Herrera has tackled water contamination and shortages, improved access to government, and worked to create resilient and sustainable communities through relationship building, community organizing, advocacy, legislation, and technical assistance. Herrera also served on the California Water Commission from 2015 to 2019 and was the recipient of the 2019 Rachel’s Network Inaugural Catalyst Award.</p>



<p><strong><u>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY (EPA)</u></strong></p>



<p>Regional Administrators lead the EPA’s 10 regional offices around the country, each of which is responsible for the execution of EPA programs within a set of several states and territories. EPA regional offices also ensure the views and needs of each region are incorporated into the formulation of agency and national policy.</p>



<p><strong><u>Casey Sixkiller, EPA Regional Administrator, Region 10</u></strong></p>



<p>Casey Sixkiller previously served as Deputy Mayor of the City of Seattle and prior to that as Chief Operating Officer of King County, overseeing the daily operations of the largest city and the largest county in Washington state, each with more than 12,000 employees and an annual budget of $6.5 billion. While at the City, Sixkiller oversaw key elements of the City’s pandemic response including support for vulnerable families, mitigating the impact of the pandemic on city services, and helping scale nation-leading testing and vaccination efforts. At King County, Sixkiller worked to embed measurable equity and social justice deliverables across departments, increase equitable access to public space and transit, and lift up the voices of BIPOC communities in decision making. Sixkiller was the founder and managing partner of Sixkiller Consulting, a Washington, D.C.-based national strategic advisory, public policy, and business development firm.</p>



<p>Sixkiller began his career in public service in Washington, D.C., first working for then-Representative Jim McDermott (D-WA) and later Senator Patty Murray (D-WA). An enrolled citizen of the Cherokee Nation, Sixkiller helped launch the Cherokee Nation’s Washington Office in 2001, serving as the Nation’s lead advocate before Congress and federal agencies. Born and raised in Seattle, Sixkiller is a graduate of Seattle Public Schools and Dartmouth College, and the proud father of Anna, Sam, and Will.</p>



<p>Region 10 serves Alaska, Idaho, Oregon and Washington.</p>



<p><strong><u>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES (HHS)</u></strong><br>Regional Directors lead HHS’s 10 Regional Offices that directly serve state and local organizations. Regional Directors ensure the Department maintains close contact with state, local, and tribal partners and addresses the needs of communities and individuals served through HHS programs and policies.</p>



<p><strong><u>Joseph Palm, HHS Regional Director, Region 7</u></strong></p>



<p>Joseph Palm is a native of Saint Louis, Missouri, with family roots in Wardell, Missouri. Palm received his Bachelors of Communications Studies and Masters in Public Health from Saint Louis University. In 2009, Palm became the Chief of the Office of Minority Health at the Missouri Department of Health and Senior Services. As the Chief, Palm was the key advisor to the Director on various health matters that affect minorities; he also served as a liaison to the Missouri General Assembly and worked with all statewide local public health agencies and elected officials. Palm supervised the Centers for Disease Control (CDC) grant-funded opioid and homicide prevention program, and he has also advised and facilitated the creation of hundreds of mobile COVID-19 testing and vaccination sites across the State of Missouri in uninsured and underserved communities. Palm has also worked on the ground during the Ferguson and Joplin daily recovery operations.</p>



<p>Palm previously worked as the Assistant to the Chief of Staff in the City of Saint Louis Mayor’s Office, as a Legislative Researcher in the Missouri State Capitol, and as an assistant to the Chief of Staff in Missouri’s 1<sup>st</sup> Congressional District Office.</p>



<p>Region 7 serves Iowa, Kansas, Missouri, and Nebraska.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Meeting with Prime Minister Andersson Of Sweden and President Niinistӧ of&#160;Finland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-andersson-of-sweden-and-president-niinist%d3%a7-of-finland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland and warmly welcomed their applications for NATO membership, which will strengthen our collective security.  At this historic moment for both Finland and Sweden, the President underscored his commitment to support both countries as they seek&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Magdalena Andersson of Sweden and President Sauli Niinistö of Finland and warmly welcomed their applications for NATO membership, which will strengthen our collective security.  At this historic moment for both Finland and Sweden, the President underscored his commitment to support both countries as they seek formal NATO accession, including by working with NATO Allies and Congress to welcome them into the Alliance as quickly as possible.  The leaders also discussed their ongoing cooperation on shared global challenges, and their commitment to continued strong support for Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on New Actions to Address Infant Formula&#160;Shortage</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/19/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-new-actions-to-address-infant-formula-shortage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53621</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 12:09 P.M. EDT MR. MUNOZ:&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Thank you for joining us this afternoon for a background press call to discuss yesterday&#8217;s new actions that are going to address the infant formula shortage in the United States and expand access to safe infant formula. This call will be on background, attributable to “senior&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>12:09 P.M. EDT<br><br>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us this afternoon for a background press call to discuss yesterday&#8217;s new actions that are going to address the infant formula shortage in the United States and expand access to safe infant formula.<br><br>This call will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; It&#8217;ll be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.<br><br>On today&#8217;s call, we have [senior administration officials].<br><br>We have a, you know, download at the top on yesterday&#8217;s actions, and then we&#8217;ll take a few questions.<br><br>With that, I&#8217;ll kick it to [senior administration official].</p>



<p><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; President Biden knows that parents across the country are worried about finding enough infant formula to feed their baby.&nbsp; That is why he directed his administration to do everything possible to ensure that there is enough safe infant formula in the country available for families that need it.<br><br></p>



<p>Yesterday, the President invoked the Defense Production Act to ensure that manufacturers have the necessary ingredients to make safe, healthy infant formula here at home.</p>



<p><br>The DPA empowers the government to require suppliers to direct needed resources to infant formula manufacturers before any other customer who may have ordered that good.<br><br>Yesterday, the President gave HHS the authority to order suppliers to direct needed resources to infant formula manufacturers before any other customer who may have ordered that good.<br><br>So with this authority, we can direct firms to prioritize and allocate the production of key infant formula inputs as needed.&nbsp; This can and will help increase production and speed up supply chains.<br><br>Just an example of how this works: There are a range of things needed to make formula &#8212; oil, fat blend, labels, cans.&nbsp; The company that makes one of those items, like a label, have a lot of customers, one of which happens to be infant formula manufacturers.&nbsp; And they are likely a very small share &#8212; those infant formula manufacturers are likely a very small share of the overall market for that good.<br><br>By having DPA authority available for infant formula, we make sure formula manufacturers are at the top of the list for that item and can maintain the higher levels of production that the companies put in place in February to address the shortage caused by the Abbott plant being shut down.<br><br>Additionally, as the Abbott plant in Sturgis, Michigan, ramps up production over the coming weeks and months, there could be a tightening of supplies across key infant formula inputs.&nbsp; DPA authorities, for example, can be used to prioritize production of key equipment that can help suppliers expand.<br><br>And last, with some important context, DPA authorities were invoked similarly at the outset of the COVID-19 pandemic to prioritize needed supplies to fight the pandemic.<br><br>Yesterday, President Biden also announced Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible.<br><br>Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services and U.S. Department of Agriculture will use Department of Defense contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards so it can get to store shelves faster.<br><br>Bypassing traditional cargo routes will speed up the importation and distribution of formula and serve as an immediate support as manufacturers continue to ramp up production.<br><br>These announcements build on previous administration actions, including an agreement by the FDA and Abbott Nutrition detailing next steps to reopen Abbott Sturgis plant, FDA guidance that will allow major formula manufacturers to safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market, efforts to cut red tape and provide consumer flexibility on types of formula they can provide, and calling on the Federal Trade Commission and State Attorney General to crack down on price gouging or unfair market practices.<br><br>This is one of the President&#8217;s top priorities, and the administration will continue working overtime to get more formula to stores as soon as possible.<br><br>Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Let&#8217;s take a few questions.&nbsp; Ali Rogan, PBS.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this call.&nbsp; What have formula companies been telling you about what they need in terms of these raw materials and in terms of flight support?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; <a>So, what the companies have told us is that they have been able to ramp up production quite rapidly since February, and in some instances, 50 percent to 30 percent above their normal production levels.&nbsp; And that is why today we are making more formula in America than we were back in February.</a><br><br>And they &#8212; and, in addition, they have said that they want to be able to maintain this kind of high-octane, high-tempo production level through &#8212; for the months ahead to make sure that we are &#8212; we have adequate supply coming out to the market.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Alex Alper at Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you guys so much for doing this call.&nbsp; You gave examples of products that this could be used for, but could you say specifically which ones the DPA invocation will be used for?<br><br>And as a second sort of follow-up, you mentioned that there could be a tightening of supply for some of these items.&nbsp; Does that mean that currently there is no tightness of supply and that the real issue is just ramping up production capacity and not a lack of these key ingredients?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We are still having active and ongoing conversations with the companies, so I have nothing more specific to report at this time about the specific instances in which we&#8217;re going to be using the authority.&nbsp; What the authority does is empower the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make these individual decisions on a case-by-case basis.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, as to the second point, could you clarify whether there currently is any tightness of supply on these ingredients or if, really, it&#8217;s a, you know, potential future issue?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We are still having active, ongoing conversations with the companies.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Alyssa Rosenberg at Washington Post.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much, Kevin.&nbsp; I know earlier in the week one of the things that the administration was discussing was efforts to monitor supply throughout the country and to attempt to work with retailers to prioritize rural areas or other areas where customers didn&#8217;t have as many options to shop around for formula at multiple stores.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Can you give us an update on what, if any, progress you&#8217;ve made there, or anything you&#8217;ve learned about areas that are in particular need, and what actions are underway to try and get formula to those areas?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We continue to work closely with governors, state WIC agencies, and with retailers to both understand &#8212; for the &#8212; with the retailers.&nbsp; They have been working very closely with us to help us understand where &#8212; where supply is distributed currently in the country.&nbsp; And with the &#8212; with the governors and with the WIC agencies at the state level, they have done tremendous work to provide regulatory flexibility so that customers can access any product that is available in their state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The situation, based on the conversations we&#8217;re having, is very different all around the country.&nbsp; It seems to be very state by state.&nbsp; There are some states in which the local authority, the retailers are saying they are not seeing challenges.&nbsp; And there are some states where, you know, people have identified, have &#8212; have suggested that there could be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it has been interesting to hear the number of states who suggest that they are not actually seeing (inaudible) in their market (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on that &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, Kevin.&nbsp; Can I follow up on that quickly?&nbsp;</p>



<p>In situations where formula is, in fact, short, is the government anticipating asking retailers to shift their stocking plans to try and serve those areas where customers may not have as many choices or options to shop around?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The data has not suggested to us that there is that kind of shortness in any of those geographies at this point, so I have nothing further to report on that.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let&#8217;s go to Maegan Vazquez at CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, can I &#8212; can I just offer one more point on the shelves &#8212; stocking?&nbsp; The data &#8212; there is data out there that &#8212; it is a little bit difficult to interpret the data on shelf availability that retailers and industry analysts typically rely on because the manufacturers have changed the types of products that they are offering out in the market.&nbsp; And so, that is why we are working closely with the retailers and the manufacturers to make &#8212; to understand the distribution right now.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go back to Maegan, CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; On Operation Fly Formula, can you all walk us through some of the logistics in terms of where is this formula being flown into, what communities will get the formula, how is that determined?&nbsp; And generally speaking, when will we see planes start to land with this formula?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to take that?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to take that.&nbsp; So, once we have identified a manufacturer that has available formula, we work with them to secure the specifics.&nbsp; Because enabled &#8212; if we&#8217;re going to use DOD-contracted commercial aircraft, we need to have a pick-up place and a drop-off place, and the amount, and other specifics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it requires some negotiations, again, with the manufacturer of the formula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We work with DOD to identify contracted commercial air &#8212; you know, get them up in the air.&nbsp; And often, they are &#8212; I shouldn’t say “often” &#8212; but they will land at airfields that are close to the factory or a manufacturing facility.&nbsp; It gets loaded onto the aircraft.&nbsp; The manufacturer actually tells us where it needs to be delivered, and that is to one of their facilities here in the United States &#8212; because a portion of it, actually, when it gets offloaded, has to go through FDA inspection.&nbsp; And then we will, from there, work through vendors and retailers to come to that manufacturing facility to pick it up and hopefully get it out to the communities that are most in need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And we are actively in conversations and discussions with manufacturers about where there might be cargo around the world that would be suitable for their procedures that [senior administration official] just laid out.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; A couple more questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Michael Shear with New York Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thank you. &nbsp;I&#8217;d like to push just a little bit more on the question of the &#8212; of the DPA and the materials that you&#8217;re hoping to facilitate to the manufacturers.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s almost impossible to judge whether this has &#8212; is going to do anything until you know whether there is actually a shortage of formula, materials, and ingredients to help prioritize.</p>



<p>So, I mean, I guess the question is: I don&#8217;t see how you can expect us to write about this without telling us if you actually know whether there is a shortage of any materials &#8212; cans, labels, or anything else.&nbsp; And if you don&#8217;t know that there&#8217;s such a shortage, how is this &#8212; why are you even invoking this?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I want to clarify one piece of the DPA authority.&nbsp; This isn&#8217;t just about a situation about shortages, it&#8217;s also about speeding up the delivery through the supply chain.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>A supplier has a lot of different customers, and they may not realize that the infant formula manufacturer is one of those suppliers, especially if they are a second-, third-tier supplier to that infant formula manufacturer.&nbsp; So that gives us the authority to work closer with the infant formula manufacturers and pull stuff through the supply chain faster.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not a situation where you have to identify a shortage; it can also be used to make things faster.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Zeke Miller with AP.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll just &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to add one more point, sorry, on the, like &#8212; on the making things faster.&nbsp; As we have said, we will do things to cut days off of production schedules and timelines to make sure that we are urgently moving quickly to get supply to store shelves.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; To follow up to Mike&#8217;s question there: If the DPA is &#8212; is as significant as you&#8217;re saying, why wait until now to invoke that authority to speed up any &#8212; some of those bottlenecks?&nbsp; And then, you know, why couldn&#8217;t this have been done a couple of months ago?</p>



<p>And then secondly, can you name the states that haven&#8217;t issued WIC waivers yet, please?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, on DPA, we have been clear from the outset that we are going to pull every lever that we can find when we need to deploy a lever to make sure that there is safe infant formula available to the American people.</p>



<p>The invoking of the DPA builds upon a lot of actions and steps that we have already taken.&nbsp; And we continue to look and execute on a range of options that can meaningfully expedite production and speed up supply chains for producing baby formula.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And on your question about the WIC waiver, USDA has a &#8212; has a detailed website that lists what states have taken which actions.&nbsp; Kevin can &#8212; can get that to you, but it&#8217;s on USDA&#8217;s website.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s do one more question.&nbsp; Josh Lederman at NBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Senators Patty Murray and Casey are calling on the administration to appoint basically a &#8220;Baby Formula Czar.&#8221;&nbsp; They say they really want to see a point person who&#8217;s focused exclusively on this issue.</p>



<p>Is the White House open to that idea?&nbsp; Do you have any thoughts on whether that would be useful to further ramping up these efforts at this time?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; As you know, we have been taking really urgent action for the last several months and in recent weeks to do everything we can to get more formula onto U.S. shelves and into the country and coming off of manufacturing lines.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have anything to preview on that today.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp; You know where to find me if you have follow-ups.&nbsp; And have a good day, guys.</p>



<p>12:26 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/19/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-and-section-614a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 19:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE<br><br>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) and Section 614(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961<br><br>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the following authorities, subject to fulfilling the requirements of section 614(a)(3) and section 652 of the FAA, in order to provide assistance to Ukraine:</p>



<p>      (1)  the authority under section 614(a)(1) of the FAA to determine whether it is important to the security interests of the United States to furnish up to $100 million in assistance without regard to any provision of law within the purview of section 614(a)(1) of the FAA; and<br><br>     (2)  the authority under section 506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to $100 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.<br><br>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"> JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-67/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 18:45:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53614</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Rubydee Calvert, of Wyoming, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting for a term expiring January 31, 2028.&#160; (Reappointment) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Kathryn Wheelbarger, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rubydee Calvert, of Wyoming, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting for a term expiring January 31, 2028.&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kathryn Wheelbarger, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice Stephen D. Krasner, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Michael K. Singh, of Illinois, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice J. Robinson West, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jonathan Wingate Burks, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice Eric S. Edelman, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lara E. Montecalvo, of Rhode Island, to be United States Circuit Judge for the First Circuit, vice O. Rogeriee Thompson, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sarah A. L. Merriam, of Connecticut, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Second Circuit, vice Susan L. Carney, retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Elizabeth Wilson Hanes, of Virginia, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Virginia, vice John A. Gibney, Jr., retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Anne M. Nardacci, of New York, to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of New York, vice Gary L. Sharpe, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ana C. Reyes, of the District of Columbia, to be United States District Judge for the District of Columbia, vice Colleen Kollar-Kotelly, retiring.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Senate Passage of Ukraine&#160;Supplemental</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-senate-passage-of-ukraine-supplemental/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 17:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I applaud the Congress for sending a clear&#160;bipartisan&#160;message to the world that the people of the&#160;United States&#160;stand together with the brave people of Ukraine as they defend their democracy and freedom.&#160;The resources that I requested will&#160;allow us to&#160;send even more weapons&#160;and ammunition to Ukraine,&#160;replenish our own stockpile, and support U.S. troops stationed on NATO territory.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I applaud the Congress for sending a clear&nbsp;bipartisan&nbsp;message to the world that the people of the&nbsp;United States&nbsp;stand together with the brave people of Ukraine as they defend their democracy and freedom.&nbsp;The resources that I requested will&nbsp;allow us to&nbsp;send even more weapons&nbsp;and ammunition to Ukraine,&nbsp;replenish our own stockpile, and support U.S. troops stationed on NATO territory. And, I want to thank Leader Schumer, Speaker Pelosi, Leader McConnell, and Leader McCarthy for moving this bill quickly to ensure there is no lapse in funding for these important needs. Together with the contributions of our Allies and partners,&nbsp;we will keep security, economic, food, and humanitarian assistance flowing to Ukraine, across the region, and around the world, and&nbsp;further strengthen Ukraine — both on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.</p>



<p>We have provided a&nbsp;historic amount of security assistance to&nbsp;Ukraine&nbsp;to date, and my Administration will continue to expedite the delivery of additional&nbsp;weapons and equipment for which Congress has provided authority.&nbsp; And today, I am announcing another package of security assistance&nbsp;that will provide additional&nbsp;artillery, radars, and other equipment&nbsp;to Ukraine, which they are already using so effectively on the battlefield. These&nbsp;weapons and equipment&nbsp;will&nbsp;go&nbsp;directly to the front lines of freedom in Ukraine, and reiterate&nbsp;our strong support for the brave people of Ukraine as they defend their country against Russia’s ongoing aggression.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
