<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 18:48:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at U.S. Coast Guard Change of Command&#160;Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/01/remarks-by-president-biden-at-u-s-coast-guard-change-of-command-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 18:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:23 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for giving my speech.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And I’m going to sit down.&#160; (Laughter.) You probably wish I would; it’s kind of getting a little warm in here.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160;&#160; Today we witness a tradition long-standing in the United States Coast Guard: the change of command as a new&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:23 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Secretary, for giving my speech.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I’m going to sit down.&nbsp; (Laughter.) You probably wish I would; it’s kind of getting a little warm in here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Today we witness a tradition long-standing in the United States Coast Guard: the change of command as a new admiral assumes the leadership of our nation’s “oldest, continuous seagoing service.”&nbsp; And it is both a connection to our earliest days as a nation and a new milestone in our history.&nbsp; We use those phrases lightly, but this is a big deal.<br><br>Admiral Linda Fagan, Coast Guard Academy Class of 1985.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Class of ’85, stand up if you’re out there.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As they say in Southern Delaware, “You all knew it then, didn’t you?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Well, you’ve crewed the Polar Star, a heavy icebreaker.&nbsp; You’ve captained the Port of New York.&nbsp; You’ve served on all seven continents.&nbsp; And you’ve commanded the Coast Guard operations in the Pacific.&nbsp; You’ve served as Vice Commandant of the Coast Guard.<br><br>Throughout her decades of service, she has demonstrated an exceptional skill, integrity, and commitment to our country.&nbsp; She upholds the highest traditions of the United States Coast Guard.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This moment of acceleration of global challenges and hybrid threats that don’t stop at any border, there’s no one more qualified to lead the proud women and men of the Coast Guard, and she will also be the first woman to serve as Commandant of the Coast Guard &#8212; the first woman to lead any branch of the United States Armed Forces.&nbsp; And it’s about time.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The Secretary of Defense, when he sent me the name, I said, “What in the hell took you so long?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; Really, congratulations.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, with her trailblazing career, Admiral Fagan shows that young people &#8212; young people entering service that we mean it when we say there are no doors &#8212; no doors closed to women.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I might add that includes her daughter, Coast Guard Lieutenant Aileen Fagan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Now that you’re &#8212; I thoroughly embarrassed you, haven’t I?&nbsp; Because you look like my son used to look when they’d say, “Vice President Biden and his son, Major Biden.”&nbsp; And he’d go, “Oh, Dad.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; It’s not meant to embarrass; it’s meant to compliment.<br><br>Every little kid growing up today who dreams of serving their country will know that this is what an Admiral and a Service Chief of the United States Armed Forces looks like.&nbsp; I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; It matters.<br><br>I concluded, when I ran, by the way, that I’d make sure that my government, my administration, and the service looked like America.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank you, Admiral Fagan, for taking the helm during this critical moment and for all that you’ve done throughout your career to open the doors of opportunity just a little bit wider to allowing those following behind you a way through.<br><br>I want to acknowledge your family.&nbsp; They’re here to support you and supported you every day, just as they have throughout your career.<br><br>John &#8212; where &#8212; John, where are you?&nbsp; I’m going to embarrass you.&nbsp; John, stand up, will you?&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; John, we don’t know one another, but we have something in common: We both married way above our station.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And Moira and Aileen, and your parents, Jon and Loann. &nbsp;Where &#8212; where’s Mom and Dad?<br><br>I watched Dad watching that young woman in the Honor Guard coming around with that rifle.&nbsp; You did &#8212; you had to &#8212; you moved quickly, Dad.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; All kidding aside, thank you for the values you instilled.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It matters a great deal to both &#8212; both of you.&nbsp; And I &#8212; you know, from the time that she was a swab, it &#8212; it just is amazing.&nbsp; I want to thank you for sharing Admiral Fagan with us<br><br>And, Admiral Schultz, thank you for leading our Coast Guard as Commandant over the last four years &#8212; a stellar capstone to your nearly four decades of outstanding service to the nation.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I got the advantage of doing &#8212; for, I think, the third time in my career &#8212; the Academy Commencement.&nbsp; And your la- &#8212; second-to-last one.&nbsp; And he also has a young man &#8212; a good-looking boy, man &#8212; who is a &#8212; who was also commissioned at the time.&nbsp; So, I don’t think we’ve seen the last of this.&nbsp;<br><br>To Dawn and to all the children &#8212; Lindsey, Kelsey, Anna- &#8212; is it Annaliese?&nbsp; I hope I’m pronouncing it correctly &#8212; and is that right? &#8212; and Zach &#8212; Zachary and Ensign Shultz.&nbsp; Where’s Ensign Shultz?&nbsp; Is he here?<br><br>ADMIRAL SHULTZ:&nbsp; He’s underway, sir.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He’s underway.&nbsp; (Laughter.) &nbsp;For those of you &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; For those of you who are not in the military, “underway” doesn’t mean they’re late on the way here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; If you say “underway” in my family, they think, “Where the hell are they?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, it’s not just those who wear the uniform who serve &#8212; and I’ve said this many times &#8212; it’s the whole family.&nbsp;<br><br>As an English poet said, “They also serve who only stand and wait.”&nbsp; “They also serve who only stand and wait.”<br><br>Many times, your son, your &#8212; was on &#8212; your daughter was on patrol somewhere, and you’re wondering &#8212; your wife or your mom.&nbsp; You stand there and you wait.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Or the year my son was in Iraq.&nbsp; And the year before that, when he was &#8212; eight months, he was &#8212; six months, he was in &#8212; in the Balkans.&nbsp; It’s what my moth- &#8212; my wife would stand there at the coffee &#8212; at the sink, drinking that coffee, just saying a prayer every day.&nbsp; It’s what all of you &#8212; we owe you.&nbsp; We owe you big.<br><br>Thank you for all that you’ve done for the country over the years.&nbsp; We’ve asked a lot of you, and you’ve risen to every challenge.</p>



<p>I also want to thank the women and men of the Coast Guard who are standing the watch today and every day, here at home and around the globe, including my Military Aide who is here today &#8212; Lieutenant Commander Jayna McCarron.&nbsp; Where is she?&nbsp; I’m going to embarrass the devil out of her, but she &#8212; (applause).&nbsp; I asked &#8212; she’s hiding somewhere.&nbsp; I met her at the Academy and asked her to come with us.</p>



<p>Our nation is grateful to all of you for your years of service and your continued service.&nbsp; And as we look to the years and the decades ahead, the Coast Guard is only going to play an increasingly prominent role in our homeland and our national security.</p>



<p>The challenges we face continue to evolve, and the choices we make today are literally going to shape the direction of the world throughout the 21st century.&nbsp; What we do the next 10 years are going to lay it down.&nbsp; We’ll be calling on the Coast Guard more and more frequently, as you know, to underwrite the international maritime security; to keep the sea lanes open and secure; to uphold a rules-based international order; to protect the waters, as was mentioned, through which nearly one quarter of United States’ GDP is transported; to manage the impact of changing climate becoming more extreme &#8212; more extreme weather and growing migration flows.</p>



<p>In addition, you see what’s happening in the Arctic.&nbsp; The Arctic is going to change drastically and become much &#8212; a place that is going to also potentially generate potential conflict, in terms of dominating the Arctic as it melts.</p>



<p>The Coast Guard is central element to the administration’s new Indo-Pacific Strategy, building partnerships with nations throughout the region to take on illegally and unreported and unregulated fishing, reported the &#8212; the shared threats that conduct and coordinate human, environmental missions.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I met yesterday with the Prime Minister of New Zealand.&nbsp; Part of what we’re initiating now is there’s another country that is literally eating up all of the fishing grounds, literally overfishing everything.&nbsp; We’ve decided we have to be engaged, and we have to be engaged with our Coast Guard and our military, our Navy.</p>



<p>And with the climate change accelerating, we’re seeing more frequent and more intense storms that carry devastating impacts across our nation and throughout the hemisphere.</p>



<p>Admiral Shultz, you oversaw the Coast Guard’s response to the most active hurricane season on record, in 2020.&nbsp; Thirty named storms, twelve of which impacted the Gulf and Atlantic coasts.&nbsp; And the Coast Guard was there for every single one of them.</p>



<p>And with today marking the official first day of the&nbsp;<s>2020</s>&nbsp;[2022] hurricane season, we’re anticipating the seventh straight year of above-average hurricane activity in the Atlantic.</p>



<p>We turned to the Coast Guard to help facilitate our national response to COVID-19 &#8212; from helping with vaccinations to protecting ports and maritime supply chains.&nbsp; And we rely &#8212; we rely on the Coast Guard to interdict illicit drug shipments at sea before they can enter the United States, and respond to the greatly increased migration flows from the Americas.</p>



<p>Folks and Admiral Fagan, we know &#8212; we know there is more work to be done to ensure the Coast Guard and all the branches of our Armed Forces reflect the full strength and diversity, including at the highest levels of our leadership.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>When Admiral Fagan commissioned in 1985, only five years after the first women graduated from the Academy, she was one of just 16 commissioned female Ensigns &#8212; only 8 percent of her graduating class.&nbsp; She was the only woman aboard Polar Star for the first set of orders.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Currently, the Corps of Cadets at the Academy &#8212; more than 1,000 cadets strong &#8212; 40 percent are women. &nbsp;Forty percent are women.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Admiral Fagan is part of a generation of pioneering women in the force, and this ceremony is historic and f- &#8212; and a historic first in that effort, a promotion earned through a career of outstanding leadership and accomplishment.</p>



<p>Now we need to keep working to make sure Admiral Fagan may be the first but not the only person.&nbsp; We need to see more women at the highest levels of command in the Coast Guard and across every service in the Armed Forces.</p>



<p>We need to ensure women have an opportunity to succeed and thrive throughout their professional careers, and that means providing support and resources so women can compete fairly and fully for promotions and make sure women are not penalized in their career for having children.</p>



<p>It also means creating an environment where every member of the Armed Forces feels safe in the ranks, including from sexual assault and harassment, and where their contributions are respected.</p>



<p>So thank you again, Admiral Shultz, for your dedicated service to our nation and your steady leadership through the years at the Coast Guard.&nbsp; He’s been called to &#8212; into &#8212; into new missions and asked to serve in extremely difficult circumstances.</p>



<p>And thank you, Admiral Fagan, for accepting this next mission and this great responsibility to lead the women and men of the Coast Guard &#8212; the finest Coast Guard in the world.</p>



<p>The Coast Guard is Semper Paratus &#8212; “always ready.”&nbsp; Always ready.&nbsp; I know that you’re ready for all that’s ahead of you, and I look forward to watching you execute your job.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>11:36 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Delivering on Tulsa Commitments to Build Black&#160;Wealth</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/fact-sheet-delivering-on-tulsa-commitments-to-build-black-wealth/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 18:20:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, commemorating the centennial of the Tulsa Race Massacre, President Biden announced two expanded efforts to help Black families and communities build wealth through homeownership and entrepreneurship. The President: Launched a first-of-its-kind interagency initiative to address inequity in home appraisals, charged with identifying and utilizing the levers at the federal government’s disposal to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, commemorating the centennial of the Tulsa Race Massacre, President Biden announced two expanded efforts to help Black families and communities build wealth through homeownership and entrepreneurship.</p>



<p>The President:</p>



<ul><li>Launched a first-of-its-kind interagency initiative to address inequity in home appraisals, charged with identifying and utilizing the levers at the federal government’s disposal to root out discrimination in the appraisal and homebuying process.<br></li><li>Announced a goal of increasing the share of federal contracts going to small disadvantaged businesses (SDBs), including Black- and brown-owned small businesses, by 50 percent by 2025.</li></ul>



<p>Since then, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken swift action:<br><br><strong><u>Rooting out bias in the home appraisal process</u></strong><br><br>Homeownership is the primary contributor to building wealth for Black and brown households, but bias in home valuations limits the ability of Black and brown families to enjoy the financial returns associated with homeownership, thereby contributing to the already sprawling racial wealth gap.<br><br>In March, the Biden-Harris Administration released the&nbsp;PAVE Action Plan,&nbsp;which, once enacted, will represent the most wide-ranging set of reforms ever put forward to advance equity in the home appraisal process.&nbsp;The Action Plan details a set of more than 20 commitments and actions across all stages of the home appraisal process, including making the appraisal industry more accountable; empowering consumers with critical information and assistance if they receive a valuation that is lower than expected; preventing algorithmic bias in home valuation; cultivating an appraiser profession that is well-trained and looks like the communities it serves; and leveraging federal data and expertise to inform policy, practice, and research on appraisal bias. You can read the PAVE Action Plan <a href="https://pave.hud.gov/">here</a>.<br><br><strong><u>Advancing equity in federal procurement</u></strong><br><br>Increasing federal spending with underserved businesses not only helps more Americans realize their entrepreneurial dreams, but also narrows persistent wealth disparities. According to an&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cea/blog/2021/12/01/the-benefits-of-increased-equity-in-federal-contracting/">analysis</a> from the White House Council of Economic Advisers, differences in business ownership account for 20 percent of the wealth gap between average white and Black households.<br><br>Recognizing this historic opportunity, the Biden-Harris Administration adopted a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/02/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-reforms-to-increase-equity-and-level-the-playing-field-for-underserved-small-business-owners/">bold set of reforms</a> to meet the President’s target of increasing the share of federal contracts to SDBs and increase opportunity for all underserved businesses. These actions include:</p>



<ul><li>For the first time, asking agencies to increase their goals so that governmentwide spending in FY22 results in 11 percent of contracting dollars being awarded to small disadvantaged businesses, up from the current statutory goal of 5 percent<br></li><li>Releasing, for the first time, disaggregated data of federal contracting spend by race/ethnicity of business owner, a powerful transparency and management tool<br></li><li>Implementing major changes to the federal government’s use of “category management” to boost contracting opportunities for underserved small businesses<br></li><li>Increasing the number of new entrants to the federal marketplace and reversing declines in the small business supplier base.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by the Vice President at the Global Water Security White House Action Plan&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/01/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-global-water-security-white-house-action-plan-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 17:41:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54576</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Indian Treaty RoomEisenhower Executive Office Building 12:03 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you all.&#160; Thank you, Sonia.&#160; And this whole &#8212; what a powerful group of American leaders.&#160; I’m honored to be with all of you this morning and in this fight.&#160; So thank you, each one of you, for the work&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Indian Treaty Room<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></p>



<p>12:03 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; Thank you, Sonia.&nbsp; And this whole &#8212; what a powerful group of American leaders.&nbsp; I’m honored to be with all of you this morning and in this fight.&nbsp; So thank you, each one of you, for the work that you are doing.<br><br>I was remembering and talking with my team about how even when I was in the Senate, you know, we would talk about this issue in some of the committee hearings when we were reviewing nominees, and the connection between this issue and national security.&nbsp; And people laughed it off.&nbsp; “Oh, is that a serious issue?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is there really a connection there?”&nbsp; And it&#8217;s only been a few short years, where people are &#8212; because of the &#8212; the extreme nature of it and the rapidity of the &#8212; of the time that has passed, in terms of the escalation of the issue, that people are finally understanding what you all have been working on for years and years and years.&nbsp; So, thank you for that, and to everyone here.<br><br>So, as many of you know, I am a daughter of California.&nbsp; And as a result, many things have probably flowed from that &#8212; pardon the pun &#8212; but one of them has been: I have been, my entire life, acutely aware of the reality of water scarcity.<br><br>I remember I was, I think, 12 &#8212; in middle school, about that age &#8212; 13 &#8212; when we experienced an extreme drought in California.&nbsp; And I remember watching in the Oakland Hills, northern California, the landscape turning from green to brown.&nbsp; And everyone &#8212; from my mother, our teachers, the radio DJs &#8212; KDIA “Lucky 13” &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; saying how important it was to conserve water.&nbsp;<br><br>And we understood that each of us had a personal responsibility, no matter our age, to take the matter seriously and to understand that with the extreme nature of the harm that results from drought, we each have a personal responsibility that may include and require some sacrifice.&nbsp; And I remember how unsettling it was to imagine how our access to a resource so basic and essential as water, how that could become so uncertain and we could not take it for granted.<br><br>It is a reality that more and more people in our nation are, however, experiencing and understanding this issue every day.<br><br>As our planet warms and weather patterns change, extreme drought is becoming increasingly common.<br><br>At this moment, about 90 million Americans are living under drought conditions.&nbsp; And the start of summer is still weeks away.&nbsp;<br><br>Across the West, we have seen the terrible cost of the climate crisis.&nbsp; And I have visited many of the places where we have seen the wildfires, where families have lost their homes and their loved ones, where entire communities have been wiped out.&nbsp;<br><br>I have met with and talked with the firefighters.&nbsp; My brother-in-law is a firefighter in California.&nbsp; And many of them who work 24-hour shifts in some of the most dangerous conditions that you can imagine to keep us safe.<br><br>Farmers and agricultural workers who lost their livelihoods because the rains just simply did not come.&nbsp; And communities who have felt firsthand how the economic impact of water scarcity ripples out, driving up prices and driving a real sense of urgency about what also results in terms of lack of opportunity.<br><br>And that’s not all.&nbsp; Our nation also faces water insecurity challenges beyond those driven by climate change.&nbsp;<br><br>For decades, of course, our country has chronically underinvested in water infrastructure, depriving many communities of reliable access to safe drinking water.<br><br>Take the issue, which many of us worked on together, of lead pipes.&nbsp; Lead is a poison.&nbsp; For adults, drinking water contaminated with lead &#8212; it can lead to an increase in blood pressure and a decrease in kidney function.&nbsp; For children, it can stunt growth, slow down learning, and cause irreparable damage to the brain.<br><br>And yet, today, as many as 10 million households get their water through lead pipes and service lines in America, as do up to 400,000 schools and childcare facilities.&nbsp; As a result, our country today &#8212; in this country, more than half of children under the age of six are at risk of lead exposure.&nbsp; Obviously, this is unconscionable and utterly unacceptable.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Every person in our nation deserves access to clean water, and every community in our nation deserves water security.<br><br>As a United States senator, I introduced legislation to advance smart water policy, to invest in efficiency and recycling technology, and to take on the problem of lead pipes.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Over the past year, I have met with many world leaders to discuss these issues &#8212; from the King of Jordan to the Prime Minister of Vietnam, to the President of Israel.<br><br>Our administration recognizes the urgency of water security, which is why our President, Joe Biden, invested over $63 billion in our nation&#8217;s water infrastructure through the bipartisan infrastructure law to put us on a path to remove every lead pipe in our country within the next 10 years and to fund water efficiency, water reuse, and groundwater storage projects &#8212; hopefully emphasizing underwater storage projects &#8212; in communities across our nation.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition, our administration has made drought resilience a priority.&nbsp; Today, we are releasing the one-year report of the first ever Drought Resilience Interagency Working Group.&nbsp; It will help chart our nation&#8217;s path forward to a more sustainable future.&nbsp;<br><br>Since we took office, our administration has made important progress in protecting water security here at home.&nbsp; We also recognize how important it is to extend that work beyond our nation&#8217;s borders.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, billions of people around the world do not have access to clean, safe water.&nbsp; And in the coming years, climate change, population growth, urbanization, and environmental degradation will only drive that number higher.<br><br>By 2030, almost half of the world&#8217;s population will struggle to meet their water needs.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; Almost half of the world&#8217;s population will struggle to meet their needs &#8212; to have access to water.&nbsp; And it will, of course, have then a profound impact on America&#8217;s interests around the globe.&nbsp;<br><br>Water insecurity makes our world less stable.&nbsp; When water is scarce, it becomes more difficult for communities to produce food, as these experts have talked about, more difficult to protect public health and to drive economic growth.&nbsp; This, in turn, as has been discussed, can lead to mass migration, which can put significant pressure on neighboring communities.&nbsp;<br><br>Water insecurity also makes our world less safe.&nbsp; Disputes between countries or communities over limited water resources can, predictably and by extension, over time provoke armed conflict.<br><br>So let&#8217;s get in front of this.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s take it seriously.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s understand the various ramifications of this issue.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s also deal with the reality that within the variety of issues that are presented, there is the issue of equity &#8212; because finally we know that water insecurity makes our world less equitable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Think about it this way: In many countries, the responsibility for collecting water disproportionately falls on women and girls.&nbsp; Worldwide, women and girls spend 200 million hours a day &#8212; 200 million hours a day &#8212; gathering water.</p>



<p>That is 200 million hours that could have been spent &#8212; we often, around this place, talk about opportunity costs; let’s have that discussion.</p>



<p>It is 200 million hours a day that could be spent by those women and girls in school, at work, or at home with loved ones.&nbsp; And unless we take action to make water more accessible for communities around the world, that number will only grow in the coming years.&nbsp;<br><br>So it comes down to this: Many of our most fundamental national security interests depend on water security.&nbsp; And that is why, today, we are releasing our Action Plan on Global Water Security.</p>



<p>This Action Plan will cement America’s role of leadership on water security issues.&nbsp; And it will do so first by fully committing our nation to the collective fight to provide access to safe water, hygiene, and sanitation services in every community in every country.</p>



<p>Second, by sharing our world-leading water data, which we are collecting on the ground, literally, and through satellite technology &#8212; collecting that data and sharing it, and technical expertise that comes with that, with the international community to help manage and preserve global water resources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And third, by using our nation&#8217;s considerable diplomatic resources &#8212; the great leader of USAID; we have so many leaders &#8212; to elevate water security as an international priority.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This action plan will help our country prevent conflict and advance cooperation among nations, increase equity and economic growth, and make our world more inclusive and resilient.&nbsp;<br><br>The past two and a half years during the pandemic have demonstrated that our world is more interconnected and interdependent than ever before.&nbsp; Water scarcity is a global problem, and it must be met with a global solution.<br><br>So, today, we make clear: The United States will be a leader in the solution.<br><br>Thank you all for your partnership in this fight.&nbsp; Together, I know we will create a future in which every person and every community has access to our world’s most precious resource.</p>



<p>Thank you all.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 12:15 P.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Fourth Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/president-biden-announces-fourth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 17:29:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54568</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 4.6 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of  Bubs Australia infant formula. Additional deliveries will follow. Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing two flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Bubs Australia infant formulas&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 4.6 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of  Bubs Australia infant formula. Additional deliveries will follow</em>.</p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing two flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Bubs Australia infant formulas from Melbourne, Australia to Pennsylvania and California on June 9 and June 11 respectively. This delivery will include 380,000 pounds of Bubs Australia infant formula, approximately 4.6 million 8-ounce bottles. Additional deliveries of Bubs Australia Infant formula will be announced in the coming days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last week, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Bubs Australia can export infant formula. Under this increased flexibility, Bubs Australia plans to export to the United States enough powdered formula to produce 27.5 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of several varieties of its infant formulas,&nbsp;including Bubs Organic Infant Formula S1, Bubs Organic Follow On Formula S2, Bubs Supreme Infant Formula, Supreme Follow On Formula, Bubs Goat Milk Infant Formula S1, and Bubs Goat Milk Follow On Formula S2.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) are authorized to use Department of Defense (DOD)-contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. Earlier today, the President announced a third Operation Fly Formula mission to air ship approximate 3.7 million 8-ounce equivalents of Kendamil infant formula,<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA to reopen Abbott Nutrition’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1294" height="626" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?w=640" alt="" class="wp-image-54573" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png 1294w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=615,298 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=768,372 768w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=1270,614 1270w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=1180,571 1180w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/bbypow.png?resize=1038,502 1038w" sizes="(max-width: 1294px) 100vw, 1294px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/01/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 17:02:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961&#160; By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to the Secretary of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section&nbsp;506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $700 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Additional Security Assistance to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-additional-security-assistance-to-ukraine-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 16:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The people of Ukraine continue to inspire the world with their courage and resolve as they fight bravely to defend their country and their democracy against Russian aggression. The United States will stand with our Ukrainian partners and continue to provide Ukraine with weapons and equipment to defend itself. &#160; Today, I am announcing a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The people of Ukraine continue to inspire the world with their courage and resolve as they fight bravely to defend their country and their democracy against Russian aggression. The United States will stand with our Ukrainian partners and continue to provide Ukraine with weapons and equipment to defend itself. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I am announcing a significant new security assistance package to provide timely and critical aid to the Ukrainian military. Thanks to the additional funding for Ukraine, passed with overwhelmingly bipartisan support in the U.S. Congress, the United States will be able to keep providing Ukraine with more of the weapons that they are using so effectively to repel Russian attacks. This new package will arm them with new capabilities and advanced weaponry, including HIMARS with battlefield munitions, to defend their territory from Russian advances. We will continue to lead the world in providing historic assistance to support Ukraine’s fight for freedom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Third Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/president-biden-announces-third-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 16:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[United Airlines will air ship approximately 3.7 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula&#160; Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration has arranged the third Operation Fly Formula flight for the first shipment of Kendamil infant formula entering the United States. United Airlines has agreed to transport Kendamil formula free of charge from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>United Airlines will air ship approximately 3.7 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration has arranged the third Operation Fly Formula flight for the first shipment of Kendamil infant formula entering the United States. United Airlines has agreed to transport Kendamil formula free of charge from Heathrow Airport in London to multiple airports across the country over a three-week period. These are the first Operation Formula Flight to be donated by an airline carrier.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These Operation Fly Formula flights donated by United Airlines will contain over 300,000 pounds or approximately 3.7 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula and will begin shipping on June 9. These flights will contain approximately 3.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil Classic Stage 1 and 540,000 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil Organic.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Kendamil formula available through Operation Fly Formula will be distributed and available for purchase at selected US retailers nationwide, as well as online. This first shipment, which includes Kendamil Classic and Kendamil Organic formula, will be available at Target stores across the country in the coming weeks.&nbsp;Last week, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Kendal Nutricare can import infant formula under the Kendamil brand. Kendal Nutricare has announced that they will export up to 2 million cans of Kendamil infant formula – the equivalent of at least 54 million 8-ounce bottles to the United States. Parents can learn more about Kendamil infant formula at&nbsp;<a href="https://kendamil.com/">https://kendamil.com/</a>&nbsp;and visit the United States website at&nbsp;<a href="https://us.kendamil.com/">https://us.kendamil.com/</a>&nbsp;for updates and information on retail locations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) are authorized to use Department of Defense (DOD)-contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. To date, Operation Fly Formula has brought in the equivalent of 1.5 million 8-ounce bottles of infant formula to the U.S.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA to reopen Abbott Nutrition’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>



<p>Kendamil Classic First Infant Milk 900g / 31.7 oz.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="977" height="977" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png" alt="" class="wp-image-54540" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png 977w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png?resize=615,615 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png?resize=1200,1200 1200w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png?resize=640,640 640w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk1.png?resize=850,850 850w" sizes="(max-width: 977px) 100vw, 977px" /></figure>



<p>Kendamil Organic First Infant Milk 800g / 28.2 oz.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="977" height="977" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-54541" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png 977w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png?resize=615,615 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png?resize=1200,1200 1200w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png?resize=640,640 640w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/milk2.png?resize=850,850 850w" sizes="(max-width: 977px) 100vw, 977px" /></figure>



<p>Kendamil Goat First Infant Milk 800g / 28.2 oz.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="977" height="977" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png" alt="" class="wp-image-54542" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png 977w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png?resize=615,615 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png?resize=768,768 768w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png?resize=1200,1200 1200w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png?resize=640,640 640w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Milk3.png?resize=850,850 850w" sizes="(max-width: 977px) 100vw, 977px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on ISM Manufacturing Report for&#160;May</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/statement-by-president-biden-on-ism-manufacturing-report-for-may/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 16:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I have long said that making more in the United States is key to any serious strategy to prevent the kinds of supply disruptions that have led to price spikes for American families this year. When&#160;we make more here at home, we make our supply chains more resilient and help avoid the kinds of disruptions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I have long said that making more in the United States is key to any serious strategy to prevent the kinds of supply disruptions that have led to price spikes for American families this year. When&nbsp;we make more here at home, we make our supply chains more resilient and help avoid the kinds of disruptions that have driven up prices in the wake of the pandemic. It is why my economic plan has prioritized American manufacturing and resilient supply chains, and has helped usher in an historic American manufacturing boom. Today, we learned that American manufacturing continued to grow in May. Since I took office, we’ve added 545,000 manufacturing jobs—and more manufacturing jobs were created in 2021 than in any year in nearly 30 years. This didn’t happen by accident—this is a direct result of my economic plan to grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out. Congress should take the next step by swiftly passing the Bipartisan Innovation Act, which is going to help lower prices, and make sure that the next generation of innovation and advanced manufacturing happens right here in America, with American workers.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the 101st Anniversary of the Tulsa Race&#160;Massacre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-101st-anniversary-of-the-tulsa-race-massacre/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 15:58:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last year, on this day, I traveled to Tulsa, Oklahoma, to tell a story that for too long was shrouded in silence in our history books. I had the honor of meeting with Mother Randle, Mother Fletcher, and Mr. Van Ellis, who were all just children 101 years ago when their thriving neighborhood of Greenwood&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Last year, on this day, I traveled to Tulsa, Oklahoma, to tell a story that for too long was shrouded in silence in our history books. I had the honor of meeting with Mother Randle, Mother Fletcher, and Mr. Van Ellis, who were all just children 101 years ago when their thriving neighborhood of Greenwood was raided, firebombed, and destroyed by a violent white supremacist mob.<br> <br>Today, we remember the hell that was unleashed that night. This was not a riot, it was a massacre. As many as 300 Black Americans were killed, and nearly 10,000 were left destitute. Homes, businesses, and churches were burned. A generation of Black wealth was extinguished. In the years that followed, even as Greenwood worked to rebuild, discrimination was systematically embedded in our laws and policies, locking Black residents out of opportunity and ensuring that the attack on Black families and Black wealth persisted across generations.<br> <br>I went to Greenwood—the first President to visit since the massacre—to help fill the silence. Because in silence, wounds deepen. In Greenwood, I called on all of us to reflect on the deep roots of domestic terrorism and hate in our nation and to recommit to combating systemic racism across our country and institutions. As part of that work, I announced two expanded efforts to help communities like Greenwood build wealth—an aggressive effort to combat racial discrimination in housing, and a bold commitment to increase the share of federal contracts going to small disadvantaged businesses, including Black- and brown-owned small businesses, by 50 percent by 2025.<br> <br>In the last year, my Administration has announced more than 20 actions from federal agencies to root out bias in home appraisals. We’ve strengthened lending programs that help address the corrosive impacts of redlining and other forms of discrimination that have extracted wealth from Black neighborhoods. We have also made significant progress to ensure we deliver on our promise to use the power of federal procurement to expand business opportunities for small disadvantaged businesses, including Black-owned businesses. That work—and all of our efforts to build wealth and opportunity for communities like Greenwood—continues.<br> <br>We cannot bury pain and trauma forever. As I said in Tulsa, great nations do not hide from their histories. We are a great nation, and by reckoning with and remedying the injustices of the past, America will become greater still.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Launches Initiative to Modernize Building Codes, Improve Climate Resilience, and Reduce Energy&#160;Costs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-initiative-to-modernize-building-codes-improve-climate-resilience-and-reduce-energy-costs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54480</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Building Codes Initiative will boost resilience to the impacts of climate change, lower utility bills for homes and businesses, and prioritize underserved communities Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a National Initiative to Advance Building Codes that will help state, local, Tribal, and territorial governments adopt the latest, current building codes and standards, enabling&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>New Building Codes Initiative will boost resilience to the impacts of climate change, lower utility bills for homes and businesses, and prioritize underserved communities</em></p>



<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a National Initiative to Advance Building Codes that will help state, local, Tribal, and territorial governments adopt the latest, current building codes and standards, enabling communities to be more resilient to hurricanes, flooding, wildfires, and other extreme weather events that are intensifying due to climate change.</p>



<p>Modern building codes and standards provide a range of smart design and construction methods that save lives, reduce property damage, and lower utility bills—for example, by ensuring that roofs can withstand hurricane winds, that construction materials are resistant to flood damage, and that insulation keeps heating and cooling costs low. With extreme weather events threatening millions of homes each year, and taking a greater toll on underserved communities, every dollar invested in building code adoption provides <a href="https://www.nibs.org/projects/natural-hazard-mitigation-saves-2019-report">eleven times more</a> in savings by reducing damage and helping communities recover more quickly.<br><br>Additionally, modernized energy codes can save households an average of <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/secretary-granholm-announces-new-building-energy-codes-save-consumers-money-reduce-impacts">$162 dollars each year</a> on utility bills, which is especially significant in reducing energy burden for low-income households. Unfortunately, nearly <a href="https://www.fema.gov/sites/default/files/documents/fema_building-codes-strategy.pdf">two out of every three communities</a> in the U.S. have not adopted the latest building codes and, as a result, are vulnerable to climate impacts and higher energy costs.</p>



<p>President Biden is committed to lowering costs for families and protecting communities from extreme weather—especially communities that have long been underserved and are disproportionately impacted by climate change. Earlier this year, President Biden’s National Climate Task Force approved the new National Initiative to Advance Building Codes to accelerate the adoption of modern building codes to improve resiliency, create good-paying jobs, and lower energy bills. Through this initiative, the Biden-Harris Administration will:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Comprehensively review federal funding and financing of building construction,</strong> to ensure federally-supported housing and other building projects follow modern building codes and standards to the greatest extent feasible, while creating good-quality jobs and advancing Administration efforts to boost affordable housing supply, with agencies reporting to the National Climate Task Force on progress. For example, the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) will promote resilient and efficient building standards in new construction supported by Community Development Block Grant-Disaster Recovery funds, which primarily aid low- and moderate-income persons in disaster recovery.<br></li><li><strong>Harness $225 million in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</strong> <strong>funding</strong> for the Department of Energy (DOE) to support implementation of updated building energy codes and create good-quality jobs, including through workforce training partnerships and direct support to state and local agencies, while prioritizing the needs of disadvantaged communities and advancing the President’s Justice40 Initiative.<br></li><li><strong>Provide incentives and support for communities to adopt current building codes and standards</strong> by providing technical assistance, implementing proven strategies and best practices—such as those in the new Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) Building Codes Strategy—across all relevant agencies in the federal government, and using mapping tools that help track code adoption based on energy efficiency and local hazards such as flood, earthquake, tornado, and hurricane risk.<br></li><li><strong>Lead by example across the federal building portfolio</strong>, by seizing opportunities to advance “above-code” resilience and energy efficiency standards in new projects, as well as developing the first Federal Building Performance Standards to help achieve net-zero emissions across new and existing federal buildings by 2045.<br></li></ul>



<p>To announce the National Initiative to Advance Building Codes, FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell and Deputy National Climate Advisor Ali Zaidi are in Miami, Florida today meeting with experts in climate resilience and building safety and efficiency.</p>



<p><strong><u>NATIONAL INITIATIVE TO ADVANCE BUILDING CODES</u></strong><br><br>Modern, consensus-based codes—developed and updated by the International Code Council, National Fire Protection Association, American Society of Heating, Refrigerating and Air-Conditioning Engineers (ASHRAE), and other organizations that rely on expert input from scientists and engineers—provide sets of model standards for several aspects of building design, including energy efficiency and improving resilience to various hazards such as wildfires, hurricanes, and floods. Communities that have adopted modern building codes are <a href="https://www.fema.gov/emergency-managers/risk-management/building-science/building-codes-save-study">already saving</a> an estimated $1.6 billion a year in avoided damage from major hazards, with projected cumulative savings of $132 billion through 2040—a figure that will become much higher if more communities adopt modern codes.<br><br>A <a href="https://www.fema.gov/emergency-managers/risk-management/building-science/bcat/fact-sheets">recent analysis</a> from FEMA categorized states based on their building code uptake and found that 39 states fell into the lowest category—meaning less than 25% of the state’s communities were covered by the latest hazard-resistant codes. <a href="https://www.fema.gov/emergency-managers/risk-management/building-science/building-codes-save-study">Nationwide</a>, only about 35% of counties, cities, and towns have the latest codes in place, leaving millions of Americans more vulnerable to extreme weather and higher energy costs.<br><br>Through an all-of-government commitment across the Biden-Harris Administration, key federal agencies will collaborate to:<br><br><strong>Increase Support and Incentives for Modern Code Adoption</strong></p>



<p>Through the Mitigation Framework Leadership Group (MitFLG), a collaborative interagency body focused on improving resilience, senior agency officials will identify opportunities across federal programming to enhance outreach, technical assistance, and capacity building to states, Tribes, territories, and local governments on building codes. For example, agencies will advance the use of innovative incentives in federal funding to support and reward jurisdictions for code adoption and enforcement, to the extent allowed by law, with a focus on assisting historically underserved communities.<br><br>As part of this holistic review, which will be reported to the National Climate Task Force, specific efforts include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>FEMA will implement its new </strong><a href="https://www.fema.gov/sites/default/files/documents/fema_building-codes-strategy.pdf"><strong>Building Codes Strategy</strong></a>, which will integrate and, where legally permissible, require current building codes in its programs, policies and guidance; strengthen partnerships with other federal agencies, other levels of government, NGOs, and the private sector; and target FEMA outreach, education, and technical support efforts to increase building code adoption in underserved and vulnerable communities.<br></li><li><strong>DOE will deploy $225 million from the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</strong> to support building energy code adoption, enforcement, training, and technical assistance at the state and local level. With these funds, DOE is launching a <a href="https://www.energycodes.gov/RECI-codes-workshop">Resilient and Efficient Codes Implementation</a> program to advance energy efficiency and resilience through building codes by, among other things, supporting sustained state code implementation efforts, creating good-paying union jobs, and advancing environmental and energy justice priorities. DOE <a href="https://www.energycodes.gov/impact-analysis">projects</a> that through 2040, model energy codes will deliver $138 billion in energy cost savings and prevent carbon emissions equivalent to what 195 million gasoline cars emit in a year.</li><li><strong>FEMA will </strong><strong>utilize and update the </strong><a href="https://geo.stantec.com/National_BCAT_Portal/viewer/"><strong>Building Code Adoption Tracking portal</strong></a> to identify the status of building code adoption relative to known climate and other natural hazard risks in each community, with a particular focus on code adoption in underserved areas, to help local policymakers advance the adoption of &nbsp;modern, hazard-resistant building codes. DOE will continue to track the status of <a href="https://www.energycodes.gov/status/residential">state energy code adoption</a>.<br></li></ul>



<p><strong>Review Federal Funding and Financing to Incorporate Modern Codes</strong></p>



<p>The federal government implements a wide range of programs that fund or finance building construction—from disaster recovery programs at FEMA and the Small Business Administration, to federally-assisted housing supported by the Departments of Agriculture, Veterans Affairs, Treasury, HUD, and other agencies.</p>



<p>To increase the use of modern building codes across these projects, the MitFLG will undertake a comprehensive review of agency programs that support new construction or substantial rehabilitation of homes and other buildings, through grants, loans, funding, financing, or technical assistance. Agencies will then work to update programs to incorporate the latest consensus-based codes, while also identifying opportunities for greater ambition. For example, HUD will:</p>



<ul><li>Require increased resilience and energy efficiency standards for residential properties newly constructed or substantially rehabilitated with the $5 billion in 2020 and 2021 <a href="https://www.hud.gov/press/press_releases_media_advisories/hud_no_22_049">Community Development Block Grant-Disaster Recovery (CDBG-DR) funds</a>. These funds can be used to provide assistance to residents of underserved communities who have been historically marginalized and are adversely affected by disasters.<br></li><li>Seek to require above-code green and resilient construction standards in HUD-assisted housing wherever feasible, especially in competitive funding announcements, and continue developing new incentives for above-code standards, including through the Multifamily and Residential Healthcare Facility Green Mortgage Insurance Premium programs.</li></ul>



<p>The goal of this interagency effort will be to ensure that building activities receiving federal funding or financing will meet or exceed the latest building codes to the greatest extent feasible regardless of local code adoption, while balancing&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/president-biden-announces-new-actions-to-ease-the-burden-of-housing-costs/">Administration policies to boost housing supply and lower upfront costs</a>, and with flexibility for operational constraints, mission requirements, technical feasibility, enforcement feasibility, individual limitations, or Tribal, cultural, or traditional structures. The MitFLG will report on progress to the National Climate Task Force.</p>



<p><strong>Lead by Example Across the Federal Building Portfolio</strong></p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration will continue to expand its efforts to adopt ambitious, above-code resilience and energy efficiency standards across the federal building portfolio. As part of ongoing work to implement the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-catalyzing-americas-clean-energy-economy-through-federal-sustainability/">Executive Order on Federal Sustainability</a>:</p>



<ul><li>Federal agencies will design all large new construction and modernization projects (above 25,000 gross square feet), starting now in Fiscal Year 2022, to be <strong>net-zero emissions</strong>—which includes the use of all-electric equipment and appliances and efficiency measures significantly above current model codes.<br></li><li>The Office of the Federal Chief Sustainability Officer, within the White House Council on Environmental Quality, will explore opportunities to integrate <strong>innovative resilience standards</strong>—including above-code protections against specific hazards like floods and wildfires.<br></li><li>The Administration will implement the first-ever <strong>Federal Building Performance Standards</strong>, being developed by the White House Council on Environmental Quality, the General Services Administration, DOE, and the Environmental Protection Agency, to advance the retrofits of existing Federal buildings and establish metrics, targets, and tracking methods to reach the Administration’s federal carbon emissions reduction goals—including a net-zero emissions building portfolio by 2045, with a 50 percent emissions reduction by 2032.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
