<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 18:58:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks on a Modern American Industrial Strategy  By NEC Director Brian&#160;Deese</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/20/remarks-on-a-modern-american-industrial-strategy-by-nec-director-brian-deese/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 18:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51467</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Economic Club of New York As Prepared for Delivery Introduction Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Thanks to Barbara Van Allen and the entire team at the Economic Club of New York for hosting me today.&#160; It’s great to be here. In the early days of the Republic, Alexander Hamilton prepared a series of reports to Congress that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Economic Club of New York</em></p>



<p><em>As Prepared for Delivery</em></p>



<ol type="I"><li><strong>Introduction</strong></li></ol>



<p>Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks to Barbara Van Allen and the entire team at the Economic Club of New York for hosting me today.&nbsp; It’s great to be here.</p>



<p>In the early days of the Republic, Alexander Hamilton prepared a series of reports to Congress that laid the intellectual foundations for the young American economy.&nbsp; The first report was about securing the public credit.&nbsp; The second was about establishing a national bank.&nbsp; And the third—his 1791 <em>Report on the Subject of Manufactures</em>—offered a vision for a strong industrial system in America.</p>



<p>In the United States, he argued, “the public purse must supply the deficiency of private resource.&nbsp; In what can it be so useful as in prompting and improving the efforts of industry?”</p>



<p>That imperative has a contested history in American economic policy. &nbsp;For much of the last half-century, even uttering the words “industrial policy” was met with something between derision and concern.&nbsp; But our economy has changed, and the world has changed, too.</p>



<p>My core point today is this: it is a critical and urgent imperative for the United States to chart and implement a <em><u>modern American industrial strategy</u></em>.</p>



<p>Properly conceived and implemented, an industrial strategy <em>is</em> an economic resilience and capacity strategy.&nbsp; Investments in our industrial capacity will leave our economy better positioned to weather future shocks—and to help all Americans thrive.</p>



<p>Ten months ago, I proposed the idea of a modern American industrial strategy to describe what animated President Biden’s approach to strengthening the economy.&nbsp; The turbulent, historic economic events of the last year have underscored the case. &nbsp;The question should move from “<em>why</em> should we pursue an industrial strategy?” to “<em>how </em>do we pursue one successfully?”</p>



<p>When the pandemic began, our economy suffered its sharpest contraction since the end of the Second World War.&nbsp; Job losses were the worst since the Great Depression—with communities of color and young people hit hardest.</p>



<p>President Biden came into office and set the nation on a new course, taking immediate action to fight the virus and deliver economic relief. &nbsp;History will judge the virtues of our crisis response—there’s room for debate.&nbsp; But there’s no question the President’s strategy helped generate the strongest recovery in modern history—with the fastest economic growth in nearly four decades; the strongest labor market recovery ever recorded; and record progress for Black and Hispanic Americans, the long-term unemployed, and others often left behind in a slow-growth economy.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes, our economy faces significant challenges.&nbsp; Our convulsive, pandemic-constrained recovery has produced high inflation globally and domestically.&nbsp; The pandemic exposed structural vulnerabilities—resulting from decades-long underinvestment in our industrial strength—that have continued to generate supply-chain bottlenecks across the economy.&nbsp; And now, Russia’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine has compounded these challenges—exacerbating supply constraints, pushing up prices, and straining the post-Cold War world order.</p>



<p>Even so, the United States retains a stronger economic position than any other major country in the world, based on economic growth, job growth, consumer spending, and household balance sheets—even taking inflation into account.</p>



<p>What we have now is an opportunity, amid historic uncertainty.&nbsp; We should seize it—with an economic strategy that matches the moment.&nbsp;</p>



<ol type="I"><li><strong>Reviewing Our Progress</strong></li></ol>



<p>Today, I’d like to take stock of how far we’ve come and reassess the case for an American industrial strategy going forward. &nbsp;For the past year, we’ve centered on two core principles:</p>



<p><strong><em>First</em></strong>, strategic public investment must serve as the backbone to a strong industrial base.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is a case in point.&nbsp; Yes, it will make our supply chains more durable and reduce price pressures.&nbsp; Yes, it will connect more people to more places, create jobs, and push innovations from laboratory to market.</p>



<p>But it also represents the most significant effort in the last half-century to make a sustained, long-term public investment in America.&nbsp; This year, for the first time in two decades, America’s infrastructure investment will grow faster than China’s.</p>



<p>We need to build on this model.&nbsp; We’re within reach of passing the Bipartisan Innovation Act, which will help reclaim America’s leadership in semiconductors; authorize historic investments in basic R&amp;D; advance our leadership in technologies like artificial intelligence, 3D printing, telecommunications, and biotechnology; and spur innovation in places previously left behind.</p>



<p>The economic and national security threat of industrial weakness is accelerating.&nbsp; Congress urgently needs to send this legislation to the President’s desk so we can get to work rebuilding our industrial strength without delay.</p>



<p><strong>S</strong><strong><em>econd</em></strong>, we need to identify sectors where private industry, on its own, has not mobilized toward our core economic and national security interests—and lay the foundation for investment.</p>



<p>There’s a longstanding critique of industrial policy that it amounts to government picking “winners and losers.”&nbsp; There’s wisdom in this concern.&nbsp; Ill-conceived government interventions in private markets can produce inefficient and, worse, corrupting outcomes.&nbsp; But allowing this critique to reflexively hold back action misses the current global moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To make critical goods, American companies need access to key inputs like raw materials.&nbsp; They need secure and reliable supply chains that the private market won’t deliver on its own—and potentially <em>cannot</em> deliver if geopolitical dynamics prevent them from accessing those inputs.&nbsp; These gaps can have major security implications.</p>



<p>Individual companies will rise and fall on their own merits.&nbsp; But it’s incumbent on us to support an ecosystem that enables American businesses to stand at the vanguard of solving these problems.</p>



<p>That’s what we have sought to do. &nbsp;Last June, we published a first-ever diagnosis and prescription for our most acute supply-chain vulnerabilities.&nbsp; Earlier this year, we released detailed resilience strategies across sectors like defense, public health, IT, and energy.</p>



<p>Consider critical minerals.&nbsp; Lithium, nickel, and cobalt are building blocks in everything from computers to appliances to electric vehicles and other clean-energy technologies—and demand is set to skyrocket.</p>



<p>Yet the United States depends heavily on foreign sources for many of these critical minerals.&nbsp; China, for instance, is estimated to control 85 percent of refining capacity for rare earths.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So far, private investment has fallen short of our national needs.&nbsp; But through strategic coordination, we can open channels for companies to invest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why President Biden invoked the Defense Production Act to support domestic production and address immediate security risks, consistent with our values.&nbsp; That’s why the Defense Department contracted with a Nevada-based company to establish the first end-to-end domestic supply chain for “permanent magnets”—with capacity to power 500,000 electric vehicles per year.&nbsp; And that’s why the Department of Energy is poised to invest nearly $7 billion to strengthen our end-to-end domestic battery supply chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re seeing companies respond.&nbsp; They’ve announced more than $200 billion in critical manufacturing investments in the United States.&nbsp; Manufacturing has seen its strongest job growth in three decades.</p>



<ol type="I"><li><strong>Re-underwriting the Case for Our Industrial Strategy</strong></li></ol>



<p>We can be proud of this progress.&nbsp; But the global economic landscape is evolving rapidly.</p>



<p>Russia’s unconscionable invasion of Ukraine is imposing a global supply shock on an already supply-constrained global economy. &nbsp;And COVID remains an acute risk to global supply chains, particularly in places like China.</p>



<p>Given this evolving landscape, how do we re-underwrite the case for a modern American industrial strategy?&nbsp; I would offer four reflections.</p>



<p><strong><em>First</em></strong>, we need to make our economy more resilient while working to lower price pressures across the economy today and over time.</p>



<p>Given the supply and inflationary pressures we’re facing, some may argue that investing for resilience and industrial strength tomorrow could push pricing higher today. &nbsp;This critique counsels caution, but misses an important point: ignoring resilience is ultimately more expensive.</p>



<p>The pandemic laid this bare.&nbsp; Our supply chains were put to test, and the allure of “just in time” turned into a cacophony of disruptions, long lead times, complexity, and massive costs.</p>



<p>Companies are confronting this reality.&nbsp; They’re recognizing that when disruptions happen, well-prepared companies can bounce back and even gain market share over competitors. &nbsp;Yet investments in resilience require time and resources up front, when the whole economy is supply-constrained.</p>



<p>We recognize this. &nbsp;It is why we’re aggressively working to make our global logistics supply chain more fluid and lower price pressures right now across the economy.&nbsp; These actions create space for longer-term investments in industrial resilience and capacity to take root.</p>



<p>We’ve worked to move our ports to 24/7 operations and reduce container dwell times, which are down 50 percent.&nbsp; We’ve also worked to recruit more truck drivers and improve the quality of trucking jobs; and trucking employment is up 35,000 over pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p>Looking ahead, we need to bring our supply-chain logistics capabilities into the twenty-first century.&nbsp; We are now working to develop a reliable <em>digital</em> infrastructure to make our supply chains more agile.&nbsp; We should consider stress-testing private-sector supply chains to future shocks.&nbsp; The pandemic has underscored how major physical shocks can be both impulsive and inexorable, and we know climate change will only exacerbate them.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>Second</em></strong>, we need a modern American industrial strategy that expands and enhances international economic engagement.</p>



<p>I hope this point rings clear: You are not witnessing an American retreat from the global economy.&nbsp; Rather, you’re witnessing a new stage in how and why we engage—which will better serve the American middle class and American workers, while prioritizing our key global partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For America and the world, economic concerns are becoming more tightly linked to national security and national interests more broadly.&nbsp; In this environment, any thoughtful industrial strategy should prioritize partnerships with countries that respect fundamental norms and values—countries we can rely on—around transparency, open and fair rules-based trade, worker’s rights, and equity and opportunity.</p>



<p>This modern industrial strategy is centered on the reality that it’s neither feasible nor advisable to produce everything domestically.&nbsp; We need to <em>both</em> build resilience and capacity at home <em>and </em>forge more effective partnerships abroad. &nbsp;The Administration has sought to show that this clear-eyed approach to global economic ties can work—that we can assemble broad coalitions that amplify our own domestic strength.</p>



<p>This is what we’ve done in renewing our economic relationship with Europe, including the world’s first carbon-based sectoral deal on steel and aluminum trade. &nbsp;It’s also what we did—in bold and serious terms—when we led an historic global tax agreement with 136 countries to halt the race-to-the-bottom on corporate taxes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it’s what we aim to do in the Indo-Pacific region, with an economic framework for sustained collaboration on everything from data flows to supply chains to clean energy.</p>



<p>We should consider the full scope of tools for cooperation—whether it’s strengthening a partnership with one trusted ally, reaching a broad multilateral agreement, or, as Secretary Yellen recently said, constructing a network of “plurilateral” trade arrangements.</p>



<p>We also need to reexamine existing barriers—whether that’s through additional “tariff exclusions” processes or other warranted steps, to make sure our trade policy serves American economic priorities.</p>



<p><strong><em>Third</em></strong>, a modern American industrial strategy needs to demonstrate that America can build—fast, as we’ve done before, and fairly, as we’ve sometimes failed to do.</p>



<p>Core to rebuilding our industrial base is exactly that: <em>building</em>.&nbsp; We need to unpack the many constraints that cause America to lag other major countries—including those with strong labor, environmental, and historical protections—in delivering infrastructure on budget and on time.</p>



<p>At the same time, past efforts to build fast often entailed discrimination and subjugation—running roughshod over already disadvantaged communities and places.&nbsp; Our generation must do better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ll need to confront complex, multilayered challenges that lack easy answers.&nbsp; For instance, building more affordable housing is vitally important, but it doesn’t happen instantly.&nbsp; It requires action by many stakeholders.&nbsp; It involves changing norms, incentives, and activities in highly localized ways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The good news: the solutions don’t map onto traditional political, economic, or geographic divides.&nbsp; And the federal government can lead by example:</p>



<ul><li>We can establish coordinated federal decisions on permitting, instead of siloed agency actions, so projects can move forward with confidence, without sacrificing our values.</li></ul>



<ul><li>We can make the most of federal incentives, like conditioning transportation grants on land-use policies that help us build more efficiently and equitably.</li></ul>



<ul><li>We can pursue place-based policies—and build in geographies that may not only cost less but also have greater impact. The pandemic’s fundamental, structural disruption to how and where we work offers a unique moment to broaden the geographic aperture of economic opportunity in America.</li></ul>



<p>Most building will be carried out by state and local partners.&nbsp; The federal government will need to build capacity; demand progress over inertia; and learn from local innovation.</p>



<p>From the transcontinental railroad in the nineteenth century to the interstate highway system in the twentieth, Americans have shown their capacity to build great things.&nbsp; One powerful example stands a few blocks from here: the Empire State Building.&nbsp; It was constructed in just over a year.&nbsp; Nearly a century later, it remains an icon of American ambition and ingenuity.&nbsp; That’s the drive we’ll need to bring to our generation’s challenges.</p>



<p>One <strong><em>last</em></strong> reflection: these priorities are overlapping and reinforcing.&nbsp; There’s no clearer example than building resilience to energy shocks.</p>



<p>The global market for hydrocarbons is not a free market.&nbsp; It’s influenced by the geopolitical impulses of petrostates, some of which don’t share our interests or values.&nbsp; At the same time, the latest U.N. climate panel report confirms we have a narrow window to avoid the most devastating impacts of climate change.</p>



<p>In these two realities lies an opportunity: an industrial strategy for true energy security will reduce our reliance on volatile commodities and protect against the costs of the climate crisis.&nbsp; As the President said recently, “We need to choose long-term security over energy and climate vulnerability.”</p>



<p>By enacting long-term, technology-neutral incentives to generate zero-carbon energy and innovation, we can lay the foundation for more American-made clean-energy technologies and bolster domestic supply chains.&nbsp; We can partner with allies to expand our collective capacity to produce clean energy, while opening new export markets for American products.</p>



<p>And we can do it in a way that lowers immediate costs for Americans, keeps our affordable-energy advantage, and accelerates growth in energy communities transitioning toward industries of the future. &nbsp;Congress urgently needs to act here as well. &nbsp;</p>



<ol type="I"><li><strong>Conclusion</strong></li></ol>



<p>From Delta and Omicron, to supply-chain disruptions, and now to Russian aggression—our economy has shown striking resilience over the past year.&nbsp; But our most important work lies ahead.</p>



<p>What people will remember fifty years from now is whether we as a nation met this global moment.&nbsp; Did our economy emerge more resilient?&nbsp; Did it set the pace for generation-defining technologies?&nbsp; Did our alliances emerge more cooperative and unified in purpose?</p>



<p>In his <em>Report on Manufactures</em>, Hamilton argued that expanding American industry would be “favorable to national independence and safety.”&nbsp; America had just achieved independence, but building a strong industrial system would truly secure it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The American economy has been transformed many times over since then.&nbsp; Yet this economic and national security imperative endures.</p>



<p>Hamilton had one more insight we should heed today.&nbsp; “To increase the total mass of industry” in a country, he wrote, “is ultimately beneficial to every part of it.”&nbsp; We must ensure the gains are shared broadly by all Americans.</p>



<p><a>And we need the business community to step up and join us in this national renewal. If we strike the right balance, the American economy—and our democracy—can emerge more vigorous, more prosperous, and more resilient to whatever challenges come our way.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces the Rural Partners Network to Empower Rural Communities to Access Federal&#160;Resources</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-the-rural-partners-network-to-empower-rural-communities-to-access-federal-resources/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is committed to ensuring federal resources and opportunities that can benefit rural America actually reach rural America. Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is launching the Rural Partners Network (RPN), a new whole-of-government effort led by the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) to transform the way federal agencies partner with rural places to create economic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is committed to ensuring federal resources and opportunities that can benefit rural America actually reach rural America. Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is launching the <strong>Rural Partners Network (RPN),</strong> a new whole-of-government effort led by the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) to transform the way federal agencies partner with rural places to create economic opportunity.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is investing historic resources in rural communities so they can continue to compete and succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century. The President’s American Rescue Plan provided billions of dollars to rural workers, local governments, and small businesses to rebuild from the COVID-19 pandemic, and President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is a once-in-a-generation investment in affordable high-speed internet, clean drinking water, clean and reliable electricity, and better roads and bridges for rural communities across America. However, just making resources available is not enough—the federal government must better serve rural communities, so that they can take full advantage of these unprecedented opportunities.</p>



<p>To transform how the federal government partners with and delivers economic opportunity for rural communities across the United States, RPN will bring the federal government to rural America. New federal field staff will be placed in more than 25 rural communities in multiple U.S. states, Tribal Nations and territories to help local leaders navigate and access the federal resources they need to build a strong and vibrant economy. Through this unique partnership, RPN staff will also identify challenges preventing rural communities from accessing federal support to inform the work of the Rural Prosperity Interagency Policy Council, a whole-of-government task force that will ensure rural places are prioritized in Washington. RPN communities will have a new direct line to D.C. to foster a federal government that delivers for <em>all</em> rural communities.</p>



<p>To begin making the federal government work better for rural America, the Rural Partners Network is:</p>



<p><strong>Helping rural communities identify and leverage critical resources with the partnership of on-the-ground federal staff</strong>.</p>



<p>To boost local capacity, the Biden Administration will deploy new RPN staff to help communities access the full breadth of federal resources for community-led economic development, working in close coordination with: local leaders in government, business, and community organizations; federal agency field offices; existing federal efforts such as <a href="https://energycommunities.gov/">Interagency Working Group on Coal and Power Plant Communities and Economic Revitalization</a> and the President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/27/fact-sheet-president-biden-takes-executive-actions-to-tackle-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad-create-jobs-and-restore-scientific-integrity-across-federal-government/">Justice40 Initiative</a>; and staff of the Regional Commissions. RPN Directors will be placed in states, territories and Tribal Nations to coordinate RPN activities, and RPN Liaisons will be placed in selected community networks to work with local leaders on an economic development vision and to secure the funds to make it a reality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While these staff will be funded by USDA, they will have a whole-of-government mandate: help rural communities create economic opportunity by leveraging resources from all federal departments and agencies. To support this effort, 13 key agencies are dedicating a D.C.-based point person or team to serve as a front door for RPN staff and communities as they navigate the resources available across the federal government. These agencies participate in regular convenings of the Rural Prosperity Interagency Policy Council, co-led by the White House Domestic Policy Council and USDA.</p>



<p>Today, the Biden Administration is announcing the launch of this new program in selected community networks this year. In cohort 1, by the end of May, RPN staff will be on the ground supporting selected community networks in the following states and Tribal Nations:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Arizona</strong>:<ul><li>San Carlos Apache Tribe</li></ul><ul><li>Tohono O&#8217;odham Nation</li></ul><ul><li>Cocopah Indian Tribe</li></ul></li><li><strong>Georgia</strong><ul><li>Southwest Georgia Regional Commission: Counties of Mitchell, Baker, Calhoun, Colquitt, Decatur, Dougherty, Early, Grady, Lee, Seminole, Miller, Terrell, Thomas, and Worth</li></ul><ul><li>Ben Hill County and City of Fitzgerald<strong></strong></li></ul><ul><li>Emanuel County and City of Twin City</li></ul></li><li><strong>Kentucky</strong><ul><li>Fulton County Partnership*<strong>: </strong>Cities of Fulton, Hickman, and Cayce</li></ul><ul><li>Kentucky Highlands: Counties of Bell*, Perry*, Harlan*, Leslie*, Letcher*, Whitley, Knox, Clay*</li></ul></li><li><strong>Mississippi</strong><ul><li>Washington County Economic Alliance: Counties of Washington, Bolivar, Sunflower, and Leflore</li></ul><ul><li>Greater Grenada-Lake District: Counties of Grenada and Yalobusha</li></ul><ul><li>North Delta Planning and Development Collaborative: Counties of Coahoma, Quitman, and Tunica</li></ul></li><li><strong>New Mexico</strong><ul><li>Northern New Mexico Pathways: Counties of San Miguel, Taos, Mora, and Colfax</li></ul><ul><li>Southwest New Mexico Council of Governments: Counties of Catron, Grant, Hidalgo, and Luna</li></ul><ul><li>Mesilla Valley Partnership: Doña Ana County</li></ul></li></ul>



<p>*Priority Energy Community as determined by the Interagency Working Group on Coal and Power Plant Communities and Economic Revitalization.</p>



<p>These states and community networks were selected by USDA based on quantitative and qualitative factors, including levels of economic distress and readiness of the communities and local stakeholder organizations to participate in RPN. As part of the selection process, USDA conducted community engagement sessions with local community leaders. The communities themselves determined the composition of their networks.</p>



<p>In addition to this first cohort, RPN will expand to <strong>Nevada, North Carolina, Puerto Rico, West Virginia, Wisconsin, and Tribal communities in Alaska</strong> in a second cohort to launch by the end of August. If provided the support from Congress requested in the President’s FY23 Budget, RPN will continue expanding to ultimately serve all 50 states, as well as more Tribal Nations and territories.</p>



<p><strong>Empowering rural communities to foster a federal government that better delivers for rural America</strong><strong>. </strong>RPN field staff will be tasked with feeding key information to federal agencies on community needs and barriers to accessing federal resources. Agencies will then take this information and use it to drive policy changes that address the unique challenges faced by rural communities. As a result, RPN will not only support selected RPN community networks but inform changes that make the federal government better deliver for all rural communities.</p>



<p>Through this new direct line between rural communities and Washington, D.C., the Biden Administration will change business as usual and work across agencies to coordinate technical assistance to rural communities, share rural data and measures of success, and align grant requirements. Members of Congress across the political spectrum have called for this whole-of-government approach, including U.S. Senators Catherine Cortez Masto, Joni Ernst, Kirsten Gillibrand, Chuck Grassley, and Mark Kelly, and U.S. Representatives Angie Craig, Dan Newhouse, Cindy Axne, Adrian Smith, Tom O’Halleran, and Randy Feenstra.</p>



<p>The federal agencies and regional commissions participating in the Rural Prosperity Interagency Policy Council include:</p>



<ul><li>Department of Agriculture</li><li>Department of Commerce</li><li>Department of Education</li><li>Department of Energy</li><li>Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Department of the Interior</li><li>Department of Labor</li><li>Department of Transportation</li><li>Department of the Treasury</li><li>Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Small Business Administration</li><li>Appalachian Regional Commission</li><li>Delta Regional Authority</li><li>Denali Commission</li><li>Northern Border Regional Commission</li></ul>



<p><strong>Creating new whole-of-government resources for rural communities.</strong> Agencies will contribute to whole-of-government rural economic development resource guides and other informational material that will help all rural communities better identify and access federal funds. Agencies will also proactively conduct outreach to rural communities and rural leaders to disseminate information, offer technical assistance support, and seek input regarding the economic development barriers they face and support they need.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure&#160;Law</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/19/remarks-by-president-biden-on-investments-in-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Hampshire Port AuthorityPortsmouth, New Hampshire 2:53 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you, Mr. Mayor.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Please, take a seat if you have one.&#160; I once, several years ago, said, “Everybody take a seat.”&#160; There were about &#8212; it was an evening &#8212; there were about 2,000 people out in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">New Hampshire Port Authority<br>Portsmouth, New Hampshire</p>



<p>2:53 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, Mr. Mayor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Please, take a seat if you have one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I once, several years ago, said, “Everybody take a seat.”&nbsp; There were about &#8212; it was an evening &#8212; there were about 2,000 people out in the &#8212; in a football field, and it was towards the end of a campaign.&nbsp; I said, “Have a seat.”&nbsp; And they all looked at me like, “We’re standing &#8212; all of it.”&nbsp; (Laughter.) &nbsp;I couldn’t see.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But anyway, thank you very, very much.</p>



<p>Look, it’s great to be here in Portsmouth with your senator, Maggie Hassan, who’s been one of my friends for a long, long time, and to talk about investments we’re making to modernize this port and create jobs and bring down the cost for families in this region in everyday life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Maggie was a key player in the Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; And it’s making a difference here in New Hampshire and, I might add, around the country.&nbsp; She made the case for high-speed Internet everywhere in New Hampshire and, you know, protecting New Hampshire’s coastlines from rising sea levels and extreme storms, and for the investments in New Hampshire’s roads and bridges, ports and waterways.</p>



<p>And, Representative Chris Pappas, thank you for a passport into your district.&nbsp; Chris, where are you?&nbsp; Is Chris over here?&nbsp; Well, thanks for the passport, ole buddy, into the district.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he’s a member of the committee that got this bill across the finish line.&nbsp; Getting big ideas into an actual bill is hard work, requiring getting into the nitty-gritty details and without losing the big picture.</p>



<p>(A baby babbles.)</p>



<p>I agree.&nbsp; I agree completely.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; By the way, kids are allowed to do anything they want when I speak &#8212; at all.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So don’t worry about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but, Chris, thank you for all the work you did.&nbsp; And you did a hell of a lot of work to get this done, and always making the economic case for how clean water, access to the Internet, rebuilding a bridge, investing in this port matters to your lives, the lives of your families, and, quite frankly, to the entire region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Representative Annie Kuster, an old good friend of mine &#8212; it’s good to see you as well, Annie.&nbsp; Thank you for everything.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Annie and I have talked a lot about what we need to do to support New Hampshire’s parents and give them just a little bit of breathing room because sometimes things get tight.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And even though she can’t be here, I also wanted to recognize Jeanne Shaheen, who is well represented today by her husband Billy and the family.&nbsp; Billy, where are you?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; If I can only have one guy in the foxhole with me, I’d pick Billy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Good to see you, Billy.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and I want to thank &#8212; because she’s sitting next to her.&nbsp; She doesn’t hold any office but a really good friend of mine.&nbsp; Her mom used to be a significant political figure up here.&nbsp; It’s great to see you, kiddo.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you for being here.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to thank Chris and Maggie and Jeanne and Annie for all they did to prove that America can do big things when we work together.&nbsp; You know, we &#8212; we can build a better America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re the only country in the world that, I believe, that has come out of every crisis we’ve faced stronger than when we went in &#8212; literally stronger than we went in.&nbsp; That’s the history of the journey of this country.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this port is a perfect example.&nbsp; A lot of important things come into these terminals and particularly this one &#8212; from salt to de-ice roads, to 85 percent of the home heating oil used in this state.</p>



<p>And a lot of important things go out of this port as well, like the massive reactor assemblies for nuclear power plants that are manufactured by Westinghouse Electric here in New Hampshire.</p>



<p>Recently, this port has been an important link to more construction equipment and materials for a $2.3 billion project that I’ve authorized in Portsmouth Naval Shipyard &#8212; 2.3 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But it wouldn’t happen without you all and what you’ve done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, I know they say the port is in Maine, but I’ve always thought it was in New Hampshire.&nbsp; But &#8212; (applause) &#8212; that’s what Billy taught me.&nbsp; And where the Navy’s nuclear-powered attack submarines are built as well and are stationed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, all in, this port supports over 2,300 jobs &#8212; 2,300 jobs; adds $275 million to this region’s economy, and that’s not even counting the more than 6,000 civilian contractors and jobs here at &#8212; over at the Navy yard.&nbsp; Jobs in Maine, New Hampshire, and all around the region.</p>



<p>But this port has even more potential than that.&nbsp; Until recently, the area in the harbor called the “turning basin” was only 800 feet long and often meant that pilots had to turn around a 765-foot ship in 800 feet.&nbsp; I call that tough parallel parking, man.</p>



<p>But seriously &#8212; and it meant that, you know, to be safe, some of the ships could only come in or sail out on high tide, they could only sail at night, or when there was &#8212; they couldn’t sail when there was too much wind.&nbsp; They couldn’t &#8212; and &#8212; because they’d get knocked off course.</p>



<p>And that &#8212; here’s why it matters: When you keep a ship in dock after the cargo has been delivered, it can cost $90,000 a day when that ship is in port.&nbsp; And those costs get paid on &#8212; get passed on to you, consumers &#8212; whatever it happens to be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It also has been a problem for decades.&nbsp; But with an $18 million investment from the Army Corps of Engineers and the help of Maggie and Chris, the port &#8212; and union labor &#8212; we widened that turning basin to 1,200 feet.&nbsp; We got it done.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Now it’s easier, faster, and cheaper, and safer for ships to get in and out.</p>



<p>And the port can welcome larger ships with more cargo, like the massive towers and hubs needed to &#8212; for offshore wind farms.</p>



<p>Look, we’ve also announced an additional $1.7 million investment to dredge &#8212; another tricky part of a shipping channel where the sands build up.</p>



<p>Without that dredging project, the port might need more restrictions on what ships can and can’t pass through this harbor.</p>



<p>Instead of turning away business, we’re sending a message: This port is open for business and will be for a long time.</p>



<p>And we’re sending the same message with our investments in roads and bridges here in New Hampshire.</p>



<p>Back in November, Maggie, Chris, and Annie were with me when I visited Pemi &#8212; the Pemi bridge in Woodstock &#8212; a couple of hours just northwest of here.</p>



<p>The bridge opened in 1939.&nbsp; Not a big bridge, but it solved big problems.&nbsp; Local businesses depended on it.&nbsp; School buses crossed it every day.&nbsp; Without the bridge, the trucks on the other side of the river would have to take a 10-mile detour to get around to the other side of the river.</p>



<p>Folks, when fires and emergencies &#8212; every single mile matters and counts how long it takes to get there.</p>



<p>Right now, there are nearly 200 bridges deemed deficient</p>



<p>in New Hampshire alone.&nbsp; There’s about 315 such bridges in Maine.&nbsp; And many of these are fast-track &#8212; fast &#8212; less-trafficked bridges that are essential to small towns and rural areas, for farmers and small businesses.</p>



<p>Let me give you an example.&nbsp; I was just in Pittsburgh not long ago &#8212; I guess over &#8212; a little over a month ago.&nbsp; And I got there the morning that one of its bridges collapsed.&nbsp; The bridge was built in 1939, if I’m not mistaken, and had been put on a list of being dangerous.&nbsp; It was about a 12-story drop from the middle of that bridge down to a small creek.&nbsp; And it was in a &#8212; but it was a ravine that covered about 300 yards.</p>



<p>Had it not been &#8212; had it not been a snow day before, there would have been a lot of school buses on that bridge.&nbsp; A lot of kids would have been killed.&nbsp; I’m not joking.&nbsp; You probably saw it on the front page of every paper in America.</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; It’s happening all over the country.&nbsp; Fortunately, it didn’t happen there.&nbsp; Fortunately, there was no one on the bridge.&nbsp; There were &#8212; actually, there were four vehicles.&nbsp; No one got killed.</p>



<p>And, you know, I was &#8212; when I was doing the Recovery Act in our last administration &#8212; Obama-Biden &#8212; I was in Pittsburgh &#8212; excuse me, in Pennsylvania, in Western Pennsylvania, in a small town.&nbsp; And in the process, I looked at a bridge, and they couldn’t &#8212; their fire department was on one side of the bridge, and, literally, from here to that holding tank outside here, was &#8212; on the other side there was a shopping center and a school.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; Their fire &#8212; you couldn’t get across the bridge; you had to go 10 miles to get around, go up over the bridge, if &#8212; could work, and get back down.&nbsp; People dying in that 10 miles of the fire truck getting there in the middle of a fire.</p>



<p>This matters.&nbsp; So we’re making a historic investments in fixing these bridges.</p>



<p>This year alone, we’re delivering $45 million to fix your bridges here in New Hampshire.&nbsp; This year alone.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You know, the last fella who had this job kept talking about “Infrastructure Week” for four years.  (Laughter.)  Well, we not only took Infrastructure &#8212; we have “Infrastructure Decade.”  (Applause.)  This is going on.  It’s a billion 200 million dollars.</p>



<p>You know, we used to have the finest infrastructure in the world.&nbsp; We now rank number 13 in the quality of our infrastructure.&nbsp; China is ahead of us.&nbsp; So many other countries have moved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, this matters.&nbsp; It matters to our safety, our security, our health, and a whole range of other &#8212;</p>



<p>Not only that, about 700 miles of highway in New Hampshire are in poor condition.&nbsp; It’s estimated that the driving on those roads &#8212; those 700 miles &#8212; roughly 700 miles &#8212; that need repairs costs New Hampshire drivers at least an average of $476 a year extra in gas and repairs and longer commute times.&nbsp; That’s a $476 hidden tax on New Hampshire drivers.</p>



<p>Look, thanks to the Infrastructure Law, we’re making the most significant investment in modernizing our roads and bridges</p>



<p>since the Interstate Highway System was built with Eisenhower.</p>



<p>We’re also going to start to replace the 100 percent &#8212; all 100 percent of lead water pipes and service lines going into our homes and our schools.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>There are 10 million homes and 400,000 schools and preschools and daycare centers that have lead water pipes bringing the water in.&nbsp; Many of that causes mental illness, brain damage.&nbsp; It’s really important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re also going to address what they call PFAS; it’s a dangerous forever chemicals that are a threat to drinking water</p>



<p>here in New Hampshire and other states &#8212; something that Senator Shaheen has championed.</p>



<p>Look, every American and every child should be able to</p>



<p>turn on a faucet, drink clean water, which will also create thousands of good-paying jobs for plumbers, pipefitters, and the folks digging those channels.</p>



<p>And, by the way, thanks to the American Rescue Plan, New Hampshire is already seeing $150 million being put into drinking water, wastewater, and storm sewer projects in this state as I speak.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Maggie, Chris, and Annie, we share a core belief: High-speed Internet is essential &#8212; essential &#8212; to success in the 21st century.</p>



<p>But even today, 1 in every 10 people in New Hampshire &#8212; every 1 in 10 households don’t have high-speed Internet.  That’s a lot of place where there’s no broadband or &#8212; infrastructure at all in New Hampshire.</p>



<p>It’s not just New Hampshire families, but for New Hampshire businesses as well.</p>



<p>This law is going to make high-speed Internet affordable and available everywhere in New Hampshire, Maine, and the region &#8212; urban, suburban, rural.&nbsp; And it’s going to create jobs. &nbsp;Thousands of union techni- &#8212; thousands of union technicians are going to be laying down these broadband lines.</p>



<p>And never again should a parent have to sit in their car in a McDonald’s parking lot &#8212; literally &#8212; so that their child can get access to high-speed Internet to do their homework over the Internet.&nbsp; Literally.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Folks, look, the law also builds up our &#8212; our resilience to extreme weather.</p>



<p>Fifteen years ago this week, this state experienced its second 100-year flood in the space of 11 months.&nbsp; Cars submerged.&nbsp; Thousands of evacuations.&nbsp; People lost everything they owned, twice.</p>



<p>Our infrastructure law upgrades stormwater management systems and builds new transmission lines and towers so fewer will be flooded out of their homes or lose power days and weeks because of these storms.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s so much more in this law.&nbsp; I’m not going to bore you with the rest of it.&nbsp; But it’s &#8212; it’s significant.</p>



<p>Look, we’ve made a lot of progress, and we have an incredible opportunity ahead of us.&nbsp; But we know what families are still struggling with higher prices.&nbsp; I grew up in a family where the price of gasoline went up at the pump, it was a discussion at the kitchen table.&nbsp; Because my dad &#8212; he was a good man, made a decent living, but always on the margins.&nbsp; Everything mattered.</p>



<p>So let’s be absolutely clear about why we have such high prices now.&nbsp; There are two reasons.&nbsp; First was COVID.</p>



<p>The way the global economy works: If a factory in Vietnam makes computer chips and shuts down in Vietnam because of a COVID outbreak, it causes a ripple effect to slow down manufacturing in Detroit where they need those &#8212; those semiconductors to build the automobiles.</p>



<p>So because of the pandemic, we had disruptions in our supply of important materials, so prices went up.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As I said, just look at automobiles.&nbsp; Last year alone, they accounted for one third of all the inflation in America because the price went up, because so fewer &#8212; fewer were being made.&nbsp; Automobile companies couldn’t get the computer chips, and the price of automobiles skyrocketed.</p>



<p>So I’m calling on Congress to pass the bipartisan Innovation Bill to make more of these chips here at home and speed the supply.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Intel came to see me &#8212; the chairman of the board of Intel.&nbsp; He said, “I want to be able to invest $20 billion to build a computer chip factories in &#8212; just west of Cleveland.”<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If, in fact, we get this other piece of legislation, which is in &#8212; passed one House and not the other, we’re going to &#8212; he’s going to invest another $100 billion &#8212; $100 billion.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know what the average job of &#8212; over 7,000 construction jobs and 3,800 full-time jobs.&nbsp; Average salary of the full-time jobs &#8212; and there &#8212; many of them are blue-collar jobs &#8212; are $126,000 a year.&nbsp; Things are changing.</p>



<p>And the second big reason for inflation is Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Putin’s invasion of Ukraine has driven up gas prices and food prices all over the world.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two major breadbaskets of wheat in the world were Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; The United States is number three and Canada number four.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, we saw the most recent inflation data.&nbsp; Last month, about 70 percent of the increase in inflation was a consequence of Putin’s price hike because of the impact on gas and energy prices.</p>



<p>I’m doing everything I can to bring down the price to address Putin’s price hike.&nbsp; That’s why I authorized the release of 1 million barrels per day for the next six months for our st- &#8212; from our Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know the press is always asking me, with good reason, why I’m always on the phone talking with other world leaders, trying to keep them organized.&nbsp; Well, one of the things I did &#8212; I went out and got a lot of other countries to agree that they would release petroleum from their oil reserves.</p>



<p>So, we worked with the U.S. oil producers to ramp up the production &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and we coordinated this release with partners and allies around the world.&nbsp; And shortly after I made the announcement, another 30 countries agreed to 60 million additional barrels a day on the market.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So now we have 240 million barrels a day for the next six months.&nbsp; That’s the largest collective reserve release in history.&nbsp; Nations coming together to help deny Putin the ability to weaponize his energy resources against American families and families in Europe and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there’s more that needs to be done.&nbsp; And Americans should already be seeing the savings.&nbsp; Although it’s only gone down about 18 cents, the savings are starting.</p>



<p>Beyond gas prices, I’ve called on Congress to move immediately to lower the cost of family utility bills, prescription drug bills, and more, while lowering the deficit and reducing inflation.&nbsp; That would make a big difference for families.&nbsp; We can do a lot of these things without raising a single penny on taxes of anyone making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; Nobody making less than $400,000 will see a single penny in their taxes raised.</p>



<p>It’s the best way Congress can address inflation right now.</p>



<p>And, folks, look, the fact is that we are in a situation where the war in Ukraine is going to continue to take its toll on the world economy.&nbsp; It’s going to take its toll on energy, and it’s going to take its toll relative to food.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I was running for office &#8212; you heard it a thousand times from me: that we&#8217;re going to build an economy around you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so tired of trickle-down economics.&nbsp; And I never found that trickle down on top of my head very much.&nbsp; I was listed &#8212; I was &#8212; had the great pleasure of being listed as the poorest man in Congress for 36 years.&nbsp; I still had &#8212; making a hell of a lot more money than anybody else because I was getting a senator’s salary.&nbsp; No kidding.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t think you should make money while you&#8217;re in office.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, at any rate, the point of it is this: An awful lot of people are hurting.&nbsp; It makes a big difference.&nbsp; It makes a big difference.&nbsp; The cost of a dozen eggs, the cost of a gallon of gasoline, it matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I concluded, when I ran this last time, that we&#8217;re going to build this economy from the bottom up and the middle out, because when that happens, everybody does well.&nbsp; The wealthy do very well and the poor have a ladder up, and the middle class has a little bit of breathing room.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I grew up in a household where we lived in a split-level home &#8212; three bedrooms, four kids, mom and dad, and a grandpop who lived with us.&nbsp; And I remember one night, you could &#8212; you know, the walls were kind of thin.&nbsp; I can &#8212; my dad was restless.&nbsp; The next morning, when he went to work, I asked mom what was the problem.&nbsp; She said, “He just noticed his company just said no more &#8212; they’re not going to &#8212; not going to cover health insurance anymore.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>It matters.&nbsp; These things matter to people.&nbsp; They matter to ordinary people.</p>



<p>We can, in fact, provide for anyone who has Type 1 diabetes or a child &#8212; or 200 million &#8212; 200,000 kids who have it.&nbsp; They need that insulin every single day.&nbsp; Average cost is six hundred and forty-seven thou- &#8212; $647 a month, sometimes as low as $90 and as high as $1,000, depending on where you are.</p>



<p>You know how mu- &#8212; made &#8212; how much it costs to make one of those vials of insulin? &nbsp;Ten &#8212; T-E-N &#8212; dollars.&nbsp; Not a single change has been made in that insulin since it was first discovered.</p>



<p>And so, we could set that price at maximum of $35.&nbsp; They still make a significant profit.&nbsp; And what they &#8212; what in God&#8217;s name are we doing?</p>



<p>Look, I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; I think people should be able to go out and make millions of dollars, even a billion if you can make it, but at least pay your fair share.&nbsp; Pay something.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;Pay something.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, I&#8217;m being deadly earnest.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s just &#8212; you know, there are &#8212; I come from the corporate capital of the world, Delaware.&nbsp; More corporations are incorporated in the state of Delaware than every other state in the nation combined &#8212; combined.&nbsp; And I survived winning seven Senate elections in that state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here’s the deal: The fact is, folks, that, you know, there are 50 Fortune &#8212; there are 50 of the top 500 corporations in America last year that made a total of $40 billion in profit.&nbsp; They didn&#8217;t pay one single penny &#8212; not one.&nbsp; The average percent that billionaires pay of the 790 of them is about 3.8 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just pay your fair share.&nbsp; We can do all these things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, one last thing: You know, the budget I submitted &#8212; my first budget that passed and became law, it cut the federal deficit by $350 billion.&nbsp; We cut the deficit $350 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the budget I proposed this year, if it comes to total fruition, it will cut the deficit by one trillion three hundred billion dollars.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So when my Republican friends start talking about “big spenders” and the reason why there&#8217;s inflation, take a look. Take a look.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve cut the deficit drastically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, we&#8217;re making progress.&nbsp; Over the course of my presidency, our recovery so far has created 7.9 million new jobs &#8212; (applause) &#8212; more jobs &#8212; more jobs created over the first 14 months than any President ever.&nbsp; Over 420,000 manufacturing jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unemployment rate is at 3.6 percent, down from 6.4 percent.  In the state of New Hampshire, you&#8217;re down from &#8212; I think it&#8217;s 4.2 percent to 3.2 [sic] percent.</p>



<p>Folks, in Maine you&#8217;ve added 28,000 jobs, and unemployment has dropped from 4.4 to 3.6.&nbsp;</p>



<p>New Hampshire, 26,000 new jobs.&nbsp; Dropped from 4.2 &#8212; I was &#8212; misspoke &#8212; to 2.5 &#8212; 2.5 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last year, as I said, we cut the deficit by more than 350 thousa- &#8212; billion dollars.&nbsp; This year, we’re on track for $1.3 trillion in cuts.&nbsp; And look, that would be the largest debt reduction in American history.</p>



<p>And it’s particularly important now we ask ourselves: How are we going to reduce pressure on inflation?</p>



<p>Maine, New Hampshire, and America have gone on the mend. &nbsp;They’re on the &#8212; they’re not on the mend any longer; they’re on the move.&nbsp; And we’re coming to &#8212; at our challenges from a position of strength.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I’m more optimistic about America today than I’ve ever been in my whole career, because I see the future that’s within our grasp.&nbsp; We can’t be afraid though.&nbsp; We’re the only nation on Earth, as I’ve said, that has always turned every single, solitary crisis we’ve had into an opportunity.&nbsp; And that’s exactly what we’re going to do today if we do it together.</p>



<p>It’s about being together &#8212; the United States of America.&nbsp; When we do that, there’s not a single thing we can’t do.</p>



<p>But God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>3:18 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on U.S. Consultations with Australia, Japan, and New Zealand in&#160;Honolulu</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-u-s-consultations-with-australia-japan-and-new-zealand-in-honolulu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 23:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 18, National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell and Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink convened a meeting in Honolulu with U.S. Navy Adm. John C. Aquilino, Commander, U.S. Indo-Pacific Command and senior officials from Australia, Japan, and New Zealand on developments in the Pacific Islands. In&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 18, National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell and Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink convened a meeting in Honolulu with U.S. Navy Adm. John C. Aquilino, Commander, U.S. Indo-Pacific Command and senior officials from Australia, Japan, and New Zealand on developments in the Pacific Islands. In Honolulu, the officials reaffirmed the four countries’ enduring and shared commitment to the Pacific Islands. The United States resolved to intensify its engagement in the region to meet 21st-century challenges, from maritime security and economic development to the climate crisis and COVID-19. We will do this in ever-closer partnership with Pacific Island nations, including through a united Pacific Islands Forum; and together with like-minded countries, within and beyond the region, including in Europe. Officials from the four countries represented also shared concerns about a proposed security framework between the Solomon Islands and the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and its serious risks to a free and open Indo-Pacific. The meeting was part of regular and extensive U.S. consultations with allies and partners on the Indo-Pacific and is part of the announced senior administration travel this week to Hawaii, Fiji, Papua New Guinea, and the Solomon Islands.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting on Reproductive Health and Rights with State Legislators from Missouri, Nebraska, and&#160;Oklahoma</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/readout-of-white-house-meeting-on-reproductive-health-and-rights-with-state-legislators-from-missouri-nebraska-and-oklahoma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 21:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, hosted a roundtable discussion with state legislators from Missouri, Nebraska, and Oklahoma to discuss their efforts to protect access to reproductive health care, in light of a series of unconstitutional attacks on women’s reproductive rights. During the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, hosted a roundtable discussion with state legislators from Missouri, Nebraska, and Oklahoma to discuss their efforts to protect access to reproductive health care, in light of a series of unconstitutional attacks on women’s reproductive rights.</p>



<p>During the meeting, state legislators reported on abortion restrictions in their states and shared steps they have taken to oppose new legislative proposals. Leaders in Oklahoma described the potential impact of recently-passed S 612, which makes providing an abortion a criminal offense in the state, with narrow exceptions. Nebraska lawmakers shared their recent success in fighting a trigger ban, which failed on the legislature floor earlier this month and would have banned abortion in the state if <em>Roe</em> were overturned. State legislators from Missouri described their efforts to oppose a number of pending restrictions. All participants underscored the devastating impact these bills would have on access to critical reproductive health care services, especially for low-income populations and those living in rural communities.</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials underscored the Administration’s support for reproductive rights and determination to protect access to health care. They thanked the legislators for their leadership in opposing and raising awareness about these dangerous bills, and made it clear that the Administration stands with them in the fight to protect reproductive health care.</p>



<p>The legislation discussed today is just a sample of the onerous and unconstitutional restrictions that have passed or are pending in states across the nation. In light of this wholesale attack on reproductive rights, Administration officials reiterated the President’s support for the constitutional right affirmed in <em>Roe v. Wade</em> and his commitment to protect women’s access to critical reproductive health care.</p>



<p>State legislators participated in today’s meeting included:</p>



<ul><li>Missouri Senator Jill Schupp</li><li>Missouri Representative Emily Weber</li><li>Nebraska Senator Machaela Cavanaugh</li><li>Nebraska Senator Adam Morfeld</li><li>Oklahoma House Minority Leader Emily Virgin</li><li>Oklahoma Representative Forrest Bennett</li><li>Oklahoma Representative Ajay Pittman</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Update on the U.S. Strategy for Addressing the Root Causes of Migration in Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/fact-sheet-update-on-the-u-s-strategy-for-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 19:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[April 2022 Vice President Harris has led the Root Causes Strategy, which aligns U.S. Government efforts to address the economic, governance, and security drivers of irregular migration from Central America.&#160; The Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive strategy combines significant U.S. Government resources with substantial private sector investments to support the long-term development of the region.&#160; To advance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>April 2022</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-strategy-to-address-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/">Vice President Harris has led the Root Causes Strategy</a>, which aligns U.S. Government efforts to address the economic, governance, and security drivers of irregular migration from Central America.&nbsp; The Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive strategy combines significant U.S. Government resources with substantial private sector investments to support the long-term development of the region.&nbsp; To advance the strategy, the Vice President met with regional leaders and traveled to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/07/fact-sheet-u-s-guatemala-cooperation/">Guatemala</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/11/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-lopez-obrador-of-mexico-before-bilateral-meeting/">Mexico</a>, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/27/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-president-castro-of-honduras/">Honduras</a> to launch new initiatives that sustainably address the root causes of migration.&nbsp; The Vice President also brought together private sector leaders through her <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/vice-president-kamala-harris-announces-new-commitments-as-part-of-the-call-to-action-for-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-central-america-now-totaling-over-1-2-billion/#:~:text=The%20Call%20to%20Action's%20six,development%3B%20and%20public%20health%20access."><em>Call to Action</em></a> initiative that has generated more than $1.2 billion in commitments to create new jobs and opportunities for people in the region.&nbsp; In addition, she has engaged partners around the world to generate new commitments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These are long-term efforts, but under the Vice President’s leadership, the Biden-Harris Administration is seeing significant progress toward creating hope for people in El Salvador, Guatemala and Honduras that a better life can be found at home.&nbsp; Highlights to date include:</p>



<ul><li>U.S. initiatives are providing micro and small businesses access to $100 million in financing to support economic recovery in the region. &nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>To combat the COVID-19 pandemic, the U.S. Government has delivered more than 15 million free-of-cost vaccine doses bilaterally and in partnership with COVAX to countries in northern Central America.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The U.S. Government has provided $26.4 million to El Salvador, $81.5 million to Guatemala and $57.1 million to Honduras to support the fight against COVID-19.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. Government support for private sector companies helped create more than 70,000 jobs.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The U.S. Government’s $300 million <em>Centroamérica Local</em> initiative is empowering local organizations to address the drivers of irregular migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. support for the region’s agricultural sector is generating increased incomes for farm families and producers.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Additional U.S. funding for school feeding programs is improving food security in northern Central America.</li></ul>



<ul><li>A new Department of Justice Anti-Corruption Task Force, which was announced by the Vice President in June 2021, is prioritizing prosecutions against corrupt actors in the region.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. sanctions and visa restrictions are targeting perpetrators of corruption and serious human rights abuse.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. training professionalized over 5,000 civilian police across the region.&nbsp; <a></a></li></ul>



<ul><li>A new task force to prevent migrant smuggling and human trafficking, which was announced by the Vice President in June 2021, is disrupting trafficking operations and its work has already led to the indictment eight leaders of human smuggling organizations.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. programs are supporting victims of unaccompanied migrant children, gender-based violence, and survivors of human trafficking.</li></ul>



<ul><li>New U.S. Government programs and scholarships are improving access to education for nearly 18,000 returning/potential migrants and at-risk youth.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. Government partnerships with local organizations are increasing income-generating opportunities for thousands of indigenous women and girls.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. programs are empowering women entrepreneurs to launch and scale their businesses across the region.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The U.S. Government is supporting at-risk youth across the region to strengthen their ability to resist gang recruitment.</li></ul>



<ul><li>New programming in northern Central America is focused on increasing collective action to address child and forced labor and improve occupational safety and health conditions for workers in the region.</li></ul>



<p>As part of the Vice President’s <em>Call to Action</em>:</p>



<ul><li>Microsoft is connecting four million people to broadband across the region, with over one million already connected to date.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Nespresso will invest $150 million to double the number of farmers it works with in the region and begin to source coffee from El Salvador and Honduras.</li><li>Mastercard is bringing five million people into the formal financial economy while digitizing one million micro and small businesses.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Parkdale Mills is investing $150 million to support a new yarn spinning facility in Honduras and an existing facility in Virginia, supporting 500 jobs in each location.</li></ul>



<ul><li>PepsiCo is investing at least $190 million in northern Central America through 2025 to improve its plants and expand distribution routes.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Grupo Mariposa is providing over 70,000 small-business owners with access to credit and digital services.</li></ul>



<p><em>For additional details, please review the </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/report-on-the-u-s-strategy-for-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/">Report on the U.S. Strategy for Addressing the Root Causes of Migration in Central America.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Report on the U.S. Strategy for Addressing the Root causes of Migration in Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/report-on-the-u-s-strategy-for-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 19:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris launched the Root Causes Strategy on July 29, 2021, to align U.S. Government efforts to address the economic, governance, and security drivers of irregular migration from Central America.  Tackling the persistent challenges that drive irregular migration requires sustained political will and cooperation across a broad range of stakeholders to foster long-term development&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-strategy-to-address-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/">Vice President Harris launched the Root Causes Strategy</a> on July 29, 2021, to align U.S. Government efforts to address the economic, governance, and security drivers of irregular migration from Central America.  Tackling the persistent challenges that drive irregular migration requires sustained political will and cooperation across a broad range of stakeholders to foster long-term development in the region.  The Vice President has led progress on the Administration’s Strategy, including by traveling to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/07/fact-sheet-u-s-guatemala-cooperation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Guatemala</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/11/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-lopez-obrador-of-mexico-before-bilateral-meeting/">Mexico</a>, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/27/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-president-castro-of-honduras/">Honduras</a> to launch new initiatives that sustainably address the root causes of migration. </p>



<p>Recognizing the important role for the private sector, Vice President Harris brought together private sector leaders through a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/vice-president-kamala-harris-announces-new-commitments-as-part-of-the-call-to-action-for-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-central-america-now-totaling-over-1-2-billion/"><em>Call to Action,</em></a><em> </em>which has resulted in over $1.2 billion in private sector commitments in Central America to create new jobs and opportunities for people in the region.&nbsp; Vice President Harris also engaged partners around the world to support our work and generate new commitments.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration’s strategy represents a comprehensive approach to promoting inclusive economic growth in the region with a sharp focus on strengthening democratic governance and combatting corruption, women’s empowerment, climate change, human rights, security and curbing gender-based violence.&nbsp; It integrates various U.S. Government tools, including foreign assistance, development finance, public diplomacy, and economic sanctions and visa restrictions.&nbsp; Because the region’s long-term development will require more than just the resources of the U.S. Government, the Strategy forges strong partnerships with the private sector and international partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Mobilizing Private Sector Investment</strong></p>



<p>The Vice President’s leadership has brought together private sector leaders through a <em>Call to Action</em>.&nbsp; In collaboration with the Partnership for Central America, this has resulted in &nbsp;more than $1.2 billion in private sector commitments in Central America to create new jobs and opportunities for people in the region.&nbsp; The <em>Call to Action’s</em> six focus areas are intended to support long-term development of the region.&nbsp; They are: promoting a reform agenda; digital and financial inclusion; food security and climate-smart agriculture; climate adaptation and clean energy; education and workforce development; and public health access.</p>



<p>Companies that have made investments and commitments in the region include Microsoft, Nespresso, Mastercard, CARE International, Cargill, Grupo Mariposa, Parkdale Mills, PepsiCo, JDE Peet’s, and PriceSmart.&nbsp; These initial commitments are already bearing fruit.&nbsp; Some highlights include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Internet Access:&nbsp; </strong>Microsoft catalyzed the development of digital access training centers, clean off-grid energy, and broadband access covering a population of 1.1 million people, and is on track to connect 4 million people to broadband by 2024.</li><li><strong>Support for Farmers</strong>:&nbsp; Nespresso works with over 1,200 farms in Guatemala to improve livelihoods in the region. The company announced its first-ever coffee sourcing from Honduras and El Salvador, with plans to increase activities in the region for the next harvest season. This is part of the company&#8217;s commitment to support the region&#8217;s economy with a minimum of $150 million to be spent across coffee purchases, price premiums, and technical assistance by 2025.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Digital and Financial Inclusion</strong>:&nbsp; Mastercard committed to bring five million people in El Salvador, Guatemala and Honduras into the formal financial economy and to digitize one million micro and small businesses.<strong>&nbsp; </strong>The company established a Digital Country Partnership with Guatemala’s Ministry of the Economy, accelerating their work to bring five million people in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras into the formal financial economy.&nbsp; This will also enable one million micro and small businesses to access online payment and management systems.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Job Creation and Supply Chain Resilience</strong>:&nbsp; Parkdale Mills is investing $150 million in a new yarn spinning facility in Honduras.&nbsp; This support will provide customers with sources for purchasing one million pounds of yarn per week within the region while increasing U.S. supply chain resilience. The investment is intended to support roughly 500 employees at each location and increase indirect job growth in Honduras and in the United States, particularly in the U.S. cotton industry across 18 states. The investment also includes $24 million in new investments in solar energy, water recapture, and energy efficient HVAC systems.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Infrastructure and Renewable Energy Investments</strong>:&nbsp; PepsiCo will invest at least $190 million in northern Central America through 2025.&nbsp; The company’s planned investments include improvements to its infrastructure and manufacturing plants; expansion of new distribution routes; IT projects; and investments aligned with its “pep+” (PepsiCo Positive) agenda. This includes spreading regenerative farming practices across seven million acres (which is approximately the size of the company’s entire agricultural footprint), becoming Net Water Positive by 2030 by reducing absolute water use and replenishing watersheds, and achieving net-zero emissions by 2040 by increasing the use of renewable energy, among other efforts.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Support for Small Businesses</strong>:&nbsp; Grupo Mariposa will provide over 70,000 small-business owners with access to credit and digital services.&nbsp; It will also support 3,500 small and medium-enterprises with access to telemedicine, education, and Internet connectivity, impacting more than 200,000 people and expanding healthcare and telemedicine solutions to 2,000 remote communities. In addition, it will invest more than $10 million to grow its coffee footprint, creating more than 500 new jobs and supporting more than 400 small and medium-sized coffee producers to increase productivity and earnings potential. <a></a></li></ul>



<ul><li>CARE announced its plans to establish a $50 million Center for Gender Equity in Central America focused on women and young people and designed to reach 500,000 individual women and their families, impacting two million people in total.&nbsp; The Center will support public and private programs in the region – scaling up those that work – to support financial inclusion, women’s economic empowerment (including in the protection of labor rights and in supporting entrepreneurship), improved agricultural outcomes, and reductions in gender-based violence. In particular, CARE will support companies joining the Call to Action with technical assistance to ensure that a gender-based lens is applied to new programs and investment.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Creating Economic Opportunity</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Job Creation:</strong>&nbsp; In Fiscal Year 2021, USAID support to private sector firms in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras helped create more than 70,000 jobs, spurred $415 million in sales, and supported agricultural producers to gain access to $860 million in financing.&nbsp; In Honduras, USAID helped establish a new $20 million loan facility to lend to underserved agricultural clients, especially women agribusiness owners.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Mobilizing Investment:</strong>&nbsp; Through USAID’s Guatemalan Entrepreneurship and Development Innovation initiative, announced by Vice President Harris in June 2021, USAID has leveraged $59 million, against its $7.5 million investment, from international and local private sector partners to scale technology-driven, market-led solutions to critical development challenges throughout the country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Public-Private Partnerships:</strong>&nbsp; U.S. Government advocacy contributed to Guatemala’s first public-private partnership (PPP) project in November 2021, which will extend and repair the highway that connects the capital with the country’s primary Pacific port, Puerto Quetzal, and can serve as a model for other infrastructure investment and help Guatemalans bring their products to the global market.&nbsp; The U.S. Trade and Development Agency (USTDA), in December 2021, awarded a feasibility study grant to develop a PPP that would install LED streetlights along more than 500 kilometers of highway across El Salvador to improve safety, increase energy efficiency, and lower energy costs.&nbsp; These PPPs can serve as powerful models for future infrastructure investment collaboration in the region.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Access to Finance:</strong>&nbsp; In October 2021, the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC) disbursed $100 million to the Central American Bank for Economic Integration (CABEI) to fund financial institution intermediaries in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras which will then lend to micro, small, and medium enterprises (MSMEs) to support economic recovery in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; The DFC, with USAID funding, provided additional loan guarantees to entities in El Salvador and Honduras to enhance lending to women-led small and medium enterprises (SMEs) and SMEs in high growth sectors of the economy to support economic growth and job creation within historically marginalized communities. &nbsp;In September 2021, USAID finalized a new loan guarantee that is facilitating access to loans for SMEs in the Western Highlands of Guatemala, a region with high levels of out-migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Trade Facilitation: &nbsp;</strong>In August 2021, the Department of Commerce’s Commercial Law Development Program (CLDP) and International Trade Administration (ITA) conducted a regional trade facilitation workshop with Guatemalan customs and trade ministries. &nbsp;In May and June of 2022, CLDP will host two workshops in Honduras on customs valuation and communication. &nbsp;These workshops are part of a multiphase effort to promote transparency, cooperation, and coordination among the northern Central American governments and improve inter-regional trade.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Strengthening Health and Education</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Vaccine Doses:</strong>&nbsp; To assist people in the region in combating the COVID-19 pandemic, the U.S. Government has delivered more than 15 million free-of-cost vaccine doses bilaterally and in partnership with COVAX to countries in northern Central America.&nbsp;Vaccination rates are steadily increasing in all three countries with Guatemala at 33 percent, Honduras at 46 percent, and El Salvador at 66 percent of their populations completing the initial COVID-19 vaccination protocol.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Vaccine Financing:</strong>&nbsp; In September 2021, the DFC, in conjunction with Citigroup Inc., provided a risk management solution to Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, to mitigate risk and overcome financial hurdles with governments that are funding COVID-19 vaccine purchases through the COVAX Facility.&nbsp; Of the $383 million in political risk insurance provided to Gavi, $50 million was provided to support allocation of vaccines to Guatemala.</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp; The U.S. Government has provided $26.4 million to El Salvador, $81.5 million to Guatemala, and $57.1 million to Honduras to support the fight against COVID-19 and strengthen health systems.&nbsp; Assistance is supporting training health care workers and public health staff in critical care management and safe and effective administration of vaccines, building laboratory capacity, strengthening contact tracing efforts, sharing critical information to prevent the spread of disease, providing technical assistance for the health information systems needed to evaluate vaccine distribution equity and monitor vaccine safety, and bolstering oxygen systems to ensure availability for patients who need them in Guatemala and Honduras.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Education:</strong>&nbsp; In El Salvador in November 2021, USAID launched a $20 million Scholarships for Education Project to curb irregular migration by increasing equitable access to formal educational opportunities for 6,450 returnees and potential migrants.&nbsp; In Honduras, USAID installed Internet hotspots in 60 community learning centers and increased access to remote learning for more than 5,000 people, including more than 600 returned migrant children. USAID also completed repairs on and expansions to two schools in western Honduras, which serve more than 1,800 local students in this area of high out-migration.&nbsp; In Guatemala, USAID provided education assistance to more than 6,300 at-risk youth and launched new partnerships to strengthen English language programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Enhancing Climate Resilience and Food Security</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Humanitarian Assistance:&nbsp; </strong>Since April 2021, USAID reached approximately 1.9 million people impacted by recurrent droughts, COVID-19, and severe damage from Hurricanes Eta and Iota in northern Central America with life-saving humanitarian assistance such as emergency food assistance, health, livelihoods restoration, protection, shelter as well as water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) support.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Food Security:&nbsp; </strong>The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) provided $30 million to expand its Food for Progress program in Guatemala, which will enable it to reach an additional 18,000 producers.&nbsp; USDA provided $45 million to expand its McGovern-Dole school feeding, health, nutrition, and educational programming in Guatemala and Honduras, reaching an additional 124,000 beneficiaries, with a projection of nearly 400,000 beneficiaries over the life of the program.<strong>&nbsp; </strong>In addition, in Fiscal Year 2021, USAID’s Feed the Future activities in Honduras directly assisted nearly 16,000 farm families and agribusinesses in adopting technologies to increase yields.&nbsp; This assistance contributed to over $23 million in incremental sales.&nbsp; In Guatemala, USAID’s Feed the Future activities created nearly 30,000 jobs and over $76 million in sales while leveraging over $10 million in financing and $6 million in investment in the agricultural sector.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Combating Corruption</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Anti-Corruption Task Force:</strong>&nbsp; In June 2021, Vice President Harris announced the establishment of the Department of Justice’s Anti-Corruption Task Force (ACTF). The ACTF subsequently created a new tip line for reporting corruption in the region and the FBI has reviewed and followed up on the resulting tips.&nbsp; The ACTF continues to operate the tip line and relies on relationships with counterparts, witnesses, cooperators and others in the region to streamline and prioritize investigations.&nbsp; In addition, the number of Department of Justice Resident Legal Advisors (RLAs), supported by the Department of State, was increased throughout the region, and RLAs continue to work with their counterparts in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.&nbsp; In November 2021, an RLA-assisted Honduran anti-corruption unit secured guilty verdicts against the former minister of health and former minister of labor on charges of embezzlement, bribery, fraud, and money laundering.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Sanctions and Visa Restrictions:&nbsp; </strong>In December 2021, the Department of the Treasury imposed sanctions on officials in El Salvador and Guatemala in connection with public corruption pursuant to the Global Magnitsky sanctions program, which allows for the targeting of corruption and serious human rights abuse.&nbsp; In addition, the Department of State publicly designated several Guatemalan and Salvadoran officials under Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act for their involvement in significant corruption, generally rendering them and their immediate family members ineligible for entry into the United States.&nbsp; Prior to these actions, the Department of State publicly included multiple current and former officials and private individuals on the Section 353 Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List generally rendering these individuals ineligible for visas and admission to the United States.&nbsp;In August 2021, the United States also launched a new visa restriction authority under Section 212(1)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act on the issuance of visas to current or former Guatemalan, Honduran, or Salvadoran government officials and other individuals believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining democracy or the rule of law.&nbsp; <strong></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Audit and Oversight:</strong>&nbsp; To promote transparency and fight corruption, USAID trained 100 auditors in Guatemala’s Specialized Center for Tax and Customs Crimes to better identify tax crimes, donated computer equipment for use in field audits, and provided technical assistance on the documentation of criminal complaints.&nbsp; With USAID support, the Center has recovered nearly $80 million in tax revenue since its inception.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing Democracy, Promoting the Rule of Law, and Protecting Human Rights</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Democratic Elections:</strong>&nbsp; The Department of State and USAID engaged all levels of Honduran society and the government ahead of the November 2021 presidential election to promote free, fair, and peaceful elections that reflected the will of Honduran voters.&nbsp; USAID assistance helped facilitate the country’s election through support to journalists and civil society organizations to objectively report on information about the election process, independent analyses that informed recommendations on elections security, and get out the vote campaigns.&nbsp; USAID also supported the strengthening of electoral management bodies.&nbsp; The Department of State supported training for police officers in advance of the elections, including content on the use of force and relevant election laws and procedures, and distributed 20,000 election day pocket guides to police officers emphasizing the importance of respecting the rights of all citizens to vote.&nbsp; The election, characterized by high voter turnout, resulted in the peaceful election of the country’s first woman president.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp; Across the northern Central American countries, the Department of State and USAID worked together to promote human rights, labor rights, and press freedom.&nbsp; USAID increased resources to respond to rising protection needs, providing critical support to journalists, human rights defenders, and anti-corruption champions. &nbsp;USAID provided timely assistance to more than 30 human rights defenders and democracy advocates in El Salvador, Guatemala and Honduras. &nbsp;To respond to high rates of extortion, human trafficking, and violence among marginalized sexual and gender minority individuals, USAID supported LGBTQI+ civil society organizations to address regressive policies and advocate for reforms to key laws.&nbsp; In Honduras, this included advocating for transgender individuals to be able to legally register under their chosen names, rather than the names on their birth certificates under the law governing the National Persons Registry. &nbsp;A public petition garnered more than 4,000 signatures before submission to the Honduran National Congress in November 2021.&nbsp; As the Congress considers its response, LGBTQI+ advocacy groups are engaged in related advocacy and policy efforts to further promote necessary protections. In addition, U.S. Southern Command’s Human Rights Initiative has efforts in all three northern Central American countries, helping to institutionalize respect for human rights in partner nation armed forces doctrine and professional education.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>New Technical Assistance to Promote Labor Rights:&nbsp; </strong>The Department of Labor (DOL) recently announced $20 million in new programs in northern Central America.&nbsp; Activities will focus on increasing collective action to address child and forced labor and improve occupational safety and health conditions of workers in the region.&nbsp; Efforts also will improve the ability of workers to exercise their labor rights in agricultural supply chains in Guatemala and Honduras and the textile/apparel sector in El Salvador.&nbsp; <strong>&nbsp;</strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Labor Roundtables:&nbsp;</strong>In June and July 2021, DOL hosted nine labor roundtables, convening over 50 unions and civil society organizations from the United States, El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to discuss the nexus between labor issues and migration.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Combating Crime and Increasing Security&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Human Smuggling:&nbsp; </strong>In June 2021, Vice President Harris announced the creation of a regional task force to identify, disrupt, and prevent migrant smuggling and human trafficking operations.Working with partners in the region, the Departments of Justice and Homeland Security’s Joint Task Force Alpha, which targets human smuggling, continues to identify and pursue priority human smuggling cases for prosecution within the United States.&nbsp; Department of Justice RLAs, with Department of State support, are working with counterparts in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to pursue investigations and prosecutions.&nbsp; In November 2021, prosecutors mentored by RLAs obtained indictments against twenty members of a human smuggling organization (HSO) that operated throughout El Salvador and Guatemala.&nbsp; In a coordinated effort, Guatemalan police and prosecutors also executed search warrants at five locations linked to the same HSO.&nbsp; In January 2022, as part of another coordinated investigation with DHS’s Homeland Security Investigations, Guatemalan authorities executed 19 search warrants, seized over $200,000, and arrested ten Guatemalan nationals for violations of foreign law related to human smuggling and money laundering. In Honduras, U.S. government efforts resulted in the formation of a migration task force to focus on investigation and prosecution of smuggling and trafficking networks.&nbsp; Since January 2021 this and other border security programs have resulted in the arrest of 283 alleged human smugglers, the rescue of 200 minors, and a tripling in the number of migrants checked against U.S. criminal and terrorist databases.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Money Laundering:</strong>&nbsp; In November 2021, U.S.-mentored prosecutors in Honduras secured money laundering convictions against seven Honduran nationals who were high-level members of the Byron Ruiz drug trafficking organization previously convicted of aggravated drug trafficking charges in Honduras.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Civilian Law Enforcement:</strong>  The Department of State worked to professionalize security forces across the region by training more than 5,000 civilian police in calendar year 2021 on topics such as community policing, investigations, and human rights. <br></li><li><strong>Conventional Weapons Destruction:  </strong>In 2021, the Department of State provided explosive ordnance disposal and stockpile management training to 86 security forces personnel, destroyed 7.91 metric tons of obsolete munitions, and provided physical security upgrades to vulnerable weapons storage facilities in El Salvador and Guatemala to prevent the illicit pilferage and proliferation of State-held weapons which contribute to armed violence and criminal activity in the region.<br></li><li><strong>Regional Information Sharing:</strong>  The Department of State supported a regional effort to share criminal intelligence about transnational criminal organizations and associated criminals in Central America, with a focus on migrant smuggling and human trafficking.  In 2021, this effort facilitated the identification of nearly 1,200 members of transnational criminal organizations.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reinsertion of Former Offenders:</strong>&nbsp; In El Salvador, USAID supported an innovative and evidence-based reinsertion model for adult and youth populations exiting prison and gang-involvement, which in the last year has led to a 70 percent success rate of participants receiving employment or consistently participating in skill building support and not re-offending.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong></strong></li></ul>



<p><strong>Focusing on Women and Youth</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Gender-Based Violence:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp; In February 2022, USAID awarded a $5 million grant to El Refugio de la Niñez, a Guatemalan NGO, to expand education, legal, housing, medical, psychosocial and other services to survivors of trafficking in persons and unaccompanied migrant children. In September 2021, the Department of State supported the design and implementation of a specialized course for Honduran prosecutors on gender-based violence, including domestic violence, which launched with an initial class of 25 prosecutors in February 2022. &nbsp;U.S. support is helping the Honduran National Police revamp its training curriculum to focus on incidents of gender-based violence and train 911 operators on how to prioritize and route the more than 60 reports of such violence daily.&nbsp; U.S. programs are also significantly increasing post-violence victim support and resources.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Young Women&#8217;s Empowerment</strong>:&nbsp; With the June 2021 launch of its $40 million Young Women’s Empowerment Initiative, USAID is partnering with Guatemalan indigenous and women’s organizations, private sector, and international organizations to increase education, professional training, and income-generating opportunities for thousands of indigenous Guatemalan women and girls.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Women Entrepreneurs:</strong>&nbsp; The Department of State’s Academy of Women Entrepreneurs (AWE) program in northern Central America provides women participants the knowledge, networks, and access to launch and scale their businesses through a proven combination of business classes, professional mentoring, and seed money.&nbsp; In September 2021, Honduras added 315 new participants and in November 2021, Guatemala graduated a class of 120 women, including representatives from highland and Afro-Guatemalan Garifuna communities with high rates of emigration, while El Salvador graduated a class of 176 women, 36 of whom received $24,000 in seed capital to invest further in their businesses and create jobs in their communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Advancing Women’s Economic Empowerment:</strong>&nbsp; On January 4, 2022, USAID launched the <em>MujerProspera</em> (WomenProsper) challenge, seeking solutions that advance women’s economic security, employment, and/or entrepreneurship in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.&nbsp; With this challenge, USAID expects to issue up to 14 awards each valued between $150,000 and $500,000 later this spring.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>At-Risk Youth:</strong>&nbsp; Since July 2021, USAID has provided psychosocial support and family counseling, gender-based violence prevention activities, life-skills training, vocational workshops, digital inclusion, sports and arts activities, and alternative education for youth left out of the formal education system for more than 27,500 children and youth in 80 high-crime and out-migration communities of the north, central, and western regions of Honduras.&nbsp; The Department of State worked with certified Gang Resistance Education and Training (G.R.E.A.T.) instructors across Honduras to reach more than 100,000 children and help strengthen their ability to resist gang recruitment. In El Salvador, USAID launched a $20 million alliance (which includes $10 million in private sector leverage) with local partner Glasswing International to improve citizen security in targeted Salvadoran communities to help reduce irregular migration, with a goal of reaching 30,000 people (mostly youth) in five years with economic and educational opportunities.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Enhancing Partnerships</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Engaging Local Organizations:</strong>&nbsp; In November 2021, USAID announced <em>Centroamérica Local</em>, a five-year, $300 million initiative to empower local organizations in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to address the drivers of irregular migration to the United States.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Cooperation with Mexico:</strong>&nbsp; In December 2021, the United States and Mexico announced <em>Sembrando Oportunidades</em>, a new framework for development cooperation to address the root causes of irregular migration from El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.&nbsp; These efforts are underway. In El Salvador, USAID is providing scholarships to graduates of Mexico’s youth workforce program, and in Honduras, USAID and its Mexican counterpart aim to reach more than 500,000 at-risk youth with skills and experience that can lead to long-term employment.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Diplomatic Engagement Around the World to Address Root Causes</strong></p>



<ul><li>The Vice President has recognized the need to internationalize her efforts, and has been rallying partners around the world to support U.S. efforts to address the root causes of migration. The Vice President’s extensive diplomatic engagement with leaders around the world includes the following important new commitments:</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Republic of Korea</u></strong>:&nbsp; After the Vice President met with South&nbsp;Korean President&nbsp;Moon Jae-in, the Republican of Korea doubled foreign assistance to northern Central America to $220 million over five years.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Japan</u></strong>:&nbsp; The Government of Japan committed to closer collaboration and has provided nearly $22 million in assistance to the three countries of northern Central America.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Israel</u></strong>:&nbsp; The Israeli government announced it would collaborate with USAID on agriculture, watershed management, and violence prevention programs in Guatemala and Honduras.</li></ul>



<p>The Vice President&#8217;s diplomacy helped establish the United Nations Humanitarian Response Plans for Honduras, El Salvador and Guatemala. She has worked with the European Union and Canada, which have become the largest donors to the effort after the United States.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 19,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/19/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-19-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 19:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Portsmouth, New Hampshire 1:16 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Welcome to our trip to New Hampshire.&#160; I highlighted a little bit of this yesterday, so I will keep this brief. But as a reminder, we are headed to Portsmouth.&#160; Portsmouth Harbor, which we are visiting, is the only deep-water harbor in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Portsmouth, New Hampshire</p>



<p>1:16 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Welcome to our trip to New Hampshire.&nbsp; I highlighted a little bit of this yesterday, so I will keep this brief.</p>



<p>But as a reminder, we are headed to Portsmouth.&nbsp; Portsmouth Harbor, which we are visiting, is the only deep-water harbor in New Hampshire and handles approximately 3.5 million tons and nearly $2 billion of cargo a year.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, we awarded $1.7 million from the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers for maintenance dredging in Portsmouth Harbor through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the investment builds on an $18.2 million Army Corps project in Portsmouth Harbor for navigation improvement, which widened the uppermost turning basin in the river.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, the President will hear from the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, Coast Guard Commander for Sector Northern New England, and New Hampshire Port Director on the impact of these projects and funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law on the port.</p>



<p>On the ground in Portsmouth, he will also see Governor Chris Sununu; Senator Hassan; Representatives Pappas and Annie &#8212; and Kuster; the mayors of Portsmouth and Manchester; and several other state and local elected officials.</p>



<p>I also wanted to note &#8212; did you all get the P+11 readout?&nbsp; Did it come to you yet?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, I’m not sure it’s gone out.</p>



<p>So let me &#8212; let me do a couple of highlights from that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Watch out, Jen.&nbsp; The door is closing.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, thank you.&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>As you know, the President had a call with the P+11 this morning, as it was part of our close coordination with Allies and partners.&nbsp; He convened the video conference to discuss their ongoing efforts to support Ukraine in the face of Russian aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leaders reiterated their commitment to continue providing security, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine in its time of need.&nbsp; The leaders affirmed their solidarity with the Ukrainian people and condemned the humanitarian suffering caused by Russia&#8217;s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They also discussed their respective diplomatic engagements and their coordinated efforts to continue to impose severe economic costs to hold Russia accountable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They agreed to continue to closely coordinate their efforts, including working with and through the G7, EU, and NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, with that, yes, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On the mask mandate, why is the DOJ not appealing that?&nbsp; And by not, do you &#8212; does the administration risk taking away some of your options for the future, especially if there&#8217;s some new variants?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, unless something&#8217;s happened when we got on the plane, I don&#8217;t think they&#8217;ve made any announcement at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as we&#8217;ve said, agencies are reviewing step &#8212; next steps, including the Department of Justice.&nbsp; Traditionally following a court decision, that can take a couple of days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve said from the start that our COVID response should be guided by the science and data and by experts.&nbsp; And just as a reminder, when we made this announcement, the CDC said it needed 15 days to assess the impacts of an uptick in cases on hospitalizations, deaths, and hospital capacity.&nbsp; We feel &#8212; still feel that is entirely reasonable, based on the latest science, and public health decisions shouldn&#8217;t be made by the courts.&nbsp; They should be made by public health experts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, again, I can&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the Department of Justice. &nbsp;We’ll let them make any decisions or announcements, but &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So they might still appeal, is what you&#8217;re saying?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It typically &#8212; yeah, it typically takes a couple of days to review and make an assessment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you don&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, if you don&#8217;t appeal, do you run the risk of sending the message that all CDC mandates are optional?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to prejudge the Department of Justice and how they make considerations or assessments about whether or not they&#8217;re going to appeal.&nbsp; We obviously feel confident in our authorities here, given we put the mask mandate in place and asked for 15 additional days to evaluate data based on public health information.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was the administration unprepared for this ruling, given that you’re not sure what you&#8217;re going to do next?</p>



<p>And also, does the confusion around the mask mandate undercut the administration&#8217;s ability to kind of give people guidance on what is actually the right thing to do at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would &#8212; I would dispute the notion that people are confused.&nbsp; We are here to alleviate their confusion, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the CDC continues to advise and recommend masks on airplanes.&nbsp; We&#8217;re abiding by the CDC recommendations, the President is.&nbsp; And we would advise all Americans to do that.</p>



<p>This was a ruling by the court.&nbsp; We obviously didn&#8217;t have advance notice of it.&nbsp; And it typically takes a couple of days to assess next steps in these cases.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And should the President be speaking &#8212; does the President have plans to speak more about this kind of evolution in how people should protect themselves from COVID, given the sense that precautions are lifting?&nbsp; You know, does he plan to speak out more in providing more guidance and leadership on this issue?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don’t see it as an evolution.&nbsp; We continue to believe that the CDC, which asked for 15 days to evaluate health data and information based on the fact that cases were rising in certain parts of the country &#8212; that that was entirely reasonable, and that they would, at the conclusion of that period of time &#8212; not a lengthy period of time &#8212; be able to make an evaluation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He also put out a 100-page plan just a couple of weeks ago on how to deal with this moment we are in as we address the virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What our biggest concern is right now &#8212; continues to be the fact that we don&#8217;t have funding from Congress to ensure that we can return to a point where we have programs for the uninsured, we’re able to purchased &#8212; purchase treatments for the immunocompromised, ensuring that we continue to be the arsenal of vaccines to the world.&nbsp; Those are our biggest concerns.&nbsp; And, yes, we will speak out about that and he will speak out about that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Russia and terrorism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the admi- &#8212; I got one.&nbsp; I got one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you talked about this yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I got one.&nbsp; Hold on, Jen.&nbsp; On this same issue &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Until we land we’re (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, it’s my turn.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the issue of masking and your strategy in general, does the administration feel like your strategies have been thwarted by courts, in general?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to &#8212; as a follow-up to Nancy&#8217;s question and to Jennifer&#8217;s question, if you &#8212; if you&#8217;re not challenging this, what are the next steps?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, if the Department of Justice makes that decision, we can talk about that.&nbsp; But they haven&#8217;t made a decision yet.&nbsp; And it typically takes a couple of days &#8212; some time to make that assessment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What was the first part of your question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m thinking about the fact that I don&#8217;t think you challenged the ruling that struck down the employer vaccine mandate.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I’m just wondering what &#8212; if you&#8217;re not going to challenge these things when they &#8212; when they get stepped out, at least in that example &#8212; we don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s going to happen with this one &#8212; what&#8217;s the next step?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not going to prejudge what the Department of Justice decides.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will say, on the employer mandate, what we did was we continued to encourage private sector companies to put in place requirements that would keep their communities safe.&nbsp; And there were a lot of big companies that had already done that &#8212; including airlines, by the way; including big hospital systems around the country &#8212; and done that effectively, efficiently without having a big drop-off of employees in their workforce.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So in this case, even as there&#8217;s not a decision yet made by the Department of Justice, we&#8217;re continuing to encourage people to wear masks in public transit.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll make that decision because it&#8217;s obviously not being implemented at this moment in time, but we&#8217;ll continue to abide by CDC guidance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the CDC changes their assessment, which certainly at some point they will, we would follow that guidance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Russia and terrorism.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you talked about this a little bit yesterday, but &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; I&#8217;m &#8212; and I know you saw CNN is reporting that the U.S. is considering labeling Russia a purveyor of state-sponsored terrorism.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about that?&nbsp; Is that true that you are considering that?&nbsp; Tell us a little bit about how that would work out.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just take a step back for a second so everybody knows how this process works, which you all may already know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But for a country to be designated as a state sponsor of terrorism, the Secretary of State would have to determine that the government of that country has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.&nbsp; And only four countries have been designated to date &#8212; right? &#8212; Cuba, North Korea, Iran, and Syria.&nbsp; The designation is defined by statute, meaning Congress has written into law the exact criteria under which a state would qualify as a state sponsor of terrorism.</p>



<p>So I know my colleague over at the State Department, Ned Price, has said there &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a lot of asks that President Zelenskyy has.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking at a range of them.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update on what their process may or may not look like.&nbsp; I would point you to them to speak to that, because it&#8217;s determined by the statute from Congress, by the State Department.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, how concerned is the White House about the IMF’s prediction of seismic, you know, problems for the economy around the world due to Ukraine?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, just following on from that, is there a sense that if this goes on, which looks like it will in Ukraine, the fallout for other countries could eventually pressure the alliance the President has been building to, you know, basically dial back a bit even if the Ukrainians want to push on &#8212; maybe, like, try and force them into, you know, reaching a settlement that &#8212; yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, okay, on the second question I would say that we&#8217;ve known from the beginning that unity doesn&#8217;t happen by accident.&nbsp; It requires a great deal of work, a great deal of diplomacy, a great deal of discussion.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s part of the reason the President had the P+11 call this morning: to continue to keep other countries updated &#8212; whether it&#8217;s NATO or the G7 or other groups of countries &#8212; on what we&#8217;re considering in terms of sanctions, what we&#8217;re considering in terms of military assistance, what other countries are doing.&nbsp; Sometimes there&#8217;s equipment the Ukrainians want we don&#8217;t have; we discuss that with them as well.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s why there&#8217;s so much time and effort &#8212; from the President, from the Secretary of State, others &#8212; is being spent on this exactly.</p>



<p>I would say on the IMF projections: You know, I would note that the projection for the United States and our growth still continues to be higher than the vast majority of the world.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And that is a sign of the strength of our economy.</p>



<p>But it is true &#8212; and we&#8217;ve said this from the beginning &#8212; that the invasion of Ukraine by President Putin and Russia is going to have a continued impact on the global economy, whether it is on the oil markets or other areas. &nbsp;And certainly, that&#8217;s something we are aware of, even as the strength of our own economy &#8212; you know, we have a strong basis to build on through this difficult time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the call this morning, the Pentagon has said that they&#8217;re concerned that the ammunition levels for Ukrainians are getting dangerously low.&nbsp; Was that something that the President brought up in trying to get Allies to provide more ammunition?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I can check on that and see if there&#8217;s anything specifically on ammunition.&nbsp; Certainly, we will continue to provide them more ammunition as we will provide them more military assistance.&nbsp; There&#8217;s obviously more money we can provide from the approved drawdown package, and the specifics of that are being worked through with the Department of Defense and our national security team.&nbsp; And that, you know, has included ammunition, and I would expect will include a range of weapons moving forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more question on the mask mandate.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand that the judge&#8217;s ruling is something that, you know, independent judiciary has made.&nbsp; However, you saw a lot of Americans, you know, immediately pulling off their masks in airplanes, very happy about the change.&nbsp; Is the administration concerned that the public is moving on, you know, without the CDC and that the country is in a different place where the administration is in?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would note, while I&#8217;ve seen those videos, anecdotes are not data.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And certainly, that does tell a part of the story.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t make these decisions based on politics or based on the political whims on a plane or even in a poll.&nbsp;<br><br>But I would note: In polls, they &#8212; and data &#8212; lengthier data &#8212; there are still a lot of people in this country who still want to have masks in place &#8212; either they have immunocompromised relatives, they have kids under five, whatever it may be.&nbsp;<br><br>So in the &#8212; even on the pure politics, I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a concrete story at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the President is going to, you know, New Hampshire today to talk about infrastructure, selling the benefits of that.&nbsp; He said a few months ago that people didn&#8217;t want to see him being a “Senator-President” anymore.&nbsp; They want to see him getting out there, and his schedule certainly reflects that.&nbsp;<br><br>But, you know, the Chief of Staff has talked about the calendar, you know, being short and there being only so many days in the calendar to do things.&nbsp;<br><br>Is he, at some point, going to come out and talk about what he wants to see in, potentially, a skinny Build Back Better bill, given that time is of the essence with that?&nbsp;<br><br>And we haven&#8217;t heard from him really &#8212; anything about the, you know, negotiations and the talks.&nbsp; Is he going to come out and sort of put a marker down, or is the fact that he hasn&#8217;t come out and maybe won&#8217;t come out sort of a sign that maybe that&#8217;s not really going anywhere?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, one of the decisions he also made &#8212; the President, that is &#8212; is that he wasn&#8217;t going to talk a lot publicly, because he didn&#8217;t feel it was advantageous to getting things done, about his conversations with members of all political stripes.&nbsp; And just because he&#8217;s not talking about it doesn&#8217;t mean those conversations are not happening behind the scenes.&nbsp;<br><br>And as it relates to not being a senator &#8212; or not being the “President-Senator” &#8212; I think is that &#8212; how you said it &#8212; I mean, going out in the country today and out later this week is a reflection of that.&nbsp; Going out and talking about the impacts of his policies and his agenda on the American people &#8212; in New Hampshire, out on the West Coast &#8212; that&#8217;s exactly our effort to do that and not being holed up in the Oval Office having congressional negotiations.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we assume that if there&#8217;s no one out there sort of talking about a new BBB bill, that there isn&#8217;t an agreement yet?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think if we had a bill that was ready to pass with 50 votes, we would make that clear.&nbsp; So the &#8212; but there&#8217;s a range of ongoing negotiations and discussions with senators amongst themselves, a lot of them &#8212; a lot &#8212; there&#8217;s a great deal of support for moving an agenda forward that lowers costs for the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>So, not having a public speech from the President is not a reflection of what&#8217;s happening behind the scenes.&nbsp; There&#8217;s actually a strategic decision made not to have public updates about behind-the-scenes conversations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on Title 42, there are some Democratic senators &#8212; including Senator Hassan, Senator Peters &#8212; who have expressed concerns about what happens, what comes next after Title 42 lapses.&nbsp; And I know you said yesterday that the answer, if people want changes, is congressional legislation.</p>



<p>(Gaggle interruption.)&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You good?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I’m good.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it’s unlikely that, you know, Congress is going to pass something in the next few months, if at all.&nbsp; So, as an alternative to that, can you tell us anything about any plans that are underway to try to ease the transition to a post-Title 42 &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I mean, the Sec- &#8212; the Home- &#8212; Department of Homeland Security and the Secretary put out a comprehensive plan for what they were going to do to prepare for any increase in influx.&nbsp; They put that out when we made an announcement about the timeline of implementation.&nbsp; And that’s something they’re having ongoing discussions with senators, members, and their teams and staff about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, certainly, I’m sure they welcome suggestions or different things that can be done.&nbsp; But they did put out a comprehensive plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The issue here &#8212; the core issue is that it is being used to tie down and hold back the COVID funding.&nbsp; And our concern here is: Let’s have a conversation about immigration. &nbsp;Title 42 is not an immigration policy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the point.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a public health authority that Congress has given the CDC authority to make a determination about.&nbsp; They made the determination.</p>



<p>So, if we want to address immigration, let&#8217;s have a conversation about that.&nbsp; But let&#8217;s not hold COVID funding hostage because we&#8217;re going to have to end a range of programs that are hurt &#8212; going to hurt the American people.&nbsp; That’s the issue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we expect any new Russia sanctions this week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There could be, Jeff.&nbsp; I think that we&#8217;re still consid- &#8212; making &#8212; doing considerations and running a process for additional sanctions, but there are some under consideration, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you tell us anything more about these Cuba-U.S. talks that the Cubans are saying that are happening, I think, tomorrow &#8212; is that right?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me get an update on that.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t had a chance to talk to the national security team about that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also on Ukraine, can you say how much money is left in that drawdown fund that you were talking about?&nbsp; And, obviously, both Schumer and McConnell have been talking about the need for sending more money to Ukraine.&nbsp; Is the White House open to that?&nbsp; Are there discussions about that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; There&#8217;s an ongoing discussion with the Ukrainians about what they need, with Congress about what we can provide, and about how to &#8212; and briefings of them &#8212; to them, I should say, about how to spend the remaining drawdown funds.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Which is how much?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will check on that for you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One question since we’re going to talk about climate in Portland and Seattle.&nbsp; Given that BBB is, you know, still &#8212; we’re not sure where the status of that is &#8212; I mean, what can you say about the &#8212; what message the President can send, given that his major climate initiatives are &#8212; they’re stalled in legislation as he’s trying to draw attention to work on climate this week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law had an enormous investment in addressing the climate crisis in it, including investing in charging stations for electric vehicles across the country.&nbsp; Never has that ever been done before in that capacity.&nbsp; He has also taken a range of steps, including &#8212;</p>



<p>(Air Force One begins landing.)</p>



<p>Oh, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; okay, we got a few more &#8212; a few more seconds here.</p>



<p>&#8212; with his own authorities, including rallying automakers and auto workers around an electric transportation future; setting a national target of 50 percent electric vehicles sales by 2030; launching the EV Charging Action Plan to deploy $7.5 billion from the Bipartisan Law I mentioned; finalizing the strongest possible passenger vehicle standards in American history; issuing the U.S. Methane Emissions Restriction Action.</p>



<p>The point is: He&#8217;s not going to wait or delay taking actions to address the climate crisis.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to fight for the key components that are in Build Back Better. &nbsp;But also, the Infrastructure Law that he&#8217;s already passed, signed into law, and is implementing has a major investment in climate in it.</p>



<p>Okay, we’re about to land.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Everybody brace for landing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaking of (inaudible) calendars, have you heard the President weigh in on which states he would prefer to go first in the nominating process?&nbsp; Has he talked about that at all, as far as &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There’s a DNC process, and we trust that process to take place and move forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so the President hasn’t weighed in, as far as you know, on &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re relying on the DNC process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he has no preference?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re relying on the DNC process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he talked to the DNC Chairman about it at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have any updates on private conversations.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>1:33 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the President’s Call with Allies and&#160;Partners</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/readout-of-the-presidents-call-with-allies-and-partners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 18:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. hosted a videoconference today with Allies and partners to discuss international support for Ukraine in the face of Russian aggression, including the ongoing provision of security, economic, and humanitarian assistance.&#160; The leaders affirmed their solidarity with the Ukrainian people and condemned the humanitarian suffering caused by Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. hosted a videoconference today with Allies and partners to discuss international support for Ukraine in the face of Russian aggression, including the ongoing provision of security, economic, and humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; The leaders affirmed their solidarity with the Ukrainian people and condemned the humanitarian suffering caused by Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion. &nbsp;They also discussed their coordinated efforts to impose&nbsp;severe economic costs to hold Russia accountable.&nbsp; They committed to continued close consultation, including working with and through the G7, EU, and NATO.</p>



<p>Joining President Biden on the call were Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada, European Commission President von der Leyen, European Council President Michel, President Macron of France, Chancellor Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Draghi of Italy, Prime Minister Kishida of Japan, NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg, President Duda of Poland, President Iohannis of Romania, and Prime Minister Johnson of the United Kingdom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 3197 and H.R.&#160;5681</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/04/19/bill-signed-h-r-3197-and-h-r-5681/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 17:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, April 19, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 3197, the &#8220;Save the Liberty Theater Act of 2021,&#8221; which directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the City of Eunice, Louisiana, by quitclaim deed and without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified parcels&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, April 19, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 3197, the &#8220;Save the Liberty Theater Act of 2021,&#8221; which directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the City of Eunice, Louisiana, by quitclaim deed and without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified parcels of land.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representative Mike Johnson and Senator Kennedy for their leadership.</p>



<p>H.R. 5681, the &#8220;Shadow Wolves Enhancement Act,&#8221; which authorizes U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) to reclassify officers assigned to the tactical patrol unit on Tohono O&#8217;odham Nation land, commonly known as Shadow Wolves, as ICE special agents.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Katko, Cuellar, Cole, Joyce, Mullin, Gallego and Senators Sinema, Hoeven, Kelly, and Hassan for their leadership</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
