<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 19:51:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by the President on the Bipartisan Confirmation of Career Prosecutor Steve Dettelbach to be the First Senate-Confirmed ATF Director in 7&#160;Years</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/statement-by-the-president-on-the-bipartisan-confirmation-of-career-prosecutor-steve-dettelbach-to-be-the-first-senate-confirmed-atf-director-in-7-years/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 19:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As I’ve made clear time and time again, the answer to the rise in crime my administration inherited is not to defund law enforcement; it’s to provide law enforcement with the resources and support they need to&#160; succeed in working effectively with the communities they serve. The Senate just took an important, bipartisan step by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As I’ve made clear time and time again, the answer to the rise in crime my administration inherited is not to defund law enforcement; it’s to provide law enforcement with the resources and support they need to&nbsp; succeed in working effectively with the communities they serve.</p>



<p>The Senate just took an important, bipartisan step by confirming Steve Dettelbach, an extraordinarily qualified and decorated career prosecutor with strong support across the law enforcement community, to be the first permanent head of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives in over 7 years.</p>



<p>Steve’s distinguished prosecutorial experience spans over two decades at the Department of Justice under four different administrations, two Republican and two Democratic. His work and reputation have earned him the support of former ATF directors who’ve led the department over the last 40 years, in addition to a wide range of law enforcement organizations and leaders, including police chiefs and sheriffs across the country. He was also endorsed by the U.S. Conference of Mayors.</p>



<p>Following the passage of the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act, today’s vote is another important sign that both parties can come together to support law enforcement and stand up against the horrific scourge of gun violence. I thank the Senate for their support. And it is my hope that we can continue working together to keep Americans safe – especially our children – from mass shootings like those in Uvalde, Buffalo, and Highland Park, as well as the daily acts of gun violence that don’t make national headlines.</p>



<p>We have so much more to do. I will continue to call on Congress to build on this momentum and ban assault weapons, expand background checks, and pass safe storage laws. At the same time, my Administration will build on our record of taking historic executive action. And as ATF Director, Steve will play a leading role in ensuring robust implementation of the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act and driving forward other executive actions to fight crime and save lives.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President López Obrador of Mexico Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/12/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-lopez-obrador-of-mexico-before-bilateral-meeting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 19:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;Oval Office 11:26 A.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Mr. President &#8212; my friend, my partner &#8212; it’s good to have you back to the White House. Over the last year and a half, we’ve devoted our teams to whole-of-government efforts focused on rebuilding the solid framework of the U.S.-Mexico relations. As I told you from the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;Oval Office</p>



<p>11:26 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212; my friend, my partner &#8212; it’s good to have you back to the White House.</p>



<p>Over the last year and a half, we’ve devoted our teams to whole-of-government efforts focused on rebuilding the solid framework of the U.S.-Mexico relations.</p>



<p>As I told you from the beginning &#8212; and I mean it &#8212; I see, we see Mexico as an equal partner.&nbsp; Our nations share close ties in family and friendship, and we’re united through our values and our history.</p>



<p>And for me and my administration, the U.S.-Mexico relationship is vital to achieving our goals of everything from the fight against COVID-19, to continuing to grow our economies, to strengthening our partnerships and addressing migration as a shared hemispheric challenge.</p>



<p>And addressing migration is a hemispheric challenge, a commitment captured in the Los Angeles Declaration adopted by the Summit of the Americas.</p>



<p>And, Mr. President, this is a relationship that directly impacts the daily lives &#8212; the daily lives of our people.&nbsp; And despite the overhyped headlines that we sometimes see, you and I have a strong and productive relationship and, I would argue, a partnership.</p>



<p>Today we’re going to be discussing our shared challenges we face and commitments on some of the major issues that we’re taking on together.&nbsp; One of those is migration.&nbsp; At historic levels throughout our hemisphere, like us, Mexico has become a top destination of migrants.&nbsp; And here’s what we’re going to do to address it together:</p>



<p>My administration is leading the way to creating work opportunities through legal pathways.&nbsp; And last year, my administration set a record.&nbsp; We issued more than 300,000 H-2 visas for Mexican workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also reached a five-year high in the visas we issued to Central Americans, and we’re on pace to double this in fiscal year for &#8212; this fiscal year for Central America.</p>



<p>I want to thank you, Mr. President, for also stepping up and increasing worker visas in Mexico for Central Americans.&nbsp; This is a proven strategy that fuels economic growth as well as reduces irregular migration.</p>



<p>And it doesn’t get much attention, but we’re also making historic investments in infrastructure modernization across our 2,000-mile border with Mexico.</p>



<p>My Bipartisan Infrastructure Law here in America is delivering $3.4 billion to major construction projects at the ports of entry between our two countries to make our border safer and more efficient for people, trade, and commerce.</p>



<p>And the American people should know, Mr. President, that you’re also making a significant investment on your side of the border to improve infrastructure to meet the needs of our times and the future.</p>



<p>And a very important point &#8212; another critical example is we are accelerating our efforts to disrupt the trafficking of fentanyl and other drugs that are literally killing.&nbsp; Fentanyl kills people.</p>



<p>We’ve had a major anti-smuggling operation underway since April, targeting human smugglers who traffic in people, drugs, and weapons.</p>



<p>Towards this effort, we’ve deployed 1,300 additional personnel, conducted 20,000 disruption operations, and we’ve made over 3,000 arrests, all since April.</p>



<p>And we have been conducting (inaudible) disruption operations along our shared border with our Mexican partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, Mr. President, we need every country in the region to join us in tracking this multibillion-dollar smuggling industry that’s preying on our most vulnerable, including the 53 souls who died in a tractor trailer in San Antonio last month.</p>



<p>President Obrador and I will also be talking about enhanced enforcement measures, including <s>reparation</s> [repatriation] efforts.&nbsp; And today we’ll agree on our next steps together on all these fronts, because we know we have to meet these challenges together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, again, welcome.&nbsp; And I look forward to our discussions after this introductory meeting.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; We’re so happy, President Biden, to be here at the White House once more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I send my greetings to the good, hardworking, the fine, and very progressive people of the United States.&nbsp; My greetings.</p>



<p>This is the second meeting in just eight months &#8212; the second meeting we are holding with you, Mr. President, here at the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes, but as you have already expressed, President Biden, this existing circumstances are demanding so many more things from us &#8212; for instance, having a closer relationship, closer ties of friendship and cooperation so that we can act together vis- à-vis the major challenges our two countries face.<br><br>And these are truly difficult times.&nbsp; No question about it.<br><br>First of all, we have the pandemic &#8212; the COVID-19 pandemic with the sequence of death, suffering, hardships, and damage &#8212; damage on the productive activities of our countries.</p>



<p><br>And now we have the war in the Ukraine.&nbsp; And as we know, it has not only constituted grief and destruction, but it made the economic crisis even worse.&nbsp; Yes, and this has resulted in inflationary spiral that the entire world is suffering.<br><br>Therefore, President Biden, I have come to see you to express, on behalf of the Mexican people, our disposal, our willingness to work together for the wellbeing of our nations.<br><br>This will not be the first nor the last occasion on which we close ranks to help each other, we know.</p>



<p><br>In spite of our differences and also in spite of our grievances that are not really easy to forget with time or with good wishes &#8212; they&#8217;re not easy to forget.&nbsp; However, on many occasions, we&#8217;ve been able to coincide and we&#8217;ve been able to work together as good friends and true allies.<br><br>During President Franklin D. Roosevelt&#8217;s administration, we were able to see a policy that we believe it was a very efficient and very fraternal policy.<br><br>Those were other times.&nbsp; However, we had circumstances that were quite similar to our existing circumstances.&nbsp; And from those policies, we should be extracting good lessons, because history is the master of life.<br><br>When President Roosevelt took office March 4th, 1933, the United States was going through one of the most profound social and economic crisis of its history.<br><br>That&#8217;s why with great definition, determination, and aplomb, since the first 100 days of its administration, he launched a whirlpool of initiatives that changed the country and gave new hopes to its inhabitants.<br><br>And throughout his administration, he also applied, he enforced a policy &#8212; a Good Neighbors policy.&nbsp; And this is something that was enforced and applied throughout the American continent.<br><br>Authenticity of this policy had, as its best example, respect for the sovereignty of Mexico.</p>



<p><br>At that time, President Lázaro Cárdenas’s administration was also launching very deep, very important reforms.</p>



<p>So then, in 1938, that&#8217;s when the oil expropriation took place in Mexico.&nbsp; However, differences were addressed and solved through a dialogue and collaboration with dignity.</p>



<p><br>This policy of respect for the sovereignty of our country, of the nations in general, gave us very good fruit.&nbsp; Yes, for instance, it created conditions which were very favorable conditions for the governments of the United States and Mexico to act as partners, as allies throughout the Second World War.</p>



<p><br>And this alliance went beyond &#8212; over and beyond mere cooperation in this bellicist effort.<br><br>When the United States went into the Second World War, thousands of Americans were recruited by the armed forces, and this meant that the agricultural field was left with no labor force.&nbsp; Farmers urgently needed labor force, as it also happens now in restaurants, factories, construction works, and out in the countryside as well.</p>



<p>At that time, under those circumstances in 1943, President Roosevelt recognized reality, and he decided to support the Bracero Program, through which thousands of Mexican agricultural laborers came into the United States legally to help in the production of foodstuffs, even during the construction of the railroad system in the United States.<br><br>1943 through 1946, 130,000 Mexican workers, farm workers were hired through this agreement signed by both governments.&nbsp;<br><br>Certainly, the program was not exempt from mistakes, abuses, and non-compliance.&nbsp; However, there is no doubt that it had very good results at the productive and labor levels.<br><br>It was a more secure framework with less human rights violations, especially with &#8212; compare that to current migration provisions.<br><br>Today, we&#8217;re proposing something similar to this program.</p>



<p><br>It is true that the USMCA is a treaty that’s already uniting and integrating our three countries.&nbsp; Our three countries &#8212; Mexico, the United States, and Canada.</p>



<p>However, there are still margins for us to intensify our bilateral relationship.&nbsp; For instance, high inflationary rates have to do with misadjustments of the world economy because of the pandemic and the war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, we should also recognize that for some time now, we haven’t been producing what we should be producing.&nbsp; In the last three decades, it was very comfortably accepted for China to become the factory of the world.&nbsp; And this was due to the fallacious idea that, with globality &#8212; with globality, it wasn’t necessary to continue our self-sufficiency in the production of foodstuffs, because we were able to produce energy and other goods.&nbsp; We didn’t have to do it; it wasn’t necessary because we could always import them as we needed them.&nbsp; So, self-sufficiency was not necessary.</p>



<p>However, the reality we live in now makes it necessary and indispensable for us to produce everything we consume in our countries and regions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without reaching an extremist position of closing our economies, we should remember that the development of our nations depends fundamentally on their productive capacity.</p>



<p>President Biden, I’m about to finish.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Let me say one thing.&nbsp; I can’t get over how that lovely lady is holding that camera steady all this time.&nbsp; (Inaudible.) (Laughter.)&nbsp; It’s amazing.</p>



<p>Sorry for the distraction.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Yes, I fully coincide with what you have proposed, President Biden.&nbsp; And I could summarize everything we&#8217;ve been saying in five basic items of cooperation.</p>



<p>Number one, since the energy crisis started, Mexico has used 72 percent of its crude and fuel oil exports to United States refineries &#8212; 800,000 barrels a day.</p>



<p>Therefore, we decided that while we’re waiting for prices of gasoline to go down in the United States &#8212; and I hope that Congress approves or passes your proposal, Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; It has gone down for 30 days in a row.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; &#8212; of lowering &#8212; lowering prices, yes.&nbsp; That’s it.</p>



<p>In the meantime, while we’re waiting for prices to go down, we have decided that it was necessary for us to allow Americans who live close to the borderline so that they could go and get their gasoline on the Mexican side at lower prices.</p>



<p>And right now, a lot of the drivers &#8212; a lot of the Americans &#8212; are going to Mexico, to the Mexican border, to get their gasoline.</p>



<p>However, we could increase our inventories immediately.&nbsp; We are committed to guaranteeing twice as much supply of fuel.&nbsp; That would be considerable support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Right now, a gallon of regular costs $4.78 average on this side of the border.&nbsp; And in our territory, $3.12.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me clarify something, and I also want to take advantage of this opportunity to thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Most of this gasoline, we are producing it in the Pemex refinery that you allowed us to buy in Deer Park, Texas.</p>



<p>Two, we are putting at the disposal &#8212; or sending at the disposal of your administration over 1,000 kilometers of gas pipelines throughout the southern border with Mexico to transport gas from Texas to New Mexico, Arizona, and California for a volume that can generate up to 750 megawatts of electric energy and supply about 3 million people.</p>



<p>Three, even though the USMCA has made progress for the elimination of tariffs, there are still some others that could be immediately suspended.&nbsp; And we could do the same with some regulations, regulatory measures, and tedious procedures or red tape in terms of trade related to foodstuffs and other products so that we can lower prices for consumers in both our countries, always being very careful in the protection of health and the environment.</p>



<p>Four, starting a private-public investment plan between our two countries to produce all those goods that will be strengthening our markets so that we can avoid having importations from other regions or continents.</p>



<p>In our country, we shall continue producing oil throughout the energy transition.&nbsp; With the U.S. investors, we are going to be establishing gas-liquefying plants, fertilizer plants, and we shall continue promoting the creation of solar energy parks in the state of Sonora and other border states as well.</p>



<p>And we’re going to accomplish this with the support of thermal electric plants and also through transmission lines to produce energy in the domestic market, as well as for exports, to neighboring states in the American union, as for instance, Texas, New Mexico, Arizona, and California.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s also important to mention that, two months ago, we took the sovereign decision of nationalizing lithium in Mexico.&nbsp; This is a fundamental mineral, a fundamental input to advance in our purpose not to depend on fossil fuels.&nbsp; And this will be available for the technological modernization of the automotive industry among our great countries &#8212; the countries of the USMCA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Five, orderly migration flow and allowing arrival in the United States of workers, technicians, and professionals of different disciplines.&nbsp; I&#8217;m talking about Mexicans and Central Americans with temporary work visas to ensure not paralyzing the economy because of the lack of labor force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The purpose of this plan would be to support and to have the right labor force that will be demanded by the plan you proposed and that was passed by Congress of using $1 trillion for the construction of infrastructure works.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it’s also indispensable that I say this in a very sincere fashion in the most respectful manner: It is indispensable for us to regularize and give certainty to migrants that have for years lived and worked in a very honest manner, and who are also contributing to the development of this great nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that your adversaries &#8212; the conservatives &#8212; are going to be screaming all over the place, even to Heaven.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be yelling at Heaven.&nbsp; But without a daring, a bold program of development and wellbeing, it will not be possible to solve problems.&nbsp; It will not be possible to get the people’s support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the face of this crisis, the way out is not through conservatism.&nbsp; The way out is through transformation.&nbsp; We have to be bold in our actions.&nbsp; Transform not maintain the status quo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On our part, we’re acting in good faith, with all transparency, because there shouldn’t be selfishness between countries, peoples that are neighbors and friends.&nbsp; On the other hand, integration does not signify hegemony or subjugation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, President Biden, we trust you because you respect our sovereignty.&nbsp; We are willing to continue working with you for the benefit of our peoples.&nbsp; Count with our support &#8212; count on our support and solidarity always.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Long live the United States. &nbsp;<em>Viva México lindo y querido.</em>&nbsp; Long live Mexico &#8212; dear Mexico, loved and beautiful Mexico.&nbsp; <em>Viva México.</em></p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, Mr. President, you’ve had a lot of important things to say, and we have much agreement.&nbsp; And some of the details, we&#8217;ll have a chance to talk about where the disagreement is.&nbsp; But the thrust of what you&#8217;re saying we agree with: We need to work closely together.</p>



<p>I might note, of all the major economies in the world, we&#8217;re the fastest growing.&nbsp; We, the United States, already the fastest growing in the world.</p>



<p>Just since I became President, we have created more jobs than any president ever has in the beginning of his administration &#8212; almost 8.5 million new jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Wages have risen five and a half percent.&nbsp; We are suffering from inflation imposed as a consequence of what’s going on in Ukraine, but we have the lowest rate of almost every major nation in the world.</p>



<p>Even last month, we created another three hundred and &#8212; I think &#8212; fifty-seven thousand new jobs.&nbsp; And it doesn&#8217;t mean we don&#8217;t have problems; we do.&nbsp; And we do believe &#8212; I do believe that, working with you, we can help solve both our problems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And China is not only not going to be the factory of the world.&nbsp; You&#8217;re in the factory of the world &#8212; the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp; We produce more agricultural product than anything close to what they do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not suggesting there are not problems.&nbsp; There are real problems, but they are solvable, as you pointed out.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m anxious for us to get into some detail about the explicit five points you raised and how we can make sure we work together on all five of those points.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I hope I&#8217;ve demonstrated my whole career I have the enormous respect for Mexico as an independent nation, a great nation, and I have great respect for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have liberals, moderates, conservatives, and extreme conservatives.&nbsp; I&#8217;m waiting for the Republican Party to come back to traditional conservative positions.&nbsp; We have to start to talk with them, to one another, in this country, with respect.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have enormous respect for you, and I&#8217;m ready to get to</p>



<p>work.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to find out how she holds that camera (inaudible).&nbsp; It’s amazing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; This is a journalist from Mexico.&nbsp; She&#8217;s exceptional.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; She is exceptional.&nbsp; Just holding that camera.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; At any rate &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:&nbsp; This is a tribute, homage to all of &#8212; all of the media here.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Women and men journalists, reporters.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p>12:12 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Twenty-First Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/president-biden-names-twenty-first-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing five new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country —&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing five new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, if confirmed, this slate would include:</p>



<ul><li>The first Asian American judge to serve on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit</li><li>The first Asian American and second Latina judge to serve on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s twenty-first round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his eighth slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 112.</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies. And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.</p>



<p><strong><u>Circuit Court Press Bio</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Cindy K. Chung: Candidate for the United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Cindy K. Chung has served as the United States Attorney for the Western District of Pennsylvania since 2021. Ms. Chung served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Western District of Pennsylvania from 2014 to 2021. From 2009 to 2014, Ms. Chung served as a trial attorney in the Criminal Section of the Department of Justice’s Civil Rights Division. From 2003 to 2009, she served as an Assistant District Attorney in the New York County District Attorney’s Office. Ms. Chung served as a law clerk for Judge Myron Thompson on the United States District Court for the Middle District of Alabama from 2002 to 2003. She received her J.D. from Columbia Law School in 2002 and her B.A. from Yale University in 1997.</p>



<p><strong><u>District Court Press Bios</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Kelley B. Hodge: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Kelley B. Hodge is a partner at Fox Rothschild in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, where she has worked since 2020. Ms. Hodge was previously Of Counsel at Elliott Greenleaf in Blue Bell, Pennsylvania from 2016 to 2017 and 2018 to 2020. Ms. Hodge was the interim District Attorney for the City of Philadelphia from 2017 to 2018. From 2015 to 2016, she was the Title IX Coordinator and Executive Assistant to the President at the University of Virginia. From 2011 to 2015, she served as the Safe Schools Advocate under the Pennsylvania Commission on Crime and Delinquency.&nbsp;From 2004 to 2011, she worked in the Philadelphia District Attorney’s Office. Ms. Hodge was a public defender in the Richmond, Virginia Public Defender’s Office from 1997 to 2003. Ms. Hodge received her J.D. from the University of Richmond School of Law in 1996 and B.A. from the University of Virginia in 1993.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>John Frank Murphy: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>John Frank Murphy is a partner at Baker &amp; Hostetler in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, where has worked since 2007. Mr. Murphy has also been an Adjunct Professor at Rutgers Law School since 2014. Mr. Murphy served as a law clerk for Chief Judge Kimberly A. Moore on the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit from 2008 to 2009.&nbsp;Mr. Murphy received his J.D.,<em> cum laude</em>, from Harvard Law School in 2007, his M.S. and Ph.D. from the California Institute of Technology in 2002 and 2004, and his B.S., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Cornell University in 1999.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Judge Mia Perez: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Mia Roberts Perez has served as a judge on the Philadelphia County Court of Common Pleas since her election in 2016.&nbsp;Judge Perez was previously in private practice at her own firm, Perez Law, from 2011 to 2016. From 2010 to 2011, Judge Perez was an associate at Friedman Schuman in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. She was an Assistant Defender at the Defender Association of Philadelphia from 2006 to 2010. Judge Perez received her J.D. from Temple University, Beasley School of Law in 2006 and her B.A. from Tufts University in 2003.</p>



<ol type="1" start="4"><li><strong><u>Judge Kai Scott: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Kai Scott has served as a judge on the Philadelphia County Court of Common Pleas since her election in 2015. Prior to joining the bench, Judge Scott was the Trial Unit Chief for the Federal Community Defender Office in the Eastern District of Pennsylvania from 2010 to 2015. Judge Scott was an Assistant Federal Defender from 2004 to 2010. From 1998 to 2004, Judge Scott was a Trial Attorney with the Defender Association of Philadelphia. Judge Scott served as a law clerk for Judge Donald Poorman of the Pennsylvania Bureau of Workers Compensation from 1996 to 1998.&nbsp;Judge Scott received her J.D. from the West Virginia University College of Law in 1995 and her B.A. from Hampton University in 1991.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Successful Counterterrorism&#160;Operation </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/statement-by-president-biden-on-successful-counterterrorism-operation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57250</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the men and women of the U.S. military and of our intelligence community successfully executed an airstrike against one of the top leaders of ISIS, Maher al Agal. His death in Syria takes a key terrorist off the field and significantly degrades the ability of ISIS to plan, resource, and conduct their operations in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the men and women of the U.S. military and of our intelligence community successfully executed an airstrike against one of the top leaders of ISIS, Maher al Agal.<br> <br>His death in Syria takes a key terrorist off the field and significantly degrades the ability of ISIS to plan, resource, and conduct their operations in the region. And, like the U.S. operation in February that eliminated ISIS’s overall leader, it sends a powerful message to all terrorists who threaten our homeland and our interests around the world.  The United States will be relentless in its efforts to bring you to justice.<br> <br>This airstrike represents the culmination of determined and meticulous intelligence work and stands as testament to the bravery and skill of our armed forces.  It also demonstrates that the United States does not require thousands of troops in combat missions to identify and eliminate threats to our country. <br> <br>On behalf of the American people, whose lives they protect every day, I thank them for their service, their dedication, their professionalism, and for the teamwork that led to this successful outcome. <br> <br>The American people — and our allies and partners — are safer today because of their actions. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing Vice President Harris&#8217;s Engagement With the Pacific Islands&#160;Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-vice-president-harriss-engagement-with-the-pacific-islands-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 17:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (July 11, 2022) MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; And thank you, everyone, for joining our call.&#160; Tonight’s call will be on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&#160; The contents of this call will be embargoed until Tuesday, July 12th, at 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&#160; Again, that’s Tuesday, July 12th, 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>(July 11, 2022)<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, for joining our call.&nbsp; Tonight’s call will be on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The contents of this call will be embargoed until Tuesday, July 12th, at 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&nbsp; Again, that’s Tuesday, July 12th, 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&nbsp; And by participating in this call, you are hereby agreeing to these ground rules.<br><br>Our speaker today, for your awareness only, is [senior administration official], who hereinafter will be referred to as a “senior administration official.”<br><br>So, with that, I’ll turn it over to him for some brief remarks before opening up for questions.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [moderator].&nbsp; Hi, everybody, and thank you all for joining.&nbsp; As we announced earlier today, the Vice President will participate virtually in the Pacific Islands Forum leaders’ meeting July 12th, Washington D.C. time.&nbsp; The United States is not a member of the PIF, the Pacific Islands Forum, but the Vice President is honored to accept an invitation from Fijian Prime Minister Bainimarama, the current Chair of the PIF, to address the PIF leaders.<br><br>We think this invitation speaks to the longstanding and deep partnership the United States has with the Pacific Islands, and our mutual interest in strengthening our relationships.&nbsp; We have a very strong foundation with the Pacific Islands, including historic ties, deep people-to-people bonds, and shared interests and values.&nbsp; And we believe that we’re now embarking on a new chapter in this longstanding partnership.<br><br>In short, the Vice President will be announcing that we’re significantly stepping up our game in the Pacific Islands.&nbsp; After this call, we will share with you an embargoed factsheet.&nbsp; But I can tell you now that the Vice President has a significant set of deliverables that she’ll be announcing to the forum as part of this engagement.&nbsp;<br><br>This new chapter in our relationship will feature increased diplomatic presence on the ground throughout the region, and that’s what most of these announcements are about: our presence and our engagement.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re expanding our footprint and making sure that we have the people and the apparatus in place to deepen our cooperation on a day-to-day basis and to deliver concrete results.&nbsp; And these deliverables emerge from close consultations with the region in recent weeks and months, and we believe that this series of steps is responsive to their priorities.<br><br>So maybe just to summarize them for you: First, we will begin discussions to establish new U.S. embassies in Kiribati and Tonga.&nbsp; This was a top ask of the region, and we’re delivering because a close partnership requires the regular exchange that comes with having an embassy.&nbsp;<br><br>Second, we’re going to appoint the first-ever U.S. envoy to the Pacific Islands Forum in order to expand our diplomatic footprint, but also to help support a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum.&nbsp;<br><br>Third, we’re going to bring the Peace Corps back to the Pacific.&nbsp; This includes returning to countries where Peace Corps previously operated, as well as exploring expansion to new Pacific Island countries.&nbsp;<br><br>Fourth, USAID will work toward reestablishing a regional mission in Suva, Fiji, to improve its cooperation with Pacific Island countries.<br><br>And then finally, we plan to triple U.S. funding for economic development and ocean resilience in the region.&nbsp; This support will increase our funding from the current $21 million per year &#8212; dollar &#8212; 21 million U.S. dollars per year to $60 million per year, which we’ll be requesting from Congress for the next 10 years.&nbsp; And these funds &#8212; these additional funds will help strengthen climate resilience; invest in marine planning and conservation; combat illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and enhance maritime security.<br><br>As part of this initiative, we also look forward to concluding negotiations on an updated South Pacific Tuna Treaty, which is the cornerstone of our economic and political cooperation.&nbsp;<br><br>So I think, you know, when you look at that altogether, it’s quite the package of measures designed to underscore our commitment to this region and to facilitate partnership going forward.<br><br>The last point on the broader strategic dynamic at play &#8212; and we recognize there’s an intense interest in the Pacific Islands among other countries.&nbsp; And I would just say that what we’re putting on the table is a true partnership based on friendship and respect and transparency.<br><br>What we offer is an affirmative, positive agenda to take on short- and long-term challenges together, whether that’s the climate crisis; economic development; IUU &#8212; or illegal, unreported, and unregulated &#8212; fishing; maritime security; food security; or others.&nbsp;<br><br>With these announcements, the Vice President is putting in place the structure to really make progress on all of these areas that matter to us and to our partners in the region.&nbsp;<br><br>Everything we do with regard to the region will be in consultation with the region.&nbsp; We’ll listen and consult closely.&nbsp; That’s how President Biden and Vice President Harris approach our relationships all around the world.&nbsp; And we’ll continue to engage constructively and transparenc- &#8212; transparently with our Pacific Island partners every step of the way.<br><br>With that, I’m happy to take a few questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; If our moderator could inform our guests the instructions to ask a question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp; Hello?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; We hear you just fine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, wonderful.&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; So I &#8212; you know, just heard that you announced several deliverables that the Vice President is going to announce tomorrow.&nbsp; Correct me if I’m wrong: I didn’t hear about the infrastructure or the Build Back Better World initiatives that President Biden announced during NATO Summit.<br><br>Is the infrastructure efforts going to expand to the Pacific Islands?&nbsp; And so, like we see that Solomon Island has had that security pact with China which worries the United States, of course.&nbsp; Is that part of the deal that we are going to offer more to counter China’s effort in those areas?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean, what I announced now is not part of the Partnership for Global Infrastructure Investment that the President announced with his G7 partners recently in Europe.&nbsp; But I think we’ve made clear that the PGII is a global fund and a global enterprise.&nbsp; And as we move forward, there are a lot of parts of the world, including this one, that I think you could expect us to look at in terms of infrastructure support.<br><br>So there haven’t been PGII announcements.&nbsp; It was just launched, as we noted, a couple of weeks ago.&nbsp; But of course, we’re going to be looking to support infrastructure development in this region.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, all.&nbsp; Thanks so much for the call.&nbsp; Just to kind of piggyback on that question broadly, I wonder if you can talk about just how the relationship between U.S. and China is factoring into these deliverables in the forum itself.&nbsp; I know you just said that you recognize that there’s an intense interest in the Pacific Islands, and, of course, a lot of that is about China’s interest in it.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, that’s clear and obvious, and that’s why I mentioned it.&nbsp; But I think our emphasis is on the positive part of our agenda rather than seeing this in terms of competition.&nbsp;<br><br>And we’ve made that clear around the world.&nbsp; We’re not asking countries to choose; we’re not asking countries not to have relations with China.&nbsp; It’s a big, important country.<br><br>We are focusing on our own engagement and our own interests and our own support.&nbsp; And of course, contrasts will be made and we’d like to think that contrast looks favorably on us where we’ve been a responsible security actor in the region and (inaudible) the entire Indo-Pacific for many decades and helping to preserve a free and open Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And we’ve got important, transparent, supportive economic relationships with these countries, and that’s what we’re trying to build on.&nbsp;<br><br>So this is not about countering any one country or China.&nbsp; It’s about the positive engagement that these leaders are asking for and we’re trying to be responsive to.&nbsp; And we’re very proud of what we’re able to announce in terms of strengthening those relationships.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, go right ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great, thanks.&nbsp; So last year when Biden addressed the forum, he mentioned that the U.S. would dramatically cut its emissions.&nbsp; And clearly, that hasn’t happened now.&nbsp; And with the recent Supreme Court ruling, as well as the death of the Build Back Better bill, there’s not a lot of concrete, significant climate pledges the U.S. can offer to the region, at least as of tomorrow.<br><br>How is this going to be addressed with the world leaders tomorrow?&nbsp; Clearly, climate is one of their primary concerns and they’re particularly anxious about the U.S. and Australia being able to deliver on some of its pledges.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean, one of the things I did announce, in terms of the increased assistance to these countries, does have to do with climate adaptation and resilience.&nbsp; Now, that’s not the same thing as global emissions cuts, but it is something they’re very interested and need, and we want to be supportive of.&nbsp; And certainly, in the immediate term, that is most important.&nbsp;<br><br>And I would just also stress the Biden-Harris administration remains absolutely committed to the Paris Climate Agreement and meeting those goals.&nbsp; It’s true that in the past year Congress hasn’t been as supportive as we might like and international progress on this issue hasn’t been what we might like, including support for developing countries from more advanced countries, which we’re strongly supportive of.&nbsp;<br><br>But this administration remains absolutely committed to those goals.&nbsp; We’re committed to helping the PIF, or the Pacific Islands, deal with the consequences of the climate crisis.&nbsp; And that’s going to be &#8212; you ask what our dialogue with them will be like.&nbsp; I’m sure they will raise it and we’ll together discuss how we can deal with the climate crisis.&nbsp; Because without it, these countries are among the most vulnerable in the entire world.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [Inaudible] in the Newsroom, New Zealand.&nbsp; To what extent does this package reflect U.S. hopes to restore stronger regional engagement in the Pacific Islands Forum from countries like Kiribati and the rest of Micronesia, especially around regional security?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, it definitely reflects our interest in engaging throughout the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; I think you’ve seen this administration be extraordinarily active throughout the Indo-Pacific in terms of &#8212; including in terms of creating new structures and building on existent ones &#8212; the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue; obviously, AUKUS; the new partnership for the Blue Pacific, which is not just U.S. but key partner countries, including Japan and the United Kingdom and Australia and New Zealand &#8212; all of us interested in the same thing, which is supporting the Pacific Islands and maintaining a free and open Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;<br><br>So, absolutely, it takes place in that context.&nbsp; And you mentioned Kiribati, which gives me an opportunity to comment on that issue.&nbsp; We are concerned by reports that Kiribati has decided to withdraw from the PIF.<br><br>We think, obviously, that the PIF is stronger when it is united.&nbsp; And that’s one of the whole points of the organization: that those countries can join together and speak as one in international fora, including on the critical issue of the climate crisis.<br><br>So I understand that discussions are still underway to reach an agreement that would allow Kiribati and others to remain in the PIF and keep it as strong as it should be.&nbsp; And we support those talks and hope they can come to a positive conclusion.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, what &#8212; everything I’ve outlined in this call will go ahead regardless of how that situation emerges because we’re committed to doing everything I said, in terms of the economic assistance, the embassies and the envoy to the region, and the strengthened Tuna Treaty.&nbsp; But it will be even stronger, it will all be more successful if a way can be found to keep Kiribati and others in.&nbsp; So we’re very supportive of that.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, thank you to our speaker for taking the time, and thank you to all of you.&nbsp;<br><br>As we mentioned, this call is embargoed until Tuesday, July 12th, at 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time.&nbsp; And we will follow up with some written materials, which will also be embargoed as well, to those on this call.<br><br>So thank you again, everyone, and we’ll be in touch shortly.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Meeting with President Lopez Obrador of&#160;Mexico</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-president-lopez-obrador-of-mexico/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 16:44:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris hosted President Lopez Obrador of Mexico for breakfast at the Naval Observatory today to deepen the longstanding cooperation between the United States and Mexico. The Vice President conveyed her appreciation for the close friendship and shared values between Mexico and the United States. Vice President Harris and President Lopez Obrador had&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><br>Vice President Kamala Harris hosted President Lopez Obrador of Mexico for breakfast at the Naval Observatory today to deepen the longstanding cooperation between the United States and Mexico. The Vice President conveyed her appreciation for the close friendship and shared values between Mexico and the United States. Vice President Harris and President Lopez Obrador had a wide-ranging discussion about our common challenges and opportunities as neighbors, partners, and friends. They discussed our shared work to address the root causes of migration from Northern Central America and the need to collaborate on concrete next steps in this effort. The leaders discussed the importance of public-private partnerships in generating investment-led growth, and agreed to explore further cooperation in this area under the U.S.-Mexico High Level Economic Dialogue (HLED), with a particular focus on economic development initiatives in southern Mexico.  </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and President Andrés Manuel López Obrador of Mexico Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/12/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-andres-manuel-lopez-obrador-of-mexico-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 15:48:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President&#8217;s ResidenceUnited States Naval ObservatoryWashington, D.C. 8:59 A.M. EDT VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  It is my great pleasure to welcome my friend, the President of Mexico.  He and I have spent some wonderful time together both in Mexico City and here in Washington, D.C.  But it is my great honor to receive you at my home.  The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President&#8217;s Residence<br><em>United States Naval Observatory</em><br><em>Washington, D.C.</em></em></p>



<p>8:59 A.M. EDT<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  It is my great pleasure to welcome my friend, the President of Mexico.  He and I have spent some wonderful time together both in Mexico City and here in Washington, D.C.  But it is my great honor to receive you at my home. <br> <br>The time that I spent with you in Mexico was so special to me.  We spent time looking at the art, talking about the culture, and, of course, talking about the relationship between our two nations. <br> <br>So welcome, my friend.  I look forward to our discussion and to continuing our partnership &#8212; longstanding partnership based on traditions and based on a friendship that has been so important to both of our nations.  Welcome.<br> <br>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:  (As interpreted.)  I am so happy about this meeting today with Vice President Kamala Harris.  She’s our friend but also a woman with principles, an intelligent woman, honest.  She’s a partisan of equality.<br> <br>So I congratulate the U.S., the American people, because they have a first-order Vice President.  I congratulate the American people for that.<br> <br>We’ve always been speaking for the benefit of our peoples and both of our nations.  And today, we are going to do exactly the same thing.<br> <br>Thank you so much.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Welcome.  Welcome.<br> <br>PRESIDENT LÓPEZ OBRADOR:  (As interpreted.)  Thank you. <br> <br>                         END                 9:03 A.M. EDT</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake&#160;Sullivan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/12/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 13:47:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room   3:50 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good afternoon. MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Thank you.&#160; All right.&#160; Today we have Jake Sullivan, the President&#8217;s National Security Advisor.&#160; Jake is here to preview the President&#8217;s upcoming trip to the Middle East, where he will build on a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p> </p>



<p>3:50 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Today we have Jake Sullivan, the President&#8217;s National Security Advisor.&nbsp; Jake is here to preview the President&#8217;s upcoming trip to the Middle East, where he will build on a new and more promising chapter of America&#8217;s engagement in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m going to let Jake take it away.&nbsp; And also, he&#8217;ll take some questions afterwards.&nbsp; Jake, it&#8217;s all yours.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; And thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to lay out a little bit of the context for this trip, make a couple of comments on tomorrow&#8217;s bilateral meeting with President López Obrador of Mexico, and then I&#8217;ll be happy to take your questions.&nbsp; But I appreciate you bearing with me as I try to lay out some of the elements of the President&#8217;s thinking as we head into this very important trip.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, President Biden will depart on a trip to Israel, the West Bank, and Saudi Arabia, where he will attend a major Middle Eastern summit.&nbsp; This trip will reinforce a vital American role in a strategically consequential region.&nbsp; And also, it will reinforce that our role is different today than it was 20 years ago on the eve of the war in Iraq.</p>



<p>This trip comes after a series of engagements with Indo-Pacific leaders in May, with Latin American leaders at the Summit of the Americas in early June, and with European leaders at the G7 and NATO Summits in late June.&nbsp; It is his first trip to the Middle East as President.</p>



<p>It is precisely because the world is becoming more geopolitically competitive, especially in the Indo-Pacific and Europe, that we need to remain intensively engaged in the Middle East.&nbsp; The Middle East is deeply interwoven with the rest of the world.&nbsp; And if we can act now to create a more peaceful and stable region, it will pay dividends for the American national interests and for the American people for years to come.</p>



<p>President Biden’s fundamental objectives when it comes to the Middle East are straightforward: a region with more stability and fewer wars that could draw the United States in, a region that is less hospitable to terrorism that threatens Americans, a region that is helping address global energy security at a moment when Russia’s war against Ukraine is roiling global energy markets, a region where no foreign power can dominate or gain strategic advantage over the United States, a region that is making progress towards greater human rights and greater human dignity.</p>



<p>And despite ongoing challenges, the Middle East President Biden will be visiting is more stable than the one we inherited 18 months ago.</p>



<p>We inherited a war in Yemen that was causing widespread death and suffering.&nbsp; We now have had more than three months of a ceasefire in Yemen &#8212; the longest peace in seven years.</p>



<p>In Iraq, we kept up pressure on ISIS, significantly degrading their capabilities, including by taking out its emir, allowing us to end the U.S. combat mission and transition our military presence in Iraq to focus on training Iraqis.</p>



<p>We’ve reunited our partners to ensure that it’s Iran, not the United States, that is isolated until it returns to the nuclear deal.&nbsp; And the frequency of Iranian-sponsored attacks against our forces in Iraq and Syria has dropped dramatically.</p>



<p>We’ve reestablished diplomatic ties with the Palestinians that had basically severed under our predecessor. Working with Congress, we’ve restored approximately $500 million in support for Palestinians.&nbsp; And we’ve reaffirmed unequivocal U.S. support for a two-state solution, which had come into question over the previous four years.&nbsp; And under President Biden’s leadership, we helped end a war in Gaza, which easily could have lasted months, in just 11 days.</p>



<p>In Saudi Arabia, we’ve reversed the blank-check policy that we inherited from the previous administration, while continuing to work with Saudi Arabia on critical priorities for the American people.&nbsp; We released the intelligence community report on the murder of Jamal Khashoggi.&nbsp; We issued new sanctions, including on the Rapid Intervention Force that was implicated in that murder.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our diplomacy with Saudi Arabia is now delivering results, including a truce in Yemen, a more integrated GCC, progress on energy security, and security cooperation against threats from Iran. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Our partnership with Israel is strong across the board.&nbsp; We passed the largest support package in Israel with the help of Congress &#8212; over $4 billion &#8212; in American history.&nbsp; We’re working closely across every dimension of the relationship &#8212; from finance and food security, to cyber and emerging technology, to intelligence and security cooperation.&nbsp; And President Biden’s deep personal commitment to the U.S.-Israel relationship and to the relationship between Israelis and Americans will be on full display this week.</p>



<p>In sum, the region is less pressurized and more integrated, with countries increasingly setting aside both old and more recent disagreements to work on practical initiatives in energy, technology, infrastructure, and more.</p>



<p>We are clear-eyed that the region remains full of challenges and threats from Iran, from terrorist groups that still operate in a number of countries; challenges in the ongoing conflict in Syria; challenges to human rights and human freedom.&nbsp; This is why the President believes there is no substitute for the power of face-to-face diplomacy.</p>



<p>In meetings on this trip, President Biden will seek to sustain and strengthen the fragile but real ceasefire in Yemen; deepen Israel’s integration into the region; provide material support to the Palestinian people while protecting the vision of a two-state solution; coordinate on the multi-faceted threat posed by Iran; advance energy security and food security objectives for the U.S. and our allies in the face of Russia’s aggression in Ukraine, while promoting a clean energy transition over time; enlisting support for Middle Eastern partners for significant initiatives in technology and infrastructure; and publicly and privately advocating for universal values including progress on human rights and political reform.</p>



<p>In Israel, the President will meet with the Prime Minister, the President, the leader of the opposition, as well as attend a reception with a number of other key Israeli leaders and public figures.&nbsp; He will also have the opportunity to receive a briefing on Israel’s missile defense capabilities, including the U.S.-supported Iron Dome and a new laser-enabled system called Iron Beam.&nbsp; He will pay his respects at Yad Vashem.&nbsp; And he will hold a four-way virtual summit with the leaders of Israel, the UAE, and India, with a focus on food security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden will also meet with President Abbas and attend a health event with Palestinian civil society.</p>



<p>In Saudi Arabia, the President will meet with the Saudi leadership with an aim to strengthen our partnership and also hold bilateral meetings with a number of other Middle Eastern leaders, before closing the trip with the summit with the GCC+3.&nbsp; At that summit, he will make a major statement on the Biden administration’s strategy &#8212; his vision &#8212; for the Middle East region.</p>



<p>There will be other engagements in a crowded and fast-paced schedule, and we will share them with you in due course.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In fact, before we even leave, tomorrow morning President Biden will meet with President López Obrador here at the White House &#8212; the second time the two leaders will meet here &#8212; to build on the significant progress made at the Summit of the Americas, where Mexico expressed support for the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity and joined 20 other countries in adopting the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection.</p>



<p>We expect the two leaders to discuss their common vision for North America and common efforts to address global challenges, including Russia’s war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>So, thank you for your patience, and I would now be happy to take your questions.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, has the President reached out to Jamal Khashoggi’s family ahead of his trip to Saudi?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have had contact with Jamal Khashoggi’s family.&nbsp; The President has not himself spoken with them, but he has been focused on this issue from the beginning.</p>



<p>And as he said when he took office and as we have stuck by since then, our goal has been to recalibrate but not rupture the relationship with Saudi Arabia, to end the blank-check policy, and to seek accountability.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we released the intelligence community&#8217;s report on the murder of Jamal Khashoggi, and it&#8217;s why we have issued 76 visa bans, in addition to sanctioning the Rapid Intervention Force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But in your remarks, you mentioned human rights multiple times.&nbsp; You know, during the campaign, the President said Saudi should pay a price.&nbsp; He referred to them as making them a pariah state.&nbsp; When it comes right down to it, isn&#8217;t this trip proof that strategic interests, including oil and gas, when it comes right down to it, are always going to override something like human rights?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; America&#8217;s values &#8212; human rights &#8212; are a strategic interest of the United States.&nbsp; So is energy security, so is stopping terrorism, so is seeking peace in a place like Yemen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we are trying to do multiple things all at once to advance along a number of different tracks.&nbsp; One of those tracks is, in fact, ending the blank-check policy.&nbsp; And as I said before, the basic thrust and purpose of our policy with respect to Saudi Arabia has been to recalibrate the relationship but not rupture it.&nbsp; We have stayed true to that from the beginning of this administration.</p>



<p>The President believes that he can deliver concrete results for the American people, for the interests of America&#8217;s national security.&nbsp; One of those is the horrific war in Yemen, where I&#8217;ve stood before you before and been asked questions &#8212; very tough, but fair questions &#8212; about what the United States was doing to bring peace to Yemen and what a high priority that was.</p>



<p>We are now heading into the fourth month of a fragile but real ceasefire, the longest peace since the war began more than seven years ago.&nbsp; That is a genuine result of both intensive diplomacy in the Middle East and intensive engagement by American leaders starting with President Biden.&nbsp; That is just one of multiple priorities that every American should be able to agree can help contribute to a more stable, more just, more prosperous region that&#8217;s fundamentally in our interests.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re going to the Middle East.</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; One, will the President be photographed shaking hands with the Crown Prince or meeting with him while in Saudi?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President will have the opportunity to have a bilateral program that will involve the King, the Crown Prince, other ministers of the Saudi government.&nbsp; And in terms of the precise modalities, I&#8217;ll leave that to the folks who are actually organizing the trip.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as you&#8217;ve been planning this trip, has the President expressed any regret for the language that he used to describe Saudi Arabia on the campaign trail?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President has not expressed regret about his statements.&nbsp; What the President has been focused on is his view that the United States has important interests to advance and protect, including in partnership with Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; And, among other things, we have to work on increasing the prospect for peace in the region; for Israel&#8217;s integration into the region; for the war in Yemen, as I mentioned before; for energy and food security; and for many other things.</p>



<p>And he also has a long and consistent record &#8212; going back to his days as senator, including his years as Vice President, including his time as President &#8212; where human rights is going to remain a feature of his agenda and an important feature of his agenda.&nbsp; And it will be on display while we&#8217;re on this trip as well.</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; Now, the President said at NATO that he would be asking GCC countries about increasing oil production.&nbsp; But the Saudis and UAE have indicated that their capacity to increase production is limited.&nbsp; So what does the administration view as possible as far as an output increase from those countries on this trip if that comes up?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;ve already seen OPEC take a meaningful step with respect to the increase in oil production in the months of July and August.&nbsp; That was a positive step; we welcomed it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will have the opportunity, among this very broad agenda, to talk about energy security with the leaders of the OPEC nations in the Middle East, just as we discussed energy security when he was on his trips in Europe and in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And we will see what results come from that.&nbsp; Ultimately, that will be up to the OPEC countries to determine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so I don&#8217;t have anything to say from this podium right now because those discussions are best, you know, confined behind closed doors.&nbsp; But we do believe there is a capacity for further steps that could be taken.&nbsp; And we will see how that unfolds as we go.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you’re not asking for a specific figure as far as &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;re not asking them for a specific figure as far as output?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; In terms of specific figures, all I will say is that we will convey our general view &#8212; as we have, as I have publicly from this podium &#8212; that we believe that there needs to be adequate supply in the global market to protect the global economy and to protect the American consumer at the pump.&nbsp; We’ll always advocate for that.&nbsp; We’ll advocate for that publicly. We’ll advocate for that privately.&nbsp; We’ll coordinate with leaders around the world, including in the Middle East, on that issue.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.&nbsp; Just to follow up on Jordan’s question, does the President believe right now that Saudi Arabia is pumping enough oil to bring gas prices down?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to get into a specific characterization on what constitutes “enough.”&nbsp; What I will say is the President believes that the price of gas is too high and that we need to do more with respect to global energy supplies.&nbsp; And he will take every step in his power, both here at home and in terms of his diplomatic engagement in the world, to try to bring that about.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just more broadly on the trip’s purpose, do you see any potential to ease or smooth the relationship between Israel and Saudi Arabia on this trip?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It is our hope and expectation that as we look out into the future, we can help facilitate Israel&#8217;s deeper integration into the region across the board.</p>



<p>Specifically with respect to Israel and Saudi Arabia, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of very intensive work that will be done in the course of this trip.&nbsp; Any normalization of any kind would be a long process.&nbsp; But looking for progress and momentum in that direction is certainly something we are focused on as we head off to the Middle East.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, you mentioned “until Iran returns to the nuclear deal.”&nbsp; Is there a deadline that Iran has been given here?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have not marked a date on the calendar.&nbsp; We have indicated that we believe there is a deal on the table.&nbsp; It is a deal that we&#8217;re backing, that our European partners are backing that is available to Iran, and Iran should step forward and take that deal.</p>



<p>If they don&#8217;t, we&#8217;re not standing still.&nbsp; Even as we speak, we&#8217;ve already introduced two rounds of sanctions to crack down on their effort to evade the existing sanctions regime.&nbsp; We are curbing their ability to smuggle oil, for example, through the Quds Force and other entities within Iran.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll keep doing that.</p>



<p>So as far as we&#8217;re concerned, Iran has a choice: It can either come back on a compliance-for-compliance basis to the JCPOA, or it will face increasing pressure from the United States and increasing isolation from the international community to include a resolution at the IAEA Board of Governors that garnered the support of more than 30 nations.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can you confirm any of the details about &#8212; you know, you spoke about Israel&#8217;s greater integration into the region.&nbsp; We certainly heard reports about the idea that there are &#8212; there are some sort of negotiations that would allow Israel commercial flights to fly over Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; Is that something that you could sort of confirm for us?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got nothing to confirm or preview here.&nbsp; What I will say is that this broad topic of Israel&#8217;s integration into the region, and steps that we can take in that direction, will be a feature of this trip.&nbsp; And I will leave the rest of it to the President as he embarks on his engagements both in Israel and in Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>I will point out that the fact that the President himself will be flying from Israel to Jeddah is itself a meaningful step and an unusual step.&nbsp; And it shows the kind of promise that greater integration could hold.</p>



<p>But in terms of the specific kinds of steps you&#8217;ve talked about, I would simply say: Nothing from the podium today.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s see how things develop over the course of this week.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You talk about the importance of personal diplomacy as part of the reason for going.&nbsp; There are risks for the President politically to go to Saudi Arabia, with an expectation among the public that maybe there will be a specific deliverable when it comes to gas prices and so forth, and supply.&nbsp; What is the burden on the President to come home with something in that category?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; it&#8217;s up to you to characterize things like “burdens on the President.”&nbsp; What I can say is what the President intends to do.&nbsp; He intends to use every tool in his toolbox to try to create adequate global energy supplies and to bring the price of gas down for American working families at the pump.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that will be measured over time: Can we get that price down and can we keep it down?&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s going to be measured on Friday or Saturday of this week; I think it will be measured over the weeks and months to come.&nbsp; And, there, we will sustain intensive engagement in our effort to ensure that, at the end of the day, we&#8217;re having a positive impact on the price of oil and thereby a positive impact on the price of gas.</p>



<p>And I think the President sees this as an important component of his engagement, not just in the Middle East, but in his previous summits as well, and as one component of a broader agenda that includes peace, security, technology, preventing a nuclear Iran, and so much else that I&#8217;ve described today.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, thanks for this.&nbsp; Is the administration considering lifting its ban on offensive weapon sales to Saudi Arabia dependent on progress that the country makes with its war &#8212; ending its war with Yemen?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So you may recall that when this administration came in, we imposed restrictions on the supply of offensive weapons as part of our effort to help bring about an end to the war in Yemen.&nbsp; And right now, there&#8217;s no &#8212; nothing on the table to lift that ban.&nbsp; Right now, we&#8217;re focused on strengthening and sustaining what is a fragile but real ceasefire, not make any fundamental changes to our weapons policy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secondly, if I may, former Governor Bill Richardson is planning to travel to Russia for talks aimed at finding a deal that would free Brittney Griner.&nbsp; Is this something that the White House is aware of?&nbsp; Have you had talks with Richardson about the trip?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have had communication from the National Security Council to former Governor Richardson.&nbsp; I won&#8217;t comment on his travel or what he intends to do.&nbsp; What I will say is that President Biden is laser-focused on a government-to-government solution to this issue.</p>



<p>As he indicated to Brittney Griner in the letter that he wrote to her, we are working directly with the Russian government, through appropriate channels, to try to bring a speedy resolution not just to her case but to Paul Whelan&#8217;s case as well.&nbsp; And we will continue to work until those two unjustly detained Americans and all unjustly detained Americans and hostages are home safely.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; Does the President plan to directly bring up the murder of Jamal Khashoggi in his meeting with &#8212; that will include the conference?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So I’m not going to characterize the &#8212; what the President will say privately in those sessions.&nbsp; I’ll let the President do that &#8212; you know, have the opportunity to have his engagement on human rights-related issues and other issues.&nbsp; And then, of course, you’ll have the opportunity to ask him about that after the trip occurs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Ukraine losing the war now, Jake?&nbsp; Is Ukraine losing the war?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sorry, I’ll come back to you on that question.&nbsp; But I think just so that I’m keeping regular order and not letting people just shout, we’ll come &#8212; but before we end the briefing, I’ll come to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; As the President goes to the Middle East, simultaneously, U.S. senators are being briefed on the importance &#8212; national security-wise &#8212; of investing in semiconductor production in the U.S.&nbsp; If we don&#8217;t pass that, what does that say to Israel and Saudi Arabia and other allies?&nbsp; What are the risks that we’re inviting?&nbsp; And does it set the President&#8217;s agenda in the Middle East back?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The national security stakes for passing this Bipartisan Innovation Act &#8212; what&#8217;s called USICA in the Senate and COMPETES in the House &#8212; are very high.&nbsp; America&#8217;s technological edge, our innovation edge, our capacity to invest in the next generation of leading technologies, the next generation of leading weapons is bound up in our ability to ensure that we have a secure and reliant, resilient supply chain for semiconductors.&nbsp; And that means getting the kinds of incentives and structures in place to increase semiconductor manufacturing, including the most sophisticated chips here in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why there&#8217;s bipartisan support for this bill.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why Democrats and Republicans have both rallied around the notion that for us to compete effectively with China, for us to be able to get the Javelins to Ukraine that we need to get to them &#8212; there are more than 20 semiconductors in every single Javelin &#8212; we need this bill.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it has been disappointing to us that Leader McConnell has been playing politics with national security.&nbsp; There are both Republicans and Democrats who are willing to step up and pass this, and we believe it should happen fast.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should the House just pass the Senate bill and get it over with?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There is a conference ongoing, and there is a pathway, in our view, to a bill that a strong, bipartisan majority of both the House and the Senate can get behind, that can be signed into law by President Biden, and that he can begin to execute in a way that enhances America&#8217;s national security, not to mention our economic competitiveness at the same time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So Secretary of State Tony Blinken visit Tokyo.&nbsp; He said he wrote a letter from the President to the former Prime Minister Shinzo Abe.&nbsp; So can you talk about the letter?&nbsp; It’s a message from the President to the former Prime Minister Shinzo’s family.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, the letter that he wrote was a private message, so it wouldn&#8217;t be appropriate for me to read it out.&nbsp; I will say that President Biden put out a very heartfelt statement that expressed his sympathies to the people of Japan, his deep sympathies and his &#8212; his heartfelt emotional connection for the loss of a family member to former Prime Minister Abe’s family.&nbsp; And for him, that came from the heart.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he went over to the Japanese Embassy and signed the guestbook.&nbsp; And I went with him.&nbsp; And actually, he sat at that table and wrote a message for several minutes &#8212; a very long message to the Japanese people in that book, in addition to the private letter that he handed to the ambassador to be taken back to Tokyo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is something that the President cares about, as a statesman, as an American President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also something that he cares about deeply as a human being, on behalf of the Prime Minis- &#8212; the former Prime Minister&#8217;s family, but especially on behalf of all of the people of Japan in their time of mourning.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If possible, will the President go to Tokyo sometime soon?&nbsp; We don’t know if (inaudible) funeral yet but is it possible for the President to go to Tokyo sometime soon?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce about any travel to Tokyo in the near term.&nbsp; But, you know, if we do have anything to share in terms of the American delegation, if there is a state funeral, we&#8217;ll let you know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just coming back to the question, James, that you asked earlier on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; on Ukraine: Russia has already substantially failed to achieve its strategic objectives in Ukraine.&nbsp; Its strategic objective was to take Kyiv, the capital; to end Ukraine as a country; to eliminate Ukrainian identity from the map; and to subsume Ukraine to within Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They have failed at that.&nbsp; Kyiv stands.&nbsp; Kharkiv stands.&nbsp; Odessa stands.&nbsp; The major cities of Ukraine across much of the country are in Ukrainian hands and are being ably and bravely defended by the Ukrainian military with the support of the United States and other NATO Allies as well as countries around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, when you take a step back and look at the trajectory of this conflict: What Vladimir Putin set out to do, he has failed to do and he will continue to fail in his ability to achieve his ultimate objectives because of the bravery of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, it is certainly the case that Russia has been able to grind out, kilometer by kilometer, inch by inch, some territory in the east.&nbsp; And the Ukrainians have made Russia pay a dear price for that.&nbsp; And the sanctions have made Russia pay a dear price for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will continue to work with the Ukrainian military and Ukrainian government on a strategy that ultimately achieves their objectives, both on the battlefield and at the negotiating table.&nbsp; And as President Biden said when we were at the NATO summit just 10 days ago, “We will do that for as long as it takes.”</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you still assess &#8212; do you still assess, Jake, that President Putin is receiving a sanitized or otherwise inaccurate fact set from his own advisors about the state of what&#8217;s going on the ground in Ukraine?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update for you, standing here today, on our intelligence assessment on Vladimir Putin&#8217;s consumption of information, but we&#8217;ll try to get that to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jake.&nbsp; So, today, Brazil’s President Bolsonaro said that a deal with Russia is close to buy much cheaper oil from Moscow, and other countries from &#8212; the Greeks are doing the same.&nbsp; So does this undermine the Western sanctions &#8212; the White House efforts to impose costs on Russia?&nbsp; And what is the White House reaction to that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And another question.&nbsp; Last week, some Democrats in the House proposed an amendment to defense &#8212; to the defense budgets to cut security assistance to Brazil if the Brazilian Armed Forces interfere in the Brazilian election in October?&nbsp; Does the White House support such an amendment?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I have not actually seen that amendment, so I&#8217;d have to take a look at it before commenting on it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With respect to the question about the purchase of oil, you will have seen at the G7 &#8212; the G7 leaders discussed imposing a price cap on Russian oil in order to have it be trans- &#8212; transferred on ships carrying Western insurance.&nbsp; A price cap, meaning that countries would have to agree to pay less for Russian oil than what the global market price is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; If it turns out that countries are imposing their own price cap and it is a substantial denial of revenue to Russia in terms of their ability to sell oil, that is not the failure of sanctions; that&#8217;s actually the success of economic pressure, because it is driving down revenues for Moscow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, from our perspective &#8212; I don&#8217;t know about the specifics of what President Bolsonaro said today, but our fundamental goal, with respect to approaching Russia&#8217;s sale of oil onto the global market is twofold: One, reduce Putin’s revenues.&nbsp; And, two, do so while imposing the minimum amount of harm on consumers on the pump.&nbsp; That&#8217;s our goal.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to keep trying to do.</p>



<p>Yes, go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; I wanted to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And will there be any repercussion to Brazil or other countries who are buying the oil, Jake?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; I wanted to follow up quickly.&nbsp; Moment ago, you said that the United States was going to be working with Ukraine to craft “a strategy that ultimately achieves their objective both on the battlefield and at the negotiation table.”&nbsp; You also noted that the major cities in Ukraine stand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as you and the President work with Ukrainian leaders to figure out what that strategy is for both battlefield and negotiation table, if Ukrainians decide that they want to claw back “kilometer by kilometer, inch by inch,” the land that has been taken by Russia, will the United States have their back?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, we are in near daily contact with Ukrainians on the question of how to both deal with defending against Russian advances and be able to reclaim some of the territory that has been taken from them on a timetable that they are kind of working through.&nbsp; Those conversations are happening in military-to-military channels, and they&#8217;re also happening at the political level so we all have a comprehensive understanding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to read out exactly what the details of those conversations are.&nbsp; I will only say that we believe that the fundamental purpose of our strategy is to put the Ukrainians in as strong a position as possible on the battlefield so that they are in as strong a position as possible at the negotiating table when diplomacy comes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as President Zelenskyy himself has said: Ultimately, this conflict will have to be pursued through diplomacy.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where the United States’ thrust and purpose &#8212; that&#8217;s where the nature of our policy stands and will go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there any limiting principle for the United States, in terms of either time or money?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;ve imposed limiting principles in terms of exactly the types of systems we are prepared to provide and for reasons related to seeking to deal with a circumstance in which some American capabilities, in our view, represent a benefit-risk analysis that runs against their provision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But from the point of view of a limiting principle on time, the President was absolutely clear on that.&nbsp; He said, “As long as it takes.&nbsp; He meant, “As long as it takes.”&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where the United States is prepared to stand.&nbsp; And we believe that&#8217;s where the broad global coalition of countries supporting Ukraine is prepared to go as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; You mentioned, during the President&#8217;s trip to Israel, that one of the meetings he will be having is with the opposition leader.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about that meeting and why are they meeting and what does the President hope to accomplish?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So it’s standard protocol for an American president to meet with leaders across the Israeli political spectrum, and the reason is simple: It’s because the President &#8212; this President and previous presidents have wanted to display that the relationship between the United States and Israel transcends politics.&nbsp; It transcends parties.&nbsp; It doesn’t matter who’s in charge in Washington or who’s in charge in Israel.<br><br>What matters is that we have a foundational, ironclad commitment to the security of the State of Israel and that our two peoples are joined in a common vision for the future.</p>



<p>That’s what he’s going to want to put on display, and that is the message that he will convey through the totality of his meetings in Israel.</p>



<p>Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Last question, and then I’ll move out.&nbsp; So &#8212; go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned earlier that Russia had failed to achieve its objectives, in particular taking Kyiv.&nbsp; Do you &#8212; are you confident then that, even if this war extends months, years in the future, that Russia will not be able to take Kyiv?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we do have confidence that the bravery of the Ukrainians and the support of the West to Ukraine will enable Ukraine to effectively defend and sustain its capital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would also point out, when I talked about the severe costs that Russia has had to endure on the battlefield as it tries to grind out territory in the east, this is coming at a cost to the sustainment of its own weapons.<br><br>And I&#8217;ll just give you one example before I leave, which is an example that I think is pretty newsworthy and noteworthy, and that is that our information indicates that the Iranian government is preparing to provide Russia with up to several hundred UAVs, including weapons-capable UAVs, on an expedi- &#8212; expedited timeline.<br><br>Our information further indicates that Iran is preparing to train Russian forces to use these UAVs with initial training sessions slated to begin as soon as early July.<br><br>It&#8217;s unclear whether Iran has delivered any of these UAVs to Russia already.&nbsp; But this is just one example of how Russia is looking to countries like Iran for capabilities that are also being used, I might add, or have been used before we got the ceasefire in place in Yemen, to attack Saudi Arabia.<br><br>So, from our perspective, we will continue to do our part to help sustain the effective defense of Ukraine and to help the Ukrainians show that the Russian effort to try to wipe Ukraine off the map cannot succeed.<br><br>And I&#8217;ll leave you guys. &nbsp;Thanks, guys.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I have a few things at the top.<br><br>So, on Wednesday, we will have new CPI inflation data, and we expect the headline number, which includes gas and food, to be highly elevated, mainly because gas prices were so elevated in June.</p>



<p>Gas and food prices continue to be heavily impacted by the war in Ukraine.&nbsp; And there are a few important points to keep in mind when we get this backwards-looking data:</p>



<p>First, June CPI data is already out of date because energy prices have come down substantially this month and are expected to fall further.<br><br>The average retail price of gas was 11 percent higher in June than it was in May.&nbsp; And the cost of gas in July is already down 7 percent from the June peak.</p>



<p>I have a chart here for you guys to &#8212; to see.&nbsp; The crude oil is the yellow.&nbsp; I’m sorry, the crude oil is the blue at the bottom, and the retail gasoline price is at the top.&nbsp; And you can see the difference there.</p>



<p>I would also note that even though gas prices shot up quickly when oil prices rose, they have not come down as quickly as oil has.<br><br>We continue to call on oil and gas companies to pass on their lower cost to consumers.&nbsp; American families should not be the first to pay and the last to benefit.</p>



<p>The President’s number one economic priority is tackling inflation.&nbsp; And looking ahead, there are a number of reasons why we expect those high prices to ease over the coming months.</p>



<p>Saturday marked the one-year anniversary of President Biden’s Executive Order to Promote Competition Across the American Economy.</p>



<p>This EO prompted a government-wide effort to help lower prices, raise wages, and encourage innovation.&nbsp; And one year in, we’re extraordinarily proud of the progress we’ve made.</p>



<p><a>Just a few example on this is: The Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission have already scored big wins for Americans.&nbsp; They have <s>locked</s> [blocked] megamergers in the insurance and sugar industries, and stopped a defense contractor megamerger that would’ve cost taxpayers billions of dollars.</a></p>



<p>In just a few months, Americans with hearing loss will be able to buy hearing aids over the counter at a &#8212; at a drug store, instead of requiring a prescription, which could save them thousands of dollars.<br><br>And the Department of Agriculture is cracking down on the meat-processing industry and supporting new competitors so farmer &#8212; farmer and ranchers get a fair price.</p>



<p>Our administration will continue driving structural change to produce lower prices, higher wages, and to make our economy dynamic and competitive.</p>



<p><a>Following a &#8212; following a briefing from NASA, the President and the Vice President will unveil the first [full]-color images NASA’s James Webb Space Telescope &#8212; the largest space telescope ever built.&nbsp; This is very cool.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>The high-resolution images will show light captured from galaxies that are more than 13 billion years old, formed shortly after the Big Bang.</p>



<p>Thanks to the incredible NASA team, this work will help scientists answer some of the biggest open questions about how and why stars form and the habitability of other worlds as well.</p>



<p>And that is it.&nbsp; Josh, do you want to kick us &#8212; kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two subjects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, how seriously is President Biden weighing a public health emergency regarding abortion access?&nbsp; And does he have any concerns about what kind of impact that emergency could have on access?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp;So, Jen Klein spoke about this when she was &#8212; when she joined the briefing room on Friday.&nbsp; And she is &#8212; for those who don&#8217;t know, she is &#8212; she chairs the Gender Policy Council, and she has been leading the effort along with other &#8212; other White House offices in &#8212; within the White House on our response to Dobbs decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But also &#8212; we have to also remember that we started working on this prior to that, prior even when the decision leaked, which is when S.B. 8 in Texas was passed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is something that this administration has been very laser-focused on.&nbsp; But the team has been evaluating every option.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When we looked at declaring a public health emergency, we learned a couple of things &#8212; and she spoke to this as well; I&#8217;m just repeating what she said when she was in the briefing room, which is &#8212; one is: It &#8212; that it doesn&#8217;t free very many resources.&nbsp; There&#8217;s very little money left &#8212; about tens of thousands of dollars that are left because we have used it for other &#8212; for other reasons, in particular the COVID &#8212; our COVID-19 response, the monkeypox, which is an issue that we&#8217;re dealing with right now that we have been very aggressive on dealing with.&nbsp; And also, it also doesn&#8217;t release a significant amount of legal authority.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s why we haven&#8217;t taken that action yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as she has said and as the President has said, that everything is on the table; it doesn&#8217;t mean that it&#8217;s off the table.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to try and figure out every meaningful action to move forward.</p>



<p>So, we haven&#8217;t taken it off the table, but there are components of this potential decision that has kind of given us pause and made us think a little bit deeper about doing that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And secondly, what&#8217;s your message to gun control groups who say that today&#8217;s event here at the White House was premature, given the additional efforts that they say are necessary?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So one of the things that I’ll say about that is: So the President clearly welcomed the bipartisan bill on gun &#8212; gun reform, and he was proud to sign it.&nbsp; We had more than 2,000 people out on the South Lawn, many from different parts of the community; many families who have suffered from gun &#8212; gun violence personally, lost some loved ones; and folks who have been fighting for gun reform for a very long time; and also legislators and congressional members.</p>



<p>And so while he welcomed &#8212; while he has been proud to sign the bill, he understand that more can be done.&nbsp; He spoke about that in his speech today &#8212; in his remarks, specifically &#8212; talking about banning the assault weapon &#8212; something that he led back in 1994, which sunset 10 years later; this is something that he is still going to continue to fight for &#8212; high-capacity magazines.&nbsp; But we do believe and the President does believe that the bipartisan legislation that he signed today on gun reform will start to save lives.&nbsp; And when you think about the red-flag laws, when you think about how that &#8212; when it is enacted, it has been effective.&nbsp; When you think &#8212; look at Democratic states and red states, it has been effective.&nbsp; When you think about this so-called boy &#8212; “the boyfriend loophole,” those things will help to save lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do we need to do more?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to continue to do everything that he can, understa- &#8212; and remembering that this is the President that has done more using executive action to deal with gun violence than any other President at this time in their administration.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One question &#8212; or two questions, but one question on the trip: Does the President plan to hold a press conference after his meetings with the Saudis?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right now, I believe &#8212; and we&#8217;ll have more to share &#8212; he has that one press conference in Israel.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything else to share on &#8212; on what else we’ll &#8212; on what are the activities of the press conference &#8212; other activity &#8212; other press conferences he may have.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We would definitely appreciate one if you &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Understood.&nbsp; Understood.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; scheduled one to ask him about the visit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Understood.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What was the President&#8217;s response to a new poll from the New York Times today showing that 64 percent of Democrats say that they would prefer a different candidate in 2024?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And I would also say from that very same poll, there were 92 percent of Democrats who support this President as well.&nbsp; Look, you know, not to be &#8212; not to get into, you know, politics from here or get into any political analysis: This is not something &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s going to be many polls.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to go up or they&#8217;re going to go down.&nbsp; This is not the thing that we are solely focused on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are focused on things like today&#8217;s signing &#8212; this bipartisan gun reform legislation, which will again save lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Do we have more work to do?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to &#8212; I was talking about inflation and how important &#8212; that is a priority for this President &#8212; and how we have seen gas prices go down by close to 30 cents a gallon in the past 25-plus days.&nbsp; That is something that the President is going to continue to work on because we still need to give Americans relief.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We saw &#8212; we have seen an economy that has bounced back from when he walked in to this administration over a year ago after dealing &#8212; or still dealing, really &#8212; in reality &#8212; with a once-in-a-generation pandemic and how he &#8212; we&#8217;ve been able to bring back jobs that we lost pre-pandemic, and also just continue to do that work.</p>



<p>And how we&#8217;ve seen unemployment at 3.6 percent.&nbsp; The jobs number that we saw last week at 375,000 jobs created in the last month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of these things are the &#8212; is what the President is going to continue to focus on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How do we deliver?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Somebody was asking Jake about USICA, also BIA and all the work that we&#8217;re putting behind that, because that is a top priority for this administration, because we need to continue to compete with countries like China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there is so much work to be done that we are &#8212; the President is going to focus on and deliver as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the event today included an interruption &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; by the father of a high school student who was killed in Parkland.&nbsp; The President first told him to sit down and listen, and then encouraged him to continue speaking.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering what your reaction is and what his feeling was about that incident today?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, you know, our hearts go out to Man- &#8212; Manuel Oliver, who has suffered a deep, deep loss.&nbsp; The President met with him earlier today before the event.&nbsp; And as you know, the President understands what loss feels like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, the President agrees with him.&nbsp; He agrees that we need to do more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why, in his speech, he called on Congress to pass legislation that would ban assault weapons, as I just mentioned, and high-capacity magazines; strengthen background checks; and enact safe storage laws.&nbsp; This is something that is important &#8212; that has been important throughout the President’s career as Vice President, as senator.</p>



<p>The President has had the opportunity, as I just mentioned, to speak with Mr. Oliver in the past, and he knows and understands that he is frustrated and that he&#8217;s hurting, and rightfully so.&nbsp; His life was up &#8212; upended when gun violence took his son.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;ll continue to engage with Mr. Oliver, as &#8212; as Ambassador Rice has.&nbsp; When Cedric Richmond was here, he had met &#8212; they had met with him as well.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re just going to continue to do the work and to have &#8212; have engagement with Mr. Oliver.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to be clear: You said they met today before Mr. Oliver interrupted him.&nbsp; Can you tell us what they spoke about this morning?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I was not part of that meeting so I can&#8217;t speak to what they spoke &#8212; spoke on.&nbsp; But as I said, the President understands what loss feels like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, our hearts go out to Mr. Oliver, and I would never want to imagine what that feels like or want to go through what he&#8217;s going through &#8212; that grieving process.</p>



<p>And, again, we agree with him; we need to do more.&nbsp; The President stated that in his speech today.&nbsp; He has mentioned that almost every time that he has spoken about gun reform and what needs to be done, what else needs to be done to really make a change.</p>



<p>This is a &#8212; you know, this is a public health emergency that we&#8217;re dealing with when we talk about gun violence.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to continue to do the work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks for the question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gosh, I&#8217;m going to go here.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll come around.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up on Kaitlan’s question earlier.&nbsp; You’d mentioned some of the accomplishments of the administration, but that same poll that came out said that 63 percent of Democrats believe the country is headed in the wrong direction.&nbsp; How &#8212; how do you explain that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we understand what the American people are feeling.&nbsp; We understand that.&nbsp; We understand that inflation is hurting families when they are around the kitchen table, when they&#8217;re trying to figure out, you know, how they&#8217;re going to deal with gas prices at the pump, how they&#8217;re going to deal with food prices as well.&nbsp; So, we understand that families are hurting right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That is why the President has been laser-focused on &#8212; on making sure that we truly deal with inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, we&#8217;ve seen the gas prices go down.&nbsp; We believe that that is going to continue &#8212; that&#8217;s going to be a trend that we will continue to see.&nbsp; The President has been working on this for months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have to understand how we also got here.&nbsp; We got here with the &#8212; with the increase of gas prices and food prices because of Mr. Putin&#8217;s war in Ukraine.&nbsp; And what we &#8212; and how &#8212; in particular with food and gas, and how his unprecedented brutal war on Ukraine has cost &#8212; has caused prices to go up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, look, the President&#8217;s going to be focused.&nbsp; We have a strong economy.&nbsp; We are going to &#8212; you know, as we&#8217;re talking about inflation, our plan right now is to do that transition from that &#8212; the growth that we&#8217;ve seen in the economy to a more stable and steady growth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve seen that in the numbers last week, with the jobs numbers.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to focus on that, give the Federal Reserve its opportunity, its space to deal with inflation.&nbsp; They have the best monetary policy to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, again, this is what the President is going to be focused on.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to pay attention to polls.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not what we&#8217;re going to do here.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re going to focus on is delivering for the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, is the President monitoring the wildfires in Yosemite?&nbsp; Is there any commitment from the administration on that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I would have to get back to the team and lay out exactly what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; We are in close contact, for sure, with local government, with governors in the state.&nbsp; This is something that we do monitor and have &#8212; have in the past worked hand-in-hand with local officials on that &#8212; on the specifics.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, is it &#8212; oh, my gosh.&nbsp; Is it time?&nbsp; Okay, let me take one more question.&nbsp; One more question.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Does the White House think abortion rights advocates are out of touch with the party, given the quote that Kate Bedingfield gave to the Washington Post this weekend?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I &#8212; let me just say &#8212; let me just say this: What happened almost two weeks ago now was an unprecedented attack &#8212; right? &#8212; on women&#8217;s right.&nbsp; It was an unprecedented attack on our freedoms.&nbsp; And the President has worked for not just &#8212; as I mentioned, not just since the leaked documents, but since we &#8212; since we have seen the S.B. 8 in Texas, to make sure that this administration, his administration, is doing everything that they can to deliver for &#8212; on this issue of making sure that we protect women&#8217;s rights.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what Kate was saying.&nbsp; She was trying to make sure that we laid out and spoke &#8212; continue to speak about what the President &#8212; the bold step that the President took.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we were responding to criticism in that particular article.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we were responding to.&nbsp; And we were responding to some activists and what they were saying in that article.&nbsp; And so, we were trying to be very specific in that as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But to say that the President has not been passionate, to say that this President has not been focused is just not true.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And even when Jen Klein was here after the President signed the executive order, she talked about NARAL.&nbsp; She talked about Planned Parenthood and how they welcome the steps that we took and what we are delivering on.</p>



<p>Now, is there going to be more work and more work to do?&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And lastly, I will say &#8212; and then we have to go because you all have to gather &#8212; is that the President has always been honest about what needs to be done and what he believes needs to be done.&nbsp; Yes, we’re going to continue to do the work in the administration.&nbsp; But really, Americans have to take it to the ballot.&nbsp; They have to make sure their voices are heard.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he also said, “Keep protesting, protesting peacefully,” but also make sure that you take action and ask Congress to take action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s what we were speaking to.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the comments were all about.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to work on &#8212; on behalf of the American public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, everybody.</p>



<p>4:39 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden Administration Outlines Strategy to Manage&#160;BA.5</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/fact-sheet-biden-administration-outlines-strategy-to-manage-ba-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House COVID-19 Team is announcing its strategy to manage BA.5. The strategy relies on ensuring that Americans continue to have easy and convenient access to the vaccines, treatments, tests, and other tools that protect against and treat COVID-19. These tools – even in the face of BA.5 – work to prevent serious&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House COVID-19 Team is announcing its strategy to manage BA.5. The strategy relies on ensuring that Americans continue to have easy and convenient access to the vaccines, treatments, tests, and other tools that protect against and treat COVID-19. These tools – even in the face of BA.5 – work to prevent serious illness, keep people out of the hospital, and save lives – and we can prevent nearly all COVID-19 deaths with them.</p>



<p>BA.4 and BA.5 – subvariants of the Omicron variant – now make up 80 percent of COVID-19 cases in the U.S., with BA.5 accounting for a majority of cases. Early indications signal that BA.5 may have some increased ability to escape immunity, including from prior infections, meaning it has the potential to cause the numbers of infections to rise in the coming weeks. This potential for increase is greatest where fewer people are up to date on their vaccinations and there is increased waning of immunity from vaccines.</p>



<p>In January 2021, the American people had limited tools to protect themselves against COVID-19. Today, that is no longer the case. Thanks to the infrastructure that the President’s comprehensive COVID-19 response has built and the tools that the Administration has worked to make widely available over the past 18 months, the U.S. is prepared to combat the challenge of BA.5. More than 222 million Americans are fully vaccinated, over 106 million people have at least their first booster shot, and virtually every American of every age is eligible for vaccination. And, we have more courses of lifesaving treatments available and being used than ever before, as well as widely available at-home tests and high-quality masks.</p>



<p>The President’s comprehensive COVID-19 response has produced tremendous results for the American people: COVID-19 is no longer the disruptive force it once was, and most COVID-19 deaths are now preventable because of the vaccines, treatments, and other tools the Biden Administration has made available to the American people. Daily COVID-19 deaths are down by 90 percent since the President took office. America’s schools are open. More Americans are working in the private sector than before the pandemic started. And, the vast majority of Americans are comfortable visiting with loved ones, eating out, traveling and doing other things that they did before COVID-19.</p>



<p>In March, the President released his National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan – a roadmap to continue our fight against the virus and to continue minimizing its impact on our lives. Since emerging from the Omicron surge this past winter, we have worked to make sure that the tools we have remain widely available and easily accessible to Americans.</p>



<p>To confront BA.5, the Administration will continue mobilizing the full strength and capabilities of the federal government and working with state and local leaders, health care workers, the private sector, and community- and faith-based organizations to ensure that the American people have easy and convenient access to and use vaccines, tests, and treatments.</p>



<p><strong>The Administration’s strategy to manage BA.5 includes:</strong></p>



<p><strong>Making it easy for people to get vaccines and boosters:</strong> The Administration will continue working with state and local leaders, doctors and pediatricians, pharmacies, community health centers, long-term care facilities, employers, and community- and faith-based organizations to drive additional uptake of booster shots, particularly among those age 50 and older and other at-risk populations, including long-term care facility staff and residents. Given the rise of BA.5, it is essential that Americans stay up to date on their COVID-19 vaccinations. The science is clear that COVID-19 vaccines remain our single-most important tool to protect people and prevent serious illness, hospitalizations, and deaths, and staying up to date on booster shots ensures that people have the highest level of protection possible. Based on the latest CDC data, adults who are up to date with their vaccinations are 3.5 times less likely to be hospitalized than unvaccinated adults; among those who are 50 and older, people who have received two booster shots are 42 times less likely to die from COVID-19 compared to those who are unvaccinated. Vaccines are free and easy to access at 90,000 convenient locations nationwide. And, the guidance is clear that every American age 5 and over should receive a booster five months after their primary series,  and individuals age 50 and older or those who are moderately or severely immunocompromised should receive a second booster shot at least four months after their first.</p>



<p><strong>Making it easy to access COVID-19 treatments and boost provider and patient awareness:</strong> The Administration will continue working across the federal government, with state and local leaders, health care providers, as well as the public and private sectors, to take additional actions to boost access and awareness of lifesaving treatments, particularly in areas where BA.5 is spreading. Today, the U.S. has three treatments that are effective against BA.5, including Paxlovid, a lifesaving antiviral pill that has been shown to reduce the risk of hospitalization or death by about 90 percent. Americans who test positive for COVID-19 should consult their health care provider about their eligibility for these treatments, or visit COVID.gov to find a Test to Treat location where they can get tested and treatments all in one place. The Administration has purchased 20 million treatment courses of Paxlovid – more than any other country in the world – and moved quickly to make these treatments widely available and to educate health care providers and patients about their availability and efficacy. Oral antivirals are now available at over 41,000 convenient locations nationwide, and nearly 90 percent of Americans live within 5 miles of a place where they can pick up a prescription. As a result of the Administration’s actions, the number of people benefiting from oral antivirals has dramatically increased over the course of this year, from about 18,000 prescriptions filled each week in January to more than 230,000 last week – a more than 12-fold increase. Each day, about one-third of confirmed and reported cases are receiving free and effective oral antiviral treatments.</p>



<p><strong>Making free COVID-19 testing, including at-home tests, widely available:</strong> Testing continues to be an important tool to help mitigate the spread of COVID-19, including BA.4 and BA.5. In the face of BA.5, the Administration is encouraging Americans to use at-home tests before attending large, indoor gatherings, traveling, or visiting indoors with immunocompromised individuals. COVID-19 testing is now more widely available and accessible to the American people than ever before, and there are now 17 over-the-counter, at-home, rapid tests authorized for the U.S. market – up from zero when the President took office. To help ensure that Americans have tests on hand if a need arises, the Administration opened COVIDtests.gov for a third round of ordering ahead of the summer, meaning that 16 free tests have been made available to each household since the launch of the program. To ensure equitable access for visually-impaired individuals, the Administration has also made available more accessible at-home tests to households with visually-impaired individuals. To date, the Administration has delivered approximately 530 million at-home tests directly to over 75 million American households for free through COVIDtests.gov. Additionally, private health insurers, Medicare, and all Medicaid programs are required to cover at-home COVID-19 tests for free; health insurance plans now cover eight free tests per month per individual which can be easily accessed at local pharmacies and online. And, there are over 15,000 federally-supported free testing sites across the nation. This free testing program has increased&nbsp; equitable access to testing, and 50 percent of individuals currently served by the pharmacy free testing program are racial and ethnic minorities or live in high social vulnerability communities.</p>



<p><strong>Making free high-quality masks widely available and communicate clear recommendations about when people should consider masking:</strong> Experts agree that masking in indoor, public spaces is an important tool to control the spread of COVID-19. The CDC’s COVID-19 Community Levels provide individuals with clear recommendations on when to consider masking in indoor, public spaces. As BA.5 drives an increase in cases, the Administration continues to encourage Americans to visit COVID.gov to find the level of COVID-19 in their community and follow CDC’s recommendations on wearing masks in public, indoor settings. Since January 2021, the Biden Administration has taken significant action, including using the Defense Production Act, to ensure that the U.S. has ample supply of high-quality masks for health care workers and that high-quality masks are also widely available to the American public online and in stores. To further increase access, over the past seven months, the Administration has made 400 million non-surgical N95 masks from the Strategic National Stockpile available to the American people for free at tens of thousands of convenient locations nationwide – the largest deployment of personal protective equipment in U.S. history. And, the Administration will continue to make masks available for health care and other essential workers through states, building on the over 75 million masks and respirators we have already distributed to states, Tribes, and territories across the country.</p>



<p><strong>Prioritizing protections for immunocompromised individuals: </strong>As BA.5 cases rise, the Administration will continue to provide support to individuals who are immunocompromised so that they have the support they need to live their lives safely. The Administration has initiated a communications campaign to ensure that immunocompromised individuals and their close contacts are up to date with COVID-19 vaccination and boosters. The availability of vaccines for kids as young as six months old also ensures that all close contacts of immunocompromised individuals can be protected by COVID-19 vaccines. The Administration also continues to make effective pre-exposure prophylactics such as Evusheld more widely available through enhanced distribution to clinicians’ offices and clinics. And, in the coming weeks, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will launch an easy-to-remember hotline to help individuals access this effective tool to prevent COVID-19.</p>



<p><strong>Encouraging all building owners to improve indoor ventilation: </strong>Improving ventilation can help prevent the spread of BA.4 and BA.5 indoors in buildings. The Administration has provided state and local leaders hundreds of billions of dollars in federal funds that can be used in schools, public buildings, and other settings to improve indoor air quality, and the Administration will continue to advance indoor air quality in buildings, including by increasing public awareness around ventilation and filtration improvements to reduce disease spread, as well as by recognizing buildings and organizations that have taken steps to improve indoor air quality. These efforts will expand on the Administration’s “best practices” guide for improving indoor air quality and reducing the risk of spreading dangerous airborne particles and the Clean Air in Buildings Challenge, which calls on all building owners and operators, schools, colleges and universities, and organizations of all kinds to adopt key strategies to improve indoor air quality in their buildings and reduce the spread of COVID-19. Additionally, CDC has released interactive tools to help individuals at home, in schools, and in other buildings to understand how air flows in their space and what they can do to help shore up air quality and improve ventilation indoors.</p>



<p><strong>Empowering people with the latest information on COVID-19 and where to access vaccines, treatments, tests, and masks at COVID.Gov:</strong> The Administration will continue to communicate clearly with the American people about COVID-19 and the steps that they can take to protect themselves and their loved ones. Earlier this year, the Biden Administration launched COVID.gov, a new one-stop shop website to help Americans find where to access lifesaving tools like vaccines, tests, treatments, and masks. People can also type in their county to find the latest updates on the level of COVID-19 in their community and related guidance. And, with a click of a button, people can access resources related to testing, ventilation, and other important COVID-19 topics. COVID.gov is available in English, Spanish, and Simplified Chinese and is accessible for those using assistive technologies. The Administration is also making all of these COVID-19 tools available over the phone through the National Hotline at 1-800-232-0233 (TTY 1-888-720-7489), which supports over 150 languages. For individuals with disabilities who may need additional support, the Disability Information and Access Line (DIAL) is also available to help at 1-888-677-1199 or via email at DIAL@usaginganddisability.org.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Vice President Harris Announces Commitments to Strengthen U.S. Partnership with the Pacific&#160;Islands</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-commitments-to-strengthen-u-s-partnership-with-the-pacific-islands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 12, Vice President Harris will participate virtually in the Pacific Islands Forum leaders’ meeting at the invitation of the Forum Chair Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama of Fiji. As part of this engagement with Forum leaders, the Vice President will announce new commitments to deepen U.S. partnership with the region and to deliver concrete&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 12, Vice President Harris will participate virtually in the Pacific Islands Forum leaders’ meeting at the invitation of the Forum Chair Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama of Fiji. As part of this engagement with Forum leaders, the Vice President will announce new commitments to deepen U.S. partnership with the region and to deliver concrete results for Pacific people. These actions advance the Biden-Harris Administration’s ongoing efforts to strengthen the U.S.-Pacific Islands partnership and to support Pacific regionalism, with a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum at the center.<br>&nbsp;<br>This milestone reflects the United States’ robust and growing commitment to the Pacific Islands region. It follows President Biden’s appointment of a Special Presidential Envoy for Compact Negotiations and the launch of the Partners in the Blue Pacific, a new coordination initiative among the United States, Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the United Kingdom to support Pacific priorities more effectively. It also builds on five decades of close cooperation with the Pacific Islands Forum, including as a founding Dialogue Partner; $350 million in annual U.S. assistance to the Pacific; and deep people-to-people ties, including among the 1.4 million Pacific Islanders who live across the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>With this foundation, the Vice President is announcing the following actions. The Biden-Harris Administration will:<br>&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Establish New U.S. Embassies in Kiribati and Tonga:</strong> The Biden-Harris Administration recognizes that our close partnership with the Pacific requires regular exchange between our governments at all levels, from our leaders to our diplomats around the world. To that end, the United States, subject to congressional notification, will commence discussions with Kiribati and Tonga about our interest in establishing U.S. embassies in those countries. The United States is on track to reopen its embassy in Solomon Islands.</li><li><strong>Triple Request for U.S. Funding for Economic Development and Ocean Resilience: </strong>For 33 years, the South Pacific Tuna Treaty has served as a cornerstone of political and economic cooperation between the United States and Pacific Islands, enabling U.S. fishing-fleet access to the Pacific, supporting livelihoods across the region, and providing a platform for broader cooperation, including to combat the scourge of illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing. Vice President Harris will announce that the United States is prepared to request from the U.S. Congress $60 million per year for the next ten years—nearly triple the current levels and $600 million in total—in connection with a new Economic Assistance Agreement with the Forum Fisheries Agency.</li><li><strong>Appoint the First-Ever U.S. Envoy to the Pacific Islands Forum:</strong> A resilient and prosperous Pacific Islands region requires a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum—the preeminent driver of action in the region. The Biden-Harris Administration will redouble our commitment to the Pacific Islands Forum by appointing, for the first time, a designated U.S. Pacific Islands Forum Envoy. In doing so, the United States will further increase our overall diplomatic footprint across the Pacific Islands.</li><li><strong>Design and Release the First-Ever U.S. National Strategy on the Pacific Islands</strong>: The Biden-Harris Administration will craft and publish the first-ever U.S. strategy on the Pacific Islands—a whole-of-government strategy to prioritize the Pacific Islands in American foreign policy and drive effective implementation. It will be nested under the Indo-Pacific Strategy of the United States, which the Biden-Harris Administration released earlier this year in Fiji. The U.S. National Strategy on the Pacific Islands will align with the goals, areas of focus, and principles of the Pacific Islands Forum’s 2050 Strategy for the Blue Pacific Continent.</li><li><strong>Bring the Peace Corps Back to the Pacific: </strong>The longevity of our ties with the Pacific Islands depends on close people-to-people relationships. Peace Corps volunteers will soon return to Fiji, Tonga, Samoa, and Vanuatu, and the Peace Corps will work with the region to explore program expansion to additional Pacific Island countries.</li><li><strong>Progress Toward&nbsp;Re-establishing&nbsp;a United States Agency for International Development&nbsp;(USAID) Regional&nbsp;Mission&nbsp;for the Pacific in Suva, Fiji:&nbsp;</strong>USAID provides life-saving&nbsp;humanitarian and development assistance&nbsp;across the Pacific Islands, from Kiribati in the wake of drought to Tonga in the wake of volcanic eruptions and tsunami waves&nbsp;to economic assistance in Papua New Guinea and Solomon Islands. The Vice President will announce that USAID&nbsp;is taking steps to&nbsp;expand&nbsp;its&nbsp;presence in the&nbsp;Pacific, subject to congressional notification,&nbsp;to&nbsp;improve&nbsp;close cooperation with its host country partners.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Implement and Advance the Partners in the Blue Pacific</strong>: Emerging challenges, from the climate crisis to infrastructure needs, require cooperation across borders. To that end, the United States and its allies and partners—Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the United Kingdom—established a new coordination mechanism, the Partners in the Blue Pacific (PBP). The PBP is dedicated to supporting Pacific priorities more effectively and efficiently, to bolstering Pacific regionalism, and to expanding opportunities between the Pacific and the world. Our countries provide a combined $2.1 billion in development assistance for the region, and we will seek to drive additional focus and resources by welcoming further members and observers, including in Europe and the Indo-Pacific. Above all, at every stage, the PBP will be led and guided by the Pacific Islands, including close consultations on its flagship projects. </li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
