<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 22:24:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of Senior Administration Travel to&#160;India</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/readout-of-senior-administration-travel-to-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 22:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh was in New Delhi to discuss ways to deepen U.S.-India economic cooperation and advance our shared interest in a free and open Indo-Pacific. Singh also continued our close consultations with Indian counterparts about the destabilizing economic impacts of Russia’s war against Ukraine. Singh met with Principal Secretary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh was in New Delhi to discuss ways to deepen U.S.-India economic cooperation and advance our shared interest in a free and open Indo-Pacific. Singh also continued our close consultations with Indian counterparts about the destabilizing economic impacts of Russia’s war against Ukraine. Singh met with Principal Secretary P.K. Mishra, Minister of Commerce and Indian G20 Sherpa Piyush Goyal, Foreign Secretary Harsh V. Shringla, Deputy National Security Advisor Vikram Misri, and Department of Economic Affairs Secretary Ajay Seth. Singh consulted with Indian counterparts on the goals and mechanisms of U.S. sanctions imposed on Russia and ways to cooperate on addressing global food insecurity and global energy prices. Singh and his counterparts also advanced ongoing discussions about the development of an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, delivering high-quality infrastructure through Build Back Better World, the development of an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, and strengthening the global economy. The conversations were productive and both sides committed to continue their close consultations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on Historic Investments in Economic Development in Underserved&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/01/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-historic-investments-in-economic-development-in-underserved-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 22:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Delta Center StageGreenville, Mississippi THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Please have a seat.&#160; Good &#8212; it&#8217;s so good to be with you all.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Good afternoon. Ms. Joyce, I want to thank you for that introduction.&#160; You know, I had the honor of visiting her shop earlier&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Delta Center Stage<br>Greenville, Mississippi</em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Please have a seat.&nbsp; Good &#8212; it&#8217;s so good to be with you all.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br><br>Ms. Joyce, I want to thank you for that introduction.&nbsp; You know, I had the honor of visiting her shop earlier today.&nbsp; And it took me back.&nbsp; I shared with her &#8212; you know, my mother would make our clothes often.&nbsp; She would make &#8212; I remember in particular a couple of very fancy dresses she made.&nbsp; And going to the shop, I saw those fancy dresses that Ms. Joyce was making, and I thought &#8212; it really took me back.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know what it means to have a place like that in the community where you can go and where families go and where it is intergenerational, in terms of the families that are impacted by the work that happens in places like that.<br><br>So, I want to thank you for allowing me to visit with you today and to visit your store.<br><br>Mayor Errick Simmons, where are you?&nbsp; I know you&#8217;re here.&nbsp; There you are.&nbsp; I want to thank you for welcoming us &#8212; so warmly welcoming us.&nbsp; The mayor met me on the tarmac as I landed, and I thank you for the warm welcome and your role of leadership.<br><br>&nbsp;It is good to be in this beautiful place.&nbsp; And so good to be here, of course, with Chairman Bennie Thompson &#8212; where is he?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I will tell you, he is a true champion for the people of this state.&nbsp; And I didn&#8217;t dare make this trip plan without checking in with Bennie Thompson &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to seek his advice and approval.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But I will tell you, in all seriousness, I have seen him, over the years, during the time that we have worked together, in the halls of the Capital, in these very ornate rooms in our United States Capital &#8212; sometimes when the camera is on, sometimes when the cameras are off &#8212; and he is the same person always.&nbsp; He is always fighting for the people of Mississippi.&nbsp; Always.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And I&#8217;ve had the pleasure of seeing him twice this week because &#8212; or last week, actually &#8212; because we were at the White House when the Pre- &#8212; together when the President signed into law the Emmett Till Antilynching Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; yes &#8212; which was a step toward finishing some unfinished business.<br><br>Also here with us today is the great Bill Bynum, the CEO of Hope Credit Union.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And Mr. Bynum, as you know, has helped connect so many people in Mississippi and across the South with opportunity and, yes, with hope to be all they can be.&nbsp;<br><br>And I shared with a couple of folks earlier &#8212; I did check in with him actually after we first came into office, because this has been a very longstanding area of focus and priority for me, which is to support our small businesses.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d been hearing for years about work of Bill Bynum and so checked in with him at the very beginning.&nbsp;<br><br>And he told me at the very beginning, during the height of the restriction &#8212; COVID &#8212; so we couldn&#8217;t really travel &#8212; and he said, &#8220;Well, Madam Vice President, if you really want to see what&#8217;s going on, you come to the Mississippi Delta.&#8221;&nbsp; So here I am.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; So here I am.<br><br>&nbsp; And so, Greenville is a city that knows so much and, in particular, knows resilience.&nbsp; In 1927, the waters of the Mississippi rose and covered every square foot of this city for three months.&nbsp; And when the water receded, the people of Greenville cleaned up and moved back in.&nbsp;<br><br>Over the past two years, like so many communities around our nation, you have faced incredible challenges.&nbsp; And you have met those incredible challenges with incredible strength.</p>



<p>Greenville is a place built by the ambition and the aspiration of its people.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As an extension of the fact that America is a place that was built by the ambition and aspiration of its people.&nbsp; America is a nation built by people who see what can be, unburdened by what has been.&nbsp;<br><br>People with the ambition and the aspiration to transform dreams into reality: to buy a house, to get an education, to start a business, to leave something behind for the next generation.&nbsp; That energy drives our entire nation forward, and it creates jobs, it accelerates innovation, it strengthens our communities, it expands our economy, and it makes our nation more globally competitive.&nbsp;<br><br>And as you know, turning ambition and aspiration into action often requires capital &#8212; capital to start and grow a business or buy or renovate a home.&nbsp;<br><br>And it requires financial services &#8212; services like checking and savings accounts, credit cards and lines of credit, financial information and good advice.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know well, not everyone in our country, sadly, can access this essential support.&nbsp;<br><br>Consider this: Black entrepreneurs are three times more likely to report that they did not apply for credit for fear of being turned away by a bank.&nbsp; Black and Latino homeowners are rejected at a higher rate when applying for home loans from traditional financial institutions, even when they have credit profiles similar to other applicants.&nbsp; Many Asian American business owners, in particular immigrant business owners, face language barriers that limit their ability to access capital and banking services.&nbsp;<br><br>And people who live in rural communities often lack access to traditional banking services of any kind.&nbsp; This includes many Native Americans and, here in the Mississippi Delta, many Black folks.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, let us acknowledge also that while they play an important role in the growth of our economy, traditional banks have not always seen the vision of small-business owners of color, small-business owners who are women, small-business owners who live in rural areas, and small-business owners who serve low-income communities.&nbsp;<br><br>Community lenders, on the other hand, were created to see that vision and to support it.&nbsp; These lenders predominantly serve overlooked and underserved communities.&nbsp; The people who run these institutions often live and work in those communities.&nbsp; They know the people to whom they are lending.&nbsp; They understand the community, their needs, their challenges, and their strengths.&nbsp;<br><br>When they make a loan, they often personally feel its impact because, of course, they are there, linked with the community.&nbsp; And so, community lenders often see the potential that others might overlook.&nbsp;<br><br>Potential like Hope Credit Union saw in Ms. Joyce.&nbsp; Hope Credit Union loaned Joyce just over $10,000, an amount too small for most traditional banks to bother lending.&nbsp; But it was an amount that was transformative for Ms. Joyce and for Greenville.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Across our nation, small businesses are engines of economic prosperity.&nbsp; And this is especially true in rural areas and in Mississippi, where over 99 percent of all businesses are small businesses.&nbsp;<br><br>Rural small businesses train and hire local workers.&nbsp; They provide essential products and services to customers that they often see on a daily basis and face to face.&nbsp; And they know and understand, and they help ensure residents have the opportunities they need to remain in the places they love.<br><br>And these businesses do not just create prosperity, they also build community.&nbsp; So often &#8212; in my experience and, I’m sure, yours &#8212; small-business owners are not only leaders in<br>business, they are community leaders.&nbsp; They are civic leaders.&nbsp; They sponsor the local softball team.&nbsp; They mentor and hire young people from the community.&nbsp; They are role models.&nbsp; And now, as we all know well, rural small businesses also face unique challenges that businesses in urban areas sometimes do not.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, many operate in communities that do not have access to affordable or accessible high-speed Internet or in communities where the roads and bridges are in desperate need of repair.&nbsp;<br><br>So, our administration is dealing with that too.&nbsp; And we have made, we are proud to say &#8212; again, thanks to the Congressman and so many others &#8212; historic investments to address these challenges.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invests $110 billion to repair our nation&#8217;s roads and bridges, to help customers and employees better access small businesses.&nbsp; And the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invests $65 billion to ensure that every person in our nation has access to affordable high-speed Internet.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And we know that part of why that is important is, of course, the subject today: Small businesses need to reach their customers.&nbsp; They need to buy supplies, even run their cash register.&nbsp; And all of that will be helped by having access to high-speed Internet.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we are fighting every day to ensure that small businesses have access to capital and the banking services they need to thrive.&nbsp; And that is why we are all here today.<br><br>Mississippi has one of the highest concentrations of community lenders of any state in our nation &#8212; (applause) &#8212; with more than 100 CDFIs &#8212; these Community Development Financial Institutions &#8212; holding assets of over $35 billion.<br><br>Those institutions have helped so many small-business owners, like Joyce, start, grow, and protect their small business.&nbsp; And they deserve more support.&nbsp;<br><br>So, like many of the lenders here with us today, expanding our nation&#8217;s investment in these institutions has been a priority of mine for years.&nbsp; When I was senator, I helped secure $12 billion for community lenders as part of a COVID-19 relief bill &#8212; because we clearly know from Joyce’s story the connection there.<br><br>Of the approximately $10 billion that has already been allocated from that investment, more has gone to community lenders in Mississippi than to lenders in any other state.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And now, our administration is working with our partners &#8212; the Secretary of the Treasury, Janet Yellen, and the Administrator of the SBA, Isabella Guzman &#8212; to broaden the reach of community lenders.&nbsp;<br><br>So I&#8217;m going to offer a couple of examples.&nbsp; Back in 2011, the Small Business Administration launched what was called the Community Advantage pilot loan program.&nbsp; Through this program, the SBA partially guarantees loans made by community lenders.&nbsp; It allows community lenders to make more investems [sic] &#8212; more investments in underserved communities and to make loans to entrepreneurs that others have deemed too risky.<br><br>Earlier this week, I was proud to announce that our administration is extending, expanding, and improving the Community Advantage program so that more small businesses will be able to benefit.&nbsp; And our work does not stop there.<br><br>Families across the nation are feeling the rising cost of housing.&nbsp; Now, there are many reasons homes are becoming more expensive to buy and to rent.&nbsp; Here is one of the most significant: Our country simply does not have enough houses.&nbsp; That is why in the budget that our administration released this week, we proposed $5 billion in funding over 10 years for community lenders to invest in construction and rehabilitation projects.&nbsp;<br><br>That will increase the number of affordable homes available to rent and to buy.&nbsp; And it will help to lower the cost of living of families throughout our country.<br><br>And I&#8217;ll end with this:&nbsp;You know, when the pundits &#8212;<br>you know, in the evening news &#8212; they talk &#8212; when they talk about economic opportunity &#8212; right? &#8212; and they&#8217;re asked their opinion about economic opportunity, have you ever noticed that they will often refer to Wall Street or Silicon Valley?&nbsp;<br><br>Well, from my perspective, I think they should be talking about places like Greenville.&nbsp; (Applause.) (Laughs.)&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Because, you know, this is a place that can help us take the temperature of how we&#8217;re doing and because this is a place that is filled with people with talent and tenacity and vision &#8212; people who, when given the opportunity, will build something extraordinary.<br><br>And there are communities like Greenville across the South and across our nation &#8212; reservoirs of ambition and aspiration just waiting to be tapped.&nbsp;&nbsp; That is why we invest in community lenders.&nbsp; And that is why we will keep working to build an economy that includes everyone.&nbsp; And that is why we will keep working to ensure that every person in our nation, no matter where they live or who they are, has an opportunity not only to succeed but to thrive.&nbsp;<br><br>Because when we do, we&#8217;re very clear, we lift up communities like Greenville and we lift up our small businesses, and all of America benefits.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all very much.&nbsp; Take care.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Statement on UN-Mediated Truce in&#160;Yemen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/president-biden-statement-on-un-mediated-truce-in-yemen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 21:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I welcome the announcement today of a two-month truce in the Yemen conflict. This initiative is a long-awaited reprieve for the Yemeni people. It entails a halt to all military activities by any party inside Yemen and across its borders, the entry of fuel ships into Hudaydah port, and the renewal of commercial flights to and from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I welcome the announcement today of a two-month truce in the Yemen conflict. This initiative is a long-awaited reprieve for the Yemeni people. It entails a halt to all military activities by any party inside Yemen and across its borders, the entry of fuel ships into Hudaydah port, and the renewal of commercial flights to and from Saan’a to agreed destinations. These are important steps, but they are not enough. The ceasefire must be adhered to, and as I have said before, it is imperative that we end this war. After seven years of conflict, negotiators must undertake the hard and necessary work to reach political compromises that can bring about an enduring future of peace for all the people of Yemen. I am grateful for the leadership role of Saudi Arabia and Oman in bringing this initiative to fruition before the Holy Month of Ramadan. I am also grateful for the hard work of the Yemeni Government and the confidence they have placed in UN-led mediation. The United States of America will work to deter threats to our friends and partners as we continue to strive for de-escalation and peace throughout the region. I wish the people of Yemen a peaceful Ramadan, and assure them of our ongoing commitment to help end this terrible war. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Robert Godec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Thailand Vinay Singh, Nominee for Chief Financial Officer, Department of Housing and Urban Development Kalpana Kotagal, Nominee for Commissioner on the Equal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Robert Godec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Thailand</li><li>Vinay Singh, Nominee for Chief Financial Officer, Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Kalpana Kotagal, Nominee for Commissioner on the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Robert Godec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Thailand</u></strong></p>



<p>Robert F. Godec, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Career Minister, currently serves as Senior Coordinator for Afghanistan in the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration at the U.S. Department of State. Prior to that, he was Acting Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of African Affairs. He previously served as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary and as Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of African Affairs. Earlier, Godec was Deputy Commandant and International Affairs Advisor at the National War College. He was U.S. Ambassador to Kenya from 2013 to 2019. Godec was also Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at U.S. Embassy Nairobi, Kenya in 2012. Before his assignment in Nairobi, Godec was the Principal Deputy Coordinator for Counterterrorism in the Bureau of Counterterrorism in the Department of State. Previously, he served as U.S. Ambassador to Tunisia. Godec has also served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs and was Deputy Coordinator for the Transition in Iraq. He served as Acting Deputy Chief of Mission and Minister Counselor for Economic Affairs at U.S. Embassy Pretoria, South Africa. His other positions include Economic Counselor at U.S. Embassy Nairobi, Kenya; Assistant Office Director for Thailand and Burma in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs; and Director for Southeast Asian Affairs at the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative.</p>



<p>A member of the Foreign Service since 1985, Godec has a Master’s degree from Yale University, as well as a Bachelor’s degree from the University of Virginia. He is the recipient of two Presidential Meritorious Service Awards, numerous Senior Performance Awards, and a Distinguished Honor Award. He speaks French and German.</p>



<p><strong><u>Vinay Singh, Nominee for Chief Financial Officer, Department of Housing and Urban Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Vinay Singh, a Certified Public Accountant, is currently a Senior Advisor to the Administrator at the U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA), assisting agency teams to deliver organizational efficiencies to better serve our communities’ small businesses. Singh has 25 years of private sector leadership experience with a deep understanding of finance, analytics, and strategy.</p>



<p>Prior to his role at SBA, Singh was a Partner and Chief Operating Officer for the Infrastructure practice at KPMG in India. As a senior member of the executive team, he led several organizational transformation projects, leveraging technology to improve profitability and decision-making. As Lead Partner for the World Bank Group account, he supported global sustainability projects focused on solving urban and rural challenges in housing, water, energy, and economic development. Previously, Singh served in the Obama-Biden Administration as a Deputy Assistant Secretary (U.S. Field). He played a key role in leading trade and investment policy and promotion efforts to better market conditions for U.S. companies. In his early years as a Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA) and Project Management Professional (PMP), Singh helped several companies improve operational and financial performance. He holds an MBA from Widener University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kalpana Kotagal, Nominee for Commissioner on the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Kalpana Kotagal is a Partner at Cohen Milstein, a member of the firm’s Civil Rights &amp; Employment practice group, and Co-Chair of the firm’s Hiring and Diversity Committee. She is co-author of the seminal legal template the “Inclusion Rider.” Kotagal is a diversity, equity, and inclusion expert, and represents disenfranchised people in employment and civil rights litigation involving issues related to Title VII, the Equal Pay Act, the Americans with Disabilities Act, the Family and Medical Leave Act, and the Fair Labor Standards Act.</p>



<p>Kotagal was a Harvard Law School Wasserstein Public Interest Fellow and was named an “Employment Law MVP” by <em>Law360 </em>in 2018, recognizing the top five most influential employment lawyers in the United States. Kotagal sits on the Boards of Directors of A Better Balance and Public Justice Foundation. She is co-chair of the Alumni Advisory Board on Equity &amp; Inclusion at the University of Pennsylvania Law School, a member of the American Constitution Society Task Force on #MeToo in the Legal Profession, and serves on the Advisory Board of the People’s Parity Project. The daughter of immigrants from India, Kotagal earned her B.S. and an A.B., with honors, from Stanford University and her J.D., <em>cum laude</em>, from the University of Pennsylvania Law School. Prior to joining Cohen Milstein, Kotagal served as a law clerk to the Honorable Betty Binns Fletcher of the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit. She resides in Cincinnati, Ohio with her husband and two sons.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the March Jobs&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/01/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-march-jobs-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 16:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50375</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 10:56 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Today, we learned that in March, our economy created 431,000 jobs.  Nice sound to it.  And we also learned that in January and February, our economy created 100,000 more jobs than had &#8212; we previously had thought.  That means that over the last three months, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>10:56 A.M. EDT<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good morning.  Today, we learned that in March, our economy created 431,000 jobs.  Nice sound to it.  And we also learned that in January and February, our economy created 100,000 more jobs than had &#8212; we previously had thought.  That means that over the last three months, the economy has created more than a half million &#8212; more than 500,000 jobs a month.<br> <br>Over the course of my presidency, our recovery has now created 7.9 million jobs &#8212; more jobs created over the first 14 months of any presidency in any term ever.  And that&#8217;s striking. <br> <br>But what&#8217;s even more striking is this: In March, the unemployment rate fell to 3.6 percent, down from 6.4 percent when I took office about 15 months ago &#8212; the fastest decline in unemployment to start a President’s term ever recorded.  <br> <br>In fact, there have been only three months in the last 50 years where the unemployment rate in America is lower than it is now. <br> <br>And that me- &#8212; what it means is clear, is very clear: Americans are back to work.  And that’s good news for millions of families who have a little more breathing room and the dignity that comes from earning a paycheck &#8212; just the dignity of having a job.<br> <br>And more and more Americans get jobs &#8212; as they do, it&#8217;s going to help to ease the supply pressures we’ve seen.  And that’s good news for fighting inflation, it’s good news for our economy, and it means that our economy has gone from being on the mend to being on the move.<br> <br>You know, the American people, I think they &#8212; they&#8217;re beginning to understand that the American Rescue Plan &#8212; and there&#8217;s no reason why they should know the names of all these pieces of legislation that got passed &#8212; but the American Rescue Plan, with it, we were able to get Americans vaccinated, schools open, and businesses humming. <br> <br>A leading financial firm, Moody’s, estimated that because of the Rescue Plan, 4 million more American jobs were created and unemployment is 2 percent lower than it would have been had we failed to move that legislation.  <br> <br>Thanks to our infrastructure law, we have more than 4,000 projects getting started this year &#8212; 4,000 &#8212; in every single state in America &#8212; a total of 4,000 in all 50 states, rebuilding America. <br> <br>We’re building a recovery worth of &#8212; worthy of American workers: strong and resilient.  And it&#8217;s going to be able to overcome the headwinds &#8212; and it has &#8212; of Delta, Omicron, and even war in Europe.<br> <br>Our policies are working.  And we’re getting results for the American people &#8212; which is what it&#8217;s all about, to state the obvious.<br> <br>Record job creation.  Record unemployment declines.  Record wage gains.  And, by the way, jobs and unemployment are not just another statistic.  They go directly to the core of what the economy represents: the ability for hardworking Americans to live with dignity, support their families, and build a better life for their children. <br> <br>People are making more money.  They’re finding better jobs.  And after decades of being mistreated and paid too little, more and more American workers have real power now to do &#8212; get better wages and to do what’s best for themselves and their families.  <br> <br>Some people see that as a problem; we&#8217;ve had this discussion in the past.  I don’t.  I see it as long overdue. <br> <br>So when you hear these numbers, they&#8217;re not statistics; it’s a statement of the type of economy we’re fighting for &#8212; an economy, as I&#8217;ve been saying from the beginning, built from the bottom up and the middle out &#8212; not from the top down.  When we do it that way, everybody does well, everybody wins. <br> <br>Even though we’ve created a record number of jobs, we know &#8212; I know &#8212; that this job is not finished.  We need to do more to get prices under control. <br> <br>Putin’s invasion of Ukraine has driven up gas prices and food prices all over the world.  To help deal with that, yesterday I authorized the release of 1 million barrels per day for the next six months from our Strategic Petroleum Reserve.   <br> <br>I acknowledge this, by far, is the largest release from our national reserves in our history.  It is a wartime bridge &#8212; is the way I look at it &#8212; to increase our oil supply as we work with our oil &#8212; U.S oil producers to ramp up their production to get us through this period. <br> <br>I&#8217;ve coordinated this release with partners and allies around the world.  This morning, over 30 countries from across the world convened an extraordinary meeting and agreed to the release of tens of millions of additional barrels of oil onto the market.  <br> <br>Hundreds of hours of meetings with key allies, keeping them together, is paying off.  Nations are coming together to deny Putin the ability to weaponize his energy resources against American families &#8212; not only American families, but families in Europe and around the world.<br> <br>I’ve also made it a priority to get America’s fiscal house in order.  Under my predecessor, the federal budget deficit went up every single year &#8212; every year.  As I committed when I was running and I got here, we’re going to turn that around.<br> <br>In fact, last year, in 2021, we cut the federal deficit by more than $350 billion.  And this year, in 2022, we&#8217;re on track to cut the deficit by more than $1.3 trillion &#8212; $1.3 trillion.  That would be the largest one-year reduction in the deficit in U.S. history.  And it&#8217;s particularly important now as we work to reduce pressures on inflation.  That&#8217;s what happens when you reduce the deficit. <br> <br>So here are the facts: It was the previous administration whose reckless policies and mismanagement led to the record budget deficits.  In my administration, that’s getting the deficit under control. <br> <br>In fact, I just released my budget this week, and it shows, going forward, we can cut the deficit by another $1 trillion over the next decade while still making prudent investments in economic growth, in climate, and other equitable economic decisions.  <br> <br>But to do that, we have to be willing to do something previous administrations and Republicans today refuse to do.  We need to make sure corporations and the super wealthy begin to pay their fair share. <br> <br>Here&#8217;s one example: Right now, billionaires &#8212; and there&#8217;s not a whole lot of them in the country; maybe I won&#8217;t give a number because I don&#8217;t know for sure.  They &#8212; they average less than 1 percent.  But my point is billionaires pay an average rate of only 8 percent on their total income.<br> <br>A family led by a firefighter and a teacher can pay double that income tax rate &#8212; double what a &#8212; what a billionaire pays; double the 8 percent. <br> <br>So my budget has a Billionaire Minimum Tax &#8212; a 20 percent minimum tax that applies only to the top one &#8212; one-hundredth of one &#8212; one-hundredth of 1 percent of American households. <br> <br>The Billionaire Minimum Tax is fair.  And here&#8217;s the deal: It raises $360 billion that can be used to lower costs for families and cut the deficit.  It would add &#8212; it would &#8212; and I would add, nobody making less than four &#8212; and you&#8217;re tired of hearing me say it, but no one making less than $400,000 a year will pay a single penny more in federal taxes.<br> <br>As I&#8217;ve said in the past, I&#8217;m a capitalist.  I have no problem with people making as much money as they are capable of making.  But I&#8217;m asking you one simple question: Just pay your fair share.  Pay your fair share.  That&#8217;s all.  That&#8217;s it.  Just your fair share.  <br> <br>And no one can argue that 20 percent for a billionaire is unfair.  <br> <br>Here&#8217;s what this adds up to: We&#8217;re going to continue to create jobs, bring down the cost for families, and rein in deficits left by my predecessor &#8212; all important steps in our pro- &#8212; to continue our historic progress to build a better America.  <br> <br>I said from the outset we&#8217;re the only country in the world that&#8217;s comes out of crises stronger than we went into them.  That’s what we’re doing here. <br> <br>I want to thank you all for showing up today.  And we&#8217;ll have plenty of time to answer questions about other items other than the &#8212; the jobs report next week.  Thank you.  Appreciate it.<br> <br>11:04 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Public Health Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/01/a-proclamation-on-national-public-health-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 16:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each year, National Public Health Week provides a chance for all of us to come together to restore and strengthen the public health of our Nation.  As we have seen so starkly over the past 2 years, public health is essential to every part of our National life &#8212; not only to the safety and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Each year, National Public Health Week provides a chance for all of us to come together to restore and strengthen the public health of our Nation.  As we have seen so starkly over the past 2 years, public health is essential to every part of our National life &#8212; not only to the safety and well-being of our families and communities but also to our prosperity.  This week, we celebrate the progress we have made to revitalize our public health, recommit ourselves to the work that still remains, and recognize all of the remarkable health care workers and public health professionals whose extraordinary sacrifice and courage on the front lines have carried our Nation through one of the most difficult periods in our history.<br><br>Thanks to our brave and dedicated public health and health care workforce, the resilience of the American people, and our comprehensive strategy to tackle COVID-19, our Nation is far better positioned today than we were a year ago.  Vaccines and boosters have been proven to offer the highest level of protection &#8212; and today, more than 250 million Americans have stepped up to protect themselves and their communities by getting at least one shot, saving more than a million American lives.  We are ready with millions of antiviral treatments that reduce your chance of ending up in the hospital by 90 percent.  We are continuing to vaccinate the world, having sent over half a billion vaccine doses to 114 countries with more to come. <br><br>My Administration has made hundreds of millions of tests available for Americans to order directly to their homes for free.  We have successfully reopened schools and businesses across the country, most Americans can now go safely mask-free, and together we are moving forward safely back to more normal routines.  We have positioned ourselves well to detect and prepare for new variants and have more tools to protect people than ever before &#8212; but making sure these tools are readily available requires additional funding from the Congress.  We urgently need the Congress to provide the funding we have requested to maintain our preparedness against COVID-19 and ensure the American people continue to have access to treatments, vaccines, and tests.  The consequences of inaction are severe and immediate, and they will only get more significant over time.<br><br>While COVID-19 remains a top public health priority, we are committed to a full range of efforts to improve the Nation&#8217;s general health, safety, and resilience.  Last year, through the American Rescue Plan and other actions, we expanded access to &#8212; and lowered the cost of &#8212; quality health care for millions of Americans.  In addition, we made new investments in mental health services; innovative health care technologies; our public health and health care workforce; and maternal, infant, and early childhood programs.  Through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we are also helping to address long-standing health inequities that have burdened communities of color and low-income neighborhoods for far too long.  Because of this law, we are beginning to replace poisonous lead pipes so that every child, in every home and school in America, finally has clean water to drink.  By making landmark investments in public transit and delivering high-speed internet to every single community in the country, we are also making health care and telehealth services more accessible to each and every family.<br><br>Of course, there is much more that we need to do to improve our public health and build a better America.  As we continue our fight to defeat the pandemic, we must also continue to expand health coverage and lower the cost of health care for every family &#8212; including the cost of prescription drugs like insulin.  We must make transformational investments in our climate resilience and continue to address dangerous environmental injustices that threaten public health and have hit communities of color the hardest.  We must take commonsense steps to address the public health epidemic of gun violence, which disproportionately impacts Black Americans.  We must come together to address the toll that the mental health epidemic takes on America&#8217;s children, deliver the physical and mental health care that our veterans and service members deserve, and make landmark investments to spark breakthroughs in our fight against cancer, Alzheimer&#8217;s, diabetes, and other diseases.<br><br>During National Public Health Week, we recommit ourselves to reaching these goals &#8212; to improve our public health and, in so doing, improve our safety and security, our economic strength, the equity and fairness of our Nation, and our quality of life.  Together, we share our appreciation to all those who safeguard the Nation&#8217;s public health through acts of service and those who seek to strengthen communities by fostering equitable opportunities for all.  My Administration encourages all Americans to do their part for public health &#8212; especially by getting vaccinated and receiving a booster shot, if eligible.  It takes all of us to preserve the health of our Nation, and together we are poised to make tremendous progress to build a better, stronger, and healthier America.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 4 through April 10, 2022, as National Public Health Week.  I call on all citizens, government agencies, private businesses, non-profit organizations, and other groups to take action to improve the health of our Nation.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on World Autism Awareness Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/01/a-proclamation-on-world-autism-awareness-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 16:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On World Autism Awareness Day, we reaffirm our commitment to ensuring that the more than 5 million Americans who live with autism are able to make the most of their talents and participate fully in our society, and we celebrate the contributions autistic Americans have made to our families, our communities, our Nation, and the world.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On World Autism Awareness Day, we reaffirm our commitment to ensuring that the more than 5 million Americans who live with autism are able to make the most of their talents and participate fully in our society, and we celebrate the contributions autistic Americans have made to our families, our communities, our Nation, and the world.<br><br>We have made significant progress in improving access to opportunity for people with developmental disabilities in recent years.  However, many autistic individuals still experience gaps in employment and income.  The COVID-19 pandemic has compounded these inequities, creating unique challenges and strains for people with autism and their families.<br><br>That is why my Administration is committed to addressing the systemic barriers people with autism face in their daily lives.  The pandemic upended school routines for children and students living with disabilities.  That is why the Department of Education is working tirelessly to accelerate pandemic recovery for special education programs.  In addition, the Department of Health and Human Services and the Department of Housing and Urban Development are committed to ensuring individuals with disabilities have access to affordable housing as we come through this pandemic.<br><br>In order to improve quality of life for people with autism and their families in every community, my Administration is committed to funding cutting-edge research to help us better understand, diagnose, and treat autism, including funding research at the National Institutes of Health and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention that seeks to better understand the underlying mechanisms of autism from childhood through early adulthood, improve methods of early identification and diagnosis, and develop innovations in the delivery of interventions and services.<br><br>My Administration remains committed to reducing barriers in access to early diagnoses, interventions, and services for people with autism &#8212; regardless of race, gender, ethnicity, culture, or geography &#8212; and to incorporating the lived experiences of individuals with autism into their research.  Last June, when I signed the Executive Order on Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility in the Federal Workforce, I promised to cultivate a Federal workforce that draws from the full diversity of the Nation.  One of the ways we are delivering on that promise is through a partnership between the Department of Labor and the Administration for Community Living, which is expanding access to competitive, integrated employment opportunities for people with disabilities, including autism.<br><br>In addition, my Administration will continue to build on the work done by the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee, the National Autism Coordinator, and others to make certain that autistic Americans have access to the care, services, and support they need, so they can pursue their educational, career, and life interests without discrimination.<br><br>Today and every day, we honor autistic people and celebrate the meaningful and measureless ways they contribute to our Nation.  We applaud the millions of educators, advocates, family members, caregivers, and others who support them.  As we continue to build a better America, we reaffirm our promise to provide Americans with autism the support they need to live independently, fully participate in their communities, and lead fulfilling lives of dignity and respect.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim April 2, 2022, as World Autism Awareness Day.  I call upon all Americans to learn more about autism to improve early diagnosis, to learn more about the experiences of autistic people from autistic people, and to build more welcoming and inclusive communities to support people with autism.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Addressing the Collective Challenges of our Time: Implementing the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote&#160;Stability</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/addressing-the-collective-challenges-of-our-time-implementing-the-u-s-strategy-to-prevent-conflict-and-promote-stability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50312</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every country, including our own, experiences risks and challenges related to stability and conflict.  The international community grapples with issues that cut across borders, societies, ways of life, and economies.  As the world has witnessed too often, the effects of conflict and instability are not constrained by borders or technologies.  Cooperation and long-term investments in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every country, including our own, experiences risks and challenges related to stability and conflict.  The international community grapples with issues that cut across borders, societies, ways of life, and economies.  As the world has witnessed too often, the effects of conflict and instability are not constrained by borders or technologies.  Cooperation and long-term investments in conflict prevention and stabilization are needed now more than ever to build peace across divided communities and boundaries.  We must collectively bolster societal resilience to prevent and reduce the heavy human and financial costs of conflicts that undermine global peace, security and sustainable development. <br> <br>On April 1, 2022, the Biden-Harris Administration launched the implementation of the <a href="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/2020-United-States-Strategy-to-Prevent-Conflict-and-Promote-Stability-2.pdf">U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability</a> with partner countries across the globe.  The Strategy outlines a ten-year, evidence-based, whole-of-government effort to foster peace and long-term stability through integrated U.S. diplomacy, development, and security-sector engagement with dual goals of strengthening national and regional peace, resilience and stability and enhancing the way our government operates in a variety of contexts.<br> <br>Through collective action and partnership, the United States seeks to advance the vision and goals of the landmark Global Fragility Act through this Strategy in four diverse countries and one sub-region facing a wide variety of challenges to peace and stability.  This Strategy advances U.S. national security and interests.  The work now underway represents an important milestone, and next step, in the implementation of the Global Fragility Act, which continues to enjoy strong support within the U.S. Congress and among civil society.  Through a spirit of partnership, we can and will build on strengths of communities, governments, and nations to rebound from shocks, confront negative global trends and create new paradigms for broader cooperation.  The Strategy and Prologue chart a new path toward positive results that strengthen democracy, rule of law, security, good governance, gender equity and equality, health, education, and respect for human rights all aligned to fuel reservoirs of peace, strength and recovery and extinguish potential discord before it is sparked.<br> <br>The United States will partner with Haiti, Libya, Mozambique, Papua New Guinea, and Coastal West Africa (Benin, Côte d’Ivoire, Ghana, Guinea, and Togo) guided by these principles:</p>



<ul><li>Work collaboratively with government and civic partners on an integrated approach to prevent conflict, promote resilience and stability, and advance economic development;<br></li><li>Look beyond urgent crises and near-term needs to focus on mutually determined strategic goals and interests through whole-of-government ten-year plans;<br></li><li>Utilize development, diplomacy, and security-sector means in a coordinated way to support the pursuit of goals, foster an enabling environment, and solidify progress;<br></li><li>Provide new tools and insights to strengthen democratic institutions, for example in the areas of rule of law, anti-corruption, law enforcement, and fiscal transparency, and to promote human rights and gender equity and equality;<br></li><li>Adapt to and learning from changing conditions, anchor efforts in local communities, and make strategic adjustments based on joint analyses, research, and monitoring and evaluation; and<br></li><li>Take a multifaceted approach to address other current and emerging challenges, such as the climate crisis, global pandemics and declining democratic practices.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>The U.S. Congress authorized up to $200 million a year for these efforts and appropriated $125 million in Fiscal Year 2022 for the Prevention and Stabilization Fund, which supplements existing bilateral U.S. assistance to these partner countries.&nbsp; This funding will support the development of ten-year implementation plans and related regional and multilateral activities.<br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration will closely monitor progress, milestones, and accomplishments under the Strategy.&nbsp; These efforts will endure across future U.S. Administrations and advance much needed innovative approaches to peace and stability.<br><br>Read the letter on the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/letter-from-the-president-on-the-implementation-of-the-global-fragility-act/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Global Fragility Act Implementation</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter from the President on the Implementation of the Global Fragility&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/letter-from-the-president-on-the-implementation-of-the-global-fragility-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The world stands today at the dawn of a decisive decade — a moment of consequence and peril, of profound pain and extraordinary possibility.&#160; Perhaps now more than ever, we have seen how the most urgent challenges of our time do not confine themselves within national borders.&#160; A global pandemic that has claimed more than&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The world stands today at the dawn of a decisive decade — a moment of consequence and peril, of profound pain and extraordinary possibility.&nbsp; Perhaps now more than ever, we have seen how the most urgent challenges of our time do not confine themselves within national borders.&nbsp; A global pandemic that has claimed more than six million lives.&nbsp; A climate crisis that threatens the future of every continent.&nbsp; An emboldening of autocrats who believe that democracy and multilateralism cannot deliver in the 21st century.&nbsp; These tests, and more, are among the sternest that the world has ever faced.</p>



<p>It is against this backdrop — at this inflection point in history — that America must lead.&nbsp; We know all too well that today’s most pressing challenges — their root causes as well as their impacts — are global in nature.&nbsp; We know that America’s security and success hinge in no small measure on the peace and stability of the world beyond our borders.&nbsp; We know that beneath the global crises we face lie breathtaking opportunities for our Nation and the world — if we can summon the will to seize them.</p>



<p>This document — a prologue to the U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability — represents an assertion of American leadership to take on the defining global challenges of our time.&nbsp; Driven in large part by the tireless commitment of humanitarian advocates and civil society organizations working on the front lines of conflict, this Strategy is the product of a bipartisan vision, manifested by the passage of the Global Fragility Act in December 2019 with overwhelming bipartisan majorities.&nbsp; It provides a roadmap:&nbsp; a 10-year effort to strengthen the security and prosperity of people everywhere by helping to fortify the footing of parts of the world that continue to grapple with challenges that can lead to destabilizing conflict and violence.&nbsp; It is, in short, an investment in global peace and security — one which will deliver critical returns not only in the nations with whom we’ll be working, but, most of all, here in the United States.</p>



<p>The heartbreaking images we are seeing in Ukraine — the result of a vicious and unprovoked attack by Vladimir Putin — are only the latest reminder of the tragic consequences of global conflict and the need to avert violence before it erupts.&nbsp; We know that working broadly, strategically, and cooperatively to prevent conflict and instability is the greatest investment we can make in America’s future, and in the future of the entire world.&nbsp; In Ukraine, as in Ethiopia, Syria, Yemen, and elsewhere around the world, the incalculable toll of lives lost, families separated, economies destroyed, and social fabrics torn threatens to spiral whole regions into cycles of violence and loss that can linger for generations.&nbsp; Doing all that we can to assist communities around the world in their conflict prevention efforts is more than just the right thing to do.&nbsp; It saves lives, safeguards Americans’ own security and prosperity, and establishes the United States as a trusted partner — a force for peace and stability in the world, and a nation that can be counted on to work and learn productively alongside the nations of every region to tackle common challenges and strengthen our shared future.</p>



<p>This Strategy lays out a whole-of-government approach to advancing America’s national interests on the world stage.&nbsp; This means tapping into the expansive expertise and resources that reside across our Government, sharpening and updating those tools where needed, humbly applying the costly and painful lessons from the past, and transforming the way we work with each other.&nbsp; Our diplomats, officers, and experts in the State Department, the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Defense, the Department of the Treasury, and others across Government, as well as members of the Foreign Service and Armed Forces, will work in close cooperation with multilateral organizations and a wide variety of local partners in each nation where these efforts will be pursued — including civil society organizations, community leaders, businesses, and government officials.&nbsp; Those who are closest and most vulnerable to these challenges know best where the opportunities for peace and stability lie — they represent the strongest source of promise and immunity from destabilizing forces, and we must support their strength and resilience.&nbsp; From strengthening social institutions and state-society relations, to mitigating the spread of extremist ideologies, to confronting the corrosive impact of gender inequality, to cultivating greater trust between security forces and citizens, to guarding against the destabilizing threat of climate change — we will help foster locally led, locally owned solutions grounded in mutual trust and long-term accountability.</p>



<p>Prevention is hard work — measured not in days and weeks, but in years and generations.&nbsp; Its successes are never as evident as its failures, and it requires us to remain focused on lasting peace and stability over the allure of easier, more temporary gains that may not strengthen our position in the long term.&nbsp; But, with this Strategy, we are committing ourselves to the effort.&nbsp; As we implement this Strategy, my Administration looks forward to working closely with the Congress on a bipartisan basis, and in close consultation with civil society institutions and stakeholders on every level.&nbsp; United in our vision, America can and must lead this essential new effort to interrupt potential pathways to conflict, alleviate threats before they escalate and arrive on our shores, and help safeguard the economy, health, and security of our Nation for generations to come.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Joseph R. Biden, Jr.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Roundtable on Mental Health with Young Women and Girl&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/31/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-on-mental-health-with-young-women-and-girl-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 23:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50306</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the last day of Women’s History Month,&#160;Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice&#160;and&#160;Gender Policy Council&#160;Director Jennifer Klein&#160;hosted a roundtable at the White House with&#160;young women leading&#160;their communities&#160;in&#160;improving&#160;mental health.&#160;Participants&#160;were joined by the&#160;leadership&#160;of national&#160;girl’s&#160;advocacy organizations, each&#160;of&#160;which have prioritized mental health policy and supported young women leaders&#160;tackling&#160;this&#160;issue. With&#160;studies continuing to highlight the toll that the COVID-19 pandemic has taken&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On the last day of Women’s History Month,&nbsp;Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice&nbsp;and&nbsp;Gender Policy Council&nbsp;Director Jennifer Klein&nbsp;hosted a roundtable at the White House with&nbsp;young women leading&nbsp;their communities&nbsp;in&nbsp;improving&nbsp;mental health.&nbsp;Participants&nbsp;were joined by the&nbsp;leadership&nbsp;of national&nbsp;girl’s&nbsp;advocacy organizations, each&nbsp;of&nbsp;which have prioritized mental health policy and supported young women leaders&nbsp;tackling&nbsp;this&nbsp;issue.</p>



<p>With&nbsp;studies continuing to highlight the toll that the COVID-19 pandemic has taken on youth mental health, participants&nbsp;shared&nbsp;their experiences and&nbsp;insight into the unique&nbsp;mental health&nbsp;challenges that women and girls face.&nbsp;The young women leaders also&nbsp;shared policy recommendations for&nbsp;strengthening mental health for girls, including&nbsp;the&nbsp;need to meet girls where they areand&nbsp;the importance&nbsp;of&nbsp;reducing stigma and other&nbsp;barriers that make it difficult for young women and girls to access mental health services.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Senior White House officials&nbsp;reinforced the Administration’s commitment to addressing our mental health crisis,&nbsp;a core&nbsp;pillar of the Unity Agenda that&nbsp;President&nbsp;Biden outlined in his&nbsp;State of the Union Address. This&nbsp;commitment includes:&nbsp;increasing&nbsp;the size and diversity of the mental health workforce;&nbsp;expandingcoverage and reducing costs for mental health services;&nbsp;and&nbsp;integrating&nbsp;mental health&nbsp;care and services across settings, from schools&nbsp;to community centers.&nbsp;&nbsp;Senior White House officials emphasized that&nbsp;the President’s FY23 budget&nbsp;proposes&nbsp;a historic$829&nbsp;million&nbsp;to strengthen and advance youth mental health.&nbsp;They&nbsp;also&nbsp;discussed the Administration’s work to address the mental health impacts of social media,&nbsp;including addressing the intersection of online harassment and abuse and gender-based violence, a commitment that is part of the first-ever&nbsp;U.S. government&nbsp;National Gender Strategy&nbsp;released by the Biden-Harris Administration last fall. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Young women leaders that participated&nbsp;in today’s roundtable include:•&nbsp;Belen Buckley,&nbsp;Youth Advisor, Georgetown&nbsp;Law&nbsp;Center on Poverty and Inequality; California<br>•&nbsp;Enshalla Dunlop, National Agenda for Black Girls (NABG)&nbsp;Advisor, Girls for Gender Equity;&nbsp;New York<br>•&nbsp;Marley Dias, Author and Literary Activist; New Jersey<br>•&nbsp;Elmirah Marcus Garcia, Youth Advocate,&nbsp;National Crittenton; New Mexico<br>•&nbsp;Kiran Kadiyala,&nbsp;Girls Inc. National Teen Advocacy Council Alumna; Florida<br>•&nbsp;Ava Macomber,&nbsp;Youth Leader,&nbsp;Girl Scouts of the USA; District of Columbia&nbsp;<br>•&nbsp;Mahogany Morris, Health and Education Intern, Justice for Black Girls Community Organization; New York<br>•&nbsp;Delgracia Sainvil, Young Women’s Advisory Council Member, Girls for Gender Equity;&nbsp;New York</p>



<p>The following organization leaders also joined for the roundtable:•&nbsp;Lisette Engel,&nbsp;Vice President for Policy and Systems Change, National Crittenton<br>•&nbsp;Rebecca Epstein,&nbsp;Executive Director, Georgetown Law Center on Poverty and Inequality&nbsp;<br>•&nbsp;Stephanie Hull,&nbsp;President and CEO, Girls Inc.<br>•&nbsp;Margaret Mitchell,&nbsp;President and CEO, YWCA<br>•&nbsp;Monique Morris,&nbsp;President and CEO, Grantmakers for Girls of Color<br>•&nbsp;Sue Santa, Senior Vice President&nbsp;for&nbsp;Public Policy &amp; Advocacy, Girl Scouts of the USA<br>•&nbsp;Joanne Smith,&nbsp;President and CEO, Girls for Gender Equity</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
