<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 16:13:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Global Health Worker&#160;Initiative</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-global-health-worker-initiative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 16:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This pandemic has spotlighted the critical role and bravery of health and care workers. That’s why I’ve asked my Administration to develop a global health workforce plan, to accelerate our contributions to the Sustainable Development Agenda and investments in health and care workers. President Joseph R. Biden, April 7, 2022 Strategic and sustained investments in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>This pandemic has spotlighted the critical role and bravery of health and care workers. That’s why I’ve asked my Administration to develop a global health workforce plan, to accelerate our contributions to the Sustainable Development Agenda and investments in health and care workers.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>President Joseph R. Biden, April 7, 2022</em></p>



<p>Strategic and sustained investments in the global health workforce are key to catalyzing the U.S. Government’s efforts to achieve the 2030 Sustainable Development Agenda. The COVID-19 pandemic has further exacerbated the estimated global shortage of 18 million health workers by 2030.  With growing health demands from new and emerging pathogens, aging populations, climate shocks, and increasing conflict and migration, the ever-increasing demand for health workers needs greater coordinated attention and action. A comprehensive, trained, protected, well-equipped, and supported workforce is foundational to expanding equitable access to public health services and health care across the globe.  Investments in health workers not only improve health outcomes, they create jobs and career pathways and economic development by strengthening human capital as part of the care economy.  Funding advancements for the health workforce will accelerate ending the COVID-19 pandemic, stimulate economic recovery, and support critical components of President Biden’s values-driven global infrastructure initiative announced at the 2021 G7 Summit by strengthening global health systems, expanding national and regional capacity, including manufacturing of essential medical products.  These investments will also build on commitments made by global partners at the 2nd Global COVID-19 Summit co-hosted by the United States to accelerate combatting COVID-19 and advancing future preparedness.<br><br>Currently, U.S. Government programs such as the U.S. President&#8217;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR), the U.S. President’s Malaria Initiative (PMI), and U.S. bilateral global health security partnerships in support of the Global Health Security Agenda, contribute approximately $1.56 billion annually to support the health workforce across the globe. Further, the President’s Fiscal Year (FY) 2023 Budget prioritizes advancing investments across health programs to strengthen health systems and the global health workforce and support. Notably, the President’s Budget includes an additional $1 billion for this new Global Health Worker Initiative to support and protect the global health workforce as part of the Administration’s increased prioritization and investments in health workforce. This funding, if provided by Congress, would be directed through the U.S. Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and coordinated with others in the U.S. government. <br><br>The Global Health Worker Initiative expands and defines &#8220;health workers&#8221; broadly to include a multidisciplinary workforce including clinicians, community health and care workers, and public health professionals. It provides a framework to guide and organize the U.S. Government’s investments and strengthen coordination with key partners including G7 and G20 countries, multilateral and regional organizations, and the private sector. While global in focus, this effort complements President Biden’s efforts to support the domestic health workforce.<br><br>From the beginning of the Biden-Harris Administration, the United States has demonstrated renewed leadership in global health through action and smart, targeted investments. The United States will continue to advance global health priorities and build upon existing efforts aligned to the following four pillars of focus under the Global Health Worker Initiative:<br><br><strong>PROTECTING HEALTH WORKERS</strong><br><br>Through global health programs, the U.S Government will advance work to ensure health workers across facilities and communities have prioritized access to vaccinations [and treatment], personal protective equipment (PPE), and services to support their physical and mental health and well-being and better protection and safeguards from violence and attacks on health facilities, including in conflict and humanitarian settings.   </p>



<ul><li><strong>Accelerate coordinated efforts to protect health workers fighting COVID-19.</strong>&nbsp;The COVID-19 Global Action Plan (GAP), announced by Secretary Blinken on February 14, 2022, has six lines of effort to help end the acute phase of the pandemic, including a dedicated effort specifically to support health workers. The GAP aims to galvanize partner countries and international organizations to decrease risks posed by COVID-19 by increasing vaccine and treatment availability, encouraging vaccine uptake, addressing workplace safety, and health worker training.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Provide tools and resources for health workers responding to COVID-19 while ensuring delivery of primary health services.</strong>&nbsp;Ongoing U.S. Government programming is adapting to account for the pandemic. For example, PMI trains health workers to efficiently and effectively diagnose and treat malaria in the context of COVID-19, including educating patients to avoid risk of transmission and where to access COVID-19 and malaria treatment services.&nbsp;&nbsp;PEPFAR-funded health workers have ensured delivery of essential HIV prevention and treatment services while responding to the pandemic, by leveraging over 100,000 health workers to support COVID-19 needs across more than 40 countries. PEPFAR is also focused on reducing the risk of health worker burnout and longer-term mental health effects by providing support, including time off for self-care, recuperation, and family’s needs; and advancing access to mental health services. Additionally, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), at the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), is working to improve local and regional healthcare personnel safety and infection prevention and control in more than 15 countries across four continents. These efforts involve healthcare worker surveillance to quickly detect infections; facility-based comprehensive safety assessments and quality improvement initiatives; infectious disease detection and response; training, supervision, and regional communities of practice; and technical engagement with Ministries of Health to ensure implementation consistent with global norms.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Supporting health workers in conflict settings.</strong>&nbsp;In Ukraine, USAID is supporting the Ministry of Health and National Health Service of Ukraine to develop an incentive system to attract, retain, and equitably distribute health care workers in war-impacted regions, using both financial and non-financial incentives so that local authorities will be better able to hire health care workers to fill critical shortages.&nbsp;&nbsp;To address the significant mental health strains of COVID-19 and the subsequent Russian invasion, USAID is also supporting the scale-up of mental health counseling services for conflict-affected populations, including health workers.</li></ul>



<p><strong><br>EXPAND THE GLOBAL HEALTH WORKFORCE AND ACCELERATE ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT</strong><br><br>The U.S Government will continue efforts to create career pathways and expand paid employment opportunities for a more diverse and gender equitable workforce in the public and private health sectors, better equipping healthcare and community health workers, to meet local population health needs including provision of patient-centered services at the primary health care level. These efforts will further build local and regional institutional capacity to manage and support a global health workforce that is adequately prepared and aligned to respond to routine and emergency surge capacity needs.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Promote fair and timely pay for all health workers.</strong>&nbsp;Through our global health programs, including PEPFAR and PMI, we will continue to promote fair and timely compensation for health workers.&nbsp;&nbsp;PEPFAR will continue to align its financial support for over 330,000 health workers, a $1 billion annual investment, helping achieve HIV epidemic control in over 40 countries. Similarly, PMI recently updated their policies to allow the use of PMI funds to provide salaries or stipends to community health workers in settings where payment to them is in line with government policy.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Develop a multidisciplinary Global Health Security workforce.</strong>&nbsp;Achieving global health security requires a multi-sectoral approach that incorporates an understanding of the linkages among human, animal, and environmental health– a “One Health” approach. As part of the U.S. Government’s Global Health Security programs, USAID is investing up to $85 million over five years to create a “next generation” health workforce. In 2021, USAID worked with more than 110 universities in 17 countries across Africa and Southeast Asia to train more than 18,000 current and future health workers for more effective disease surveillance and control. CDC has partnered with five leading international organizations to develop the Global Laboratory Leadership Programme (GLLP).&nbsp;&nbsp;The GLLP is a comprehensive One Health-based training program for human and animal health laboratories. The GLLP is currently implemented in over 20 countries in the Americas, Africa, Asia, and the Middle East. In addition, the CDC Field Epidemiology Training Program (FETP) is recognized worldwide as an effective means to strengthen countries’ capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to public health threats through enhanced surveillance, epidemiology, and outbreak response functions. CDC works with partner countries to establish FETPs and to train epidemiologists across all levels of a country’s health system. To date, FETP has been implemented in more than 80 countries around the globe with more than 20,000 graduates with many FETP graduates becoming leaders and managers in&nbsp;&nbsp;Ministries of Health or national public health institutes.&nbsp;&nbsp;These activities accelerate progress of the United States Global Health Security Strategy, and will continue to help our partners build country-level capacities in line with their World Health Organization&nbsp;&nbsp;Joint External Evaluations, National Action Plans for Health Security, and other tools the strengthen compliance with the International Health Regulations (IHR 2005).<br></li><li><strong>Collaborate with local partners and country governments to build a sustainable health workforce.</strong>&nbsp;As part of localization efforts, USAID is advancing work with local partners to strengthen human resources planning, management, and oversight to overcome health worker shortfalls. Increasing direct partnerships with host country government entities is essential to improving sustainability of health systems. For example, USAID, through a $10 million Government-to-Government (G2G) investment, is working with the Government of Malawi to fill critical health workforce financing gaps and strengthen health systems.&nbsp;&nbsp;Part of the Malawi G2G programming agreement includes a phased transition of these health workforces to Malawi Government financing, with immediate provision of critical health services while building systems to sustain those health workers beyond USAID funding.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Optimize the health workers to support global COVID-19 vaccination efforts.</strong>&nbsp;The Initiative for Global Vaccine Access (Global VAX), a whole-of-government effort to turn vaccines in vials into vaccinations in arms around the world, builds on existing U.S. Government efforts with total cumulative commitments of more than $1.7 billion, helping over 100 countries prepare to receive and administer COVID-19 vaccines with surge funding and support to 11 countries (Angola, Côte d’Ivoire, Eswatini, Ghana, Lesotho, Nigeria, Senegal, South Africa, Tanzania, Uganda and Zambia). Through Global VAX, the U.S. Government is providing financial and technical assistance to engage and train additional health workers for vaccination efforts, including vaccine delivery, community engagement, record keeping, local micro-planning, and cold chain maintenance.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>ADVANCE EQUITY AND INCLUSION</strong><br><br>President Biden’s commitment to advancing equity and inclusion goes beyond our borders. The U.S Government will carry forward his commitment globally to address numerous barriers, including gender, ethnic/racial, geographic, age, and others, particularly among the community health workforce, to build a more diverse cohort of health worker graduates and leaders that reflects inclusivity, is better-equipped to serve local populations and provide patient-centered care including at the primary health care level.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Addressing the gender gap.</strong>&nbsp;Recognizing that women represent 70 percent of the global health workforce, the U.S. Government is increasing waged employment opportunities and leadership opportunities for women in the health workforce in alignment with the U.S. Government’s first-ever National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality with commitment to advance the full participation of all people- including women and girls- in the United States and around the world,&nbsp;&nbsp;focus on building the global care economy and care infrastructure, and improve economic security and accelerate economic growth. This includes USAID’s development of recruitment strategies for employment of at-risk, vulnerable youth and women; partnership with the private sector; and supporting the professionalization of community health workers.&nbsp;&nbsp;PEPFAR has invested more than $1.3 billion supporting nearly 2.5 million adolescent girls and young women through the Determined, Resilient, Empowered, AIDS-free, Mentored and Safe (DREAMS) program in the last five years. The partnership supports adolescent girls and young women with socioeconomic opportunities, including employment in the health sector, as part of efforts aimed at reducing rates of HIV among adolescent girls and young women in the highest HIV burden countries.<br></li><li><strong>Health workers reflect the populations they serve</strong>. It is critical that countries recruit and retain a diverse health workforce to help meet the needs of those populations.&nbsp;&nbsp;PEPFAR has partnered with Historically Black Colleges and Universities through Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), at HHS, to provide opportunities for adolescent girls and young women, who are at high risk for early sexual debut and HIV, to receive training as community health workers and be employed to provide essential health services to their home communities in areas where there are critical shortages of health care workers. This work has started in Malawi.<br></li><li><strong>Diversifying the global health research workforce.</strong>&nbsp;The National Institutes of Health (NIH), part of HHS, is the largest funder of health research in the world, and is building an inclusive, diverse, and global scientific workforce conducting research in Federal government laboratories. In addition, the NIH Fogarty International Center (FIC) has an exclusive international mission and responsibility for foreign research coordination that includes a focus on building research capacity in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) by providing training and research support through a variety of programs to address emerging global health needs. Much of FIC’s resources are dedicated to building research capacity in LMICs.&nbsp;&nbsp;Since 1989, more than 7,500 individuals from over 130 countries have trained through FIC programs.<br></li><li><strong>Reaching rural and remote populations</strong>. Across the globe, Peace Corps staff and Volunteers continue to work alongside existing health service providers and community health workers in difficult to reach rural and “last mile” communities and provide training of health workers to support vaccination, community engagement, disease prevention measures, surveillance activities, referral facilitation, and social and behavioral change to promote delivery of improved quality health services delivery.<br></li></ul>



<p><strong>DRIVE AND INVEST IN TECHNOLOGICAL ADVANCEMENTS AND INNOVATION</strong><br><br>The U.S Government will further harness innovation and expand digital technologies that equip health workers with the ability to provide more efficient, quality-integrated service delivery, including telehealth services that can extend the reach of health services from facilities and into communities, including the most marginalized populations. The use of digital platforms will be expanded to improve the availability and routine use of quality health workforce data to inform decisions about workforce planning and operations, including performance management and consistent remuneration, and also expand the use of digital tools.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Digital health as a tool to advance primary health care.</strong>&nbsp;USAID’s Vision for Action in Digital Health and Vision for Health System Strengthening 2030 together lay out a plan for how USAID can increase the responsible use of digital technologies to accelerate programming in the health sector in strategic coordination with partner countries. USAID is investing in integrated digital platforms to advance patient-centered care and support front-line health workers. Current investments include working to advance broad-based functionality and guide improvement of standardized digital health tools and systems used to support health workers in providing a set of essential patient-centered primary health care services.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Digital systems provide real time data to health workers.&nbsp;</strong>PMI supports digital tools in partner countries to equip health workers with real-time data. PMI improves evidence-based decision making by strengthening data collection, management, analysis, and utilization at all levels of the health care delivery system. PMI has invested $8.5 million in Rwanda, Senegal, and Burkina Faso to strengthen integrated and equitable care by equipping community health workers with tools needed to be better-connected to other health workers, bring care to unreached populations, and improve access to near real-time data.<br></li><li><strong>Technology to support data for decision making.&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;PEPFAR invests nearly $22 million annually to support the development and use of human resource information systems and digital health platforms. These investments provide data for better understanding of the available health workforce and health worker utilization and an additional modality to ensure continuity of safe provision of services. These investments proved invaluable during the COVID-19 pandemic with the employment of modified service delivery models including telehealth service.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Nominates Bipartisan Slate for the United&#160;States Sentencing&#160;Commission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/president-biden-nominates-bipartisan-slate-for-the-united-states-sentencing-commission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 14:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is announcing seven experienced and qualified nominees for the U.S. Sentencing Commission, a bipartisan independent agency created during the Reagan Administration.&#160; The Commission was created to reduce sentencing disparities and promote transparency and proportionality in criminal sentencing. The Commission has lacked a quorum since 2019, which has prevented it from doing critical business.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is announcing seven experienced and qualified nominees for the U.S. Sentencing Commission, a bipartisan independent agency created during the Reagan Administration.&nbsp; The Commission was created to reduce sentencing disparities and promote transparency and proportionality in criminal sentencing.</p>



<p>The Commission has lacked a quorum since 2019, which has prevented it from doing critical business. &nbsp;Today, President Biden is pleased to announce the nominations of these individuals – a bipartisan slate including the first Black chair of the organization – whose confirmations would allow the Commission to conduct its important work.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge Carlton W. Reeves</u></strong><strong><u>: Nominee for Commissioner and Chair of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Carlton W. Reeves&nbsp;has served as a United States District Court Judge for the Southern District of Mississippi since 2010. Judge Reeves was previously a partner at Pigott Reeves Johnson &amp; Minor, P.A. from 2001 to 2010. From 1995 to 2001, Judge Reeves served as Chief of the Civil Division for the United States Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of Mississippi. From 1991 to 1995, Judge Reeves was an associate at Phelps Dunbar LLP. In 1991, Judge Reeves was a staff attorney for the Supreme Court of Mississippi. Judge Reeves served as a law clerk for Justice&nbsp;Reuben V. Anderson on the Mississippi Supreme Court&nbsp;from 1989 to 1990.</p>



<p>Judge Reeves received his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1989 and his B.A.&nbsp;from&nbsp;Jackson State University&nbsp;in 1986.</p>



<p><strong><u>Laura Mate: Nominee for Commissioner and Vice Chair of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Laura Mate has served as the Director of Sentencing Resource Counsel, a project of the Federal Public and Community Defenders in the Office of the Federal Public Defender for the District of Arizona, since 2021 and from 2010 to 2021 was a member of Sentencing Resource Counsel. From 2001 to 2010, Ms. Mate served in the Office of the Federal Public Defender for the Western District of Washington in various roles, including as Assistant Federal Public Defender. Ms. Mate was an associate at Perkins Coie LLP from 1998 to 2001.</p>



<p>Ms. Mate received her J.D. from the University of Michigan Law School in 1998 and her B.A. from Kenyon College in 1992.</p>



<p><strong><u>Claire McCusker Murray: Nominee for Commissioner and Vice Chair of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Claire McCusker Murray served as the Principal Deputy Associate Attorney General of the United States Department of Justice from 2019 to 2021. She also served as Acting Associate Attorney General in 2021 and as Counselor to the Attorney General in 2019. From 2017 to 2019, Ms. Murray served in the White House Counsel’s Office as Special Assistant and Associate Counsel to the President. From 2013 to 2017, Ms. Murray worked at Kirkland &amp; Ellis as an associate until she was elevated to partner in 2015. From 2010 to 2012, Ms. Murray served as a trial attorney in the Criminal Division of the United States&nbsp;Department of Justice as part of the Attorney General’s Honors Program and as a Special Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Virginia in 2011.&nbsp;She served as a law clerk for Justice Samuel Alito on the Supreme Court of the United States from 2012 to 2013 and for then-Judge Brett Kavanaugh on the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit from 2009 to 2010.</p>



<p>Ms. Murray received her J.D. from Yale Law School in 2009 and her A.B.,&nbsp;<em>magna cum laude</em>, from Harvard College in 2004. She also received an M.Phil. from the University of Cambridge in 2008 and a d.e.a. from l’Ecole des Hautes Etudes en Sciences Sociales in Paris in 2005.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge Luis Felipe Restrepo: Nominee for Commissioner and Vice Chair of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Luis Felipe Restrepo has served as a&nbsp;United States Court of Appeals Judge for&nbsp;the Third Circuit since 2016. Judge Restrepo previously served as a United States District Court Judge for the&nbsp;Eastern District of Pennsylvania&nbsp;from 2013 to 2016. Judge Restrepo served as a&nbsp;United States Magistrate Judge&nbsp;for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania from 2006 to 2013. Judge Restrepo was a partner at Krasner &amp; Restrepo from 1993 to 2006.&nbsp;From 1990 to 1993, he served as an Assistant Federal Defender in the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, and from 1987 to 1990 as an Assistant Defender with the&nbsp;Defender Association of Philadelphia.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Judge Restrepo received his&nbsp;J.D.&nbsp;from Tulane Law School&nbsp;in 1986&nbsp;and his B.A from the&nbsp;University of Pennsylvania in 1981.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge Claria Horn Boom: Nominee for Commissioner of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Claria Horn Boom has served as a&nbsp;United States District Court Judge for the Eastern and Western Districts of Kentucky since 2018. Judge Boom was previously a partner at&nbsp;Frost Brown Todd LLC. Judge Boom served as an&nbsp;Assistant United States Attorney for the United States Attorney’s Office in the Eastern District of Kentucky from 2001 to 2002 and for the Western District of Kentucky from 1998 to 2001. From 1995 to 1998, Judge Boom was as an associate at King &amp; SpaldingLLP.&nbsp;Judge Boom served as a law clerk for Judge&nbsp;Pierce Lively&nbsp;on the&nbsp;United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit&nbsp;from 1994 to 1995.</p>



<p>Judge Boom received her&nbsp;J.D.&nbsp;from Vanderbilt University Law Schooland her B.A.&nbsp;from&nbsp;Transylvania University,&nbsp;<em>summa cum laude</em>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge John Gleeson: Nominee for Commissioner of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge John Gleeson is a partner at Debevoise and Plimpton LLP in New York, where he has practiced since 2016. From 1994 to 2016 Judge Gleeson served as a United States District Court Judge for the Eastern District of New York. From 1985 to 1994, Judge Gleeson served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of New York. Judge Gleeson served as a law clerk for Judge Boyce Martin on the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit.</p>



<p>Judge Gleeson received his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1980 and his B.A. from Georgetown University in 1975.</p>



<p><strong><u>Candice C. Wong: Nominee for Commissioner of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Candice C. Wong serves as an Assistant United States Attorney and Chief of the Violence Reduction and Trafficking Offenses Section in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia. Ms. Wong joined the United States Attorney’s Office in 2015, and from 2017 to 2021, was detailed to the Criminal Division of the United States Department of Justice. There, she served in various roles, including as Acting Deputy Assistant Attorney General and Acting Chief of Staff in the Criminal Division. From 2020 to 2021, Ms. Wong also served as the Department of Justice’s ex officio member on the United States Sentencing Commission. Ms. Wong was previously an associate at Bancroft PLLC from 2013 to 2015 and at King &amp; Spalding LLP from 2009 to 2011. Ms. Wong served as a law clerk for Justice Sandra Day O’Connor and Justice Sonia M. Sotomayor on the Supreme Court of the United States from 2011 to 2012, and for then-Judge Brett M. Kavanaugh on the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit from 2008 to 2009.</p>



<p>Ms. Wong received her J.D. in 2008 from Harvard Law School and her A.B. in 2004 from Harvard College.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Biden on Consumer Price Index&#160;in April</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/statement-by-president-biden-on-consumer-price-index-in-april/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 14:03:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While it is heartening to see that annual inflation moderated in April, the fact remains that inflation is unacceptably high.&#160;As I said yesterday, inflation is a challenge for families across the country and bringing it down is my top economic priority.&#160; This starts with the Federal Reserve, which plays a primary role in fighting inflation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>While it is heartening to see that annual inflation moderated in April, the fact remains that inflation is unacceptably high.&nbsp;As I said yesterday, inflation is a challenge for families across the country and bringing it down is my top economic priority.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This starts with the Federal Reserve, which plays a primary role in fighting inflation in our country. I thank the Senate for confirming Dr. Lisa Cook to the Board of Governors last night, and urge the Senate to confirm my remaining nominees without delay. While I will never interfere with the Fed’s independence, I believe we have built a strong economy and a strong labor market, and I agree with what Chairman Powell said last week that the number one threat to that strength – is inflation. I am confident the Fed will do its job with that in mind. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond the Fed, my inflation plan is focused on lowering the costs that families face and lowering the federal deficit. Already this week, my Administration has announced new steps in partnership with the private sector to lower the price of high speed internet for tens of millions of Americans. And, the Congressional Budget Office reported that the federal budget deficit in the first seven months of this fiscal year fell by $1.5 trillion—putting us on track for the most deficit reduction in any year on record. The CBO also confirmed that the budget deficit so far this year is lower than it was during the same period in 2019, before the pandemic began. &nbsp;Today, I am traveling to Illinois to speak with farmers about more we can do to lower their costs and help them&nbsp;produce more, lowering the price of food for Americans and around the world. All of this is progress, but the&nbsp;fight against global supply chain issues related to the pandemic and Putin’s price hike will continue every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congressional Republicans talk about inflation, but their only plan is to raise taxes on working families, taking even more money out of their pockets.&nbsp; If they are serious about inflation, they should send me the bipartisan innovation bill to bolster our supply chains and make more in America, along with legislation that cuts costs and the cuts the deficit, reducing families’ prescription drug and utility bills and restoring fairness to our tax code. We’ve made enormous progress in getting our economy back on track, and these measures would help us sustain this progress and bring prices down for families.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Private Sector Steps Up on Cancer Moonshot Call to Action on Cancer&#160;Screening</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-private-sector-steps-up-on-cancer-moonshot-call-to-action-on-cancer-screening/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52930</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The White House announces private sector commitments in response to the call to action from President Biden and First Lady Jill Biden on cancer screening. These new actions and collaborations mark progress toward the Cancer Moonshot goal to decrease the death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent over the next 25 years.  Just&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The White House announces private sector commitments in response to the call to action from President Biden and First Lady Jill Biden on cancer screening. These new actions and collaborations mark progress toward the Cancer Moonshot goal to decrease the death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent over the next 25 years. </em></p>



<p>Just under 100 days ago, President Biden reignited the Cancer Moonshot with renewed White House leadership and new ambitious goals: to reduce the death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent over the next 25 years, and improve the experience of people and their families living with and surviving cancer – and, by doing this and more, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/fact-sheet-president-biden-reignites-cancer-moonshot-to-end-cancer-as-we-know-it/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">end cancer as we know it today</a>.</p>



<p>In March, in his first State of the Union Address, President Biden highlighted the Cancer Moonshot as part of his Unity Agenda for the nation. The White House convened the Cancer Cabinet to establish a prioritized agenda across government including the development of new interagency programs and collaborations and announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2022/03/17/fact-sheet-white-house-announces-initial-steps-for-reignited-cancer-moonshot/">initial steps for the Cancer Moonshot</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last week, Cancer Cabinet agencies and departments hosted a virtual series of 10 roundtable discussions,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cancermoonshot/events-and-webinars/past-events/">Cancer Moonshot Community Conversations</a>, to inform and advance Cancer Moonshot priorities and the White House released a new webpage featuring the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/cancermoonshot/yourstories/">stories of people</a>&nbsp;living with cancer, survivors, and caregivers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, leaders from the patient and caregiver community, foundations, non-profits, companies, health care providers, and others will come together at the White House and virtually to strategize how we can each act to make progress on the seven pillars of how we know cancer today. The goal is to identify impactful steps to: (1) improve cancer screening; (2) enhance prevention; (3) address inequities; (4) target effective treatments to patients; (5) develop approaches for deadly and rare cancers, including childhood cancers; (6) support patients, survivors, and caregivers; and (7) learn more from people living with cancer.</p>



<p>As part of the reignited Cancer Moonshot, the President and First Lady announced a call to action on cancer screening to jumpstart progress on the nearly 10 million screenings in the United States that were missed as a result of the pandemic, and to work to ensure that all Americans equitably benefit from the tools we have to prevent, detect, and diagnose cancer. The following announcements comprise an initial response to that call to action.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, this includes efforts to reduce disparities in access to cancer screening by bringing: high-quality care to New York City’s Harlem, Washington, DC, and three other cities; mobile lung cancer screening to communities in Appalachia and rural parts of Tennessee, Georgia, and Alabama; support from screening through care to women in South Florida; and bilingual navigation services to reach Latinas in Baltimore and Washington, DC. These commitments also include business leaders around Columbus, Ohio committing to support employees with the time and resources needed to get their recommended cancer screenings and national efforts that will reach communities from coast to coast with knowledge, support, and access to cancer early detection.</p>



<p>To add your story, ideas, or new actions and collaborations, engage with us at: whitehouse.gov/cancermoonshot.</p>



<p><strong><u>Private sector actions in response to cancer screening call to action:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Bringing Cancer Screening to More Communities&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>The Association of Community Cancer Centers (ACCC) and AstraZeneca Join Efforts to Create the “Rural Appalachian Lung Cancer Screening Initiative.”</strong>&nbsp;The ACCC and AstraZeneca are launching a new partnership to develop and implement person-centered and sustainable approaches to increase lung cancer screening in rural America through the “Rural Appalachian Lung Cancer Screening Initiative.”&nbsp;As part of an initial $1.3 million investment, the Initiative will collect best practices and develop screening resources that will be shared with ACCC pilot sites with the potential to engage up to 30 percent more eligible individuals in the first five years.&nbsp;Upon project completion, data will be shared with all 2,100 ACCC cancer programs and practices nationwide.&nbsp;The United States has made great strides in reducing lung cancer incidence and mortality over the last five years. In Appalachia, however, driven, in part, by increased rates of tobacco use, cancer mortality is 10 percent higher than the national rate and, for rural Appalachian counties, cancer mortality is 15 percent higher than the region’s metro counties.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>ACCC will build on its portfolio of resources and tools for health care providers, including “Fostering Excellence in Care and Outcomes in Patients with Stage III and IV NSCLC,” &#8220;Improving Care Coordination: A Model for Lung Cancer Patients on Medicaid,” and “Understanding &amp; Improving Lung Cancer Treatment in Asian Americans &amp; Pacific Islanders in the Community Setting.” AstraZeneca convened the Lung Ambition Alliance (LAA) in 2019 with key partners, and is focused on accelerating advances in lung cancer survival and improving patient outcomes, with the goal of eliminating lung cancer as a cause of death. The LAA’s initial goal is to double the five-year survival rate for lung cancer.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Nonprofits Family Reach and Nueva Vida Collaborate to Provide Community Navigation and Financial Support for Latinas Facing Breast Cancer:</strong>&nbsp;Nueva Vida, a support network for Latinas with &#8212; or at risk of &#8212; cancer, is partnering with Family Reach, a national nonprofit removing financial barriers to cancer treatment, to provide continuous support to 800 additional Latinas in the Washington, D.C. and Baltimore metro areas during breast cancer screening and treatment. Latinas face unique and increasing challenges accessing and adhering to breast cancer screening and treatment due to psychosocial, logistical, financial, and systemic barriers.&nbsp;<br><br>Nueva Vida addresses the unmet needs of Latinas through free culturally-competent services. Bilingual/bicultural patient navigators attend appointments to ensure timely delivery of diagnostic and treatment services, provide language and clinical interpretation, and facilitate financial support for medications and basic needs. Their Navigators build trusting, long-term relationships with clients to ensure critical needs are met and that patients can effectively plan for and adhere to treatment.&nbsp;<br><br>Family Reach offers comprehensive financial services that reduce patients’ financial distress and improve access to care during treatment, regardless of immigration status. Nueva Vida’s Navigators will leverage Family Reach’s Financial Treatment Program to deliver financial tools that meet the unique needs of each family, ensuring they can both stay on treatment and keep their families housed and fed.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>GO2 Foundation for Lung Cancer Expands Mobile Screening to At-Risk Communities</strong>: The GO2 Foundation for Lung Cancer, in partnership with Catholic Health Initiatives Memorial, Chattanooga, Tennessee, a GO2&nbsp;Foundation for Lung Cancer Center of Excellence (COE), and with support from AstraZeneca, Bristol Myers Squibb, Merck, and a private funder, is bringing lung cancer screenings to at-risk, rural residents across southeast Tennessee and northern Georgia. The Breathe Easy mobile screening program currently provides more than 1,000 lung cancer screenings annually, primarily to those who are uninsured and those with public insurance. Expansion of the Breathe Easy program will extend mobile lung cancer screening further south in Georgia and into Alabama where, in part, due to higher than the national average rates of tobacco use, there are over 20,000 individuals at risk for lung cancer and eligible for lung cancer screening but currently without ready access to these services.&nbsp;An initial $1 million investment supporting the launch of this new mobile screening unit is estimated to provide services for 10 years, screening as many as 3,000 people per year.<br></li><li><strong>Promise Fund of Florida Doubles Down on Model to Improve Women’s Health</strong>:<br>The Promise Fund of Florida plans to double its reach in 2022 – to serve more than 30,000 women – with a Continuum of Care model that supports women in South Florida from screening through care for breast and cervical cancer. The Promise Fund of Florida co-locates a Women’s Health Center offering mammography and ultrasound services at a federally-qualified health center. In one example, FoundCare in West Palm Beach, this approach led to screening rates jumping from 10% to 57%, demonstrating that women are more likely to obtain screenings when they are familiar with their provider organization, have been connected to financial assistance by a navigator, and are able to receive multiple services in one day, which reduces the associated barriers of having to secure rides to appointments and requesting additional time off from work.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Ralph Lauren Corporate Foundation (RLCF) Commits $25 million to Improve Equity in Cancer Prevention, Screening, and Care.</strong>&nbsp;In its single largest funding commitment to date, the RLCF is pledging $25 million to five cancer care and prevention programs benefiting Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, Georgetown Lombardi Comprehensive Cancer Center, and three yet-to-be-named additional National Cancer Institute-designated centers focused on reducing disparities in cancer care in underserved communities. The programs will provide increased screenings, early diagnosis, and treatment and patient navigation services, while improving access to high-quality care for those most in need.&nbsp;<br><br>As part of its commitment, the RLCF will build on its support of the Memorial Sloan Kettering (MSK) Ralph Lauren Center in Harlem, New York.&nbsp;&nbsp;In Washington D.C., the Georgetown Lombardi Comprehensive Cancer Center will newly establish the Ralph Lauren Center for Cancer Prevention. The renamed and reimagined center will build on the existing practices of the Capital Breast Care Center and expand access to diagnostic and navigation services for the District’s most underserved populations, focusing on breast, colorectal, lung, and prostate cancer, the area’s four most prevalent types of cancers. Going forward, RLCF will collaborate with Conquer Cancer®, the ASCO Foundation, to identify three additional grant recipients selected based on their National Cancer Institute-designation and demonstrated commitment to overcoming health disparities for communities in need.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Expanding Messaging and Support for Cancer Early Detection&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>American Cancer Society (ACS) Launches National Platforms on Cervical and Breast Cancer</strong>: ACS will initiate two new national roundtables in 2022 – one focused on cervical cancer, the other on breast cancer – to bring together leading organizations and experts to drive progress and improve the lives of people living with cancer as well as their families. ACS has established this convening model as an effective structure for collaboration and impact and this approach aligns with the President&#8217;s Cancer Panel recently-released&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cancer.gov/news-events/cancer-currents-blog/2022/cancer-screening-presidents-cancer-panel-report">report on cancer screening</a>. ACS is also pursuing several additional initiatives aimed at ensuring greater equity in cancer screening and early detection, including launching a learning collaborative with six community health centers across the country to address medical mistrust related to colorectal cancer screening. Finally, ACS&#8217;s advocacy affiliate, the American Cancer Society Cancer Action Network (ACS CAN), will advocate for robust and sustained funding for breast and cervical cancer early detection programs at the state and federal level to ensure those who are uninsured and underinsured have access to potentially lifesaving screenings and treatment once cancer is detected.<br></li><li><strong>Cancer Support Community (CSC) Creates Pledge and Resources to Promote Urgency Around Cancer Screening.&nbsp;</strong>CSC is launching a new social media campaign to encourage people to take a pledge to prioritize getting cancer screening and urging their friends and family to do the same. They expect to reach more than 150,000 people through email and social media efforts and expect thousands to come to the landing page to support the pledge and/or become more informed about screenings. CSC will provide resources to help people learn more about which routine screenings are currently available and recommended. Additionally, since anxiety and depression are not only common in people impacted by cancer, but often prevents people from even seeking cancer screening, these resources will include support and navigation services provided along the entire cancer continuum, from before screening, to waiting for test results, and through diagnosis, treatment, and survivorship. This will include a toll-free Cancer Support Helpline and a network of 175 locations across the United States, including CSC and Gilda&#8217;s Club centers, in addition to healthcare partnerships.<br></li><li><strong>Coalition of Companies Step Up to Help Employees Access Recommended Cancer Screenings</strong>: Pelotonia, a non-profit cancer research organization and The Columbus Partnership, a membership organization that convenes CEOs from some of Central Ohio’s largest employers around opportunities to advance economic development and prosperity, are committed to developing a platform whereby employers access and adopt recommended cancer health education and screening materials to better the health of their workforces – an effort that will initially reach more than 250,000 employees. These employers will distribute cancer prevention and screening education materials, host on-site screening opportunities, and offer flexible time off to ensure their employees can take part in recommended cancer screenings, as a commitment to the health of their workforce.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Fight Colorectal Cancer (Fight CRC) Leads Renewed Push for Improved Screening Access at No Cost to Patient:</strong>&nbsp;Fight CRC will build on the Administration&#8217;s recent guidance to commercial insurance plans that they must cover colonoscopy without out-of-pocket costs following an abnormal non-invasive colorectal cancer screening test. Fight CRC is working through its Catalyst State-by-State Advocacy Program to build on its state-level policy work to remove cost barriers to screening and help ensure that the Administration&#8217;s guidance is effectively and equitably implemented.<br><br>Additionally, Fight CRC launched its Path to a Cure report, a professional, multidisciplinary publication, which seeks to summarize and communicate a plan for the colorectal cancer community to rally around: pushing forward critical areas of research; care for patients; and policy, with prevention and early detection as priority areas. Through convening key stakeholders, identifying gaps and opportunities in both research and public policy, Fight CRC is committing to identifying and implementing strategies to increase access to colorectal cancer screening in all communities as part of its Path to a Cure.<br></li><li><strong>Cancer Stage Shifting Initiative Launched by the National Minority Quality Forum (NMQF) to Reach Millions</strong>: NMQF is announcing a multi-sponsored Cancer Stage Shifting Initiative (CSSI) guided by a board of scientific and community thought leaders. CSSI’s mission is to move from late stage to early-stage diagnosis and treatment of cancer in minority populations, with a special, but not exclusive, focus on people living with colorectal cancer. NMQF expects to reach an audience of more than 11 million patients, clinicians and other stakeholders monthly through its collaborations in advocacy and policy, social media communication, clinical research in underserved communities, representative data and quality improvement and community engagement.&nbsp;&nbsp;The initiative will have a clear focus on equity and is expected to improve cancer care for all. Stage shifting will require system changes brought on by a coordinated effort that involves patients, caregivers, families and all stakeholders in the oncology community and beyond, advocating for, educating and communicating about earlier detection and treatment of cancer among underserved populations.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Philips and RadNet Partner to Improve Cancer Screening Reach and Accuracy:&nbsp;</strong>Philips, a global leader in health technology, and RadNet, the largest owner of outpatient imaging centers in the United States, are collaborating to deploy and develop new solutions that can improve the early detection, diagnosis, and treatment of cancer. RadNet will be using Philips solutions for workflow management and patient engagement in their lung cancer screening programs to increase the impact of patient outreach efforts, efficiently scale lung cancer screening workflow and programs, and get more at-risk people screened for lung cancer. Moreover, RadNet is using Artificial Intelligence (AI)-enabled technologies to improve detection and characterization of cancer at earlier stages, preventing false positive findings and reducing unnecessary patient burden, which can lead to better outcomes. Through RadNet’s network of imaging centers and educational outreach programs reaching 15 million Americans each year, many of whom are located in densely-populated, ethnically-diverse communities with at-risk populations, Philips and RadNet are striving for improved education, earlier detection, and more engaged participants, which could yield improved cancer outcomes for all Americans.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Announces New Actions to Address Putin’s Price Hike, Make Food More Affordable, and Lower Costs for&#160;Farmers </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-new-actions-to-address-putins-price-hike-make-food-more-affordable-and-lower-costs-for-farmers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 12:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pandemic-related supply chain disruptions and Putin’s Price Hike are increasing the price of food for working families here at home and leading to shortages of food in countries across the globe. Today, President Biden will visit a family farm to announce actions his administration is taking to support American farmers, reduce food prices, and feed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Pandemic-related supply chain disruptions and Putin’s Price Hike are increasing the price of food for working families here at home and leading to shortages of food in countries across the globe. Today, President Biden will visit a family farm to announce actions his administration is taking to support American farmers, reduce food prices, and feed the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Putin’s unjustified invasion of Ukraine has cut off a critical source of wheat, corn, barley, oilseeds, and cooking oil. It has also disrupted global supply chains for fertilizer, which farmers depend on to maximize yields. These and other actions, combined with the ongoing pandemic-related disruptions to global supply chains, have put pressure on food prices, with global food prices increasing nearly 13 percent following Putin’s invasion.</p>



<p>America’s farmers are the breadbasket of democracy and are already playing a critical role in the fight against Putin’s Price Hike. During President Biden’s first year in office, American agricultural exports shattered all previous records, reaching a combined $177 billion, generating an estimated $378 billion in total economic output, and supporting 1.3 million jobs here in the United States.</p>



<p>Last month, the President mobilized American farmers to fuel America when he announced that his Administration would allow E15 gasoline—gasoline that uses a 15 percent ethanol blend—to be sold this summer. Today, the President is announcing new actions to give farmers the tools and resources they need to boost production, lower food prices and feed the world. As the world’s second largest exporter of wheat and soybeans, these actions will help grow new markets for American-grown food, supporting jobs in rural communities across America. Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Increase the number of counties eligible for double cropping insurance.</strong> Double cropping allows farmers to plant a second crop on the same land in the same year, helping boost production without relying on farmers to substitute crops or cultivate new land. But it is not free from risk and some farmers who practice double cropping cannot obtain crop insurance.  The Biden-Harris Administration is seeking to expand insurance for double cropping to as many as 681 additional counties, bringing the total number of counties where this practice qualifies for crop insurance to as many as 1,935, so more American farmers have the financial security they need to start or expand double cropping. <br></li><li><strong>Cut costs for farmers by increasing technical assistance for technology-driven “precision agriculture” and other nutrient management tools. </strong>Precision agriculture is a farm management system that allows farmers to use technology to target application of inputs to soil and plant needs, resulting in less fertilizer usage without reducing yields, saving farmers money over time and extending the usefulness of critical products in short supply worldwide. The U.S. Department of Agriculture has planning and cost sharing assistance programs available to help American farmers with nutrient management. The Biden-Harris Administration is working to boost outreach to farmers, streamline the application process, and prioritize application approvals to expand access to these critical programs. <br></li><li><strong>Double funding for domestic fertilizer production. </strong>Fertilizer prices have more than doubled since last year, due in part to supply chain disruptions created and exacerbated by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, including rising energy costs. Today, President Biden is announcing that he is doubling his initial $250 million investment in domestic fertilizer production to $500 million to lower costs and boost availability for farmers, so they can obtain the inputs they need at prices they can afford to maximize yields. </li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Releases Permitting Action Plan to Accelerate and Deliver Infrastructure Projects On Time, On Task, and On&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-permitting-action-plan-to-accelerate-and-deliver-infrastructure-projects-on-time-on-task-and-on-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52903</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is making a once-in-a-generation investment in America’s infrastructure and competitiveness that will create good-paying union jobs, grow our economy, invest in communities, combat climate change, and help lower costs for families. To make the most of these historic investments and ensure infrastructure projects are delivered on time and on budget, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is making a once-in-a-generation investment in America’s infrastructure and competitiveness that will create good-paying union jobs, grow our economy, invest in communities, combat climate change, and help lower costs for families.<br><br>To make the most of these historic investments and ensure infrastructure projects are delivered on time and on budget, the Biden-Harris Administration is releasing a new <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Biden-Harris-Permitting-Action-Plan.pdf">Permitting Action Plan</a> to strengthen and accelerate Federal permitting and environmental reviews by fully leveraging existing permitting authorities, as well as new provisions in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.<br><br>The Action Plan outlines the Administration’s strategy for ensuring that Federal environmental reviews and permitting processes are effective, efficient, and transparent, guided by the best available science to promote positive environmental and community outcomes, and shaped by early and meaningful public engagement. Taken together, these new steps will help strengthen supply chains, lower costs for families, grow our clean energy economy, revitalize communities across the country, support good-paying jobs, and deliver infrastructure investments on task, on time, and on budget without unnecessary bureaucratic delay.&nbsp;<br><br>Long overdue improvements to our nation’s ports, airports, rail, and roads will help ease inflationary pressures, create conditions for businesses to thrive, and strengthen supply chains – which will ultimately lower costs for families. Building new clean energy generation and transmission projects will improve access to affordable clean energy that powers homes and businesses at lower costs. Responsible and sustainable domestic sourcing of critical minerals and materials will power our clean energy economy and reduce reliance on unreliable foreign supply chains. And delivering clean residential water supplies, high-speed internet, healthy forests and open space to all Americans, especially those historically underserved, is critical to make us stronger.<br><br>The Action Plan is the latest example of the Administration taking action to swiftly deliver the benefits of infrastructure investment to the American people through well-designed projects that support the President’s ambitious climate and clean energy goals. Putting the Action Plan into place will result in better permitting outcomes, enhanced predictability for project sponsors, and increased accountability across Federal agencies to execute efficiently and effectively.<br><br>The Permitting Action Plan is built on five key elements that will help ensure the timely and effective delivery of crucial upgrades to America’s infrastructure.<br><br><strong><em>Accelerating Smart Permitting through Early Cross-Agency Coordination</em></strong></p>



<p>Ensuring early coordination and effective communication across Federal agencies is critical for moving infrastructure projects forward efficiently and on-time. Under the Permitting Action Plan, the Administration will:</p>



<ul><li>Leverage the interagency Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council’s expanded authorities under the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to improve coordination among agencies, help avoid and resolve potential conflicts and bottlenecks, identify and share best practices, and accelerate information sharing and troubleshooting;<br></li><li>Convene sector-specific teams of experts to facilitate interagency coordination on siting, permitting, supply chain, and related issues, and promote efficient and timely reviews;<br></li><li>Leverage the Department of Transportation’s Interagency Infrastructure Permitting Improvement Center to help facilitate environmental review and permitting for Bipartisan Infrastructure Law-funded transportation projects by developing guidance, sharing best practices, coordinating reviews, tracking project milestones and outcomes, and exploring innovative approaches;<br></li><li>Develop and prepare new approaches to permitting and environmental review that help address common issues, eliminate duplication, and site and design projects in a way that reduces resource conflicts and incorporates a climate-smart approach; and<br></li><li>Work to reform outdated permitting laws and regulations, such as the Mining Law of 1872, to establish stronger environmental, sustainability, safety, Tribal consultation, and community engagement standards.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Establishing Clear Timeline Goals and Tracking Key Project Information</em></strong><br><br>Communities and project proponents all benefit from having clear information about the schedules, key milestones and deadlines, and public comment opportunities for the environmental review and permitting of major projects. Timeline goals and up-to-date information increase accountability, encourage efficiency, enable greater public participation in project decisions, and build greater trust in government. Under the Permitting Action Plan, agencies will:</p>



<ul><li>Create permitting schedules with clear timeline goals that are both ambitious and realistic, contain relevant milestones, and meet all requirements in applicable law to complete environmental review and permitting in a sound and timely manner;<br></li><li>Increase transparency and accountability by tracking key project information, including timetables and milestones, on the <a href="https://www.permits.performance.gov/">Federal Permitting Dashboard</a>; and<br></li><li>Identify the lead Federal agency that will be responsible for working with other agencies in the permitting processes to develop and implement coordination plans, interagency agreements, or other tools designed to ensure sustained and effective coordination and accountability.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Engaging in Early and Meaningful Outreach with States, Tribal Nations, Territories, and Local Communities</em></strong><br><br>Proactive, early, and ongoing engagement with the public, including disadvantaged, underserved, or overburdened communities, and State, Tribal, local, and territorial partners is fundamental to delivering timely projects that serve the needs and priorities of communities across the country. As part of a robust engagement strategy, which will help inform agencies’ decision-making, agencies will:</p>



<ul><li>Consult with affected Tribal Nations as early as possible, in a sustained manner, and in a fashion that respects the Nation-to-Nation relationship;<br></li><li>Proactively partner and coordinate with relevant State, territorial, and local governments as early as possible and in a sustained manner; and<br></li><li>Review and update policies, procedures, and staffing to ensure that the public, including disadvantaged communities, has a meaningful opportunity to participate in decision-making.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Improving Agency Responsiveness, Technical Assistance, and Support</em></strong><br><br>Providing responsive technical assistance and support helps project sponsors, permit applicants, affected communities, Tribal communities, and other stakeholders navigate the environmental review and permitting process effectively and efficiently. To address this need, agencies will:</p>



<ul><li>Identify, share, or develop resources, trainings, and tools to help stakeholders navigate the environmental review and permitting process effectively and efficiently; and<br></li><li>Review environmental review and permitting information collection requirements to help consolidate or simplify reporting requirements, and identify ways that information can be collected more efficiently.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Using Agency Resources and Environmental Reviews to Improve Impact</em></strong><br><br>Timely, informative environmental reviews that are guided by the best available science and help deliver positive environmental and community impact require sufficient levels of skilled agency staff and effective use of budgetary resources. Agencies should therefore:</p>



<ul><li>Prioritize available resources to address workforce needs and implementation of the initiatives in this Action Plan;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Use best practices for accelerated hiring and coordinating with other agencies to efficiently use existing resources, such as conducting collaborative field studies and funding liaison positions; and<br></li><li>Use technology, data, and tools to efficiently and holistically assess environmental and community effects, including information on climate change effects, and identify ways to use new technology to collect, analyze, share, and publicly communicate relevant information.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on House Passage of the Ukraine&#160;Supplemental</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-house-passage-of-the-ukraine-supplemental/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 03:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House took a critical step today in sending a clear, bipartisan message to Ukraine, to Russia, and to the world that the United States stands with the people of Ukraine as they defend their democracy against Russian aggression. We thank House leadership and members of the Appropriations committee for working across the aisle to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The House took a critical step today in sending a clear, bipartisan message to Ukraine, to Russia, and to the world that the United States stands with the people of Ukraine as they defend their democracy against Russian aggression. We thank House leadership and members of the Appropriations committee for working across the aisle to get this done, and appreciate the strong bipartisan support for the President’s proposal to provide much needed security, economic, humanitarian, and food assistance to Ukraine, across the region, and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our assistance to date, together with the contributions of our Allies and partners, has been critical in helping Ukrainians win the battle for Kyiv and defend their freedoms. The additional resources included in this bill will allow us to send more weapons, such as artillery, armored vehicles, and ammunition, to Ukraine. And they will help us replenish our stockpile and support U.S. troops on NATO territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President said yesterday, we cannot afford any delay in this vital effort. We look forward to continuing to work with Senate leadership to get this bill to the President’s desk quickly and keep assistance flowing to Ukraine without interruption.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Prime Minister Kiril Petkov of Bulgaria&#160;</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-prime-minister-kiril-petkov-of-bulgaria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:17:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Prime Minister Kiril Petkov of Bulgaria. The Vice President expressed her appreciation for the strong alliance and warm friendship between the United States and Bulgaria. She thanked the Prime Minister for Bulgaria’s support to Ukraine and affirmed U.S. solidarity in the face of Russia’s latest attempt to use&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris met today with Prime Minister Kiril Petkov of Bulgaria. The Vice President expressed her appreciation for the strong alliance and warm friendship between the United States and Bulgaria. She thanked the Prime Minister for Bulgaria’s support to Ukraine and affirmed U.S. solidarity in the face of Russia’s latest attempt to use energy as a weapon. They agreed on the need to strengthen European resilience by further diversifying energy supplies away from Russia and the importance of continued strong defense and deterrence along NATO’s Eastern flank.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Readout of the Meeting Between President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and Prime Minister Mario&#160;Draghi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/10/joint-readout-of-the-meeting-between-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-and-prime-minister-mario-draghi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 23:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52898</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States and Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy met today at the White House. The leaders reaffirmed the strong and broad U.S.-Italian partnership reflected in the deep and enduring ties between our people and our countries, of which our alliance through NATO and the U.S. partnership with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. of the United States and Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy met today at the White House. The leaders reaffirmed the strong and broad U.S.-Italian partnership reflected in the deep and enduring ties between our people and our countries, of which our alliance through NATO and the U.S. partnership with the EU are critical components. They discussed recent developments in Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified war in Ukraine. They underscored their continued commitment to&nbsp;pursuing peace by&nbsp;supporting Ukraine and imposing costs on Russia.&nbsp;In the face of the global economic challenges created by Russia’s actions, they discussed measures aimed at fostering food security and reshaping global energy markets. They committed to maintaining their work together on global crises from COVID-19 to climate change, as well as to continuing their cooperation on shared foreign policy challenges, including China and Libya. The leaders looked forward to further discussions at the G-7 Summit and NATO Summit in June.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki,&#160;May 10, 2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/10/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-may-10-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:40 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Okay.  It’s a little rowdy in here today.  All right.  Tomorrow, the President will visit a family farm in Kankakee, Illinois, with the Secretary of Agriculture, Tom Vilsack, to discuss the impact of President Putin’s invasion of Ukraine on the rise in food&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:40 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  Okay.  It’s a little rowdy in here today. <br> <br>All right.  Tomorrow, the President will visit a family farm in Kankakee, Illinois, with the Secretary of Agriculture, Tom Vilsack, to discuss the impact of President Putin’s invasion of Ukraine on the rise in food prices at home and abroad.<br> <br>He’s going to talk about the support we need to continue to give to farmers to help continue to produce more and more domestically to help address the food shortages that we’re seeing in some parts of the world.<br> <br>We know that U.S. agricultural exports can help address that and can play an important role.  Just as we are providing weapons, we are going to work on doing more we can to support farmers to provide more wheat and other food around the world.  He’ll talk about that tomorrow.<br> <br>We’ll also &#8212; we’ll also see tomorrow morning the latest inflation numbers for the month of April.  And the President will deliver remarks on the effect of Putin’s price hike on the cost of food and energy, and his administration’s actions to support farmers and food processers, lower their costs, and lower prices for families.<br> <br>Later in the day, the President will give remarks at the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers’ &#8212; IBEW &#8212; 40th Convention in Chicago, Illinois, on his support for union jobs in the infrastructure and energy industries.<br> <br>I also wanted to note for all of you that this afternoon, soon, in the next couple of hours, the President will host Speaker Pelosi and other members of a congressional delegation who recently traveled to Ukraine in the Situation Room. <br> <br>The President previously spoke to Speaker Pelosi about the delegation’s trip by phone.  As we said earlier this month, he wanted to hear a more thorough account of their time in Ukraine, in person, after they returned to the United States.  So this is an opportunity to do exactly that.<br> <br>The President is eager to hear from them and to continue working together on their shared bipartisan goal of providing Ukraine with additional urgensly [sic] &#8212; urgently needed security and economic assistance as soon as possible.  And we&#8217;ve heard good news about that, hopefully moving forward soon.<br> <br>With that, go ahead, Josh.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Three things.  First, I wanted to &#8212; I was hoping to clarify something President Biden said today on inflation.  He said his policies helped, rather than hurt, on inflation.  Does the President believe that his COVID relief package played any role in the increase in inflation last year?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  The President believes, as many economists, including within the government, that the main drivers of inflation were the pandemic &#8212; have been the pandemic and our ongoing fight to address that, as well as President Putin&#8217;s invasion into Ukraine and the impact on energy prices.<br> <br>What the President has done is taken steps to address both of those enormous, enormous challenges and tried to put forward solutions to them. <br> <br>We&#8217;ll leave it to the Federal Reserve, outside economists, inside economists to make other projections on what&#8217;s next.  They&#8217;ve already made projections about when they expect inflation to come down.<br> <br>As he noted today, he is the President.  We do- &#8212; do control all forms of &#8212; branches of government.  That&#8217;s why he laid out very clearly what he&#8217;ll continue to do as President to bring down prices. <br> <br>Q    So then, just to make sure, like, what he’s saying is: The pandemic is distinct from the spending in response to the pandemic, and he does not believe the size of the spending mattered with regard to inflation?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Again &#8212; no.  He &#8212; and we have &#8212; we have spoken to this in the past, Josh, as you know.  The President made a decision that in order to address what was in part a<br>economic crisis that came in, in conjunction with the pandemic, that we needed to put forward the American Rescue Plan. <br> <br>And without it, the economy would have gotten worse.  People would not have been able to put food on the table.  We would not have 100 percent of schools open today.<br> <br>So, no, he does not think that is the driver.  He knows the pandemic was the driver.  There was, of course, an accompanying economic downturn as a result.  And we&#8217;ve seen in recent months the impact of President Putin&#8217;s invasion and the energy prices that have gone up and been a main driver of inflation.<br> <br>Q    Gotcha.  Secondly, Italian Prime Minister Mario Draghi just now pushed for a limited ceasefire to allow talks to resume between Russia and Ukraine.  Does the U.S. believe that these talks would be productive?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We certainly believe that this will be resolved through a diplomatic process and a diplomatic solution.  But we know and you heard, I think, our Director of National Intelligence on Capitol Hill today say that we don&#8217;t see a sign from the Russians that they are open to or eager to invade &#8212; engage in those discussions.<br> <br>There have been several fits and starts at attempts at ceasefires, even in smaller parts of the country, in Ukraine, as you know.  We&#8217;ve been supportive of all of those, but it requires the Russians being at the table and being willing to take part in a diplomatic process.<br> <br>And then lastly, Mexico&#8217;s President said he might not go to Los Angeles for the Summit of the Americas if the U.S. doesn&#8217;t invite Cuba and Nicaragua and Venezuela.  What does President Biden plan to do?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, the invitations have not yet been issued.  The summit is not until early June &#8212; June 10th &#8212; 6th through the 10th, I should say.  We know that the summit is a valuable opportunity to focus on some of the most important shared issues, like the ongoing fight for freedom and democracy for every country; our shared climate goals; a stronger, more collaborative COVID-19 response; and addressing the root causes of migration, like going after organized crime and economic instability.<br> <br>But no invitations have been issued at this point.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    On gas prices, despite the steps the President has taken, despite tapping the strategic oil reserve, prices have hit a new high at $4.37 a gallon.  How long should Americans be prepared to pay this much at the pump?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say &#8212; you heard the President say today and reiterate today that he is relentlessly focused on easing Putin&#8217;s price hike at the pump.  And that means taking as many steps as he can to continue to lower costs for Americans. <br> <br>Now, the steps that he can take and he has taken, of course, include a historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, leading the world in their release to ensure there&#8217;s more supply in the global markets, to reduce the price of oil &#8212; which is exactly what it has done.<br> <br>He&#8217;s also taken steps that are definitely smaller but meant to do anything possible, including issuing a waiver for E15 so that thousands of pumps in the Midwest could have gasoline that &#8212; and make it available to Americans so that that&#8217;s 10 cents less. <br> <br>But he also has noted, and we would note &#8212; and he noted this this morning &#8212; that oil companies should also do their part in ensuring they&#8217;re not price gouging customers at the pump.  As oil prices come down, so should gas prices at the pump.  And that&#8217;s also something that we are going to continue to watch closely and continue to call on steps to be taken.<br> <br>But given that the steps taken so far haven’t been able to bring down prices, can Americans be confident that some of the steps that you&#8217;re outlining now will be able to have an effect?  Or is it just going stay this way &#8212; is Putin’s price hike going to stay until Putin’s war is over?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we certainly won&#8217;t accept that.  But what I think is important to note is the oil market is global.  And what the President can do and will continue to do is ensure he&#8217;s doing everything in his power to ensure that supply in the market meets the demand out there in the market.<br> <br>But the point is: When there is enough oil out there in the market, oil prices come down, as we&#8217;ve seen them come down, and gas prices should also come down.  And that is something that Americans should be watching closely and be clear about where we&#8217;re seeing price hikes come from.<br> <br>Q    I just have a question on messaging.  Who came up with this phrase “Ultra-MAGA”?  Why the need to kick it up a notch?  MAGA wasn&#8217;t enough?  I mean, why now use this phrase?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I will tell you, it is &#8212; it is the President&#8217;s phrase, and the President made those comments himself just last week, as you know. <br> <br>And I think what has struck him is how extreme some of the policies and proposals are that a certain wing of the Republican Party &#8212; that is taking up too much of the Republican Party &#8212; are for and are advocating for.<br> <br>And you &#8212; you&#8217;ve heard the President talk about this.  It&#8217;s &#8212; but it&#8217;s not just obviously putting at risk a woman&#8217;s right to make choices about her own healthcare. <br> <br>It is also, as you heard him talk about this morning, Rick Scott&#8217;s extreme plan that will raise taxes on 75 million Americans making less than $100,000 a year. <br> <br>It is Rick Scott&#8217;s plan to get rid of, eliminate &#8212; that&#8217;s what “sunset” means: “get rid of” &#8212; Medicare and Social Security, something people over 70 in this country rely on. <br> <br>And it&#8217;s also the obsession with culture wars and wars against Mickey Mouse and banning books.  The President thinks that&#8217;s extreme.  That is not what the American people care about or what they want.<br> <br>And so, to him, adding a little “ultra” to it, give it a little extra pop.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    So then who is an “Ultra-MAGA” Republican?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say people who support that portion of the Republican agenda.<br> <br>Q    So, Rob Portman, Susan Collins, Mitt Romney, would they be “Ultra-MAGA” Republicans?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  They can all make their own choices, Ed.  And I can &#8212; we can let others evaluate that.<br> <br>But I would say that the President&#8217;s view is: Those who support a plan by Rick Scott &#8212; by Chairman Scott, that would raise taxes on 75 million Americans and get rid of, “sunset,” eliminate &#8212; whatever you want to call it &#8212; Medicare and Social Security, that&#8217;s a MAGA position.<br> <br>And that includes the Chairman of the Republican National Committee.  That&#8217;s a MAGA position.  That is the chairman of the party.<br> <br>So that&#8217;s what the President considers.  But also, obviously, given two thirds of the American people, according to a Fox News poll, believe that women&#8217;s &#8212; that Roe v. Wade should be protected, if you&#8217;re on the other side of that, you&#8217;re supporting an “Ultra-MAGA” position, in the President&#8217;s view.<br> <br>So we&#8217;ll let &#8212; we don&#8217;t need to name-call individuals unless they have positions that are aligned with what he feels is the “Ultra-MAGA” wing of the party.<br> <br>Q    Two other quick on foreign affairs.  Just to follow up on Josh&#8217;s question, you said invites to the Summit of the Americas haven&#8217;t gotten out.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Can you confirm, though, that someone from Venezuela, someone from Nicaragua, someone from Cuba will actually be invited to the summit?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I can&#8217;t because a final decision has not been made yet.<br> <br>Q    You don’t rule out that those three countries might be exempted?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We haven&#8217;t made a decision about who will be invited, and no invitations have been issued yet.<br> <br>Q    And then, last night at a fundraiser in suburban Washington, the President said this about Vladimir Putin, quote: “He is a very, very, very calculating man.  And the problem I worry about now is that he doesn’t have a way out right now, and I’m trying to figure out what we do about that.”<br><br>Can you describe how that process is going?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  What we do &#8212;<br><br>Q    Does it involve &#8212; does it involve, for example, considering the Italian Prime Minister’s suggestion that there be a temporary ceasefire for talks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think, to be clear, we’ve long supported ceasefires.  It requires both the parties, including the party that has invaded the other country, to be a part of that, and they haven’t shown a willingness to sit at the negotiating table. <br><br>So I think there have been efforts, as you know &#8212; humanitarian ceasefires and others &#8212; in a limited fashion in the past and in the past couple of months, which the Russians have failed to implement.<br><br>What the President meant by this, and I &#8212; and I talked to him about exactly that this morning &#8212; or what he was referring to is the fact that, as we all know and we all have seen and you all have reported, this war has not gone as President Putin has planned.  You know, he has seen his military be demoralized.  He did not march through the city of Kyiv yesterday.  NATO and the West are united.  And right now, he&#8217;s dealing with crippling financial sanctions in his country while he has become a pariah in the world.<br><br>So what the President&#8217;s point was is that we have to be clear-eyed about the impact that has on a dictator that has invaded another country, a sor- &#8212; a sovereign country that it hasn&#8217;t gone as plan- &#8212; as he thought it would go.<br> <br>Q    If he’s so concerned, why not try to directly engage Putin himself?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say our role right now &#8212; we feel the most constructive role is to continue to support the Ukrainians’ hands at the negotiating table and support them militarily.  And I would note that our support &#8212; obviously, their bravery and courage has been what has helped them win the Battle of Kyiv, but our military assistance, the assistance &#8212; our humanitarian and economic assistance is a &#8212; is a close second.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    So, today, the President said that a “majority” of Republicans have signed on to Senator Scott&#8217;s tax plan.  That does not seem to be the case.  Senator Scott said that today.  Mitch McConnell had said that the party is not behind this.  Are there any Republicans that you can think of or the President might be referencing that is currently behind this?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Do you count the chairman of the Republican Committee as an important Republican?<br> <br>Q    He is the chairman of a committee.  But if no other Repub- &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  She.  It’s actually a “she.”  The chairman of the Republican Party &#8212;<br><br>Q    I thought you were referring to Scott there.  I &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  So, Chairman Ronna McD- &#8212; Ronna McDaniel praised Senator Scott&#8217;s proposal as a, quote, “clear plan” for Republicans that offers, quote, “real solutions.”<br><br>She&#8217;s the chairwoman of the party.  Rick Scott is not a random senator.  He is literally in charge of winning back the Senate for Republicans and what the plan is.  So he is the person who&#8217;s put forward this plan. <br>    <br>Senator Ron Johnson has called the Congressional GOP plan a, quote, “positive thing.”  Senator Mike Braun has said he was, quote, “glad Rick did it.”  Senator Tommy Tuberville said he was, quote, “on board” with the Congressional GOP plan.  Congressman Matt Gaetz said he was, quote, “proud of Senator Rick Scott for <s>providing</s> [producing] this bold agenda.”<br><br>So not only that, which seems to be quite a range of Republicans, but there isn&#8217;t an alternative plan they&#8217;ve put forward.  So it&#8217;s either this, put together by the person who is leading the effort to win back the Senate, or nothing.<br><br>And the President this morning talked about what his plan is.  If they have an alternative plan, we would welcome them putting it forward.<br> <br>Q    And he did say one was coming in this summer.  And as far as Senator Scott goes, he acknowledged today that a majority is not behind him.  He says this is his individual plan for this.<br><br>I do want to ask, as well &#8212; I mean, the Department of Justice was very swift in responding to school board members who felt like they were being harassed and intimidated a couple months back.  Does the President feel that the demonstrations outside of, say, Justice Alito’s home &#8212; are those attempts to interfere or intimidate?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think I said yesterday, but I&#8217;m happy to repeat because I think it&#8217;s important for everybody to hear, that the President&#8217;s longstanding view has been that violence, threats, and imitat- &#8212; intimidation of any kind have no place in political discourse.  And we believe, of course, in peaceful protest.<br><br>What I do find is interesting, and I think most &#8212; many people have noted, is that there are voices on the right who have called out this &#8212; protests that are happening &#8212; while remaining silent for years on protests that have happened outside of the homes of school board members, the Michigan Secretary of State, or including threats made to women seeking repo- &#8212; reproductive healthcare, or even an insurrection against our Capitol.<br><br>So I know that there&#8217;s an outrage right now, I guess, about protests that have been peaceful to date &#8212; and we certainly continue to encourage that &#8212; outside of judges’ homes.  And that&#8217;s the President&#8217;s position.  But the silence is pretty deafening about all of the other intimidation that we&#8217;ve seen to a number of people.<br><br>Q    This is a pending court case though.  That’s where the federal law comes into place.  This is a pending court case.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, but I think that intimidation and protests &#8212; and intimidation outside of the homes of school board members, the Michigan Secretary of State &#8212; you know, intimidation and threats against people seeking legal reproductive healthcare &#8212; and against our Capitol and American democracy also warrant some outrage.  And we haven&#8217;t really seen that.<br><br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Jen, you mentioned this a bit yesterday, but the situation has changed since then: We&#8217;ve now heard a bipartisan Senate proposal resolution from Senators Blumenthal and Graham who are urging the Biden &#8212; or would be urging the Biden administration to designate Russia as a state sponsor of terrorism under Vladimir Putin.  Is there any new information, from your view, on that?  Is that something the President supports?  And if not, why not?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we expect, certainly &#8212; and Speaker Pelosi said this yesterday, that this is a topic she will raise &#8212; or we&#8217;ll leave it to her if she wants to raise it when she meets with the President today.<br><br>Q    What’s his view?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would note, as the President has said in the past, this is a process that &#8212; a legal process that the State Department goes through and reviews.  And what they look at &#8212; it&#8217;s defined by statute &#8212; by Congress, actually.  They take a look at the law and undergo a review of whether somebody has violated or a country has violated international terrorism laws.  And that is what they look closely at.<br><br>I would note &#8212; and when Speaker Pelosi spoke to this yesterday, and others, they expressed a desire and an interest in making sure we were doing everything we could &#8212; maximum efforts &#8212; to hold Russia accountable.<br><br>And &#8212; and they looked at, understandably, what has been done to other countries that have been labeled state sponsors of terrorism.  Only four, of course, have &#8212; have been designated that way.<br><br>And we have been doing, already, what has happened to those other countries.  So, extensive financial sanctions, export controls, also working diplomatically to limit investment by other countries in &#8212; in the &#8212; the pariah states &#8212; the other four and, certainly, Russia.<br><br>So we&#8217;ve already been taking those steps. <br><br>There &#8212; there’ll be an ongoing review at the State Department.  That process should see itself out &#8212; itself through.  And that&#8217;s where the President thinks it should be.<br><br>Q    On the Ukrainian package that the President is proposing, Congress is now, you know, working on such a package.  We heard from Mitch McConnell on the Hill a short time ago saying the Republicans don&#8217;t want, in his words, “extraneous items to be included.”  Does the White House believe that the Afghanistan Advancement Act should be included in there &#8212; in there, Ukraine refugee aid, oligarch sanctions?  I’ll start with Afghanistan Act.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think as you&#8217;re touching on here, but just to get others up to speed on where it stands, the House proposal that they&#8217;re expected to introduce is about $40 billion, which is larger than the package that we had proposed &#8212; about $7 billion over our initial request.<br><br>So, while it has $3.4 billion more for security and humanitarian assistance, it doesn&#8217;t &#8212; it&#8217;s not expected to include some items, including, as you touched on, providing a pathway to permanent status for African refugees &#8212; something we certainly support, right?<br><br>Q    So do you believe that that should be included in this package?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  There’ll be a negotiation and a discussion in Congress.  I&#8217;m not going to prejudge that.  We&#8217;ve supported that being included.  But obviously, there&#8217;s an urgency to getting this funding done, given we have nine more days until we run out of money.<br> <br>Q    Okay.  I guess the question is: If &#8212; if this is to delay your ability to accomplish this within nine days, is the President &#8212; would he be okay with that being not included in the final package?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  If what were to delay?<br> <br>Q    If this were to delay the nine days, you said, until money runs out.  If you were not to include the Afghan aid, for example, the President would be okay with that being out, is what you’re saying?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, again, this hasn&#8217;t even been formally introduced by the House.  We have supported that.  But the President &#8212;<br><br>Q    (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  &#8212; has been &#8212; has been very clear &#8212; it&#8217;s not being discussed upstairs, it&#8217;s &#8212; well, being discussed with Speaker Pelosi when she comes.  Sure.  But the President has been clear we need to get this funding and security assistance funding so that we can continue to provide assistance to the Ukrainians.<br><br>Q    Let me ask one last question, because I asked the President earlier and he said it was being weighed &#8212; this was as it related to dropping the China tariffs right now &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br><br>Q    &#8212; to help the &#8212; to help the domestic economy here.  Is the President sensitive that doing that could actually &#8212; would be a political liability if it may help Americans in the near term, in terms of their pocketbook, their costs?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  A political &#8212; so &#8212; say that one &#8212;<br><br>Q    Does the President have concerns that, basically, lifting tariffs on China &#8212; which could be used as a battering ram by political opponents saying you’re being soft on China &#8212; would be a political challenge for him, even if it would help Americans, in terms of their pocketbook issues in the near term, (inaudible)?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we already &#8212; we already announced some tariffs that we were lifting back in March.  So it&#8217;s been an ongoing review.  And we expect to do more.  And his &#8212;<br><br>Q    But he said he’s weighing new ones, so (inaudible).<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  He’s weighing new ones.  Yes.  Because it&#8217;s an ongoing process, and there are more that are still in place.  And we didn&#8217;t feel that the ones that were in place when the President took office were all advantageous and were doing what they needed to do to make clear what our positions were on China&#8217;s approach to investment and economic engagement, which we&#8217;ve obviously been clear about our issues with. <br><br>And we have &#8212; but we are &#8212; we are continuing to review where it would be advantageous to take steps that would help, you know, reduce wages &#8212; or increase wages and help certain industries that are &#8212; that are impacted by these tariffs in a way that &#8212; that we don&#8217;t feel is effective.<br><br>So, there will be more and he&#8217;s continuing to weigh them.  But Ambassador Tai is &#8212; is leading that effort.<br><br>Q    Is Jill Biden going to be in the Situation Room for that meeting, given her experience?<br>MS. PSAKI:  Dr. Biden?  I don&#8217;t know that she will be in the meeting.  But the President &#8212; she and the President obviously had a number of conversations since she returned.  She &#8212; he was talking just this morning about how proud he was of her trip and how grateful he was that she traveled there.<br> <br>Go ahead.  Go ahead, Jeff.<br> <br>Q    Jen, just to follow up on the tariffs: Do you have a sense of the timeframe for when the next round or when the next decision on lifting tariffs could come?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have a prediction of that.  What we&#8217;re looking at is how to evaluate what&#8217;s working for American workers, industry, farmers, and consumers and change what is not.<br> <br>I mean, I expect we&#8217;ll have more to say in the coming weeks, but I don&#8217;t have an assessment for you on how expensive that will be or how many decisions about tariffs there will be at that point in time.  But we expect we&#8217;ll have more to say in the coming weeks.<br> <br>Q    Elon Musk today said that he would reverse the decision to have Twitter &#8212; that Twitter made to ban President Trump.  I’m wondering if the White House has a reaction to that and how that would impact this White House’s dealing with misinformation.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say it&#8217;s the decision by a private sector company to make on who will or will not be allowed on their platforms.<br> <br>What I will say, broadly speaking, is that our effort is to, of course, make sure that freedom of speech is protected across the country but that, also, these platforms are not used for format &#8212; forums for disinformation. <br> <br>And we have seen a history of that not just on Twitter but also on Facebook.  The President believes there&#8217;s more that needs to be done in reforming Section 230.  And there&#8217;s a lot of bipartisan interest in that, so this may be a reminder of the urgency of doing that.<br> <br>Q    And lastly, the United States is about to hit a grim milestone of a million COVID-related deaths.  How does the President plan to commemorate this?  And looking back at the last two years, why has that number gotten so high in this country?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we&#8217;re facing &#8212; we&#8217;ve been battling a historic pandemic, Jeff, I think.  And while we have more than 75 percent of the country vaccinated, which is a significant number, we still know that far too many people are &#8212; have not been vaccinated, have not taken the maximum protections, even if they’re vaccinated and not yet boosted, to massively reduce their likelihood of hospitalization and death.<br> <br>It is still incumbent upon us and we are still working every day on increasing the number of vac- &#8212; people vaccinated, the number of people boosted, and expanding the protections.  In terms of how we&#8217;re going to mark that moment, the President will certainly be marking that day.  I expect we’ll have more to say soon.  We look at the CDC data and the Johns Hopkins data.<br> <br>I know different news organizations evaluate it differently.  But in terms of when we will mark it, it will be aligned with when that data hits the number.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Last November, President Biden asked the Federal Trade Commission to look into whether oil and gas companies were playing a role in keeping gas prices high.  Has he gotten the results of that investigation?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, they&#8217;re independent, so they would make any announcements about any intention to take steps on their own &#8212; of their own accord, out publicly to all of you.  And obviously, they have not done that.<br> <br>But what we can certainly see and watch, Kaitlan, even without any announcement or indication by the FTC, is, as we see the price of oil &#8212; barrels of oil come down, the price of gas should also come down at the pump.  And we haven&#8217;t always seen that trend take place.  And that is something we are also closely watching and certainly the FTC would be watching as well.<br> <br>Q    Is it the White House’s understanding that they&#8217;re actually investigating that?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Again, you&#8217;d have to speak to them.  They’re independent.  The President sent a letter.  He&#8217;s spoken about this a number of times publicly, but they would speak to any intention of investigating, given they’re independent.<br> <br>Q    And what&#8217;s the White House&#8217;s expectation for the inflation report that is expected to come out this week?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have a prediction.  I know I sometimes do, but I don&#8217;t have a prediction on it at this moment from here.<br> <br>Obviously, once it comes out, I expect we&#8217;ll have more to say.  And our focus continues to be on taking steps to lower costs.  And obviously, the President addressed this morning and outlined this morning what his plan is to do exactly that.<br> <br>Go ahead.  Oh, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Last question on Ukraine.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    The President&#8217;s comment last night that he&#8217;s worried Putin does not have a way out of this that he can see &#8212; what does he believe Putin&#8217;s goal is right now?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think what the President was referring to is the fact that this has not gone as President Putin planned and that &#8212; while he had predicted in a very public speech we all talked about at the time in February that he would not only subsume Ukraine and to make that a part of Russia, he would be marching through the streets and maybe he’d do more from there.  And that obviously hasn&#8217;t happened.<br> <br>The Ukrainians won the battle of Kyiv.  He obviously &#8212; he also thought that NATO would be divided, that the West would be divided &#8212; that has not happened.  And he certainly did not predict he would be facing the level of crippling sanctions enforced by all Western countries together that he is today.<br> <br>So, the point he was making is that, you know, we have to be cleareyed about the fact that this war is not over, that they are &#8212; he still has ambitions and he is still fighting the war.  And we&#8217;ve seen that on the ground every day.  But even as the Ukrainians have had successes, as Director Haines said today, this is going to be a long war and we need to prepare ourselves for that.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Jen, on Monday, you tweeted out that the President strongly believes in the right to protest, that such protests should never include violence, threats, or vandalism.  And you specifically mentioned the ability of judges to be able to do their jobs. <br> <br>Is the administration worried that abortion rights protests may turn violent?  And was there any specific group of protesters that that tweet was geared towards?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think, to be very clear, the protests outside of judges’ homes have not turned violent.  And I don&#8217;t think we need to make a prediction of that from here.  Just because people are passionate, it does not mean they&#8217;re violent.  And I think that&#8217;s probably why you&#8217;re asking the question, Ashley. <br> <br>But I think it is important to &#8212; the President felt it was important for us to be clear that as people&#8217;s passions are high, as people are fearful about their own healthcare, that should never resort to violence, it should never resort to vandalism.  And we have seen some elements of that &#8212; vandalism.  And he wanted to be clear that his position was to call for peaceful protests.<br> <br>Q    And on a similar theme, Senator Collins called the police over the weekend after someone wrote a non-threatening abortion rights message in sidewalk chalk in front of her house in Maine.  I was just curious, sort of, what you made of that &#8212; of her response.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have any specific comment on her response, other than to say that: Even as passions are high, even as people are fearful, even as people are scared and frustrated, which is understandable, we should not &#8212; no one should resort to violence, of course, nor threats, nor intimidation, nor vandalism, and that those are not effective means.<br> <br>Q    Do you consider sidewalk chalk vandalism?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I&#8217;ll let others define that.  But there are lots of ways to peaceful protest.<br> <br>What&#8217;s also important to note here is what I would call the hypocrisy of the silence on the other side when there have been intimidation, protests outside of the homes of school board members, the Michigan Secretary of State.  There have been countless women who have dealt with and navigated through threats made as they&#8217;re seeking repro- &#8212; reproductive healthcare, which, by the way, has been legal for 50 years.  And there has been no outcry about that.<br> <br>There has been outcry about &#8212; about protests that have been peaceful outside of judges’ homes, which, again, you know, have been peaceful and have not been violent.  And the President has been clear about his view on them.<br> <br>Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.  I wanted to ask you about another aspect of what the President might call the “Ultra-MAGA Agenda,” which is election denial.  More than 140 House and Senate Republicans voted against certifying his victory in January 2021.  There are many more candidates running for seats in this election that have pledged that they would have done that and may do the same in the future.<br> <br>The President&#8217;s ramping up his rhetoric and going after Republicans on economic policies, tax policies.  Is he planning to go to voters and tell them that their vote this November could impact their ability to have their vote counted two Novembers hence?  Or is he not concerned that a Republican House would refuse to certify a Democratic victory in 2024?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think the way you can expect &#8212; without getting into the politics of it, which I have to be careful of from here &#8212; the President to talk about voting and voting rights is about his view and belief that we should have people elected across the country stand up for protecting and expanding access, and not questioning and making it more difficult or oppressing people&#8217;s right to exercise their right to vote.<br> <br>Q    Just a follow-up.  It seems more and more that a tenet of the Republican agenda is to denigrate him as illegitimate or &#8212; or worse.  Is &#8212; is it hard for him to hear these things?  What&#8217;s his reaction every day to hearing that there are people referring to his administration as “the regime” and talking about him as if he&#8217;s a dictator?  Is &#8212; is he bothered by that, or does he just see it as politics as usual these days?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I haven&#8217;t heard that one as much.  But I would say that you heard the President &#8212; Ed asked him earlier today about Senator Scott&#8217;s comments about him.  And, you know, the President&#8217;s response was, “[He] has a problem.”<br> <br>And his view of a lot of these comments is that people are freaking out in some capacity.  Because if you look at Senator Scott, his &#8212; his plan that is going to raise taxes on 75 million Americans, even peo- &#8212; some people in his own party &#8212; not enough, but some people in his own party are backing away from. <br> <br>So, you know, I don&#8217;t think he spends a lot of time worried about people&#8217;s angry tweets or &#8212; or angry verbal, you know, missives.  He spends time on laying out the contrast of what he&#8217;s going to present with what their plans are.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Briefly, to follow up on the questions about gas prices &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Can you give us a little more specifics about any new policies the administration might be considering to address high gas prices?  And how seriously is the administration considering calling for a suspension of the federal gas tax?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, on the federal gas tax, that is an option on the table.  There &#8212; it would lower gas, I think, about &#8212; you can check me on this; I think you know the answer &#8212; about 18 cents, I believe.  And certainly, that&#8217;s something that remains on the table. <br> <br>There are a lot of ideas in Congress about steps that can be taken to lower gas prices even temporarily or provide some relief to Americans, so we&#8217;re in a constant discussion about that.<br> <br>He does continue to view the challenge as one being about ensuring there is supply in the marketplace.  And obviously, he&#8217;s taken the steps he took with the &#8212; this historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.  We’ll continue to talk with big global producers about what steps we can take.  And he&#8217;s going to continue to look at steps we can take to provide relief to Americans.<br> <br>I would say the other piece that&#8217;s very much on his mind is that when we look at inflation and what the impact of inflation is on Americans, we know that it has driven, at this point, 60 to 70 percent &#8212; depending on the data you&#8217;re looking at &#8212; by energy prices.<br> <br>And so, in addition to addressing that, he wants to think about how to bring down costs for Americans in a range of ways. <br> <br>And, you know, a couple of weeks ago, he announced fixes to the “family glitch” in the Affordable Care Act.  He&#8217;s announced a pause on the repayment of student loans. <br> <br>And if you&#8217;re a family at home balan- &#8212; you know, trying to figure out how you&#8217;re going to pay bills, you&#8217;re looking at what your costs are incoming, and he is going to take every step he can to provide relief as people need it in this moment, and he certainly recognizes that.<br> <br>Q    And speaking of inflation, is he concerned at all that widespread loan forgiveness would actually increase inflation and further exacerbate it by pumping money into the economy (inaudible)?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I know some economists &#8212; and I don&#8217;t have an official assessment from here &#8212; but I would say that Jared Bernstein, who is one of our economists, has spoken to this.  And he&#8217;s talked about &#8212; more about the impact of pausing federal loan repayments and the fact that, in his view &#8212; and you can quote him directly &#8212; it would be something like 0.001 percent, which, in his view, the impact of that &#8212; the impact of giving people relief who need relief, who are stressed and can&#8217;t repay these loans right now as they&#8217;re having higher costs in other areas, outweighs that impact.<br> <br>But again, I don&#8217;t have a projection here on specifically what the inflationary impact would be.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Just two things up.  Can you offer any further details on what the Women&#8217;s Health Policy Council has in mind on executive orders for abortion rights, since you all seem to (inaudible) that issue?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  Well, we&#8217;ve talked about &#8212; it may not all be executive orders.  I mean, there&#8217;s &#8212; a lot of this is ensuring that we have increased access and funding so that women who are living in the states, if Roe were to be overturned, would be able to have expanded access and capabilities.  And some of that could be from the Department of Justice, obviously, which they would make final decisions about.<br> <br>We&#8217;ve said that we weren&#8217;t going to preview until there&#8217;s a final opinion because we&#8217;re still speaking about a potential opinion that has not yet been released.  But what I would point you to is what we did around S.B. 8 and the law in Texas, which was to take steps, including by creating new grants to increase funding, given the fact that we know that 75 percent of women who seek an abortion are under 200 percent of the poverty level.  So increase funding to ensure we&#8217;re making it more &#8212; you know, making sure that funding is available to people.<br> <br>HHS has also started a number of programs with the exact same objective intended to protect patients and providers in response to the law.<br> <br>And the Department of Justice has also issued statements in response to S.B. 8 that reaffirm their commitment to using existing federal law to protect the safety of patients seeking access to reproductive health services.<br> <br>So what we&#8217;re looking at and what we&#8217;re trying to address is our assessment and understanding of what the impact will be that 13 states have trigger laws, 26 states have indicated that they could overturn or ban or take immediate action should this &#8212; should this be the final opinion.  And we know who is most &#8212; would be most impacted.<br> <br>So, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point.  As we said, we wouldn&#8217;t before there&#8217;s a final opinion.  But those are the factors we&#8217;re looking at.<br> <br>Q    And just one more question.  Where does the White House stand on whether the DOJ Antitrust Chief, Jonathan Kanter, should be recused from Google cases?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I will check and see if we have a position on that or if it’s something we&#8217;d punt to the Department of Justice.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    With the COVID funding now separated from the Ukraine funding, what is the path for the COVID funds to pass?  And also, should Americans start preparing for shortages of tests or vaccines or treatments this fall?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, on the second part of your question, I think we don&#8217;t want to sugarcoat it that we need more money.  We don&#8217;t have a plan B here.  We will use the few funds we have remaining to continue getting tests, treatments, and vaccines out to Americans for as long as we can.<br> <br>And we&#8217;re going to continue to work the phones, hold briefings, and make our case publicly and privately with lawmakers, imploring Congress to act immediately after our long &#8212; after &#8212; to help us on our long-overdue COVID needs.<br> <br>I will say that we are having conversations at a bipartisan level with a bi- &#8212; bicameral about what the impact will be, which the President said in a statement yesterday, “More Americans will die needlessly.” <br> <br>And why?  Because we&#8217;re going to exhaust our treatment supply, we&#8217;ll lose out to other countries on promising new treatments, we&#8217;ll lose our place in line for America to order new COVID vaccines, we’ll be unable to maintain our supply of COVID tests, and our effort to get &#8212; help lower-income countries get COVID vaccines into arms will stall, which is especially relevant given the international summit we&#8217;re hosting.<br> <br>So, we will use the remaining funds we have to kind of spread it as we can, but we need more money in order to continue to effectively run the programs we&#8217;ve been running to date.<br> <br>Q    If it takes a vote on Title 42, would the President be okay with a vote happening to try to block Title 42 going away in order to get a vote on the COVID funds?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I know there&#8217;s a lot of talk on this out there, and so I understand why you&#8217;re asking.  But right now, there&#8217;s a lot of steps that would need to happen before that came to the President&#8217;s desk.<br> <br>I would say our view &#8212; or his view continues to be that the lifting of Title 42 is a decision made by the CDC.  It was the authority given to them by Congress.  That should not be holding up funding that&#8217;s necessary to save the lives of Americans. <br> <br>But again, those are ongoing discussions in Congress at this point.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  I have two questions: oil and inflation.  Oil first.  The President referred to the Strategic Reserve, and then there&#8217;s this &#8212; we talked about that again &#8212; but the rallying our allies to release the additional 60 million barrels of oil from different countries.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    How successful has he been on this, on this very &#8212; convincing allies to release more oil?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say it&#8217;s the largest historic release ever by the global community, so I would say that&#8217;s pretty successful.<br> <br>In terms of the status of when the releases would happen, we said at the beginning that it would be over the course of time.  What we&#8217;re trying to do is fill the needs for the next several months until a number of oil companies have said they would be able to pump more.<br> <br>Q    Have you been &#8212; have you had commitment on that?  I mean &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We announced commitments just a few weeks ago.<br> <br>Q    On countries?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    From countries.  I&#8217;ll go back in my notes then.<br> <br>As for inflation, I just want to check something with you.  Because as you know, the eight-foot two-by-four goes to between $6 and $7 each these days.  Some construction is &#8212; construction is getting more and more costly.  I was reading a report from Habitat for Humanity saying 30,000 houses are $30,000 more expensive because of the cost of the &#8212; of material.<br> <br>As you know, the tariff on Canadian softwood is still over 11 percent.  Is that a way to get rid of part of the inflation by getting rid of these tariffs &#8212; which, actually, Canadian softwood is secure, strong, you know, easily accessible?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You love &#8212; you love some good Canadian lumber.<br> <br>I don&#8217;t have anything to predict in terms of tariffs on Canadian lumber.  I will say that, obviously, taking steps not just to address the supply chain but to manufacture more at home, here in the United States, is part of the President&#8217;s longer-term plan to address these increasing costs over the long term.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you so much.  Would you have a comment on the presidential election in the Philippines?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  On the presidential election in the Philippines &#8212; I believe I have something in here.  There’s a lot happening today.  If not, we will get you something right after the briefing because I believe we may have something on that.  So why don’t we venture to do that.<br> <br>Q    And also, I had one on Afghanistan as well.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br> <br>Q    There were, like, dozens of women today in Kabul protesting the latest restriction, which is that they now must fully cover their faces and bodies in public.  And this is just the latest in a series of restrictions.<br> <br>Is the administration surprised that this is all happening?  And what is the administration doing to assist women and girls in Afghanistan?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, on the &#8212; let me just get &#8212; let me give you a comment on the Philippines first, because I found it, and then I&#8217;ll get to your Afghanistan question.<br> <br>So we are &#8212; this is not very exciting, I will just preface for you &#8212; but we are monitoring election results.  We look forward to renewing our partnership and to working with the next administration on key priorities, including strengthening our alliance; advancing a free, open Indo-Pacific; and promoting human rights.<br> <br>We understand that vote tabulation is well underway and that candidate Ferdinand Marcos Jr. stands in the lead, but we&#8217;re going to wait for the official call before we have a more formal comment.<br> <br>In terms of Afghan women in the street, I would say: One, even as the President made the choice to pull our troops out of Afghanistan after a 20-year failed war that cost thousands of American lives and spent billions of dollars of American taxpayer dollars, we still have committed to be supporters &#8212; humanitarian supporters through a range of NGOs and other organizations of the amazing courage of Afghan women and girls.<br> <br>And does it surprise us that they&#8217;re protesting in the streets?  No.  These are women who have been courageously standing up against oppression, against the Taliban for decades. And, you know, we will continue to be supporters, through any means possible, of their efforts and their bravery and courage they&#8217;re showing today.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Nancy asked you a little bit about the substance of some potential abortion EOs.  But I want to ask you about something Majority Leader Schumer said just a little while ago &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; to reporters on the Hill.  He said that President Biden is meeting with what he said was a group of people today to discuss possible executive action on abortion.  Is there such a meeting on the President&#8217;s schedule today?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say that one of the steps we&#8217;ve said we&#8217;ve been taking all along is having the Gender Policy Council, our Counsel&#8217;s Office, and the Department of Health and Human Services come up with options and proposals for what we would do were this opinion issued to be final or a version of it to be final. <br> <br>So those are ongoing internal meetings.<br> <br>Q    So can I ask who he&#8217;s meeting with today?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not aware of a meeting today but these are ongoing meetings, including with the President, that have been happening for the last several days.<br> <br>Q    And on the potential abortion EOs, is that something &#8212; in terms of the timetable, is it safe to assume that that&#8217;s something that you wouldn&#8217;t do until after you get the Supreme Court ruling or maybe sooner, given the things that have already happened and (inaudible)?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I think we&#8217;ve been clear from the beginning that we are not going to announce specific steps until we have a final opinion. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Also on abortion, Jen, we&#8217;ve seen the President speak out against states that had passed laws that he disagreed with.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Voting rights especially.  But last year, he supported calls for Major League Baseball to move the All-Star Game out of Georgia because of their voting laws.  Would the President support private businesses pulling out of states that are passing or will pass restrictive abortion laws?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I haven&#8217;t had that discussion with the President, so I don&#8217;t have anything to comment on at this point.<br> <br>Yeah, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Yeah.  So &#8212; thanks, Jen.  So the President said today that inflation is his top domestic priority.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Has that replaced climate change, then, for this administration as the top priority?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say first that inflation and the rise in cost for people across the country has long been the top issue for peo- &#8212; for &#8212; in every poll we&#8217;ve seen and certainly has been the number one issue for the President for some time.<br> <br>When he came into office, he said that his agenda was going to focus on four major priorities.  That includes addressing the climate crisis, of course, and he will continue to do that. <br> <br>But we are certainly aware that right now, in this moment, that inflation and reducing costs is what is most on the minds of Americans.<br> <br>Q    So the President was also asked if he took responsibility for any of his policies related to inflation &#8212; not just gas prices, but inflation.  When he took office, inflation was 2.5 percent year over year.  It&#8217;s now 8.5 percent. The invasion didn&#8217;t happen until about one year into his term. So why doesn&#8217;t the President take any responsibility?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI: I think the President said today that he&#8217;s President and that we control all three &#8212; obviously Congress, the House and Senate as well. <br> <br>What is also true is that the pandemic was going on before he took office; that fighting this historic pandemic &#8212; which has been front and center for his agenda, we know, and every economist will tell you this &#8212; has been the major driver of inflation over the past year-plus and we&#8217;ve continued to fight the pandemic since then.<br> <br>We&#8217;ve also heard Chairman Powell, Secretary Yellen, and others convey &#8212; and we&#8217;ve seen this in nearly every element of data we&#8217;ve seen on inflation since Pu- &#8212; President Putin invaded Ukraine &#8212; that energy prices account for the majority of inflationary increases over the past several weeks since the war began. <br> <br>So, you don&#8217;t have to take my word for it; that&#8217;s what economists and data have told us.<br> <br>What our focus is on &#8212; and you heard the President say this today &#8212; is not whether inflation is or isn&#8217;t an issue.  We all agree it&#8217;s an issue.  What our plan is and what the President&#8217;s plan is to address costs and bring down costs is what he outlined this morning.  It&#8217;s a multi-step plan. <br> <br>What are we seeing on the other side?  We&#8217;re seeing the plan proposed by Chairman Scott, which would instead raise costs on the American people and sunset or end &#8212; whatever you want to call it &#8212; Medicare and Social Security.<br> <br>Q    But last week, Chairman Powell did say that partly what the Fed did, as well as spending from Congress, is the reason that we&#8217;re in this high inflation environment.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He also talked about energy pri- &#8212; the invasion and the impact on energy prices, did he not? <br> <br>Q    He did.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, that seems like an important part of context, doesn&#8217;t it?<br> <br>Q    But it wasn&#8217;t until one year into the presidency that the invasion happened.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  And you&#8217;re asking me about recent inflationary data, which we know 60 to 70 percent of is because of energy prices, which even Chairman Powell quoted and said was because of the invasion of Ukraine.  Right?  Okay.<br> <br>Go ahead, April.<br> <br>Q    Jen, a couple of questions &#8212; one on abortion, following up on these meetings.  Has the President in recent weeks been more deliberate in his conversations as to who he&#8217;s talking with about the issue of abortion and this leaked draft has come &#8212; that came out on the opinion &#8212; possible opinion?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  When you say “more deliberate,” do you mean have we been having more conversations?  Or tell me more about what you mean.<br> <br>Q    (Inaudible) the President of the United States been more deliberate in who he&#8217;s talking with &#8212; abortion advocates or pro-lifers, pro-choicers?  Has he been talking to &#8212; more deliberate in talking to Schumer?  Has he been more deliberate in his conversations about abortion since this leak?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yes, but so has the entire administration.  And he has asked the Gender Policy Council, the Department of Health and Human Services, his Counsel&#8217;s Office to put together a plan and proposal, which he&#8217;s been engaged in meetings about, to discuss what we should prepare to do to protect women&#8217;s basic fundamental rights that have been the law of the land for 50 years. <br> <br>I think there&#8217;s no question, not just for Americans who care deeply about this but for the President as well, that this leaked opinion, whether it&#8217;s final or not &#8212; which we know the Supreme Court has said it&#8217;s not and they need to issue a final one at the appropriate time &#8212; has raised the alarm bells about what is at risk here, even though we have seen prior to this, you know, a number &#8212; 288 Republicans sign on to the amicus brief on the Mississippi case. <br> <br>So, it&#8217;s not that the effort to overturn Roe v. Wade is new; that has been ongoing for decades.  But certainly, this leaked draft raised the concern, raised the alarms, and certainly has heightened our focus on preparing what options are possible.<br> <br>Q    Right, since 1973.  You know, there&#8217;s been a stronger fight since all this happened.  But now you have people like Elizabeth Warren and Senator Schumer who are pushing this hard.  Has he been in conversations with both of them, and is he planning on talking to them before tomorrow?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We&#8217;ve been in touch with a range of senators.  We don&#8217;t read out those conversations as it relates to him from here.<br> <br>Q    (Inaudible) from the President.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I understand.  We don&#8217;t read them out per his ask.  So, he has a range of conversations.  It&#8217;s rare that I&#8217;m in the Oval Office and he doesn&#8217;t pick up the call &#8212; pick up the phone and call a member of Congress.  So, I can assure you he is in touch with a range of members.  And, obviously, this is front and center on their minds as are other issues. <br> <br>But certainly we will continue to assess directly with Congress.<br> <br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br> <br>Q    Wait a minute.  I&#8217;m not finished.  Please!<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Go ahead, April.<br> <br>Q    All right, so the next question on inflation.  The President has drilled down and administration officials have drilled down on issues of price gouging &#8212; going back to Kaitlan’s question, but this is more on a broader scale. <br> <br>The Agriculture Secretary came here a few months ago &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; talking about price gouging.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    He called out Tyson Foods &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; people who are profiting.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Record profits yesterday.<br> <br>Q    Right.  What&#8217;s hap- &#8212; across the board, you have gas companies that are profiting.  You have food companies that are profiting.  Consumers are having a hard time dealing with what&#8217;s at the grocery store and at the pump.<br> <br>Is the President going to start putting more of a focus on this profiteering or price-gouging issue?  Because you&#8217;re seeing these numbers from Tyson, you&#8217;re hearing about what&#8217;s happening at the pump.  And he even talked about &#8212; he asked local gas stations to look at the prices and see if they could make a cut themselves.  Is there going to be an extra focus or a more concerted focus on this issue of price gouging?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah &#8212; you heard the President talk about it this morning.  And tomorrow, he&#8217;s going to be traveling to Illinois where he&#8217;s going to be talking about how we need to continue to help small farmers on agriculture. <br> <br>So, we have talked about this, we have elevated it, and we want to make sure people across the country understand that some of these conglomerates &#8212; you mentioned the meat industry, but also oil and gas industry &#8212; should not be raising prices on consumers while they are making record profits. <br> <br>Okay, thank &#8212; let me &#8212; let me do Lynn Sweet because I have a soft spot for her. <br> <br>Lynn Sweet, go ahead.  Lynn Sweet.  Lynn Sweet, let&#8217;s hear it.  Lynn Sweet is going to ask a question.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.  And this relates to his visit to Kankakee.  And &#8212; (laughs) &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Lynn, thank you.  I should have found a friend on the pronunciation.  I practiced it.  I didn&#8217;t get it right.  I should have seen you here. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Okay, so on his visit to Kankakee and Chicago, I have noticed, as others have, that &#8212; the language that you used today and a bit in recent days on calling this “Putin’s price hike” and “Ultra-MAGA.”  I&#8217;m curious: When you go to the IBEW to talk about supporting the new jobs, infrastructure, energy issues, and the record on those issues, is this effective language to use in that kind of audience?  Because when you go to Kankakee, it&#8217;s really your event.  And it&#8217;s clear you don&#8217;t have to worry about an audience reacting one way or the other.  Could you speak to that?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think when he goes &#8212; he&#8217;s visiting a family farm in Kankakee.  How did I do there?  Okay.  And so, when he&#8217;s there, he&#8217;s really going to talk about the role of American farmers and the amazing agricultural sector we have in this country and the role that all Americans are playing in standing up for democracy and against autocracy. <br> <br>We think of it often as weapons &#8212; and obviously he went to the Javelin plant last week &#8212; but it&#8217;s also about providing American food that&#8217;s produced here in this country and what can we do more to produce more.  So that&#8217;s what those remarks will be more about.<br> <br>I have not yet looked at the remarks he will give at the IBEW tomorrow afternoon, but I can tell you you will &#8212; whether it&#8217;s tomorrow or in days and weeks ahead, people &#8212; you will all continue to hear him talk more about his concern about Ultra-MAGA Republicans and their agenda.  And, of course, this is not the last you&#8217;ve heard from us about Chairman Scott&#8217;s tax plan that will raise taxes. <br> <br>Okay, thanks, everyone.<br> <br>3:30 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
