<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 11:57:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden on the Return of Trevor&#160;Reed</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/27/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-the-return-of-trevor-reed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 11:57:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we welcome home Trevor Reed and celebrate his return to the family that missed him dearly. Trevor, a former U.S. Marine, is free from Russian detention. I heard in the voices of Trevor’s parents how much they’ve worried about his health and missed his presence. And I was delighted to be able to share&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we welcome home Trevor Reed and celebrate his return to the family that missed him dearly. Trevor, a former U.S. Marine, is free from Russian detention. I heard in the voices of Trevor’s parents how much they’ve worried about his health and missed his presence. And I was delighted to be able to share with them the good news about Trevor’s freedom.</p>



<p>I’m grateful for the tireless and dedicated work of Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs Roger Carstens, U.S. Ambassador to the Russian Federation John Sullivan, and many others across our government to ensure that Trevor came home safely. The negotiations that allowed us to bring Trevor home required difficult decisions that I do not take lightly. His safe return is a testament to the priority my Administration places on bringing home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained abroad. We won’t stop until Paul Whelan and others join Trevor in the loving arms of family and friends.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki and White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Coordinator Dr. Ashish&#160;Jha</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/26/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-white-house-covid-19-response-coordinator-dr-ashish-jha/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 22:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:09 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Hi.&#160; How are you? MS. PSAKI:&#160; Great.&#160; Okay.&#160; Today, as promised, we have the premiere of Dr. Ashish Jha, our new White House COVID Response Coordinator, in the briefing room. Dr. Jha will be talking about two important pieces of work&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:09 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; How are you?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Today, as promised, we have the premiere of Dr. Ashish Jha, our new White House COVID Response Coordinator, in the briefing room.<br><br>Dr. Jha will be talking about two important pieces of work in our &#8212; we are working on with Congress: first, expanding access to lifesaving COVID-19 treatments; and second, our urgent need for funding from Congress.</p>



<p>He has time just to take a very small number of questions today, but he will be &#8212; come back af- &#8212; soon, I’m sure.<br><br>So, with that, I will turn it over to him, and then we’ll proceed with a normal briefing.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well, it’s great to be with all of you.&nbsp; A little exciting and a little scary to be with this crowd.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>So I want to take a minute to talk about where we are with the pandemic.&nbsp; We are &#8212; I believe we are at an inflection point.&nbsp; On one hand, we know that BA.2, the subvariant of Omicron, has become dominant; cases are rising across the country.&nbsp; But hospitalizations are at the lowest level of the pandemic &#8212; right? &#8212; and deaths are continuing to fall.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re down to about 300 deaths a day &#8212; still too many, still too high, but doing so much for the &#8212; better than we have throughout much of this pandemic.</p>



<p>Despite all of that progress &#8212; and I think a lot of that is driven by the fact that we have more than 200 million Americans vaccinated, more than 100 million Americans boosted &#8212; we know this virus is tricky.&nbsp;<br><br>We know that the risk of potential surges, even of a potential new variant, remains out there.<br><br>The good news is we are at a point where we have a lot more capabilities, a lot more tools to protect the American people: testing, vaccines, therapeutics.&nbsp; These are the &#8212; sort of the pillars of how we manage the rest of this pandemic.<br><br>And that&#8217;s why what I want to do is spend some time talking to you about those tools, about our capabilities, what we&#8217;re doing as an administration, and what we need from Congress to continue to protect the American people.</p>



<p>So, first, I want to talk about Paxlovid, the &#8212; the therapy that is become &#8212; is becoming increasingly available to the American people.</p>



<p>For those of you who have not followed this very closely, Paxlovid became authorized by the FDA in late December.&nbsp; At that point, there was just a very limited supply of these pills.</p>



<p>The clinical data suggests that it has an enormously beneficial impact, reduces hospitalizations by more than 90 percent, and is very, very effective at preventing severe disease.</p>



<p>Over the last few months, the administration has worked very hard with Pfizer to increase the supply of Paxlovid and acquire more and more doses for the American people.</p>



<p>And now our job is to make sure that these doses are getting out there and they&#8217;re getting into &#8212; into the hands of patients who would benefit from them.</p>



<p>So, what are we doing?&nbsp; And I want to talk about four major things.</p>



<p>The first is: We are opening up the number of sites that can order directly from the federal government supplies of Paxlovid.</p>



<p>Until &#8212; until this recent change, the way pharmacies got Paxlovid &#8212; either you were a Test to Treat site or you got it from your state.&nbsp; But now we&#8217;re opening up a federal ha- &#8212; a federal pharmacy channel.&nbsp; And what that means is pharmacies can order directly from the federal government.</p>



<p>Currently, there are about 20,000 sites in the United States that carry Paxlovid.&nbsp; We expect with this change that we will very quickly get to 30,000.&nbsp; And within the next couple of weeks, I expect us to get to about 40,000 sites.</p>



<p>Paxlovid will be widely available everywhere in America.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to help a lot.</p>



<p>The second is: The President announced the Test to Treat effort that we have launched.&nbsp; Right now, there are about 2,200 Test to Treat sites across the country.&nbsp; And we are going to make a series of efforts to expand the number of Test to Treat sites, including new federal initiatives that will allow for us to build on other federal testing sites to allow for &#8212; for those to also have a treatment component.&nbsp; So if you test positive, you can go and get treated with Paxlovid, of course if you are eligible and deemed so by a &#8212; by a provider.</p>



<p>Third is: We really are doubling down on our communication and education efforts with physicians and other prescribers.</p>



<p>In the beginning, when the &#8212; when the &#8212; when Paxlovid first became available, the word on the street was these things are not widely available, you should restrict it to the highest risk patients.&nbsp; Too many physicians still have that mindset, and what we need to do is to help American physicians and nurse practitioners and others who can prescribe understand that we now have plenty available.&nbsp; And anybody who is eligible, anybody who&#8217;s high risk, should be getting Paxlovid, obviously based &#8212; as long as they meet the clinical criteria.&nbsp; And so that education campaign is going to be really important.</p>



<p>And then last but certainly not least is we&#8217;re ramping up our public awareness campaign so that patients also understand that if they test positive, they should consider going to a Test to Treat site or reach out to their physician, but to get assessed for whether Paxlovid would be useful for them.</p>



<p>Those are all really critical steps that I think are going to make an enormous difference in getting more Paxlovid out to the community, to getting it out to patients.&nbsp; And with a very simple goal &#8212; right? &#8212; which is we want to lower the severity of the disease that people get if they get infected, and we want to lower hospitalizations, we want to lower deaths.<br><br>Paxlovid is a really important step in our ability to fight this pandemic.</p>



<p>Treatments like these vaccines that we have developed &#8211;these are the key, essential tools that we&#8217;re going to need to get through the rest of this pandemic.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the second part of the conversation I want to have with all of you, because all of this requires funding from Congress.</p>



<p>So far, Congress has not stepped up to provide the funds that are needed for our most urgent needs.</p>



<p>Now, I know they were off on a two-week recess; they are back.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking forward to working with Congress &#8212; we all are &#8212; to get the funding needs of the American people met on this &#8212; on the issue of COVID and COVID treatments.</p>



<p>Let me give you a couple of concrete examples of what will happen if we do not get the funding we need.</p>



<p>You may have heard, if you&#8217;ve been tracking this, that FDA is working with Moderna and Pfizer, looking at what the next generation of vaccines may look like.&nbsp; And it is possible that we may get a whole new generation of vaccines in the fall or winter that may be more effective and more durable.</p>



<p>None of those are going to be available to the American people if we don&#8217;t get more funding.</p>



<p>We are tracking new treatments that are coming online that are as effective, maybe even more effective, with fewer side effects.&nbsp;Those treatments will not be available to Americans because other countries are stepping up and making purchases for those treatments while we await funding from Congress.</p>



<p>The bottom line is that none of us can predict with any certainty where exactly this pandemic is going, what the virus is going to do next.&nbsp; All we can do is prepare.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we need Congress to do, is to help us prepare and be ready for whatever eventuality comes.</p>



<p>Let me make one last point that I want to &#8212; think is incredibly important, and that is that there are some people in this country who sometimes think that we can take a domestic-only approach to a global pandemic.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a thing.&nbsp; You can&#8217;t do that.</p>



<p>If we&#8217;re going to fight a global pandemic, we have to have a global approach.&nbsp; That means we need funding to ensure that we&#8217;re getting shots in arms around the world.</p>



<p>The President and his leadership has enabled us to now have plenty of vaccines for the world.&nbsp; But vaccines don&#8217;t save lives, right?&nbsp; Vaccinations do.&nbsp; We have got to finish the job.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to get the resources we need to get shots in arms so we can actually vaccinate the world and help bring this pandemic to a close.</p>



<p>So those are &#8212; those are the essential things that are in front of us.&nbsp; This will require a partnership between the administration and Congress.&nbsp; I am confident that Congress will deliver for the American people.&nbsp; And I look forward to working with them on that.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Chris.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Every time a high-profile person, like the Vice President, catches COVID, there’s more attention on the infection.&nbsp; For Americans following that news, what lessons should they draw from that experience if somebody as protected as her has caught COVID?<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Good question.&nbsp; So I think if you take a step back and look at the Vice President, she is boosted &#8212; she’s actually twice boosted.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>We have a very, very contagious variant out there.&nbsp; It is going to be hard to ensure that no one gets COVID in America.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not even a policy goal.</p>



<p>The goal of our policies should be, obviously, minimize&nbsp;infections whenever possible, but to make sure people don’t get seriously ill.&nbsp;<br><br>The best ways of doing that are making sure people are vaccinated and boosted, as the Vice President is, and making sure we have plenty of therapeutics so, you know &#8212; so that that is available as well.&nbsp; And that, to me, is the key lesson here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has she received any therapeutics?&nbsp; Since we’re on the topic of therapeutics.<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; You know, that&#8217;s a conversation that she&#8217;s having with her physician.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not her physician; I&#8217;m not privy to those conversations.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t know the answer to that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Cecilia.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Jha.&nbsp; Welcome to the briefing room, by the way.<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To your point that so many Americans can and will get this: In this report that just came out today, that 60 percent of Americans have had &#8212; it appears have had COVID, the President is getting ready to ramp up his travel schedule; the Vice President just caught it.&nbsp; She&#8217;s twice boosted.&nbsp; Should Americans be prepared for a time when President Biden gets this?&nbsp; Is it just a matter of time that the President could get COVID?<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t say it&#8217;s “just a matter of time.”&nbsp; But of course, it is possible that the President, like any other American, could get COVID.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line is: He is vaccinated and boosted.&nbsp; He is very well protected.&nbsp; He&#8217;s got very good protocols around him to protect him from getting infected.&nbsp; But there is no 100 percent anything.&nbsp; And I think the key focus has got to be: We got to continue protecting the President.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the protocols around him are designed to do.<br><br>Yeah, let me just &#8212; let me leave it at that.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tam.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Part of the congressional funding is to potentially deal with the uninsured fund that has run out of money.&nbsp; What does the uninsured fund, not having any money in it, mean for Paxlovid?&nbsp; Or if someone who&#8217;s uninsured gets COVID right now, what does that mean for them?<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, so first of all, Paxlovid itself will be free, because the &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They have to see a doctor?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; They have to see a &#8212; someone who can actually prescribe it for them.&nbsp; And this is &#8212; one of the absolutely critical things in a pandemic is that people need to be able to access healthcare.&nbsp; It turns out it&#8217;s also critical not in a pandemic.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp;<br><br>But &#8212; but particularly in a pandemic with an infectious disease, it&#8217;s really important that people be able to access healthcare services, get the care they need.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good for them; it&#8217;s good for people around them.&nbsp; And so, making sure uninsured people have access is absolutely critical.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, right now, what does that look like?&nbsp; If someone gets COVID and they&#8217;re uninsured, are they able to get treatment?&nbsp; Are they able to get tests?&nbsp; Or does CVS just eat the cost?&nbsp; How does that work right now?&nbsp;<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; So, I think, right now, because we don&#8217;t have the funding, there&#8217;s a little bit of patchwork of what is happening.&nbsp; There are obviously places that serve uninsured people &#8212; community health centers, others people can get care.&nbsp; There are still &#8212; people are still going to CVS and other places that still are offering those services.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s not a sustainable solution.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>So, right now, we&#8217;re in this kind of middle ground where people are still getting care.&nbsp; But over time, if Congress continues to not fund these urgent priorities, it&#8217;s going to get harder and harder for people to access care.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kristen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This will be the last one too.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; He’ll be back soon.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Jha.&nbsp; Thank you so much for being here.&nbsp; Just a couple of questions.&nbsp; One, can you tell us: Was President Biden tested today, and has he tested negative?&nbsp; Do we know the last time he tested negative?&nbsp;<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not involved in the President&#8217;s testing protocols.&nbsp; So I am &#8212; I just don&#8217;t know the answer to the question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He was tested yesterday, and he tested negative.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On Paxlovid, I just want to be crystal clear, because you&#8217;re trying to expand access to it, but you still say “if people meet the medical requirements.”<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does that mean that Paxlovid should only be taken by people of a certain age and who are immunocompromised, or that it should be taken by anyone who has symptoms?<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; So &#8212; so, neither.&nbsp; FDA has laid out a very clear set of criteria for who should get Paxlovid, and, very basically, it&#8217;s anybody who&#8217;s at high risk of developing complications.&nbsp; And the FDA points to a CDC assessment.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a long list.&nbsp; I can read it all to you, but, of course, age is important, presence of chronic diseases.&nbsp;<br><br>But the bottom line is that &#8212; and what I am recommending to family and friends is &#8212; if you get COVID, you should see a provider and make that assessment with your provider.&nbsp; A lot more people are eligible and bene- &#8212; would benefit than I think people think.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just very quickly, can you help us to understand this moment that we are in?&nbsp; Because on the one hand, cases are going up, particularly on the East Coast.&nbsp; As you have said, hospitalization and deaths are going down.&nbsp; But is the country in the midst of a surge?<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; What I would say is, you know, we are going to see cases go up and go down during this pandemic as we &#8212; as we head into the mont- &#8212; weeks, months, and years ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The key things that we need to be following are: “Are healthcare systems getting stressed?”&nbsp; “Are people ending up in the hospital with severe illness?”&nbsp; Obviously, “Are people dying at high rates?”&nbsp; Those are the &#8212; in my mind, the most important metrics.<br><br>And right now, while infection numbers are rising &#8212; and, of course, we all want to see infection numbers coming down &#8212; the good news is, because of the extraordinary work of this administration, we&#8217;ve got Americans much better protected.&nbsp; And that means that we&#8217;re not seeing a huge bump in hospitalizations, that deaths are still declining.&nbsp; Obviously, we want to continue tracking those metrics.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Jha.&nbsp; You’re invited anytime.<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Dr. Jha.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Okay, a couple items at the top.&nbsp;<br><br>Today &#8212; we announced this morning that during Second Chance Month, President Biden made a number of announcements focused on second chances and reentry, which, as leaders on both sides of the aisle recognize, will help prevent and reduce crime and strengthen our communities.<br><br>The President announced 75 sentence commutations and 3 full pardons.&nbsp; All of these individuals were convicted of non-violent drug offenses, and many have been successfully serving their time on home confinement.<br><br>He also announced more than 20 major actions from a dozen agencies to expand second-chance opportunities.&nbsp; This includes a first-of-its-kind partnership between the Department of Justice and the Department of Labor to invest $145 million in job training and intensive reentry in federal prisons.&nbsp; It also includes steps that will make more incarcerated students eligible for Pell Grants, make it easier for those who were incarcerated to enroll in Medicare, and help formerly incarcerated veterans get their benefits restored.<br><br>As we speak, Susan Rice, Dana Remus, and Cedric Richmond are holding a virtual roundtable with six formerly incarcerated individuals to discuss the President’s first clemency announcement, the new reentry policies and programs we announced today.<br><br>Today’s announcement mark import- &#8212; marks important progress, and we will continue to review &#8212; the President will continue to review clemency petitions and deliver reforms that advance equal justice and public safety.<br><br>I also wanted to note that, today, Secretary Austin &#8212; you may have seen &#8212; hosted a meeting of the Ukraine Defense Consultative Group with ministers of defense and chiefs of defense from more than 40 countries at Ramstein Air Base in Germany.<br><br>The goal is to bring together countries from around the world for a series of meetings on the latest Ukraine defense needs to help Ukraine win the fight against Russia’s unjust invasion, and to help Ukraine’s defenses for tomorrow’s challenges.<br><br>As Secretary Austin said, it was an important and constructive day.&nbsp; Agenda topics today included near-time &#8212; near-term priorities and longer-term planning; the latest battlefield assessments of the renewed Russian offensive; establishing a framework for prioritizing requirements and logistics for resupply; and energizing the defense industrial base to continue the steady flow of security assistance.<br><br>More than 30 countries have now stepped up to meet Ukraine’s urgent needs and have committed more than $5 billion of equipment, including $3.7 billion from the United States, to support Ukraine’s defenses.&nbsp;<br><br>We also wanted to welcome an important announcement by our German allies today to send Ukraine some 50 Cheetah anti-aircraft systems.&nbsp;<br><br>We would also highlight the British government’s announcement yesterday that it will provide Ukraine with additional anti-aircraft capabilities and Canada’s announcement that it will send Ukraine armored vehicles.<br><br>I believe that’s it.&nbsp; Why don’t we jump around to people who didn’t get questions initially.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A quick question on Dr. Jha talking about cases going up and the VP testing positive.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about whether the administration and society as a whole perhaps have moved away a bit too quickly from mitigation efforts such as masking?&nbsp; And is the administration perhaps thinking about strengthening any of those measures, especially the ones that were loosened?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, those decisions and those recommendations are made by the CDC and our public health officials.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you.&nbsp; Those are decisions that they make, and we obviously abide by that from here.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;d remind you that their recommendations include &#8212; are based on what zone of the country you live in &#8212; right? &#8212; whether it is a green zone, a yellow zone, or a zone that has a higher rate. &nbsp;And they continue to recommend masking on transportation on fed- &#8212; you know, that we &#8212; and we abide by that from here as well.<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t have any changes on that to preview.<br><br>But as Dr. Jha noted, our focus &#8212; and as we noted when we rolled out our 100-page plan &#8212; continues to be on tracking and reducing hospitalizations and deaths.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re certainly aware that a very &#8212; with a very transmissible variant, that there &#8212; we expect that there could be case increases, as we&#8217;ve seen over the last few weeks with BA.2.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, even in the regions that are witnessing a surge, I mean, there is &#8212; there are no discussions that perhaps you can talk about &#8212; about, you know, what these latest, sort of, surge in cases could potentially lead to?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, but masking requirements change depending on what the numbers look like in your community.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And a quick one on the EU.&nbsp; Reuters is reporting that the EU plans to declare that it is entering a new post-emergency phase for COVID.&nbsp; Given, sort of, the uptick in cases in the U.S., I&#8217;m wondering if you can talk a little bit about that timing.&nbsp; I mean, is that unusual?&nbsp; Or do you think it is the right time for the &#8212; for countries around the world to be headed towards that goal, and if the U.S. is perhaps considering announcing something similar going forward?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; you mean an end of the emergency?&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview.&nbsp; Again, those recommendations are made by our public health and medical experts, so we rely on them for their guidance on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask one on Ukraine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, just earlier today, the announcement from Germany on a new package for heavier weapons &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That obviously comes, you know, as Russia has said that such assistance would lead to a nuclear war.&nbsp; And it sort of seemed like the U.S. was brushing off Russia&#8217;s recent nuclear threat.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if the administration &#8212; to what extent is it really taking this latest threat seriously?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think you heard some of our national security officials make clear there&#8217;s no winning a nuclear war.&nbsp; And obviously, our objective continues to be to call on reducing the rhetoric, on taking the rhetoric on that front down.<br><br>And I think there have been some officials who have abided by that.&nbsp; But I would note that the announcement by Germany is in line with announcements we&#8217;ve seen by a number of European countries in providing assistance they have never before provided, which is part of the significance here.&nbsp;<br><br>So, this is an unprecedented change to provide lethal aid to another country, and that&#8217;s the significance here from Germany.&nbsp; But I&#8217;d also note that Norway provided Mistral anti-air missiles, that a number of countries have provided types of assistance that they have never done in the past.&nbsp; And that really speaks to the signi- &#8212; the unity of NATO, of European countries in confronting what we see as, of course, a horrific war in Ukraine launched by the Russians.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it possible that there might be any updates to protocols &#8212; COVID protocols within the White House in light of Vice President Harris testing positive for COVID?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would not expect that, no.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So there have been no discussions, and you don&#8217;t expect that for the time being?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s important to remember that we have stringent protocols here that go over and above CDC recommendations, even as it relates to how long you stay at home if you test positive.&nbsp; So, individuals who test positive for &#8212; here &#8212; and I can speak to this two times over.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t return to work until you have &#8212; you have received a negative test.&nbsp; If that is before 10 days, you are still going to be masking.&nbsp; That is beyond what CDC protocols are.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s a regular testing cadence.&nbsp; Obviously, the Vice President was tested this morning because of that regular testing cadence.&nbsp; And for the rest of us, anyone who&#8217;s going to be around the President, to travel with him, to see him in the Oval Office is tested that day.&nbsp; And even if you&#8217;re not going to see him, you&#8217;re on a regular testing cadence around here.<br><br>We also take the step to socially distance in meetings as frequently as we can.&nbsp; And also, a number of us have chosen to wear masks in meetings as well just as an additional step and protocol.&nbsp;<br><br>So those have been in place prior to today, and we will continue to abide by those moving forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on a different topic: Senator Manchin told reporters this morning that there is not a Build Back Better revival.&nbsp; He said that social spending programs, he believes, should go through a regular order, not through the reconciliation process.&nbsp; I wondered if you could explain just from the White House&#8217;s perspective how you all are thinking about reconciliation versus regular order, in terms of wanting to get done some of the President&#8217;s top legislative priorities.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you&#8217;ve heard the President say many times that he believes that a lot of the objectives he has should be achievable through bipartisan work together.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not Democrats to &#8212; you know, Democrats shouldn&#8217;t be able to own efforts to reduce prescription drug costs or the ability to negotiate the price of prescription drugs, nor should we be the ones completely owning, on our own, efforts to lower the cost of childcare or healthcare.&nbsp; Those aren&#8217;t Democratic ideals.&nbsp; Those should be &#8212; those are &#8212; those are proposals that are broadly supported by many Americans across the country.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we &#8212; we know that Senator Manchin has, of course, talked about his efforts to pursue a bipartisan package or bipartisan plan as it relates to energy costs, and we&#8217;re not going to prejudge that effort.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to continue to engage with a broad range of Democrats, including, of course, Senator Manchin about how to get the President&#8217;s agenda done.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there anything you can tell us about the President&#8217;s schedule today?&nbsp; There wasn&#8217;t anything publicly announced.&nbsp; Is he in touch with members of Congress, particularly since they&#8217;re coming back this week?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I expect he will have a range of conversations and engagements with members of Congress.&nbsp; He also has a range of internal meetings, policy meetings, planning meetings.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing more I can preview on that from here.&nbsp; But if &#8212; if there&#8217;s more I can tell you after the briefing, I&#8217;m happy to do that.<br><br>Go ahead, Weijia.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll start with something else Senator Manchin said &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; since we’re just talking about him.&nbsp; He said today: We need an immigration policy, and Title 42 should not be done away with until we get an immigration policy or until the CDC basically says we no longer have a health crisis.&nbsp; What does it say about the communication with members of the President&#8217;s own party that Senator Manchin believes that Title 42 is an immigration tool?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak to that necessarily.&nbsp; I can tell you that &#8212; what it is and isn&#8217;t.&nbsp; It is not an immigration tool; it is a health authority and one the CDC &#8212; our health experts, of course &#8212; do have authority to make a decision about. And they&#8217;ve made the decision that the conditions no longer exist to keep Title 42 in place.<br><br>We do agree with him.&nbsp; Absolutely, there should be an immigration policy, and there should be immigration reforms, and they are long overdue.&nbsp; And we&#8217;d love to work with him and any other members on moving that forward.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does it concern you that he&#8217;s saying that Title 42 should not be done away with until there is an immigration policy?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s just not how it works.&nbsp; Obviously, Title 42 is &#8212; the authority was given to the CDC by Congress.&nbsp; They made a decision.&nbsp; If Congress wants to decide &#8212; make any decisions about the next steps for Title 42, they can work together on that.&nbsp; But that is an authority or a decision that have to &#8212; would have to lay in the body that he works in.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; I have a follow-up on what Dr. Jha said about Test to Treat sites.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the administration doing to expand those sites, including converting some testing sites to have a treatment component?&nbsp; What are the challenges to that?&nbsp; And do you have any timeframe for when you expect to ramp up those facilities?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a really good question, Weijia.&nbsp; I’ll probably have to talk to Dr. Jha and others from the healthcare team about it.&nbsp; And next time, he’ll take more questions, I promise.&nbsp;<br><br>You are right, there are some challenges, just like any aspect of applying COVID policy or COVID treatment policies or COVID &#8212; efforts to fight COVID policies, in that we have to educate a large swatch of public, including healthcare providers, about this works or how it would work.&nbsp; There is continued efforts to do that, but I&#8217;m happy to check with them on expansion plans or how that might work.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one more quick one on vaccines for children under five.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The group Protect their Future is just one of many groups that are urging the FDA to consider Moderna’s application for an EUA before June, which is when Pfizer will also submit theirs.&nbsp; What is your response to these groups who are concerned that appears &#8212; concerned that it appears the administration is doing Pfizer a favor by waiting to consider both Moderna and Pfizer at the same time, when Moderna’s data is already ready for review by the end of this week?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;d really point you to the FDA for their decision-making process.&nbsp; But I would tell you that, of course, as a parent of a child under five, I&#8217;m eager to have vaccines approved and available, and I want to make sure they go through the proper protocols and process.&nbsp; But I would point you to the FDA.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on clemency &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; there are 18,000 petitions pending for clemency.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President planning to increase his pace for consideration as he talked about possibly doing?&nbsp; And also, is there consideration about a permanent clemency review process that would, you know, kind of institutionalize this process going forward?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me &#8212; it&#8217;s important to note that the President has issued more sentence commutations at this early point in his presidency than any of the la- &#8212; his last five predecessors at the same point in their first terms.<br><br>So we are far ahead of anyone, any of the last five Presidents.&nbsp; That is because this is a priority to the President.&nbsp; And as I noted, when I &#8212; at the top of this briefing, he feels this is &#8212; second chances are important, and he believes this is absolutely a right step in our justice system.&nbsp;<br><br>He is &#8212; he&#8217;s going to continue to review clemency petitions, and that is going to be an ongoing process.&nbsp; That is, of course, run through our Counsel&#8217;s Office.&nbsp; So it doesn&#8217;t stop here; it will be ongoing, and there will be more in the future.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On Title 42, we&#8217;ve heard you guys say that this is a public health order, it&#8217;s not an immigration order, it&#8217;s the CDC’s decision.&nbsp; But yesterday, members of the Congressional Hispanic Caucus, who met with the President, relayed some of what he expressed in that meeting.&nbsp; And one of them said that the President told the group that he was looking forward to lifting Title 42, describing it as an excuse to keep people out of the country and anti-immigrant.&nbsp; Is the President really wanting Title 42 to go away because it was a Trump-era policy?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President has never felt that Title 42 was a &#8212; an effective immigration policy, and he talked about that during the campaign.&nbsp; But the authority has always rested in the CDC to make that determination.&nbsp; And he left the CDC to make that determination, unlike his predecessor, about a range of decisions.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the President has never &#8212; never made a secret of the fact that he thinks immigration reform is necessary and that Title 42 was never a replacement for comprehensive immigration reform that would put in place smarter security, that would ensure there was an asylum processing system that worked.&nbsp; And that is something he would be eager to work with anyone on to get done.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So if this &#8212; conditions warranted it, would the White House want to see the CDC reimpose Title 42 in the instance that the cases are up and the metrics that they use to measure that warrant that decision?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the CDC, again, has the authority to make a determination about what the health conditions warrant, so we will leave it to them to make any decisions or recommendations.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, with the Vice President being out &#8212; obviously, she&#8217;s broken a lot of ties for votes &#8212; and then we have senators; I believe Warre- &#8212; Wyden and Murphy also out &#8212; is there any concern about ability to get confirmations through this week with her absence?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say there are also some Democrats who have announced that they have also tested positive for COVID.&nbsp; You may be referring to the Federal Reserve nominees or others.&nbsp; That is something that members and leaders will work through in Congress.&nbsp; We are confident we have the votes to get them confirmed.&nbsp; We&#8217;re eager to have them in place.&nbsp; But, of course, we need all of people &#8212; all members there to do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then I had one follow-up on Dr. Jha &#8212; something that he said earlier.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’ve talked about the administration surging resources to the border &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; including resources to vaccinate migrants.&nbsp; And the last time I asked about this, I believe your answer was something along the lines of, “We have enough funding and supply to take care of the 23 sites that DHS is going to be running to get migrants vaccinated and also take care of uninsured Americans.”&nbsp; But it sounded, in his answer, like that might not be the case anymore.&nbsp; So are we in a place now where there might be a choice where people would have to choose or the administration would have to choose between supplying resources to migrants coming across the border versus taking care of uninsured Americans?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check on those resources, Jacqui.&nbsp; I would say that our broad concern about COVID funding is based on a couple of issues that he talked about.&nbsp; One of them is making sure that we are ahead of the world on being able to order ahead, primarily, a lot of different treatments that will help ensure that we have the best vaccines, the best boosters, enough supply once individuals under 50 are eligible.&nbsp;<br><br>And certainly, we want to keep all of our programs running across the country.&nbsp; But &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just have one more on the Hunter Biden reporting that we&#8217;ve seen come out.&nbsp; Does the President still maintain that he never spoke with his son about his business dealings? And given this reporting on Eric Schwerin, does he also say that he has never spoken to his son&#8217;s business partners about his son&#8217;s business dealings?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He maintains his same statements that he&#8217;s made in the past.&nbsp; I would say &#8212; I know you&#8217;re referring to WAVES records that were released more than 10 years ago.&nbsp; I really don&#8217;t have more detail or information on them.&nbsp; I&#8217;d note that there was a gap when WAVES records were not released, but I don&#8217;t have more information about visits from more than 10 years ago.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, well, let me go around to people who haven&#8217;t gotten &#8212; go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thanks.&nbsp; Two questions on the war on Ukraine.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First of all, on food aid &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; does the administration have any idea of how much<br>money you&#8217;ll need yet for global food aid, given the shortfalls into the war on Ukraine?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So &#8212; well, let me first say that we are not expecting a food shortage here at home, but we are acting to bolster food security around the globe, both unilaterally and in conjunction with allies and partners.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>One of the steps we&#8217;re taking is we&#8217;re really conducting extensive diplomacy to encourage all countries to refrain from export restrictions and excessive stockpiling &#8212; obviously, buying up or not exporting goods or products they would normally do &#8212; because it can exacerbate supply chall- &#8212; chain challenges and price inflation.&nbsp; And we want to consider how to expand production of key areas where we could see that happening: oil seeds and associated commodities.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re also working through multilateral channels, including the G7, to provide a range of funding to the Global Agriculture and Food Security Program.&nbsp; A $1.7 billion multilateral financing mechanism is part of what we&#8217;ve done there that has helped the world&#8217;s poorest countries increase investments in agriculture and food security as we&#8217;re anticipating global &#8212; shortages in some regions of the world.&nbsp;<br><br>And through Feed the Future, our new nutrition commitments, we&#8217;re also committing over $11 billion over the next five years to address food security threats and nutrition across the globe in addition to the over $4 billion in humanitarian assistance funding.<br><br>So we&#8217;ve taken a number of steps &#8212; funding mechanisms &#8212; you know, multilateral financing mechanisms; also contributing and trying to use through diplomatic channels, you know, efforts to prevent stockpiling and decreasing of exports, because we anticipate it could be an issue, and we&#8217;re already seeing that in some parts of the world.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So no idea what the global overall total would be for how much food &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we have a prediction of that at this point.&nbsp; So what we&#8217;re trying to do is we&#8217;re trying to get ahead of what we anticipate being&nbsp;a shortage or an impact in some parts of the world and working through multilateral mechanisms to help address that, even as we don&#8217;t foresee it being a food shortage issue here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on natural gas, Russia says it&#8217;s going to cut off Poland starting tomorrow, which is a pretty big escalation by Russia.&nbsp; Is the administration concerned that Gazprom might cut off other European nations from &#8212; to get natural gas supplies?&nbsp; And is the U.S. going to do anything to help Poland make up for &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; shortages there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me check and see if there&#8217;s anything specific to Poland.&nbsp; What I can tell you &#8212; and we&#8217;ve talked about the little bit in &#8212; a little bit in here before &#8212; is that for the last several months, and even prior to the invasion, we have been working to increase natural gas supply and options to European countries that have been reliant on Russia for natural gas supply in anticipation of the possibility of this happening or a decrease in what they&#8217;re providing.<br><br>So, some of that has been asking some countries in Asia who have excess supply to provide that to Europe.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve done that in some cases. &nbsp;And it&#8217;s been an ongoing effort, but I can see if there&#8217;s anything specific for Poland, given this recent announcement.<br><br>Go ahead, Matt.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Two questions on the pardons.&nbsp; There were &#8212; pardons and commutations.&nbsp; There were three pardons; two of them were for nonviolent drug offenses.&nbsp; Can you talk at all about, sort of, what it was about those two cases that stuck out to the President, given that there are a lot of people who applied for pardons that have similar circumstances and didn&#8217;t receive a pardon today?&nbsp; Is there anything about those two that are emblematic of anything that is on his &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I think many of you reported on these cases and the compelling nature of their personal stories.&nbsp; But I would note that his focus at this point in time was on individuals who had less than four years to serve.&nbsp; A number of them &#8212; a good percentage of them, and I can find the exact number in here &#8212; are also already under home confinement currently.<br><br>And this is, again, just the first step.&nbsp; And he will continue to review clemency requests and petitions over the course of his presidency and, certainly, in the coming months.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in addition, there is a large backlog of people who have applied for pardons and commutations.&nbsp; And given that, was there any denials in this first wave?&nbsp; Is he denying anybody a pardon or a commutation this &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with our counsel&#8217;s office and see or if it was just &#8212; this was the first round that was granted through the process.<br><br>Go ahead, Sheryl.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions, Jen.&nbsp; First, following up on Dr. Jha, he said that &#8212; he talked about global funding &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for the coronavirus pandemic.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Republicans have said that they want that money offset.&nbsp; So, has the administration &#8212; does the administration intend to propose ways to offset that $5 billion?&nbsp; Or do you think that&#8217;s a lost cause?<br><br>And, second, the President has a number of crowded events coming up on his calendar &#8212; a couple of funerals, the White House Correspondents’ Dinner.&nbsp; And in light of the Vice President&#8217;s diagnosis, can you talk about the calculations that the President is making and thinking about whether to attend these kinds of events, and also whether he has any special obligation as President to keep himself safe?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, on the first question, Sheryl, we&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp; I mean, we have requested 22.5 in the past, and obviously, that is where our emergency requests will be moving forward for the short-term needs that we have.&nbsp;<br><br>This has been passed &#8212; past COVID funding, as you well know, has been passed through emergency authorities where it hasn&#8217;t been offset.&nbsp; And we certainly think that&#8217;s reasonable.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re at such the early stage of this process, having not even sent it up to the Hill yet, we&#8217;re going to have to have all of those conversations about how to move it forward.<br><br>On the second piece, what I will tell you is that we make risk assessments here, just like every American does, and as it relates to, of course, keeping the President safe and all of us safe.<br><br>Now, naturally, he has access to the best healthcare in the world.&nbsp; He consults closely with his doctor.&nbsp; We take a range of steps &#8212; I noted in response to MJ’s question earlier &#8212; that go beyond even most workplaces in the country in terms of required testing for those who &#8212; who will be around him, social distancing.&nbsp; Obviously, he has his own regular testing cadence.<br><br>But we do make assessments and he makes assessments about when he feels it&#8217;s important for him to attend or participate in an event.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ve mentioned two of them &#8212; obviously, this weekend, he&#8217;ll be attending the White House Correspondents’ Dinner.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an opportunity to honor the work of all of you and many of your colleagues and to &#8212; and to talk about the importance of journalism in the world.<br><br>That&#8217;s an event he&#8217;s attended many times in the past, and he made a decision, through consultations, that it was an event he could attend and wanted to attend again.<br><br>And obviously, former Vice President Mondale is someone he had an important personal relationship with.&nbsp; He wanted to attend his memorial service.<br><br>Obviously, these discussions are always done through our scheduling team, the COVID team to make sure we&#8217;re taking every step possible.&nbsp; But just like many Americans, he makes risk assessments.<br><br>And I would say, the last piece &#8212; what you didn&#8217;t ask about, but, you know, people ask about in here as well &#8212; is he has been traveling the country more, recently.&nbsp; You know, he was traveling three days last week.&nbsp; And we &#8212; in, of course, coordination with the President &#8212; made a decision that was vitally important to him, to his presidency, to the American people.<br><br>And certainly, that&#8217;s one of the reasons we want to be very clear that it is possible he could test positive for COVID.&nbsp; That, just like any American, even though he&#8217;s double boosted, that is possible.&nbsp; And, you know, we will, of course, be very transparent about that if that were to take place.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, do you have time for a few more questions?&nbsp; We&#8217;re told you have a hard out soon &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I do.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but didn&#8217;t know if you wanted to &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, yeah.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll try to go the back.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Multiple outlets &#8212; CBS and Washington Post &#8212; have reported today that in yesterday&#8217;s meetings with &#8212; meeting with the Congressional Hispanic Caucus, that President Biden signaled that he was prepared to use executive authority to cancel student debt in the coming months.&nbsp; Can you confirm that this was something relayed to them by the President?&nbsp; And why?&nbsp; What exactly has the President considered doing when it comes to &#8212; to student aid debt?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me use this opportunity to reiterate that nobody has paid a sing- &#8212; a penny in student loan &#8212; federal student loans since the President took office.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;ve said from here is that &#8212; and what he reiterated &#8212; is that he will make a decision before there&#8217;s an end to that pause.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, it&#8217;s been extended through August.&nbsp; And we have talked about how we are looking at and he is looking at other executive authority options he has to bring relief to people who have student loans.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what he conveyed during the meeting yesterday.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, regarding using executive action, though, I mean, is that something &#8212; a step now that the President is seriously looking at?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about that in the past, so he&#8217;s continuing to look at it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then lastly, going back to Vice President Harris&#8217;s positive test for COVID, is the White House trying to determine exactly where and when she would have been exposed to COVID?&nbsp; Is it the assumption that it was during a trip to California last week?&nbsp; And is the White House and the Vice President&#8217;s Office doing any effort to contract [sic] trace in order to maybe notify people &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; during that lengthy trip who she might have ran into?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Just like for anyone who tests positive around here, we do contact tracing so that people are aware if they should take additional measures or precautions, whether it&#8217;s masking or getting additional PCR tests.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re certainly doing that in light of the Vice President&#8217;s positive test as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask if the White House had any reaction to that court case that put the temporary block on Title 42 being repealed.&nbsp;<br><br>And then I have a follow-up question about Vice President Harris.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure. &nbsp;Well, things sometimes happen when I&#8217;m out here.&nbsp; But when I &#8212; before I came out here, they had only done kind of the verbal briefing, as of last night.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not sure if there&#8217;s &#8212; has there been a new development?&nbsp; Or that &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Shakes head “no”.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So what I will tell you is the Department of Justice will need to review, kind of, any &#8212; any rulings before commenting.&nbsp; And that was verbal; there&#8217;ll be something more formal, is our expectation.&nbsp; And they would discuss any next legal steps or interpretation of the ruling.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll leave that to them.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll see if more comes out today.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on Vice President Harris, do you know the last time she was tested prior to this morning?&nbsp; And is there any therapeutics that she&#8217;s taking?&nbsp; A doctor’s (inaudible) &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So she&#8217;s on a regular testing protocol, just like the President.&nbsp; I can certainly check and see that information.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, as Dr. Jha referenced, she would consult with her doctor on any treatments.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Nadia.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On foreign policy, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan is supposed to meet with his Israeli counterpart tomorrow.&nbsp; The Israelis have made it perfectly known that there is disagreement with the White House vis-à-vis Iran and going back to the negotiation.&nbsp; Can you update us?&nbsp; First of all, why he&#8217;s coming here?&nbsp; What’s on the agenda?&nbsp; And I have another question.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, they consult regularly.&nbsp; I would say, as you know, the President had a fruitful conversation with Israeli Prime Minister Bennett just a couple of days ago.&nbsp; And so, this is a follow-up to that conversation, and they&#8217;ll discuss a range of regional and global security issues.&nbsp;<br><br>And part of that &#8212; you know, the President, when he spoke with Prime Minister Bennett, they also talked about a range of global and regional issues, and Prime Minister Bennett extended an invitation for him to visit Israel, which he accepted and will do.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a date yet to announce.&nbsp;<br><br>They also talked about the Iran nuclear deal negotiations, which we &#8212; we keep the Israelis briefed regularly on.&nbsp; So, certainly that could be a part of this conversation as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also, Secretary Blinken this morning testified at the Senate Foreign Relations Committee.&nbsp; He said the breakout time for Iran is weeks away.&nbsp; He blamed the previous administration from withdrawing from the deal.&nbsp; Does this worry the White House that we’re talking about two weeks that Iran could actually develop a nuclear weapon?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, it definitely worries us.&nbsp; I would say that if we go back, you know, under the &#8212; under the Iran nuclear deal, Iran&#8217;s nuclear program was tightly constrained and monitored by international inspectors.&nbsp; And since the Trump administration ceased U.S. participation in the deal, Iran has rapidly accelerated its nuclear program and reduced cooperation with international inspectors in non-performance of Iran nuclear deal commitments.&nbsp;<br><br>So, as you noted, what Secretary Blinken said during his testimony this morning was that their breakout period is down from about a year &#8212; which is what we knew it was during the deal &#8212; to just a few weeks or less.&nbsp; And certainly, that is a direct impact of pulling out of the nuclear deal, making us less safe, giving us less visibility.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s one of the reasons we pursued a diplomatic path, again, when the President took office.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Follow on that one?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, April, last one.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then mine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, April last one.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Jen.&nbsp; Two questions &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; really fast.&nbsp; When it &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I thought you were going to the back.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When it comes &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tomorrow is a new day.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, April.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The back has never been called on.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, this is April.&nbsp; I’m sorry.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) in the back.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the two questions: On Haiti, what are the conversations?&nbsp; Can you shed light on the conversations about the Haitian immigration issue as Title 42 is set to end next month?<br><br>And also, as the Vice President has tested positive for COVID, and it is in the realm of possibility as the President is traveling &#8212; if he gets COVID, in this moment, what is the line of succession if both of them are very ill with COVID at this point?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, technically, the Speaker of the House is the third in line.&nbsp; So, there you go.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know, but I just want to make sure.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m just confirming that for you.&nbsp; It is true, as we&#8217;ve noted many times, it is possible the President could test positive.&nbsp; We will be very transparent with you if that were to happen.&nbsp; He has access to the best healthcare in the &#8212; in the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we believe, because of all of the precautions and steps we have taken, that he would be able to continue his duties, as the Vice President is, as well, as Vice President.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any prediction of that at this point in time.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of your first question on Haiti, tell me a little bit more about what you mean.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The way I understand: that there has been conversation or various conversations &#8212; to include at the U.N., here &#8212; about how do you handle the Haitian migrant issue when Haitian are being sent back, and then you&#8217;re bringing other refugees in.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m hearing that there are conversations around the administration about how to handle once Title 42 ends.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would have to dig into this a little bit deeper.&nbsp; And as you know, there&#8217;s TPS &#8212; right? &#8212; that has been granted for a period of time.&nbsp; So that is something that Haitians who have been here at a certain &#8212; from a certain point in time have access to.&nbsp; Beyond that &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) Title 42.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; our focus, though, is, of course, on continuing to be the largest provider of aid and assistance to Haiti, ensuring we can take steps there to lead in the world, encouraging other countries in the world to take steps as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Beyond that, maybe we can talk after the briefing and I can find out a little bit more about what you mean.&nbsp; I will go to the back tomorrow first thing.&nbsp; Thank you so much, everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>3:57 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Regional Appointments for&#160;HHS</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/president-biden-announces-key-regional-appointments-for-hhs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51732</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS): Ala Stanford, HHS Regional Director, Region 3 Antrell Tyson, HHS Regional Director, Region 4 Janine Boyd, HHS Regional Director, Region 5 These regional appointees will be critical to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS):</p>



<ul><li>Ala Stanford, HHS Regional Director, Region 3</li><li>Antrell Tyson, HHS Regional Director, Region 4</li><li>Janine Boyd, HHS Regional Director, Region 5</li></ul>



<p>These regional appointees will be critical to the President’s efforts to rebuild communities most impacted by the pandemic, the economic recovery, and climate change. They bring deep expertise in their issue areas as well as critical relationships with federal, state, tribal, and local leaders. And, consistent with the President’s commitment to building an administration that looks like America, these regional appointees represent the diversity of America and the communities they serve.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES (HHS)</u></strong><br>Regional Directors lead HHS’s 10 Regional Offices that directly serve state and local organizations. Regional Directors ensure the Department maintains close contact with state, local, and tribal partners and addresses the needs of communities and individuals served through HHS programs and policies.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ala Stanford, HHS Regional Director, Region 3</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Ala Stanford, a practicing physician for over 20 years, is board certified by the American Board of Surgery in both pediatric and adult general surgery and a health care advocate. She is the Founder of The Black Doctors COVID19 Consortium (BDCC). The consortium was formed in response to the disproportionate number of African Americans being diagnosed and dying from coronavirus in Philadelphia, PA and the lack of swift intervention to mitigate disease spread. The mission of the consortium is to educate, provide advocacy and barrier free coronavirus testing and coronavirus vaccination in an effort to decrease the morbidity and mortality associated with the disease. Her research in basic science, clinical research, and public health have been published in peer reviewed medical journals. Stanford also serves as a medical correspondent for local and national news outlets. She is the former director of the Center for Minority Health and Health Disparities of Temple University School of Medicine, and serves on the CDC Philadelphia Department of Public Health COVID19 Vaccine Advisory Committee. Stanford has received many accolades, notably being named a 2021 Top 10 CNN Hero and 2021 George H.W. Bush Points of Light Award recipient.</p>



<p>Region 3 serves Delaware, the District of Columbia, Maryland, Pennsylvania, Virginia, and West Virginia.</p>



<p><strong><u>Antrell Tyson, HHS Regional Director, Region 4</u></strong></p>



<p>Antrell Tyson previously served as the Director of Business Services and Policy for the city of Atlanta&#8217;s Workforce Development Agency. In this role, Tyson re-established the city&#8217;s federally-funded work-based training programs to help buld a highly skilled and responsive workforce. Additionally, Tyson served as the agency&#8217;s top legal advisor to ensure the agency&#8217;s compliance with local, state, and federal laws and regulations. Tyson previously served as the District Director for Representative Lucy McBath (D-GA-06). As the Congresswoman&#8217;s top District advisor, Tyson oversaw the daily operations of the district office. Tyson also helped to advance many of the Congresswoman&#8217;s policy priorities, including expanding access to affordable healthcare, lowering prescription drug costs, and decreasing maternal mortality rates.</p>



<p>Tyson laid a strong foundation as a public policy professional while working on and off Capitol Hill in Washington, D.C. He has served as Counsel for a Member of Congress and a U.S. Senate committee, as well as Assistant General Counsel for the National Association of Broadcasters. Tyson holds a Bachelor of Arts in Political Science from Colgate University, and a Juris Doctor from the T.C. Williams School of Law at the University of Richmond. He is a native of Decatur, Georgia, and resides in Atlanta with his wife Laurie and their son Dorian.</p>



<p>Region 4 serves Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Kentucky, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Tennessee.</p>



<p><strong><u>Janine Boyd, HHS Regional Director, Region 5</u></strong></p>



<p>Janine R. Boyd is a pediatric speech and language pathologist turned advocate and state legislator. With almost two decades of experience in health and human services advocacy and policy as a government affairs professional, Boyd has been actively involved in Ohio’s state budget process and identifying federal opportunities on behalf of programs that serve&nbsp;the&nbsp;most vulnerable citizens. Through her experience with the&nbsp;state&nbsp;legislative process, Boyd has been an advocate for change in Columbus and has developed strong working relationships with agency directors, statewide elected officials, and lawmakers from all backgrounds and political parties. As a former Cleveland Heights council member, Boyd worked to establish a mentoring and juvenile diversion program and catalyzed the expansion of human rights laws to increase protections for members of the LGBT+ community.</p>



<p>In Ohio’s Legislature, Boyd served as Ranking Minority Member on the House Health Committee, as well as the Committee on Community and Family Advancement, among other committees. Boyd co-founded the first statewide Black Maternal Health Caucus and sits on the board of the Ohio Children&#8217;s Trust Fund.&nbsp;Boyd has also been a servant leader in her community, as&nbsp;a trustee on the&nbsp;board for the Heights Emergency Food Center and for Beaumont Catholic High School, her alma mater. She follows the longtime public service example set by her mother, Barbara Boyd.</p>



<p>Region 5 serves Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, Ohio, and Wisconsin.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 19:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE:     Bridget A. Brink, of Michigan, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Ukraine. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>    Bridget A. Brink, of Michigan, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary to the Vice President Kirsten&#160;Allen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/statement-from-press-secretary-to-the-vice-president-kirsten-allen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 16:25:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Harris tested positive for COVID-19 on rapid and PCR tests. She has exhibited no symptoms, will isolate and continue to work from the Vice President’s residence. She has not been a close contact to the President or First Lady due to their respective recent travel schedules. She will follow CDC guidelines and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Harris tested positive for COVID-19 on rapid and PCR tests. She has exhibited no symptoms, will isolate and continue to work from the Vice President’s residence. She has not been a close contact to the President or First Lady due to their respective recent travel schedules. She will follow CDC guidelines and the advice of her physicians. The Vice President will return to the White House when she tests negative. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Bilateral Virtual Meeting Between President Joe&#160;Biden and President Andrés Manuel López&#160;Obrador</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-bilateral-virtual-meeting-between-president-joe-biden-and-president-andres-manuel-lopez-obrador-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 13:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51794</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, April 29, President Joe Biden will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador virtually. In this virtual event, the two leaders will discuss their vision for the Ninth Summit of the Americas and how North America can lead on priority initiatives for the region. They also plan to discuss cooperation on migration, joint&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, April 29, President Joe Biden will meet with President Andrés Manuel López Obrador virtually. In this virtual event, the two leaders will discuss their vision for the Ninth Summit of the Americas and how North America can lead on priority initiatives for the region. They also plan to discuss cooperation on migration, joint development efforts in Central America, competitiveness and economic growth, security, energy, and economic cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Expands Second Chance Opportunities for Formerly Incarcerated&#160;Persons</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-expands-second-chance-opportunities-for-formerly-incarcerated-persons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America must offer meaningful opportunities for redemption and rehabilitation to empower those who have been incarcerated to become productive, law-abiding, members of society, and reduce crime and make our communities safer. Leaders on both sides of the aisle recognize that second chance opportunities offer people who have made mistakes and served their time a path&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America must offer meaningful opportunities for redemption and rehabilitation to empower those who have been incarcerated to become productive, law-abiding, members of society, and reduce crime and make our communities safer. Leaders on both sides of the aisle recognize that second chance opportunities offer people who have made mistakes and served their time a path to make meaningful contributions to their communities and reduce recidivism. In doing so, we can break the cycle of crime, and allow law enforcement to focus their time and resources on the most pressing threats to public safety.<br><br>Embodying the President’s belief that America is a nation of second chances, today the President granted pardons to three people and <a>commuted</a>&nbsp;the sentences of 75 people, all of whom have made efforts to rehabilitate themselves, including through educational and vocational training or drug treatment in prison.<br><br>Advancing successful reentry outcomes makes our communities safer, disrupts cycles of economic hardship, and strengthens our economy. Improving reentry is also key part of the comprehensive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/">strategy</a><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-comprehensive-strategy-to-prevent-and-respond-to-gun-crime-and-ensure-public-safety/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> </a>President Biden announced last June to tackle gun crime and violence. And, since President Biden took office, our economy has added a record 7.9 million jobs and the unemployment rate has fallen to 3.6 percent. At the same time, many industries are facing workforce shortages to meet growing demand as their businesses flourish. America is in a prime position to offer opportunities for meaningful employment to the more than 600,000 people that leave prison every year—for whom securing stable employment is among the most significant challenges.<br><br>Today, during Second Chance Month, the Biden-Harris Administration is releasing a comprehensive <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Incarceration-to-Employment-Strategy.pdf">strategy&nbsp;</a>that expands Incarceration to Employment opportunities, as well as the following concrete policy actions as part of a whole-of-government effort to advance employment, bolster reentry, empower formerly incarcerated persons, and strengthen our communities and our economy:<br><br><strong>Investing in Job Training and Intensive Reentry in Federal Prisons</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Launching Historic DOJ-DOL Partnership.</strong> Today, the Department of Justice and the Department of Labor are announcing a first-of-its-kind collaboration to invest $145 million over FY22-FY23 to provide job skills training and individualized employment and reentry plans for people incarcerated in Bureau of Prisons (BOP) facilities, and to provide pathways for a seamless transition to employment and reentry support upon release. This landmark initiative is part of the Department of Justice’s implementation of the First Step Act, and it will be the first time the Department of Labor will bring its job training and reentry support and expertise to federal prisoners.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Expanding Federal Job Opportunities and Loan Programs</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing New Workforce Grant Funding.</strong> The Department of Labor has announced solicitations for grants totaling $140 million to advance job opportunities:<br><ul><li><a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/ETA/grants/pdfs/FOA-ETA-22-03_.pdf"><strong>Growth Opportunities</strong></a> is a new $85 million program that will provide education and training, paid work experience, mentorship, and leadership development to justice-involved youth and young adults.<br></li><li><a href="https://www.dol.gov/sites/dolgov/files/ETA/grants/pdfs/FOA-ETA-22-04%20.pdf"><strong>Pathway Home</strong></a> will fund $55 million for job training, pre-apprenticeship programs, digital literacy training, and pre-release and post-release career counseling for justice-involved adults.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Access to Business Capital.</strong> This week, the Small Business Administration (SBA) will publish <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2020/12/14/2020-26446/regulatory-reform-initiative-streamlining-and-modernizing-the-7a-microloan-and-504-loan-programs-to?msclkid=08f00f42c0ee11ecae5d0207f5e651a9">changes</a> to remove barriers to eligibility based on irrelevant criminal history records for its 7(a), Microloan, and 504 loan programs. SBA is also developing other ways to reduce restrictions in its programs. The SBA recently <a href="https://www.sba.gov/article/2022/mar/30/biden-harris-administration-expands-sba-pilot-program-targeting-access-capital-underserved">announced</a> the elimination of criminal record restrictions to access its Community Advantage loans, a critical program that provides loans to low-income borrowers and those from underserved communities. These actions build on SBA’s February 2021 expansion of eligibility for the Paycheck Protection Program by removing restrictions for entrepreneurs with certain prior criminal convictions or other involvement in the justice system.</li><li><strong>Expanding Access to Federal Employment. </strong>This week, the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) will publish <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/public-inspection/2022-08975/fair-chance-to-compete-for-jobs">proposed regulations</a> that remove barriers to federal employment for formerly incarcerated individuals under the bipartisan Fair Chance to Compete for Jobs Act. Once enacted, these regulations will expand the positions covered by the federal government’s “ban the box” policy, which delays inquiries into an applicant’s criminal history a conditional offer has been made. The regulations also create new procedures that outline due process and accountability steps for hiring officials who are alleged to have violated the “ban the box” procedures.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Leveraging Historic Investments in Infrastructure to Promote Hiring of Formerly Incarcerated Persons. </strong>The Department of Transportation is expanding access to jobs for formerly incarcerated persons and historically marginalized populations in bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act grant programs, including the <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/RAISEgrants">RAISE Grants</a>, <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/grants/infra-grants-program">INFRA Grants</a>, and the <a href="https://www.maritime.dot.gov/PIDPgrants">Port Infrastructure Development Program</a>.</li><li><strong>Promoting Best Practices with Federal Construction Industry Contractors. </strong>Given the landmark level of funding available under the bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to the construction industry and provisions in those grant programs aimed at expanding access to project jobs for formerly incarcerated persons, it is critical that federal contractors and subcontractors comply with the law. This is why the Department of Labor’s Office of Federal Contracting and Compliance Programs (OFCCP) issued <a href="https://content.govdelivery.com/accounts/USDOLOFCCP/bulletins/3136722">new guidance</a> to federal contractors and subcontractors that underscores its earlier <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/directives/2013-02">directive</a> that criminal background check policies, which may have a disparate impact on protected classes, may violate existing nondiscrimination obligations. &nbsp;OFCCP also developed compliance assistance materials for contractors including a <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/compliance-assistance/outreach/webinars">webinar</a>, <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/ofccp/faqs/construction-compliance">Construction Compliance FAQs</a>,&nbsp;and a <a href="https://ofccptraining.dol.gov/catalog/construction-compliance-review-contractors">training</a>. OFCCP has also <a href="https://content.govdelivery.com/accounts/USDOLOFCCP/bulletins/2ef6204">released</a> a new memorandum identifying 400 federal contractors and subcontractors who have been neutrally selected to undergo a full compliance review of their hiring practices to ensure people with arrest and conviction records are not being discriminated against.</li><li><strong>Expanding Second Chance Visiting Fellowship Program.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Justice’s Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA) <a href="https://www.ojp.gov/blog/second-chance-fellows-john-bae-and-angel-sanchez">brought on two new Second Chance Fellows&nbsp;</a>who were formerly incarcerated to help develop reentry policy. For the first time, one of those Fellows will work with the Department of Education (ED) on educational policy for carceral settings and upon reentry.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Promoting Best Practices for Hiring Across the Federal Government</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing Interactive Training and Technical Assistance for Job Seekers.</strong> The Office of Personnel Management has published <a href="https://chcoc.gov/content/second-chance-month">detailed guidance</a> for applicants with arrest and conviction records who are interested in federal employment. To further support them, OPM is hosting interactive sessions between federal agencies’ Human Resources practitioners and applicants with arrest and conviction records.</li><li><strong>Leveraging Existing Hiring Authorities for Agencies.</strong> OPM will host a <a href="https://secondchance.eventbrite.com">training webinar</a> on April 28 to assist federal hiring officials, human resource and DEIA practitioners, and supervisors with leveraging existing federal hiring authorities to recruit and hire formerly incarcerated persons into the federal government.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting Veterans</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expediting the Restoration of Benefits</strong>. In partnership with the Social Security Administration and the Bureau of Prisons, the Department of Veterans Affairs’ Veterans Benefits Administration <a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5780">announced</a> a new effort to automate information-sharing among these agencies to accelerate benefit restoration and reduce the administrative burden for veterans.</li><li><strong>Conducting Outreach to Incarcerated Veterans.&nbsp;</strong> The VA <a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5780">announced</a> new efforts to increase the number of state prisons and jails that use its Veterans Reentry Search Service, which helps identify veterans in their custody and connect them with reentry services.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Expanding Access to Health Care and Housing</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Access to Health Care. </strong>The Department of Health and Human Services is <a href="https://www.cms.gov/files/document/cms-4199-p.pdf">proposing</a> to establish a Special Enrollment Period (SEP) of six months post-release for Medicare for people who missed an enrollment period while incarcerated, which would reduce potential gaps in coverage and late enrollment penalties.</li><li><strong>Expanding Access to Housing.</strong> The Department of Housing and Urban Development announced that it has <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/Main/documents/Memo_on_Criminal_Records.pdf">initiated a 6-month comprehensive review</a> of its existing regulations and guidance to identify how HUD programs can increase their inclusivity of people with arrest and conviction records.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Developing and Amplifying Educational Opportunities</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Second Chance Pell.</strong> ED will select 73 additional schools to <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-announces-expansion-second-chance-pell-program-and-actions-help-incarcerated-individuals-resume-educational-journeys-and-reduce-recidivism">expand</a> its Second Chance Pell Initiative. The expansion of the program into these schools will ultimately provide access to thousands of additional students. First established in 2015 by the Obama-Biden Administration, the Second Chance Pell Initiative provides Pell Grants to incarcerated individuals to participate in postsecondary education programs. This expansion of sites will help the Department to prepare for full expansion of Pell Grant eligibility to incarcerated students in July 2023.</li><li><strong>Providing a Pathway Out of Loan Default. </strong>ED will also announce <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-announces-expansion-second-chance-pell-program-and-actions-help-incarcerated-individuals-resume-educational-journeys-and-reduce-recidivism">changes</a> to policies to help incarcerated individuals get out of loan default to access Pell Grants. In the short term, incarcerated persons who have defaulted will get a “fresh start.” Like other defaulted borrowers, incarcerated borrowers with defaulted loans will reenter repayment in good standing when the student loan payment pause ends. ED is also announcing a longer-term fix that will take place after “fresh start” is implemented: it will allow incarcerated persons to consolidate their loans to get out of default. Incarcerated persons interested in enrolling in Second Chance Pell were twice as likely as the broader population to be turned away because of defaulted loans. This change will now allow incarcerated persons the same opportunity to get out of default as non-incarcerated persons.</li><li><strong>Investing in Digital Literacy.</strong> The Department of Commerce’s <a href="https://broadbandusa.ntia.doc.gov/resources/grant-programs/digital-equity-programs">Digital Equity Planning Grant</a>, funded by the bipartisan Infrastructure and Investment Jobs Act, will provide $60 million to states and Puerto Rico to invest in digital literacy and equity programs for underserved communities,&nbsp; including incarcerated and formerly incarcerated persons.</li><li><strong>Publishing New Guidance on Correctional and Reentry Education Resources.</strong> ED published <a href="https://cte.ed.gov/yadiversion/">guidance</a> to states and localities on how to divert young adults from the juvenile and criminal justice system. ED also published new <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ovae/pi/AdultEd/take-charge-your-future.pdf">guidance</a> for incarcerated persons seeking educational opportunities, summarizing the resources available to support them.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Supporting Job Seekers and Establishing Best Practices for Employers</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Tax Credits and Free Bonding Programs for Employers. </strong>DOL developed <a href="https://reo.workforcegps.org/resources/2022/04/06/17/28/Reentry-Employment-Opportunities-Recognizes-April-as-Second-Chance-Month">new resources</a> for justice-involved job seekers, reentry service providers, and employers to learn about existing federal reentry employment incentives including the <a href="https://bonds4jobs.com/">Federal Bonding Program</a> and the <a href="https://www.irs.gov/businesses/small-businesses-self-employed/work-opportunity-tax-credit">Work Opportunity Tax Credit</a>.</li><li><strong>Resources for Employers, Job Seekers, and Employees.</strong> The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission’s new <a href="https://www.eeoc.gov/arrestandconviction">landing page</a> centralizes existing resources on the use of arrest and conviction records in employment decisions, and other technical assistance documents for employers and job seekers.</li><li><strong>Supporting Reentry 2030.</strong> DOJ’s Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA  partnered with the Council of State Governments (CSG) to launch the <a href="https://bja.ojp.gov/events/advancing-successful-reintegration-every-person-reentry-2030-national-launch#:~:text=Reentry%202030%20is%20a%20partnership,towards%20their%20Reentry%202030%20goals.">national Reentry 2030 campaign</a>, which will work with state leaders to set public reentry goals to achieve better economic mobility and outcomes for persons exiting prison, parole or probation by 2030.</li><li><strong>Promoting Resources for Second Chance Month. </strong>The National Reentry Resource Center (NRRC) is <a href="https://nationalreentryresourcecenter.org/second-chance-month-april-2022-calendar">hosting a series</a> of live training and technical assistance events for Second Chance Act grantees as well as the public in honor of Second Chance Month.</li><li><strong>Reentry Toolkit. </strong>The <a href="https://nationalreentryresourcecenter.org">National Reentry Resource Center</a> launched the Bureau of Justice Assistance’s <a href="https://nationalreentryresourcecenter.org/resources/toolkits/reentry">Reentry Toolkit</a> for local reentry coalition leaders and community leaders to allow assessment of existing reentry efforts and opportunities to strengthen outcomes for incarcerated persons in their communities. The NRRC will also continue to host its searchable database of reentry resources.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Clemency Recipient List</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/clemency-recipient-list/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is granting clemency to 78 individuals, consisting of three pardons and 75 commutations. President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is pardoning the following three individuals: Abraham W. Bolden, Sr. – Chicago, IllinoisAbraham Bolden is an 86-year-old former U.S. Secret Service agent and was the first African American to serve on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is granting clemency to 78 individuals, consisting of three pardons and 75 commutations.<br><br>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is pardoning the following three individuals:<br><br><strong>Abraham W. Bolden, Sr.</strong> – Chicago, Illinois<br>Abraham Bolden is an 86-year-old former U.S. Secret Service agent and was the first African American to serve on a presidential detail.  In 1964, Mr. Bolden was charged with offenses related to attempting to sell a copy of a Secret Service file.  His first trial resulted in a hung jury, and following his conviction at a second trial, even though key witnesses against him admitted to lying at the prosecutor’s request, Mr. Bolden was denied a new trial and ultimately served several years in federal custody.  He has steadfastly maintained his innocence, arguing that he was targeted for prosecution in retaliation for exposing unprofessional and racist behavior within the U.S. Secret Service.  Mr. Bolden has received numerous honors and awards for his ongoing work to speak out against the racism he faced in the Secret Service in the 1960s, and his courage in challenging injustice.  Mr. Bolden has also been recognized for his many contributions to his community following his release from prison.<br><br><strong>Betty Jo Bogans</strong> – Houston, Texas<br>Betty Jo Bogans is a 51-year-old woman who was convicted in 1998 of possession with intent to distribute crack cocaine in the Southern District of Texas after attempting to transport drugs for her boyfriend and his accomplice, neither of whom were detained or arrested.  At the time of her conviction, Ms. Bogans was a single mother with no prior record, who accepted responsibility for her limited role in the offense.  Because of the harsh penalties in place at the time she was convicted, Ms. Bogan received a seven-year sentence.  In the nearly two decades since her release from custody, Ms. Bogans has held consistent employment, even while undergoing treatment for cancer, and has focused on raising her son.   <br><br><strong>Dexter Eugene Jackson</strong> – Athens, Georgia<br>Dexter Jackson is a 52-year-old man who was convicted in 2002 for using his business to facilitate the distribution of marijuana in the Northern District of Georgia.  Mr. Jackson was not personally involved in trafficking marijuana, but allowed marijuana distributors to use his pool hall to facilitate drug transactions.  He accepted full responsibility for his actions at the time he was charged, and pled guilty.  Since his release from custody, Mr. Jackson has converted his business into a cell-phone repair service and hired local high school students through a program that seeks to provide young adults with work experience.  Mr. Jackson has also worked to build and renovate homes in a community that lacks quality affordable housing.<br><br>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is commuting the sentences of the following 75 individuals:<br><br><strong>Sergio Acosta</strong> – Montgomery, Alabama<br><strong>Offense:</strong> Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing methamphetamine (Eastern District of Kentucky). <br><strong>Sentence:</strong> 97 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 23, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant:</strong> Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Kathy Marie Albrecht</strong> – Jamestown, North Dakota<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute a controlled substance (District of North Dakota).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 150 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (November 6, 2014).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Maria Isabel Arreola</strong> – San Bernardino, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>:<br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute cocaine (Eastern District of Texas).<br>2. Conspiracy to distribute cocaine hydrochloride (Middle District of North Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>:<br>1. 121 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (March 24, 2016).<br>2. 130 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (November 17, 2016).<br>Prison sentences and terms of supervised release in each case to run concurrently.<br><strong>Commutation Grant:</strong> Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year terms of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Roberto Barrio </strong>– South Gate, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute cocaine base and cocaine powder; interstate travel in aid of racketeering enterprise (four counts); use of a telephone to facilitate the distribution of cocaine base and cocaine powder (two counts) (Western District of Oklahoma).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: Life imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (October 23, 2000).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Kelvin Beaufort</strong> – Charlotte, North Carolina<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute cocaine and cocaine base (Western District of North Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 324 months of imprisonment, 20-year term of supervised release (December 10, 2007); amended to 262 months of imprisonment, 20-year term of supervised release (January 20, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant:</strong> Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 20-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Brandon Todd Berry </strong>– Sikeston, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of a substance containing methamphetamine (Eastern District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (October 19, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Sharon Louise Boatright</strong> – Richardson, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 190 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (December 16, 2013); amended to 188 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (July 15, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the four-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Terry Booty</strong> – Morgan City, Louisiana  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with the intent to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectable amount of methamphetamine (Eastern District of Louisiana).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release, $10,000 fine (November 13, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $10,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Ramola Kaye Brown</strong> – Huntsville, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute five kilograms or more of cocaine and less than 50 kilograms of marijuana (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 145 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (September 15, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Julian Burford </strong>– Bedford, Ohio<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with the intent to distribute cocaine (Northern District of Ohio).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (September 17, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Mark Richard Burton</strong> – Odessa, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine and/or 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence: </strong>121 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $15,000 fine (March 16, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Nickolas Cano</strong> – Amarillo, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute 50 grams or more of methamphetamine and aiding and abetting (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 140 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (September 5, 2014).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the four-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Ruben Lopez Cazares</strong> – Chula Vista, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute controlled substance (District of Nebraska).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 300 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 7, 2007); amended to 262 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (January 12, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Jose Luis Colunga </strong>– Juniata, Nebraska<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possession with intent to distribute 1,000 kilograms or more of marijuana (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (July 13, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on October 26, 2023, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Paul Hernandez Contreras</strong> – Perris, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possession with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing a detectable amount of methamphetamine and a mixture and substance containing a detectable amount of cocaine (District of Colorado).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 108 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (January 8, 2019).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Karen Cox</strong> – Salt Lake City, Utah  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute methamphetamine (District of Wyoming).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 121 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $900 community restitution (June 16, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 60-month term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $900 community restitution.<br><br><strong>Lori Jean Cross</strong> – North Richland Hills, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (September 12, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Mario Cruz</strong> – Grand Rapids, Michigan<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute an unspecified quantity of cocaine and heroin (Western District of Michigan).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 121 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (January 23, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Christopher Dancy </strong>– Prince George, Virginia<br><strong>Offense: </strong>Conspiracy to distribute cocaine hydrochloride (Eastern District of Virginia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 336 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 27, 2009); amended to 288 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (December 19, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Catalina Davis</strong> – San Antonio, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute methamphetamine; aiding and abetting the possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 6, 2014); amended to 151 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 31, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Stacie Demers</strong> – Constable, New York<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute marijuana; aiding and abetting the possession with intent to distribute marijuana (Northern District of New York).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (October 26, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Deborah Ann Dodd</strong> – Forney, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectible amount of methamphetamine or 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine (Eastern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 140 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 19, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Manuel Ruben Duran-Pimentel</strong> – Miami, Florida<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to import controlled substances; laundering of monetary instruments (District of Puerto Rico).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 151 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (April 20, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Nova Neal Finau</strong> – Fort Worth, Texas<br><strong>Offense: </strong>Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 140 months of imprisonment, four-year term of supervised release (March 31, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the four-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Tina Marie Finazzo</strong> – Las Vegas, Nevada<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute 50 grams or more of methamphetamine (District of Hawaii).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 172 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 16, 2012); amended to 168 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (May 19, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David C. Frazier</strong> – St. Louis, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute cocaine; possession with intent to distribute a mixture containing cocaine; maintaining a drug involved premises (Eastern District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 144 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (May 21, 2014).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Julio Garza </strong>– Edinberg, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>:  Possession with intent to distribute 10 kilograms of cocaine (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (May 13, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Odell Givens</strong> – Certe, Illinois<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute a controlled substance; possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance (three counts) (Northern District of Illinois).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 186 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (December 14, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Dianna Gonzalez-Agosto</strong> – Altura de Rio G, Puerto Rico<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute at least 3.5 kilograms but less than 5 kilograms of cocaine within a protected location (District of Puerto Rico).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 87 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (July 14, 2020).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Virgil Goodman, Jr. </strong>– Lexington, Tennessee<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession of methamphetamine with intent to distribute (Western District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 262 months of imprisonment, six-year term of supervised release (June 30, 2005).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the six-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Christopher Gunter</strong> – Columbia, South Carolina  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute 50 grams or more of cocaine base, 5 kilograms or more of cocaine, and 100 kilograms or more of marijuana; possession with intent to distribute a quantity of marijuana and a quantity of MDMA (District of South Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (September 25, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Rachel Lynn Hanson </strong>– Richton Park, Illinois<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession of an unspecified quantity of cocaine with intent to distribute (Western District of Michigan).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 151 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (March 4, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Stephanie Hernandez</strong> – Dallas, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of a controlled substance (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (April 21, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Brandon Jermaine Huguley</strong> – Chattanooga, Tennessee<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 280 grams or more of cocaine base (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 235 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 20, 2012); amended to 188 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (May 22, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David Charles Jenkins</strong> – Beaumont, Texas<br><strong>Offense:</strong><br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute cocaine base; possession with intent to distribute cocaine base (Western District of Louisiana).<br>2. Violation of supervised release (Eastern District of Texas).<br>3. Production of counterfeit access devices (Eastern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>:<br>1. 151 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release, $5,000 fine (November 28, 2011); amended to 121 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release, $5,000 fine (February 9, 2018).<br>2. 24 months of imprisonment (January 5, 2012).<br>3. 24 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $2,516 restitution (April 29, 2015).<br>Prison sentences and terms of supervised release in each case to run consecutively.<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight and three-year terms of supervised release, and the unpaid remainders, if any, of the $5,000 fine and $2,516 restitution.<br><br><strong>Douglas Dean Johnson</strong> – Dickens, Iowa<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to manufacture and distribute 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine and possess and distribute pseudoephedrine following a felony drug conviction; travel in interstate commerce and aid and abet travel in interstate commerce with the intent to promote and facilitate a business enterprise involving the manufacture and distribution of controlled substances (Northern District of Iowa).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (December 8, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Gregory Jones </strong>– Philadelphia, Pennsylvania  <br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute five kilograms or more of cocaine; attempted possession with the intent to distribute five or more kilograms of cocaine and aiding and abetting (East District of Pennsylvania).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 216 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,500 fine (March 30, 2012).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $2,500 fine.<br><br><strong>Stephan George Jones</strong> – Rosebud, South Dakota<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute a controlled substance (District of South Dakota).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $1,000 fine (April 11, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $1,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Terri Kelly </strong>– Rialto, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams of methamphetamine (Eastern District of Kentucky).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (November 30, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Tellas Levallas Kennedy </strong>– Glennville, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute a quantity of cocaine hydrochloride (Southern District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $4,800 fine (September 30, 2013); amended to 168 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $4,800 fine (October 22, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and $4,800 fine.<br><br><strong>Vincent Edward Kennedy </strong>– Surfside Beach, South Carolina<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute cocaine; money laundering (District of South Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 180 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (June 26, 2014); amended to 145 months of imprisonment 10-year term of supervised release (June 29, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Brittany Krambeck </strong>– Fort Worth, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Maintaining drug involved premises; structuring transactions to evade reporting requirements (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 220 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (October 29, 2010).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2024, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Carry Le </strong>– Duluth, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 1,000 or more marijuana plants (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 4, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David Lee </strong>– Philadelphia, Pennsylvania<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute more than one kilogram of heroin and to distribute or manufacture in or near a school zone; distribution and possession of heroin with intent to distribute (seven counts); use of communication facility (Eastern District of Pennsylvania).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 300 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release, $1,500 fine (October 1, 2007); amended to 243 months of imprisonment,10-year term of supervised release, $1,500 fine (June 24, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release and $1,500 fine.<br><br><strong>Rosamaria Lucero </strong>– New Braunfels, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance, aiding and abetting (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (February 13, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Paul A. Lupercio </strong>– Blue Springs, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 1,000 kilograms or more of marijuana and five kilograms or more of cocaine (Western District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (May 8, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Angelica Marquez </strong>– Apple Valley, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute more than 50 grams of methamphetamine (District of Kansas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 117 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (April 23, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Eddie Mateus </strong>– New York, New York<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute heroin and cocaine (Southern District of New York).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (January 17, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Stephanie McMurphy </strong>– Adel, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of methamphetamine within 1,000 feet of a school (Middle District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 102 months of imprisonment, six-year term of supervised release (October 22, 2018).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the six-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Byron James Miller</strong> – St. Louis, Missouri<br><strong>Offense:</strong><br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute crack cocaine; possession with intent to distribute in excess of 500 grams of cocaine (Eastern District of Missouri).<br>2. Possession with intent to distribute heroin; possession of heroin in a federal prison (District of Central Illinois).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: <br>1. 292 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (June 6, 1997); amended to 188 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (December 17, 2019).<br>2. 210 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (March 5, 1999).<br>Prison sentences and terms of supervised release in each case to run consecutively.<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the consecutive eight and three-year terms of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Bethel Cheyenne Mooneyham </strong>– Spencer, Tennessee<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to manufacture and distribute 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine and 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing methamphetamine (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (June 13, 2011).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Colleen Mossberger </strong>– Crest Hill, Illinois<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of methamphetamine (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 5, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Quang Nguyen </strong>– Houston, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 1,000 or more marijuana plants (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 30, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Rickey Wayne Norton </strong>– Augusta, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Southern District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $40,000 fine (October 17, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $40,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Shannon Ann Norton </strong>– Augusta, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute a controlled substance (Southern District of Georgia).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $40,000 fine (October 17, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $40,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Thomas Perkins </strong>– Louisville, Kentucky<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute in excess of 5 kilograms or more of cocaine hydrochloride (mixture) and 50 grams or more of cocaine base (mixture) (Southern District of Indiana).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (December 22, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Aaron Ponce </strong>– Odessa, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute a controlled substance, 50 grams or more of actual methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (July 11, 2013).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Rose Trujillo Rangel </strong>– Waco, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute cocaine, a schedule II-narcotic-drug-controlled substance (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release, $5,000 fine (April 14, 2008).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $5,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Alejandro Reyna</strong> – Brownsville, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Importation of more than 50 grams of methamphetamine (Western District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,000 fine (January 16, 2014); amended to 180 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,000 fine (February 26, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $2,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Fermin Serna</strong> – Rio Grande City, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute in excess of 1,000 kilograms of marijuana, a schedule I controlled substance (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (November 9, 2007).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Mackie Shivers</strong> – Ft. Lauderdale, Florida<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 5 kilograms or more of cocaine; possession with intent to distribute 5 kilograms or more of cocaine (Southern District of Florida).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: Life imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (April 10, 2001).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Kirstie Marie Smith Israel</strong> – Albertville, Alabama<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute 50 grams or more of methamphetamine (Northern District of Alabama).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 97 months of imprisonment, three-year term of supervised release (August 23, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the three-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Tony Lee Stanfield</strong> – Villa Rica, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (Western District of North Carolina).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (November 2, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Cleola Sullivan</strong> – Tallahassee, Florida<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with intent to distribute cocaine base and 5 kilograms or more of cocaine; possess with intent to distribute 500 grams or more of cocaine (Northern District of Florida).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (December 13, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Charles Arnold Thomas </strong>– Inglewood, California<br><strong>Offense</strong>:<br>1. Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute 100 grams or more of phencyclidine, or one kilogram or more of a mixture containing a detectable amount of phencyclidine (Southern District of Texas).<br>2. Possession of a prohibited item by a prison inmate (Eastern District of Arkansas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>:<br>1. 210 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 4, 2011).<br>2. Seven months of imprisonment (April 25, 2018).<br>Prison sentences in each case to run consecutively.<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentences commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Edwin G. Tierney </strong>– Council Bluffs, Iowa<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute methamphetamine (District of Nebraska).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (November 8, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Jesse Alan Trimue</strong> – Burton, Michigan<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute and possess with the intent to distribute 5 grams of actual methamphetamine and 50 grams or more of methamphetamine mixture, a schedule II-controlled substance (Eastern District of Tennessee).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (June 6, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Daniel Valencia</strong> – Maylene, Alabama<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Importation of a quantity of 50 grams or more of methamphetamine and 500 grams or more of a mixture and substance containing a detectable amount of methamphetamine (Southern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 135 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $2,000 fine (April 24, 2015).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $2,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Martin R. Vandemerwe</strong> – Price, Utah<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (District of Utah).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 20 years of imprisonment; five-year term of supervised release (September 23, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>James Darrell Walker</strong> – Lubbock, Texas<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of and possession with intent to distribute cocaine base (Northern District of Texas).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 327 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (August 21, 2006); amended to 262 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 9, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Cindy Noella Williams</strong> – Casper, Wyoming<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Possession with intent to distribute methamphetamine (District of Wyoming).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 120 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release, $800 restitution (October 10, 2018); amended to 102 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release; $800 restitution (November 4, 2019).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $800 restitution.<br><br><strong>Cynthia Lynn Yeley-Davis</strong> – Mills, Wyoming<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to possess with intent to distribute, and to distribute methamphetamine (District of Wyoming).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 240 months of imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release, $1,000 fine (December 17, 2009).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence to expire on August 24, 2022, leaving intact and in effect the 10-year term of supervised release and the unpaid remainder, if any, of the $1,000 fine.<br><br><strong>Andrea Zavala</strong> – Waterloo, Iowa<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute at least 50 grams of a mixture or substance containing methamphetamine and 5 grams of actual methamphetamine (Northern District of Iowa).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 108 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (June 7, 2017).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>Courtney Donnell Zeno </strong>– Warner Robins, Georgia<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Distribution of cocaine base (five counts); possession with intent to distribute cocaine base; forfeiture (Western District of Louisiana).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: Life imprisonment, 10-year term of supervised release (August 31, 2010); amended to 240 months of imprisonment, eight-year term of supervised release (February 7, 2013).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the eight-year term of supervised release.<br><br><strong>David L. Zouck </strong>– Buffalo, Missouri<br><strong>Offense</strong>: Conspiracy to distribute 500 grams or more of methamphetamine; distribution of five grams or more of actual methamphetamine (Western District of Missouri).<br><strong>Sentence</strong>: 132 months of imprisonment, five-year term of supervised release (March 30, 2016).<br><strong>Commutation Grant</strong>: Sentence commuted to expire on April 26, 2023, with the remainder to be served in home confinement, leaving intact and in effect the five-year term of supervised release.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Clemency and Second Chance&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-clemency-and-second-chance-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America is a nation of laws and second chances, redemption, and rehabilitation. Elected officials on both sides of the aisle, faith leaders, civil rights advocates, and law enforcement leaders agree that our criminal justice system can and should reflect these core values that enable safer and stronger communities. During Second Chance Month, I am using&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America is a nation of laws and second chances, redemption, and rehabilitation. Elected officials on both sides of the aisle, faith leaders, civil rights advocates, and law enforcement leaders agree that our criminal justice system can and should reflect these core values that enable safer and stronger communities. During Second Chance Month, I am using my authority under the Constitution to uphold those values by <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/clemency-recipient-list/">pardoning and commuting</a> the sentences of fellow Americans.</p>



<p>Today, I am pardoning three people who have demonstrated their commitment to rehabilitation and are striving every day to give back and contribute to their communities. I am also commuting the sentences of 75 people who are serving long sentences for non-violent drug offenses, many of whom have been serving on home confinement during the COVID-pandemic—and many of whom would have received a lower sentence if they were charged with the same offense today, thanks to the bipartisan First Step Act. &nbsp;</p>



<p>My Administration is also announcing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-expands-second-chance-opportunities-for-formerly-incarcerated-persons/">new steps</a> today to support those re-entering society after incarceration. These actions include: a new collaboration between the U.S. Department of Justice and the U.S. Department of Labor to provide job training; new grants for workforce development programs; greater opportunities to serve in federal government; expanded access to capital for people with convictions trying to start a small business; improved reentry services for veterans; and more support for health care, housing, and educational opportunities.  </p>



<p>As I laid out in my comprehensive strategy to reduce gun crime, helping those who served their time return to their families and become contributing members of their communities is one of the most effective ways to reduce recidivism and decrease crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While today’s announcement marks important progress, my Administration will continue to review clemency petitions and deliver reforms that advance equity and justice, provide second chances, and enhance the wellbeing and safety of all Americans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Increases Access to COVID-&#8288;19 Treatments and Boosts Patient and Provider&#160;Awareness</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/26/fact-sheet-biden-administration-increases-access-to-covid-19-treatments-and-boosts-patient-and-provider-awareness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 response, there are now more tools than ever before to protect people from the virus, including highly-effective treatments. Over the past 15 months, the Administration has pulled levers across the federal government and deployed resources Congress provided to expedite the development, production, and procurement of COVID-19 treatments. As a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 response, there are now more tools than ever before to protect people from the virus, including highly-effective treatments. Over the past 15 months, the Administration has pulled levers across the federal government and deployed resources Congress provided to expedite the development, production, and procurement of COVID-19 treatments. As a result, the U.S. now has several treatments available that can help keep people out of the hospital and save lives.<br><br>One of the most effective available treatments is Pfizer’s oral antiviral pill, Paxlovid, which has been shown to reduce the risk of hospitalization or death by about 90 percent. The U.S. has committed to purchase 20 million treatment courses—more than any other country in the world. Although Paxlovid was initially in short supply after Food and Drug Administration (FDA) authorization, the Administration has worked with Pfizer to accelerate the delivery of these pills, and they are now in ample supply. The President’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/covidplan/">National COVID-19 Preparedness Plan</a> lays out a roadmap for ensuring that these pills, along with other treatments, are available for any American who needs one.<br><br>Since December 2021, the Administration has distributed COVID-19 oral antivirals directly to states, Tribes, territories, and community health centers for free. States and territories play an important role in distributing these treatments to health care providers, pharmacies, and other locations, and any doctor can prescribe treatments. In March, as supply began to ramp up, the President announced the Test-to-Treat initiative to help make it easier for people at high risk of severe disease to quickly access oral antiviral treatments. The Test-to-Treat initiative creates additional locations where people can get a COVID-19 test, a visit with a medical provider, and, if needed, free oral antiviral pills—all in one visit.<br><br>To date, the Administration has worked with pharmacies, long-term care facilities, community health centers, and other health care settings to establish more than 2,200 Test-to-Treat sites around the country, including sites specifically for military families and veterans. As a result, usage of oral antivirals has more than doubled over the last several weeks.<br><br>Today, the Administration is announcing new actions to make these treatments even easier to access and to make sure health care providers and patients know about their safety, efficacy, and availability. These actions will help strengthen and further build the infrastructure to ensure that lifesaving treatments for COVID-19 are quickly distributed around the country, widely available, and easy to access. At the same time, ensuring that this remains the case—and securing more and even better treatments—will require additional funding from Congress.<br><br>Today’s actions include:<br><br><strong>Nearly doubling the number of places oral antivirals are available in the coming weeks. </strong>Right now, oral antivirals are available in about 20,000 locations across the country—including pharmacies, community health centers, hospitals, urgent care centers, and Veterans Affairs clinics, and Department of Defense Medical Treatment Facilities. Now that the United States has ample supply of these treatments, the Administration is making it easier for pharmacies to order antivirals from the federal government. Starting this week, the Administration will allow all pharmacy partners in the federal antiviral pharmacy program—tens of thousands of pharmacy locations nationwide—to order free oral antiviral treatments directly from the federal government. Pharmacies will also continue to be able to receive treatments from state and territorial health departments and through the Test-to-Treat initiative. For many Americans, pharmacies are the most common and convenient place to pick up their prescriptions and receive other forms of health care. Opening ordering to all of these pharmacies will dramatically expand the number of local pharmacies with oral antivirals in stock for patients in their community. The Administration expects that oral antivirals will soon be available in more than 30,000 locations. The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will work with pharmacy partners to increase availability even further to up to 40,000 sites over the coming weeks—bringing these treatments closer to more Americans.<br><br><strong>Launching a new effort to stand up federally-supported Test-to-Treat sites. </strong>Building on the current 2,200 Test-to-Treat sites in pharmacies and other clinical settings, the federal government will work with states and jurisdictions to establish additional Test-to-Treat locations with federal support. These sites will co-locate testing, an assessment from a medical provider, and oral antiviral treatments in one convenient stop—launching in partnership with state, Tribal, and territorial governments, and with support and coordination from HHS and the Federal Emergency Management Agency. These sites will launch in select communities in the coming weeks and, as more data comes in, the Administration will determine how federally-supported sites can best be expanded and scaled if needed during any potential future surge in cases. These sites will be targeted to meet demand and increase equitable access to lifesaving COVID-19 treatments and will function in direct collaboration with state and local health agencies. The Administration will also continue working with existing Test-to-Treat pharmacy partners to improve the patient experience, including through telehealth options.<br><br><strong>Supporting medical providers with more guidance and tools to understand and prescribe treatments. </strong>It is critical that health care providers stay informed about the latest information on effective COVID-19 treatments—including their benefits, contraindications, drug-to-drug interactions, and other side effects—so that they are in a position to quickly prescribe one of these treatments where appropriate. The Administration has been working for months with health care providers around the country to inform them about new treatments, with weekly webinars with state and territorial health officials, health care and medical organizations, as well as biweekly clinical webinars with health care providers, including those who specialize in treating high-risk patients. The Administration will continue to engage the clinical community to broaden awareness and understanding of these treatments and to make sure that health care providers are counseling their patients about these effective treatments, prescribing them when appropriate, and helping patients identify where their prescription can be filled. This includes providing toolkits and resources to help doctors assess whether treatments are appropriate for their patients and additional guidance and outreach to every state, pharmacy chain, and major medical association to increase awareness around eligibility, accessibility, contraindications and prescribing considerations for COVID-19 treatments. To that end, just yesterday, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) issued a <a href="https://emergency.cdc.gov/han/2022/pdf/CDC_HAN_463.pdf">Health Alert Network health advisory</a> to its extensive network of public health officials to provide additional information about the efficacy and availability of these treatments. Building on its ongoing work with electronic health record companies to develop and disseminate information about COVID-19 treatments to providers, the Administration is also calling on these companies to incorporate information about oral antivirals directly into their health records interface. This would make it easier to prompt doctors with information about treatments and locations when interacting with a patient—helping to better integrate the prescription of oral antivirals to patients that need them into doctors’ everyday practice.<br><br><strong>Communicating to the American people that safe, effective treatments are widely available. </strong>Now that the Administration has made treatments widely available and there are tens of thousands of sites around the country where they can be dispensed, the Administration will ramp up its public awareness and education efforts on COVID-19 treatments. The Administration’s efforts will focus on making sure that people know that COVID-19 oral antiviral treatments must be taken within the first five days of symptom onset and understand their role in reducing the risk of severe disease and death from COVID-19. These efforts build on steps that the Administration has taken in recent weeks to help people access treatments, including the launch of COVID.gov, creating shareable infographics with clear test-and-treat messages, promoting test-and-treat messages on social media, launching the <a href="https://covid-19-test-to-treat-locator-dhhs.hub.arcgis.com/">Test-to-Treat locator</a>, and standing up a call center (800-232-0233) to provide help in English, Spanish, and more than 150 other languages.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
