<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 12:12:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on the Department of Justice Leak Investigation Policy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/05/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-department-of-justice-leak-investigation-policy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19825</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As appropriate given the independence of the Justice Department in specific criminal cases, no one at the White House was aware of the gag order until Friday night. While the White House does not intervene in criminal investigations, the issuing of subpoenas for the records of reporters in leak investigations is not consistent with the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As appropriate given the independence of the Justice Department in specific criminal cases, no one at the White House was aware of the gag order until Friday night. While the White House does not intervene in criminal investigations, the issuing of subpoenas for the records of reporters in leak investigations is not consistent with the President’s policy direction to the Department, and the Department of Justice has reconfirmed it will not be used moving forward.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden Recognizing the 40th Year of the HIV/AIDS Epidemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/05/statement-by-president-joe-biden-recognizing-the-40th-year-of-the-hiv-aids-epidemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19815</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Forty years ago today, five young men in Los Angeles were confirmed as the first known patients stricken with an illness that the world would later come to know as AIDS. In the decades since, more than 700,000 Americans and 32.7 million people worldwide have been lost to AIDS-related illnesses – a heartbreaking human toll&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Forty years ago today, five young men in Los Angeles were confirmed as the first known patients stricken with an illness that the world would later come to know as AIDS. In the decades since, more than 700,000 Americans and 32.7 million people worldwide have been lost to AIDS-related illnesses – a heartbreaking human toll that has disproportionately devastated LGBTQ+ communities, communities of color, and underserved and marginalized people around the world.</p>



<p>On the 40th year of the HIV/AIDS epidemic, we remember the lives that were cut short by this terrible disease – including so many whose pain went unacknowledged for far too long. We also celebrate the resilience and dignity of the over 38 million people worldwide, including approximately 1.2 million Americans, living with HIV.</p>



<p>Thanks to the tireless dedication of activists, scientific researchers, and medical professionals, we have made tremendous progress to advance HIV research, prevention, treatment, and care. And after years of neglect, discrimination, fear-mongering, and limited action by government officials and the public, America has grown to become a leading force in the fight to end the HIV crisis. Through the President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief – and as the largest donor to the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria – the U.S. has invested more than $85 billion since 2002 to support HIV programs around the world, including $250 million provided in my American Rescue Plan to address the impacts of COVID-19 on our progress in the fight against HIV. All told, these efforts are estimated to have saved more than 20 million lives globally. To help accelerate and strengthen our efforts to end the HIV epidemic in the United States, I have requested $670 million from Congress, an increase of $267 million over previous levels, to aggressively reduce new HIV cases by increasing access to treatment, expanding the use of preexposure prophylaxis (PrEP), and ensuring equitable access to services free from stigma and discrimination.</p>



<p>Despite the progress we’ve made, our work is not yet finished. In honor of all those we have lost and all those living with the virus – and the selfless caregivers, advocates, and loved ones who have helped carry the burden of this crisis – we must rededicate ourselves to reducing HIV infections and AIDS-related deaths. We must continue empowering researchers, scientists, and health care providers to ensure equitable access to prevention, care, and treatment in every community – particularly for communities of color and the LGBTQ+ community. And we must provide moral leadership to eradicate the stigma and discrimination still faced by those living with HIV, rededicating ourselves to continuing the vital work of ending this epidemic once and for all.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on the President’s Calls with Senator Shelley Moore Capito and House Transportation and Infrastructure Chairman Peter DeFazio</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/04/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-presidents-calls-with-senator-shelley-moore-capito-and-house-transportation-and-infrastructure-chairman-peter-defazio/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 21:02:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President spoke to Senator Shelley Moore Capito and Chairman Peter DeFazio today. Senator Capito conveyed to the President a new offer from her group which consisted of an about $50 billion increase in spending across a number of infrastructure programs. The President expressed his gratitude for her effort and goodwill, but also indicated that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President spoke to Senator Shelley Moore Capito and Chairman Peter DeFazio today.</p>



<p>Senator Capito conveyed to the President a new offer from her group which consisted of an about $50 billion increase in spending across a number of infrastructure programs. The President expressed his gratitude for her effort and goodwill, but also indicated that the current offer did not meet his objectives to grow the economy, tackle the climate crisis, and create new jobs. He indicated to Senator Capito that he would continue to engage a number of Senators in both parties in the hopes of achieving a more substantial package. They agreed to speak again on Monday.</p>



<p>The President also spoke to Chairman DeFazio to thank him for all his hard work on key elements of the American Jobs Plan, and to offer his support for the Committee mark-up that Chairman DeFazio will begin on Wednesday. The President and Chairman DeFazio agreed on the benefits of continued engagement with Democratic and Republican Senators as the House work on infrastructure advances this coming week.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s call with National Security Advisor Thanos Dokos of Greece</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/04/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-apnsa-jake-sullivans-call-with-national-security-advisor-thanos-dokos-of-greece/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Dr. Thanos Dokos, National Security Advisor of Greece.&#160;Mr. Sullivan welcomed the strong relationship between our countries, including our growing defense cooperation, and conveyed the Biden Administration’s commitment to further deepening these ties. They discussed the importance of stability in the Eastern Mediterranean. Mr. Sullivan welcomed the resumption&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Dr. Thanos Dokos, National Security Advisor of Greece.&nbsp;Mr. Sullivan welcomed the strong relationship between our countries, including our growing defense cooperation, and conveyed the Biden Administration’s commitment to further deepening these ties. They discussed the importance of stability in the Eastern Mediterranean. Mr. Sullivan welcomed the resumption of dialogue between Greece and Turkey, and he pledged continued U.S. support for UN-facilitated efforts to reunify Cyprus as a bizonal, bicommunal federation. They also discussed the importance of countering harmful influence in the region, as Mr. Sullivan welcomed Greece’s recent efforts to secure its critical telecommunications and energy infrastructure. They agreed to remain in touch on shared interests, underscoring the importance of regional cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum for the Secretary of Defense on 2020 Unified Command Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/04/memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-defense-on-2020-unified-command-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 18:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19777</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pursuant to my authority as Commander in Chief, I&#160;hereby rescind direction dated January 13, 2021, to the Department of Defense to begin drafting Change&#160;1 to the 2020 Unified Command Plan to reassign the responsibility for Greenland from United States European Command to United States Northern Command. &#160; Consistent with title 10, United States Code, section&#160;161(b)(2)&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Pursuant to my authority as Commander in Chief, I&nbsp;hereby rescind direction dated January 13, 2021, to the Department of Defense to begin drafting Change&nbsp;1 to the 2020 Unified Command Plan to reassign the responsibility for Greenland from United States European Command to United States Northern Command. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Consistent with title 10, United States Code, section&nbsp;161(b)(2) and title 3, United States Code, section 301, you are directed to notify the Congress on my behalf.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Appoints Members to President’s Commission on White House Fellowships</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/04/president-biden-appoints-members-to-presidents-commission-on-white-house-fellowships/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 17:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden appointed 22 members to the President’s Commission on White House Fellowships. The Commission is composed of outstanding citizens who reflect the diversity and strength of America while representing a broad range of backgrounds, experiences, and professions. Commissioners are responsible for recommending a group of candidates to the President for selection as White&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden appointed 22 members to the President’s Commission on White House Fellowships.</p>



<p>The Commission is composed of outstanding citizens who reflect the diversity and strength of America while representing a broad range of backgrounds, experiences, and professions. Commissioners are responsible for recommending a group of candidates to the President for selection as White House Fellows, a prestigious program for leadership and public service that provides young Americans experience working at the highest levels of the federal government.</p>



<p>“These leaders represent the best of America – our collective character, creativity, and diversity. I am grateful these dedicated and accomplished Americans will help select and mentor the next class of White House Fellows who demonstrate exceptional leadership, unwavering passion, and a strong commitment to public service,” <strong>said President Biden.</strong></p>



<p><strong><u>President’s Commission on White House Fellows</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Demetra Lambros, Chair</strong></p>



<p>Demetra Lambros is a criminal appellate lawyer who, during 20 years at the Justice Department, handled high-profile murder, public corruption, drug conspiracy, human trafficking, fraud, and gang-related prosecutions. During the Obama Administration, she served as Counsel to then-Vice President Biden. In the 1990s, she was General Counsel for the Senate Judiciary Committee, under the chairmanship of then-Senator Biden, where she worked on the Violence Against Women Act, among other measures. Previously, Demetra was in private practice at Williams &amp; Connolly. She currently lives in Missoula, Montana where she cooks for domestic violence survivors and young, single moms.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Karen R. Adler</strong></p>



<p>Karen R. Adler is an independent management consultant working with high-net-worth families and their foundations. She is Senior Vice President of&nbsp;the Adler Group, a multi-generational family business, and President of the Jewish Communal Fund. Karen has spent much of her career mentoring and encouraging young people to seek out and accept the challenges and rerewards of a career in public service.</p>



<p><strong>Raumesh Akbari</strong></p>



<p>A proud Memphian and passionate advocate for justice and equality, Senator Raumesh Akbari serves in the Tennessee State Senate for the 29<sup>th</sup> district where her work to improve student outcomes and reform broken criminal justice policies has earned national and international recognition. Senator Akbari, an attorney for her family’s small business, represents the heart of downtown Memphis and parts of greater Shelby County, but her leadership is felt throughout the state as the Chairwoman of the Tennessee Senate Democratic Caucus, and her ideas are heard nationally as a leader on presidential task forces and a member of organizations advancing women, equity, and solution-oriented policies.</p>



<p><strong>Cordell Carter II</strong></p>



<p>Cordell Carter II leads the Aspen Institute Socrates Program, a global education forum for leaders, and Expectant Advisory, an equity-focused consultancy working towards a society where everyone belongs and has an equitable opportunity to thrive. Previously, he held leadership roles with the TechTown Foundation, Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, Business Roundtable, National Alliance for Public Charter Schools, and the IBM Corporation. He has been selected as an Eisenhower Fellow (China), Robert Bosch Stiftung Fellow (Germany), and a Broad Resident in Urban Education.</p>



<p><strong>Marco A. Davis</strong></p>



<p>Marco A. Davis is President and CEO of the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute (CHCI), a national nonprofit organization dedicated to developing the next generation of Latino leaders. Prior to joining CHCI, Davis was a partner at New Profit, a national nonprofit venture philanthropy. He served in the Obama-Biden Administration as Deputy Director of the White House Initiative on Educational Excellence for Hispanics and as Director of Public Engagement for the Corporation for National and Community Service. He is a member of Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, Inc. and holds a B.A. in History and Latin American Studies from Yale University. Originally from the New York City area, he lives in the District of Columbia with his wife and daughter.</p>



<p><strong>Dr. George E. Gabriel</strong></p>



<p>Dr. George E. Gabriel is a lifelong educator and researcher with over 40 years of demonstrated experience on two continents. He has a strong belief that higher education is the primary tool for socioeconomic mobility with equity at the heart of the mobility agenda. Dr. Gabriel is a first-generation college graduate and an immigrant to the United States who obtained his doctorate at Vanderbilt University as a Fulbright Scholar. He has spent over a quarter century as a researcher and administrator at two large community colleges. His focus has been on student success in community colleges with the specific goal to narrow achievement gaps in student outcomes by implementing innovative practices.</p>



<p><strong>Robert Hoopes</strong></p>



<p>Robert Hoopes is founder and president of VOX Global, a DC based consultancy that works across policy issues including ESG, education, IOT, and diversity, equity, and inclusion. Robert is passionate about good government, education, and democracy; he has worked in the U.S. Senate Office of Joseph R. Biden, Jr. and served as Chief of Staff for then-Vice President Biden at the 2012 Democratic National Convention. Robert earned his B.A. in government from Colby College and an MLA from The George Washington University. He serves on the Board of Trustees at Colby College and the Board of Advisors at the Graduate School of Political Management at GWU. Robert is married to Hilary Barnes Hoopes and they have three children.</p>



<p><strong>Nomaan</strong><strong>&nbsp;“Nomi” K. Husain</strong></p>



<p>Mr. Nomaan “Nomi” K. Husain is the founder of Husain Law + Associates, PC, a boutique law firm based in Houston, Texas that focuses on litigation, immigration, aviation. He currently serves as a Commissioner on the Harris County Houston Sports Authority, is an Advisor to Harris County Sheriff Ed Gonzalez, Ft. Bend County District Attorney, and is a member of the Dean’s Advisory Committee for University of Texas at Austin’s College of Liberal Arts and University of Texas School of Dentistry. He has also served as the Chairman of City of Houston’s Ethics Commission, Chairman and President of the South Asian Chamber of Commerce, member of the Mayor’s Advisory Committee for South Asia, and as the legal counsel to Pakistan Chamber of Commerce.</p>



<p><strong>Joe Kennedy III</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Joe Kennedy III served as a Member of the House of Representatives from Massachusetts, in the Peace Corps, as a legal aid volunteer, and an assistant district attorney. He currently resides in Newton, Massachusetts with his wife Lauren, their children Eleanor and James, and their dog Banjo.</p>



<p><strong>Hildy Kuryk</strong></p>



<p>Hildy Kuryk is a Partner at Artemis Strategies, a boutique consultancy that helps companies and individuals distill, articulate, and connect their values to their desired consumer. Prior to Artemis, Hildy was the Executive Director of Communications at Vogue. Before joining Vogue, Hildy spent her career in professional politics serving two presidents. She started in the White House Office of Legislative Affairs for President Bill Clinton and ended as the National Finance Director of the Democratic National Committee for President Barack Obama.&nbsp; She currently lives in Brooklyn with her husband and two children.</p>



<p><strong>Deborah Jospin</strong></p>



<p>Deborah (Deb) Jospin is the founder of Jospin Strategic, a consulting firm that provides strategic advice for public and private sector clients. Along with her former business partner Shirley Sagawa, Deb is the co-author of <em>The Charismatic Organization: Eight Ways to Grow a Nonprofit that Builds Buzz, Delights Donors and Engages Employees</em>, Jossey-Bass, 2008. Before starting her consulting career, Deb was the Associate General Counsel and Chief of Staff at the Corporation for National Service, and she served as the Director of AmeriCorps from 1997-2001.</p>



<p><strong>Nicole&nbsp;</strong><strong>Malachowski</strong></p>



<p>An inductee into the National Women&#8217;s Hall of Fame, Colonel Nicole Malachowski (USAF, Retired) served over 21 years in the United States Air Force as an officer and career fighter pilot. During that time, she had the honor of commanding a fighter squadron, flying as a USAF Thunderbird pilot, and serving as a White House Fellow and advisor to the First Lady of the United States. Following her medical retirement from the military, Nicole became a staunch national-level patient advocate for those enduring Tick-Borne Illnesses and recently founded Nicole Malachowski &amp; Associates, LLC where she serves as a professional speaker and leadership consultant.</p>



<p><strong>Stacey&nbsp;</strong><strong>Mindich</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Stacey Mindich is a Tony, Grammy, and Olivier Award-winning theatrical producer. She has produced more than 20 plays and musicals, and originated the international sensation <em>Dear Evan Hansen</em>, which will relaunch its critically-acclaimed productions on Broadway, in London, and on a national tour this fall, alongside the release of a major motion picture adaption. Previously a journalist and editor, Stacey is the co-chair of New York City Center’s Board of Trustees, as well as a founding member of The Lilly Awards. Her proudest productions are the three sons she shares with husband, Eric Mindich.</p>



<p><strong>Courtney O’Donnell</strong></p>



<p>Courtney Diesel O’Donnell has driven social impact through global public affairs and partnership development in senior roles in the White House, at non-profit organizations, national political campaigns, and in the private sector. Most recently, O’Donnell served as Director of Global Partnerships at Airbnb where she established alliances to encourage sustainable tourism, support economic empowerment, and promote female entrepreneurship around the world. In the Obama-Biden Administration, she served as Communications Director to Dr. Jill Biden, and on the Biden-Harris presidential campaign, O’Donnell served as Chief of Staff to Douglas Emhoff and advised on women’s engagement. O’Donnell serves on the Advisory Boards of the Beeck Center for Social Impact + Innovation at Georgetown University and the Thomson Reuters Foundation.</p>



<p><strong>Katherine Rice</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Katherine Rice is a senior executive, board director, and investment professional with a passion for advancing the next generation of successful women leaders Rice is currently a Senior Advisor to GingerBread Capital, investing in women founders of growth companies. She is also the Founder and CEO of Rice Advisory Corp., a strategy consulting business focused on scaling consumer companies.&nbsp; Active in community and political affairs, Rice is a long-time advocate for women’s and LGBTQ+ rights.&nbsp; Rice holds an M.B.A. from the Stanford University Graduate School of Business and a B.A. from Vanderbilt University. Originally from Texas, Rice currently resides in Mill Valley, California with her partner Jennifer and daughter Avery.</p>



<p><strong>Ramona Romero</strong></p>



<p>Ramona Emilia Romero is the Vice President and General Counsel of Princeton University. Before joining the University in 2014, Romero was the General Counsel of the U.S. Department of Agriculture. Earlier in her career, Romero worked in a variety of legal roles at DuPont and as a litigator at Crowell &amp; Moring, LLP. Romero is currently a trustee of Barnard College and a director of Legal Services of New Jersey. She is a former National President of the Hispanic National Bar Association (HNBA). An immigrant from the Dominican Republic, Romero holds a B.A. from Barnard College and a J.D. from Harvard Law School.&nbsp; She, her husband, and their two daughters live in Princeton, NJ.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Jennie Rosenthal</strong></p>



<p>Jennie Rosenthal is a current Board Member and immediate past Chair of the National Board of The Planned Parenthood Action Fund, Vice President of the Board of The Ohio Innocence Project, Board Member of The Democracy Alliance, Member of the Ohio Progressive Collaborative, Emeritus Trustee of the Contemporary Arts Center in Cincinnati, and Co-Director of the Rosenthal Family Foundation. The mission is to improve the social and economic fabric of Cincinnati focusing on affordable housing, food insecurity, social and criminal justice, education, women’s rights, and innovative programs in the arts. Jennie is a fundraiser, grassroots organizer, and advisor for local, state, and national political campaigns.</p>



<p><strong>Michael Schrum</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Michael is Political Director for Emerson Collective where he leads political grantmaking and advocacy efforts in pursuit of a more equal and just America, with a focus on fair representation and access to democracy. Prior to joining Emerson, he served as Personal Aide to then-Vice President Biden, followed by two years as Vice President Biden’s Director of Intergovernmental Affairs and Special Assistant to the President. After leaving the White House, he served as Treasurer for the American Possibilities PAC, and then he helped with the launch of Biden for President. Prior to his time with then-Vice President Biden, he was appointed as Deputy Director of the Department of Labor’s Office of Public Engagement. Michael lives in D.C with his wife Maya and two kids Eshaan and Neela.</p>



<p><strong>Kenny Thompson Jr.</strong></p>



<p>Kenny Thompson, Jr. is Vice President of Corporate Affairs, North America at PepsiCo. He applies his experience with social impact, corporate responsibility, sustainability, advocacy, and communications to generate new business, amplify PepsiCo’s business partnerships, and grow PepsiCo’s reputation as a responsible corporate citizen. Before joining PepsiCo, Kenny held several positions in the Obama-Biden White House, including Director of Message Events for then-Vice President Joe Biden, Senior Advisor to United States Trade Representative Ron Kirk, and Special Assistant and Advance Lead for President Barack Obama.A native Texan, Kenny completed his undergraduate degree at Texas Christian University where he was a proud member of the Horned Frog baseball team. He later earned a Master of Business Administration from Georgetown University.</p>



<p><strong>Linda Whitlock</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Currently Founder and Principal of The Whitlock Group, providing management, strategy, and governance consulting to boards and CEOs. Linda was a transformative CEO of Boys &amp; Girls Clubs of Boston, served in the administrations of Massachusetts Governors Dukakis and King, and taught at MIT, Tufts, and the University of Michigan. Now serving on the boards of the Red Sox Foundation and the National Association of Corporate Directors New England, Linda has been honored as a Distinguished Bostonian by the Greater Boston Chamber of Commerce and has been recognized by many other corporate, civic, and philanthropic organizations in the region. Linda has an A.B. from Mount Holyoke College and an A.M. from the University of Michigan, and she completed Executive Education programs at Harvard Business School, Harvard Kennedy School, and the Aspen Institute.</p>



<p><strong>Fidel Vargas</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Fidel A. Vargas is President and CEO of the Hispanic Scholarship Fund (HSF). Prior to joining HSF, Fidel was a Founding Partner of Centinela Capital Partners. At the age of 23, Fidel was elected the country’s youngest mayor of a major city in Baldwin Park, California. Fidel graduated with honors from Harvard University with an A.B. in Social Studies and received his M.B.A. from Harvard Business School with a concentration in Entrepreneurship and General Management.</p>



<p><strong>Dr. Alfred Yung</strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Yung is a Professor of Neuro-Oncology, Senior Advisor of the Brain Tumor Center, and a member of the Cancer Moonshot leadership at the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center at Houston. He received his M.D. degree from the University of Chicago Pritzker School of Medicine. He joined MDACC 1981 and served as Chair of Department of Neuro-Oncology for 15 years. He was the second Editor-in-Chief of Neuro-Oncology, Co-Chair of the NCI Brain Malignancy Steering Committee. Currently, he is serving as Special Scientific Advisor of the National Brain Tumor Society and a member of the Scientific Advisory Committee of the Ludwig Institute of Cancer research, among many other roles.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the May Jobs Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/04/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-may-jobs-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 17:35:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19769</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rehoboth Beach Convention CenterRehoboth Beach, Delaware 10:38 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, folks.&#160; Good morning.&#160; Today, we received great news for our economy and our recovery and for the American people.&#160; This morning, we learned that, in May, our economy created 559,000 new jobs, unemployment rate fell to 5.8 percent, and wages went up for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rehoboth Beach Convention Center<br>Rehoboth Beach, Delaware</p>



<p>10:38 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, folks.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Today, we received great news for our economy and our recovery and for the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>This morning, we learned that, in May, our economy created 559,000 new jobs, unemployment rate fell to 5.8 percent, and wages went up for American workers.&nbsp; That means we have now created over 2 million jobs in total since I took office &#8212; more jobs than have ever been created in the first four months of any presidency in modern history, triple the rate of my predecessor, eight times the rate of President Reagan.<br><br>The unemployment rate is now below 6 percent for the first time since the pandemic hit.&nbsp; The first 14 months &#8212; first time &#8212; first time in 14 months, we saw the largest decline in the number of long-term unemployed, more &#8212; in more than an entire decade, in the last 10 years.<br><br>Long-term unemployment dropped by the second largest amount ever recorded.&nbsp; Not only that, but the signs of further progress are already here.&nbsp;<br><br>This report is based on a weekly &#8212; a week in early May.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we &#8212; they determine the &#8212; the job rate &#8212; growth or loss; we have growth.&nbsp; And that &#8212; and this &#8212; that week in May, we only had 35 percent of working-age adults had been fully vaccinated.&nbsp; Now we&#8217;re still all &#8212; they were still all wearing masks.&nbsp;<br><br>Since then, 21 million more adults have gotten vaccinated, making it easy for them to return to work safely.&nbsp; In short, this is progress &#8212; historic progress.&nbsp; Progress that&#8217;s pulling our economy out of the worst crisis it&#8217;s been in 100 years.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s testament to the new strategy that is growing this economy, not only growing it, but growing it from the bottom up and the middle out.<br><br>Remember, when I took office in January, our economy was in a tailspin, job growth had stalled, COVID was raging, average initial claims for unemployment insurance were over 830,000 per week.&nbsp; Now those claims have fallen below 430,000 &#8212; about half of what they were when I took office.&nbsp;<br><br>Before I took office, almost 24 million Americans were going hungry.&nbsp; Remember those long lines of cars, miles long, people waiting for just a box of food to be put in their trunk?&nbsp; That number has already dropped by 25 percent.&nbsp; Still too many, but clear progress.<br><br>Before I took office, independent experts were projecting that the American economy would grow by 3 or 4 percent in 2021 &#8212; this year.&nbsp; This week, the Organisation of Economic Co-operation and Development &#8212; the so-called OECD, which makes up a group that includes the world&#8217;s largest economies in its membership and has been one of the meeting body&#8217;s analyzing economic growth worldwide in individual nations &#8212; increased their projection for U.S. economic growth this year to 6.9 percent in 2021.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the fastest pace in nearly four decades.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, the U.S. is the only major economy where projections of future growth are stronger today than they were before the pandemic hit in 2020. &nbsp;<br><br>And in May, manufacturing activity was nearly as strong as it was in more than 15 years &#8212; stronger than in 15 years.&nbsp; No other major econo- &#8212; major economy in the world is growing as fast as ours.&nbsp; No other major economy is gaining jobs as quickly as ours.&nbsp;<br><br>And none of this success is an accident; it isn&#8217;t luck.&nbsp; It&#8217;s due in no small part, first of all, to the cooperation of the American people in responding to my effort to get COVID under control &#8212; wearing masks initially and getting vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>And it&#8217;s no small part to the bold action we took by passing the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; The plan provided those resources to get shots in people&#8217;s arms; underwrite the vaccination effort; enough vaccine supply for every single American; more vaccinators, people to put shots in the arms; and more vaccination sites.&nbsp;<br><br>And now, 52 percent &#8212; 52 percent of American adults are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; 75 percent of our seniors are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; And the American Rescue pan [sic] &#8212; Plan delivered economic benefits directly to the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>Because of that law, more than 167 million of those Rescue payments of up to $1,400 have gone out to individual families.&nbsp; A recent study &#8212; the Census Bureau data found just how much these checks mattered.&nbsp; They drastically reluced [sic] &#8212; reduced depression &#8212; according to study &#8212; anxiety, and hardship for families.&nbsp; More than 40 percent fewer families struggled to afford food, rent, utilities, car payments, student loans, and healthcare expenses.<br><br>Small businesses and restaurants are &#8212; were getting killed.&nbsp; Now we&#8217;re delivering loans and support they need to reopen and to stay open.<br><br>Schools are struggling to reopen, so we made vaccinating teachers a priority.&nbsp; We delivered schools the much support they needed.&nbsp; State and local governments had to lay off tens of thousands of educators and first responders.&nbsp; Many are now back on the job, thanks to the Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, in May, state and local governments added 103,000 education jobs &#8212; returned them to work.&nbsp; These funds are continuing to get out this month to support state and local governments, which will help get more people back to work.<br><br>Small- and medium-sized businesses are now able to take advantage of a special tax credit called the “Employee Retention Tax Credit.”&nbsp; It provides businesses a generous tax credit to retain or hire more workers.&nbsp;<br><br>Through our Restaurant Revitalization Fund, we anticipate being able to help over 100,000 hard-hit restaurants stay open or reopen.&nbsp;<br><br>And beginning next month, most families with children will be getting a tax cut, which will be going into &#8212; deposited into their accounts &#8212; directly into their bank accounts every month.&nbsp;<br><br>We know that access to childcare is one of the biggest barriers in the way of parents going back to work.&nbsp; Our administration is delivering $39 billion in childcare relief to help childcare providers get back on their feet &#8212; the providers &#8212; and serve more families.<br><br>And this month, our economy added nearly 20,000 more childcare jobs that weren&#8217;t there last month &#8212; in fact, allowing parents to have access to get help.<br><br>And temporary boost in unemployment benefits that ended &#8212; that we enacted, I should say &#8212; helped people who lost their jobs through no fault of their own, and who still may be in the process of getting vaccinated.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s going to expire in 90 days.&nbsp; That makes sense it expires in 90 days.<br><br>To sum it up: Look, COVID cases are down, COVID deaths are up [down], unemployment filings are down, hunger is down, and vaccinations are up, jobs are up, wages are up, manufacturing is up, growth is up, people gaining healthcare coverage is up, and small business confidence is up. &nbsp;<br><br>America is finally on the move again.&nbsp; As we continue this recovery, we&#8217;re going to hit some bumps along the way.&nbsp; Of course, that will happen.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t reboot the world&#8217;s largest economy like flipping on a ni- &#8212; light switch.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s going to be ups and downs in jobs and economic reports, but we&#8217;re going to be &#8212; supply chain issues and price pressures on the way back to stability and steady growth.<br><br>In the coming weeks, my administration is going to take steps to combat these supply constraints, building on the work we&#8217;re doing on the computer chips; that is, we&#8217;re providing more computer chips to be manufactured here in the United States so it doesn&#8217;t slow up the manufacturing of automobiles, for example.<br><br>Everyone needs to get their shots though.&nbsp; Now is the time to accelerate the <s>process</s> [progress] we’ve been making.&nbsp; Now is the time to build on the foundation we&#8217;ve laid, because while progress is undeniable, it is not assured.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s why I proposed the American Jobs Plan and the American Family Plan for generational investments we need today.&nbsp; We need to make those investments today to be able to continue to succeed tomorrow.<br><br>We have a chance to seize on the economic momentum of the first months of my administration, not just to build back, but to build back better.&nbsp;<br><br>This much is already clear: We&#8217;re on the right track. &nbsp;Our plan is working.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re not going to let up now.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to move on.&nbsp; I&#8217;m extremely optimistic.&nbsp; I hope you are as well.&nbsp;<br><br>And may God bless you, may God bless America, and may God protect our troops. &nbsp;Thank you all for being here this morning. &nbsp;Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, do you have (inaudible) on the infrastructure talks?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m going to be having a talk this afternoon, and I’ll be able to report to you after that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you expecting a counteroffer, Mr. President?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ll tell you after I meet this afternoon.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you still have confidence in Dr. Fauci?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, I’m very confident in Dr. Fauci.<br><br>10:48 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Op-Ed: Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh on Supporting the Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders Community</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2021/06/04/op-ed-deputy-national-security-advisor-daleep-singh-on-supporting-the-asian-americans-and-pacific-islanders-community/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 15:05:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By: Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh My story is the story of so many other Indian Americans. In search of a better life for their kids – and maybe a bit of adventure for themselves &#8211; my parents left India for America in the 1970s. I was born in Maryland, spent a few years&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>By: Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh</em></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>My story is the story of so many other Indian Americans. In search of a better life for their kids – and maybe a bit of adventure for themselves &#8211; my parents left India for America in the 1970s. I was born in Maryland, spent a few years in Chicago, and settled in North Carolina when I was about seven years old.</p>



<p>I’ve always described my childhood as a happy one. Surrounded by a loving family, I felt like I was part of something bigger than myself, and that my life meant something to those around me. I also felt enormous pride and gratitude in being an American – having the freedom to find and become my authentic self, and the opportunity to dream big, even if in my case these were mostly athletic delusions.</p>



<p>At a young age, I also knew that we were different. I remember on the first day we arrived in Raleigh, our apartment was filled with unopened boxes. But instead of unpacking, my parents grabbed the phone book, found three Indian-sounding last names, and invited them over for dinner. All of them arrived within hours and, from that point on, we probably shared at least one weekend meal within the Indian community until I went away for college.</p>



<p>As I got older, I began to understand how much these gatherings meant. Like anyone else, my parents wanted a space where their traditions and beliefs were accepted, and that hadn’t always been their experience. When he first moved to the U.S., my dad &#8211; a turbaned Sikh &#8211; was told by his boss: if he wanted to keep his job, he’d need to fit in better. So that’s what my dad did – he sacrificed part of his identity to provide for his family. Meanwhile, my mom worked for the Raleigh city government, and I’ll never forget her coming home in tears after her boss openly bragged that he was a member of the KKK. He made sure to remind her of that throughout her years of dedicated but painful service in Raleigh city government.</p>



<p>I also wanted to feel accepted, but for that to happen as a kid it sometimes involved compromises that I now regret. I remember feeling dread in middle school whenever we’d have a substitute teacher, knowing they would butcher my name, and giving the whole class a good laugh at my expense. Sometimes I thought the solution was to just own it, so I’d speak during class with a thick Indian accent. When I think about that now, I’m ashamed. I made a joke out of my family’s background to deal with my own insecurity about being different.<br>Fast forwarding to the past few years, the rise in hateful attacks against Asian Americans and other communities of color made me realize that I was still carrying a lot of memories – painful ones – that felt heavier over the years. I’d almost forgotten the humiliation of getting beat up on the back of an elementary school bus for being the “dirty brown kid with smelly food,” or what it felt like to get told I couldn’t go on a date with someone in high school because I’m brown.</p>



<p>Much of the reason I’d been able to let these memories go was my deeply held belief that things were getting better when it came to race; that my kids would grow up in a different way. So I’ll admit, the slow progress and setbacks left me angry at times. I suspect many in the Indian American community feel the same way: we’re tired of watching the past repeat itself, and we’re exhausted from being quiet.</p>



<p>But to make change, we first have to recognize that we can all do better, myself included. That means being real about my own privilege as an Indian American from a middle-class household. I’m not at risk of being stopped and frisked. My wife and I don’t have to teach our kids how to survive if they get pulled over by the police. For those of us who’ve faced prejudice, we also need to check own our bias, and see our own privileges, if we’re going to do better.</p>



<p>It also means we need to speak out and do our part if we’re going to be seen as 100%, full-fledged, just-like-you citizens. As an Asian American, I’m deeply humbled and honored to have the privilege of serving in President Biden’s administration at a defining moment in our country’s history, while being a part of the most diverse administration ever assembled. My experience serving our country bears no resemblance to my mom’s days in Raleigh city government, but her experience back then, and recent violence toward Asian Americans, are a constant reminder to me about the responsibility I have of representing and standing up for the AAPI community every day in this job.</p>



<p>My role at the White House is to help create a self-reinforcing dynamic between domestic renewal, American leadership abroad, and national security. Part of domestic renewal has to do with economics: creating sustained and inclusive growth in jobs and wages, boosting the resilience of our critical supply chains, and strengthening our innovative edge. Another part of domestic renewal involves healing the wounds of racial injustice and coming together as a society to deliver on American’s unmatched promise. I don’t have direct policy responsibility in this area, but it’s central to what President Biden is trying to deliver, and a big reason why I’m here.</p>



<p>As a final thought, I want to use this platform to send love and support to my sisters and brothers in the Sikh community who have been a particular target of harassment, racism, and violence in recent years. I stand with them today and always.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki and Director of the National Economic Council Brian Deese, June 4, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/04/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-director-of-the-national-economic-council-brian-deese-june-4-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:39 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI: Hi, everyone. Happy Friday.  We have a special guest with us today, on Jobs Day &#8212; Brian Deese, our Director of the National Economic Council &#8212; who will give some brief remarks on the jobs numbers and take a few questions, and then we&#8217;ll&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:39 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Hi, everyone. Happy Friday.  We have a special guest with us today, on Jobs Day &#8212; Brian Deese, our Director of the National Economic Council &#8212; who will give some brief remarks on the jobs numbers and take a few questions, and then we&#8217;ll proceed with the briefing.</p>



<p>MR. DEESE: Great. Hi, everybody. Glad to be with you today. So you all heard from the President early today &#8212; earlier today with his perspective on the May employment report. So I won&#8217;t repeat what he said, but I just did want to provide a couple of contextual points and a little bit more looking under the hood of that report from an economic perspective.</p>



<p>So a couple of things that I think were notable from our perspective: First, beyond the topline &#8212; strong job gains and the now consistent pace of over 500,000 jobs a month for the last four months &#8212; we saw in May the largest one-month decline in long-term unemployment &#8212; the long-term unemployment rate since 2011, so in about a decade. That measure is measuring people who have been out of work for at least 27 weeks, so for more than half a year. And that number fell by 431,000 this month.</p>



<p>This is a really important indicator, certainly for those of us who have been watching and tracking the economy closely over the course of the last several years and into and through the pandemic. Because we know the economic evidence that those who are long-term unemployed tend to have the hardest time getting back into the labor force and eventually find new employment.</p>



<p>And so, this substantial reduction is an important indicator of the &#8212; that the health of the labor market and something that is obviously very good news for those people and also, I think, for the economy writ large.</p>



<p>Second is on wages. And the President touched on this, but we saw average weekly earnings rise a half a percent this month, which &#8212; consistent with the wage growth that we saw last month. We saw analogous data on aggregate compensation come out earlier this week.</p>



<p>And this again is &#8212; it&#8217;s good news &#8212; good news for the American worker, and also consistent with what the President was talking about when he went to Cleveland last week, around looking at the broader goals of our economic recovery to drive toward full employment and to put our economy in a situation where we see sustained job gains but also wage gains for American workers.</p>



<p>Third point is just how we see in this jobs report some of the impact of the American Rescue Plan and the specific elements of that work that were designed to try to address challenges that we face. Obviously, beyond the direct vaccination effort, two of the key elements of the American Jobs Plan were around trying to provide the support necessary to get schools open, and then, in particular, to provide the support for childcares and childcare centers to actually get more childcare centers open, because we know that the more centers that are open, the more slots there are, the safe &#8212; safe childcare environment is a key element of how families and parents think about how to sustain work in the post-COVID environment.</p>



<p>In May, we saw employment increase by 103,000 in state and local education. That is a direct result of seeing more schools open, more educator jobs. Good news for those people who are getting back to work but also for the broader economic recovery.</p>



<p>We saw 18,000 jobs added in child and daycare services. Again, you draw a direct line between the resources that were provided in the Rescue Plan for those purposes and the results we&#8217;re seeing now.</p>



<p>I would also provide the context on that: You know, despite that progress, we&#8217;re still down 800,000 state and local education jobs since February of 2020. And we&#8217;re still down 135,000 jobs in childcare. And I think that that&#8217;s a reminder of the depth of the crisis of this pandemic, the ways that we have to go, but also, I think, importantly, a reminder of why it is that we focused on passing a Rescue Plan that would sustain support over the course of this year &#8212; that the Rescue Plan was designed to not just provide support for a day or for a month, but over the course of the year, as we understood &#8212; and the need to continue to provide support, to continue to build back to a stronger foundation.</p>



<p>Fourth, I think that, you know, we&#8217;re looking at this employment report in the context of &#8212; of a number of contemporaneous economic data points.</p>



<p>The first &#8212; probably the most important that provides, I think, additional reason for economic optimism &#8212; is that this report was a snapshot of what &#8212; of where we were on May &#8212; May 12th. And perhaps most evocatively, and just how quickly things are changing, were we &#8212; were we to have been doing this briefing on the day that this &#8212; you know, on a day in that week, we all still would have been masked. Things are changing very quickly. And, in fact, since that period, an additional 21 million adult-age Americans have gotten fully vaccinated. And so we&#8217;re making progress even &#8212; even since this snapshot in time.</p>



<p>And secondly, we&#8217;re looking at, you know, this job growth in the context of the overall health and growth of the economy. And we saw earlier this week the OECD significantly increase its economic growth forecast to 6.9 percent for 2021.</p>



<p>In that report, citing that the American Rescue Plan and the United States fiscal response likely adding 3 to 4 percentage points to GDP this year and positioning the U.S., as the President heads to his first G7, as the only G7 country, the only OECD country in a position where our future growth prospects are actually stronger today than they were pre-pandemic in January 2020. That&#8217;s the &#8212; that&#8217;s only true of the United States, not any other developed country.</p>



<p>The final point that I will make is a point that you will hear me repeat is &#8212; if and when I come back and we talk more about jobs numbers in the future &#8212; is that we are in an unprecedented situation; there&#8217;s a lot of uncertainty in our economy; and we never put too much weight on any individual data point, be it a jobs report or any other report.</p>



<p>We expect there to be ups and downs. We expect there to be bottlenecks as we turn this economy back on. And our focus, the President&#8217;s focus, is on executing an economic strategy that is working &#8212; we see that in the data from today &#8212; but to be patient and think to the long term about what the American economy needs and the American workers need as well.</p>



<p>So with that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah. Just take a few &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. DEESE: &#8212; happy to open it up and take some questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &#8212; a few today.</p>



<p>But go ahead, Zeke.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Brian. You mentioned just now, and the President mentioned in his remarks earlier, the administration is going to look to efforts to address some of the supply bottlenecks. Industry experts say semiconductors &#8212; that&#8217;s a multi-year process to fix that. So what is the administration going to do to fix some of those bottlenecks that are raising prices right now?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE: Yeah, it&#8217;s a great question. So, first of all, I would say this is an issue that the President has been focused on from the campaign and early on in &#8212; upon taking office; that one of the things that the pandemic has exposed is the degree of vulnerability in supply chains and the need to have a deliberate strategy to try to build resilience in our supply chains.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s why the President actually, on February 25th, signed an executive order tasking an all-of-government approach to try to look at supply chain challenges across a set of four critical areas &#8212; one of them being semiconductors &#8212; but also to launch a longer-term effort to look at supply chain vulnerabilities and opportunities across sectors of the economy.</p>



<p>So, that &#8212; that executive order had a 100-day timeframe associated with it, which is &#8212; which is coming due at the end of this week. So you can expect to hear more from us on this topic early next week.</p>



<p>But, in short, what I would say is, look: On a lot of these issues, there is no immediate short-term, you know, magic-bullet fix. We have been at this issue of semiconductors now for some time. We&#8217;ve been spending an enormous amount of time with industry participants up and down the semiconductor supply chain. We&#8217;ve identified some very concrete solutions that we need to take, and thinking about a long-term strategy to actually build resilience so that we&#8217;re not left vulnerable, the way that we have been, to supply chain challenges in the future. Some of that is working on bipartisan legislation to actually fund a dedicated strategy to build out a domestic &#8212; domestic semiconductor industry in the United States. We&#8217;re making a lot of progress on that front and are optimistic there.</p>



<p>The other thing that we will be looking at is: Some areas where we have seen, over the course the last 100 days, bottlenecks emerge that are more short-term in nature, that may not connect to a longer-term geostrategic or &#8212; or &#8212; or strategic supply chain issue, but are blockages, in part because we&#8217;re seeing demand come back in some areas faster than people anticipated.</p>



<p>So whether that&#8217;s in, you know, housing and construction materials, or in transportation and logistics, those are areas we’re building on the all-of-government approach that we have in place, we&#8217;re going to intend to really zero in on: Are there pragmatic issues that we can help facilitate? And some of that is bringing the right industry actors around the table to really understand where those bottlenecks are and whether there are ways to unstick them.</p>



<p>At the end of the day, a lot of that issues are transitory, associated with turning an economy back on, and supply and demand mismatches that the market will work through. But we want to be doing everything that we can to try to help facilitate practical solutions where they exist.</p>



<p>So, we’ll have a lot more to say about the specifics of that, but I think that hopefully gives you the context.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;MS. PSAKI: Monica.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;Q&nbsp; So, last month, President Biden assessed that federal unemployment benefits had not contributed &#8212; or he didn’t see much evidence &#8212; to the more lackluster numbers. Is that still his assessment for this month? And given how many states are now going to end them through the month of June, with the President’s comments earlier today about them expiring in 90 days, should other states consider ending them sooner? Or could that money be used elsewhere?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE: So, I’d say a couple things about that. I mean, the first thing that &#8212; the first takeaway from this report is that we&#8217;re seeing really robust job growth. And we&#8217;re seeing, in fact, historic job growth in the context of historic economic growth.</p>



<p>So, we find ourselves &#8212; the American economy now &#8212; the economy is growing faster than any other major economy, jobs are growing faster than any other major economy. So, that&#8217;s the &#8212; that&#8217;s the &#8212; that&#8217;s the immediate context.</p>



<p>With respect to the UI benefits &#8212; you heard the President earlier today &#8212; this &#8212; that program was designed as a temporary lifeline. The UI program itself provides a critical support network to the American people and the American economy. And those temporary &#8212; the temporary boost is slated to now expire in 90 days. And as the President said, that&#8217;s appropriate.</p>



<p>With respect to some of the state changes, I just &#8212; just the important context &#8212; which I think is implicit in your question, but just to be clear &#8212; is that none of the state &#8212; none of the states have actually eliminated any benefits yet. Some states will initiate that process over the course of the next several weeks.</p>



<p>But, in many cases, what we&#8217;re talking about is states making changes to benefits for four weeks, six weeks, eight weeks before the expiration that is &#8212; that will happen under current law.</p>



<p>So, as we look at where we are in the economy, we see strong job growth &#8212; 500,000 jobs a month on average the last four months, the U.S. outpacing every other major economy in the world &#8212; and we see reason to really focus on what are &#8212; what are actually going to be the drivers to accelerate this recovery and then sustain it for the long term.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s where you&#8217;ll see the President&#8217;s continued focus is on finishing the job on vaccinations, delivering benefits to get schools open, to get childcare available, and focusing now &#8212; now is the right time to focus on what are those investments that are actually going to sustain us, not just through a rapid recovery, but into full employment and the kind of productive investments that you see in the Jobs Plan and the Families Plan.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Nancy, did you &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; I didn’t &#8212; oh, yeah. I &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: It’s got to be the last one, though, because he’s got to go to a meeting.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; My question was similar to Monica’s, so I’ll ask another one. How do you explain the drop in construction jobs last month? Wasn&#8217;t this a sector that was actually revving up?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE: Yeah, so it&#8217;s a great question. I think if you look under the hood in employment, in the establishment survey, what you see in May is job gains very broad-based across almost all sectors &#8212; job gains.</p>



<p>We did see, you know &#8212; we did see a reduction in construction. I think that, you know, the first thing I would say to that is that in any given month, you see some movements up and down, and so you never want to read too much into one month. But you saw construction jobs increase in the prior month. We saw manufacturing jobs decline in the prior month and up this month.</p>



<p>I think &#8212; but &#8212; so, you don&#8217;t want to read too much into one individual month. But I do think that some of this is connected to the prior question where we are &#8212; as we &#8212; as this economy recovers, we&#8217;re seeing some supply chain bottlenecks, we&#8217;re seeing some mismatches between supply and demand.</p>



<p>And as we anticipate those to be short term, they are still &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re still causing bottlenecks. And we&#8217;re seeing that in different sectors of the economy. I think some of that may be what&#8217;s going on in the &#8212; in the construction sector as well.</p>



<p>So &#8212; so I think, you know, bottom line, we saw broad-based job growth over the course of May. And I think that that&#8217;s the most important takeaway. And, at the same time, you can expect the administration to be really laser-focused on those places where we are seeing those bottlenecks, trying to make sure that we&#8217;re doing everything that we can, in a practical level, to try to help unstick those temporary issues.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: We can do one more.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; I just want to clarify really quickly, because you didn&#8217;t say yes or no: Does the President still feel that these enhanced jobless benefits are not discouraging people from finding jobs?</p>



<p>MR. DEESE: The President &#8212; I’ll just, you know, restate what the President said today: The President believes that the temporary unemployment benefits and the temporary boost to those benefits has provided a critical lifeline, that that lifeline was designed to be temporary and to expire in about 90 days. And that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s appropriate.</p>



<p>And I would, you know, also just put that in the context of that is a &#8212; that is a very short-term issue, where most states you’re talking about a set of weeks. And, really, as we look forward and are focused on what are the things that are really going to drive the durability of this economy going forward, you&#8217;re going to see the President continue focus like a laser on the vaccination program.</p>



<p>The President identified and recognized, before coming into office, that there would be no economic recovery if there wasn&#8217;t a viable eco- &#8212; vaccination strategy. We&#8217;re seeing the progress in the vaccination strategy help to &#8212; help to drive economic gains, help to make it possible for more people to feel comfortable and capable to go back to work.</p>



<p>And we anticipate that as we continue to succeed on that front, we continue to make investments in things like school opening and childcare and otherwise, we&#8217;re going to be able to sustain this progress going forward.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Thank you, Brian, very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Do you have a status report on infrastructure? The infrastructure talks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: We’ll have more this afternoon.</p>



<p>MR. DEESE: We will have a status report on that later this afternoon &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yes.</p>



<p>MR. DEESE: &#8212; so, stay tuned.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: More to come.</p>



<p>MR. DEESE: Thanks, guys.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Okay, thank you so much, Brian. Let’s do this again next month. Okay, a couple of items for all of you: Starting this weekend, as we noted the other day, we will &#8212; and with collaboration and support &#8212; we will be launching our National Month of Action, so that is exciting. We&#8217;ve outlined a lot of those specific details, but it&#8217;s starting this weekend, so wanted to note that.</p>



<p>I also wanted to give you all an update that, today, the U.S. government delivered 1 million doses of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine to the Republic of Korea. The friendship and alliance between our two countries run deep, especially in times of great need and hardship.</p>



<p>As was noted when the President hosted &#8212; hosted the South Koreans here just a few weeks ago, this was done in order to ensure the safety and readiness of U.S. and ROK military forces. And today, thanks to a whole-of-government effort, we are delivering on that promise.</p>



<p>And I would just note, again, that our plan &#8212; our commitment to deliver 80 million doses is five times more than any other country and 13 percent of the U.S. supply. And we&#8217;re committed to doing that by the end of June.</p>



<p>Also would note the Vice President is traveling to Mexico and Guatemala next week in her role overseeing diplomacy toward the Northern Triangle and Mexico.</p>



<p>She lands in Guatemala on the evening of June 6th. She&#8217;ll be on the ground there until the evening of June 7th before flying to Mexico. Then she&#8217;ll be in Mexico until the evening of June 8th. She&#8217;ll meet with the President of Guatemala, the President of Mexico, and &#8212; as well as community leaders, innovators, entrepreneurs, and U.S. embassy personnel. And I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;ll do many readouts from there.</p>



<p>The week ahead: On Monday, the President will meet with NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg at the White House. The President and Secretary General will discuss the June 14th NATO Summit in Brussels and many issues on the NATO agenda, including reinforcing transatlantic security in the face of challenges from Russia and China.</p>



<p>They will also discuss adapting NATO to address threats like cyberattacks and climate change, while continuing to ensure a more equitable sharing of responsibility among Allies.</p>



<p>As we&#8217;ve said, revitalizing our alliances is a priority for this administration, and our Alliance with NATO is a big part of that.</p>



<p>As you all know, on Wednesday, the President and First Lady will also be traveling to the United Kingdom for their first stop for their first overseas trip. And we&#8217;ll have one of the members of the national security team, hopefully at the highest level &#8212; we’re working on schedules &#8212; on Monday to do a full preview of the trip for all of you.</p>



<p>Last thing I would note &#8212; I think that was it, actually.</p>



<p>Zeke, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. Looking ahead to that trip, the backend &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; &#8212; the meeting with Russian President Vladimir Putin: He had some comments today where he was suggesting that he was not expecting any concrete breakthroughs. I was hoping you could describe what the President hopes to get out of that meeting. And is the President going to commit to raising issues, like the imprisonment of Navalny, the imprisonment of American citizens in Russia, directly with President Putin, face to face?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, first, I would say that the President never holds back in raising human rights issues, the detainment of activists, with the Russian President. And, certainly, as our &#8212; as our readout made clear when he spoke with him directly, he didn&#8217;t hold back in that conversation. I don&#8217;t expect he will when they meet in two weeks at the summit.</p>



<p>In terms of the focus of the summit: You know, I think the &#8212; we’ll have more to preview on Monday. But as I&#8217;ve noted in here previously, I think the President expects to raise a number of issues, including Ukraine and what we&#8217;ve seen as aggressive behavior at the border by the Russians.</p>



<p>He also will raise cyber activity, malign activity, problematic activity, harmful activity we&#8217;ve seen take place. Of course, there is the SolarWinds hack, but also the ransomware hacks. As we&#8217;ve talked about, the actions of criminal groups within a country &#8212; there&#8217;s a responsibility of the leaders of that country to take action. And there&#8217;s no doubt President Biden will be raising that directly in that conversation.</p>



<p>I don’t think we’re setting this up to be a meeting where there is going to be, you know, an outcome that resolves every issue or every challenge in our relationship. We expect there still to be challenging conversations moving forward. But it&#8217;s an opportunity to discuss areas where we &#8212; where we have mutual interest, like nuclear &#8212; nuclear security and stability, and also to raise issues where we have concern. And we expect that &#8212; this to be a forum for that, face to face.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Separately, the President just got back from a couple days at the beach. Heading into the summer travel season, should we expect to hear from the President &#8212; you know, encouraging Americans to travel, particularly domestically, as a way to stimulate the economy, to spend their money here at home? As sort of &#8212; as the pandemic seems to be waning and travel does seem to be picking up, is that &#8212; is there going to be a pivot from &#8212; on the part of the President, going forward, to encourage Americans to, sort of, get out there and spend the money?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I think the President will continue to encourage Americans to safely get out there into their communities, especially vaccinated Americans, who are safer to travel, to go to restaurants, to not wear masks. And certainly, we abide by CDC guidelines, as you know. But the President went to a restaurant just last weekend with the Vice President &#8212; last weekend? &#8212; on Monday with the Vice President. They had a meal &#8212; something he hasn&#8217;t done a lot of; most Americans haven&#8217;t done a lot of over the last year and a half.</p>



<p>So certainly, he will &#8212; he will lead by action and continue to encourage Americans to take advantage of the benefits of being vaccinated; and for those who are not vaccinated, to get a shot so they can take advantage of those benefits themselves.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And just one last one for me, since it&#8217;s Friday: Has the President been briefed on the unidentified aerial phenomena report? And is he satisfied with the conclusions? Does he want additional work in that space?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Because it&#8217;s Friday &#8212; it&#8217;s always a little wacky on Friday. So, let me first say that we know there have been press reports about the status of this report. This is a DOD report, and so I would certainly refer to them on the status of the report. Their work with ODNI is ongoing.</p>



<p>We &#8212; the team is actively working on it, but it&#8217;s not at a conclusion phase, as I understand, and as I think they&#8217;ve commented from their building.</p>



<p>I will say that we take reports of incurgion [sic] &#8212; incursions into our airspace by any aircraft, identified or unidentified, very seriously and investigate each one. Safety and security of our personnel, of our operations are of paramount concern. There&#8217;s a requirement to put out this report, and certainly our appropriate teams are working on finalizing it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; But was the President briefed on it? Or has he been briefed on it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t have any update on internal briefings, no.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. There seems to be a bit of a shift in tone here because, last month, the President was pretty adamant that he did not believe that these enhanced unemployment benefits were playing a role or factoring into people&#8217;s decisions not to get back into the jobs market. Today, though, he’s underscoring that these benefits are simply temporary, set to expire in 90 days. So, which is it? Yes or no: Does the President believe that these unemployment benefits are playing a role here?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I think we shouldn&#8217;t lose sight of some basic facts here, which is that those governors who have made the decision, as they have every right to do, to pull back on unemployment benefits &#8212; or not accept them, I should say, accurately &#8212; that hasn&#8217;t even taken effect in any state across the country. So in terms of how we&#8217;re evaluating the impact, we haven&#8217;t even seen the impact yet; that takes effect in June.</p>



<p>It is important for people to understand, factually, that the President, no one from the administration has ever proposed making these permanent or doing it over the long term. And sometimes I think that was just an effort to make that clear in the public.</p>



<p>So we understand there&#8217;s politics at play here. That&#8217;s okay. Every governor is going to make their own decision.</p>



<p>At the end of the day, what we see as the biggest driving factor is vaccines and individuals being vaccinated feeling safe to go back to workplaces. The fact that childcare centers have rehired, that teachers have gone back to work &#8212; those are all positive signs. And at the end of the day, we&#8217;ve created &#8212; the President and this administration has created more jobs than any President and any administration in modern American history.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s, kind of, how we see the jobs data.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; But based on the data, do you believe that these benefits are having any kind of impact in people deciding not to maybe reenter the job force right now?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, again, I think that&#8217;s a really difficult thing to analyze, given we have created a historic number of jobs in the last four months &#8212; more than any President in modern American history. So &#8212; and the jobs &#8212; the UI benefits haven&#8217;t even been pulled back in any state.</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s a question I&#8217;m sure we can have a discussion about in the next couple of months as we see what the impact is on different states, or if that&#8217;s a factor. But we think the biggest factors overall are more people getting vaccinated, more people being comfortable and feeling safe going out into the workforce, and that&#8217;s where we feel there&#8217;s going to be an encouraging upward trend.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; I guess I’m trying to understand what happened in the last month though. Because last month, you said you didn&#8217;t see any indication of that, when looking through the data.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t think we can evaluate the data that hasn&#8217;t been applied in states across the country yet. And what we&#8217;re really talking about from state to state is governors making a decision to pull back on accepting unemployment benefits for six weeks or eight weeks. That&#8217;s it. It hasn&#8217;t even started yet.</p>



<p>So I would leave it to all of you and your outside analysts to decide whether that is a big factor in terms of economy and data, or whether that is a political discussion we&#8217;re having.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. Does the White House have any reaction to Facebook&#8217;s decision to suspend President Trump for two years? Was this a reasonable consequence for what he said?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, as always, it&#8217;s a decision for the company to make and any platform to make. And clearly, they&#8217;ve come out and made their decision.</p>



<p>Our view continues to be, though, that every platform &#8212; whether it&#8217;s Facebook, Twitter, any other platform that is disseminating information to millions of Americans &#8212; has a responsibility to crack down on disinformation; to crack down on false information, whether it&#8217;s about the election or even about the vaccine, as we&#8217;re trying to keep the American public safe and get more people &#8212; or return to normal out in society.</p>



<p>And I think, as we look at it, we learned a lot from President Trump &#8212; the former president &#8212; over the last couple of years about his behavior and how he uses these platforms. It feels pretty unlikely that the zebra is going to change his stripes over the next two years. We&#8217;ll see.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; So does this decision validate what President Biden has repeatedly said about Mr. Trump, which is that words matter?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I don&#8217;t know that it&#8217;s a validation. I think the President isn&#8217;t the only one who thinks that. Words do matter. Words do have an impact. We saw the impact, on January 6th, of words on social media platforms, and we&#8217;ve seen the impact of words as it relates to disinformation, traveling, around the vaccine, around election integrity.</p>



<p>So, of course, we think words matter. This is a decision by a private-sector company. We&#8217;ll see what their evaluation is a couple of years from now and what other steps they can take, most importantly.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Jen, our reporting indicates that the Biden administration is considering counter cyberattacks to stop the ransomware criminals in Russia. How big a factor is the upcoming summit in that decision making? Is there a concern that if you did that before the meeting in Geneva, it could derail the talks? And if it doesn&#8217;t happen before then, what message does it send to Russia after these multiple cyber intrusions?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, let me first say that we always reserve the option of responding to behavior or actions that are unacceptable and are harmful. And some of those responses are seen and some of them are unseen, and we typically don&#8217;t give a timeline on that in a public capacity.</p>



<p>But I will also note to you that when the President &#8212; when we announced the invitation to have this discussion, it was also in the same time period where we announced the sanctions that we were putting in place in response to harmful actions by the Russian government &#8212; right? &#8212; in response to SolarWinds, in response to their engagement in our own election.</p>



<p>So we expect &#8212; this is &#8212; this is diplomacy in action here, right? We will take action when warranted &#8212; sometimes seen, sometimes unseen. We typically don&#8217;t predict that ahead of time. And we also will look for areas of opportunity to have a discussion.</p>



<p>But we are not having this summit as a reward. We&#8217;re not having the summit because we expect to only talk about areas where we agree or disagree.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And in the President’s budget blueprint, there&#8217;s only about $1.3 billion dedicated to bolstering cybersecurity. Given what we&#8217;ve seen over the last few weeks, is that enough? Are there talks that more resources need to be dedicated to this? Or are you thinking more to leave this to the private sector for those companies that we&#8217;ve seen that have been impacted?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah, it&#8217;s a really good question. I mean, I will say that we know that the ransomware threat is urgent, it&#8217;s complex, and it&#8217;s been increasing over the last several years. And, you know, it feels new to us over the last couple of weeks, but it has been increasing rapidly around the world over the last several years.</p>



<p>One of the reasons that we have initiated a rapid review internally is because we recognize that threat. And we will assess, based on that review, what additional needs there are, both from the federal government &#8212; in coordination with Congress &#8212; or from the private sector. And that review is focused on the disruption of ransomware infrastructure and actors working closely with the private sector; building an international coalition, of course &#8212; which will be a focus of the President &#8212; will be a topic of discussion, I should say, of the President&#8217;s foreign trip; expanding cryptocurrency analysis, which we know is a factor, given so many of these ransomware attacks are &#8212; you know, if ransom is paid, which, of course, we don&#8217;t recommend and don&#8217;t advise from the FBI, but it&#8217;s often done through cryptocurrency channels; and reviewing our own policy.</p>



<p>So that review is ongoing internally with our national security team, and we&#8217;ll assess what additional needs might be needed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And one last bit of housekeeping. Last month, you said you didn&#8217;t have an update but that you maybe expected the President to get his first physical soon. Do you have anything &#8212; any update to provide on that? Should we expect that to happen this summer, or is there anything else you can give us (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: It will definitely happen this year. And when he has his next physical, we will provide that information transparently to all of you, but I don&#8217;t have a date for you.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thank you, Jen. Would the President support a commission to investigate the initial U.S. response to COVID-19?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: A commission in Congress?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Or a presidential commission.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I would say, if members of Congress have a discussion and want to have a discussion about that, we&#8217;re happy to hear from them. But our focus right now, as you know, Peter, is on our own internal investigation &#8212; our own internal process, I should say &#8212; using all of the resources of government, tapping into our data and science experts to see what more we can determine over the next 90 days, or less than 90 days, about the origins of the pandemic.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Mike Pompeo is now saying that when he was the Secretary of State and he was trying to investigate the origins of COVID-19 there, the NIH folks were trying to suppress what he was doing. So is there any concern from the White House that there may have been people at the NIH who were making policy decisions based not in science, but based on their personal political beliefs or preferences?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I really don&#8217;t have any analysis of the last administration&#8217;s inter-working.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Well, a lot of these people are still over there, and you see how they operate.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Here’s what we know, Peter: We know that Dr. Fauci and many members of the NIH team &#8212; medical and science experts &#8212; because of their work over the last 10 years, we have developed a focus, an effort, an apparatus to fight this pandemic, and we are grateful to them for their work. Everybody wants to get to the bottom of the origin: former Secretary Pompeo, President Biden, Democrats and Republicans across the board.</p>



<p>We all share a concern about the challenge &#8212; and that is the intransigence, at times, by the Chinese in providing data and providing information. We share agreement on that. We all want to get to the bottom of what happened here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And you mentioned Dr. Fauci. There have been these emails that have come out through a FOIA request that make it seem like &#8212; we knew that he had his hands full at the time, trying to figure out what to do, but it seems like there were times that he was saying one thing in email and then coming to this microphone and saying something else. If that is the case and if that affected the U.S. policy posture at the time, should he be held accountable?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I&#8217;ve talked a little bit about Dr. Fauci, and Dr. Fauci has been out doing several interviews himself and answering questions on these emails and questions that you all may have.</p>



<p>Dr. Fauci is a renowned public servant &#8212; civil servant, I should say &#8212; career civil servant. He&#8217;s overseen management of multiple global health crises. And attacks &#8212; and attacks launched on him are certainly something we wouldn&#8217;t stand by.</p>



<p>I understand there&#8217;s interest in the emails. He&#8217;s answered a lot of questions on the emails. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m going to have much more to add on them from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Do you think the attacks are political against Dr. Fauci?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I&#8217;m going to let Dr. Fauci speak to his own defense of his emails from 17 months ago, before this President even took office.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Okay. And then, finally, does President Biden have a position on gain-of-function research?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, we have not &#8212; as Dr. Fauci has actually said repeatedly, we&#8217;ve never approved any funding for gain-of-function research in Wuhan. I know that&#8217;s, I think, why you&#8217;re asking the question. I believe some may have been approved, or there was funding approved during the prior administration. There&#8217;s a framework, I should say. This is not meant to be a criticism of funding and how it&#8217;s approved through different NIH programs, but I would send you to them to give more of an explanation of the funding mechanisms.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And just &#8212; since you mentioned Dr. Fauci again, can you imagine any circumstance where President Biden would ever fire him?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: No.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Just to follow up a little bit on Russia: I know you&#8217;ve said repeatedly that this is not a reward to Vladimir Putin, but what can you do in terms of stage management to make sure that it doesn&#8217;t become that. I mean, become a platform for him to offer alternate facts, alternate analysis of history, of what&#8217;s going on, and also provide, you know, a way for him to damage the opposition within his own country. Are you thinking through that issue? Are you &#8212; how will you address that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, one thing is we&#8217;re going to bring all of you with us to report on what he says and doesn&#8217;t say, and factcheck what he says or doesn&#8217;t say.</p>



<p>The other piece is: President Biden, as you&#8217;ve heard him talk about, has known, has engaged with President Putin in the past throughout his career, and he is never one to hold back on areas where he has concern, areas where he feels the actions of the Russian government or Russian leadership are hurting the United States. And he certainly has no intention of holding back during this meeting, publicly or privately.</p>



<p>But at the end of the day, our job, or our focus, is on moving toward a more stable and predictable relationship with Russia. There are areas where we can work together. We&#8217;ve talked a little bit about &#8212; you know, we renewed START &#8212; New START, early on in the administration, for five years. That&#8217;s an area we can work together.</p>



<p>There are ongoing negotiations for the Iran nuclear deal. They just finished their fifth round of discussions. Russia is a member of the P5+1. We can have a discussion there.</p>



<p>At the same time, we also feel that no country should be, you know, harboring &#8212; has responsibility not to harbor criminal individuals who are launching ransomware attacks, and that will certainly be a part of the discussion as well.</p>



<p>So, you&#8217;re right: When we have conversations with leaders we disagree with, where we have some adversarial components of our relationship, it is important to send the message that we&#8217;re not validating their actions. In fact, we&#8217;re calling them out on it. But it is also an opportunity, face to face, to raise those issues and also to hopefully move toward a more stable and predictable relationship moving forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And on infrastructure &#8212; you know, is the corporate tax hike that was originally proposed, is that pretty much dead now? Can we expect to see it in reconciliation? And is there anything else that President Biden plans to offer when he speaks with the senator today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, since you gave the opportunity, Trevor, I think there&#8217;s an important note here. One is that we didn&#8217;t talk a lot about the book line taxes that the President talked about yesterday &#8212; that we&#8217;ve talked about a little bit yesterday &#8212; the 15 percent tax that these companies &#8212; we’re asking these companies &#8212; or we think these companies should pay &#8212; that pay no tax &#8212; no tax.</p>



<p>That was in his original American Jobs Plan proposal. It was in the lengthy factsheet. I&#8217;m sure Reuters wrote many stories about.</p>



<p>So, that was a component that we didn&#8217;t get &#8212; we didn&#8217;t have a lot of a public debate about, but it has been something he talked about on the campaign. It&#8217;s in our budget. It was in his American Jobs Plan proposal.</p>



<p>In terms of the corporate tax increases that was also proposed and certainly has been more of a public component of our discussion, you know, that&#8217;s something he continues to believe corporations can pay more money; that that&#8217;s a way to fund his bold ideas.</p>



<p>There are a lot of ideas that he wants to move forward on, whether it&#8217;s extending the Child Tax Credit, universal pre-K &#8212; proposals that he has put forward in the American Families Plan, which we are looking forward to having a continued discussion about. And there are also a range of payfors he has proposed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And that 15 percent minimum that you just</p>



<p>brought up, is that &#8212; did you bring that up because that&#8217;s something that Yellen is pursuing on the international stage as well?</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;MS. PSAKI: No. Separate. I&#8217;m glad you asked that question. Separate issue. I know it&#8217;s confusing because the 15/15. Separate issue. There is a discussion, as you noted, on the global stage about a global minimum tax.</p>



<p>But this is a &#8212; this is a proposal the President talked about on the campaign trail, he proposed in his American Jobs Plan, and also in our budget that would eve- &#8212; would require &#8212; you know, would have companies that didn&#8217;t pay any tax, wouldn&#8217;t allow them to pay zero tax.</p>



<p>And so we see it as a separate entity. We still believe the tax rate should be higher than that, as the President has proposed, on a corp- &#8212; for a corporate rate.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Josh.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of what your expectations are for their discussion? Like, is it by phone, for instance, with Senator Capito (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Oh, sure, sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Is this &#8212; are we any near a decisional process or a point for the President?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Sure. So they will be talking by phone &#8212; President and Senator Capito &#8212; this afternoon. He&#8217;ll also be talking with Congressman DeFazio. And we will be doing readouts of those conversations that are happening this afternoon &#8212; as we speak, perhaps. But we will provide readouts.</p>



<p>You know, I&#8217;m not going to obviously prejudge conversations, but I would say, for the conversation with Senator Capito, they&#8217;ve had good-faith discussions. There are areas where, of course, you know, the President has priorities, where he&#8217;d like to see more, including more investments, but also areas including electric vehicle investments, rebuilding veterans hospitals. And that&#8217;s part of the discussion &#8212; as well as payfors.</p>



<p>And as Trevor just asked about, but as we talked about a bit yesterday, what the President put forward &#8212; he looked at all of his tax proposals, and what he put forward are ways to pay for an infrastructure proposal that he &#8212; that shouldn&#8217;t cross any bar or line for Republicans in the Senate who say they won&#8217;t touch the 2017 tax plan.</p>



<p>So, I think the question, really, on that front is: Do you think these companies should pay no tax at all or 15 percent, which is very viable, supported by 85 per- &#8212; 84 percent of Republicans in the country?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Does the President believe he&#8217;s running out of time to try to reach a deal, or is there runway left?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: There&#8217;s runway left. He&#8217;s going to have these discussions. There are Democrats and Republicans who are talking with each other. We&#8217;re going to engage with them as well and continue to have a discussion with a range of interested leaders in Congress about how we can come together to make a historic investment in infrastructure. There are some realities of timelines, including the fact that Congressman DeFazio is leading the markup of key components of the American Jobs Plan next week &#8212; key infrastructure components &#8212; where there is a big overlap. There is a lot of interest and excitement by many Democrats in Congress about that.</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s not unlimited, but we have an opportunity. He&#8217;s going to talk to Senator Capito this afternoon. We&#8217;re going to see how those conversations go. We&#8217;re going to keep a range of pathways open to move these bold ideas forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And just briefly, Brian Deese talked about the supply shortage issue. Can you talk about any particular types of supplies that we&#8217;re talking about, the &#8212; you know, with regards, for instance, to the construction job gains that were pretty sluggish? What are we talking about here? Lumber? Like, what are the powers the government has to try to address those?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, you &#8212; I know you&#8217;ve covered this closely, as have others. Lumber is certainly one of the areas, and we&#8217;ve seen an impact on the housing market in part because of a shortage of some of these supplies that&#8217;s having an impact on new builds, that’s then having an impact on the pricing for homes that have been around a longer period of time. I know you know this, but just to catch everybody else up. So &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; (Inaudible.) (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Okay. So &#8212; so we&#8217;ve seen that impact, and we have been doing this 100-day review. Certainly, looking at how we can address those challenges and issues through the role of the federal government is what we&#8217;ll talk about when we have more details to share, and hopefully that will be next week.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Are tariffs a way that you can address the supply shortages?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I&#8217;m just not going to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Or changing tariffs?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I&#8217;m not going to get too ahead or ahead at all of where we will come down in our final rollouts of our supply chain review process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead, Kaitlan.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Is the President expecting a counteroffer during this conversation with Senator Capito today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I think the President is expecting they&#8217;re going to have a discussion. Part of negotiation is seeing how you can come closer to each other. He&#8217;s obviously come down quite a bit in what he originally proposed, and hopefully they&#8217;ll have more they can add to their proposal, but we’ll see. But it&#8217;s a discussion, not an exchange of paper.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Well, you described Wednesday as a discussion too, but President Biden made a counteroffer, kind of, to them on Wednesday.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I think that might be over-formalizing the discussion. There&#8217;s a discussion about where there might be areas of agreement, then, obviously, she’ll &#8212; she may have to take things back; he may have to discuss on our end with Democratic leadership.</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s more of a discussion and where we can find common ground, hear each other out. And we’ll see, you know, if this continues to be a viable path forward, and we&#8217;ll continue to pursue a range of paths.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thank you. And on these ransomware attacks, does the President view those as a national security threat?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I certainly think the President views those as a rising national concern &#8212; security concern and an area where we need to continue to keep our focus, keep our assets, focus on energy and brainpower on what we can do to address it.</p>



<p>That’s why we launched this rapid review to take a look at these four areas of focus, including our approach through the U.S. government, including how we work with the private sector, including cryptocurrency, and also including what role we can have on the global stage.</p>



<p>So, certainly this is a priority to him and an area where we will be spending a significant amount of time in the coming months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Okay. And my last question, just on the &#8212; on the enhanced unemployment benefits, you said that you can&#8217;t really make a determination because no states have actually cut them off yet &#8212; the states that are pulling out of the program early. But if nothing has changed, shouldn&#8217;t you be able to maintain the President’s pretty unequivocal position, last month, that they are not encouraging people to stay home?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, if we had that concern, we would be ending them. We&#8217;re not. I mean, we &#8212; there&#8217;s still 7 million people out of work &#8212; right? &#8212; and we&#8217;re talking about $300 benefits for three more months.</p>



<p>I think the point I was trying to make, and I think Brian was trying to make, is that the governors who have made the decision &#8212; which they have every right to do &#8212; to pull back on these benefits are really talking about having them for six weeks or eight weeks less than we would already intend to have them.</p>



<p>So I think the question is: Do you think Americans &#8212; given 7 million are still out of work, or more than that &#8212; could benefit from eight more weeks or 10 more weeks of these $300 unemployment benefits? Our view is they can, and they should. And that&#8217;s an extra helping hand we can give to millions of people across this country. Some governors disagree. That&#8217;s okay. At the end of the day, in early September, these &#8212; these benefits will no longer be a part of the plan.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; One quick thing &#8212; housekeeping on Russia, and then I have something on Israel.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; You mentioned a few moments ago that the press will be with the President when he attends the summit in Geneva. Can you commit that he will have a press conference, a side-by-side with President Putin, as previous U.S. presidents have done?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I don&#8217;t know what the format will look like at this point in time. I can certainly commit that he will communicate and speak to all of you, but I don&#8217;t know what the format looks like yet.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; I mean, obviously, a press conference would be preferable, but I think &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: He will answer questions. I don’t know what the format will look like at this point.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Yeah. But, I mean, the &#8212; given the history of the &#8212; fairly recent history of side-by-side press conferences between the U.S. president and the Russian president, it would make certainly a &#8212; it would be an opportunity for us to ask the kind of questions of both presidents that I think our President might want to answer.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I know that we will make President Biden available to all of you, and I certainly hope my Russian counterpart makes President Putin available to all of you as well. I don&#8217;t know what the format will look like at this point.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; On Israel: We’re a couple of clicks closer to the formation of the new government. Have there been any developments here in President Biden&#8217;s interaction with either the existing government or the new government in formation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: No, not at this point. I think we&#8217;re going to allow for that process to move forward. And as you know, it may be a little bit more time before the final formation is completed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; What is the plan for his interaction with the new government, should it be formed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, we have a long and abiding relationship, strategic relationship with Israel, and that will continue to be the case no matter who is leading the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; But would he call Prime Minister Bennett upon the formation of that government?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I don’t have any calls to predict for you, but certainly he will continue to engage with his counterparts in Israel and many countries around the world.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And then, lastly, were you able to nail down whether or not he had actually ever met Naftali Bennett before?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: You did ask that question. I’m sorry, I did not ask him. I will follow up and see if I can find that out.</p>



<p>He, I know &#8212; well, Naftali Bennett &#8212; you would remember the years he was the chief of staff to Prime Minister Netanyahu. We’ll have to do a little data tracing here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Yeah, (inaudible) jobs. But &#8212; (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah. Yeah.</p>



<p>Okay. Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. On the vaccine announcement from yesterday &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yep.</p>



<p>Q &nbsp;&#8212; can you give an idea at all of how many doses we can expect? Are there going to be monthly surplus shipments going out to other countries? And will they follow the same 25 percent, 75 percent, sort of, breakdown? Are there any discussions about that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Eighty million doses by the end of June.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; But in future months. I mean, it was said yesterday there &#8212; we can expect more this summer. So (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: That’s right. And we’re going to continue to provide part of our supply to the global community. But I don’t have anything to predict for you beyond that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And, on infrastructure, can we expect the President to meet with Senators Romney and Manchin at all as one of the pathways that the White House is exploring?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Look, I think, as I &#8212; as I alluded to a little bit earlier, the President is certainly open to and interested in continuing to engage with a range of members who have an interest in making a historic investment in our nation&#8217;s infrastructure; modernizing our roads, rails, and bridges; and preparing us to compete over the long term.</p>



<p>I know those are two of the members who have expressed that publicly, so we will see what the future days hold.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And just on the President&#8217;s trip: Can we expect him to meet with the Pope at all? There&#8217;s been some reporting out there that he might be meeting with the Pope.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: That&#8217;s surprising. I don&#8217;t think you can expect that on this trip.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Thanks, Jen. Again, on the issue of the COVID vaccines: Can you talk a little bit about the timing? I know you said by the end of June, I think.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; But how soon can the other countries start expecting to receive these vaccines? And also, how are you prioritizing which countries will get them first?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Sure. Well, first, let me say &#8212; I mentioned, a little bit earlier, 80 million by the end of June. Obviously, 25 percent of those are coming &#8212; are going bilaterally to countries. We&#8217;re going to get those doses out &#8212; those 25 million as quickly as we can, and we&#8217;ll provide you updates as those doses go out.</p>



<p>So I had an update this morning about the dose &#8212; or this afternoon about the doses that went out to the ROK, and we’ll continue to have more updates on that, on those doses.</p>



<p>The additional doses &#8212; the 75 percent, which are going through COVAX &#8212; we&#8217;ve put out, kind of, our prioritization of the regions that those will be going to. And part of our focus right now is on the herculean logistical challenge of getting these vaccines out to the right places. This is one of the reasons that we&#8217;re doing a large percentage of them through COVAX: because of their capability to do exactly that.</p>



<p>But just to step back, and as a reminder: This is not just, kind of, shipping these doses overseas. This is also ensuring that we can get them to the right places, that they have the ability to put them in arms, that they are at the right temperature. And so, these are all factors we&#8217;re considering as we&#8217;re determining how to get them out and the pace in the weeks ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; One more. The U.S. and the EU have begun discussions on lifting tariffs on steel and aluminum imports. I’m just wondering if you have an update on what kind of progress, if any, has been made in those talks and if you expect this issue to come up during the G7.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, we certainly expect that our G7 partners will range &#8212; will raise a range of issues of concern to them and a focus. And, certainly, I&#8217;d let them to speak to what those are, but the tariffs could be one of them. I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you or preview for you.</p>



<p>I have to wrap this up in a minute, but, Jerry, I&#8217;m just going to go to you because I &#8212; you haven&#8217;t been here since I&#8217;ve been here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; I have not.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Okay. Good to see you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Good to see you. Kind of a parochial Buffalo question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; The Canadian border has been closed for a very long time.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of concern about that in all the northern tier states right now. And Prime Minister Trudeau has said that he has to get 75 percent of the people in his country vaccinated before the border reopens.</p>



<p>That being the case, would the United States consider opening the American side of the border first, before Prime Minister Trudeau would do that? Or does there have to be a binational agreement?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, I&#8217;ll first say that, as it relates to borders &#8212; Canada or Mexico &#8212; we really rely on the guidance of the CDC and our health and medical experts. So, in terms of how they look at the data and information, I would point you to them and whether they would do that in a preliminary fashion or not.</p>



<p>Certainly, any discussion about reopening a border would be done through &#8212; in part through diplomatic channels. But we really are relying and waiting on the guidance of the CDC before we make any next decision there on the border.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; And how much concern is there in the White House about the fact that here we are &#8212; it’s summer travel season, there&#8217;s a lot of concern in those northern border states about the economic impact, as well as the personal impact on people who&#8217;ve may &#8212; you know, couples that may be separated by the border?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Yeah, we&#8217;re very sensitive to that, Jerry. And we certainly know that many people want to not just get back to normal, but be able to travel; be able to see loved ones, some living on different sides of the border; be able to go to restaurants and shop and even do things along those lines. And we&#8217;re eager to get back to normal, whatever that means, including reopening the border. But we have a responsibility during a global pandemic, which we&#8217;re still fighting every day, to rely on the advice and guidance of our medical experts.</p>



<p>Okay, I think we have one more question here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Jen, does the administration remain committed to waiving vaccine patents at the WTO? Today, the EU submitted a counterproposal, saying that they don&#8217;t want to do that. And will the President be pushing for this issue at the G7?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Our position hasn&#8217;t changed on that.</p>



<p>I think we have one question. Okay. Hello to our virtual Melissa. Hi, Melissa. Thanks for joining us.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp; Hi, thank you. Right now, approximately 16 million public school students in the U.S. live at home that lack Internet &#8212; high-speed Internet. The President released a plan to ensure that people in rural areas will have Internet access, but reports show that 13.6 million urban households also do not have Internet; many can’t afford it. What does the administration plan to do to increase home Internet service for families in low-income urban neighborhoods?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, it&#8217;s a great question. And, Melissa, thanks for joining us, and hopefully you weren&#8217;t waiting too long.</p>



<p>I will say that in the pa- &#8212; in the President’s American Jobs Plan he’s proposed, we&#8217;re proposing to expand universal broadband access across the country to urban and rural areas to level exactly that playing field: to ensure that kids in cities, as well as in more rural communities where there isn&#8217;t as expansive broadband access, have &#8212; have access. And we&#8217;ve seen over the last year and a half, during the pandemic, what a disparity it creates, both economically, but for kids who are just trying to get an education.</p>



<p>The Vice President, as the President announced in his joint session address, is leading this effort. It’s an important part of the negotiation, and fortunately one where Democrats and Republicans have a lot of agreement about the need to move forward on expanding access to broadband.</p>



<p>Thank you so much. I apologize for this being short today. I have to go do some regional TV. And anyone who has follow-up questions, come up or email me and we&#8217;ll talk more. Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>2:34 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, June 3, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/03/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-june-3-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 23:17:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=19669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:56 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; All right.&#160; I have a couple of items for all of you at the top, and some charts.&#160; We love charts in here.&#160;&#160;In today&#8217;s encouraging report, initial claims for unemployment insurance fell to their lowest level and below 400,000 for the first time since the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:56 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; I have a couple of items for all of you at the top, and some charts.&nbsp; We love charts in here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In today&#8217;s encouraging report, initial claims for unemployment insurance fell to their lowest level and below 400,000 for the first time since the pandemic hit.&nbsp; This is just the latest evidence that President Biden&#8217;s economic strategy and vaccination plans are working.&nbsp; While weekly data can be volatile, since taking office, average claims have fallen by about 50 percent, which you can see in this chart, over the course of time, and by more than 100,000 in last &#8212; in the last month alone.<br>&nbsp;<br>And earlier this week, the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development &#8212; the OECD, as it&#8217;s commonly known &#8212; one of the leading bodies in analyzing economic growth around the world, increased their projection for U.S. economic growth this year to 6.9 percent due to the strength of the American Rescue Plan and our pandemic response to get Americans vaccinated and lift our economy out of the crises that we inherited.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, the United States is the only major industrialized nation to have its growth projection through 2025 revised upward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also learned earlier this week that manufacturing activity in May was near its highest level in more than 15 years.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; I also wanted to note, which many of you saw this morning, that our Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber, Anne Neuberger, who&#8217;s been here a couple of times, released an open memo to corporate executives and business leaders urging them to take immediate steps to address the threat of ransomware.&nbsp; Obviously, this is in light of the attack this week &#8212; the ransomware attack this week, and the one from just a few weeks ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The federal government, under the leadership of President Biden, has been stepping up to strengthen the nation&#8217;s defenses against cyberattacks, but we can&#8217;t do it alone.&nbsp; Business leaders have a responsibility to strengthen their cyber defenses to protect the American public and our economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The most important takeaway from the recent spate of ransomware attacks on the United States, Ireland, and Germany, and organizations &#8212; other organizations around the world, is that companies that view ransomware as a threat to their core business operations, rather than a simple risk of data theft, will react and recover more effectively.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our Deputy National Security Advisor laid out a small number of highly impactful steps that private-sector companies can take to harden their cybersecurity.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve outlined them here.&nbsp; And again, it was in the memo that she put out just this morning, and that&#8217;s something we will encourage &#8212; continue to encourage companies to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally &#8212; lots of news out there this morning &#8212; as you all know &#8212; and many of you were probably on this call &#8212; Jeff Zients and Jake Sullivan announced the President&#8217;s strategy for global vaccine sharing and their allocation plan for the first 25 million doses to be shared globally.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, just a couple of highlights from that:<br>&nbsp;<br>First, having successfully secured enough vaccine supply for Americans, we’re donating excess &#8212; donating surplus U.S. vaccine supply and encouraging other countries with surplus supplies to do the same.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He’s announced &#8212; the President has announced a U.S. commitment to sharing a total of 80 million doses by the end of June.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s 25 million doses that will go out as soon as possible, very quickly.&nbsp; A number of those are going to even go out as soon as today.&nbsp; And that is five times the number of doses any other country has committed to sharing and 13 percent of the total vaccines produced by the United States by the end of this month.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, we&#8217;re working with vaccine manufacturers to vastly increase vaccine supply for the rest of the world in a way that can also create jobs here at home.&nbsp; So that &#8212; so we have all these manufacturers who have facilities that will enable us to continue to produce additional supply, even beyond, so that we can provide that to the rest of the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>We will also work with our partner nations and pharmaceutical companies and other manufacturers to create the kind of global vaccine production and manufacturing capacity and capabilities that can not only help the world beat this pandemic, but also helps prepare the world to respond to future threats.<br>&nbsp;<br>A couple of additional highlights: One, our approach today was rooted in a couple of considerations.&nbsp; One, ensuring vaccines are delivered in a way that is efficient and equitable and follows the latest science and public health data.&nbsp; Two, providing vaccines for populations across different regions and those most at risk, as well as the nations experiencing surges, high burdens of disease, or low vaccination rates.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, the President &#8212; as the President said, we will not use our vaccine supply and the doses we&#8217;re sharing with the world to secure favors from other countries, and that’s a value from the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, today, we announced that we&#8217;re sharing at least 75 percent of these vaccines, which is approximately 19 million, through COVAX, which will &#8212; of the 25 million, I should say, that are going out &#8212; through COVAX, which will facilitate equitable distribution to reach those most at risk.&nbsp; So, approximately 6 million for Latin America and the Caribbean; 7 million for South and Southeast Asia; 5 million with the African Union and Africa CDC.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re sharing 25 percent of these vaccines with countries with immediate needs and to help surges around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>As final determinations are made about additional supply and where it&#8217;s going, we will provide that to all of you, but wanted to convey how we&#8217;d be approaching this and where the initial set of supply is going.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; I hope everyone had a snack.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Alex, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; With the news that the Trump Justice Department sought the records of more journalists, this time from the New York Times, can you talk a bit about Biden’s pledge that the practice won’t continue under his Justice Department?&nbsp; Can you speak to, in particular, how can the President keep that promise while also making good on his pledge to uphold the independence of the Justice Department?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me &#8212; for those of you who didn&#8217;t follow as closely what Alex referenced, although I bet many of you did, this is the third announcement by the Department of Justice of attaining records of journalists during the last year of the Trump administration &#8212; so, something they&#8217;re projecting publicly that happened during the last year of the Trump administration.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve also indicated that this is the last.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you noted, Alex, the President has made clear that, on his watch, freedom of press will be protected.&nbsp; He laid out core principles several weeks ago, because this is something that he is personally passionate about, and he has a long record with respect to protecting the rights of journalists.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as he&#8217;s always been emphatic about &#8212; he was always alarmed by the way the former administration, the Trump administration, abused their power in some cases.&nbsp; And the career, nonpartisan, civil servants often were doing their work with great professionalism and honor and were put in a difficult position.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I will say that he&#8217;s always felt that it&#8217;s important, as is evident by his words he shared just a few weeks ago, that we should always be refining and improving our approaches to how we approach this issue and any other issue.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of a specific policy moving forward, but it&#8217;s something that he is &#8212; that&#8217;s, kind of, his principles he will approach this from, moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you said the White House had not spoken to the DOJ about this particular issue.&nbsp; Was it just a suggestion to the DOJ?&nbsp; I mean, how is this going to become codified?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, obviously, the President spoke to it himself publicly, and we&#8217;re in touch at the appropriate layers of the White House and the Department of Justice.&nbsp; And &#8212; but certainly this is the position of the President of the United States &#8212; what principles he wants to abide by as President, and he conveyed that publicly, so it wasn&#8217;t exactly in secret.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And then, on infrastructure: President Biden tried to give Republicans an alternative to funding infrastructure.&nbsp; He suggested a 15 percent minimum tax, rather than a hike in the corporate tax rates.&nbsp; So, can you talk a little bit about how this informs his broader vision?&nbsp; Is this a change to his broader vision on infrastructure? &nbsp;And is he basically proposing that no profitable corporations should be able to avoid taxes?&nbsp; Is that the, sort of, founding principle of that proposal?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, on the last one, that&#8217;s absolutely a principle.&nbsp; I will note &#8212; and I know this was a lengthy factsheet at the time &#8212; but the “book minimum tax,” which is the 15 percent minimum tax, was actually in the American Jobs Plan as one of the payfor components.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So what happened over the last couple of days and also in the meeting yesterday is that the President did a thorough review of all of the tax reforms he&#8217;s proposed &#8212; many of them on the campaign.&nbsp; So he talked about this on the campaign.&nbsp; It was in the American Jobs Plan as a payfor and also is reflected in our budget that we just put out last Friday.&nbsp; And he looked to see what could be a path forward with his Republican colleagues on this specific negotiation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, I think it&#8217;s important to step back and remember that what &#8212; the proposals about the American Jobs Plan is a historic investment in infrastructure, modernizing our nation&#8217;s infrastructure, becoming more competitive around the world.&nbsp; He&#8217;s proposed ways to pay for it.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Others have not exactly done the same in many capacities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is a way for him to identify pieces that he&#8217;s long been a proponent of as ways where he feels it would not violate.&nbsp; This would not &#8212; this would &#8212; this should be completely acceptable to a number of Republicans who have said that they &#8212; they want to leave their bottom lines, they want to leave the 2017 tax law untouched.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I wouldn&#8217;t say it&#8217;s a new approach by the President. This is in our budget.&nbsp; It was on the campaign.&nbsp; It was in the American Jobs Plan proposal.&nbsp; He also talked, of course, about the benefit of tax enforcement and how that could be a revenue raiser.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what really should stand out at this point to people is that opposing this proposal would not &#8212; would mean not only opposing raising taxes on the wealthiest Americans who&#8217;ve done extraordinarily well during the pandemic; it would mean opposing the very enforcement of the 2017 tax law.&nbsp; It would mean maybe having the view that nobody should pay &#8212; that these 50 corporations who didn&#8217;t pay taxes shouldn&#8217;t pay any taxes at all.&nbsp; And that certainly is not the view the President has.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more quick one.&nbsp; Can you clarify the President&#8217;s position on the filibuster?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In what way?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Where does he stand?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve said &#8212; I talked about it quite extensively yesterday.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to repeat it &#8212; and often.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the President’s view is that he believes that there should be a path forward for Democrats and Republicans to work together to get the job done on behalf of the American public, whether that is voting rights and ensuring that more people have access to voting rights, or whether that is moving forward on other priority items for him.<br>&nbsp;<br>He has talked, in the past, about a move back to the talking filibuster.&nbsp; It shouldn&#8217;t be so easy to invoke the filibuster; that is his view.&nbsp; But it hasn&#8217;t changed beyond that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, following up on infrastructure, quickly: The President and Senator Capito had said they aim to reconnect tomorrow.&nbsp; Is that going to be another face-to-face meeting here at the White House, or is that going to be happening virtually?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question, Monica.&nbsp; I think it could &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a definite format for you, but it certainly could happen.&nbsp; They&#8217;re just going to reconnect and engage.&nbsp; It certainly could happen on the phone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is the expectation from the White House that tomorrow Republicans will offer yet another counterproposal and that that may be the final step in the set of negotiations?&nbsp; Or do you anticipate this will go through the weekend until Monday, June 7th, as you had noted?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know everybody is excited to work through the weekend.&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to prejudge what Senator Capito will come to the table with tomorrow.&nbsp; I will leave that to her to speak to and other Republicans who have been a part of these good-faith discussions and negotiations.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note that this has been a good discussion and &#8212; good, ongoing discussion where we’ve &#8212; we’re working to find areas of agreement.&nbsp; We also feel there are a number of paths forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Next week, the House is going to be marking up the American Jobs Plan; Congressman DeFazio will be leading that effort.&nbsp; There are a number of Democrats and Republicans who have talked about working together &#8212; many of you have reported on &#8212; to come up with a proposal where they can all mutually agree on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the President is looking forward to engaging with Senator Capito tomorrow; feels they&#8217;ve had good discussions &#8212; good-faith discussions.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also going to keep options open and keep a range of paths open for how we move his ideas forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, on vaccines, how does the two-dose regimen factor into the 25 million doses?&nbsp; How many of them are Johnson &amp; Johnson?&nbsp; Or should this be viewed as something that is potentially more for 10 to 12 million people to get vaccinated given, of course, it requires two shots?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, also, what is the plan for doses that may expire this month or soon?&nbsp; What is the U.S. going to do to ensure that gets there quickly enough to ensure they can actually be viable?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, on the second question, we are going to, of course, look closely to determine that we get doses out as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And, as I noted, 25 million will be going out as quickly as we can logistically get those out the door.&nbsp; And we are going to &#8212; that&#8217;s certainly a factor as we are working to operationalize this, which is kind of a historic herculean effort to get these doses to all of the communities and countries that we have committed them to.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of Johnson &amp; Johnson, you know, of the doses that will be going out, they will be all approved doses by the FDA, of which Johnson &amp; Johnson is one of them.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an exact breakdown between the three, but you&#8217;re absolutely correct that, obviously, if it&#8217;s Johnson &amp; Johnson, it would be one dose; if it&#8217;s the other two approved &#8212; Moderna and Pfizer doses &#8212; it would require two doses.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Steve.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, do you feel like you&#8217;re close to a deal on infrastructure &#8212; that you’ve significantly narrowed the gap?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, over time, we feel that all parties &#8212; of course, we have been and we certainly feel that Senator Capino [sic] &#8212; Capito and the other Republicans who&#8217;ve been a part of that have been operating in good faith.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, and negotiation &#8212; as you know, Steve, from covering a lot of these &#8212; is exactly that.&nbsp; It’s seeing how much each side can come closer to the other.&nbsp; And the President has some priorities, including ensuring that we&#8217;re investing in infrastructure of the future.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are areas that are personally important to him: making sure we&#8217;re rebuilding veterans hospitals; making sure we&#8217;re making electric vehicles a reality; charging stations, buses, et cetera.&nbsp; Some of these proposals have been in our counterproposal, on the original proposal.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, certainly, part of negotiating is coming up in numbers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has he abandoned the plan to raise the corporate tax rate to 28 percent?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that off the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; What the President believes is, one, that corporations can afford to pay a little bit more, and that&#8217;s a way that can &#8212; we can pay for a range of the bold proposals that he has put forward.&nbsp; But he also took a look at these proposals, and the &#8212; all of the tax proposals that he has put forward over time to find a way where there should be payfors that, based on their &#8212; based on their bottom lines, many of the Republican negotiators should be able to agree to.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, Israel seems to be on the cusp of a new prime minister.&nbsp; What&#8217;s at stake for the United States here? Does policy change as a result of this leadership change?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will leave &#8212; which won&#8217;t be a surprise to you, Steve &#8212; the politics and the determination about political formation in Israel up to the parties there.&nbsp; Israel will remain an important strategic partner, one where we have an abiding security relationship.&nbsp; And that will continue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll come back to you guys.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, just to clarify: Is the President&#8217;s position that he would be willing to do away with this increase in the corporate tax rate if Republicans agreed to a minimum 15 percent corporate tax rate?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s take a step back.&nbsp; The minimum &#8212; the book minimum was in the President&#8217;s American Jobs Plan proposal as a proposed payfor.&nbsp; It was also in our budget.&nbsp; So this is not a new idea; this is a component of what he&#8217;s proposed for a payfor that he&#8217;s lifting up as a question as to whether they could agree to that, because it certainly doesn&#8217;t violate anything about the 2017 taxes.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s putting forward as an idea that he&#8217;s asking them where their point of view is.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he’s saying it could be one or the other?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, no.&nbsp; He believes that we should continue to look at raising the corporate rate; that is a way to pay for a range of ideas.&nbsp; He&#8217;s got a lot of ideas out there, a lot of bold proposals, including that aren&#8217;t a part of this infrastructure negotiation.&nbsp; And he continues to believe that corporations can pay more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the bottom line is that these proposals he&#8217;s put forward as payfors in the American Jobs Plan, including IRS enforcement &#8212; which is also in our budget, of course &#8212; and this book minimum tax are ways that, unless you think corporations shouldn&#8217;t pay any tax at all &#8212; and we&#8217;ll leave that to others to speak to &#8212; then there should be a way to find a path to agreement.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how was that proposal received by Senator Capito?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll leave her &#8212; I&#8217;ll leave that to her and others to speak to.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; The President said yesterday that he&#8217;s putting Vice President Harris in charge of the White House&#8217;s efforts to combat voting restrictions around the country.&nbsp; What is this effort going to look like exactly?&nbsp; What is the White House going to do to push back on bills that are making their way through state legislatures?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that the Vice President put out an extensive statement on this just two days ago.&nbsp; And she has this assignment because she asked to lead the effort on voting rights, because it&#8217;s an issue she is personally passionate about, and she wants to spend time and effort and energy working on.<br>&nbsp;<br>What she&#8217;s conveyed &#8212; the President certainly supports and agrees on &#8212; is that there&#8217;s a federal component here &#8212; continuing to push for legislation to move forward at a federal level &#8212; but there&#8217;s also an important component of working with grassroots organizations, leaders in states, and others to see how we can push back on laws that have been &#8212; that are moving toward getting approved, that make it harder to vote, and how we can use the power of the vice presidency to activate energy and engagement on these issues.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, finally: The FBI has been investigating Postmaster General Louis DeJoy in connection with his former business.&nbsp; Does President Biden believe that the Postmaster General should step down or be replaced?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;ll leave &#8212; he’ll let &#8212; he’ll leave the investigation and the process forward to the Department of Justice.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Going back to infrastructure: I understand that the President offered to repurpose $75 billion in unspent COVID money after there was some concern from the White House that doing that would jeopardize aid to rural hospitals in the areas where it was intended in the beginning.&nbsp; What changed in that negotiation?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, is there any more room for that, given the jobs report and the 20 states not taking enhanced federal unemployment anymore?&nbsp; Could more be taken from unemployment to dedicate to the $75 billion (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that what he&#8217;s referencing &#8212; or there might be some openness to &#8212; is pre-ARP money, which passed during the prior administration; there is a tiny, minimal amount left.&nbsp; So that’s certainly not going to pay for the majority &#8212; the vast majority of these proposals.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, I would note that a lot of this funding &#8212; as we&#8217;ve talked about before &#8212; the vast majority of this funding is allocated, and it is meant to go to, as you noted, hospitals, to firefighters, to keeping law enforcement on the job, to state and localities that have suffered during the pandemic.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;ve proposed alternatives to pay for these proposals, as we&#8217;ve been talking about a bit in here.&nbsp; Why wouldn&#8217;t it be a better option for companies that paid no tax to pay 15 percent? &nbsp;Which is still a lower tax rate than even was in the Trump tax package.&nbsp; Why wouldn&#8217;t it be a better proposal to invest in enforcement &#8212; IRS enforcement &#8212; something that&#8217;s supported by 84 percent of Republicans in the country?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are a range of ideas out there.&nbsp; The President&#8217;s bottom line is: He&#8217;s not going to raise taxes on people making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; He&#8217;s proposed a lot of different options that don&#8217;t cross that red line.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s looking forward to seeing what the other side has to offer.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Where did that $75 billion come from?&nbsp; What pot did it come out of?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The pre-ARP COVID funding.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then going to the emails with Dr. Fauci: There was an exchange between Dr. Collins and Dr. Fauci referencing a Fox News report, discussing it as &#8212; basically, the lab leak as a conspiracy.&nbsp; Collins denied, you know, jumping to conclusions, and he asserted that his mention of conspiracies was referring to the thought, the rumor that the virus was engineered &#8212; bioengineered as a weapon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Is that the position of the administration and their top health experts, that this was not engineered?&nbsp; Or is that still an open question and part of this review?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;ve spoken to this pretty extensively from here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me just say, on Dr. Fauci and his emails, he&#8217;s also spoken to this many, many times over the last &#8212; over the course of the last few days, and we&#8217;ll let him speak for himself.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s been an undeniable asset in our country&#8217;s pandemic response.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s obviously not that advantageous for me to re-litigate the substance of emails from 17 months ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve launched, based on the President&#8217;s direction, an entire internal review process to use all of the resources across government to get to the bottom of the origins.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a 100-day process, and we&#8217;ll look forward to providing more when that &#8212; or 90 days, sorry &#8212; when it&#8217;s concluded.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak at all to the Vanity Fair report about this State Department factsheet that came out five days before inauguration?&nbsp; You know &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Five days before this President’s inauguration?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Do you know if there was any crossover of that; how that was seen by this administration &#8212; the conclusions that they were trying to put out in the final days of the Trump administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;m just going to focus on our own internal review that&#8217;s going to use every resource in the federal government &#8212; whether that is our health experts, our medical experts, our national security team &#8212; to see what more we can unearth about the origins, which certainly we all want to get to the bottom of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, back on infrastructure.&nbsp; So just to be clear on this: One trillion in new spending, and the focus on the minimum tax instead of corporate tax hikes.&nbsp; Is this the President&#8217;s best and final offer to Republicans?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, I think it&#8217;s important to note we have a range of means for moving the President&#8217;s ideas and proposals forward.&nbsp; And the President is going to have a conversation with Senator Capito tomorrow.&nbsp; He&#8217;s very much looking forward to that.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will tell you, for clarity, that what he put forward would have been new spending on top of a baseline of $400 billion over five years.&nbsp; That amount of money &#8212; that would be expected to be invested in infrastructure regardless of these talks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And beyond that, I think, in terms of the payfors, we&#8217;re open to other options.&nbsp; The President is just not going to raise taxes on Americans making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; If the Republicans want to go back to raising the corporate rate as a part of this specific negotiation, we are absolutely for that, and we think that these corporations could pay more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If there are other options, great.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to go down the road of user fees or other areas that would raise taxes on the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And how much of the plan does that minimum tax cover? &nbsp;Does the White House &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s in our budget.&nbsp; You can &#8212; you can take a look.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the corporate tax rate: Are you confident progressive Democrats in Congress would get behind a proposal that doesn&#8217;t include an increase in the corporate tax rate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, to be clear, the President absolutely thinks that corporations can afford to pay more, and especially &#8212; including corporations that paid zero in taxes over the last several years.&nbsp; That’s why it was in his proposal as a payfor.&nbsp; And certainly, a range of members, including progressives, are certainly well aware of what was in the President’s American Jobs Plan proposals as payfors.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the hack &#8212; the cyber hacking.&nbsp; The White House is telling businesses to take steps to prevent this.&nbsp; You know, what&#8217;s the message to Americans, to businesses that keep seeing these hacks happening?&nbsp; Would you consider enforcement? Would you consider other regulations that would try to make this, you know, stricter to prevent these cyberattacks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I will say that there has been. &nbsp;Ransomware is a global problem, as I think we &#8212; you all know.&nbsp; And we have seen these attacks &#8212; ransomware attacks, I should say &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen these attacks disrupt organizations around the world, from hospitals across Ireland, Germany, and France, to pipelines, as you all know, in the United States and banks in the United Kingdom.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These attacks have been on the rise for years because these criminal groups are able to make a profit off the backs of businesses, schools, local governments, and more.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the reasons that we&#8217;re doing our own review internally, which has the focus of four lines of effort &#8212; because we recognize this is an increasing threat; that it is a threat here, but it&#8217;s also a threat around the world, and certainly one that we&#8217;ll be discussing on the President&#8217;s trip in just two weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our focus is on the destruction of ransomware infrastructure and actors, including through close cooperation with the private sector &#8212; part of that communication; building the international coalition &#8212; hence part of the President&#8217;s trip; expanding cryptocurrency analysis to find and pursue criminal transactions; and reviewing our own ransomware policies.&nbsp; That&#8217;s ongoing &#8212; something that&#8217;s a priority to the President, and that will be a priority in the national security team.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kaitlan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he view the $1 trillion in new spending as the lowest he is willing to go?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from here, but certainly we look forward to the President having the discussion with Senator Capito tomorrow.&nbsp; And as a reminder, there are some other lever &#8212; or some other paths that are currently happening.&nbsp; We&#8217;re days away from the House marking up the American Jobs Plan.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something a lot of Democrats in Congress are pretty excited about, as you all know.&nbsp; And also, there are, as has been evidence in much of your reporting, Democrats and Republicans who have been working together to come up, perhaps, with their own proposal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re looking forward to seeing that as well.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to keep optionality on the table, and we&#8217;ll see how the conversation goes tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So he could potentially be open to going lower than $1 trillion in new spending?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give you any new bottom lines from here, but I think it&#8217;s important to note that there are a range of options moving forward.&nbsp; And certainly, his approach and his priority is making a historic investment in infrastructure, creating millions of jobs, and seeing how we can do that as quickly as possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You noted that the markup is just a few days away.&nbsp; Does he see Monday as, kind of, the deadline for any major breakthroughs on where these talks are going?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to have conversations with Democrats and Republicans about what the path forward may look like.&nbsp; And certainly it&#8217;s an important &#8212; it&#8217;s an important moment in the timeline, of course, because there will be movement then.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen Speaker Pelosi talk about how she wants to move forward with infrastructure in June.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen Senator &#8212; Leader Schumer talk about how he wants to move forward with infrastructure in July.&nbsp; Those are some realities in the timeline.&nbsp; But the President is not &#8212; we&#8217;re not here to set new deadlines; we’re going to continue those conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, just checking.&nbsp; Because the Transportation Secretary did say on Sunday that they do view Monday as a deadline for any breakthroughs on these talks.&nbsp; So President Biden does not view Monday as a deadline?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to keep our options open to see what paths we can move forward on.&nbsp; And certainly, the President is not going to accept a deal that doesn&#8217;t help create millions of jobs and make a historic investment in our nation&#8217;s infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; My last question: Before he goes abroad on his trip next week, should we expect any ambassador nominations to come from the White House?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know yet, Kaitlan.&nbsp; We will see.&nbsp; I know that there&#8217;s an interest in that, and we hope to have more soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would note that one of the processes in the ambassadorial nomination process is that countries have to agree to these selections, and so sometimes that&#8217;s part of the timeline.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that holding this up (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a holdup.&nbsp; It’s just part of the process. &nbsp;So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Annie.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In general, when so much of Biden&#8217;s agenda includes long-term things that will take a while to bear fruit, even once they’re passed &#8212; infrastructure being at the top of that list &#8212; is the White House concerned that Congress is moving slower than a snail’s pace on everything from democracy reform, to a policing bill, to these endless infrastructure talks, and that it will get harder as you get closer to the midterms for you to tackle your priorities?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, that’s not our view.&nbsp; I would say, first, the American Rescue Plan passed at a pretty rapid speed.&nbsp; That&#8217;s typically faster than most pieces of legislation, as many of you know, moves through Congress.&nbsp; I mean, not that this is necessarily our model in terms of timeline, but the Affordable Care Act took a year to move through Congress.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, we certainly recognize that sausage-making is messy.&nbsp; It takes some time.&nbsp; The President has talked about wanting to sign a bill into law this summer, and there is certainly appetite and interest and a commitment to moving forward on infrastructure from Speaker Pelosi, as well as Leader Schumer.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say, as it relates to police reform, we certainly know that coming together &#8212; in order to get that across the finish line, there needs to be agreement from the negotiators about what the path forward looks like.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve said they&#8217;re making progress; they&#8217;ve been encouraged by the tone of the discussions.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a positive sign to us, and we&#8217;re going to continue to support those efforts as they move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess, just, the question is: You know, how are you going to show voters who are trying to decide if Biden was an effective President, beyond the falling virus numbers, that his approach is working?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Beyond falling virus numbers?&nbsp; Beyond getting a global pandemic under control?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) voters.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, Anne &#8212; you know, from polling and from what the American people care about and are focused on &#8212; getting the pandemic under control; ensuring that we&#8217;re saving tens of thousands, if not hundreds of thousands of lives; making sure that the majority &#8212; more than 70 percent of people in this country are vaccinated so that they can return to their normal lives, which means returning to their jobs, kids returning to school, seeing friends, going to concerts, returning to life pre-pandemic &#8212; that is the number one, two, three, four, five issue on everyone&#8217;s mind.&nbsp; That has been the President&#8217;s focus from day one and absolutely how he has spent the majority of his time to date.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other question on Israel.&nbsp; Gantz was here today and met with Jake Sullivan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; His plan was to ask for a billion dollars in emergency military aid.&nbsp; Is the U.S. expected to grant &#8212; to provide those funds?&nbsp; And if so, does it have any expectation that we would get cooperation from the Israelis on rebuilding Gaza if we did?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t &#8212; I knew we were going to do a readout of that.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if that&#8217;s come out yet &#8212; the readout of the call.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It came out and it didn’t mention anything about whether or not those requests would be granted.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check and see if there&#8217;s any update on that.&nbsp; It may be that we have to consider their requests.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not sure we&#8217;ll have a rapid response, but I will check with our team and see if we have any update.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Mara.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; In terms of the voting &#8212; the ballot bills that are being introduced around the country &#8212; the President spoke out pretty strongly in Tulsa about them &#8212; other than the Vice President, as you said, working with grassroots groups, if you don&#8217;t have the votes to stop these laws in the state legislatures, and you don&#8217;t have the votes to overturn the filibuster so you could pass H.R. 1 or the John Lewis Act, what can he do other than engender a public backlash to them?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, we don&#8217;t accept that &#8212; that that&#8217;s the case.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to press for Congress to move forward with legislation on voting rights.&nbsp; We know it&#8217;s not always a straight line and that sometimes it takes time. And there needs to be discussion and negotiation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And in states, it&#8217;s not just about engaging with community organizations; we&#8217;re also talking about working with the private sector, working with voting rights groups, strengthening and uplifting efforts on voting rights nationwide.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So this is an across-the-board effort that&#8217;s not just focused federally, it&#8217;s also focused on states.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also focused on local and grassroots organizations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly, one of the President&#8217;s lessons from having been &#8212; done this for 50 years or more is that, you know, the engagement and the activism of the American people is often the driver of change.&nbsp; And so a part of this effort is certainly to engage with that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Even though some of these bills have already been signed into law or are about to be (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, laws sometimes are meant to be changed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I have a question about the cyberattacks.&nbsp; Is this something that he would talk to Putin about?&nbsp; Is it something he thinks that Russia has some responsibility for or could do something to stop?&nbsp; Or what &#8212; how does he &#8212; what is Putin&#8217;s &#8212; where does Putin fit into these ransomware attacks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, we expect it to be a topic of discussion at the summit that is happening in just less than two weeks.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s message will be that responsible states do not harbor ransomware criminals, and responsible countries must take decisive action against these ransomware networks.&nbsp; So that will be a part of the discussion when he sees him in less than two weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just have one more quick one, just to put infrastructure to bed.&nbsp; I understand it &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s to bed.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand if &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s like brushing its teeth or something.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He&#8217;s saying &#8212; he&#8217;s saying that for infrastructure, it&#8217;s not &#8212; he can &#8212; he has so many payfors it&#8217;s not necessary to raise the corporate tax, or just enforcement and the book minimum would take care of infrastructure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Does he believe that raising the corporate tax and raising the tax on people who make more than $400,000 is still necessary to fund his other proposals like the American Families Plan?&nbsp; Or is he &#8212; or is he &#8212; does he believe that maybe this is not necessary at all?&nbsp; I&#8217;m not talking about whether you&#8217;re for it or not; I&#8217;m asking you if he still feels that those hikes are necessary for his agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He wouldn&#8217;t have proposed them and put them in his budget if he didn&#8217;t think so.&nbsp; I mean, I think there&#8217;s a math ch- &#8212; not challenge &#8212; there&#8217;s a math problem here somewhere, you know, in that the President has come down in his proposal, and what &#8212; and as we&#8217;re negotiating with Republicans on an infrastructure package.&nbsp; As you noted, Mara, there&#8217;s a range of other ideas that he has put forward that he wants to get passed into law: Child Tax Credit, universal pre-K, et cetera.&nbsp; He&#8217;s also proposed ways to pay for it.<br>&nbsp;<br>So these are components that would help pay for his proposals in this negotiation.&nbsp; But, certainly, raising the corporate rate is something &#8212; going back to what the rate was in, you know, the early days of the George W. Bush administration &#8212; is certainly something that he feels &#8212; sees as a viable payfor for many of his bold ideas.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8220;Viable payfor&#8221; or necessary to pay for it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I think it&#8217;s important to take a step back and remember this is not about &#8212; these proposals were not standalone corporate tax increases. &nbsp;These proposals were an American Jobs Plan to make historic investment in our nation&#8217;s infrastructure. They were to level the playing field and make universal pre-K eligible &#8212; you know, kids across the country eligible.<br>&nbsp;<br>So he&#8217;s proposed a range of ways to pay for it.&nbsp; Those payfors can be moved around.&nbsp; And certainly raising the corporate rate is a &#8212; is an area he feels is a viable, good, positive, essential option.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, in light of the recent ransomware attack, what is the White House guidance to private companies, the private sector about paying ransom?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our guidance continues to be &#8212; from the FBI &#8212; that companies should not pay ransom because it incentivizes these attacks on other companies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, separately on the &#8212; on a fourth stimulus check idea that is supported by dozens of Democrats in Congress.&nbsp; I know, a month ago, you said, you know, stimulus checks aren&#8217;t free, and it&#8217;s really up to Congress to decide whether to move forward on that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering, at this point, does the President support that idea?&nbsp; Or does he believe that his American Jobs and Families Plan provide enough economic assistance that a fourth stimulus wouldn&#8217;t be necessary?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as he said at the time &#8212; as I said at the time, I should say when you asked this before: The President is certainly open to a range of ideas.&nbsp; There are some who are proposing an elimination of the SALT deduction.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think I said it the right way.<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are some who are proposing making the Child Tax Credit permanent.&nbsp; There are some who are proposing additional stimulus.&nbsp; He&#8217;s happy to hear from a range of ideas on what would be most effective and what&#8217;s most important to the economy moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>But he&#8217;s also proposed what he thinks is going to be the most effective for the short term, for putting people back to work, to getting through this pivotal period of time, and also to making us more competitive over the long term.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to clarify, the President does support an extension of the family Child Tax Credit that&#8217;s going to start taking effect next month, correct?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s in &#8212; in his American Families Plan, he&#8217;s proposed an extension of the Child Tax Credit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Does the choreography of the Europe trip, having these sit-downs with allies and NATO before Putin, is this meant to effectively project President Biden as a messenger of the West, not just the U.S., when he sits down with the Russian leader?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that his commitment to attend the G7 and NATO predated the scheduling of the summit, just factually, as you all know.&nbsp; But I would certainly say thematically that what you&#8217;ll see from the President, and him talk about on this trip, is his advocacy for democracy over autocracy &#8212; domestically, here in the United States, but certainly around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he&#8217;s always felt that we are stronger when we are working with our partners and our allies &#8212; many of them are in the G7 and in NATO &#8212; and certainly discussing issues as it relates to cyberthreats, the threat of climate change, or problematic behavior from some where we have disagreements &#8212; including Russia, including China &#8212; would certainly be a part of those engagements.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would it be fair to say that that theme you&#8217;re talking about, the democracy over autocracy, is that maybe his guiding theme through that whole week?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Stay tuned.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, Eugene.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President hasn&#8217;t nominated a &#8212; someone for the top Antitrust role at the DOJ yet.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the longest since before H.W. Bush.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering if there&#8217;s a hold-up there.&nbsp; And if so, what is it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of any particular hold-up.&nbsp; And certainly, he wants to select and nominate the right people for each of these important positions.&nbsp; We can check and see if there&#8217;s any update on the timeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on H.R. 40 &#8212; President Biden was obviously in Tulsa there.&nbsp; I was also there talking to some activists, and they heard from the President and they’ve heard from this White House that he is supportive of a committee to study reparations, which is what H.R. 40 would do.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he hasn&#8217;t called for Congress to pass H.R. 40 or talked about his support for the bill specifically, so I&#8217;m just curious if he supports the bill as written that just went through (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he supports a number of components of the bill, including the funding and the proposal for a study, which he feels would be the next important step forward and something that he feels would be absolutely correct in addressing this moment in history &#8212; these moments in history.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But not H.R. 40 as it stands?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have more of an assessment of the legislation.&nbsp; But he, of course, supports a study of reparations and feels that would be the best next step.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I know that you don&#8217;t want to relitigate what happened when Biden wasn&#8217;t in office and when those e-mails were sent.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Uh-oh. &nbsp;That&#8217;s a setup.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Probably not.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But has anyone from your team briefed the President of what was in those FOIA&#8217;ed Fauci e-mails?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of him being briefed on the publicly reported e-mails.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, given that there were some things that Fauci said privately that contracted &#8212; contrasted with what he said publicly &#8212; whether it was masks or whether or not someone who had the virus, you know, could have immunity, or<br>you know, other questions as well &#8212; I mean, does he still have confidence in his NIH director?&nbsp; Does this change anything at all &#8212; these e-mails?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, the President and the administration feel that Dr. Fauci has played an incredible role in getting the pandemic under control, being a voice to the public throughout the course of this pandemic.&nbsp; And, again, I would reiterate a lot of these emails are from 17 months ago or more, certainly predating this administration, but some time ago in &#8212; as we look to history.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more.&nbsp; This morning, on &#8220;Morning Joe,&#8221; Anthony Fauci said that one of the ways to get transparency from the Chinese on the origins of COVID-19 was to, quote, &#8220;don&#8217;t be accusatory.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Does the President feel that the initial investigation of the origin of the virus, including that WHO survey that your team had deep concerns over &#8212; was the problem with that that it was too accusatory?&nbsp; I mean, is that a problem that this administration is being accusatory?&nbsp; Or &#8212; I mean, is this a situation where, you know, &#8220;we&#8217;re just following the evidence where it leads&#8221;?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think our primary objective here has been working with the international community &#8212; rejoining the WHO, working with the international community to unite in pressing the Chinese to be transparent, to provide the underlying data so other scientists can take a look at that data, and to participate in a constructive way in the second round of &#8212; the next round &#8212; or the next phase, I should say, of the WHO investigation.<br>&nbsp;<br>As we noted at the time when we announced our own internal next step here, our 90-day review, one of the things that was happening in the timeline was the Chinese conveying that that was not their inclination.&nbsp;<br>So, I can&#8217;t assess what the impacts are.&nbsp; I can tell you what our position is and what we&#8217;ve been pressing for on the international stage.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Just about the 90-day review.&nbsp; One thing that&#8217;s not clear is: How is it that the U.S. intelligence officials knew about the workers in Wuhan lab &#8212; that they knew about them getting sick back in 2019, and then, in February, the intelligence officials were saying that they still hadn’t ruled out the possibility that the virus came from the lab? &nbsp;But the inquiry didn’t happen until late May of this month, and I&#8217;m wondering what took the U.S. so long before it launched its &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s not actually an accurate depiction of the timeline.&nbsp; The President actually asked his intelligence community to look into &#8212; to do an internal assessment, which then was presented to him in an internal meeting back in March.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, but the official &#8212; the 90-day inquiry, the one you&#8217;re describing, but the full look at this hypothesis, that was not announced publicly &#8212; I mean, people were not aware of &#8212; until May 26.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He didn’t &#8212; he didn’t decide to launch it.&nbsp; The timeline here was: He asked the intelligence team to do an internal review, an internal assessment.&nbsp; When that was done several weeks ago, he asked it to be made public &#8212; to declassify that information.&nbsp; That goes through a process.&nbsp; Sometimes it takes a couple of weeks to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>When that assessment was done, we were presented with an option for a public statement, and the President decided we wanted to do a more extensive review and tap into our lab scientists and experts, our &#8212; more of our national security team to see what more we can uncover over the course of 90 days.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the timeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, maybe I wasn&#8217;t saying it &#8212; or maybe I was saying it too specific with the dates.&nbsp; But the question &#8212; the bigger question is: What took the U.S. so long to take it seriously, when there were reports about the possibility of this virus coming from there, you know, way, way (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We completely refute that argument or notion.&nbsp; Obviously, the President asked his intelligence team to do an internal assessment, which happens all the time.&nbsp; We rarely talk about that publicly.&nbsp; We obviously took the step to declassify that, and that&#8217;s something that he did early on in his administration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, great.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Sorry, Nancy.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t mean to skip you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, that’s fine.&nbsp; Come back to (inaudible) &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned that vaccination rates are slowing down?&nbsp; And with the National Month of Action, if you do not get to that 70 percent goal, what is your plan B?&nbsp; And is there a concern that you have to throw in some more incentives in there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, we&#8217;re not going to prejudge our outcome here on July 4th.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we launched the Month of Action and one of the reasons why we are working with every entity that can play a constructive role here.&nbsp; Free beer &#8212; that seems to be very appealing to the public, it seems, by headlines.&nbsp; Krispy Kreme Doughnuts.&nbsp; Getting into raffles for flights.&nbsp; And a range of incentives that states are implementing.&nbsp; Many of them did not come from us, obviously.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because we recognize that, at this stage &#8212; and we always knew that the rate of vaccination would slow down because we were at a period of time &#8212; we went through a period of time where there wasn&#8217;t enough supply for the demand, and then we got to a period of time where we had more supply than the demand.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we launched a $3 billion effort to do local engagements, working with community leader leaders, clergy, other trusted voices, doctors, pediatricians.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But now we&#8217;re at a one-month &#8212; it reminds me a little bit of political campaigns where you are knocking on doors, you&#8217;re making phone calls, you&#8217;re incentivizing &#8212; all legal, of course &#8212; ways to get people to the polls.&nbsp; This is: How can we get more shots in arms?&nbsp; And we’re &#8212; we&#8217;ve welcomed the engagement from a range of &#8212; range of entities in the private sector to do exactly that.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will also say, as of yesterday, about a dozen states had met their 70 percent or higher.&nbsp; And ultimately, this is going to be up to individuals to get shots in their arms.&nbsp; We can take every creative step we possibly can take.&nbsp; We also understand we don&#8217;t have 100 percent control here, but we&#8217;re going to do everything we can from the federal government to reach that goal.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He did create this initiative with Shots in the Shops within barber shops across the country.&nbsp; How are you going to work with other, you know, I guess, communities, especially in the South, where there is a concern that those vaccination rates are going down?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you&#8217;re absolutely right that we are &#8212; and they&#8217;re going down in different parts of the country, which, again, we anticipated.&nbsp; But in communities and areas where we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; the lower numbers are actually primarily under 40, and they&#8217;re more among young people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, one of the ways we focused is on how we can reach and engage with the communities that don&#8217;t have the highest percentage rate.&nbsp; People over 65: there&#8217;s a huge percentage of people who have received their first and even second doses.&nbsp; And even over 40, it&#8217;s quite a high percentage.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, again, what we&#8217;ve learned from our data is that local engagement, working with trusted voices.&nbsp; Maybe it&#8217;s the primary care physician that somebody has been seeing for 20 years; maybe it&#8217;s local churches where they go every Sunday or they go more than once a week.&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re working at a very local level to do this, and also working through the private sector on, kind of, some of these engagements where it could incentivize some of the communities that have not &#8212; that don&#8217;t have as high of a percentage rate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last question: Does the President have an idea of when things would be quote, unquote, “back to normal,” especially with these ramping up of vaccine efforts?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you know, we obviously are guided by CDC guidance.&nbsp; But what we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; and they&#8217;ve announced over the last several weeks &#8212; is that, you know, if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you don&#8217;t have to wear a mask inside, outside, you know, going into stores.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that in &#8212; around the country, as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;re already seeing a move toward “back to normal,” but it really depends on community to community.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the other guidance that we have been providing and emphasizing &#8212; because if a community has a vaccination rate of 80 percent, they are clearly in a different place than a community that has a vaccination rate of 55 percent.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s really going to be determinations made at a very local level about what is safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Nancy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just in terms of &#8212; back to the corporate tax rate for a second.&nbsp; If it’s something that the President is willing to, you know, drop out of a potential bipartisan infrastructure deal, does the White House see it fitting in as a payfor for the American Families Plan?&nbsp; Or where else could that be slotted in?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have no shortage of ideas around here, Nancy.&nbsp; I will note that, again, he&#8217;s put forward a range of ways to pay for his big, bold ideas, including raising the corporate tax rate.&nbsp; And there are a number of components of his ideas that are not in this infrastructure negotiation right now &#8212; and you&#8217;ve referenced many of them &#8212; in the American Families Plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to predetermine what all the aligning of items will be in the future because that obviously isn&#8217;t a package that&#8217;s a part of this specific negotiation.&nbsp; But, certainly, he thinks that raising the corporate rate, ensuring &#8212; asking corporations who have &#8212; many of whom have made a big profit during the pandemic &#8212; to pay a little bit more is a very viable way to pay for ideas moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more thing on the COVID vaccination distribution.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How does the White House expect to donate 80 million doses without AstraZeneca?&nbsp; Does that mean that the J&amp;J shot will definitely be part of the distribution?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, J&amp;J has been approved by the FDA, so it would be a part &#8212; those doses would be a part of what we&#8217;re distributing, along with Moderna and Pfizer, including in this initial set of 25 million.&nbsp; AstraZeneca, as you know, we&#8217;re waiting for FDA approval to &#8212; to even approve it to go overseas.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that certainly we could utilize those doses, and they would be a part of the doses of the 80 million.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, in the &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead, Alex.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, just &#8212; we&#8217;re weeks and weeks into these infrastructure negotiations, and I&#8217;m curious, what does the White House think it has to show for it?&nbsp; What do you think &#8212; what progress would you point to?&nbsp; What would you point to to show that, you know, we’re closer to a deal than when this process began?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that it may feel foreign, but the process of policymaking and negotiating can be messy and can &#8212; the sausage-making isn&#8217;t always beautiful or pretty.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re in the middle of right now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President has pledged to the American people, when he ran for office, that he would work with Democrats and Republicans to try to get important initiatives forward on behalf of the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is an example of that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re having ongoing discussions with Republicans.&nbsp; We feel that those discussions have been done in good faith.&nbsp; The President is looking forward to talking to Senator Capito tomorrow.&nbsp; We also are eager to see what proposal may be put forward by Democrats and Republicans who are talking about what they might agree on.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are a range of paths forward here, and the President remains committed to his goal of signing a bill into law &#8212; historic investment infrastructure &#8212; by the summer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Remain in Mexico Policy has ended.&nbsp; Is it still your message to immigrants coming from Central America not to come &#8212; that the border is still closed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Our message is still: “This is a dangerous time to come.”&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been clear in our assessment that the MPP program &#8212; more commonly known as Remain in Mexico &#8212; was quite problematic.&nbsp; It led to dangerous and inhumane conditions along Mexico&#8217;s northern border, in part because of the camps and the conditions at the camps.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s something the President talked about, or we&#8217;ve talked about, for some time.&nbsp; And Secretary Mayorkas and DHS determined that the program does not adequately or sustainably enhance border management either.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our message continues to be: “This is not the time to come.”&nbsp; We want to have an effective immigration system in place, including asylum processing at our border.&nbsp; And that has not changed, but the &#8212; ending the “Remain in Mexico” program is something we&#8217;ve long talked about our commitment to.<br>&nbsp;<br>Brittany, go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The President has tasked Vice President Harris with two contentious, if not at least very-difficult-to-wrap-your-head-around, time-consuming issues in American politics: you know, immigration, the Northern Triangle, and race (inaudible) voting rights.&nbsp; It’s not just National Space Council stuff that hasn&#8217;t kicked off yet.&nbsp; Broadband, dealing with labor unions.&nbsp; Should we expect any other major additions to Vice President Harris&#8217;s portfolio in the coming months &#8212; let me say, by the end of the year?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the President is confident that the Vice President is absolutely up to the task.&nbsp; He sees her as a partner and someone who he &#8212; is playing the role of a modern-day Vice President, which is taking on challenging tasks, tasks that won&#8217;t be easy.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s certainly something he felt he did as Vice President, and he is confident that Vice President Harris will do exactly the same thing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, as you know, she&#8217;s traveling to the Northern Triangle next week.&nbsp; She&#8217;s just taken on this initiative, per her request, on voting rights.&nbsp; She&#8217;s going to be active on that in the weeks ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I can&#8217;t predict what&#8217;s going to come our way or what initiatives she&#8217;ll need to take on over the months ahead, but certainly, these are two big tasks that he&#8217;s confident in her ability to lead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you said earlier that Harris had asked to take on this issue of voting rights.&nbsp; Is that how she&#8217;s &#8212; her portfolio has been determined.&nbsp; Has she been the one advocating for herself for these other assignments?&nbsp; Or has it been (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Typically a discussion.&nbsp; They have regular lunches, and they discuss areas where they know there needs to be one of them at the helm.&nbsp; And certainly, this is an area where she expressed a direct interest in.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m going to have to just wrap it up shortly, but go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just quickly, a little update on the White House cat. Is that something that is still happening here?&nbsp; Our readers are asking us a lot, so I figured I have a right to ask.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I bet.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been joking, although maybe it might be true, that we&#8217;re waiting for a bad news day for that to come out.&nbsp; If you see a tail wagging coming out of the briefing room, you&#8217;ll know something bad is about to happen.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update on the cat.&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s a lot of interest.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the symbolic importance of the President&#8217;s meeting with the Queen at Windsor Castle in the UK?&nbsp; And also, when he sits down with Boris Johnson &#8212; there&#8217;s also a long history of meetings between American presidents and British prime ministers, but will this one be different because the UK is no longer part of the European Union?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we continue to have a Special Relationship with the United Kingdom, and I&#8217;m certain we&#8217;ll have more to preview early next week about what the trip looks like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But there&#8217;s a range of issues of mutual interest.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about some of them in this briefing &#8212; from the future of economic growth in the world, to addressing the COVID pandemic, to security issues around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So they have a range of topics they can clearly discuss, and certainly it should be seen as significant that it&#8217;s the President&#8217;s first stop on a foreign trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And this is his first meeting with the Queen.&nbsp; Is that something he&#8217;s always looked forward to?&nbsp; Does he have any kind of relationship with her?&nbsp; Obviously the first time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Who among us wouldn&#8217;t want to meet the Queen?&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more personal to read out.&nbsp; I will check and see if he has met her in the past.&nbsp; I believe he has, but let me check on that to confirm for sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They issued, of course, a graceful invitation, which he certainly accepted.&nbsp; He&#8217;s looking forward to seeing her with Dr. Biden, as well, on &#8212; a couple days into his trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In Tulsa, the President talked about the American Jobs Plan and what it does for closing the racial wealth gap.&nbsp; Does he give a cast-iron guarantee that whatever these negotiations are with Republicans, that will remain intact, there&#8217;ll be no compromise on racial equity?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Racial equity and addressing racial equity is central to the President&#8217;s initiatives, his commitments to rebuilding our economy around the country, and certainly he&#8217;s not going to give up on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m sorry, I&#8217;ve got to wrap it up for another meeting.&nbsp; Apologize.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it fair to call it a 1.4 trillion-dollar plan? &nbsp;Because it’s a &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will allow you to do the math yourself.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>1:50 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
