<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 20:43:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Supreme Court Decision to Overturn Roe V.&#160;Wade</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-supreme-court-decision-to-overturn-roe-v-wade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 20:43:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56249</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[C.W. Avery Family YMCAPlainfield, Illinois 2:23 P.M. CDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon, everyone.  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon. Well, first, I want to thank Senator Durbin.  I had the privilege of serving with him, as he mentioned, on the Senate Judiciary Committee.  And I can tell&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>C.W. Avery Family YMCA<br><em>Plainfield, Illinois</em></em></p>



<p>2:23 P.M. CDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  (Applause.)  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon, everyone.  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Good afternoon.<br><br>Well, first, I want to thank Senator Durbin.  I had the privilege of serving with him, as he mentioned, on the Senate Judiciary Committee.  And I can tell you, Illinois, you are very, very well represented by Senator Dick Durbin.  He is an extraordinary leader, a great fighter for all of American and &#8212; all of America, and in particular for the people of Illinois.<br>So, thank you, Dick Durbin, and congratulations to your grandchild, for her honor today as well. <br><br>And I want to thank all the leaders for joining us today, and a special thank you, of course, to Lauren Underwood.  Where are you?  Lauren.  (Applause.)  I have seen you when the cameras are on and when the cameras are off.  She’s always fighting for the people of her district.  And all that you have done for our government, for the people of our country, and for Plainfield, I thank you for that.  I thank you for your partnership and your leadership.<br><br>So, as Senator Durbin mentioned, we traveled here today.  In fact, they both joined me, along with the Secretary, on Air Force Two.  And we traveled here from D.C. today to talk with you about maternal health, which should be one of our highest priorities as a nation.<br><br>And I had planned to speak about our strategy for improving care for pregnant women and mothers across our country.  And as you know, on the way here, however, we learned that the United States Supreme Court had rendered its decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization.<br><br>Here’s what that decision means: For nearly 50 years, we have talked about what Roe v. Wade protects.  Today, as of right now, as of this minute, we can only talk about what Roe v. Wade protected.  Past tense. <br><br>This is a healthcare crisis, because understand: Millions of women in America will go to bed tonight without access to the healthcare and reproductive care that they had this morning; without access to the same healthcare or reproductive healthcare that their mothers and grandmothers had for 50 years.<br> <br>This is the first time in the history of our nation that a constitutional right has been taken from the people of America.  And what is that right? &#8212; some might ask.  It’s the right to privacy.<br> <br>Think about it as the right for each person to make intimate decisions about heart and home; decisions about the right to start a family, including contraception, such as IUDs and the morning-after pill; decisions about whether to have a child, including, as Senator Durbin mentioned, through in-vitro fertilization; decisions to marry the person you love &#8212; Obergefell v. Hodges, Loving vs. Virginia.<br> <br>This opinion also says, when your read it, that abortion is not deeply rooted in our nation’s history.  They offer that in the opinion as a foundation for the decision they rendered today.<br> <br>In holding that it is not deeply rooted in our history, today’s decision on that theory, then, calls into question other rights that we thought were settled, such as the right to use birth control, the right to same-sex marriage, the right to interracial marriage.<br> <br>The great aspiration of our nation has been to expand freedom, but the expansion of freedom clearly is not inevitable.  It is not something that just happens &#8212; not unless we defend our most fundamental principles; not unless we elect leaders who stand up for those principles.<br> <br>The strength of our nation has always been that we move forward. <br><br>Today, I invite all people to stand together in defense of one of the most fundamental ideals and principles that for generations, for centuries, I believe, we have held dear, which is that fundamental principle about the importance of liberty &#8212; to stand for liberty, to stand for freedom, to stand for self-determination, and for the right to privacy.<br> <br>You have the power to elect leaders who will defend and protect your rights.  And as the President said earlier today, with your vote, you can act, and you have the final word. <br> <br>So this is not over.  God bless you.  And God bless America.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END                 2:30 P.M. CDT</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 735, H.R. 767 and ​H.R.&#160;1444</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/24/bills-signed-h-r-735-h-r-767-and-h-r-1444/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 20:25:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56247</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, June 24, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 735, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 502 East Cotati Avenue in Cotati, California, as the Arturo L. Ibleto Post Office Building; Thank you to Representative Mike Thompson and many others for their leadership. H.R. 767, which designates&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, June 24, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 735, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 502 East Cotati Avenue in Cotati, California, as the Arturo L. Ibleto Post Office Building;</p>



<p>Thank you to Representative Mike Thompson and many others for their leadership.</p>



<p>H.R. 767, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 40 Fulton Street in Middletown, New York, as the Benjamin A. Gilman Post Office Building;<br><br>Thank you to Representative Sean Patrick Maloney and many others for their leadership.</p>



<p>H.R. 1444, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 132 North Loudoun Street, Suite 1 in Winchester, Virginia, as the Patsy Cline Post Office.<br><br>Thank you to Representative Wexton and the bipartisan efforts of the Virginia delegation for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Announces Actions In Light of Today’s Supreme Court Decision on Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health&#160;Organization</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/24/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-actions-in-light-of-todays-supreme-court-decision-on-dobbs-v-jackson-womens-health-organization/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 19:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56241</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden announced actions that his Administration is taking to protect women who will face the grave consequences of today’s Supreme Court decision. This decision expressly took away a Constitutional right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to choose, free from government interference. This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden announced actions that his Administration is taking to protect women who will face the grave consequences of today’s Supreme Court decision. This decision expressly took away a Constitutional right from the American people that it had recognized for nearly 50 years – a woman’s right to choose, free from government interference.</p>



<p>This decision will have devastating consequences in the lives of women around the country.</p>



<p>The President made clear that the only way to secure a woman’s right to choose is for Congress to restore the protections of <em>Roe</em> as federal law. Until then, he has announced two actions the Administration is taking to protect women.</p>



<p><strong>Protecting the Right to Seek Medical Care</strong></p>



<p>As the <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/attorney-general-merrick-b-garland-statement-supreme-court-ruling-dobbs-v-jackson-women-s#:~:text=%E2%80%9CThe%20Justice%20Department%20will%20use,civil%20rights%20of%20all%20Americans.%E2%80%9D">Attorney General made clear,</a> women must remain free to travel safely to another state to seek the care they need.</p>



<p>A person has the right to travel between states for whatever reason they want – it is no one else’s business – especially the government’s. If a woman lives in a state that restricts abortion, the Supreme Court’s decision does not prevent her from traveling from her home to a state that allows it.</p>



<p>If any state or local official tries to interfere with women exercising this basic right, the Biden Administration will fight that deeply un-American attack.</p>



<p><strong>Protecting Access to Medication</strong></p>



<p>The President directed the Secretary of Health and Human Services to protect women’s access to critical medications for reproductive health care that are approved by the Food and Drug Administration—including essential preventive health care like contraception and medication abortion.</p>



<p>More than 20 years ago, the FDA approved mifepristone to safely end an early pregnancy; this drug is also commonly used to treat miscarriages. The American Medical Association and the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists wrote to President Biden and Vice President Harris, asking the federal government to protect access to this care. In the face of threats from state officials saying they will try to ban or severely restrict access to medication for reproductive health care, the President directed the Secretary of Health and Human Services to identify all ways to ensure that mifepristone is as widely accessible as possible in light of the FDA’s determination that the drug is safe and effective—including when prescribed through telehealth and sent by mail.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">***</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Supreme Court Decision to Overturn Roe v.&#160;Wade</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-supreme-court-decision-to-overturn-roe-v-wade/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 18:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56232</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cross Hall 12:37 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Today is a &#8212; it’s not hyperbole to suggest a very solemn moment.&#160; Today, the Supreme Court of the United States expressly took away a constitutional right from the American people that it had already recognized. They didn’t limit it.&#160; They simply took it away.&#160; That’s never been&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cross Hall</p>



<p>12:37 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Today is a &#8212; it’s not hyperbole to suggest a very solemn moment.&nbsp; Today, the Supreme Court of the United States expressly took away a constitutional right from the American people that it had already recognized.</p>



<p>They didn’t limit it.&nbsp; They simply took it away.&nbsp; That’s never been done to a right so important to so many Americans.</p>



<p>But they did it.&nbsp; And it’s a sad day for the Court and for the country.</p>



<p>Fifty years ago, Roe v. Wade was decided and has been the law of the land since then.</p>



<p>This landmark case protected a woman’s right to choose, her right to make intensely personal decisions with her doctor, free from the inter- &#8212; from interference of politics.</p>



<p>It reaffirmed basic principles of equality &#8212; that women have the power to control their own destiny.&nbsp; And it reinforced the fundamental right of privacy &#8212; the right of each of us to choose how to live our lives.</p>



<p>Now, with Roe gone, let’s be very clear: The health and life of women in this nation are now at risk.</p>



<p>As Chairman and Ranking Member of the Senate Judiciary Committee, as Vice President and now as President of the United States, I’ve studied this case carefully.&nbsp; I’ve overseen more Supreme Court confirmations than anyone today, where this case was always discussed.</p>



<p>I believe Roe v. Wade was the correct decision as a matter of constitutional law, an application of the fundamental right to privacy and liberty in matters of family and personal autonomy.</p>



<p>It was a decision on a complex matter that drew a careful balance between a woman’s right to choose earlier in her pregnancy and the state’s ability to regulate later in her pregnancy.&nbsp; A decision with broad national consensus that most Americans of faiths and backgrounds found acceptable and that had been the law of the land for most of the lifetime of Americans today.</p>



<p>And it was a constitutional principle upheld by justices appointed by Democrat and Republican Presidents alike.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Roe v. Wade was a 7 to 2 decision written by a justice appointed by a Republican President, Richard Nixon.  In the five decades that followed Roe v. Wade, justices appointed by Republican Presidents &#8212; from Eisenhower, Nixon, Reagan, George <s>W.</s> [H.W.] Bush &#8212; were among the justices who voted to uphold the principles set forth in Roe v. Wade.</p>



<p>It was three justices named by one President &#8212; Donald Trump &#8212; who were the core of today’s decision to upend the scales of justice and eliminate a fundamental right for women in this country.</p>



<p>Make no mistake: This decision is the culmination of a deliberate effort over decades to upset the balance of our law.&nbsp; It’s a realization of an extreme ideology and a tragic error by the Supreme Court, in my view.</p>



<p>The Court has done what it has never done before: expressly take away a constitutional right that is so fundamental to so many Americans that had already been recognized.</p>



<p>The Court’s decision to do so will have real and immediate consequences.&nbsp; State laws banning abortion are automatically taking effect today, jeopardizing the health of millions of women, some without exceptions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So extreme that women could be punished for protecting their health.</p>



<p>So extreme that women and girls who are forced to bear their rapist’s child &#8212; of the child of consequence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s a &#8212; it just &#8212; it just stuns me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So extreme that doctors will be criminalized for fulfilling their duty to care.</p>



<p>Imagine having &#8212; a young woman having to ch- &#8212; carry the child of incest &#8212; as a consequence of incest.&nbsp; No option.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Too often the case that poor women are going to be hit the hardest.&nbsp; It’s cruel.</p>



<p>In fact, the Court laid out state laws criminalizing abortion that go back to the 1800s as rationale &#8212; the Court literally taking America back 150 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This a sad day for the country, in my view, but it doesn’t mean the fight is over.</p>



<p>Let me be very clear and unambiguous:&nbsp;The only way we can secure a woman’s right to choose and the balance that existed is for Congress to restore the protections of Roe v. Wade as federal law.</p>



<p>No executive action from the President can do that.&nbsp; And if Congress, as it appears, lacks the vote &#8212; votes to do that now, voters need to make their voices heard.</p>



<p>This fall, we must elect more senators and representatives who will codify a woman’s right to choose into federal law once again, elect more state leaders to protect this right at the local level.</p>



<p>We need to restore the protections of Roe as law of the land.&nbsp; We need to elect officials who will do that.</p>



<p>This fall, Roe is on the ballot.&nbsp; Personal freedoms are on the ballot.&nbsp; The right to privacy, liberty, equality, they&#8217;re all on the ballot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Until then, I will do all in my power to protect a woman’s right in states where they will face the consequences of today’s decision.</p>



<p>While the Court’s decision casts a dark shadow over a large swath of the land, many states in this country still recognize a woman’s right to choose.</p>



<p>So if a woman lives in a state that restricts abortion, the Supreme Court’s decision does not prevent her from traveling from her home state to the state that allows it.&nbsp; It does not prevent a doctor in that state &#8212; in that state from treating her.</p>



<p>As the Attorney General has made clear, women must remain free to travel safely to another state to seek the care they need.&nbsp; And my administration will defend that bedrock right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If any state or local official, high or low, tries to interfere with a woman’s ex- &#8212; exercising her basic right to travel, I will do everything in my power to fight that deeply un-American attack.</p>



<p>My administration will also protect a woman’s access to medications that are approved by the Food and Drug Administration &#8212; the FDA &#8212; like contraception, which is essential for preventative healthcare; mifepristone, which the FDA approved 20 years ago to safely end early pregnancies and is commonly used to treat miscarriages.</p>



<p>Some states are saying that they’ll try to ban or severely restrict access to these medications.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But extremist governors and state legislators who are looking to block the mail or search a person’s medicine cabinet or control a woman’s actions by tracking data on her apps she uses are wrong and extreme and out of touch with the majority of Americans.</p>



<p>The American Medical Association and the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists wrote to me and Vice President Harris stressing that these laws are not based on &#8212; are not based on evidence and asking us to act to protect access to care.&nbsp; They say by limiting access to these medicines, maternal mortality will climb in America.&nbsp; That’s what they say.</p>



<p>Today, I’m directing the Department of Health and Human Services to take steps to ensure that these critical medications are available to the fullest extent possible and that politicians cannot interfere in the decisions that should be made between a woman and her doctor.&nbsp; And my administration will remain vigilant as the implications of this decision play out.</p>



<p>I’ve warned about how this decision risks the broader right to privacy for everyone.&nbsp; That’s because Roe recognized the fundamental right to privacy that has served as the basis for so many more rights that we have come to take &#8212; we’ve come to take for granted that are ingrained in the fabric of this country: the right to make the best decisions for your health; the right to use birth control &#8212; a married couple &#8212; in the privacy of their bedroom, for God’s sake; the right to marry the person you love.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, Justice Thomas said as much today.&nbsp; He explicitly called to reconsider the right of marriage equality, the right of couples to make their choices on contraception.&nbsp; This is an extreme and dangerous path the Court is now taking us on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me close with two points.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, I call on everyone, no matter how deeply they care about this decision, to keep all protests peaceful.&nbsp; Peaceful, peaceful, peaceful.&nbsp; No intimidation.&nbsp; Violence is never acceptable.&nbsp; Threats and intimidation are not speech.&nbsp; We must stand against violence in any form regardless of your rationale.</p>



<p>Second, I know so many of us are frustrated and disillusioned that the Court has taken something away that’s so fundamental.&nbsp; I know so many women are now going to face incredibly difficult situations.&nbsp; I hear you.&nbsp; I support you.&nbsp; I stand with you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The consequences and the consensus of the American people &#8212; core principles of equality, liberty, dignity, and the stability of the rule of law &#8212; demand that Roe should not have been overturned.</p>



<p>With this decision, the conservative majority of the Supreme Court shows how extreme it is, how far removed they are from the majority of this country.&nbsp; They have made the United States an outlier among developed nations in the world.&nbsp; But this decision must not be the final word.</p>



<p>My administration will use all of its appropriate lawful powers.&nbsp; But Congress must act.&nbsp; And with your vote, you can act.&nbsp; You can have the final word.&nbsp; This is not over.</p>



<p>Thank you very much.&nbsp; I’ll have more to say on this in weeks to come.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>12:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Maternal Health Blueprint Delivers for Women, Mothers, and&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/24/fact-sheet-president-bidens-maternal-health-blueprint-delivers-for-women-mothers-and-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 15:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House released the Biden-Harris Administration’s  Blueprint for Addressing the Maternal Health Crisis, a whole-of-government approach to combatting maternal mortality and morbidity. For far too many mothers, complications related to pregnancy, childbirth, and postpartum can lead to devastating health outcomes — including hundreds of deaths each year. This maternal health crisis is particularly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House released the Biden-Harris Administration’s  <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Maternal-Health-Blueprint.pdf">Blueprint for Addressing the Maternal Health Crisis</a>, a whole-of-government approach to combatting maternal mortality and morbidity. For far too many mothers, complications related to pregnancy, childbirth, and postpartum can lead to devastating health outcomes — including hundreds of deaths each year. This maternal health crisis is particularly devastating for Black women, Native women, and women in rural communities who all experience maternal mortality and morbidity at significantly higher rates than their white and urban counterparts.</p>



<p>Under President Biden and Vice President Harris’s leadership, this Administration is now taking the next step towards a future where the United States will be the best country in the world to have a baby. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to cutting the rates of maternal mortality and morbidity, reducing the disparities in maternal health outcomes, and improving the overall experience during and after pregnancy for people across the country. This commitment will require bold, unprecedented action through a whole-of-government strategy.</p>



<p>To start, the Administration is calling on Congress to improve and expand coverage by closing the Medicaid coverage gap and requiring continuous Medicaid coverage for 12 months postpartum, as well as making the significant investments included in the President’s FY23 budget to reduce maternal morbidity and mortality.</p>



<p>The Administration also recognizes that addressing the maternal health crisis in the United States requires immediate action. That is why, in addition to urging Congressional action, the White House has mobilized over a dozen federal agencies to develop the White House Blueprint for Addressing the Maternal Health Crisis. The Blueprint outlines five priorities to improve maternal health and outcomes in the United States:</p>



<p>• Increasing access to and coverage of comprehensive high-quality maternal health services, including behavioral health services.<br>• Ensuring women giving birth are heard and are decisionmakers in accountable systems of care.<br>• Advancing data collection, standardization, harmonization, transparency, and research<br>• Expanding and diversifying the perinatal workforce.<br>• Strengthening economic and social supports for people before, during, and after pregnancy.</p>



<p><strong>For women who are pregnant, postpartum, or hoping to become pregnant, the actions in the Blueprint mean:</strong></p>



<p>• <strong>Extended Postpartum Coverage: </strong>States are encouraged to extend Medicaid coverage from two months to one year postpartum, so that women do not lose or have changes in their coverage during or soon after pregnancy.<br>• <strong>Investments in Rural Maternal Care: </strong>Rural health care facilities will have more staff and capabilities to provide maternal care through increased funding from the expanding the Rural Maternity and Obstetrics Management Strategies Program and more robust training for rural health care providers.<br>• <strong>A Maternal Mental Health Hotline: </strong>Providers will be trained on mental health during pregnancy, and women will have access to a national, confidential, 24-hour, toll-free hotline if they are experiencing mental health challenges.<br>• <strong>Substance Use Services: </strong>Federal agencies will partner with community-based organizations to ensure that addiction services and people trained in substance use disorder during pregnancy are more available.<br>• <strong>No More Surprise Bills: </strong>Through the No Surprises Act, women are now protected from certain unexpected medical bills, which may occur during pregnancy, postpartum care, and/or delivery.<br>• <strong>Better Trained Providers: </strong>More providers will be trained on implicit biases as well as culturally and linguistically appropriate care, so that more women are listened to, respected, and empowered as a decisionmaker in their own care.<br>• <strong>Improved Maternal Health Data: </strong>Through enhanced federal partnerships with state and local maternal health data collection entities, communities, hospitals, and researchers will have access to better data to they can analyze poor outcomes during pregnancy and make improvements to support healthy pregnancies.<br>• <strong>A More Diverse Maternal Care Workforce:</strong> Federal agencies will invest more in hiring, training, and deploying more physicians, certified nurse midwives, doulas, and community health workers to support women during pregnancy, delivery, and postpartum. The federal government will work to ensure these providers come from diverse communities and backgrounds.<br>• <strong>Better Access to Doulas and Midwives: </strong>The Administration will work with states to expand access to doulas and midwives, and encourage insurance companies to cover their services.<br>• <strong>Expanded Social Services: </strong>Stronger partnerships between the Departments of Housing and Urban Development, Agriculture, and Health and Human Services will help make it easier to enroll in federal programs for housing, food, childcare, and income assistance, as we know health care is only one part of what makes for a healthy pregnancy.<br>• <strong>Stronger Workplace Protections for Mothers: </strong>Federal agencies will promote greater awareness of workplace protections and accommodations for new parents, like access to a private lactation room and break time to pump.</p>



<p>The actions outlined in the Blueprint are just the latest in this Administration’s multi-year effort to combat maternal mortality and morbidity. Since taking office, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken significant steps to address the maternal health crisis in the United States, including:</p>



<p>• <strong>Extending Postpartum Medicaid Coverage. </strong>Through the American Rescue Plan, states now have an easier pathway to extend Medicaid coverage from two to twelve months postpartum. Currently, 14 states and the District of Columbia have availed themselves of this opportunity, extending coverage for more than 250,000 women.<br>• <strong>Announcing the New “Birthing Friendly” Hospitals Initiative. </strong>During the December Call to Action, the Vice President announced that, through the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Administration will be deploying a “Birthing Friendly” hospitals designation—the first federal hospital quality designation with a focus on maternal health.<br>• <strong>Hosting the First-Ever Meeting of Cabinet Officials on Maternal Health.</strong> In April of this year, Vice President Harris hosted the first-ever meeting of Cabinet officials to discuss maternal health. This meeting brought together twelve agency leaders including leaders from the Departments of Health and Human Services, Defense, Veterans Affairs, Agriculture, and Housing and Urban Development to discuss ways that this Administration could deploy the resources of the federal government to tackle maternal mortality and morbidity.<br>• <strong>Leading the White House’s First-Ever Maternal Health Day of Action. </strong>In December 2021, the Vice President issued a nationwide Call to Action for federal agencies, businesses, and non-profits to collaboratively solve the maternal health crisis. During that event, the Vice President announced that this Administration had secured millions of dollars in private sector commitments aimed at improving maternal health.</p>



<p>As we continue taking bold action to confront the maternal mortality and morbidity crisis, we will continue to listen to people who are pregnant and new mothers and ensure their feedback informs our approach to improve maternal health and strengthen our health care system. With the support of all parts of government and society, we can make this vision a reality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the Surfside Remembrance&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/24/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-surfside-remembrance-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 14:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Surfside, Florida Good morning. Hidden in crowds—scattered throughout workplaces, and grocery stores, and parks—there is a fellowship of loss.  To the uninitiated, we look normal, average, whole. But like a secret handshake, I can spot them—by the sadness that rests at the corner of their smile. By the curve of their shoulders, as if they can still feel the small arms of a child&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Surfside, Florida</p>



<p>Good morning. Hidden in crowds—scattered throughout workplaces, and grocery stores, and parks—there is a fellowship of loss. <br><br>To the uninitiated, we look normal, average, whole. But like a secret handshake, I can spot them—by the sadness that rests at the corner of their smile. By the curve of their shoulders, as if they can still feel the small arms of a child wrapping around their neck. <br><br>And though we are strangers, we know untellable truths about one another: That we will spend the rest of our lives longing for a face that’s gone forever—and that when they left our world, they took a light inside of us with them. <br><br>There are some who might say that the hurt fades over time. But we know that’s not true. There is a collapsed star spinning inside of us, and we will forever live in its gravity. <br><br>The things we carry are heavier now. And one year later—or many years later—our knees sometimes buckle beneath the weight of our grief. <br><br>Still, we have discovered moments of grace too. Somehow, and against all odds, we rise from the floor. We find a fortitude that we didn’t know we had—and we reach out for help. We realize that we’re not alone. <br><br>Today, we gather to remember the 98 people lost. <br><br>On behalf of my husband, President Biden, whose heart and prayers have never left this community, we stand with you today and always. And as we gather, we express gratitude for this community: <br><br>The fire fighters and other first responders who bound up wounds and spent weeks working to recover your loved ones.<br><br>The members of Surfside who came together to embrace you—who prayed for you every night, and wrapped their arms around you.<br><br>The Americans from across our country who donated and found ways to spread kindness.<br><br>We honor the light you found in each other—a fellowship you never wanted to be a part of, but draw strength from just the same. <br><br>If there is something strong enough to help us carry the burden of grief forward—something able to break its gravitational pull—it’s love. <br><br>The love that makes us tell that story one more time, that makes us laugh with tears in our eyes, and knows a part of them is still inside of us, even though they left before we were done needing them. <br><br>The love of the friends and family who refuse to leave us alone, who remind us that joy can be found even in sorrow. <br><br>The love of a community that lifts us when we’re weak—that carries us. <br><br>Take it one breath at a time. We are praying for you and grieving with you. <br><br>God bless you. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"> ###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Senate Passage of Bipartisan Gun&#160;Legislation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-senate-passage-of-bipartisan-gun-legislation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 02:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tonight, after 28 years of inaction, bipartisan members of Congress came together to heed the call of families across the country and passed legislation to address the scourge of gun violence in our communities. Families in Uvalde and Buffalo &#8211; and too many tragic shootings before &#8211; have demanded action. &#160;And tonight, we acted. This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Tonight, after 28 years of inaction, bipartisan members of Congress came together to heed the call of families across the country and passed legislation to address the scourge of gun violence in our communities. Families in Uvalde and Buffalo &#8211; and too many tragic shootings before &#8211; have demanded action. &nbsp;And tonight, we acted.</p>



<p>This bipartisan legislation will help protect Americans. Kids in schools and communities will be safer because of it. The House of Representatives should promptly vote on this bipartisan bill and send it to my desk.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/23/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 02:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section&nbsp;506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $450 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at a Cancer Moonshot Event in&#160;Florida</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/23/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-a-cancer-moonshot-event-in-florida/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56196</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[West Palm Beach, Florida Thank you,&#160;Liliana. No one should have to fight so hard just to get the treatments they need. No one should have to lose so much to save their own life. We’ve made incredible progress to get people care—but your work ensures women don’t have to face this alone. Thank you.  Nancy, you’ve&#160;changed&#160;lives and you’ve&#160;saved&#160;them.&#160;And&#160;I’m so grateful for your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">West Palm Beach, Florida</p>



<p><br>Thank you,&nbsp;Liliana.</p>



<p>No one should have to fight so hard just to get the treatments they need. No one should have to lose so much to save their own life.</p>



<p>We’ve made incredible progress to get people care—but your work ensures women don’t have to face this alone. Thank you. </p>



<p>Nancy, you’ve&nbsp;changed&nbsp;lives and you’ve&nbsp;saved&nbsp;them.&nbsp;And&nbsp;I’m so grateful for your partnership and friendship.&nbsp;It’s wonderful&nbsp;to learn more about the Promise&nbsp;Fund of Florida&nbsp;program.</p>



<p>Deputy Secretary Palm, thank you for your leadership at HHS.</p>



<p>And Representative Frankel—and all the elected officials with us today—we’re so glad to have you here. </p>



<p>Certain words have the power to make time stop.&nbsp;Malignant.&nbsp;Aggressive.&nbsp;Terminal.&nbsp;Cancer.</p>



<p>Like a spell,&nbsp;they&nbsp;still&nbsp;the air around us—frozen in place,&nbsp;we feel&nbsp;the&nbsp;world&nbsp;we knew slipping&nbsp;away.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when the&nbsp;hands of the&nbsp;clock&nbsp;begin to move once again,&nbsp;we are not the person we once were,&nbsp;but someone&nbsp;changed:</p>



<p>A mother imagining all of the things she might not be there to teach her daughters.</p>



<p>A husband wondering how he will&nbsp;juggle chemotherapy appointments with work and child care.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A&nbsp;son trying to be strong for the parents who&nbsp;could&nbsp;outlive him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Cancer&nbsp;changes&nbsp;everyone it touches.&nbsp;And in some ways,&nbsp;it&nbsp;touches us all.</p>



<p>Like Nancy, I&nbsp;was drawn to this work because I lost someone to breast cancer&nbsp;almost thirty years ago—a&nbsp;dear friend&nbsp;named Winnie.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in the decades since, I’ve met countless families who have faced this loss. </p>



<p>Before they say a word, I know exactly what they’ve been through—the ache of sitting bedside and watching someone you love seem to fade away, the shattering devastation of having your prayers go unanswered.</p>



<p>Or I see those who have walked through the fire and come out on the other side. </p>



<p>It’s subtle—the way they carry their shoulders, the lift of a chin—but it’s there: the hard-won strength of a survivor.  </p>



<p>They don’t come from one state or area.&nbsp;This disease doesn’t care who you vote for.</p>



<p>It’s not a red or blue issue.&nbsp;It’s an&nbsp;American&nbsp;issue.&nbsp;It’s a global issue.&nbsp;And it will take&nbsp;all of us&nbsp;to end cancer as we know it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have to bring to the table the brightest minds and fiercest hearts&nbsp;to learn,&nbsp;and collaborate,&nbsp;and discover&nbsp;together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why Joe and I reignited the Cancer Moonshot—and why it’s a key pillar of his Unity Agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have an ambitious goal to reduce the death rate&nbsp;from cancer by at least half over the next 25 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re making sure that all Americans—no matter their background—have equal access to cancer diagnostics,&nbsp;therapeutics,&nbsp;clinical trials.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve created a cancer cabinet to bring our entire&nbsp;government together around this cause.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’re investing in the newest treatments and therapies.</p>



<p>While those who are touched by cancer come from all walks of life,&nbsp;they often share a similar story.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Survivors&nbsp;tell me&nbsp;that&nbsp;they wish they had found their diagnosis sooner.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Families say how difficult it can be to understand&nbsp;treatment plans or advocate for their loved ones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And those are the issues where I’m focusing my efforts:&nbsp;increasing&nbsp;early detection and screenings,&nbsp;and&nbsp;improving the&nbsp;patient,&nbsp;family,&nbsp;and caregiver&nbsp;experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the last year and a half,&nbsp;I’ve traveled across the country—and even the world—to learn about innovative programs and partnerships that are making progress in these areas.&nbsp;And there is so much hope to be found.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Promise Fund is&nbsp;an incredible&nbsp;example&nbsp;of that hope.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We just came from&nbsp;FoundCare—a clinic up the road.&nbsp;With&nbsp;the Promise Fund’s help, they have&nbsp;made mammograms not only affordable and accessible,&nbsp;but easy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as Nancy said,&nbsp;so many other clinics in this area are&nbsp;finding new ways to serve women,&nbsp;thanks to the Promise Fund’s help.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, Nancy, you’ve been a pioneer in this field for decades. </p>



<p>But one of the things I admire most about you is how you listen to women and adapt your strategy. </p>



<p>You saw a need here—where women weren’t able to get care because they struggled to find child care or transportation. </p>



<p>And you found a way to meet that need. So thank you once again for your leadership. </p>



<p>And thank you to all of the patient navigators who do that critical work. </p>



<p>Because of all of you, patients and their families know that they don’t have to do this alone. </p>



<p>Yes, cancer&nbsp;has the power to&nbsp;change us.&nbsp;But it connects us as well.&nbsp;It forces us to reach out—for answers,&nbsp;for help,&nbsp;for healing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It tears away the things that divide us—reminding us that we need to fight this disease,&nbsp;not each other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It inspires us to come together and find the common ground on which our future can be built.</p>



<p>For Joe and me,&nbsp;this is the mission of our lives.&nbsp;And we are ready and proud to work beside you.</p>



<p>And now, I’d like to ask Nancy and our patient navigators to come join us on stage.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris’s Meeting with State Attorneys General on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-state-attorneys-general-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened Attorneys General from seven states to discuss the fight for reproductive rights. The roundtable followed recent meetings about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with health care providers, faith leaders, and constitutional law, privacy, and technology experts, and was part of the Administration’s work to build coalitions and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened Attorneys General from seven states to discuss the fight for reproductive rights. The roundtable followed recent meetings about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with health care providers, faith leaders, and constitutional law, privacy, and technology experts, and was part of the Administration’s work to build coalitions and preparedness in response to the attack on reproductive rights.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Vice President told the Attorneys General that they play a pivotal role in defending a woman’s right to make decisions about her own body. She spoke about how Attorneys General have a role in protecting the health, safety, and wellbeing of the women in their state — and as a result, can consider the various authorities they have to defend reproductive rights and freedoms, including access to abortion. The officials shared the steps they have taken so far to protect access to reproductive health care in their states, and they discussed their powers under their authority as their state’s chief legal officers.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Vice President thanked the Attorneys General for their leadership in safeguarding our nation’s most fundamental rights and freedoms. She encouraged them to continue striving for new ways to protect reproductive rights.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Participants:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Attorney General Josh Kaul (Wisconsin)</li><li>Attorney General Aaron Ford (Nevada)</li><li>Attorney General Kwame Raoul (Illinois)</li><li>Chief Deputy Attorney General Venus Johnson (California)</li><li>Attorney General Kathleen Jennings (Delaware) (virtual)</li><li>Attorney General Letitia James (New York) (virtual)</li><li>Attorney General Bob Ferguson (Washington state) (virtual)</li><li>Julie Chavez Rodriguez, Director of White House Office of Intergovernmental Affairs</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
