<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 03:41:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Vice President Harris Announces Commitments to Strengthen U.S. Partnership with the Pacific&#160;Islands</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-commitments-to-strengthen-u-s-partnership-with-the-pacific-islands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 12, Vice President Harris will participate virtually in the Pacific Islands Forum leaders’ meeting at the invitation of the Forum Chair Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama of Fiji. As part of this engagement with Forum leaders, the Vice President will announce new commitments to deepen U.S. partnership with the region and to deliver concrete&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 12, Vice President Harris will participate virtually in the Pacific Islands Forum leaders’ meeting at the invitation of the Forum Chair Prime Minister Frank Bainimarama of Fiji. As part of this engagement with Forum leaders, the Vice President will announce new commitments to deepen U.S. partnership with the region and to deliver concrete results for Pacific people. These actions advance the Biden-Harris Administration’s ongoing efforts to strengthen the U.S.-Pacific Islands partnership and to support Pacific regionalism, with a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum at the center.<br>&nbsp;<br>This milestone reflects the United States’ robust and growing commitment to the Pacific Islands region. It follows President Biden’s appointment of a Special Presidential Envoy for Compact Negotiations and the launch of the Partners in the Blue Pacific, a new coordination initiative among the United States, Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the United Kingdom to support Pacific priorities more effectively. It also builds on five decades of close cooperation with the Pacific Islands Forum, including as a founding Dialogue Partner; $350 million in annual U.S. assistance to the Pacific; and deep people-to-people ties, including among the 1.4 million Pacific Islanders who live across the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>With this foundation, the Vice President is announcing the following actions. The Biden-Harris Administration will:<br>&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Establish New U.S. Embassies in Kiribati and Tonga:</strong> The Biden-Harris Administration recognizes that our close partnership with the Pacific requires regular exchange between our governments at all levels, from our leaders to our diplomats around the world. To that end, the United States, subject to congressional notification, will commence discussions with Kiribati and Tonga about our interest in establishing U.S. embassies in those countries. The United States is on track to reopen its embassy in Solomon Islands.</li><li><strong>Triple Request for U.S. Funding for Economic Development and Ocean Resilience: </strong>For 33 years, the South Pacific Tuna Treaty has served as a cornerstone of political and economic cooperation between the United States and Pacific Islands, enabling U.S. fishing-fleet access to the Pacific, supporting livelihoods across the region, and providing a platform for broader cooperation, including to combat the scourge of illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing. Vice President Harris will announce that the United States is prepared to request from the U.S. Congress $60 million per year for the next ten years—nearly triple the current levels and $600 million in total—in connection with a new Economic Assistance Agreement with the Forum Fisheries Agency.</li><li><strong>Appoint the First-Ever U.S. Envoy to the Pacific Islands Forum:</strong> A resilient and prosperous Pacific Islands region requires a strong and united Pacific Islands Forum—the preeminent driver of action in the region. The Biden-Harris Administration will redouble our commitment to the Pacific Islands Forum by appointing, for the first time, a designated U.S. Pacific Islands Forum Envoy. In doing so, the United States will further increase our overall diplomatic footprint across the Pacific Islands.</li><li><strong>Design and Release the First-Ever U.S. National Strategy on the Pacific Islands</strong>: The Biden-Harris Administration will craft and publish the first-ever U.S. strategy on the Pacific Islands—a whole-of-government strategy to prioritize the Pacific Islands in American foreign policy and drive effective implementation. It will be nested under the Indo-Pacific Strategy of the United States, which the Biden-Harris Administration released earlier this year in Fiji. The U.S. National Strategy on the Pacific Islands will align with the goals, areas of focus, and principles of the Pacific Islands Forum’s 2050 Strategy for the Blue Pacific Continent.</li><li><strong>Bring the Peace Corps Back to the Pacific: </strong>The longevity of our ties with the Pacific Islands depends on close people-to-people relationships. Peace Corps volunteers will soon return to Fiji, Tonga, Samoa, and Vanuatu, and the Peace Corps will work with the region to explore program expansion to additional Pacific Island countries.</li><li><strong>Progress Toward&nbsp;Re-establishing&nbsp;a United States Agency for International Development&nbsp;(USAID) Regional&nbsp;Mission&nbsp;for the Pacific in Suva, Fiji:&nbsp;</strong>USAID provides life-saving&nbsp;humanitarian and development assistance&nbsp;across the Pacific Islands, from Kiribati in the wake of drought to Tonga in the wake of volcanic eruptions and tsunami waves&nbsp;to economic assistance in Papua New Guinea and Solomon Islands. The Vice President will announce that USAID&nbsp;is taking steps to&nbsp;expand&nbsp;its&nbsp;presence in the&nbsp;Pacific, subject to congressional notification,&nbsp;to&nbsp;improve&nbsp;close cooperation with its host country partners.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Implement and Advance the Partners in the Blue Pacific</strong>: Emerging challenges, from the climate crisis to infrastructure needs, require cooperation across borders. To that end, the United States and its allies and partners—Australia, Japan, New Zealand, and the United Kingdom—established a new coordination mechanism, the Partners in the Blue Pacific (PBP). The PBP is dedicated to supporting Pacific priorities more effectively and efficiently, to bolstering Pacific regionalism, and to expanding opportunities between the Pacific and the world. Our countries provide a combined $2.1 billion in development assistance for the region, and we will seek to drive additional focus and resources by welcoming further members and observers, including in Europe and the Indo-Pacific. Above all, at every stage, the PBP will be led and guided by the Pacific Islands, including close consultations on its flagship projects. </li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Cyber Director Chris Inglis’s Travel to Israel and&#160;Europe</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/12/readout-of-national-cyber-director-chris-ingliss-travel-to-israel-and-europe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From June 26 to July 5, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis traveled to Israel, the Netherlands, and the United Kingdom to meet with government officials, private sector executives, and academic thought leaders to discuss efforts to promote the security of our common digital ecosystem and the integrity of our hardware and software supply chains. Director&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>From June 26 to July 5, National Cyber Director Chris Inglis traveled to Israel, the Netherlands, and the United Kingdom to meet with government officials, private sector executives, and academic thought leaders to discuss efforts to promote the security of our common digital ecosystem and the integrity of our hardware and software supply chains.</p>



<p>Director Inglis met with officials from the Governments of Israel, the Netherlands, and the United Kingdom to share lessons learned on enhancing national cybersecurity, growing the cyber talent pool, and ensuring the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure. He also solicited feedback on themes of the Biden-Harris Administration’s forthcoming National Cybersecurity Strategy. Director Inglis met with leaders from the private sector to discuss the Biden-Harris Administration’s priorities for public-private cyber collaboration and the vital role that the private sector plays in protecting national and international cybersecurity. Director Inglis met with educators and academic leaders to discuss efforts to promote the digital literacy and cybersecurity awareness of our citizens and expand the cyber talent pipeline.</p>



<p>Director Inglis’s visit served to strengthen and reinforce partnerships necessary to ensure a secure and resilient international cyber ecosystem that reflects democratic values, safeguards our individual and collective security, and supports U.S. interests abroad.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris in a Briefing to Preview the First Images from the James Webb Space&#160;Telescope</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-in-a-briefing-to-preview-the-first-images-from-the-james-webb-space-telescope/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57151</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 6:13 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Well, good evening, everyone.&#160; I am very honored to be with you all.&#160; President Joe Biden and I talk often about our mutual passion for everything you all do.&#160; This is a very exciting moment to join you for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>6:13 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Well, good evening, everyone.&nbsp; I am very honored to be with you all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Joe Biden and I talk often about our mutual passion for everything you all do.&nbsp; This is a very exciting moment to join you for the unveiling of the work that you have been laboring on for decades.</p>



<p>So, to our President, Joe Biden, thank you for your leadership around all of these issues.&nbsp; Our NASA Administrator, Bill Nelson, and the Office of Science and Technology Policy Acting Director, Dr. Alondra Nelson.</p>



<p>Thank you also to our colleagues from across the White House and NASA and everyone else joining us from home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, yes, as Chair of the National Space Council, I know that today represents an exciting new chapter in the exploration of our universe.&nbsp; From the beginning of history, humans have looked up to the night sky with wonder.&nbsp; And thanks to dedicated people who have been working for decades in engineering and on scientific marvels, we can look to the sky with new understanding.</p>



<p>When NASA launched the Hubble Space Telescope in 1990, we were able to see the stars unobstructed by the Earth&#8217;s atmosphere and understand the universe in ways we could have never imagined even a few decades earlier.</p>



<p>And now we enter a new phase of scientific discovery.&nbsp; Building on the legacy of Hubble, the James Webb Space Telescope allows us to see deeper into space than ever before and in stunning clarity.&nbsp; It will enhance what we know about the origins of our universe, our solar system, and possibly life itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This was made possible by partnership among nations.&nbsp; And it is an example of how the scientific endeavor can build upon the international rules and norms that govern our cooperation in space.</p>



<p>This telescope is one of humanity&#8217;s great engineering achievements.&nbsp; And the images we will see today are a testament to the amazing work done by the thousands of workers across our nation who dedicated years to this project.&nbsp; They embarked on this complex endeavor for the benefit of humankind, and in the process, accelerated American innovation, strengthened partnerships with our allies, and will undoubtedly inspire generations to look to the heavens with excitement and ambition.</p>



<p>With that, it is my great honor to introduce a leader who has always believed in the power of American innovation and international cooperation to achieve the remarkable: our President, the President of the United States, Joe Biden.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s great to be with you all.&nbsp; And I was going to say “good afternoon,” but we&#8217;re starting this meeting late because I was engaged in preparing for a trip to the Middle East.</p>



<p>But today is a historic day.&nbsp; And thank you, Vice President Harris, Chair of the National Space Council.&nbsp; And thank you, my dear friend and our outstanding NASA Administrator and the guy&nbsp;&#8212; the only guy here who’s been in space, Bill Nelson.&nbsp; Bill, you&#8217;re a good friend.&nbsp; Thank you very much for what you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and, Dr. Nelson, you&#8217;re doing a great job leading this Office of Science and Technology Policy.&nbsp; It really is a matter &#8212; it really is amazing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Six and a half months ago, a rocket launched from Earth carrying the world’s newest, most powerful deep-space telescope on a journey one million miles into the cosmos &#8212; first of all, that blows my mind: a million miles into the cosmos &#8212; along the way unfolding itself<a>, deploying a mirror 21 feet wide, a sunshield the size of a tennis court, and 250,000 tiny shutters</a>, each one smaller than a grain of sand.</p>



<p>Put together, it’s a new window into the history of our universe.</p>



<p>And today, we’re going to get a glimpse of the first light to shine through that window &#8212; light from other worlds, orbiting stars far beyond our own.&nbsp; It’s astounding to me when I read this and saw the &#8212; I mean, it really is.&nbsp; It’s &#8212; it’s &#8212; anyway, I don’t want to &#8212; I’ll see what they think when we see this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But light where stars were born and from where they die.&nbsp; Light from the oldest galaxies.&nbsp; The oldest documented light in the history of the universe from over 13 billion &#8212; let me say that again: 13 billion years ago.&nbsp; It’s hard to even fathom.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, when this image is shared with the world, it will be a historic moment for science and technology, for astronomy and space exploration, for America and all of humanity.</p>



<p>You know, as an international collaboration, this telescope embodies how America leads the world not by the example of our power, but the power of our example.&nbsp; A partnership with others, it symbolizes the relentless spirit of American ingenuity.&nbsp;&nbsp; And it shows what we can achieve, what more we can discover, not just about distant places, but about our very own planet and climate, like NASA’s Earth System Observatory that we launched last year.</p>



<p>That’s why the federal government must invest &#8212; must invest in science and technology, more than we have in the past.</p>



<p>These images are going to remind the world that America can do big things.&nbsp;&nbsp;And they’ll remind the American people, especially our children, that there’s nothing beyond our capacity &#8212; nothing beyond our capacity.</p>



<p>We can see possibilities no one has ever seen before.&nbsp; We can go places no one has ever gone before.&nbsp; You know, you’ve &#8212; you’ve heard me say it over and over again.&nbsp; America is defined by one single word: possibilities.&nbsp; Possibilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank the team at NASA for once again showing that that’s who we are &#8212; that’s who we are as a nation: a nation of possibilities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now let&#8217;s take a look at the very first image from this miraculous telescope.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(The image is displayed.)&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>NASA Administrator Nelson, I&#8217;m going to turn this over to you.&nbsp; So will you please tell us about what we’re seeing?</p>



<p>ADMINISTRATOR NELSON:&nbsp; Mr. President, if you held a grain of sand on the tip of your finger at arm&#8217;s length, that is the part of the universe that you&#8217;re seeing &#8212; just one little speck of the universe.&nbsp; And what you&#8217;re seeing there are galaxies.&nbsp; You&#8217;re seeing galaxies that are shining around other galaxies whose light has been bent.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re seeing just a small little portion of the universe.<br><br>You know, 100 years ago, Mr. President, Madam Vice President &#8212; 100 years ago, we thought there was only one galaxy.&nbsp; Now, the number is unlimited.&nbsp; And in our galaxy, we have billions of stars, or suns.&nbsp; And there are billions of galaxies with billions of stars and suns.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re getting our first glimpse.<br><br>As you said, Mr. President, we&#8217;re looking back more than 13 billion years.&nbsp; Light travels at 186,000 miles per second.&nbsp; And that light that you are seeing on one of those little specks has been traveling for over 13 billion years.<br><br>And, by the way, we&#8217;re going back further, because this is just the first image.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going back about 13.5 billion years.&nbsp; And since we know the universe is 13.8 billion years old, we&#8217;re going back almost to the beginning.<br><br>That is the discovery that we are making with this.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s another thing that you&#8217;re going to find with this telescope: It is going to be so precise, you&#8217;re going to see whether or not planets, because of the chemical composition that we can determine with this telescope of their atmosphere, if those planets are habitable.<br><br>And when you look at something as big as this is, we are going to be able to answer questions that we don&#8217;t even know what the questions are yet.<br><br>This is what&#8217;s happening, and it&#8217;s because of this wonderful team that&#8217;s out here, part of that team led by Thomas Zurbuchen.&nbsp; It was in trouble financially five years ago.&nbsp; He took it over.&nbsp; He got Greg Robinson, that you&#8217;re going to meet, to direct it.&nbsp; And the result is what you&#8217;ve seen.<br><br>So, what an incredible team &#8212; joined, by the way, with our international partners, the European Space Agency and the Canadian Space Agency.&nbsp; So this is an international endeavor.</p>



<p><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It&#8217;s amazing.&nbsp; I wonder what the press is like in those other places.</p>



<p>6:23 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate, on the Continuation of  the National Emergency with Respect to Hong&#160;Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-hong-kong-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 23:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#160;emergency is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&nbsp;emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to Hong Kong that was&nbsp;declared in Executive Order 13936 of July 14, 2020, is to&nbsp;continue&nbsp;in&nbsp;effect beyond July 14, 2022.</p>



<p>The situation with respect to Hong Kong, including recent actions taken by the People&#8217;s Republic of China to fundamentally undermine Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat, which has its source in substantial part outside the United States, to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13936 with respect to the&nbsp;situation in Hong Kong.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Hong&#160;Kong</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/11/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-hong-kong-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 23:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57140</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 14, 2020, by Executive Order 13936, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&#160;States constituted by the situation with respect to Hong Kong. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 14, 2020, by Executive Order 13936, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States constituted by the situation with respect to Hong Kong.</p>



<p>The situation with respect to Hong Kong, including recent actions taken by the People&#8217;s Republic of China to fundamentally undermine Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on July 14, 2020, must continue in effect beyond July 14, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section&nbsp;202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13936 with respect to the situation in Hong Kong.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 11, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at an Event Commemorating the Passage of the Safer Communities&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/11/remarks-by-president-biden-at-an-event-commemorating-the-passage-of-the-safer-communities-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 23:07:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 11:17 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; Doc, thank you.&#160; Your heroism in treating the wounded children in Uvalde, many of whom you’ve known their whole lives &#8212; their whole lives &#8212; and treated them with normal child problems as a pediatrician, it’s something we’ll never forget. And, Garnell, it’s good to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>11:17 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Doc, thank you.&nbsp; Your heroism in treating the wounded children in Uvalde, many of whom you’ve known their whole lives &#8212; their whole lives &#8212; and treated them with normal child problems as a pediatrician, it’s something we’ll never forget.</p>



<p>And, Garnell, it’s good to see you again.&nbsp; I know how tough it is.&nbsp; A lot of people in here have been victims of gun violence &#8212; lost sons, daughters, husbands, wives.&nbsp; They understand your pain.&nbsp; And every time you stand up to talk about it, even for a good cause, it brings it all back like it happened yesterday.&nbsp; But thank you for the courage to do it.</p>



<p>Jill and I will never forget the time we spent with you and your families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank &#8212; thank the Vice President Harris and the Second Gentleman; and members of the Cabinet, eight of whom are here today; as well as mayors and elected officials from across the country.</p>



<p>I want to particularly thank the Governor of Illinois and the Mayor of Highland Park for being here.&nbsp; We’ve had &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; We had a number of conversations immediately after the attack in Highland Park.&nbsp; And I’ve been impressed with the way they’ve handled things.&nbsp; It’s been extraordinary.&nbsp; And as the three of us have discussed, we have more to do.</p>



<p>I also want to thank the bipartisan group of senators who worked so hard to get this done, especially Senators Murphy &#8212; (applause); Sinema &#8212; (applause); Cornyn and Tillis.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I hope it doesn’t get you in trouble mentioning your name.&nbsp; Thank you for the courage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As well as all of the members of Congress who have worked on these issues for a long time, 80 of whom are with us today.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’m sorry Senators Schumer and Blumenthal can’t be here today, but they’re working from home, overcoming mild cases of COVID.</p>



<p>I know how hard it is to get things done because I know how hard it was to write the first gun legislation &#8212; at least the first from my career &#8212; that was passed nearly 30 years ago.&nbsp; That’s how long ago it was.</p>



<p>And as I look out in this crowd, I see so many advocates and families, many of whom have become friends, whose lives have been shattered by gun violence and who have made it their purpose to save other lives.</p>



<p>I’ve spent so much time with so many of you over the years that we’ve actually become personal friends.&nbsp; And I can’t thank you enough for your willingness to continue to fight for other families.</p>



<p>Nothing can bring back your loved ones, but you did it to make sure that other families don’t have to experience the same loss and pain that you’ve experienced.</p>



<p>And you have felt and you feel the price of inaction, that this has taken too long, with too much of a trail of bloodshed and carnage.&nbsp; And I know public policy can seem remote, technical, and distant from our everyday lives.&nbsp; But because of your work, your advocacy, your courage, lives will be saved today and tomorrow because of this.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>What we are doing here today is real, it’s vivid, it’s relevant.&nbsp; The action we take today is a step designed to make our nation the kind of nation we should be.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about the most fundamental of things &#8212; the lives of our children, of our loved ones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We face, literally, a moral choice in this country &#8212; a moral choice with profound, real-world implications.</p>



<p>Will we take wise steps to fulfill the responsibility to protect the innocent and while keeping faith with constitutional rights?</p>



<p>Will we match thoughts and prayers with action?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I say yes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And that’s what we’re doing here today.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Today is many things.  It’s proof that despite the naysayers, we can make meaningful progress on dealing with gun violence.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We have to do more than that!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because make no mistake &#8212; sit down.&nbsp; You’ll hear what I have to say if you think &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We have to do more than that!&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We have to open an office in the White House.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; I’ve been trying to tell you this for years.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; President Biden!&nbsp; Yeah!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have one.&nbsp; Let me finish my comments.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let him talk.&nbsp; Let him talk.&nbsp; No one &#8212; okay?</p>



<p>Because make no mistake about it: This legislation is real progress, but more has to be done.&nbsp; The provision of this new legislation is going to save lives.&nbsp; And it’s proof that in today’s politics we can come together on a bipartisan basi- &#8212; basis to get important things done, even on an issue as tough as guns.</p>



<p>And one more thing: It’s a call to action to all of us to do more &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to take away from the legislation, it is not &#8212; that’s not what we can do.&nbsp; It’s to take the &#8212; the take-away from this is that now &#8212; now we’re opening to get much more done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Senator Murphy has said: When you look at the biggest social issues America has faced throughout our history, quote, “Success begets success.”&nbsp; And that’s when you, quote, “finally move that mountain.”&nbsp; You can &#8212; you can ignite a movement when you do that for more progress to follow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have finally moved that mountain &#8212; a mountain of opposition, obstruction, and indifference that has stood in the way and stopped every effort at gun safety for 30 years in this nation.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And now is the time to galvanize this movement, because that’s our duty to the people of this nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s what we owe those families in Buffalo, where a grocery store became a killing field.</p>



<p>It’s what we owe those families in Uvalde, where an elementary school became a killing field.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s what we owe those families in Highland Park, where, on July 4th, a parade became a killing field.</p>



<p>And that’s what we owe all those families represented here today and all over this country the past many years, across our schools, places of worship, workplaces, stores, music festivals, nightclubs, and so many other everyday places that have turned into killing fields.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we owe the families all across this nation where, every day, tragic killings that don&#8217;t make the headlines are more than passing mention &#8212; a little more than passing mention in the local news.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Neighborhoods and streets have been turned into killing fields as well.</p>



<p>Today&#8217;s legislation is an important start.&nbsp; And here are the key things that it does: It provides $750 million in crisis intervention and red-flag laws so the parent, a teacher, a counselor can flag for the court that a child, a student, a patient is exhibiting violent tendencies, threatening classmates, or experiencing suicidal thoughts that makes them a danger to themselves and to others.</p>



<p>Fort Hood, Texas, 2009: 13 dead, 30 more injured.</p>



<p>Marjorie Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida, 1918 [2018]: 17 dead, 17 injured.</p>



<p>In both places, countless others suffering with invisible wounds.</p>



<p>In both places, red-flag laws could have stopped both those shooters.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You know, this new law requiring &#8212; requires young people under 21 to [under]go enhanced background checks before purchasing a gun.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How many more mass shootings do we have to see where a shooter is 17, 18 years old and able to get his hands on a weapon and go on a killing spree?</p>



<p>You know, it closes the so-called “boyfriend loophole.”&nbsp; If you’re convicted of assault against your girlfriend or boy- &#8212; you can’t buy a gun.&nbsp; You can&#8217;t do it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>According to a recent study, in over 50 percent of mass shootings, the shooter shot a family member or a partner.</p>



<p>So if we keep guns out of the hands of domestic abusers, we can save the lives of their partners, and we can also stop more mass shootings.</p>



<p>One, this law includes the first-ever federal law that makes gun trafficking and straw purchases explicit federal crimes.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>It clarifies who needs to register as a federally licensed gun dealer and run background checks before selling a single weapon.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>It invests in anti-violence programs that work directly</p>



<p>with the communities most at risk for gun crimes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this law also provides funding vital for funding to address the youth mental health crisis in this country &#8212; (applause) &#8212; including the trauma experienced by the survivors of gun violence.</p>



<p>It will not save every life from the epidemic of gun violence, but if this law had been in place years ago, even this last year, lives would have been saved.</p>



<p>It matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; But it’s not enough, and we all know that.</p>



<p>In preparation for today’s signing, I asked to send me their story &#8212; people to send me their stories about their experience with gun violence.&nbsp; I received over 2,500 responses in 24 hours.&nbsp; I didn’t get to read them all, but I read some.</p>



<p>A 17-year-old wrote me saying, quote, “A school shooting sophomore year shattered every sense of normalcy I&#8217;ve ever felt.&nbsp; Almost three years later, I still have nightmares.”</p>



<p>A 24-year-old wrote about growing up in what was a, quote, “seemingly endless era of gun violence.”</p>



<p>A 40-year-old wrote me about two friends shot and killed by abusive partners and former partners.</p>



<p>Someone else wrote me about a 6-year-old child who was sitting near his father’s coffin, was asking, quote, “Why is Daddy in that scary box? &nbsp;Wake up, Daddy.&nbsp; Wake up Daddy.”&nbsp; His father had been gunned down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I read these stories and so many others.&nbsp; So many others.&nbsp; And, you know, I see the statistics.&nbsp; Over 40,000 people died from gunshot wounds last year in the United States, 25,000 by suicide.</p>



<p>I think: Can this really be the United States of America?&nbsp; Why has it come to this?&nbsp; We all know a lot of the reasons: gun lobby, gun manufacturers, special interest money, the rise of hyper-partisan tribal politics in the country where we don’t debate the issues on the merits and we just rather turn on each other from our corners and attack the other side.</p>



<p>Regardless, we’re living in a country awash in weapons of war &#8212; weapons that weren’t designed to hunt are not being used &#8212; the weapons designed that they&#8217;re purchasing are designed as weapons of war to take out an enemy.</p>



<p>What is the rationale for these weapons outside war zones?&nbsp; Some people claim it’s for sport or to hunt.&nbsp; But let’s look at the facts: The most common rounds fired from an AR-15 move almost twice as fast as that from a handgun.&nbsp; Coupled with smaller, lighter bullets, these weapons maximize the damage done coupled with those bullets, and human flesh and bone is just torn apart.</p>



<p>And as difficult as it is to say, that’s why so many people and some in this audience &#8212; and I apologize for having to say it &#8212; need to provide DNA samples to identify the remains of their children.&nbsp; Think of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s why trauma surgeons who train for years for these moments know it’s unlikely that someone shot with a high-powered assault weapon will make it long enough for the ambulance to get them to the hospital.</p>



<p>It’s why these scenes of destruction are resembling nothing like a weekend hunting trip for deer or elk.</p>



<p>And yet, we continue to let these weapons be sold to people with no training or expertise.</p>



<p>Case in point: America has the finest fighting force in the world.&nbsp; We provide our service members with the most lethal weapons on Earth to protect America.</p>



<p>We also require them to receive significant training before they’re allowed to use these weapons.</p>



<p>We require extensive background checks on them and mental health assessments on them.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>We require that they learn how to lock up and store these weapons responsibly.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>We require our military to do all that.&nbsp; These are commonsense requirements.&nbsp; But we don’t require the same commonsense measures for a stranger walking into a gun store to purchase an AR-15 or some weapon like that.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It makes no sense.&nbsp; Assault weapons need to be banned.&nbsp; They were banned.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I led the fight in 1994.&nbsp; And then, under pressure from the NRA and the gun manufacturers and others, that ban was lifted in 2004.</p>



<p>In that 10 years it was law, mass shootings went down.&nbsp; When the law expired in 2004 and those weapons were allowed to be sold again, mass shootings tripled.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re the facts.&nbsp; I’m determined to ban these weapons again and high-capacity magazines &#8212; (applause) &#8212; that hold 30 rounds and that let mass shooters fire hundreds of bullets in a matter of minutes.&nbsp; I’m not going to stop until we do it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Here’s another thing we should do: We should have safe storage laws, requiring personal liability for not locking up your gun.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The shooter in Sandy Hook came from a home full of guns and assault weapons that were too easy to access &#8212; weapons he used to kill his mother and then murder 26 people, including 20 innocent first graders.</p>



<p>If you own a weapon, you have a responsibility to secure it and keep it under lock and key.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Responsible gun owners agree: No one else should have access to it, so lock it up, have trigger locks.&nbsp; And if you don’t and something bad happens, you should be held responsible.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I have four shotguns; two are mine and two are my deceased son’s.&nbsp; They’re locked up, lock and key.&nbsp; Every responsible gun owner that I know does that.</p>



<p>We should expand background checks to better keep guns out of the hands of felons, fugitives, and those under domestic violence restraining orders.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Expanded background checks are something that the vast majority of Americans, including the majority of gun owners, agree on.</p>



<p>My fellow Americans, none of what I’m talking about infringes on anyone’s Second Amendment rights.</p>



<p>I’ve said it many times: I support the Second Amendment.</p>



<p>But when guns are the number one killer of children in the United States of America &#8212; let me say that again &#8212; guns are the number one killer of children in the United States.&nbsp; More than car accidents.&nbsp; More than cancer. <a>&nbsp;And over the last two decades</a>, more <s>high-school</s> [school-age] children have died from gun shots than on-duty police officers and active-duty military combined.&nbsp; Think of that.&nbsp; Then we can’t just stand by.&nbsp; We can’t let it happen any longer.</p>



<p>With rights come responsibilities.</p>



<p>Yes, there’s a right to bear arms, but we also have the right to live freely &#8212; (applause) &#8212; without fear for our lives in a grocery store, in a classroom, on a playground, at a house of worship, in a store, at a workplace, a nightclub, a festival, in our neighborhoods and our streets.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The right to bear arms is not an absolute right that dominates all others.</p>



<p>The perennial price for living in a community with others is being neighbors, of being fellow citizens, is that we obey the laws and customs that ensure what that Fra- &#8212; what the Framers called “domestic tranquility.”</p>



<p>That’s what civilization is.&nbsp; That’s what we have been at our best.&nbsp; That’s what America must always be: a place where we preserve the rights but fulfill our responsibilities.</p>



<p>I know this: There can be no greater responsibility than to do all we can to ensure the safety of our families, our children, and our fellow Americans.</p>



<p>When I spoke to the nation after Uvalde, I shared how a grandmother who had lost her granddaughter gave me and Jill a handwritten letter.&nbsp; We spent four hours, almost five hours with her.</p>



<p>And I read it.&nbsp; It reads, quote, “Erase the invisible line that is dividing our nation to come up with a solution and fix what is broken and to make the changes that are necessary to prevent this from happening again.”&nbsp; End of quote.</p>



<p>That’s why we’re here.&nbsp; That’s why we’re here.</p>



<p>Today, I want to thank those in Congress, both Democrat and Republicans, who erased that invisible line dividing our nation and moved us forward on gun safety.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s an important step.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And now we must look forward.&nbsp; We have so much more work to do.</p>



<p>And I might add, there is $75 million in there for mental health reasons &#8212; a whole range of other things I’m not going to take time to go into today, but it’s important.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>May God bless all of us with the strength to finish the work left undone and &#8212; on behalf of the lives we’ve lost and the lives we can save.&nbsp;</p>



<p>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>11:36 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Message to the Senate Regarding the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of&#160;Sweden</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/message-to-the-senate-regarding-the-protocols-to-the-north-atlantic-treaty-of-1949-on-the-accession-of-the-republic-of-finland-and-the-kingdom-of-sweden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 21:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To the Senate of the United States: I transmit herewith, for the advice and consent of the Senate to its ratification, the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of Sweden (the &#8220;Protocols&#8221;).&#160; The Protocols were signed in Brussels on July 5, 2022,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>To the Senate of the United States:</p>



<p>I transmit herewith, for the advice and consent of the Senate to its ratification, the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of Sweden (the &#8220;Protocols&#8221;).&nbsp; The Protocols were signed in Brussels on July 5, 2022, on behalf of the United States and the other Parties to the North Atlantic Treaty.&nbsp; Also transmitted for the information of the Senate is an overview of the Protocols by the Department of State.&nbsp; Full ratification of the Protocols will allow Finland and Sweden to become Parties to the North Atlantic Treaty and members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO).</p>



<p>Article 10 of the North Atlantic Treaty, which outlines NATO&#8217;s Open Door policy, is part of the doctrinal foundation of the Alliance.&nbsp; It states that Allies may, by unanimous consent, invite any other European State in a position to further the principles of the Treaty and to contribute to the security of the North Atlantic area to accede.&nbsp; As further explained in the&nbsp;reports on the accession of Finland and Sweden to NATO, transmitted to the Congress on May&nbsp;19 and July 1, 2022, in light of section 3(2)(E) of the Resolution of Advice and Consent to Ratification of the Protocols to the North Atlantic Treaty of 1949 on the Accession of Poland, Hungary, and the Czech Republic of April 30, 1998, Finland and Sweden more than meet these qualifications.&nbsp; They will be net contributors to the Alliance, in both capabilities and resources, and they share critically important values with the United States.&nbsp; Finland&#8217;s and Sweden&#8217;s accession will help further United States priorities within&nbsp;NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I ask the Senate to continue working with my Administration in advancing a strong and free Europe by providing its prompt advice and consent to ratification of the Protocols.&nbsp; We are encouraging all Allies to act expeditiously in their own ratification processes as well, given current global considerations. &nbsp;My Administration stands ready to brief and assist you in your deliberations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 11, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 21:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57130</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Ann Marie Yastishock, of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ann Marie Yastishock, of Pennsylvania, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Solomon Islands and Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Vanuatu.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Manuel P. Micaller, Jr., of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Tajikistan.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kristina A. Kvien, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Armenia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Henry V. Jardine, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Mauritius, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Seychelles.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Diane Susan Kaplan, of Alaska, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for Public Broadcasting for a term expiring January 31, 2026, vice Patricia D. Cahill, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Patrice H. Kunesh, of Minnesota, to be Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, Department of Health and Human Services, vice Jean Carol Hovland.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Milancy Danielle Harris, of Virginia, to be a Deputy Under Secretary of Defense, vice Kari A. Bingen.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jeffrey R. Gural, of New York, to be Chairperson of the Public Buildings Reform Board for a term of six years.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Phillip A. Washington, of Illinois, to be Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration for the term of five years, vice Stephen M. Dickson, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Frances Kay Behm, of Michigan, to be United States District Judge for the Eastern District of Michigan, vice David M. Lawson, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tamika R. Montgomery-Reeves, of Delaware, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Third Circuit, vice Thomas L. Ambro, retiring.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; James A. Diossa, of Rhode Island, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the James Madison Memorial Fellowship Foundation for a term expiring October 3, 2024, vice Harvey M. Tettlebaum, term expired, which was sent to the Senate on July 15, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ed Gonzalez, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security, vice Sarah R. Saldana, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Raymond M. Jefferson, of Hawaii, to be Under Secretary for Benefits of the Department of Veterans Affairs, vice Paul R. Lawrence, which was sent to the Senate on March 21, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden Administration Makes Public First Full-Color Image from Webb Space&#160;Telescope</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/biden-administration-produces-first-full-color-image-from-webb-space-telescope/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden Administration made public the first full-color image from the Webb Space Telescope, which captured the highest-resolution images of the infrared universe in history. The Webb Space Telescope launched from French Guiana in December 2021 and is now orbiting the Sun one million miles away from Earth. The image was previewed to President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden Administration made public the first <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/webbfirstimages">full-color image</a> from the Webb Space Telescope, which captured the highest-resolution images of the infrared universe in history. The Webb Space Telescope launched from French Guiana in December 2021 and is now orbiting the Sun one million miles away from Earth. The image was previewed to President Biden and Vice President Harris during a briefing at the White House by officials from the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), where they discussed how these revolutionary images will enable breakthroughs in nearly every branch of astronomy.</p>



<p>During the briefing, President Biden publicly showed the first of the images: “Webb’s First Deep Field,” the “deepest” and sharpest infrared image of the distant universe ever produced. This image is filled with galaxies, some more than 13 billion years old, which means they formed just after the Big Bang. Over the coming days, NASA will publish additional images, which reveal details about the atmosphere of an exoplanet outside our solar system, “stellar nurseries” where stars form, galaxies that interact and trigger star formation and black holes, and a glimpse into how stars die.</p>



<p>The Webb Space Telescope is an international program led by NASA with its partners,&nbsp;ESA (European Space Agency)&nbsp;and the&nbsp;Canadian Space Agency. Its revolutionary technology will study every phase of cosmic history over the past 13.5 billion years — from inside our solar system to the most distant observable galaxies in the early universe. The telescope gives us the capacity to explore a wide range of questions that help us understand the origins of the universe and our place within it. The telescope is one of humanity’s great engineering feats, launching from Earth on a rocket, and then unfolding itself in space. Thousands of engineers and hundreds of scientists worked to make the telescope a reality, along with over 300 universities, organizations, and companies from 29 U.S. states and 14 countries.</p>



<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris, who chairs the National Space Council, were briefed by NASA Administrator Bill Nelson, Deputy Assistant to the President Dr. Alondra Nelson, who leads the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, Head of NASA Science Thomas Zurbuchen, James Webb Space Telescope Program Director Greg Robinson, Operations Project Scientist Jane Rigby, and Space Telescope Science Institute Deputy Director Nancy Levenson.</p>



<p>The images from the Webb Space Telescope illustrate the great leaps in science and technology discovery that can be made with U.S. government leadership, in partnership with other countries. The Biden-Harris Administration has worked to restore scientific integrity to Federal policy-making and to more broadly and equitably engage and serve Americans around science and technology solutions, including addressing great challenges like pandemics, cancer, and the climate crisis, and ensuring America remains the world leader in technologies and industries of the future that will be critical to our economic prosperity and national security.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/11/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57115</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:  Richard Mills, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Federal Republic of Nigeria Ann Marie Yastishock, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration: <br></p>



<ul><li>Richard Mills, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Federal Republic of Nigeria</li><li>Ann Marie Yastishock, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, the Solomon Islands, and the Republic of Vanuatu</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Richard Mills, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Federal Republic of Nigeria</u></strong><br><br>Richard Mills, Jr., a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the U.S. Deputy Permanent Representative to the United Nations. Previously, he was Deputy Chief of Mission and then Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at the U.S. Mission to Canada. Prior to that, Mills served as U.S. Ambassador to Armenia. He has also served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Beirut, Lebanon and as Deputy Chief of Mission and Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at U.S. Embassy Valetta, Malta. Other assignments include Senior Democracy Advisor at U.S. Embassy Baghdad, Political Counselor at U.S. Embassy London, and Political Officer at the U.S. Mission to the United Nations. Prior to joining the Foreign Service, Mills was an Associate Attorney with the firm of Duncan, Allen and Mitchell in Washington, D.C. A native of Louisiana, Mills earned a B.A. in Foreign Service from Georgetown University, a J.D. from the University of Texas School of Law and a M.S. in National Security Policy from the National Defense University. He is the recipient of multiple State Department awards and speaks French and Russian.<br><br><strong><u>Ann Marie Yastishock, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Independent State of Papua New Guinea, the Solomon Islands, and the Republic of Vanuatu</u></strong><br><br>Ann Marie Yastishock, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator, Bureau for Asia, USAID. Previously, she was the USAID Mission Director in Hanoi, Vietnam. During the transition to the Biden-Harris Administration , she served as the Chief Advisor to the Acting Administrator and Chief Operating Officer for USAID. Prior to that, she was the Acting Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator of the Bureau for Asia responsible for USAID missions and programs in East Asia and the Pacific. Before that, she oversaw USAID activities in South and Central Asia as the Deputy Assistant Administrator in the Bureau for Asia. Earlier in her career, she served as the Deputy Mission Director for the regional office of USAID covering Ukraine, Moldova, Belarus and Cyprus. Other assignments include Interim Deputy Mission Director for USAID Burma; Deputy Director of the USAID Center of Excellence on Democracy, Human Rights and Governance; Senior Legal Advisor to USAID/Afghanistan; and Resident Legal Advisor to Georgia, Armenia and Azerbaijan. Prior to joining USAID, Yastishock worked as a Rule of Law Liaison for the American Bar Association/Central and East European Law Initiative with the parliaments of Kazakhstan and Tajikistan. A native of Pennsylvania, Yastishock earned her B.S. in Economics from Pennsylvania State University and a J.D. from the Widener University School of Law. She is the recipient of numerous USAID performance awards and speaks Russian.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
