<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 19:36:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Message on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Lebanon</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/20/a-letter-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-lebanon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 19:32:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to Lebanon declared in Executive Order 13441 of August 1, 2007, is to continue in effect beyond August 1, 2021.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Certain ongoing activities, such as Iran&#8217;s continuing arms&nbsp;transfers to Hizballah &#8212; which include increasingly sophisticated weapons systems &#8212; serve to undermine Lebanese sovereignty, contribute to political and economic instability in&nbsp;the region, and continue to constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13441 with respect to Lebanon.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>July 20, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Mali</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/20/a-letter-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-mali/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 19:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the situation in Mali declared in Executive Order 13882 of July 26, 2019, is to continue in effect beyond July 26, 2021.</p>



<p>The situation in Mali, including repeated violations of ceasefire arrangements made pursuant to the 2015 Agreement on Peace and Reconciliation in Mali; the expansion of terrorist activities into southern and central Mali; the intensification of drug trafficking and trafficking in persons, human rights abuses, and hostage-taking; and the intensification of attacks against civilians, the Malian defense and security forces, the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali (MINUSMA), and international security presences, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States. &nbsp;Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13882 with respect to the situation in Mali.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"> JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>July 20, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Lebanon</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/20/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-lebanon/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 19:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On August 1, 2007, by Executive Order 13441, the President declared a national emergency with respect to Lebanon pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions of certain persons to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On August 1, 2007, by Executive Order 13441, the President declared a national emergency with respect to Lebanon pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions of certain persons to undermine Lebanon&#8217;s legitimate and democratically elected government or&nbsp;democratic institutions; to contribute to&nbsp;the deliberate breakdown in the rule of law in Lebanon, including through politically motivated violence and intimidation; to reassert Syrian control or contribute to Syrian interference in Lebanon; or to infringe upon or undermine Lebanese sovereignty.&nbsp; Such actions contribute to political and&nbsp;economic instability in that country and the region.</p>



<p>Certain ongoing activities, such as Iran&#8217;s continuing arms&nbsp;transfers to Hizballah &#8212; which include increasingly sophisticated weapons systems &#8212; serve to undermine Lebanese sovereignty, contribute to political and economic instability in&nbsp;the region, and continue to constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared on August 1, 2007, must continue in effect beyond August 1, 2021.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of&nbsp;the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency with respect to Lebanon declared in Executive Order 13441.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>July 20, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to Mali</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/20/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-mali/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 19:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 26, 2019, by Executive Order 13882, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by&#160;the situation in Mali. The situation in Mali,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 26, 2019, by Executive Order 13882, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by&nbsp;the situation in Mali.</p>



<p>The situation in Mali, including repeated violations of ceasefire arrangements made pursuant to the 2015 Agreement on Peace and Reconciliation in Mali; the expansion of terrorist activities into southern and central Mali; the intensification of drug trafficking and trafficking in persons, human rights abuses, and hostage-taking; and the intensification of attacks against civilians, the Malian defense and security forces, the United Nations Multidimensional Integrated Stabilization Mission in Mali (MINUSMA), and international security presences, continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States. &nbsp;For this reason, the national emergency declared on July 26, 2019, must continue in effect beyond July 26, 2021. &nbsp;Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13882 with respect to the situation in Mali.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.           </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>July 20, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Honoring the Super Bowl LV Champions, the Tampa Bay Buccaneers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/20/remarks-by-president-biden-honoring-the-super-bowl-lv-champions-the-tampa-bay-buccaneers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 18:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:39 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good morning, I think &#8212; still &#8220;good morning.&#8221;&#160; And it’s great to see everybody here.&#160; I want to thank the &#8212; the representatives here.&#160; The Second Gentleman is here.&#160; Representative Castor, Crist &#8212; PARTICIPANT:&#160; (Inaudible.) THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Okay, you got &#8212; (laughs).&#160; I&#8217;ll tell you, that Florida thing is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:39 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good morning, I think &#8212; still &#8220;good morning.&#8221;&nbsp; And it’s great to see everybody here.&nbsp; I want to thank the &#8212; the representatives here.&nbsp; The Second Gentleman is here.&nbsp; Representative Castor, Crist &#8212;<br><br>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay, you got &#8212; (laughs).&nbsp; I&#8217;ll tell you, that Florida thing is something else.&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And Soto and Murphy and Franklin.&nbsp; And one of my best friends in the world &#8212; now he&#8217;s coming back from outer space &#8212; Bill Nelson, who runs NASA now.<br><br>We’re here today to congratulate and welcome to the White House the Super Bowl Champion Tampa Bay Buccaneers.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; To the players, the coaches, and the Glazer family &#8212; my good friends &#8212; it’s an honor to have you here.<br><br>We have to say that the fans down in Western Florida are having a pretty good year this year.&nbsp; I tell you, you know, the Stanley Cup and &#8212; in addition to the Super Bowl.&nbsp; But, you know, we’re making a pretty strong case to start calling Tampa the &#8220;City of Champions.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the &#8212; this Buccaneer team is a testament of the fact that it’s never too late to come together and achieve extraordinary things.&nbsp; Three quarters of the way through the season, they found themselves in the middle of the pack: seven wins and five losses.&nbsp;<br><br>But this is a team that didn’t fold and always got up, dug deep.&nbsp; They won their last four games of the season and then stormed through the playoffs &#8212; winning on the road in Washington, New Orleans, and Green Bay &#8212; and capping it all off back home in Tampa to become the first team to win the Super Bowl on their home turf in a decisive victory against the defending champs, the Kansas City Chiefs.<br><br>You know, it&#8217;s an incredible run by one of the most well-rounded teams in recent memory.&nbsp; A pair of All-Pro linebackers. Star pass rushers.&nbsp; A dangerous secondary.&nbsp; A dominant offensive line.&nbsp; And a legendary tight end who gave up what, I’m told, was a promising career to return to &#8212; acting career &#8212; to return to the game.&nbsp;<br><br>And most importantly, you’ve got a star receiver from Delaware.&nbsp; I&#8217;m mildly prejudiced about that.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; Where’s Chris?&nbsp; Where are you, Chris?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I called him before the game to tell him &#8212; to give him some tips on how to run some patterns.&nbsp; That was a &#8212; (laughter).<br><br>But, you know, born in Pennsylvania, raised in Delaware.&nbsp; Where I come from, that’s a heck of a combination, man.&nbsp; You know, Chris and I had a chance to speak before the Super Bowl.&nbsp; And I know, like me, he takes a lot of pride in his home state of Delaware.&nbsp; Chris, you’re inspiring a whole lot of kids back home in Delaware.<br><br>And he went to a &#8212; by the way, he went to a high school called Middletown &#8212; a perennial winner of the state championship.&nbsp; But I pointed out to him, when my son, Hunter, was a senior, he went to my Alma Mater&#8217;s high school named &#8212; by the way, all sit down.&nbsp; What are we &#8212; just standing?&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>I &#8212; you know, and I told him my son scored the scoring touchdown at Archmere and won the state championship that year.&nbsp; But, anyway, that’s &#8212; we don’t &#8212; we don’t count those things.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;ve never met an athlete that doesn’t remember every damn play he made.<br><br>And, of course, two other guys worth mentioning: the coach and the quarterback.&nbsp; You know, a lot has been made about the fact that we have the oldest coach ever to win a Super Bowl and the oldest quarterback to win the Super Bowl.<br><br>Well, I’ll tell you right now: You won’t hear any jokes about that from me.&nbsp; As far as I’m concerned, there’s nothing wrong with being the oldest guy to make it to the mountaintop.&nbsp; That’s how I look at it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And, Tom, looking at you, you’ve got about 20 more years left.&nbsp; You’re just about the best ever to play.&nbsp; And making it to 10 Super Bowls in the last 20 years &#8212; that ain’t bad, man. (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’ll tell you what, we’ve never seen anything like it in the game.&nbsp;<br><br>And, of course, these guys all know that sports are more than just a game.&nbsp; It’s something &#8212; some of my strongest memories, most enduring memories and lessons and cherished friendships come from the days I played &#8212; not went anywhere near anybody on that stage.&nbsp; I started in grade school playing in CYO league.&nbsp;<br><br>And I’ll never forget getting knocked out when I was in fifth grade, and my dad &#8212; walking off &#8212; he said, “Get up.&nbsp; Get up.&nbsp; Get up.&nbsp; Unless something is broken, get up.”&nbsp; Well, I think that’s what sports tell you: You just get up.&nbsp; You get up.<br><br>I went to the University of Delaware to play football, although it didn’t very do much for my career &#8212; I didn’t do very well.&nbsp; But, you know, I found out that your career can be embellished a little over time.&nbsp; It’s an amazing kind of thing.<br><br>You know, there’s an awards banquet that, many years later &#8212; which is called the Timmie Awards &#8212; was it?&nbsp; &#8212; and was held here in Washington.&nbsp; Supreme Court Justices and Presidents would show up to this big banquet.&nbsp; And the University of Delaware football program received the award, and I had a chance to introduce a Hall of Fame coach, one of my &#8212; the backfield coach when I played.&nbsp; I didn’t play much.&nbsp; His name was Tubby Raymond.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, I got up and I said, “Here is my coach, Tubby Raymond.”&nbsp; Made &#8212; said some nice things about Tubby.&nbsp;<br><br>Tubby was really, kind of, nervous and &#8212; standing in front of Presidents and Supreme Court Justices and so many distinguished people.&nbsp; And he went up on &#8212; on to talk about what an incredible ball player I was at the University of Delaware.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It was amazing.&nbsp; It was amazing.&nbsp; That’s why I decided to run for President.&nbsp; I figured, if he was still around and I&#8217;d get to be elected President, I would’ve been an All-American.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I could’ve been big.&nbsp; I could’ve been big.&nbsp;<br><br>But all kidding aside, you guys did it the hard way. &nbsp;And I hope you all know just how important it was for &#8212; after such a tough year for the nation.&nbsp; In the middle of a long, dark winter, every Sunday, people were able to sit down and watch you play.&nbsp; You created memories that helped folks make it through and believe that we could get back to normal again.&nbsp; And you did it as a team, trailblazing, including the first team with two women full-time coaching positions.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And realizing that of the &#8212; of the 25 or 26 Glazer grandchildren and about 24 of them being women &#8212; you had no choice.&nbsp; It’s about time they stepped up.&nbsp; Right, guys?&nbsp;<br><br>Anyway, all kidding aside, the step &#8212; your team stepped up off the field, too, donating millions of meals to families in need; helping Americans exercise their sacred right to vote, including at Raymond James Stadium.&nbsp; Your stadium also became a lifeline for families in Tampa Bay this spring, administering nearly 200,000 vaccine shots.&nbsp; And you all who don’t have a shot, man: Get one, okay?<br><br>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; Amen.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Get one.&nbsp; Get one.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And you’re saving lives &#8212; helping us get back our lives and loved ones.<br><br>And I want to thank the NFL for setting strong vaccination goals so fans can go see a game without it becoming a super-spreader event.<br><br>Getting vaccinated is about staying healthy and understanding that no one is invincible, even if you are young and you’re fit.&nbsp; It’s about looking out for those and the frontline workers out there, like the ones the team played in front of on Super Bowl Sunday.<br><br>Those workers remind us of a quintessential lesson about sports and America itself.&nbsp; That no matter how much and how many times we get knocked down, we always get up.&nbsp; We come back.&nbsp; We come back stronger together and achieve incredible things &#8212; just like your team did, just like we’re doing as a country.<br><br>So, congratulations, and thank you all for being here.&nbsp; Good luck to you all this season.&nbsp; And now let me bring up Bryan to say a few words.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>MR. GLAZER:&nbsp; Mr. President, on behalf of our family, the Tampa Bay Buccaneers coaches, players, and staff, and all of our loyal fans, thank you for hosting us today.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an honor for us to be at the White House.<br><br>For our family and fans, this day has been nearly 20 years in the making.&nbsp; Because despite this being our second Super Bowl Championship, this our first visit to the White House.&nbsp; In 2003, following our Super Bowl 37 victory, there were world events that prevented us to visit.&nbsp; So that makes today even more special.<br><br>And we&#8217;re here today because this team did the impossible: new players, including a new quarterback; no offseason mini camps; no preseason; limitations on meetings,\; rules and regulations were changing every day.&nbsp; But they stayed focused and went on to win their final eight games, as the President spoke about, and became the first team to win the Super Bowl at home.&nbsp; Amazing.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s only fitting that as we enter the 46th season in Tampa Bay Buccaneer history that we celebrate it with the 46th President of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We start this season with only one goal in mind: It’s to come back here next summer and spend a Super Bowl victory again with you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>MR. ARIANS:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President, for giving us this day.&nbsp; It &#8212; I get emotional, but it&#8217;s very, very special.&nbsp; This is actually my third time; it never gets old.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank our coaches, our players, our entire organization &#8212; men, women that did such a great job last year of coming together and banding together &#8212; not to beat the other team; we had to beat the virus first.&nbsp; And you sacrificed more than any team I&#8217;ve ever been around &#8212; players, coaches, your families &#8212; to make sure that we had our team on the field every Sunday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s a great compliment to all of you.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t say enough about our owners, the Glazer family.&nbsp; They’re the best owners I&#8217;ve ever known and ever been around.&nbsp; Our players are outstanding.&nbsp; They do what they&#8217;re supposed to do on and off the field because they take care of each other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We live by three words: trust, loyalty, and respect.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any rules.&nbsp; If you have those, you&#8217;ll have accountability and you&#8217;ll be able to do anything you want.&nbsp; One team, one cause.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I hope the Senate and the House start helping you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; One team, one cause.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Again, thank you all for having us here.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President. &nbsp;And Go Bucs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And Tom has got some stuff to say.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. BRADY:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s certainly an honor to be here.&nbsp; Thank you very much for your hospitality your entire staff has given us today.&nbsp; I think what &#8212; behind me is an amazing group of players.&nbsp; We have a bunch of coaches and staff here sitting down.&nbsp;<br><br>And it was actually a very challenging season for a lot of reasons, but we bonded together, we worked really hard, we put all our individual agendas aside, and we came together as a team.</p>



<p>And sports has an amazing way of bringing people together.&nbsp; If you look at us, we&#8217;re all a little bit different ages.&nbsp; I&#8217;m a little older than most of them.&nbsp; But we come from a lot of different places across the country, a lot of different schools, a lot of different backgrounds, but we love each other; we&#8217;re committed to one another.&nbsp; And when you do that, amazing things happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And these guys are amazing group of men.&nbsp; It didn&#8217;t look great there at one point.&nbsp; We were seven and five, struggling a little bit, as the President alluded to.&nbsp; But we found our rhythm.&nbsp; We got on a roll.</p>



<p>Not a lot of people, you know, think that we could have won.&nbsp; And, in fact, I think about 40 percent of the people still don&#8217;t think we won.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I understand that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MR. BRADY:&nbsp; You understand that, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I understand that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. BRADY:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And personally, you know, it&#8217;s nice for me to be back here.&nbsp; We had a game in Chicago where I forgot what down it was.&nbsp; I lost track of one down in 21 years of playing, and they started calling me “Sleepy Tom.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Why would they do that to me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MR. BRADY:&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s great to be &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re on the eve of football season.&nbsp; We start, tomorrow, practice.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to do everything we can to work to achieve another one of those Lombardi trophies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s a different group of men.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll be a different challenge, but we&#8217;re excited for it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re excited for the opportunity to compete and work hard and show everyone what we&#8217;re made of.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re not going to throw the Super Bowl trophy this time, Cam, but we&#8217;re going to offer President Biden a special presentation from Mr. Glazer.&nbsp; And then we&#8217;re going to challenge 11 of us, 11 White House interns to game of football here on the lawn, and we intend to run it up on you guys, so &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; get ready to go.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>(The President is presented with a Buccaneers jersey.)&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you, man.&nbsp; Unusual number, huh?&nbsp; Forty-six.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>11:53 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Jonathan Kanter for Assistant Attorney General for Antitrust</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/20/president-biden-announces-jonathan-kanter-for-assistant-attorney-general-for-antitrust/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 18:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate Jonathan Kanter for Assistant Attorney General for the Antitrust Division at the Department of Justice. Jonathan Kanter, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General, Antitrust Division, Department of Justice Jonathan Kanter is a distinguished antitrust lawyer with over 20 years of experience. Throughout his career, Kanter&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate Jonathan Kanter for Assistant Attorney General for the Antitrust Division at the Department of Justice.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Jonathan Kanter, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General, Antitrust Division, Department of Justice</u></strong></p>



<p>Jonathan Kanter is a distinguished antitrust lawyer with over 20 years of experience. Throughout his career, Kanter has also been a leading advocate and expert in the effort to promote strong and meaningful antitrust enforcement and competition policy. He is currently a partner at The Kanter Law Group LLP, which is a boutique antitrust law firm that advocates in favor of federal and state antitrust law enforcement.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Prior to founding The Kanter Law Group, Kanter was Co-Chair of the antitrust practice at Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton, and Garrison LLP. Jonathan also served as an attorney for the U.S. Federal Trade Commission’s Bureau of Competition.&nbsp; Kanter earned his J.D. from Washington University in St. Louis and his B.A. from State University of New York at Albany.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Listening Session with Cuban American Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/readout-of-white-house-listening-session-with-cuban-american-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Senior Advisor and Director of the White House Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond and Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere for the National Security Council Juan Gonzalez met with Cuban American leaders to listen to their policy recommendations and concerns in light of the recent, unprecedented demonstrations unfolding across Cuba. Administration officials underscored that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Senior Advisor and Director of the White House Office of Public Engagement Cedric Richmond and Senior Director for the Western Hemisphere for the National Security Council Juan Gonzalez met with Cuban American leaders to listen to their policy recommendations and concerns in light of the recent, unprecedented demonstrations unfolding across Cuba. Administration officials underscored that the White House is monitoring the situation in Cuba closely and that addressing the moment and ongoing situation in Cuba is a top priority for the Administration. They also affirmed what the President said last week: that the demonstrations are the direct result of a failed communist government, and reminded the leaders that the President stands firmly with the people of Cuba. Stakeholders shared what they’ve done over the last week to help elevate the voices of demonstrators in Cuba and provided their recommendations for how the U.S. government can help. Today’s was the latest event in ongoing work the White House has done to reach Cuban American leaders following the historic demonstrations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the Occasion of Eid al-Adha</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-occasion-of-eid-al-adha/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24477</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I send our warmest greetings to those celebrating Eid al-Adha around the world. The Eid traditions and Hajj rituals of providing for those less fortunate in commemoration of Abraham and his son’s devotion to God carry a special meaning this year as we continue to navigate the challenges of COVID-19 and work to&#160;respond&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I send our warmest greetings to those celebrating Eid al-Adha around the world. The Eid traditions and Hajj rituals of providing for those less fortunate in commemoration of Abraham and his son’s devotion to God carry a special meaning this year as we continue to navigate the challenges of COVID-19 and work to&nbsp;respond to and&nbsp;recover from the global pandemic. The American people are proud to be helping lead the fight to end COVID-19 globally by donating more than half a billion vaccines to countries around the world, including Muslim-majority nations. We must all work together to save lives and end this pandemic everywhere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Hajj, which convenes people from all walks of life&nbsp;and&nbsp;from&nbsp;every corner&nbsp;of the globe, is also a reminder of Islam’s commitment to equality and the shared roots of&nbsp;the world’s Abrahamic faiths.&nbsp;The United States is committed to working&nbsp;with the international community to emerge stronger from the pandemic,&nbsp;and&nbsp;thousands of Muslim Americans are among those eager to perform the pilgrimage next year, God willing. &nbsp;</p>



<p>On behalf of the American people, we wish all those celebrating a safe and wonderful holiday. Eid Mubarak.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-26/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 23:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24469</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Julie Chung, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka. &#160; &#160; &#160;Janet Louise Yellen, of California, to be United States Governor of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Julie Chung, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Janet Louise Yellen, of California, to be United States Governor of the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, vice Steven T. Mnuchin.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Janet Louise Yellen, of California, to be United States Governor of the Inter-American Development Bank for a term of five years; United States Governor of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development for a term of five years; and United States Governor of the International Monetary Fund for a term of five years, vice Steven T. Mnuchin.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting with King Abdullah II of Jordan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-with-king-abdullah-ii-of-jordan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 22:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan to reaffirm the enduring strength of the partnership between the United States and Jordan. President Biden confirmed unwavering U.S. support for Jordan and His Majesty’s leadership. He was proud to announce the delivery of over 500,000 COVID-19 vaccines to Jordan,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan to reaffirm the enduring strength of the partnership between the United States and Jordan. President Biden confirmed unwavering U.S. support for Jordan and His Majesty’s leadership. He was proud to announce the delivery of over 500,000 COVID-19 vaccines to Jordan, underscoring the U.S. commitment to bringing the same urgency to international vaccination efforts that we have demonstrated at home.</p>



<p>The leaders discussed pressing economic challenges exacerbated by the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic, both at home and across the globe.&nbsp; They focused on the benefits of investing in infrastructure, and discussed the President’s infrastructure plan as well as Jordan’s plans for a desalination project and Jordan’s potential for greater regional economic integration through investments in energy infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leaders also consulted on opportunities to enhance peace and stability in the Middle East. In that regard, the President expressed his strong support for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict and respect for Jordan’s special role as custodian of Muslim holy places in Jerusalem. The President expressed U.S. support for engagement between Jordan and the new Israeli Government, as demonstrated by their bilateral agreement earlier this month to improve Jordan’s access to fresh water and increase Jordan’s exports to the West Bank.</p>



<p>President Biden commended the important role Jordan plays in the wider stability of the region and welcomed the recent trilateral summit in Baghdad between Iraq, Jordan, and Egypt. The two leaders discussed the enormous challenges in Syria and the importance of a broad humanitarian initiative to reach all Syrians in need.</p>



<p>The leaders reflected on the strategic U.S.-Jordan defense relationship. They discussed U.S. support for the modernization of Jordan’s fleet of F-16 fighter jets, which will allow for greater interoperability and effectiveness of the Jordanian Armed Forces.&nbsp; President Biden thanked Jordan for its important early contributions to the successful campaign to defeat ISIS, and honored the memory of Captain Muath al-Kasasbeh as an example of Jordanian courage and heroism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden reaffirmed that his administration looks forward to strengthening bilateral cooperation in multiple areas over the coming months, including the promotion of economic opportunities that will be vital for a bright future in Jordan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
