<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:36:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The United&#160;States-Palestinian&#160;Relationship</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/fact-sheet-the-united-states-palestinian-relationship/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57460</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tomorrow, President Biden will announce a number of initiatives to support the Palestinian people by: Improving access to health care and technology; Rolling out long overdue 4G digital connectivity to both Gaza and the West Bank; Bolstering economic growth; Providing critical services for Palestinian refugees; Reducing food insecurity; Fostering people-to-people dialogue to support peace.&#160; President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Tomorrow, President Biden will announce a number of initiatives to support the Palestinian people by:</p>



<ul><li>Improving access to health care and technology;</li><li>Rolling out long overdue 4G digital connectivity to both Gaza and the West Bank;</li><li>Bolstering economic growth;</li><li>Providing critical services for Palestinian refugees;</li><li>Reducing food insecurity;</li><li>Fostering people-to-people dialogue to support peace.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>President Biden will also announce new contributions totaling $316 million to support the Palestinian people.&nbsp;This is on top of the more than half a billion dollars the United States has provided to the Palestinian people since the Biden Administration restored much needed funding to the Palestinians.</p>



<p><strong>Improve Healthcare Access for Palestinians</strong></p>



<ul><li>During his visit to the Augusta Victoria Hospital in East Jerusalem, the President will announce the United States intends to provide a new multi-year U.S. contribution of up to $100 million for the East Jerusalem Hospital Network (EJHN), subject to congressional approval.&nbsp; The EJHN is a grouping of six hospitals in East Jerusalem providing specialized services including oncology, dialysis, neo-natal intensive care, and specialized maternity, ophthalmology, and emergency services to 50,000 patients from East Jerusalem, the West Bank, and Gaza annually.&nbsp; The funding is provided by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and paired with health system and hospital reforms.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Bolstering the Digital Economy to Improve Palestinian Economic Growth</strong></p>



<ul><li>To boost Palestinian businesses and improve connectivity for Palestinians in the West Bank and Gaza, Israel has committed to speeding up the long overdue transformation of 3G to 4G in the West Bank and afterwards 2G to 4G in Gaza.&nbsp; Israeli and Palestinian teams will work together immediately to start the technological surveys, with an aim to roll out an advanced infrastructure for 4G by the end of 2023.&nbsp; This commitment will accelerate digital transformation and foster a more well-connected Palestinian economy.&nbsp; It will also generate jobs, increase productivity, and increase online operations in the health and education sectors.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Improve the Travel Experience from the West Bank to Jordan</strong></p>



<ul><li>President Biden supports creating a more autonomous, efficient, and reliable Palestinian experience of traveling abroad.&nbsp; He will announce that Israel is prepared to take measures to increase efficiency and accessibility to the Allenby Bridge for the benefit of Palestinians.&nbsp; In order to upgrade facilities, Israel has agreed to enable access 24 hours per day, 7 days per week, by September 30, 2022.&nbsp; A working group will assess several measures including the use of biometric passports and will complete its assessments within the next month and discuss conclusions with U.S. partners.&nbsp; In addition, the working group will consider steps to establish Palestinian Authority presence on Allenby Bridge while maintaining Israel&#8217;s security considerations.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Support Critical Services for Palestinian Refugees</strong></p>



<ul><li>The United States believes that Palestinian refugees deserve to live in dignity, to see their basic needs addressed, and to have hope for the future.&nbsp; President Biden will announce an additional $201 million for the UN Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees (UNRWA) to continue delivering critical services to Palestinian refugees in the West Bank, Gaza, Jordan, Lebanon, and Syria.&nbsp; UNRWA’s comprehensive services remain a lifeline to millions of vulnerable Palestinians – consistent with its mandate to provide assistance and protection to Palestinian refugees pending a just and lasting solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict.&nbsp; These services directly contribute to maintaining regional stability, which is beneficial to the interests of the United States, our allies, and our partners.&nbsp; This contribution cements the United States’ status as UNRWA’s largest donor. &nbsp;These new funds bring the total United States assistance to UNRWA during the Biden Administration to more than $618 million. &nbsp;The United States is committed to supporting UNRWA to provide the most effective and efficient assistance possible and to continue to improve its operations and delivery. &nbsp;UNRWA’s work must be done while fully respecting the UN principles of neutrality, tolerance, human rights, equity, and non-discrimination. &nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Re-Launching Israeli-Palestinian Economic Discussions and Promoting Steps to Improve Lives</strong></p>



<ul><li>President Biden will share with President Abbas that Israel intends to convene the Joint Economic Committee with the Palestinians.&nbsp; Restarting discussions through the Joint Economic Committee has been a longstanding request of the Palestinian Authority. &nbsp;The committee last met in 2009 and is the mandated entity under the Oslo Accords for the Israeli government and Palestinian Authority to meet to discuss joint economic issues, including wastewater, clean energy, and other measures that impact Palestinian lives in the West Bank.&nbsp; President Biden also announced that Israel agreed to increase the number of permits for Palestinians in Gaza to work and do business in Israel to 15,500.&nbsp; The Biden Administration strongly supports increased access and movement for Palestinians, and this is a positive step toward that goal.&nbsp; Additionally, Israel agreed to approve the registration of 5,500 previously unregistered Palestinians on the Palestinian Population Register.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensure Food Security for Palestinians</strong></p>



<ul><li>In response to rising food insecurity for Palestinians in the wake of the Russian invasion of Ukraine, President Biden will announce that the United States is providing $15 million in additional humanitarian assistance for vulnerable Palestinians.&nbsp; Via funding to the UN World Food Program and two non-governmental organizations, the United States is providing electronic food vouchers, multipurpose cash assistance, and emergency livelihoods support, helping more than 210,000 food-insecure people meet their household food needs in coming months.&nbsp; This funding is part of the pledge of additional U.S. government resources that President Biden made at the G7 Leaders’ Summit in Germany in late June to protect the world’s most vulnerable populations from the escalating global food security crisis.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Fostering People-to-People Ties</strong></p>



<ul><li>To build grassroots support for peace through an eventual negotiated two-state solution, President Biden will announce two new grants under the Nita M. Lowey Middle East Partnership for Peace Act (MEPPA).&nbsp; MEPPA authorizes up to $250 million dollars over five years to implement projects led by both Israelis and Palestinians establishing the environment necessary to achieve long term peace.&nbsp; The first new grant, for $2.21 million to the Peres Center for Peace, will support collaboration and professional exchanges between the Palestinian and Israeli health sectors as they work to build mutual trust, confidence, and understanding between the two societies.&nbsp; The second new grant, for $5 million to AppleSeeds, will provide young Palestinian and Israeli professionals the opportunity to work together and learn critical technology and leadership. For more information on these and other activities under MEPPA please visit <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/west-bank-and-gaza/meppa">https://www.usaid.gov/west-bank-and-gaza/meppa</a>.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Mayors on Reproductive Rights&#160; </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-mayors-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, met with women and allied mayors from across the country to discuss reproductive rights.&#160; From safeguarding public health to overseeing critical infrastructure, mayors lead and implement policies closest to home. As abortion bans go into effect in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, met with women and allied mayors from across the country to discuss reproductive rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From safeguarding public health to overseeing critical infrastructure, mayors lead and implement policies closest to home. As abortion bans go into effect in states across the country, compromising women’s access to critical reproductive health care services,&nbsp;mayors can play an important role in their communities, including by supporting public education and outreach on reproductive health care, supporting the funding of services,&nbsp;sharing accurate information, and taking additional actions to protect abortion access and promote safety.</p>



<p>On June 30, the Women Mayors Network released a&nbsp;<a href="https://nam12.safelinks.protection.outlook.com/?url=https%3A%2F%2Furldefense.com%2Fv3%2F__https%3A%2Fwww.womenmayorsnetwork.org%2Fabortionaccessletter2%2F__%3B!!AQdq3sQhfUj4q8uUguY!iz9lbb4k2qPMql2vQSzaIkbXehLFnIQSVFuYJ2uZbuErKQuqz-Pff91Bk8qG5HwgiLZ7mKsWjHcBjY1K2BwAE2_hnuJ7A_G_IKfr%24&amp;data=05%7C01%7CZMiller%40ap.org%7C928d3918aa964d68d4d908da65a61411%7Ce442e1abfd6b4ba3abf3b020eb50df37%7C1%7C0%7C637934061221694690%7CUnknown%7CTWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0%3D%7C3000%7C%7C%7C&amp;sdata=CJ8Y7dIJBu23JiIBcCBL3skploii%2BYuIOtLNmO2Vm7g%3D&amp;reserved=0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">letter</a>&nbsp;from more than 65 women mayors and additional male allies in response to the Supreme Court’s decision in&nbsp;<em>Dobbs v. Jackson</em>&nbsp;<em>Women’s Health Organization.&nbsp;</em>In the letter, the mayors commit to “actions that safeguard our clinics and our residents who are seeking abortion services or helping others do so and funding services and logistical support whenever possible, and to organize with residents and activists to support actions that expand access to abortion care.”</p>



<p>In the meeting, which was co-hosted by the Women Mayors Network, mayors shared what they are seeing and hearing on the ground as patients from states that ban abortion travel to seek care. The mayors also discussed actions they have taken to support reproductive rights, as well as key messaging and outreach strategies. White House Senior Officials thanked the mayors for their leadership and reinforced the Administration’s commitment&nbsp;to working together to protect access to abortion.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on the Opening of Saudi&#160;Airspace</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-the-opening-of-saudi-airspace/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:36:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden welcomes and commends the historic decision by the leadership of Saudi Arabia to open Saudi airspace to all civilian carriers without discrimination, a decision that includes flights to and from Israel. This decision is the result of the President’s persistent and principled diplomacy with Saudi Arabia over many months, culminating in his visit&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden welcomes and commends the historic decision by the leadership of Saudi Arabia to open Saudi airspace to all civilian carriers without discrimination, a decision that includes flights to and from Israel. This decision is the result of the President’s persistent and principled diplomacy with Saudi Arabia over many months, culminating in his visit today. This decision paves the way for a more integrated, stable, and secure Middle East region, which is vital for the security and prosperity of the United States and the American people, and for the security and prosperity of Israel. The President will have more to say on this breakthrough later today, as we embark on his historic flight directly from Israel to Jeddah, Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris before Briefing from CENTCOM and SOCOM&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-briefing-from-centcom-and-socom-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MacDill Air Force BaseTampa, Florida THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I am very much looking forward to our discussion.&#160; And I&#8217;m very pleased to be here on the ground with you, who have been doing extraordinary work on so many levels.&#160;&#160;I was &#8212; all that I &#8212; that I admire about the service,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>MacDill Air Force Base<br><em>Tampa, Florida</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I am very much looking forward to our discussion.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m very pleased to be here on the ground with you, who have been doing extraordinary work on so many levels.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I was &#8212; all that I &#8212; that I admire about the service, the dedication, the discipline, and the skill that our men and women apply to this work was reinforced with the quick visit that I just had out in the hangar.&nbsp; And so, I want to thank everyone here for what you do every day.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are here to highlight and to &#8212; to uplift with praise the work of CENTCOM and SOCOM.&nbsp; This work is critical to our national security.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As we know, the President is overseas right now in the Middle East.&nbsp; And there is so much about what happens through the leadership here on the ground that allows us to reinforce and strengthen our partnerships around the globe and reinforces our commitment to international rules and norms and America’s willingness and preparedness to uphold and defend those international rules and norms.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I&#8217;m here to speak with these leaders &#8212; in particular, General Kurilla and General Clarke.&nbsp; And I want to thank you both for hosting us today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The United States Military, without any question certainly in my mind or the President&#8217;s mind and in the mind of the American people, is the strongest and the best fighting force in the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>When you look at the work that happens just right here, you will see extraordinary work that is about dedication, discipline, the building and strengthening of skills, and just sheer commitment to defending our country and the principles upon which we were founded.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I&#8217;m here to talk with the leaders here to discuss the missions that are currently active around the globe and to talk with them about what might be necessary in terms of the additional support and resources that they need to do their job and complete their mission.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;I also am here to express gratitude not only to the service members but to their families.&nbsp; In particular, the folks who work out of CENTCOM and SOCOM are supported by wonderful families who dedicate so much of their lives to allow their family member to serve as they do for our country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I am here to praise, again, the work that is being done by all of these folks.&nbsp; I also want to mention that partic- &#8212; in particular, regarding the work of CENTCOM, President Biden, being in the Middle East, is there to also make sure that we are clear about the role and the responsibility the United States plays in that region of the world, with an emphasis on many points, including our enduring relationship in support of our allies and friends and partners in Israel.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>His visit is also about emphasizing the work that is happening through CENTCOM that strengthens the relationships that we have in that region of the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>CENTCOM’s work also directly benefits the American people, in addition to ensuring that all of the values we care about in terms of our security are upheld.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>CENTCOM’s work includes protecting commercial shipping lanes and energy resources that Americans rely on and &#8212; in this moment when we know that commerce and the &#8212; the active ability of us to engage in commerce is something that directly affects the American people where they live and how they live.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Regarding SOCOM, this year we celebrate the 30th &#8212; 35th, excuse me, anniversary of its founding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And we call the Special Operations Forces our “quiet professionals” for a reason.&nbsp; They do big work.&nbsp; They never look for praise or acknowledgement.&nbsp; But the work they do we take for granted.&nbsp; Sometimes we don&#8217;t see, but we surely benefit from it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I&#8217;m here to also talk about the work that is happening in the frontlines on our continued fight against terrorism around the world and the work that SOCOM does to ensure that America&#8217;s interests are well served, including at this moment during Russia&#8217;s unprovoked aggression and the war in Ukraine, where the men and women of this division have been doing the work that they do around the globe, including training the forces that are the forces of our allies and, in particular, the Ukrainians in their fight to preserve their sovereignty and territorial integrity.<br>&nbsp;<br>So together, CENTCOM and SOCOM advance our national security interests and defend and strengthen our international rules-based order.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I will conclude by saying to all here how much we appreciate you every day.&nbsp; I mentioned to the folks that I was with in the hangar: We talk about you guys all the time when we&#8217;re sitting in the Situation Room or in the Oval Office, talking about America&#8217;s responsibility not only to the citizens of our country but to our friends and allies around the world.&nbsp; We talk about you, because we could not follow through on anything that we do in the context of those relationships and priorities were it not for what you all are doing here on the ground.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you.&nbsp; And your mission remains critically important to the President, to me, and to our country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I thank the press.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll see you all later.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END<br>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with Florida State Legislators on Reproductive Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-florida-state-legislators-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:08:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, July 14, 2022, Vice President Kamala Harris convened Florida state legislators who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights. The Vice President was joined by Secretary of Health and Human Services Xavier Becerra for the meeting which took place in Orlando, Florida. Today’s convening follows engagements about reproductive rights that the Vice&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, July 14, 2022, Vice President Kamala Harris convened Florida state legislators who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights. The Vice President was joined by Secretary of Health and Human Services Xavier Becerra for the meeting which took place in Orlando, Florida. Today’s convening follows engagements about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with health care providers, faith leaders, constitutional law and privacy experts, advocates, State Attorneys General, and other state legislators from across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>During the meeting, the Vice President conveyed the Administration’s commitment to protecting access to reproductive health care, including abortion access, and she encouraged the legislators to continue fighting to protect reproductive rights in Florida.&nbsp;She emphasized that the government should not interfere with the right of every American to make the most intimate decisions about “heart and home” – including reproductive health care access. The Vice President reiterated the Administration’s commitment to partnering with elected leaders at the local, state, and federal level to protect reproductive health care.&nbsp;The Vice President discussed actions the Administration is taking to defend health care access, and&nbsp;she applauded the state legislators for their work defending abortion access in Florida.<br><br>The state legislative leaders shared what is happening in Florida as extremist legislators are fighting to further limit reproductive health care access. Florida currently has a 15 week ban on abortion, with no exception for rape or incest. The law was signed into law by Governor DeSantis in April and went into effect on July 1, 2022. Participants shared stories of patients who have experienced the harmful impact of Florida’s abortion restrictions, noting that every person deserves access to comprehensive health care. The legislators conveyed how the impact of abortion bans across other southern states is overwhelming the health systems in Florida. They also discussed how in states like Florida, the extremist legislators who are attacking reproductive rights are also restricting LGBTQI+ rights and voting rights. The Vice President recognized the importance of building coalitions to defend rights and freedoms. The Vice President and the state leaders reaffirmed their commitment to working together to protect reproductive rights for all women across the state of Florida and our nation.<br>&nbsp;<br>In attendance were the following:</p>



<ul><li>HHS Secretary Xavier Becerra</li><li>Doctor Robyn Schickler, Chief Medical Officer at Planned Parenthood of Southwest and Central Florida</li><li>Leader Lauren Book</li><li>Leader Designate Fentrice Driskell</li><li>Representative Anna Eskamani</li><li>Senator Victor Torres Jr.</li><li>Representative Kristen Arrington</li><li>Representative Kamia Brown&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Representative Jervonte Edmonds</li><li>Representative Christine Hunschofsky&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Representative Andrew Learned&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Senator Rosalind Osgood&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li><li>Representative Yvonne Hinson</li><li>Representative Geraldine Thompson</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Brian Deese Remarks on President&#160;Biden’s Competition&#160;Agenda</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/brian-deese-remarks-on-president-bidens-competition-agenda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 21:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[REMARKS AS PREPARED Thank you, Vivian.&#160; I’m grateful to you, Cecilia, and everyone at the Aspen Institute for spotlighting President Biden’s competition agenda.&#160; It’s great to be here. A little over a year ago, President Biden issued a landmark Executive Order on Competition. &#160;That day, he articulated both the opportunity and the challenge. &#160;“The heart&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">REMARKS AS PREPARED</p>



<p>Thank you, Vivian.&nbsp; I’m grateful to you, Cecilia, and everyone at the Aspen Institute for spotlighting President Biden’s competition agenda.&nbsp; It’s great to be here.</p>



<p>A little over a year ago, President Biden issued a landmark Executive Order on Competition. &nbsp;That day, he articulated both the opportunity and the challenge. &nbsp;“The heart of American capitalism,” the President explained, “is a simple idea: open and fair competition.” &nbsp;But he also warned that “capitalism without competition isn’t capitalism; it’s exploitation.”<a href="#_ftn1" id="_ftnref1">[1]</a></p>



<p>This isn’t the first time an American President has trained his focus on competition. &nbsp;Theodore Roosevelt confronted an economy with industry after industry dominated by trusts. &nbsp;Franklin Roosevelt faced a highly cartelized economy struggling to recover from the Great Depression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Both Roosevelts transformed antitrust enforcement in their time and set precedents for rising to this challenge on behalf of the American people. &nbsp;And both Roosevelts understood something important: antitrust policy doesn’t operate in a vacuum; it is interwoven with the fabric of the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Consider one example. &nbsp;Teddy Roosevelt is of course remembered for “trust-busting”—in particular against railroads,<a href="#_ftn2" id="_ftnref2">[2]</a> meatpackers,<a href="#_ftn3" id="_ftnref3">[3]</a> and Standard Oil<a href="#_ftn4" id="_ftnref4">[4]</a> in the courts. &nbsp;But his insight was broader: not only was it necessary to vigorously enforce antitrust laws, but it was also critical to reshape the regulatory framework—to work with Congress and to create rules of the road (or rules of the rail) that kept these early common carriers from using their market position to privilege incumbents and discriminate against new entrants.<a href="#_ftn5" id="_ftnref5">[5]</a></p>



<p>That basic insight—using tools from across the government to implement <em>structural </em>changes to enhance competition—is more relevant than ever today. &nbsp;We face an economy today with challenges impossible for the Roosevelts to imagine. &nbsp;But there are familiar echoes. &nbsp;</p>



<p>For President Biden, a strong competition policy is an indispensable part of an economic strategy for the twenty-first century. &nbsp;He believes driving structural changes that promote competition across the economy holds the prospect of generating more innovation, productivity, and opportunity in America, while lowering prices for consumers and raising wages for workers.</p>



<p>For decades, the competitive attributes of our economy have been atrophying. &nbsp;Most industries have become less competitive. &nbsp;Both consumers and workers have been left with fewer options.&nbsp;<br><br></p>



<p>Reversing these trends is a significant task. It amounts to turning around the proverbial aircraft carrier. &nbsp;But now, one year in, we can begin to see the ship turning in the right direction. &nbsp;We’ve already delivered on many key promises, with more announcements coming soon. &nbsp;And under the direction of the President’s executive order—and through our White House Competition Council—we are changing how the government approaches competition policy, and indeed economic policy. &nbsp;If done right, these changes will pay dividends for years to come as we continue the hard work of shifting course.</p>



<p>Today, I’d like to address the competition challenges we face, the progress we’ve made during the last year, and the work that lies ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<ol type="I"><li><strong>Today’s Competition Challenges</strong></li></ol>



<p>Let’s talk, first, about the competition challenges we’re confronting.</p>



<p>A growing body of academic research has demonstrated our economy is suffering from a loss of competition and rising corporate concentration. &nbsp;Six years ago, my colleagues at the Council of Economic Advisers sounded the alarm around what they described as “increasing industry concentration, increasing rents accruing to a few firms, and lower levels of firm entry and labor market mobility.”<a href="#_ftn6" id="_ftnref6">[6]</a></p>



<p>Those concerns emanated from stark realities: Over the prior decades, concentration had increased in more than three-quarters of U.S. industries,<a href="#_ftn7" id="_ftnref7">[7]</a> while both investment and labor’s share of the economy decreased.<a href="#_ftn8" id="_ftnref8">[8]</a>&nbsp; This occurred during a period of both low productivity growth and rising inequality.<a href="#_ftn9" id="_ftnref9">[9]</a></p>



<p>The core problem involves what economists call excessive market power.  Careful work by leading thinkers—including Jonathan Baker,<a id="_ftnref10" href="#_ftn10">[10]</a> Fiona Scott Morton<a id="_ftnref11" href="#_ftn11">[11]</a> and Nancy Rose<a id="_ftnref12" href="#_ftn12">[12]</a>—has documented the rise of market power.   A striking conclusion comes from a landmark study by John Kwoka, which surveyed the impact of nearly four dozen major mergers.  More than 80 percent of those mergers led to price <em>increases</em>.  The average price increase was around 10 percent[13]—and even more dramatic in some industries, like hospital care<a id="_ftnref14" href="#_ftn14">[14]</a> and airline tickets.<a id="_ftnref15" href="#_ftn15">[15]</a></p>



<p>These studies have upended the long-held assumption in some academic quarters that mergers generally—or indeed inherently—increase efficiency and lower prices.  The best research does not support that assumption, and that must inform our approach.</p>



<p>Recent research has also helped underscore how lack of competition can hurt workers—something that’s particularly important to President Biden. &nbsp;Because of work by economists like José Azar,<a></a><a href="#_ftn16" id="_ftnref16">[16]</a> Ioana Marinescu,<a></a><a href="#_ftn17" id="_ftnref17">[17]</a> Marshall Steinbaum,<a href="#_ftn18" id="_ftnref18">[18]</a> and Eric Posner,<a href="#_ftn19" id="_ftnref19">[19]</a> we can now see more clearly how fewer employers competing over the same talent pool reduces employees’ bargaining power.&nbsp; A recent Treasury Department report found that a lack of labor-market competition decreases wages by roughly 20 percent, as compared to a fully competitive market.<a href="#_ftn20" id="_ftnref20">[20]</a> &nbsp;This is one way that lack of competition has aggravated our inequality problems.<a href="#_ftn21" id="_ftnref21">[21]</a></p>



<p>In addition, lack of competition can dampen innovation.&nbsp; The empirical research favors a competition policy that encourages rival companies to reduce costs, strengthen quality, and develop new products, while retaining rewards for innovation.<a href="#_ftn22" id="_ftnref22">[22]</a>&nbsp; No pressure, no diamonds.</p>



<p>In short, our competition challenges ripple across our economy, harming workers, consumers, small businesses, our economic growth and competitiveness. &nbsp;One study by Thomas Philippon aggregated the harms from higher prices and lower wages and found that lack of competition could be costing the median American household some $5,000 every year.<a href="#_ftn23" id="_ftnref23">[23]</a></p>



<ol type="I"><li><strong>President Biden’s Competition Executive Order</strong></li></ol>



<p>It was against this backdrop that President Biden issued his executive order last July.<a href="#_ftn24" id="_ftnref24">[24]</a></p>



<p>This historic order has galvanized a government-wide effort to promote competition across our economy. &nbsp;At its core, it did three things:</p>



<p><strong><em>First</em></strong>, it directed 72 specific actions by more than a dozen agencies to take on concrete competition problems—from non-compete agreements to unjustifiable occupational licensing requirements, to prescription drugs and Internet bills, to airline tickets and device repairs, to personal banking and meat-processing.<a href="#_ftn25" id="_ftnref25">[25]</a> &nbsp;Our agencies worked hard to deliver over the last year. &nbsp;Here are just a few examples of what’s changing as a result:&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The FDA is changing its regulations so that hearing aids for mild-to-moderate hearing loss can be sold over-the-counter.<a href="#_ftn26" id="_ftnref26">[26]</a> &nbsp;Roughly 48 million Americans suffer from hearing loss.<a href="#_ftn27" id="_ftnref27">[27]</a> &nbsp;We expect this to be a gamechanger—spurring innovation and reducing hearing-aid prices.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Agriculture Department is issuing a suite of new rules under the Packers and Stockyards Act, including finally changing the unfair contracting system for poultry farmers.<a href="#_ftn28" id="_ftnref28">[28]</a></li></ul>



<ul><li>Just last week, the Patent and Trademark Office and FDA announced plans to scrutinize drug patents that are driving up prices.<a href="#_ftn29" id="_ftnref29">[29]</a></li></ul>



<p>These efforts aren’t just about opening up markets to promote competition. &nbsp;They’re about looking inward, too—because government regulations can themselves get in the way of innovation and entry. &nbsp;Indeed, sometimes powerful incumbents have enlisted government to entrench themselves—so we’re working to lift regulatory barriers to encourage challengers to enter markets and compete.</p>



<p>We’re proud that the vast majority of the actions we’re taking have attracted bipartisan support. &nbsp;They’re also spurring the private sector and state legislatures to act. &nbsp;After President Biden’s executive order endorsed a “right to repair,” Apple<a href="#_ftn30" id="_ftnref30">[30]</a> and Microsoft<a href="#_ftn31" id="_ftnref31">[31]</a> announced they’d allow people to fix their own devices, and New York just passed the nation’s first “Fair Repair Law.”<a href="#_ftn32" id="_ftnref32">[32]</a></p>



<p><strong><em>Second</em></strong>, the order called on the traditional antitrust agencies—the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission—to fully and vigorously enforce our antitrust laws. &nbsp;The President nominated Jonathan Kanter to head DOJ’s Antitrust Division and Lina Khan lead the FTC. &nbsp;Both received broad bipartisan support in the Senate and are now ably leading these efforts. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Their work requires developing sensible frameworks and pursuing cases zealously in a challenging legal environment.&nbsp; It requires thinking forward to new industries and new technologies—including the challenges posed by the rise of the dominant Internet platforms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it requires resources to rebuild capability. &nbsp;During just the last decade, our economic output increased by nearly half,<a href="#_ftn33" id="_ftnref33">[33]</a> and the annual number of completed mergers and acquisitions doubled.<a href="#_ftn34" id="_ftnref34">[34]</a>&nbsp; Yet total appropriations for DOJ’s Antitrust Division<a href="#_ftn35" id="_ftnref35">[35]</a> and the FTC<a href="#_ftn36" id="_ftnref36">[36]</a> have been essentially flat—and <em>decreased</em> in real terms.&nbsp; Keep in mind, these agencies’ core missions involve bringing complex cases against some of the best-resourced companies in the world. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Even under these constraints, our antitrust enforcement agencies have achieved important but underreported legal victories over the past year. &nbsp;The FTC, for example, worked with the Pentagon to challenge a vertical merger and keep the largest defense contractor from acquiring a major missile-component producer—likely saving taxpayers billions.<a href="#_ftn37" id="_ftnref37">[37]</a> &nbsp;And DOJ blocked a $30 billion merger between two of the world’s largest insurance brokers that would have raised prices.<a href="#_ftn38" id="_ftnref38">[38]</a></p>



<p>It’s unacceptable for these agencies’ resources to lag so far behind the growth of the economy they’re charged with protecting.&nbsp; That’s why President Biden’s Budget calls for boosting funding for both agencies, and that’s why we’ve supported passing the Merger Filing Fee Modernization Act. &nbsp;Congress should act swiftly to deliver these enhanced resources.</p>



<p><strong><em>Finally</em></strong>, the executive order prioritized <em>structural</em> change in our competition policy by establishing the White House Competition Council.&nbsp; The Council, which I chair, currently includes 17 federal agencies, and their leaders meet with the President twice a year.<a href="#_ftn39" id="_ftnref39">[39]</a>&nbsp; This body institutionalizes competition policy as part of our overall economic policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This structural element of establishing a Competition Council may sound at first like government arcana—but in fact it’s profoundly important to turning this aircraft carrier around.&nbsp; Because what we need, at core, is capacity, creativity, and coordination across the federal government. And I want to take a moment to thank every cabinet secretary and leader of the 17 Council members for their leadership over the course of the last year. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This structure marks a fundamental innovation by President Biden—something that’s never been done before in history: Agencies are now working together to leverage <em>all </em>legally available tools to promote competition. &nbsp;That means not only more coordination and collaboration, but also a newfound ability to survey the entire economic landscape and assess how competition policy intersects with other areas, like trade policy and supply chains.</p>



<p>One year in, the Competition Council has spurred collaboration and cross-pollination between agencies. &nbsp;To take just one example, the Justice and Agriculture Departments together launched FarmerFairness.gov, a one-stop shop for reporting suspected legal violations in agriculture.<a href="#_ftn40" id="_ftnref40">[40]</a> &nbsp;Make no mistake, that’s not just another website—it reflects an innovative approach to enforcement, where these two departments now review every complaint together to assess how to best deploy <em>both </em>sets of legal authorities.</p>



<p>The Competition Council has also successfully set priorities in critical areas that are particularly important to our economy, like ocean shipping.&nbsp; Competition and performance issues in ocean shipping have spillover effects across the economy, because many businesses rely on it to transport their goods.</p>



<p>The ocean-freight system is dominated by three global alliances.&nbsp; The impact has been stark: during the pandemic, the price of shipping a container rose more than 10-fold.<a href="#_ftn41" id="_ftnref41">[41]</a> &nbsp;We’re proud that Congress answered President Biden’s call to crack down on these price hikes and unfair practices by passing the bipartisan Ocean Shipping Reform Act—the most significant reform of ocean shipping rules in decades.<a href="#_ftn42" id="_ftnref42">[42]</a></p>



<p>We’re putting forward an array of other priorities, too—from opening up labor markets<a href="#_ftn43" id="_ftnref43">[43]</a> to fighting misleading pricing.<a href="#_ftn44" id="_ftnref44">[44]</a> &nbsp;Another key area is promoting competition in the tech sector, to give small businesses and startups a better chance to compete on a level playing field. That’s why I want to reinforce our Administration’s call for Congress to pass bipartisan tech antitrust legislation.</p>



<p>Finally, the Competition Council is helping embed competition thinking into agencies’ operations.&nbsp; Our agencies are going beyond the executive order’s immediate directives to new frontiers. &nbsp;The Transportation Department just issued rules to make our new, federally funded electric-vehicle charging network open and interoperable.<a href="#_ftn45" id="_ftnref45">[45]</a> &nbsp;That wasn’t specified in the executive order, but thanks to the Competition Council’s work, we recognized the risks and potential and took action.</p>



<ol type="I"><li><strong>Reinforcing the Case for Competition</strong></li></ol>



<p>Across each of these areas—concrete agency actions; reinvigoration of antitrust enforcement; and structural change in our approach to competition policy—we’ve made great progress.</p>



<p>But before we look forward, I want to pause to clarify some things we <em>haven’t </em>been doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>First</em></strong>, we have not, and will not, adopt a blanket policy that “big is bad,” or that there’s a one-size-fits-all approach to antitrust and competition policy. &nbsp;Not in E.O. 14036, and not in any of our work.&nbsp; We do take the view that market structure matters, and that we need be concerned about highly concentrated markets—particularly in an environment where our antitrust agencies have been under-resourced for so long.&nbsp; But that’s different from fighting bigness for bigness’s sake.</p>



<p>And<em> <strong>second</strong></em>, we don’t see competition as the singular cure for inflation, nor do we see it as the driving cause of the global inflation we are dealing with today. &nbsp;At the same time, it <em>is </em>easier for firms to maintain higher prices in a market with just a few rivals.<a href="#_ftn46" id="_ftnref46">[46]</a> &nbsp;That’s why promoting competition is one tool—not the only one, but one tool—that can help lower price pressures in the economy across time.</p>



<p>Looking ahead, the case for bolstering competition is particularly powerful because it supports another important objective: resilience. &nbsp;A market with more competitors is usually better-equipped to handle disruptions and deliver to businesses and consumers what they need. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Consider:</p>



<ul><li>After a cyberattack hit the country’s second-largest meat processing company last year, the company had to suspend production at its plants—which process one-quarter of America’s beef and one-fifth of its pork.<a href="#_ftn47" id="_ftnref47">[47]</a></li></ul>



<ul><li>And as we saw with infant formula this year, the closure of a single plant—owned by a company that controls almost half the market—created a national shortage.<a href="#_ftn48" id="_ftnref48">[48]</a> &nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>This is one more reason sound competition policy belongs at the center of our economic policy. &nbsp;By addressing the underlying structural problem of competition, we make our supply chains more resilient—more capable of dealing with whatever shocks may come.&nbsp;</p>



<ol type="I"><li><strong>Looking Ahead</strong></li></ol>



<p>I’ve talked about what we’ve done in the last year, and why. &nbsp;But there’s much more ahead.</p>



<p>In the coming months, we’ll deliver on more of the executive order’s commitments—everything from new rules to provide airline travelers<a href="#_ftn49" id="_ftnref49">[49]</a> and broadband customers<a href="#_ftn50" id="_ftnref50">[50]</a> with upfront information to comparison-shop, to the Treasury Department collaborating with the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau on fintech.<a href="#_ftn51" id="_ftnref51">[51]</a></p>



<p>We’ll also keep pushing to institutionalize competition work across the government. &nbsp;Right now, we’re focused on bringing in the sharpest talent to drive this work. &nbsp;We’ll have more to say soon, but for all the economists, policy experts, and litigators out there—now is the time for you to consider public service. &nbsp;Your country needs you, and it’s an exciting and historic moment. &nbsp;Help us keep turning the ship.</p>



<p><strong>Conclusion</strong></p>



<p>America has boldly recalibrated its competitiveness before—and instituted durable, structural change.&nbsp; Teddy Roosevelt did it.&nbsp; Franklin Roosevelt did it, too.&nbsp; Today, we stand at another inflection point.&nbsp; It’s within our grasp to do it again.</p>



<p>We know that innovation and openness are part of America’s economic DNA.&nbsp; This is a nation that’s led technological revolutions across industries for two centuries, and repeatedly transformed the global economy for the better. &nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden’s actions to promote competition carry that same spirit.&nbsp; We’re confronting decades of growing market power and corporate concentration.&nbsp; That won’t be reversed overnight.&nbsp; But we’re going to keep working tirelessly to turn this ship around—and set us on a course that better serves America’s economic dynamism.</p>



<p>Thank you—and I look forward to this conversation.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator" />



<p><a href="#_ftnref1" id="_ftn1">[1]</a> <em>Remarks by President Biden at Signing of an Executive Order Promoting Competition in the American Economy</em>, White House (July 9, 2021), https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-an-executive-order-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref2" id="_ftn2">[2]</a> <em>Northern Securities Co. v. United States</em>, 193 U.S. 197 (1904).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref3" id="_ftn3">[3]</a> <em>Swift &amp; Co. v. United States</em>, 196 U.S. 375 (1905).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref4" id="_ftn4">[4]</a> <em>Standard Oil Co. of N.J. v. United States</em>, 221 U.S. 1 (1911).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref5" id="_ftn5">[5]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, Doris Kearns Goodwin, The Bully Pulpit: Theodore Roosevelt, William Howard Taft, and the Golden Age of Journalism 444-66 (2013); Sidney Milkis, <em>Theodore Roosevelt: Domestic Affairs</em>, Univ. of Va.: Miller Ctr., https://millercenter.org/president/roosevelt/domestic-affairs (last visited July 14, 2022).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref6" id="_ftn6">[6]</a> Council of Econ. Advisers, White House, Benefits of Competition and Indicators of Market Power 4 (Apr. 2016), https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/sites/default/files/page/files/20160414_cea_competition_issue_brief.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref7" id="_ftn7">[7]</a> Gustavo Grullon, Yelena Larkin &amp; Roni Michaely, <em>Are US Industries Becoming More Concentrated?</em>, 23 Rev. Fin. 697, 698 (2019), https://academic.oup.com/rof/article/23/4/697/5477414.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref8" id="_ftn8">[8]</a> David Autor et al., <em>Concentrating on the Fall of the Labor Share</em>, 107 Am. Econ. Rev. 180 (2017), https://pubs.aeaweb.org/doi/pdfplus/10.1257/aer.p20171102.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref9" id="_ftn9">[9]</a> Jason Furman &amp; Peter Orszag, <em>Slower Productivity and Higher Inequality: Are They Related?</em> (Peterson Inst. for Int’l Econ. Working Paper No. 18-4, 2018), https://www.piie.com/system/files/documents/wp18-4.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref10" id="_ftn10">[10]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, Jonathan B. Baker, The Antitrust Paradigm: Restoring a Competitive Economy (2019); <em>see also</em> Jonathan B. Baker &amp; Carl Shapiro, <em>Reinvigorating Horizontal Merger Enforcement</em>, <em>in</em> How the Chicago School Overshot the Mark (Robert Pitofsky ed., 2008), https://faculty.haas.berkeley.edu/shapiro/mergerpolicy.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref11" id="_ftn11">[11]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, Fiona Scott Morton, <em>Reforming U.S. Antitrust Enforcement and Competition Policy</em>, <em>in</em> Vision 2020: Evidence for a Stronger Economy (2020); Herbert Hovenkamp &amp; Fiona M. Scott Morton, <em>Framing the Chicago </em><em>School of Antitrust Analysis</em>, 168 U. Pa. L. Rev. 1843 (2020), https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=3481388.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref12" id="_ftn12">[12]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, Nancy L. Rose, <em>Concerns About Competition</em>, <em>in</em> Maintaining the Strength of American Capitalism (Melissa S. Kearney &amp; Amy Ganz eds., 2019); <em>Competition Policy for the Twenty-First Century: The Case for Antitrust Reform: Hearing Before the S. Comm. on the Judiciary</em>, 117th Cong. (statement of Nancy L. Rose, Professor, MIT), https://www.judiciary.senate.gov/imo/media/doc/Rose%20-Written%20Testimony%2011<br>%20March%202021.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref13" id="_ftn13">[13]</a> John E. Kwoka, Jr., <em>Does Merger Control Work? A Retrospective on U.S. Enforcement Actions and Merger Outcomes</em>, 78 Antitrust L.J. 619, 632 (2013), https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=1954849; <em>see also</em> John Kwoka, Mergers, Merger Control, and Remedies: A Retrospective Analysis of U.S. Policy (2015).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref14" id="_ftn14">[14]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, Martin Gaynor &amp; Robert Town, <em>The Impact of Hospital Consolidation—Update</em>, Robert Wood Johnson Found. (June 2012), https://www.rwjf.org/en/library/research/2012/06/the-impact-of-hospital-consolidation.html.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref15" id="_ftn15">[15]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, Craig Peters, <em>Evaluating the Performance of Merger Simulation: Evidence from the U.S. Airline Industry</em>, 49 J.L. &amp; Econ. 627 (2006), https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/abs/10.1086/505369.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref16" id="_ftn16">[16]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, José Azar, Ioana Marinescu &amp; Marshall Steinbaum, <em>Measuring Labor Market Power Two Ways</em>, 109 Am. Econ. Ass’n Papers &amp; Proceedings 317 (2019), https://pubs.aeaweb.org/doi/pdfplus/10.1257/pandp.20191068; José Azar, Ioana Marinescu &amp; Marshall I. Steinbaum, <em>Labor Market Concentration</em> (NBER Working Paper No. 24,147, 2017) https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w24147/revisions/w24147.rev0.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref17" id="_ftn17">[17]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, <em>supra </em>note 16; Ioana Marinescu &amp; Herbert J. Hovenkamp, <em>Anticompetitive Mergers in Labor Markets</em>, 94 Ind. L.J. 1031 (2019), https://www.repository.law.indiana.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=11340&amp;context=ilj.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref18" id="_ftn18">[18]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, <em>supra</em> note 16.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref19" id="_ftn19">[19]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, Eric A. Posner, How Antitrust Failed Workers (2021); <em>see also</em> Suresh Naidu, Eric A. Posner &amp; E. Glen Weyl, <em>Antitrust Remedies for Labor Market Power</em>, 132 Harv. L. Rev. 536 (2018), https://harvardlawreview.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/536-601_Online.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref20" id="_ftn20">[20]</a> U.S. Dep’t of the Treasury, The State of Labor Market Competition, at ii (2022), https://home.treasury.gov<br>/system/files/136/State-of-Labor-Market-Competition-2022.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref21" id="_ftn21">[21]</a> <em>Cf.</em> Sean Ennis, Pedro Gonzaga &amp; Chris Pike, <em>Inequality: A Hidden Cost of Market Power</em> (OECD Working Paper No. DAF/COMP(2015)10, 2017), https://www.oecd.org/daf/competition/Inequality-hidden-cost-market-power-2017.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref22" id="_ftn22">[22]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, Jonathan Baker, <em>Beyond Schumpeter vs. Arrow: How Antitrust Fosters Innovation</em>, 74 Antitrust L.J. 575 (2007), https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=962261; Giulio Federico, Fiona Scott Morton &amp; Carl Shapiro, <em>Antitrust and Innovation: Welcoming and Protecting Disruption</em>, <em>in</em> Innovation Policy and the Economy (Josh Lerner &amp; Scott Stern eds., 2020), https://www.law.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/Shapiro-Carl-Antitrust-and-Innovation-Welcoming-and-Protecting-Disruption.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref23" id="_ftn23">[23]</a> <em>See</em> Thomas Philippon, The Great Reversal: How America Gave Up on Free Markets (2019).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref24" id="_ftn24">[24]</a> Exec. Order No. 14,036, 86 Fed. Reg. 36,987 (July 9, 2021), https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021<br>/07/14/2021-15069/promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref25" id="_ftn25">[25]</a> <em>Id.</em>; <em>see also</em> <em>Fact Sheet: Executive Order on Promoting Competition in the American Economy</em>, White House (July 9, 2021), https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref26" id="_ftn26">[26]</a> <em>FDA Issues Landmark Proposal To Improve Access to Hearing Aid Technology for Millions of Americans</em>, U.S. Food &amp; Drug Admin. (October 19, 2021), https://www.fda.gov/news-events/press-announcements/fda-issues-landmark-proposal-improve-access-hearing-aid-technology-millions-americans.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref27" id="_ftn27">[27]</a> <em>One in Five Americans Has Hearing Loss</em>, Johns Hopkins Med. (Nov. 14, 2011), https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/news/media/releases/one_in_five_americans_has_hearing_loss.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref28" id="_ftn28">[28]</a> <em>Biden-Harris Administration Announces New Actions To Strengthen Food Supply Chains, Level the Playing Field for Growers, and Lower Prices for American Consumers</em>, U.S. Dep’t of Agric. (May 26, 2022), https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/05/26/biden-harris-administration-announces-new-actions-strengthen-food.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref29" id="_ftn29">[29]</a> Kathi Vidal &amp; Robert M. Califf, <em>The Biden Administration Is Acting To Promote Competition and Lower Drug Prices for All Americans</em>, U.S. Patent &amp; Trademark Office (July 6, 2022), https://www.uspto.gov/blog/director<br>/entry/the-biden-administration-is-acting.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref30" id="_ftn30">[30]</a> J. Fingas, <em>Apple’s Self Service Program Will Let You Repair iPhones and Macs Yourself</em>, Engadget (Nov. 17, 2021), https://www.engadget.com/apple-self-service-repair-iphone-mac-142122774.html.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref31" id="_ftn31">[31]</a> B. Menegus, <em>iFixit Partners with Microsoft on Official Repair Tools</em>, Engadget (Dec. 14, 2021), https://www.engadget.com/ifixit-microsoft-repair-tools-partnership-170115725.html.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref32" id="_ftn32">[32]</a> Russell Brandom, <em>New York State Passes First-Ever ‘Right To Repair’ Law for Electronics</em>, Verge (June 3, 2022), https://www.theverge.com/2022/6/3/23153504/right-to-repair-new-york-state-law-ifixit-repairability-diy.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref33" id="_ftn33">[33]</a> <em>See Gross Domestic Product</em>, Fed. Reserve Bank of St. Louis: FRED, https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/GDP (last visited July 14, 2022).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref34" id="_ftn34">[34]</a> <em>See</em> <em>United States – M&amp;A Statistics</em>, Inst. for Mergers, Acquisitions &amp; Alls., https://imaa-institute.org<br>/mergers-and-acquisitions-statistics/united-states-ma-statistics (last visited July 14, 2022).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref35" id="_ftn35">[35]</a> <em>See</em> <em>Appropriation Figures for the Antitrust Division, Fiscal Years 1903-2021</em>, U.S. Dep’t of Justice, https://www.justice.gov/atr/appropriation-figures-antitrust-division (last modified June 1, 2021).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref36" id="_ftn36">[36]</a> <em>See</em> <em>FTC Appropriation and Full-Time Equivalent (FTE) History</em>, Fed. Trade Comm’n, https://www.ftc.gov<br>/about-ftc/bureaus-offices/office-executive-director/financial-management-office/ftc-appropriation (last visited July 14, 2022).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref37" id="_ftn37">[37]</a> <em>See Statement Regarding Termination of Lockheed Martin Corporation’s Attempted Acquisition of Aerojet Rocketdyne Holdings Inc.</em>, Fed. Trade Comm’n (Feb. 15, 2022), https://www.ftc.gov/news-events/news/press-releases/2022/02/statement-regarding-termination-lockheed-martin-corporations-attempted-acquisition-aerojet.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref38" id="_ftn38">[38]</a> <em>Attorney General Merrick B. Garland’s Statement on Aon and Willis Towers Watson Decision To Terminate Merger Agreement</em>, U.S. Dep’t of Justice (July 26, 2021), https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/attorney-general-merrick-b-garland-s-statement-aon-and-willis-towers-watson-decision.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref39" id="_ftn39">[39]</a> <em>See</em> <em>White House Competition Council</em>, White House, https://www.whitehouse.gov/competition (last visited July 14, 2022).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref40" id="_ftn40">[40]</a> <em>Justice Department and U.S. Department of Agriculture Launch Online Tool Allowing Farmers, Ranchers To Report Anticompetitive Practices</em>, U.S. Dep’t of Justice (Feb. 3, 2021), https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-and-us-department-agriculture-launch-online-tool-allowing-farmers-ranchers.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref41" id="_ftn41">[41]</a> <em>Fact Sheet: Lowering Prices and Leveling the Playing Field in Ocean Shipping</em>, White House (Feb. 28, 2022), https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-lowering-prices-and-leveling-the-playing-field-in-ocean-shipping.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref42" id="_ftn42">[42]</a> <em>Statement by President Joe Biden on Congressional Passage of Ocean Shipping Reform Act</em>, White House (June 13, 2022), https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-congressional-passage-of-ocean-shipping-reform-act.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref43" id="_ftn43">[43]</a> <em>Departments of Justice and Labor Strengthen Partnership To Protect Workers</em>, U.S. Dep’t of Justice (Mar. 10, 2022), https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/departments-justice-and-labor-strengthen-partnership-protect-workers.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref44" id="_ftn44">[44]</a> <em>E.g.</em>, <em>CFPB Moves to Reduce Junk Fees Charged by Debt Collectors</em>, Consumer Fin. Prot. Bureau (June 29, 2022), https://www.consumerfinance.gov/about-us/newsroom/cfpb-moves-to-reduce-junk-fees-charged-by-debt-collectors;<em> Enhancing Transparency of Airline Ancillary Service Fees: Department of Transportation</em>, Office of Mgmt. &amp; Budget: Office of Info. &amp; Regulatory Affairs, https://www.reginfo.gov/public/do/eAgendaViewRule<br>?pubId=202204&amp;RIN=2105-AF10 (last visited July 14, 2022); <em>FCC Acts To Empower Broadband Consumers Through Transparency</em>, Fed. Commc’ns Comm’n (Jan. 27, 2022), https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-acts-empower-broadband-consumers-through-transparency-0.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref45" id="_ftn45">[45]</a> <em>Biden-Harris Administration Takes Key Step Forward in Building a National Network of User-Friendly, Reliable, and Accessible Electric Vehicle Chargers</em>, U.S. Dep’t of Transp. (June 9, 2022), https://www.transportation.gov<br>/briefing-room/biden-harris-administration-takes-key-step-forward-building-national-network-user.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref46" id="_ftn46">[46]</a> <em>See </em>U.S. Dep’t of Justice &amp; Fed. Trade Comm’n, Horizontal Merger Guidelines §7.2 (2010), https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/atr/legacy/2010/08/19/hmg-2010.pdf;Marc Ivaldi et al., The Economics of Tacit Collusion: Final Report for DG Competition, European Commission (2003), https://ec.europa.eu/competition/mergers/studies_reports/the_economics_of_tacit_collusion_en.pdf.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref47" id="_ftn47">[47]</a> <em>See </em>U.S. Dep’t of Agric., USDA Agri-Food Supply Chain Assessment: Program and Policy Options for Strengthening Resilience 12 (2022), https://www.ams.usda.gov/sites/default/files/media<br>/USDAAgriFoodSupplyChainReport.pdf;<em> see also</em> Jesse Newman &amp; Jacob Bunge, <em>Meat Supplies Tighten as Cyberattack on JBS Snarls Food Chain</em>, Wall St. J. (June 2, 2021), https://www.wsj.com/articles/jbs-meat-plants-face-slow-restart-after-cyberattack-11622633982.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref48" id="_ftn48">[48]</a> <em>See, e.g.</em>, Julie Creswell &amp; Madeleine Ngo, <em>Baby Formula Shortage Has an Aggravating Factor: Few Producers</em>, N.Y. Times (May 20, 2022), https://www.nytimes.com/2022/05/20/business/economy/baby-formula-shortage-market.html; Madison Muller &amp; Leah Nylen, <em>How US Baby Formula Monopolies Have Failed Families</em>, Bloomberg (May 20, 2022), https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2022-05-20/baby-formula-shortage-shows-risk-of-us-industry-concentration.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref49" id="_ftn49">[49]</a> <em>See Enhancing Transparency of Airline Ancillary Service Fees: Department of Transportation</em>, Office of Mgmt. &amp; Budget: Office of Info. &amp; Regulatory Affairs, https://www.reginfo.gov/public/do/eAgendaViewRule?pubId<br>=202204&amp;RIN=2105-AF10 (last visited July 14, 2022).</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref50" id="_ftn50">[50]</a> <em>See FCC Acts To Empower Broadband Consumers Through Transparency</em>, Fed. Commc’ns Comm’n (Jan. 27, 2022), https://www.fcc.gov/document/fcc-acts-empower-broadband-consumers-through-transparency-0.</p>



<p><a href="#_ftnref51" id="_ftn51">[51]</a> <em>See </em>Exec. Order No. 14,036, 86 Fed. Reg. 36,987 (July 9, 2021), https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021<br>/07/14/2021-15069/promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By Vice President Harris After Air Force Two&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-air-force-two-arrival-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Q    Madam Vice President, why come to Florida?  Why come to Florida on an issue like abortion rights?  Do you believe it&#8217;s going to really turn out voters here? THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So, I&#8217;m here in Florida to do a number of things.  Immediately, I&#8217;m going to be speaking with a group of Black women leaders about&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Q    Madam Vice President, why come to Florida?  Why come to Florida on an issue like abortion rights?  Do you believe it&#8217;s going to really turn out voters here?<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So, I&#8217;m here in Florida to do a number of things. <br> <br>Immediately, I&#8217;m going to be speaking with a group of Black women leaders about the issues that I believe are most pressing and most immediate for the women of America, including the issue of choice. <br> <br>Later, I&#8217;ll be meeting with Florida State legislators.<br> <br>And then, I will end the day here in Florida, in Tampa, meeting with American servicemembers who are working in an extraordinary way to defend our liberties and our freedoms and to ensure the security of our homeland. <br> <br>When I think about the issue of choice, the President and I feel very strongly that we have a duty and obligation to protect the American people, including American women, and that includes the women in Florida. <br> <br>Here in Florida, just most recently, a law was passed &#8212; effective, I believe, July 1st &#8212; that is going to allow the government to impose its decisions on the women of Florida instead of giving women the right to choose to make decisions about some of the most personal matters a woman could have to deal with. <br> <br>We say and it is our position and it’s the position of the majorit- &#8212; of the majority of Americans: Let women, including the women of Florida, make those most personal decisions for themselves, in consultation with their priest or their pastor or their rabbi.  But it should not be the government making those decisions.<br> <br>In Florida, in particular, there&#8217;s no exception for rape or incest.<br> <br>So, I&#8217;m here to speak with these leaders to talk about what we can do together to ensure that we use all that is within our capacity to protect the women of America, which includes the women of Florida.<br>    <br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in Roundtable Discussion With State&#160;Legislators</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-roundtable-discussion-with-state-legislators/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57536</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Orange County Convention CenterOrlando, Florida THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I want to thank the Florida State legislators for joining us this afternoon for a discussion about one of the, I think, most pressing issues facing our country today, which revrol- &#8212; revolves around the point that every woman in America should be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Orange County Convention Center<br><em>Orlando, Florida</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I want to thank the Florida State legislators for joining us this afternoon for a discussion about one of the, I think, most pressing issues facing our country today, which revrol- &#8212; revolves around the point that every woman in America should be free to make decisions, some of the most intimate decisions a woman can make, about their own bodies and their life.<br><br>And we are having this conversation in the context of a Supreme Court that took a constitutional right, that had been recognized, from the women of America.<br><br>We&#8217;re having this conversation in the context of states and so-called leaders of states, such as some in Florida, who are seeking to restrict a woman&#8217;s right to make decisions about her own body at a state level.<br><br>And I think that we collectively agree, as do most Americans, that there are certain things the government should just not interfere with.&nbsp; And one of them is what should be the right of every American to make the most intimate decisions about what I like to call “heart and home.”<br><br>So that&#8217;s the context in which we are having this conversation.&nbsp; I think many of us also agree that this is not an issue that requires any particular person to change their faith or their belief system.&nbsp; It is simply that we should agree that in a democracy, in America, the government should not interfere with certain decisions.&nbsp; Let the woman make that decision with her doctor, her loved ones, her pastor, her priest, her rabbi.&nbsp; But the government should not be doing that.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So that&#8217;s the cons- &#8212; that&#8217;s the issue.&nbsp; That is also a constitutional issue.&nbsp; And &#8212; and we know that this fight to stand up for these rights is occurring and will occur on a national level, but certainly is also happening at a state level.&nbsp; And so I applaud the leaders who are here.&nbsp;<br><br>When the President and I think about our responsibilities, it is certainly to do the work I&#8217;ve done my entire career, which is to fight for the safety, health, and wellbeing of the women of America.&nbsp; And that, of course, includes the women of Florida.<br><br>And so we&#8217;re here to have that conversation and &#8212; and also to recognize that this is not happening in a vacuum.&nbsp; I look at a state like Florida, and it is from the same so-called leaders that these restrictions are being imposed on women that there are also restrictions on voting rights.&nbsp; There are also restrictions on the rights that members of our LGBTQ+ community should have, to live and love freely.<br><br>And so this is the environment in which &#8212; in which we work.&nbsp; And we will together do what we can to stand together for the people of America and each state, and also to build the coalitions between all of the communities that are directly impacted, with the knowledge that the whole country has something at stake when we are looking at these laws.<br><br>So with that, I thank you all.&nbsp; And I want to, in particular, thank Secretary of Health and Human Services, Xavier Becerra, for his leadership &#8212; longstanding leadership &#8212; and also through the agency he runs.<br><br>And so I will invite you, Secretary Becerra, if you can begin the discussion, and then we&#8217;ll go around the table.<br><br>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; Madam Vice President, I will begin by saying, first, thank you for coming to Florida.&nbsp; Thank you for inviting me to come, because we know that there are champions here for access to healthcare everywhere in America.&nbsp; But certainly here in Florida, we know folks are fighting &#8212; the leaders in the medical community, leaders in our legislative community, and we want to say thank you for that.<br><br>And we, at HHS, hope to put in action the instructions you and the President have given us to try to make sure we preserve that access to care, that we continue to protect those rights that Americans did know for some 50 years, and that we do it in a way that continues to move our country forward instead of moving backwards.<br><br>I think most of us have always known America as a place where the best days are ahead, and that requires us to believe in that.&nbsp; And so I&#8217;m thrilled to be able to speak to folks here in Florida about the actions that you and the President have asked HHS to take on.<br><br>And so thank you very much for the invitation.<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Secretary.&nbsp; And with that, we will go around the table.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d invite Dr. Schickler to my right to offer a few words about your perspective as the chief medical officer of Planned Parenthood of <s>Southeast </s>[Southwest] and Central Florida.<br><br>(Press departs.)<br><br>END</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By Vice President Harris At Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority’s 70th&#160;Boule</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-alpha-kappa-alpha-sororitys-70th-boule/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Orange County Convention CenterOrlando, Florida 11:48 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning, sorors!  (Applause.)  (Laughs.)  Oh, my goodness.  Oh.  Good morning, good morning, good morning.  (Applause.) Please have a seat.  We have so much to talk about.  (Laughter.)  Oh, my goodness.  What a sight my eyes do behold.  (Applause.) It is so good to be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Orange County Convention Center<br><em>Orlando, Florida</em></em></p>



<p>11:48 A.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good morning, sorors!  (Applause.)  (Laughs.)  Oh, my goodness.  Oh.  Good morning, good morning, good morning.  (Applause.)<br></p>



<p>Please have a seat.  We have so much to talk about.  (Laughter.)  Oh, my goodness.  What a sight my eyes do behold.  (Applause.)<br><br>It is so good to be here.  I can’t even explain how this feels.  I can’t even explain how this feels.  (Applause.)<br><br>To our Supreme Basileus, Dr. Glenda Glover &#8212; (applause); members of the Directorate; former Supreme Basilei; and all who serve Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated &#8212; (applause) &#8212; good morning to everyone.  Good morning.<br> <br>Dr. Glover, you have been a tremendous friend to me, and sister, over so many years, and a phenomenal leader of our sisterhood.  So I want to thank you in front of everyone &#8212; (applause) &#8212; for all that you have done and for your commitment, your enduring commitment to exemplify excellence.<br> <br>I also want to thank our International President, Danette Anthony Reed, as you guide us into the next chapter of our sorority.  (Applause.)  I’m so excited to walk with you on this journey.<br> <br>And what an amazing sight to look out and to see so many of our sorority sisters under one roof at the same time.  (Applause.)  I look out at all of you and, of course, I see family.<br> <br>In fact, our sorority, some of you may know, has been a part of my life since I was a little girl.  You see, my aunt, Christine Simmons, joined Alpha Kappa Alpha at Howard University in the year 1950.  And so &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  We know!<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Yes, you know.  And &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and when I was a teenager, she was basileus of Alpha Nu Omega chapter in Oakland, California.  (Applause.)  And when I graduated high school, there, of course, was no question that I would attend Howard University.  And I was determined, from a young girl, to join Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated.  (Applause.)  And, of course, this sisterhood remains a key part of who I am today.<br> <br>In fact, when Auntie Chris was basileus, I’ll never forget: She hosted one of our revered founders, Miss Norma E. Boyd.  And Miss Boyd was in her late 80s at the time, and we had a reception for her.  And she was then signing of her book, “A Love That Equals My Labors.”  And she signed a copy: “To Kamala, with love, Norma E. Boyd.”  And I will tell you, I proudly display the signed copy of that book in my West Wing office in the White House.  (Applause.)  Yes, I do.  The legacy lives on.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>And last month, I’ll tell you &#8212; and I see some of them here &#8212; I was so proud to host my line sisters, the 38 Jewels of Iridescent Splendor &#8212; (applause) &#8212; at my home in the official residence of the Vice President of the United States.  (Applause.)<br> <br>All of that being just one of the thousands of stories of how enduring and lifelong and through the generations our sisterhood is.<br><br>Our sorority, along with all the Divine Nine organizations, was founded to create lasting bonds of community.<br> <br>All of our founders were acutely aware we needed to build networks of support for young Black men and women who attend college in America.<br> <br>AKA, of course, was the first sorority created to meet this call.  (Applause.)<br> <br>As we all remember, Ethel Hedgemon Lyle led the effort to found our sisterhood &#8212; and in the face of terrible challenges.<br> <br>Just think: In the year 1908, when our soro- &#8212; sorority was founded, 89 Black people were lynched across the country.  Just think: At the time of the founding of our sorority, American life was deeply segregated.<br> <br>When Miss Lyle attended Howard, less than a quarter of the students were women.  And yet, despite all of this, and perhaps because of it, she believed in the power of sisterhood and in the power of service to create desperately needed social and legal change &#8212; beliefs that guide us all to today.<br><br>Our legacy is service to all mankind, and our work in Mississippi alone over the last 87 years is a perfect example.<br> <br>During the Great Depression, our sorors provided free medical care to poor Black women in the Mississippi Delta.  (Applause.)  And generations later, many of you here ran vaccination drives in those same communities during the COVID pandemic.  (Applause.)  It’s but one example of so many.<br> <br>You know, recently I was reminded of another example of our longstanding, enduring commitment to service when I was a member of the United States Senate.<br> <br>So across the street from the United States Senate &#8212; and my office is in the Hart building, it’s called &#8212; sits the Library of Congress.  And I would visit the Library of Congress from time to time.  And one time I visited, and the librarian was very proud to show me an old photograph from the year 1950 of President Truman.<br><br>He was meeting with representatives from the National Pan-Hellenic Council, which included a member of our sorority, to talk about ending employment discrimination in America.<br> <br>And fast-forward to today, there are recent photographs &#8212; very recent &#8212; of the Divine Nine presidents at the White House while they met with me in the Ceremonial Office of the Vice President of the United States.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And these photographs are a testament, then, to how members of the Divine Nine have always made sure Black voices are in the rooms where decisions are being made &#8212; (applause) &#8212; how our advocacy has been the history of moving the highest levels of government into action, and how we will always fight for what our communities need and for the best of who we are as a nation.<br> <br>In the year 2020, our sorority proved this yet again.  Our sorority registered more than 250,000 people to vote.  (Applause.)  Our sorority teamed up with our Divine Nine sisters and strolled to the polls &#8212; (laughter and applause) &#8212; indeed &#8212; and with the entire Divine Nine to combat voter suppression.  And I will never forget how, during those long days, you turned out for almost every rally and campaign event.<br> <br>In fact, at one of my events, my &#8212; I was in a hold room in the back, and some folks who were working the event came, and they said, “Ma’am, there are a bunch of ladies out there wearing pink and green” &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; “and they’d like to see you.”  (Laughs.)  And of course I said, “Well, you bring them in immediately.  Those are my sorors!”  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, in 2020, just as a most recent example, you not only showed up for President Biden and me, you showed up for America.  (Applause.)  And together, we were joined in our fight for progress, which is part of our legacy.<br> <br>Together, we said we must fight to address the current challenges we face as a nation and that we are prepared to lead on issues like the Black maternal health crisis in our country.  (Applause.)  Because we know Black women are three times as likely to die from pregnancy-related causes, and we know women in rural America are more than one and a half times more likely to die.<br> <br>So, after the election, the President and I and all of us elevated the issue of maternal health to a national priority, building on the work that we did together over the years.<br> <br>In fact, for the first time, we hosted the women most impacted &#8212; Black women, rural women, Native women &#8212; to the White House to discuss &#8212; get this &#8212; at the White House to discuss the importance of doulas &#8212; (applause); to discuss and speak up and out about the issues of fibroids &#8212; (applause); post-partum depression; and the barriers to care for women of color and rural women.  (Applause.)  Because we’re not going to be quiet when we know there is a role and a need for us to serve.<br><br>And through the work we have done together, we’ve dedicated resources to hire and train doulas.  We have done the work of funding research to address the biggest contributors to maternal mortality, and to advance and speak about the need to advance culturally competent care.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Through the work that we did together on this issue, we have now got to the point where we have encouraged &#8212; in a positive way &#8212; encouraged states &#8212; urged them, cajoled them to understand that Medicaid postpartum coverage should not just be 2 months, it should be 12 months.  (Applause.)  Because the women who require and count on Medicaid coverage require that, after giving birth to a human being &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; that their needs are recognized for beyond just the first 2 months.  And this will benefit over a quarter million women as of today.  (Applause.)<br><br>Together, we all said we must help our children reach their God-given potential.  And so our administration extend &#8212; extended the Child Tax Credit, which lifted up nearly 40 percent of Black children in America out of poverty just last year alone.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We recognized working people are struggling and, in particular, when it comes to covering the cost of their basic needs, including the cost of raising a child.  So we passed a tax cut to give working families a tax cut of up to $8,000 a year, which gives folks more room in their budgets to buy food, medication, and school supplies for their children.<br> <br>We’ve been traveling the country.  Many of you have joined me in different places in our country to talk about the longstanding, very serious problem of lead pipes, where our babies are being forced to drink toxic water, having well documented, then, health consequences, including consequences to their ability to learn.<br><br>So, together, we did the work to remove lead pipes.  We are in the process of doing that to ensure that no child has to drink water poisoned with lead, and to make sure that we, again, are doing everything we can, understanding our children &#8212; God has given them so much capacity, but we here, on Earth, must do our part to make sure they are protected and can live in an environment that allows them to thrive.<br><br>Which is why, together, we have also addressed the issue of high-speed Internet.  Because I know there are a whole lot of folks here right now who know what that pandemic meant to your child’s ability to learn and go to school &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and what that required in terms of you having access and being able to afford high-speed Internet.<br><br>I travel the country.  I can’t tell you how many parents I met who would have to go and &#8212; and drive the kids to the local fast-food restaurant or library to have access to the public Wi-Fi there.  The kids would be in the back seat of the car, trying to do their homework.<br><br>We know what an education means in terms of what it allows for the future of one’s ability to grow and succeed.  However, so many of the children in our country will be impaired in that ability if they don’t have the basic tools, like access to high-speed Internet.<br><br>So we’ve invested billions of dollars to provide what we know needs to be access to high-speed Internet &#8212; (applause) &#8212; across the country, including subsidies for low-income and working families so that they can afford it, even if they have access.<br> <br>We have talked about the fact that so many of our children and, therefore, their families and their parents, are in need &#8212; in dire need of support when it comes to those children who have disabilities &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and what we need to do to ensure that the families have resources they need.  So we are fighting together for home health care work, that it is affordable. <br><br>We are fighting to say that if we want to have a nation that can compete around this world &#8212; Dr. Glover talked about it &#8212; I have been traveling all of this world as Vice President.  I have met with, I’m told, at least 80 prime ministers and presidents, talking with them about the challenges that face our world.<br>    <br>One of the common themes, everyone knows, is you invest in the children of a nation, you are investing in the future of a nation.  (Applause.)  And when we invest in the education of the children of a nation, we are doing the best &#8212; (applause) &#8212; in terms of ensuring certain outcomes.<br> <br>So, together, for example, we all said: Let&#8217;s support some of the most excellent academic institutions in the United States of America, which are referred to as HBCUs.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And so, under Dr. Glover’s leadership, our sorority raised millions of dollars for HBCUs &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and our administration invested an historic $5.8 billion in our HBCUs.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And as a point of personal privilege, as the first Vice President to be a graduate of an HBCU, I&#8217;m particularly proud of that fact.  (Laughs.) (Applause.) <br> <br>So, as we move forward, we know that there is more work to do.  And that means to ensure that we have invested in the success of all of the people of our nation.  And, Dr. Glover, again, I want to thank you for being the Vice Chair of the White House HBCU Initiative, which we can ensure will lead to its success.  (Applause.) <br> <br>So, Sorors, together, we said that our country must build more wealth and opportunity for all communities.  That is part of what we fight for. <br> <br>And our administration then invested billions of dollars in minority and women entrepreneurs, knowing there is nothing more important than building the wealth for most Americans, and that means investing in home ownership.  This is something the sorority has worked on through the years.<br> <br>We know, historically, that one of the impediments to economic health, growth, and wealth for the Black community has been biases in the system that allows for homeownership.  And that continues to today. <br> <br>So I&#8217;ve met with many of the leaders here and around the country to talk about the fact that one of the remaining issues in terms of the bias and the system is the bias in home appraisals.  (Applause.)  You (inaudible).  Right?  You&#8217;ve heard the stories. <br> <br>The stories of how a Black family wants to sell their home or learn the value of their home because maybe it is then the assets of that home that will be the basis of sending their child off to college or helping their child grow a business.  And then the appraisers come in and the family knows, &#8220;No, that sounds like a low estimate of the value of our home.&#8221; <br> <br>And there are stories, which I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ve all heard, about that family then having &#8212; friends of the family and other family who are white and inviting them to come in and put up their family pictures &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and the Black family takes down their own, leaves the house for a couple of days and the appraiser comes in and, lo and behold, the same house appraises for a higher amount.<br> <br>So, one of the issues we&#8217;ve been dealing with is speaking that truth and dealing with it around what we need to do to eliminate racial bias in home appraisals, understanding when we have an economic agenda, the value of a home for so many of our families is the greatest source of their wealth and intergenerational wealth.  (Applause.) <br> <br>So, moving forward, that is part of the work that we have done so that we can make sure that folks can realize the full and actual value of their home.<br> <br>When we look at then where we are, we also know that, together, we said, &#8220;Police reform is long overdue.&#8221;  We cannot stop having that discussion.  (Applause.)  And President Biden issued an executive order to increase accountability in policing, including a ban on chokeholds in federal law enforcement.  (Applause.)  And there is still more work to do.<br> <br>And last but not least: Together, we said we needed better representation on the federal courts.  (Applause.)  You know where I&#8217;m going.  (Laughs.)<br> <br>So, first, I will tell you and share with you, we have appointed the most diverse group of judges in the history of the United States &#8212; (applause) &#8212; including, of course, the first Black woman appointed to the United States Supreme Court: Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And I was so proud to be a part of that process.  And when we look at where she sits and think about our founders and think about everything that is the spirit behind who we are and why we serve, it&#8217;s such a perfect example of what makes all that work worthwhile. <br> <br>So, I say all of this and I went through that list of accomplishments because all of this was possible because of your work.  And I just want to remind you of that.  Because this is a group of leaders that is so invested in fighting for the best of our country. <br> <br>This is a group of leaders who know the power of service and the need in the power of service to create needed social and legal change.  And so all of that to say: Thank you, Sorors.  Thank you. <br> <br>Because this is the progress that you fought for.  And I’ve not had a chance before today to thank you all in one place for what you have done for the lives of people you may not ever meet and people who may never know your name.  This progress is what you stood in line for. <br> <br>And so I&#8217;m also here to say: We must do it again this November.  (Applause.)  Because there is still more work to do.  To have a strong workforce, we have to do more to support working parents.  We must continue the fight to make sure that parents don’t have to pay more than 7 percent of their income in childcare.  That’s the work we still have yet to complete.  (Applause.)<br> <br>We cannot let up our fight to lower the cost of home healthcare, including eldercare.  And we must continue the fight to lower the cost of prescription drugs, including insulin &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so that it is no more than $35 a month and not causing people to look at bankruptcy just to take care of their basic health needs.<br> <br>There is more work to do.  If we want as a nation to keep our communities safe from gun violence, well, we must demand that Congress has the courage to repeal the liability shield that protects gun manufacturers, and we must demand they have the courage to renew the assault weapons ban.  (Applause.) <br> <br>We have lost too many precious lives.  I attended the funeral in Buffalo of an 86-year-old grandmother.  And you know her story, and if not, I will share with you.  She was going to the grocery store after having left her husband who she’d been caring for, who’s in a nursing home.  She was just going to buy some groceries.  A matriarch of a family. <br> <br>So, in Buffalo. In Uvalde, those babies and their teachers.  In Highland Park, I went there within 24 hours of that massacre that was supposed to be a parade route.  And in communities and cities across our country.<br> <br>Listen, as we applaud &#8212; and we must applaud &#8212; our President, Joe Biden, for signing the first federal gun safety bill in 30 years &#8212; (applause) &#8212; he signed it. <br> <br>And there is still more work to do to see it through, especially when, in America today, while Black people are 13 percent of America’s population, Black people are 62 percent of gun homicide victims. <br> <br>This is our issue.  This is our issue in terms of our leadership on this issue of the need for reasonable gun safety laws.  It is an issue on which we lead because we know we have so much at stake as leaders in our country.  When young Black men are 18 times more likely to be victims of gun homicides, we will lead on this issue. <br> <br>And we have more work to do.  (Applause.) <br> <br>But I’m here to, obviously, speak a little truth &#8212; a lot of truth.  And so, in that spirit, the road to get there, to see it through, it’s not going to be easy.  It’s never been easy.<br> <br>And there are, as there have always been, forces that stand in our way.  Forces that oppose even the most &#8212; on this issue of gun safety &#8212; even the most commonsense gun safety proposals.  Forces that include extremist so-called leaders who, instead of expanding rights, work to restrict rights; these so-called leaders who, after we fought and marched &#8212; members of our sorority being among the greatest leaders, fought for the right to vote &#8212; these so-called leaders, right here in this state and in other places in the country, making it more difficult for people to vote!  (Applause.) <br> <br>So-called leaders: In neighboring states, making it even illegal to give folks food and water as they’re standing in line to vote.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And we know what we need to do.  One of the things we need to do is pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act and the Freedom to Vote Act.  (Applause.)  So-called leaders.<br> <br>So-called leaders who are in the process of criminalizing doctors and punishing women who want to make health decisions for themselves.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So we know what we need to do.  We need to continue to fight for a woman’s right to make the most intimate, personal decisions for herself, with her doctor, with her pastor, with her priest, with her loved ones, but not her government telling her what she’s supposed to do.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, all of this to say that we have a legacy of fighting for social and legal change in our country.  And when we have done that, everyone has benefitted.  When we have fought for social and legal change, it has never been about fighting against something, it’s about fighting for something for the benefit of all mankind.  (Applause.) <br> <br>And so much of what we have fought for is on the line again.  And so we know what we need to do.<br> <br>In particular &#8212; because I’m going to leave you with a couple specifics &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; we need two additional United States senators to protect voting rights.  (Applause.)  We need two additional United States senators to protect a woman’s right to make decisions about her own body.  (Applause.)  And we need to elect people who will defend these rights up and down the ballot &#8212; from district attorneys to state attorneys general to local sheriffs to governors.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And to make this happen, let us do what we do best: We build coalitions.  We know how to do that.  We got the meanest, baddest phone trees in the world.  (Laughter.)  We know how to network.  We are fueled in the deeply held belief that we all have so much more in common than what separates us. <br> <br>So let’s do the kind of work that we have done, because we do it so well, and continue to activate and organize our communities.  Let’s continue to be on the frontlines of the greatest movement for progress in our country.<br> <br>And I’ll close with this: Our soror, the great Coretta Scott King, once said that freedom must be earned and won in each generation.<br> <br>I look out at this group, and I see among the folks here a young woman who is still making her way through college, sitting next to a woman who has served her community in pink and green with pride for over 75 years.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Ours is an intergenerational sisterhood.  (Applause.)  And we live with that knowledge, with the knowledge that we stand on great and broad soldiers, like Norma E. Boyd.  We live knowing that we are their legacy, that we learn from each other, that we teach each other, and that we have always been about fighting for the best of our country.<br> <br>Because the women of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated have always been unburdened by what has been, unburdened by what society may say we can or cannot be.<br> <br>And through our sisterhood, we teach that there is no barrier we cannot break and there is no obstacle we cannot overcome.<br> <br>We are built for leadership.  And every day, we see it through.  We strive.  And we do.  (Applause.)<br> <br>And so, I celebrate the many.  And today, I’ll honor the first: Alpha Kappa Alpha.  Thank you all very much.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  Thank you. <br> </p>



<p>END                 12:25 P.M. EDT</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Names Twenty-Third Round of Judicial&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/14/president-biden-names-twenty-third-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 20:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57513</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing the nominations of four new federal judicial nominees, his intent to nominate a fifth federal judicial nominee, and three nominees for local courts in the District of Columbia—all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to fulfill the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing the nominations of four new federal judicial nominees, his intent to nominate a fifth federal judicial nominee, and three nominees for local courts in the District of Columbia—all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, if confirmed, this slate would include:</p>



<ul><li>The first Black woman to serve on the U.S. District Court for the District of Oregon</li></ul>



<p>This is President Biden’s twenty-third round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his tenth slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 123.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies. And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.</p>



<p><strong><u>District Court – Press Bios</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Matthew L. Garcia: Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of New Mexico</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Matthew L. Garcia has served in the Office of New Mexico Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham as Chief of Staff from 2020 to 2022 and General Counsel from 2019 to 2020. From 2012 to 2018, he was a partner at Garcia Ives Nowara in Albuquerque, New Mexico, and from 2009 to 2012, he was a partner at Bach &amp; Garcia in Albuquerque, New Mexico. Mr. Garcia had his own solo practice from 2008 to 2009. From 2006-2008 Mr. Garcia was an associate at Freedman Boyd Daniels Hollander Goldberg &amp; Ives in Albuquerque, New Mexico. Mr. Garcia received his J.D. from the University of New Mexico School of Law in 2005, an M.P.P. from Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government in 2003, and a B.A., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from the University of New Mexico in 1999.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Lindsay C. Jenkins: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois—<em>Intent to Nominate</em></u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Lindsay C. Jenkins is a partner at Cooley LLP in Chicago, Illinois, where she has worked since 2021. She previously served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Northern District of Illinois from 2006 to 2021. Ms. Jenkins was previously an associate at Jones Day from 2004 to 2006. She served as a law clerk for Judge Solomon Oliver, Jr. on the United States District Court for the Northern District of Ohio from 2002 to 2004. Ms. Jenkins received her J.D., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Cleveland-Marshall College of Law at Cleveland State University, in 2002 and her B.A. from Miami University of Ohio in 1998.</p>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong><u>Justice Adrienne C. Nelson: Candidate for the United States District Court for the District of Oregon</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Justice Adrienne C. Nelson has served as an Associate Justice on the Oregon Supreme Court since 2018. From 2006 to 2018, Justice Nelson served as a trial judge on the Multnomah County Circuit Court. Justice Nelson worked as a senior attorney for Portland State University from 2004 to 2006, and she was in private practice at Bennett, Hartman, Morris &amp; Kaplan from 2004 to 2006. From 1996 to 1999, Justice Nelson was a public defender with Multnomah Defenders, Inc. Justice Nelson received her J.D. from the University of Texas School of Law at Austin in 1993 and her B.A., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from the University of Arkansas at Fayetteville in 1989.</p>



<ol type="1" start="4"><li><strong><u>Judge Andrew G. Schopler: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Southern District of California</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge Andrew G. Schopler has served as a United States Magistrate Judge for the Southern District of California since 2016.&nbsp;From 2004 to 2016, Judge Schopler was an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of California. He worked at Rudolf and Maher in Chapel Hill, North Carolina from 1998 to 2004 He was a solo practitioner from 1997 to 1998.&nbsp;Judge Schopler received his J.D. from Harvard Law School in 1997 and his B.A., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Dartmouth College in 1994. He has served in the United States Army Reserve and California Army National Guard since 2014.</p>



<ol type="1" start="5"><li><strong><u>Judge James Edward Simmons Jr: Candidate for the United States District Court for the Southern District of California</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Judge James Edward Simmons Jr. has been a judge on the California Superior Court since 2017. He is currently the Supervising Judge of the North County Branch of the San Diego Superior Court. From 2006 to 2017, he was a Deputy District Attorney in the San Diego District Attorney’s Office. In 2005, Judge Simmons was a Deputy City Attorney in the San Diego City Attorney’s Office. Judge Simmons received his J.D from Golden Gate University School of Law in 2004 and B.A. from the University of California, Berkeley in 2001.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>D.C. Court of Appeals</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Vijay Shanker: Candidate for D.C Court of Appeals</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Vijay Shanker is the Deputy Chief of the Appellate Section in the Criminal Division of the United States Department of Justice, where he has worked since 2005. He was previously Counselor and Acting Deputy Chief of Staff to the Assistant Attorney General for the Criminal Division and Senior Litigation Counsel in the Criminal Division’s Fraud Section at the Department of Justice. Mr. Shanker was an associate at Mayer Brown from 2004 to 2005 and at Covington &amp; Burling from 1999 to 2000 and 2001 to 2004. He served as a law clerk for Judge Chester J. Straub on the United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit from 2000 to 2001. Mr. Shanker received his J.D., Order of the Coif, from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1999 and his B.A., <em>cum laude</em>, from Duke University in 1994.</p>



<p><strong><u>D.C. Superior Court</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong><u>Laura Crane: Candidate for D.C. Superior Court</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Laura Cranehas served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia since 2014. Before joining the United States Attorney’s Office, Ms. Crane was a senior associate at WilmerHale in Washington, D.C. from 2013 to 2014 and a litigation associate at Cravath, Swaine, and Moore in New York City from 2010 to 2012. She served as a law clerk for the Judge James E. Boasberg on the United States District Court for the District of Columbia from 2012 to 2013. Ms. Crane received her J.D., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from the Washington University School of Law om 2009 and her B.A., <em>magna cum laude,</em> from Duke University in 2003.</p>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong><u>Veronica Sanchez: Candidate for the D.C. Superior Court</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Veronica Sanchez is an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia, a role she has held since 2009. Ms. Sanchez was a trial attorney in the Antitrust Division of the United States Department of Justice from 2002 to 2009. She served as a law clerk for Judge Melvin Brunetti on the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from 2001 to 2002 and for Judge Edward C. Reed on the United States District Court for the District of Nevada from 1999 to 2001. Ms. Sanchez received her J.D. from the UCLA School of Law in 1999 and her B.A. from Duke University in 1996</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
