<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 21:38:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Fourth CEO Summit of the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-fourth-ceo-summit-of-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 21:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Intercontinental HotelLos Angeles, California 11:13 A.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Mr. Ambassador.&#160; Thank you all so much.&#160; Please, have a seat.&#160; I’ve only been President about a year and a half, but every time I walk in a room and everybody stands up, I think there may be a fire or something.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Press,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Intercontinental Hotel<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>11:13 A.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Ambassador.&nbsp; Thank you all so much.&nbsp; Please, have a seat.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve only been President about a year and a half, but every time I walk in a room and everybody stands up, I think there may be a fire or something.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Press, that was a joke.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That was a joke.</p>



<p>Well, it’s wonderful to be with you this morning.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I want to thank the Chamber of Commerce for bringing together this group of business leaders from all across the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all of us here in Los Angeles for a simple reason: because we believe in the incredible economic potential of the Americas.&nbsp; I know I do.&nbsp; We all do.&nbsp; I mean, it’s &#8212; I &#8212; I just think the potential is unlimited.</p>



<p>The region is filled with dynamic energy: entrepreneurs who are ready to break out, innovators who will change the way we think and the way we do things, young people poised to seize the future.</p>



<p>Everybody &#8212; the press always asks me why am I so optimistic with the way things are.&nbsp; Take a look at all these young folks.&nbsp; They’re the best educated.&nbsp; They’re the most generous.&nbsp; They’re the people who have done the most, they’re ready to volunteer, and they’re the least prejudiced folks in the world.&nbsp; It’s a new generation.&nbsp; And underpinning &#8212; it gives me an enormous sense of &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; an enormous sense of optimism.</p>



<p>We have everything we need right here in the Western Hemisphere not only to point ourselves toward a future that is more prosperous, secure, and democratic, but the ability to achieve it as well.&nbsp; And for &#8212; all of you are essential to making sure we get to this place we have to get to.</p>



<p>You know, the private sector is able to move quickly to mobilize vast amounts of investment capital that’s going to be needed to unlock the enormous potential for growth in this hemisphere, in the region.</p>



<p>And when we combine the ability of government to direct economic activity toward specific challenges, to help mitigate risks, guard against unfair practices, and create a predictable demand with the agility of the private sector, I believe we can deliver real improvements for people’s lives.&nbsp; I really believe it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, just &#8212; well, I &#8212; my wife often reminds me that I had a doctor who &#8212; a long time ago &#8212; who was saying, when I had &#8212; I had an aneurism, he kept saying, “Is it congenital or is it environmental?”&nbsp; And I said, “I don’t care.&nbsp; I just &#8212; just get it done.”&nbsp; He said, “You know what your problem is, Senator?”&nbsp; I said, “No.”&nbsp; He said, “You’re a congenital optimist.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I am.&nbsp; I’m an American, and that’s why I’m a congenital optimist.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So, look &#8212; I really mean it.&nbsp; We can do anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jobs that pay good wages and respect workers’ rights.</p>



<p>Communities that come to life around investments.&nbsp; Families that can envision a future with an opportunity to just &#8212; as my dad would say, “just give them a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; A little bit of breathing room.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When that happens, everyone prospers, including all of you.&nbsp; All of you.&nbsp; But to achieve this, we’ve got to update our recipe, in my view, for economic growth.&nbsp; It’s time to put a nail in the coffin, in my view, of trickle-down economics.&nbsp; It doesn’t work.&nbsp; It keeps you in an increasingly smaller and smaller world.&nbsp; It doesn’t work.&nbsp; It keeps yielding the same results: greater inequity, slower growth, less competition, and less innovation.</p>



<p>In the past few years, we exposed the weakness of prioritizing short-term profits and working exclusively to maximize efficiency.</p>



<p>We learned firsthand the pain that happens when just-in-time supply chains break down or hit a bottleneck.&nbsp; It’s a fundamental difference.&nbsp; And to all of &#8212; and you all felt it as well.</p>



<p>The COVID-19 pandemic triggered a global economic crisis that we’re still digging out of.</p>



<p>And now, Putin’s brutal, unprovoked war in Ukraine has created economic disruptions that are affecting the entire globe.&nbsp; And that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And these won’t be the only shocks we’re going to have to navigate.&nbsp; Climate change is increasing the pace and intensity of natural disasters. I leave from here &#8212; on my way back east, I&#8217;m going to be stopping in New Mexico.&nbsp; They’ve had an incredible impact on their &#8212; on their environment of late.</p>



<p>Rising inequity and food insecurity around the world can fuel political instability.&nbsp; You all know that.</p>



<p>And the question is not “if” we face another pandemic; it’s “when” we face it and are we going to be prepared this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the economy of the future will increasingly belong to those who place a premium on resilience and reliability, who invest in innovation over long te- &#8212; over the long term and strengthen systems and supply chains now, and mitigate the impact of future shocks before they hit.</p>



<p>Each of us &#8212; each of us &#8212; the government and the private sector &#8212; have a critical role to play.&nbsp; That’s why I’m focused on driving economic policies that grow our economy from the bottom up and the middle out, because, quite frankly, when that works, everybody does well and the wealthy do very, very well.&nbsp; No one gets hurt.&nbsp; No one gets hurt.</p>



<p>For example, here in the United States, we’re making a generational investment on our infrastructure.&nbsp; It used to &#8212; we used to be number one in the world when I first came to the United States Congress.&nbsp; Now we’re number 13 in the world.&nbsp; Thirteen.</p>



<p>I don’t have to tell business people what that means in term of economic growth.&nbsp; But we’re fixing that.&nbsp; That’s going to be the benefit to the entire region.</p>



<p>We’re investing $1.2 trillion, bipartisanly, to upgrade our infrastructure &#8212; to fix crumbling roads and bridges and ports, airports all across the country.</p>



<p>And that’s going to help you get goods to market faster while creating good-paying union jobs &#8212; and I know a lot of you don’t like my saying “union” &#8212; but unions jobs to support working families, because that’s what&#8217;s happening.</p>



<p>Everyone benefits.&nbsp; Everybody wins when that occurs.</p>



<p>And the return on our investment is going to strengthen U.S. competitiveness throughout the 21st century.</p>



<p>You know, this is the same approach we’re taking across the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity.</p>



<p>Many of the countries in our region qualify as middle-income countries, but that label doesn’t remove the persistent structural challenges that run &#8212; and deep inequity.&nbsp; “Middle-income” means you don’t get the benefit of a lot of opportunities.</p>



<p>So, we can change that and help governments make life better, easier, and fairer for their peoples by using hemispheric multinational financial institutions to modernize and mobilize greater levels of private investment and create good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>I know there are real barriers for you to contend with.&nbsp; That’s why we want to work with you to level the playing field.</p>



<p>As I said last night, the United States is prepared to put new capital in the Inter-American Development Bank’s private-sector lending arm &#8212; the IDB Invest &#8212; to help catalyze the flow of private capital into the region, especially to support startups, digital connec- &#8212; digital connectivity, and renewable energy, and health.</p>



<p>For example, we need to make it easier for countries in Latin America and the Caribbean to develop their 5G infrastructure without having to choose between investing in their digital future or renewable energy structure &#8212; to be able to do both.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We de- &#8212; we need to unlock the financing so that both can be done at the same time.&nbsp; We want to make sure our closest neighbors have a real choice between the debt-trap development that has become more common &#8212; more and more common in the region and the high-quality, transparent approach to infrastructure and investment that delivers lasting gains for workers and their families.</p>



<p>And by working through the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation to lower the risk around these kinds of investments, support policy reforms to improve investment in climate in countries &#8212; excuse me &#8212; the investment in climate &#8212; the climate investment in these countries, and level the playing field, we’re going to open up new areas of private-sector investors that are not only economically viable but are highly desirable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, over the course of this summit, the governments are coming together to make significant, concrete commitments across a range of issues vital to achieving sustainable and equitable growth throughout the region:</p>



<p>On bringing supply chains closer to home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On fostering innovation and developing a shared framework for our digital future.</p>



<p>On kicking our action on climate change into high gear and speeding our clean energy transition.</p>



<p>On bolstering health systems and food security in the Western Hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On managing safe and orderly migration as a shared responsibility through innovative and coordinated action to enforce our borders and stabilize migrant populations, while seizing the shared opportunity for economic growth.</p>



<p>My challenge to all of you is: If you step up and play a bigger role in driving inclusive, sustainable, equitable growth in the 21st century, a lot is going to happen.&nbsp; What more can you do to engage in these issues that shape our future?&nbsp; Not as a favor to me or to any government leader, but because it’s in your own overwhelming economic self-interest.</p>



<p>If you make the investments necessary to build more secure and resilient supply chains, that’s ultimately going to bring down your cost and make you more competitive and boost your bottom line.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’re going to hear from John Kerry about the opportunities for private-sector innovation and new markets that will be critical to reach our climate goals.</p>



<p>Yesterday, Vice President Harris spoke about the $3.2 billion mobili- &#8212; mobilized by our Call to Action efforts in Central America, including &#8212; including from several companies in this room, to bring quality economic opportunity to the region.</p>



<p>We’re expanding the 100,000 Strong in the Americas program to focus on opportunities for young people in climate and STEM fields, especially in the Caribbean and Central America.</p>



<p>And I urge you &#8212; I urge you to join us with matching funds, just as you did when we launched the program 10 years ago.</p>



<p>There are many more examples, but let me close with this:&nbsp; We stand at an inflection point.&nbsp; I know you’re tired of hearing me say when I was running, and I continue to say it every day.&nbsp; We’re at an inflection point.&nbsp; More is going to change in the next 10 years than has changed in the last 30 years in the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Decisions we make today are going to have far-reaching impacts on our future.&nbsp; They’re going to last well into the middle of the century.&nbsp; And, business leaders, as &#8212; you all see where the trend lines are reporting &#8212; are pointing as clearly as I do.</p>



<p>And our challenge is to shape the outcomes so the future reflects the democratic values of our region, an economy that we want to live and work in and that ensures a fair playing field for our workers and our businesses.</p>



<p>As we navigate this inflection point, leaders and business and those who come out ahead are going to be the people who are going to lead this change for the future &#8212; not those stuck looking backwards and sitting on the sidelines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>None of us will be able to fully realize our ambition for the region on our own.</p>



<p>So let’s use this summit to tackle the obstacles to growth, come together around new ideas and new opportunities to take our region’s biggest challenges on and defeat them, and for all of us &#8212; all of us to prosper.</p>



<p>I really believe there is nothing we&#8217;re unable to do.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re prime &#8212; we’re primed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll close with this that I&#8217;m going to say a little later at the general session: I think &#8212; I find no reason why the Western Hemisphere &#8212; the Western Hemisphere, over the next 10 years, is not developed into the most democratic hemisphere in the world, most democratic region in the entire world.&nbsp; We have everything.&nbsp; We have the people.&nbsp; We have the resources.&nbsp; And we have more democracies in this hemisphere than any other hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there&#8217;s a lot we can do, but a lot of it matters in the private enterprise side of the equation.  You all &#8212; you all are on the <s>font</s> [front] of enormous ideas and opportunities. </p>



<p>So I want to thank you all, and I look forward to working with you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as &#8212; as my &#8212; every time I’d walk out of my Grandpop Finnegan’s house, he’d yell, “Joey, keep the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandmother would yell, “No, Joey, spread it.&nbsp; Spread the faith.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>11:26 A.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-justin-trudeau-of-canada-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 21:32:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles Convention CenterLos Angeles, California 12:08 P.M. PDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Mr. Prime Minister and to your delegation, we start by saying we have no better friend in the whole world than Canada.&#160; And that&#8217;s not hyperbole.&#160; That&#8217;s real.&#160; And you’re a good personal friend as well. Before I begin, one of the things that’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles Convention Center<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>12:08 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Mr. Prime Minister and to your delegation, we start by saying we have no better friend in the whole world than Canada.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; That&#8217;s real.&nbsp; And you’re a good personal friend as well.</p>



<p>Before I begin, one of the things that’s going to occupy my country tonight, I suspect, is the first open hearings on January the 6th.&nbsp; And as I said when it was occurring and subsequent, I think it was a clear, flagrant violation of the Constitution.&nbsp; I think these guys and women broke the law, tried to turn around the result of an election.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a lot of questions &#8212; who&#8217;s responsible, who&#8217;s involved.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to make a judgment on that, but I just want to know that &#8212; want you to know that we&#8217;re going to probably be &#8212; a lot of Americans are going to be seeing for the first time some of the detail that occurred.</p>



<p>But you and I have a lot to talk about.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be hanging out with each other a fair amount at the G7, at the NATO conference in Spain.</p>



<p>But today we&#8217;re engaged in our hemisphere.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; it’s presumptive of me to say, but I think we both share the same sense that the possibilities for the hemisphere are unlimited.</p>



<p>We already have with &#8212; notwithstanding some difficulties in the hemisphere, we already have a circumstance where it&#8217;s the most democratic hemisphere in the world.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no reason why, from Canada and along the Arctic, all the way down to the tip of Chile and Argentina, that we can&#8217;t &#8212; this can&#8217;t become a more &#8212; a democratic, a united, and middle-class, economically prosperous hemisphere.</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s one of my objectives in this Summit of the Americas.&nbsp; There’s a lot we have to work through.&nbsp; But I want to thank you for your partnership.</p>



<p>PRIME MINISTER TRUDEAU:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; That’s a place I want to start &#8212; just the friendship between Canada and the United States is deep.&nbsp; It was reminded to me as I was visiting NORAD a couple of days ago just how much we do together.&nbsp; We’re the only places &#8212; the only place in world where there is a truly binational command to protect our homelands.&nbsp; It is an example of that.</p>



<p>But as we gather here today, and the reflections that you’re bringing forward on democracy, it reminds us that it is extraordinarily important to be there for each other and to be there for our allies around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the work that we can do on supporting and projecting and sharing our values has a way of actually supporting and impacting citizens around the world to make the case that democracy is not just fairer but it’s also better for citizens, in terms of putting food on the table, putting futures in front of them.&nbsp; Those are the things we need to work on.</p>



<p>We have worked very closely over the past many months on the issue of Ukraine, where Canada is deeply engaged and supportive of everything we’re doing as a West on being there against Russia’s illegal invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; And we will continue to work together on that.</p>



<p>We’re also dealing with real challenges around climate around the world and stepping up on that.&nbsp; And it’s always a pleasure to be doing that.&nbsp; But the center of it has to be, even as we gather with our friends across the Americas, how we create prosperity, how we counter the rising cost of living, how we create good jobs for our citizens not just in our respective countries but in each other’s countries and throughout the hemisphere.</p>



<p>And that’s why I’m so pleased to be here to work with you on.</p>



<p>(Speaks in French.)&nbsp; (No translation provided.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Well, thank you all very much.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>12:12 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in a Meeting With Leaders of Caribbean&#160;Nations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/09/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-a-meeting-with-leaders-of-caribbean-nations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 21:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:40 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  I &#8212; it is good to see all of you again.  We met virtually just a few weeks ago, and I&#8217;m looking forward to the conversation that we will have &#8212; a continuing conversation about the work we will do together, our partnership, and the commitments that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:40 P.M. PDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  I &#8212; it is good to see all of you again.  We met virtually just a few weeks ago, and I&#8217;m looking forward to the conversation that we will have &#8212; a continuing conversation about the work we will do together, our partnership, and the commitments that we are prepared to make with each other around the issues that challenge us, but also the opportunities that are presented.<br> <br>As neighbors in the Western Hemisphere, the United States shares common bonds and interests with Caribbean nations.  As I said when we convened six weeks ago, our partnership is key to our shared prosperity and security.<br> <br>Today, our main focus will be the climate crisis, which, of course, is an existential crisis for our entire planet, and the Caribbean is on the front line of this crisis.<br> <br>In our last meeting, we discussed your priorities as it relates to this issue and many others.  And I indicated that the United States would look into these issues and work with you as we seek to resolve the challenges that each of our nations are presented with.  And I committed that we would develop a plan.<br> <br>Today, I&#8217;m pleased to announce the launch of the United States-Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis, also known as PACC &#8212; P-A-C-C &#8212; 2030.  PACC 2030 is the United States government&#8217;s primary mechanism for addressing energy security and the climate crisis in this region.<br> <br>Through this partnership, we will support energy infrastructure and climate resilience projects at every stage of development, from beginning to end, in four particular ways.<br> <br>First, we will work with you to identify new clean energy projects.<br> <br>Second, we will provide technical assistance to make sure these projects are viable and appealing not only to you, but to investors.  We will bring them &#8212; investors &#8212; to the Caribbean on, essentially, roadshows to showcase the projects.<br> <br>And fourth and finally, we will improve access &#8212; and importantly &#8212; we will improve access to development financing, which will make these projects a reality.  We will engage with the private sector at every stage of this work because, of course, their involvement is essential to making this productive and meaningful.<br> <br>When we accelerate the transition to clean energy, I think we all believe that we unlock great economic opportunities for the entire region.<br> <br>When we work together to address this urgent threat, it benefits the people of the United States and the people of the Caribbean.  And all of us, of course, benefit by reducing emissions.<br> <br>In conclusion, strengthening the U.S.-Caribbean relationship is a priority for me.<br> <br>And regarding the climate crisis, it is one of our highest priorities.  But there are other issues that are also very important that we can and must address together.<br> <br>I want to thank all of the leaders for being here.  Again, welcome to Los Angeles, to California.  And I look forward to a meaningful conversation and a productive conversation &#8212; meaning that out of our conversations thus far, we have actually taken action.  And I look forward to continuing to do just that.<br> <br>And with that, I now invite Dr. Carla Barnett, the Secretary General of the Caribbean Community, also known as CARICOM, to share a few words.<br> <br>END                 12:44 P.M. PDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Trudeau of&#160;Canada</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-trudeau-of-canada/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 20:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55213</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada in Los Angeles on the margins of the Ninth Summit of the Americas to review regional cooperation on economic development, the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, and food insecurity. The President and Prime Minister underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada in Los Angeles on the margins of the Ninth Summit of the Americas to review regional cooperation on economic development, the COVID-19 pandemic, migration, and food insecurity. The President and Prime Minister underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide economic, development, and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected by the violence, as well as to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine.  The President lauded Canada’s close partnership with the United States throughout this crisis and its leadership in enacting comprehensive sanctions and restrictions on Russia. The President also stated he looks forward to seeing the Prime Minister in Madrid for the NATO Summit.<br> <br>The Leaders also discussed the potential of developing critical minerals in both countries and joint efforts to make our supply chains and economies more resilient to external shocks, including through the work of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/CANADA-U.S.-SUPPLY-CHAINS-PROGRESS-REPORT.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">the U.S.-Canada Supply Chain Working Group</a>.  As major energy producers, both Canada and the United States play key roles in supporting security and resilience of supply chains, but Leaders also emphasized a shared commitment to achieve net-zero emissions by 2050 to decrease our reliance on fossil fuels. The President thanked the Prime Minister for Canada’s support to bolster democracy in the Americas and throughout in the world, and for Canada’s support of the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity and the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection. Both Leaders reaffirmed the strong bonds between our nations and their commitment to deepening the U.S.-Canada relationship across the breadth of our bilateral agenda.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/09/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-85/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 19:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55202</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 11:10 A.M. EDT DR. JHA:&#160; Good morning, everybody.&#160; I’m delighted to be joined by two great colleagues: the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, Dawn O’Connell, and our nation’s Surgeon General, Dr. Vivek Murthy.&#160; Thank you for joining us. Now, today we want to provide an update on a topic that I know&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:10 A.M. EDT<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Good morning, everybody.&nbsp; I’m delighted to be joined by two great colleagues: the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, Dawn O’Connell, and our nation’s Surgeon General, Dr. Vivek Murthy.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us.</p>



<p>Now, today we want to provide an update on a topic that I know many parents and grandparents are focused on: the potential for the first COVID-19 vaccines for kids under five.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have waited a long time for this moment.&nbsp; More than two years into the COVID-19 pandemic and after nearly 18 months since the first set of vaccines became available for adults, we are on the cusp of having safe, highly effective vaccines for kids under five.</p>



<p>Now, we want to lay out today the work we’re doing to make sure parents can easily get access to those vaccines.</p>



<p>Let me start off by making one very important point: We are not here to prejudge the outcome of the independent, science-driven process that is being led both by FDA and the CDC.</p>



<p>The FDA’s advisory committee is going to be meeting next week on Tuesday, June 14th, and Wednesday, June 15th, to review the data that was submitted by Pfizer and Moderna, and they will make their recommendations.&nbsp; We expect the FDA to make a decision shortly after those meetings.</p>



<p>The CDC’s Advisory Committee is then going to meet on Friday, June 17th, and Saturday, June 18th.&nbsp; We expect the CDC Director, Dr. Rochelle Walensky, to then make her recommendation sometime after those meetings.&nbsp; If the FDA authorizes and CDC recommends that kids under five get vaccinated, vaccinations will begin quickly thereafter.</p>



<p>So, what does this mean for you if you’re a parent or a pediatrician?&nbsp; Realistically, it means we could see shots in arms of kids under five as early as the week of June 20th.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, as a reminder, Monday, June 20th, is an important federal holiday in observation of Juneteenth, and so we expect that many pediatricians’ offices may be closed.&nbsp; So we think that vaccinations would really start in earnest on Tuesday, June 21st.</p>



<p>And importantly, vac- &#8212; the vaccination program is going to ramp up in the days and weeks that follow, with more and more doses and more and more appointments becoming available.</p>



<p>Now, let’s actually take a moment to understand what a historic moment this is.&nbsp; If the FDA and CDC recommend these vaccines, this would mark an important moment in the pandemic.&nbsp; It would mean that, for the first time, essentially every American, from our oldest to our youngest, would be eligible for the protection that vaccines provide.</p>



<p>Now, I know many parents have been eagerly awaiting the opportunity to vaccinate their youngest kids.&nbsp; We share in that eagerness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also know that it is important to do this right.</p>



<p>As my HHS colleagues will detail, we have been planning for this moment for months.&nbsp; We have been getting ready to launch a comprehensive effort to help America’s youngest kids get protected.&nbsp; That means working with state and local health departments.&nbsp; It means working with America’s pediatricians and family doctors.&nbsp; It means working with pharmacies and rural health clinics and community health centers and so many more.</p>



<p>Now, I want to close with a word on what we already know about COVID-19 vaccines and kids.&nbsp; While the deliberations and the data review for vaccines for kids under five are ongoing, we know that for kids over five, vaccines have made a tremendous difference.</p>



<p>Kids who are vaccinated are far less likely to get seriously ill from COVID.&nbsp; They’re far less likely to end up in the hospital or in the ICU.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re far less likely to get complications of COVID, like Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome of Children.</p>



<p>Vaccines are already making an enormous difference in keeping our kids over five protected as the pandemic continues.</p>



<p>Tens of millions of children in the U.S. and around the world have been vaccinated against COVID, and the safety profile of these vaccines is truly extraordinary.</p>



<p>So, the data on kids over five and vaccines is clear: Kids are better protected, they are better off if they’re vaccinated.&nbsp; That’s why I, as a dad, have three children, all of whom have been vaccinated and boosted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is why every physician, including every pediatrician and family physician I know, has vaccinated their own eligible kids and why we are anxiously awaiting the careful review of the FDA and the CDC to determine whether we can extend that protection to kids under five.</p>



<p>You know, when President Biden took office, he made a commitment to ensure that every American benefitted from the miracles that science has delivered us in these pandemics.</p>



<p>If these vaccines are authorized and recommended, we will get one giant step closer to fulfilling that commitment.</p>



<p>So, thank you for joining us this morning.&nbsp; I’d like to turn it over now to my colleague, Dawn O’Connell.</p>



<p>Dawn.</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Jha.&nbsp; I&#8217;m pleased to be here.</p>



<p>Over the past 16 months, together with our partners, we have managed one of the most complex logistical challenges in our nation’s history: delivering more than 700 million doses of COVID-19 vaccine to more than 90,000 locations nationwide.</p>



<p>Today, more than 220 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; But we know that our work is not done yet.</p>



<p>COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of five would be a momentous milestone in our historic vaccination program, helping extend the protection that vaccines offer to our youngest Americans and some additional peace of mind to parents and guardians.</p>



<p>Our objective is clear: to be ready to swiftly and efficiently deliver vaccines for kids under the age of five to communities nationwide as soon as the FDA grants emergency use authorization.</p>



<p>We are ready.</p>



<p>To achieve our objective, we have engaged state, local, Tribal, and territorial health departments; pediatricians and primary care providers; children’s hospitals and health systems; and pharmacies on operational planning.</p>



<p>These are many of the same partners we&#8217;ve been engaged with on other vaccination and COVID-19 response efforts over the past few years.&nbsp; These partners are on the frontlines and critical to success, and we stand ready to help them in any way we can.</p>



<p>Last week, we opened up pre-ordering for states, Tribes, territories, and other partners to order doses.&nbsp; We are making 10 million doses of vaccine available initially, with millions more available in the coming weeks.</p>



<p>This approach allows us to seed communities with enough vaccine so that it is readily accessible and equitably distributed across the country.</p>



<p>We estimate that 85 percent of children under the age of five live within five miles of a potential vaccination site.</p>



<p>We have asked states and other partners to leverage prior pediatric vaccination best practices and tap into existing pediatric vaccination locations as they continue to sign up additional pediatricians and providers.</p>



<p>We have also asked states and other partners to ensure equity, giving priority to sites that will vaccinate children at highest risk for severe COVID-19 disease and considering factors such as hours of operation.</p>



<p>At this point in the Biden administration’s vaccination program, our partners are accustomed to this process, and so are we.&nbsp; Our teams are standing by and will immediately begin shipping vaccines across the country after &#8212; should FDA authorize a vaccine.</p>



<p>It will take some time to position these vaccines across the country, and vaccinations can’t begin until CDC has made its decision.&nbsp; But we also know that many parents have been waiting for a long time, so we will be working 24/7 until every dose is shipped and delivered.</p>



<p>As we have said previously, we are not in the predicting business, we’re in the planning business.&nbsp; Our teams are hard at work planning for the possibility that FDA and CDC will give the green light in the near future.&nbsp; And if and when they do, we will be ready to deliver.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And I’ll turn to you now, Dr. Murthy.</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Thanks so much, Dawn.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First of all, it’s good to be with everyone again today.</p>



<p>As many of you know, my daughter is four years old, and she&#8217;s not yet eligible to be vaccinated.&nbsp; And my wife Alice and I, like millions of parents across the country, carry with us every day an added layer of worry knowing that our children under five don’t have the same opportunity as older children and adults to get vaccinated and, hence, protected from the worst outcomes of COVID-19.</p>



<p>More than 30,000 children under five in our country have been hospitalized with COVID during this pandemic, and nearly 500 deaths have been reported in this age group.&nbsp; So I know how eager many parents and caregivers are for good news on this front, to know that our youngest children have an added layer of protection.</p>



<p>But I also know that all of us as parents want to ensure that anything we are giving our children has gone through a rigorous scientific assessment and that it is both safe and effective for our kids.</p>



<p>That is why as soon as the FDA authorizes and the CDC recommends a pediatric vaccine for kids under five, we are going to launch a national public education campaign to ensure parents and families have all the information they need to make the best choices for their children.</p>



<p>Now, in addition to having medical and scientific experts from government speaking to communities, we will be working closely with community partners, as we have done in the past, to make sure that community members are hearing from local leaders and organizations that they know and trust.</p>



<p>We’re going to partner with organizations like the American Academy of Pediatrics, the Association of Children’s Museums, the American Library Association, the National PTA, the National Diaper Bank Network, and the National Association of Community Health Centers, as well as a number of Black, Latino, Asian American, Native Hawaiian, Pacific Islander, and Native American community-based organizations, including the W. Montague Cobb Health Institute and LULAC, the League of United Latin American Citizens.</p>



<p>We will support these organizations and local stakeholders as they launch health fairs, pop-up clinics, community forums, doctors’ speaking bureaus, and more.</p>



<p>And we’re going to mobilize the 17,000-plus-member COVID-19 Community Corps, which we launched last spring, to help provide creative, kid-focused English and Spanish language toolkits for trusted local messengers, including, I would add, a superhero-themed toolkit that I can tell you will play well in my house.</p>



<p>In this effort, we’re going to be building on lessons that we have learned and the trusted networks that we’ve built over the last 18 months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our prior COVID-19 vaccination efforts helped us protect millions of Americans from hospitalization and loss of life.&nbsp; As before, we will ensure that equity is at the center of our approach as we work hard to get vaccines to our hardest-hit communities.</p>



<p>I do want to caution parents about one thing, and that is misinformation.&nbsp; Misinformation has been a challenge throughout this pandemic.</p>



<p>And as I have said in the past when I issued a Surgeon General’s Advisory on Health Misinformation, false and misleading information about COVID-19 &#8212; misinformation that is often spread on social media, in fact &#8212; has led to confusion and has prevented people from benefiting from lifesaving treatments and vaccines.</p>



<p>So please make sure the information you are relying on is coming from trusted sources like your doctor, your local children&#8217;s hospital, your department of health, medical associations like the American Academy of Pediatrics, and the FDA and CDC.</p>



<p>Lastly, I want to emphasize this: Real progress in our vaccination effort has happened when people who are trusted in their communities reach out to their friends, families, neighbors, and community members.&nbsp; And that is what we will need to do now as well: build a people-powered campaign to protect our youngest children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to close by saying to those trusted messengers and, in particular, the pediatricians, family physicians, and nurses out there just how much our nation needs your help right now to make this effort a success as we work to keeping our youngest ones safe.</p>



<p>Whether it is in countering misinformation with accurate, science-based information or helping families find places to get vaccinated, your role could not be more vital right now as it has been throughout this pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m incredibly grateful for all you have done to serve and protect your communities over the last two and a half years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, let me turn it back to Dr. Jha.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Murthy.&nbsp; And thank you, Dawn.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s now open it up for questions.&nbsp; And to Kevin, do you want to call on folks to ask their questions?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Yes, thank you.&nbsp; We have time for a few questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Joyce Frieden at MedPage Today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp; Hello?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Hi, Joyce.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you &#8212; okay.&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; My question is about the money.&nbsp; I&#8217;m interested in how much doing all this is costing.&nbsp; And also, you know, previously, the President had talked about there maybe not being enough money for vaccines later on if, you know, Congress didn&#8217;t act and so forth. &nbsp;So I&#8217;m wondering how that might impact this effort.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to start it and then see if Ms. O’Connell has anything else to add.</p>



<p>Look, the good news is, because of prior funding from Congress, we have secured enough vaccines and we have the resources to get these vaccines out to the American people. We&#8217;ve been very clear that because of those resources, we can get every child who wants to be vaccinated, every parent who wants to vaccinate their kid vaccinated now.&nbsp; We have the resources to do this this summer.</p>



<p>The challenge &#8212; the resource challenge, the money challenge you&#8217;ve been hearing about from me, from others, is really about what&#8217;s going to happen in the fall.&nbsp; We do not have enough resources for the &#8212; to have enough vaccines for every American for the next generation of vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the challenges are coming up in the fall.&nbsp; We need the money now.&nbsp; But the money we&#8217;re using for kids’ vaccines today is money that was appropriated previously by Congress.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, next question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Betsy Klein at CNN.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Betsy?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, can you &#8212;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yes, we can hear you now.&nbsp; Or not.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Betsy, we can &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; Just to follow up on COVID funding, can &#8212; Dr. Jha, if you could give us an update on whether the last month you&#8217;ve had meetings on Capitol Hill, if that&#8217;s borne any fruit, and whether there&#8217;s been any congressional reaction on your end to some of the funding reallocations you announced yesterday.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s take a step back and talk about the kinds of decisions we are having to make.&nbsp; What you heard yesterday was us making a series of very painful decisions, taking resources away from what we think are vital programs to make sure that we&#8217;re at the table when it comes to purchasing the next generation of vaccines, to make sure that we have enough therapeutics for Americans so &#8212; as we get into the fall and winter.</p>



<p>These are very, very difficult choices.&nbsp; These are not &#8212; this is not where we should be in the pandemic.&nbsp; We have been making &#8212; we&#8217;ve been communicating this very clearly to Congress.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been meeting with members of Congress, both Democrats and Republicans, in the House and Senate.</p>



<p>And I think members of Congress that I&#8217;ve been meeting with and speaking with understand the situation we are in.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve got to keep making this point clear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me just say one more thing.&nbsp; Because of the delay that Congress has not acted, we are losing our place in line in terms of our ability to get vaccines and therapeutics out to the American people this fall and winter.&nbsp; This is why it&#8217;s urgent that Congress act now and get us the resources we need as an administration so we can continue to get the tools we need to protect the American people.</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; (Inaudible) add something to that as well?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Please.</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Betsy, I&#8217;m really glad you asked this point.&nbsp; And I would just add to what Dr. Jha said.&nbsp; When I go around the country and talk to people across America about our &#8212; where we are in the COVID pandemic, people don&#8217;t understand why it is that after incredible progress that we made developing lifesaving vaccines or treatments, after demonstrating that we&#8217;re actually able to save lives by making these available to people, we are now suddenly halting, when it comes to funding, the ongoing availability of these lifesaving treatments and tests.</p>



<p>It doesn&#8217;t make sense to people, and I think that&#8217;s because it doesn&#8217;t make sense.&nbsp; It&#8217;s because we learned in prior public health emergencies that when we fail to sustain our attention and funding to public health interventions, the cost of that failure can be measured in illness incurred and lives lost.</p>



<p>This is a choice.&nbsp; You know, it is not inevitable that we &#8212; you know, that we don&#8217;t have funding and that we don&#8217;t make these treatments and tests available.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a choice.&nbsp; And my hope is that we can &#8212; and our collective hope is that we can make the choice, work together with Congress to get that funding &#8212; because, again, we are in a much better place in this pandemic than we were, but we are not done with the pandemic.&nbsp; The virus is still here, and we&#8217;re reminded that, you know, each day.&nbsp; You know, and we look at the folks who are getting infected; we&#8217;re still losing several hundred people a day to this virus.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve got to keep going.&nbsp; This is not the time to take our focus off the pandemic.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Thank you, Vivek.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m just going to add one more quick thing to this, which is a point that I think often gets lost and it&#8217;s really the point that Dr. Murthy was making.&nbsp; We are in a better place in this pandemic because we&#8217;re using these tools &#8212; right? &#8212;&nbsp;because we&#8217;re &#8212; we have vaccines, because we&#8217;re using therapeutics.</p>



<p>And so there&#8217;s a sense that some people have that, “Oh, because we&#8217;re in a better place, we don&#8217;t have to fund this anymore.”&nbsp; It&#8217;s actually quite the opposite.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve demonstrated that we can get us &#8212; we can get the country to a better place.&nbsp; It&#8217;s particularly important that we keep and sustain that effort to get us through the rest of this pandemic.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, both.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Adrianna Rodriguez at USA Today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for holding this briefing and for taking my question.&nbsp; Another question on COVID funding.&nbsp; It seems to be popular this morning.&nbsp; I was wondering if we could talk about maybe the thought process behind some of those difficult decisions that were mentioned, specifically the one to reallocate funding from testing and protective equipment to vaccines.&nbsp; What was, I guess, the thought process behind going there?&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Dawn, do you want to take it?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to start, absolutely.</p>



<p>So as has been noted already this morning, each of these decisions has been challenging; none of them are ideal.&nbsp; And they all require using funds that we were planning to spend on other critical programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We looked across all six supplemental bills that we&#8217;ve received funding with and are pulling funds from each of those bills.&nbsp; One of the &#8212; to look at the legally available funding for the purchase of the vaccines that Dr. Jha mentioned &#8212; the Paxlovid and then the monoclonal that we&#8217;re purchasing in these next few weeks.</p>



<p>Not all the funds that are out there are available to be used for those purchases.&nbsp; So we looked at all the legally available funds, and we landed on some very difficult decisions. We&#8217;re going to give up domestic testing capacity, something that you all know we worked so hard to build through Delta and Omicron.&nbsp; We&#8217;re also not going to be able to do out-year support for the PPE warehousing and supplies that we&#8217;ve worked so hard to build.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it is challenging for us to think about taking a step backwards in that way.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve come so far in these two years, thanks to the support of Congress.&nbsp; And now having to make these challenging decisions is going to set us back.&nbsp; We hope to continue to work with our partners in Congress to continue to move forward and to not have to make any more of these difficult decisions.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; And I will add: One of the urgencies of this &#8212; and we&#8217;ve been saying this to Congress for the last couple of months &#8212; is that we are starting to lose our place in line; that other countries are negotiating contracts with these companies to purchase the next generation of vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The idea that America would not have the next generation of vaccines available to any American, we thought, was unacceptable.&nbsp; And so we have pulled enough funds that we can be at the negotiating table and begin to &#8212; begin to negotiate so that we don&#8217;t fall further behind in line.</p>



<p>Let me be very clear: We do not have enough resources to make sure that every American who wants one of the next generation of vaccines will be able to get one.&nbsp; That part is clear to us.&nbsp; But we needed to be at the negotiating table.&nbsp; And waiting longer, waiting for Congress no longer felt like an acceptable option.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we pulled the funds that Ms. O’Connell talked about.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Mike Stobbe at the Associated Press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; This question came up before, but I don&#8217;t think I understand the answer.</p>



<p>Assuming that both the Pfizer and Moderna shots are authorized and recommended, will parents get to choose which vaccine their child gets?&nbsp; How will they do that?&nbsp; Will there be a federal resource that will tell them where the Moderna shots are and the Pfizer shots are?&nbsp; If you could help parents understand how they could do that.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Dawn, any thoughts on that?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re now not in the position of presupposing what the FDA and CDC are going to authorize and recommend.&nbsp; But in planning for the potential authorization of both, we&#8217;re making both vaccines available in equal numbers during our preordering phase, and we’ll continue to provide equal numbers as states would like them.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Any other thoughts on that, Vivek?</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Well, I would just say, Mike, to your question also &#8212; I mean about how parents are going to make this decision: That will depend in part on the FDA and CDC process that unfolds over the next few days.&nbsp; They will be, you know, looking at the data very closely, and we will also be looking for their recommendations to help parents &#8212; help guide parents in their decisions about which vaccine to choose.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let’s go Shannon Pettypiece at NBC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question on the vaccine for kids.&nbsp; But real quick, just to make sure we&#8217;re clear on the funding: Do you expect there &#8212; is there more money from the previously allocated COVID funds that you could reach into to get more vaccines for the fall?&nbsp; It sounds like you&#8217;re saying that this money you&#8217;ve reallocated so far gets you started, but it&#8217;s not going to be enough for the vaccines to be widely available in the fall.&nbsp; So is there any more money that you think you could reallocate to get additional vaccines for the fall if Congress doesn&#8217;t come through?</p>



<p>And then, yeah, I have a follow-up about the questions &#8212; about the vaccine for kids real quick, too.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Any thoughts on that?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re looking under every couch cushion to see what is available.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;ve made available yesterday with that announcement about the $5 billion is what we&#8217;re able to put towards the vaccine negotiation right now.&nbsp; We certainly hope that we can work with Congress in the coming weeks to, you know, receive additional funds to be able to purchase more doses.&nbsp; But at this point, we&#8217;re not in a position to guarantee that we&#8217;ll be able to do that with remaining funds.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, the only thing I will add is: These were incredibly painful decisions.&nbsp; If you&#8217;ve, you know, certainly tracked the work of this administration, listened to us for last couple of years, we believe deeply in widespread availability of testing.&nbsp; To cut back on funding &#8212; to pull funds from testing availability, to lose funds for domestic testing manufacturing &#8212; these were incredibly difficult decisions.</p>



<p>And so, you know, the bottom line here is: These are not the tradeoffs that we should be having to make at this point in the pandemic.&nbsp; We shouldn&#8217;t have to choose between testing and vaccines.&nbsp; We should be able to do both.&nbsp; We can do both, but we do need Congress to step up and be a partner in this effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, you had a question about kids under five, I think, as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Do you guys &#8212; I know you&#8217;re going to do everything you can to get as many kids vaccinated in this age group as possible.&nbsp; Do you expect the adoption rate to be similar to the 5- to 11-year-olds, where I think the numbers are around a third of 5- to 11-year-olds who have gotten their first doses.&nbsp; Do expect it to be higher, lower with this youngest age group?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Well, let me start off with a couple of thoughts on this, and then I&#8217;d love Dr. Murthy to talk about it as well.</p>



<p>Two things.&nbsp; First is: Our job, first and foremost, is to make sure that these vaccines are widely available and highly accessible.&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is number one.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to make sure that happens.</p>



<p>Again, all of this, and everything we&#8217;re talking about today, is with the assumption that FDA and CDC authorize these.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s set that aside.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to be the critical part.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Assuming they do, first and foremost, we&#8217;re going to make sure that in the &#8212; in the days and weeks that follow any CDC recommendation, we make these vaccines widely available, highly accessible so that parents can get their kids vaccinated.</p>



<p>Now, second important point is: If you go back to December of 2020 and look at surveys that were done of adults, about a third of adults said they would go out and get vaccinated right away.&nbsp; What we know now is about 80 percent of adults have gotten at least one shot.</p>



<p>A reminder that these things take time, that vaccine confidence builds over time.&nbsp; It builds with trusted voices, physicians, faith leaders, others helping people get vaccinated.&nbsp; This is not a one-and-done, this is not an automatic.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we have seen for kids 12 and above.&nbsp; We’re continuing to see that with kids 5 to 11.&nbsp; And we expect that to be an ongoing journey for kids under five.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I remain very optimistic that we&#8217;re going to get more and more children vaccinated and protected over time.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t have any internal targets of what that number should look like after a week or after three weeks or after a month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vivek.</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Yeah, no, I certainly agree with Dr. Jha on this.&nbsp; And, you know, if you look at the past, like Dr. Jha was saying, the things that have actually increased people&#8217;s confidence in getting vaccinated is when the FDA and CDC weigh in, look at the data, and make that data publicly available, and then weigh in with a recommendation.&nbsp; When people see their friends and family members getting vaccinated, that also helps. And when people can have conversations with their doctors, with their friends and family, that also helps to increase their comfort with getting vaccinated.</p>



<p>What we are going to do in this vaccination effort is build on all of the lessons that we have learned over the last 18 months to make sure that we are getting parents the information that they need to make a decision for their kids, but also to make sure they have as much access as possible to these vaccines &#8212; that they can get them easily in pharmacies, in children&#8217;s hospitals, in pediatricians’ offices, and in other locations around the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But our lessons from the past have taught us that in addition to us speaking directly to the public, that our partnerships &#8212; partnerships we built over the last 18 months &#8212; are going to be critical here &#8212; partnerships with doctors and nurses, with faith leaders, with educators, and with community organizations across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is why we built the COVID-19 Community Corps to begin with in the spring of 2021.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve continued to engage with that community.&nbsp; And it’s why we&#8217;re calling the broader community to action right now to make sure parents have accurate information, that they don&#8217;t fall prey to misinformation that&#8217;s out there but they have the right information so they can make the best decisions for their kids.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Kevin, back to you.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Just a couple more questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Jeannie Baumann at Bloomberg.&nbsp; Hey, Jeannie, can &#8212; might be on mute.&nbsp; All right, Jeannie, we will come back to you.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s go to Nate Weixel at the Hill.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; A question about supply.&nbsp; You know, it seems like there&#8217;s going to be 10 million doses initially.&nbsp; Is there a plan B if only one gets authorized, in terms of what&#8217;s going to be available to states?&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Dawn, thoughts?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; Thank &#8212; thank you for that good question.&nbsp; So we do have 10 million available across both vaccines, and we&#8217;re not in a position to pre-judge what the FDA and CDC are going to decide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;ll continue to make both vaccines available in our preordering phase accordingly.&nbsp; Should we end up with only one vaccine authorized, which we&#8217;re not anticipating or pre-judging whether that might happen, we will adjust supply accordingly.&nbsp; But at this point, it has been our goal to have both of these vaccines available and preordering.</p>



<p>You know, we&#8217;re really lucky to have two good options being considered by FDA and CDC next week, and we&#8217;ll continue to prepare as if both will be recommended and authorized.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Jeannie, I&#8217;m just checking if you&#8217;re able to speak.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me now?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Hi, Jeannie.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; I was just wondering how this rollout is different from the 5- to 11-year-old vaccine rollout, or if it is, what the distinction is.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll start off, because I was not in this role during the 5 to 11-year-olds.&nbsp; So I &#8212; what I know &#8212; and then, again, my colleagues here were, so I&#8217;d love to hear from them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One thing that I think is going to be different is, you know, while we are going to make this widely available across a variety of different locations and channels, my suspicion is a lot more parents are going to get their kids vaccinated in physician offices and pediatricians’ and offices of family physicians.&nbsp; So, I think that part will be different.</p>



<p>But &#8212; and every time we&#8217;ve done a rollout, we have learned from the lessons of the past.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve looked at what has worked and not and thought about what are the changes that we need to make so that we&#8217;re constantly learning and constantly getting better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I wasn&#8217;t here for the previous rollout, so I&#8217;m going to first turn it to Dawn and then to Vivek to see if you have any more specific reflections.</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just a couple of distinctions that Dr. Jha didn&#8217;t mention.&nbsp; One is we didn&#8217;t have two vaccines that were both being considered at the same time for the five to elevens.&nbsp; And so, the planning we&#8217;ve been talking about, where we&#8217;re making and planning for both to be available, is different.&nbsp; And &#8212; but one of the things that we know is important for us to be able to provide both, should both be authorized and recommended.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then just to underscore what Dr. Jha said about the smaller children likely not going into a major pop-up clinic or site or large vaccination center but likely, you know, seeking this vaccine in a pediatrician’s office, a &#8212; you know, a family care provider, a pharmacy setting.&nbsp; And so, making sure that we adjust the availability of doses to accommodate the needs of this younger age population.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Dr. Murthy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Yeah, and as Dr. Jha said, you know, this &#8212; we&#8217;re really building on lessons we&#8217;ve learned in the past.&nbsp; And one of the key lessons that has come up, especially during our 5 to 11 campaign, is that, you know, parents, understandably, are cautious about the decisions they make when it comes to their children&#8217;s healthcare.&nbsp; Sometimes they want to have not one but two or three conversations with somebody they trust.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, our goal then is to double, triple down on the relationships and partnerships we&#8217;re building with those trusted messengers.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re working even more closely with pediatricians and family medicine doctors.&nbsp; We’re working harder to make sure that parents can get vaccines in sites that they&#8217;re comfortable with, like doctors’ offices and their children&#8217;s hospital.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;ll continue to do in this, knowing that parents of kids, you know, who have &#8212; of under five &#8212; and I say this as a parent myself of a four-year-old &#8212; they want to be absolutely sure that they&#8217;ve got the right information, and sometimes that requires multiple contexts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re going to keep working on this.&nbsp; And again, our goal is to make sure that every parent out there of a child under five has the information they need to get their child vaccinated.&nbsp; And we also want to use this as an opportunity, Nate, to make sure that &#8212; or Jeannie &#8212; to make sure that people who have kids who are over five also take this as an opportunity to remember that getting vaccinated is important as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, if you&#8217;re out there and you&#8217;ve got a child who&#8217;s five years old or above and they haven&#8217;t gotten vaccinated yet, or they&#8217;re eligible to get boosted and they haven&#8217;t gotten boosted yet, please go out there and consider getting your child a shot &#8212; because we know that there is still COVID around.&nbsp; We know that kids who are vaccinated are less likely to be hospitalized or end up with severe complications, like the Multisystem Inflammatory Syndrome.</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s a step we&#8217;re taking.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why I got my five-year-old vaccinated.&nbsp; And it’s why when a vaccine is available for kids under five, I will be in line with my four-year-old to get her vaccinated as well.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Last question, let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett with ABC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering when you will need funding to be able to reverse the stoppage of the domestic manufacturing on testing and if you&#8217;re still asking for $22.5 billion, even though you&#8217;ve now moved some funds around.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Let me start, and I&#8217;d love to hear Dawn&#8217;s thoughts on this.&nbsp; The domestic manufacturing of testing issues really &#8212; it&#8217;s really very unfortunate because we &#8212; the U.S. government put in a lot of effort and resources into building up that domestic manufacturing.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re seeing is, day by day, week by week, that beginning to go away.</p>



<p>Companies, because the demand has fallen for these tests, are laying off workers.&nbsp; They&#8217;re shutting down production lines. And in some cases, they’re se- &#8212; they’ve &#8212; in the past &#8212; and they&#8217;re going to likely do this again &#8212; selling off their equipment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, if we get more resources down the road, we will be able to reverse some of it.&nbsp; It will be more expensive.&nbsp; It will be difficult.&nbsp; If we do not get these resources now and we find ourselves in a surge without enough tests, we will largely rely on foreign manufacturers, mostly from China, to provide the tests that Americans need.</p>



<p>That is not the situation we need to be in.&nbsp; And it is absolutely essential that we continue to have a domestic manufacturing capacity that can produce tests for the American people, both during times when infection numbers are low but particularly so when infection numbers are high.&nbsp; And I think, personally, that it&#8217;s hugely problematic that we&#8217;re not able to continue doing that because of congressional inaction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of the resources we need &#8212; $22.5 billion has been our request, because what that will do is allow us to get enough vaccines for every American, to make sure that we have enough therapeutics, to make sure that we actually can continue the domestic manufacturing, but just make sure we have enough testing supply.</p>



<p>So those resources are still what are essential.&nbsp; And, of course, the money we&#8217;ve taken away &#8212; we need to have a PPE national stockpile.&nbsp; It&#8217;s unacceptable that, as a country, we are not stockpiling personal protective equipment to protect doctors and nurses.&nbsp; Those are the kinds of choices we are being forced into.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, yes, the resources that we need are still there to make sure that we are able to continue those efforts.</p>



<p>Dawn?</p>



<p>MS. O’CONNELL:&nbsp; And just to underscore what Dr. Jha said, you know, we would need the money as soon as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the lessons we learned last year and have applied during the Omicron surge is when &#8212; in the spring of last year, when vaccines were being introduced and tests weren&#8217;t as readily available, we didn&#8217;t have the over-the-counter tests, a lot of, you know, the companies saw demand drop off, and they let workers go; sold the equipment, as Dr. Jha mentioned; and really downsized.&nbsp; And then we saw Delta, and then we saw Omicron.</p>



<p>And what we also learned was how long it takes for them to hire the employees they need and to ramp up production.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a weeks-to-months process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also learned in the course of these two years that this virus is anything but predictable.&nbsp; So for us to lose this capacity again and then be forced to ramp up by hook or by crook in the coming months with a potential variant coming, you know, it&#8217;s just not a good place for the country to be.&nbsp; It puts us back to where we were, despite all the effort and all the hard work we&#8217;ve invested in this testing manufacturing capacity.</p>



<p>So we, you know, urge Congress to work with us to restore this funding as quickly as possible so we don&#8217;t find ourselves flat-footed.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; And let me make one last point on this.&nbsp; It is also fiscally the prudent thing to do.&nbsp; It&#8217;s far more expensive to have to rebuild that domestic manufacturing capacity, far more expensive to have to go back and rehire and buy new equipment, and how &#8212; and we end up funding and supporting a lot of that effort.</p>



<p>So, from a just pure fiscal prudence point of view, maintaining this capacity, making sure we can tap into it when there is a surge and we need more testing, is really a smart thing to do.&nbsp; Obviously, from a public health point of view, it&#8217;s a no-brainer, in terms of protecting the health of the American people.&nbsp; But even financially, it&#8217;s much smarter.</p>



<p>So, acting early is clearly the right thing to do.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re hoping that Congress steps up and acts much &#8212; as quickly as possible so we can move in the right direction.</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Kevin, back to you.&nbsp; Are we &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; We&#8217;re done.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, everybody, for joining us today.&nbsp; And a huge thanks to both Dawn O’Connell, our Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, and Dr. Vivek Murthy, our Surgeon General, for joining us.&nbsp; Thank you both.&nbsp; And thank you for all your questions.</p>



<p>And we look forward to staying engaged and involved and sharing with you all the information we have in the days and weeks ahead as we &#8212; as we work to get vaccines out to the last group of Americans who are yet eligible &#8212; who have not yet been eligible, to make sure they get protected as well.</p>



<p>Thank you so much.&nbsp; And have a great day, everybody.</p>



<p>11:49 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Harris Launches the U.S.-Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis 2030 (PACC&#160;2030)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-launches-the-u-s-caribbean-partnership-to-address-the-climate-crisis-2030-pacc-2030/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 16:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Harris announced the U.S.-Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis 2030 (PACC 2030). &#160;PACC 2030 is the Biden-Harris Administration’s new initiative involving fresh commitments to — and integration of — climate adaptation and resilience and clean energy programs across the Caribbean region. &#160;The Biden-Harris Administration recognizes the unique and evolving climate and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Harris announced the U.S.-Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis 2030 (PACC 2030). &nbsp;PACC 2030 is the Biden-Harris Administration’s new initiative involving fresh commitments to — and integration of — climate adaptation and resilience and clean energy programs across the Caribbean region. &nbsp;The Biden-Harris Administration recognizes the unique and evolving climate and energy challenges facing Caribbean nations, and we are committed to working together on solutions. &nbsp;This comprehensive, adaptive, and goal-oriented approach will support our Caribbean neighbors in addressing energy security and climate adaptation and resilience with the urgency these challenges demand.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Caribbean is on the front lines of the climate crisis, including sea level rise that threatens low-lying islands and exacerbates storm surge associated with hurricanes. &nbsp;The climate crisis is also compounding the challenges facing Caribbean nations as a result of COVID-19-related economic disruptions. &nbsp;Addressing energy security and building climate resilience can unlock new opportunities and safeguard communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>PACC 2030 establishes a framework to elevate U.S. cooperation with Caribbean countries to support climate adaptation and strengthen energy security, while building the resilience of critical infrastructure and local economies to the climate crisis. &nbsp;PACC 2030 will serve as the U.S. government’s primary mechanism for regional climate adaptation and resilience and energy cooperation through 2030, as we work toward meeting the long-term goals of the Paris Agreement and the 2030 Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).<br>&nbsp;<br>This approach recognizes that all countries in the region are vulnerable to climate change and extreme weather events and require support to address these challenges.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our collaboration under the PACC 2030 framework will advance two strategic objectives:</p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong>Strengthening Energy Security: &nbsp;</strong>The United States will partner with Caribbean nations and regional institutions to promote stable access to clean energy resources and resilient energy infrastructure on a timely, sustainable, and affordable basis. This includes enhancing the resilience of the region’s energy systems to both natural and manmade shocks, from hurricanes to oil price spikes.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Promoting Climate Adaptation and Resilience</strong>:&nbsp; The United States will collaborate with governments in the region to enhance the Caribbean’s adaptive capacity and resilience to climate change; facilitate access to climate-smart services, tools, and technical assistance; and support the design and development of climate-resilient infrastructure.</li></ol>



<p>To achieve these objectives, PACC 2030 will organize its activities and programs under four pillars:</p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong>Improving Access to Development Financing:&nbsp; </strong>Recognizing that access to financing is critical to achieving the region’s climate and clean energy objectives, PACC 2030 will work to expand existing access to project financing and unlock new financing mechanisms to support climate and clean energy infrastructure development in the region. &nbsp;Key actions under this pillar will include increasing U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC) financing for climate and clean energy projects in underserved Caribbean countries, as well as collaborating with multilateral development banks (MDBs) and multilateral climate and environmental trust funds to improve the policy environment and unlock access to additional&nbsp;infrastructure financing, for the Caribbean.</li><li><strong>Facilitating Clean Energy Project Development and Investment:&nbsp;</strong>To attract private investment in clean energy infrastructure and climate adaptation projects in the region, PACC 2030 will support the development of bankable infrastructure projects, promote sound regulatory policies, build project pipelines, and facilitate investment opportunities.<strong> &nbsp;</strong>Key actions under this pillar will include the establishment of a new PACC 2030 Investment Facilitation Team and a new PACC 2030 Technical Assistance Program that can help mobilize private investment and partner with electric utilities and regulators to integrate more clean energy into Caribbean power and transportation systems.</li></ol>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong>Enhancing Local Capacity Building:&nbsp; </strong>With the goal of enhancing local capacity to assess, plan for, predict, mitigate, and respond to extreme weather events and related risks in a changing climate, PACC 2030 will increase access to and effective utilization of climate and weather information and decision-support tools. &nbsp;Additionally, PACC 2030 will establish clean energy and climate-focused educational exchanges, internships, and trainings to support pathways to careers in climate adaptation and clean energy. &nbsp;Key actions under this pillar will include providing access to global climate data and new forecasting tools, as well as expanding the 100,000 Strong in the Americas public-private partnership to the Caribbean.</li><li><strong>Deepening Collaboration with our Caribbean Partners:</strong>&nbsp; Leveraging engagements at all levels — from leader-level Summits to technical working groups — to achieve strategic objectives, PACC 2030 will focus on translating high-level climate and clean energy political commitments to policy roadmaps, implementation plans, and concrete outcomes.&nbsp; Key actions under this pillar will include collaboration with the Caribbean Centre for Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency (CCREEE) and the Caribbean Electric Utility Services Corporation; participating in the Caribbean Sustainable Energy Forum to elevate technical engagement on clean energy and transportation development in the region; and collaboration with the Caribbean Disaster Emergency Management Agency, the Regional Security System, and the Caribbean Institute for Meteorology and Hydrology on climate adaptation and resilience issues.</li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong><u>U.S.-Caribbean PACC 2030 Pillars of Action</u></strong></p>



<ol type="1"><li><strong>Improving Access to Development Financing:</strong>&nbsp;</li></ol>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">U.S. Development Financing</span>:  DFC will explore ways to increase access to DFC financing for climate and clean energy projects in underserved Caribbean countries.  DFC will ensure integrated collaboration under the PACC 2030 Technical Assistance Program by following up on project-specific technical assistance with financing options.  DFC will also seek to partner with the World Bank, the Inter-American Development Bank (IDB), the Caribbean Development Bank (CDB), and other MDBs to enhance capital mobilization and expand access to financing. </li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">International Financing Mechanisms</span>: The United States will advocate for improved access to international financing mechanisms to unlock additional financing for infrastructure projects in underserved Caribbean countries.  The Department of Treasury will (1) explore options to expand the use of MDB debt deferment clauses to create additional fiscal space to respond to economic shocks; (2) be open to extending temporary access to World Bank Group resources following extreme events for climate-vulnerable Caribbean countries that have graduated from MDB financial assistance programs; (3) request that the World Bank improve transparency on the criteria for accessing International Development Association assistance in the event of climate-related disasters; (4) support expanded access to blended financing for Caribbean Nations and advocate for robust access to finance for all small island developing states in multilateral environment and climate funds (e.g. Green Climate Fund, Global Environment Facility); and (5) work to extend additional support for Latin American and Caribbean countries through new resources for IDB Invest and, in the context of meaningful structural reforms, the IMF’s Resilience and Sustainability Trust.  </li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">Caribbean Development Bank</span>:  The United States, through its bilateral grants, technical assistance, and project financing, will expand cooperation with the Caribbean Development Bank (CDB) and will encourage deeper cooperation between the CDB and the IDB and the World Bank on financing to CDB member states. To advance this effort, the United States will explore, including through consultations with the U.S. Congress, membership in the CDB, consistent with U.S. standards for membership in multilateral development banks.</li></ul>



<ol type="1" start="2"><li><strong>Facilitating Project Development and Investment:</strong>&nbsp;</li></ol>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">PACC 2030 Investment Facilitation Team</span>: The State Department’s Bureau of Energy Resources will collaborate with the U.S. Agency for International Development and the U.S. Trade and Development Agency to lead the new PACC 2030 Investment Facilitation Team, which will: (1) build a pipeline of climate and clean energy projects in the Caribbean; (2) identify existing funding gaps in renewable energy and energy efficiency sectors; (3) explore opportunities to expand power generation from cleaner sources; and (4) and establish a project facilitation and investment mechanism to leverage greater private sector investment in climate and clean energy projects. </li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">PACC 2030 Technical Assistance Program</span>:  The United States will collaborate with Caribbean national and regional authorities and institutions to promote the goals of PACC 2030 and will explore ways to deliver technical support to develop bankable climate and clean energy projects in the Caribbean.  Support under this program will prioritize: (1) conducting feasibility studies and comprehensive analyses to move projects from concept to financing; (2) building Caribbean regulatory and utility capacity to deploy clean energy and operate reliable and resilient power systems; (3) strengthening the use of climate science and analysis for decision-making; (4) developing and implementing climate adaptation strategies for infrastructure development and building codes; (5) implementing climate-smart resource management strategies, such as improved watershed management and climate smart agriculture; and (6) accelerating the development and adoption of climate and disaster resilient approaches in the region’s priority economic sectors of agriculture, water, and blue economy.   </li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">PACC 2030 Roadshow Series</span>:  The United States will host a series of project development roadshows and reverse trade missions in the Caribbean to identify and cultivate new clean energy and climate adaptation projects for priority consideration.  </li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">Climate and Clean Energy Reverse Trade Missions</span>: The United States will host targeted reverse trade missions and trainings to present U.S. technologies, solutions, and best practices to key stakeholders to support them in addressing climate and clean energy challenges in the Caribbean.</li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">Energy Procurement Exchanges</span>:  The United States will convene energy sector procurement officials for climate and energy resilience-focused exchanges and visits to the United States.  These activities will support Caribbean countries’ efforts to establish procurement practices and policies that integrate life-cycle cost analysis and best value determination in a fair and transparent manner. </li></ul>



<ol type="1" start="3"><li><strong>Enhancing Local Capacity Building:</strong>&nbsp;</li></ol>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">Global Climate Data, Tools, and Information</span>: The United States will work with Caribbean partners to address region-specific needs for early warning, disaster risk reduction, and climate adaptation, and to provide access to global climate data, tools, and information.  To strengthen regional and national partner institutions and fora, the United States will support capacity building to forecast, prepare for, and respond to coastal hazards and extreme weather, water, and climate events; enhance ecosystem resilience; and help develop the next generation of climate-informed decision-makers.</li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">User-Informed Climate Data Systems</span>:  The United States will work with Caribbean partners to make climate information relevant, accessible, and useful for decision-makers in both the public and private sectors to improve their ability to adapt to climate change, mitigate disasters risks, and enhance resilience.  Activities will focus on strengthening and expanding user-informed climate data systems to support climate information sharing and use through improved availability and accessibility; increasing the adoption of adaptation plans and coping mechanisms and strategies; and supporting efficient hazard information systems to improve disaster resilience.</li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">100,000 Strong in the Americas — Climate and STEM</span>: The United States will expand this signature public-private partnership to include a focus on the Caribbean, which will aim to build institutional capacity and increase access to innovative, inclusive training and student development programs in climate, green economies, STEM, health, and other areas. </li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">Building Local Island-to-Island Solutions for Climate and SDGs</span>: The United States will facilitate peer-to-peer networks connecting Caribbean climate experts with those of island jurisdictions in the United States and beyond, providing targeted assistance in response to stakeholder needs to advance best practices in climate strategies and data applications to advance 2030 SDG and climate goals. </li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">Nature-Based Solutions to Climate Change</span>:  The United States will support climate change adaptation, mitigation, and resilience by working with Caribbean countries to build capacity for designing and managing effective and expanded marine protected area networks.  These activities will focus on nature-based solutions to climate change that protect coastlines, sequester carbon, and result in more resilient habitats, living marine resources, and communities that depend upon them.</li></ul>



<ol type="1" start="4"><li><strong>Deepening Collaboration with Caribbean Partners:</strong>&nbsp;</li></ol>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">U.S.-Caribbean Leader Engagement at the Summit of the Americas</span>: At the Summit of the Americas, Vice President Harris will discuss with Caribbean leaders how to leverage this comprehensive, adaptable, and goal-oriented partnership to further engage the private sector and support the Caribbean in addressing energy security and climate adaptation with the urgency it demands. </li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">Caribbean Clean Energy and Climate Adaptation and Resilience Events</span>:  The United States will co-convene a panel discussion with the Dominican Republic, as the lead of the Summit of the Americas Transitional Energy Working Group, to highlight the key role the private sector will play in the Caribbean’s transition to clean and renewable energy.  In addition, the United States will participate in the biennial Caribbean Sustainable Energy Forum to elevate engagement on clean energy and transportation development in the region.  In consultation with Caribbean governments and partners, additional events will be developed that may include investment promotion, technical and regulatory capacity building and training, and other activities.</li><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">Caribbean Centre for Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency (CCREEE)</span>:  The United States will collaborate with CCREEE to promote the use of sustainable energy in the region through a climate resilient path that supports economic growth and social development. </li></ul>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">Caribbean Regional Climate Outlook Forum</span>:  The United States will work with partners, including the Caribbean Institute for Meteorology and Hydrology, to foster joint research, training, and engagement focused on enhancing the Caribbean Regional Climate Outlook Forum and the use of this network to reduce climate risks and enhance resilience across the region. </li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on the Administration&#8217;s Operational Plan for Vaccinating Children Under Five Against&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/09/background-press-call-on-the-administrations-operational-plan-for-vaccinating-children-under-five-against-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 15:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (June 8, 2022) 5:33 P.M. EDT MR. MUNOZ:&#160; All right.&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Thank you for joining us for a call to discuss the Biden administration’s plan &#8212; operational plan for vaccinating children with &#8212; against COVID-19.&#160; On today’s call we have [senior administration official].&#160; She is our [redacted].&#160; We also have [senior administration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(June 8, 2022)</p>



<p>5:33 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us for a call to discuss the Biden administration’s plan &#8212; operational plan for vaccinating children with &#8212; against COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On today’s call we have [senior administration official].&nbsp; She is our [redacted].&nbsp; We also have [senior administration official].&nbsp; And for questions, we also have [senior administration official].</p>



<p>With that, I will kick it to [senior administration official] for remarks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much, Kevin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks so much for joining the call.&nbsp; We’re very excited to talk to you about all the planning that we’ve been doing in anticipation of possible authorization and recommendation for pediatric doses for kids under five.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; So, let me start with the timeline we’re currently tracking.&nbsp; Right now, FDA is working through a rigorous and independent scientific process.</p>



<p>As part of that process, FDA’s advisory committee will meet next Tuesday, June 14th, and Wednesday, June 15th, to review the data submitted by both Pfizer and Moderna for their vaccines for kids under six and under five.</p>



<p>We expect &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you may have muted yourself.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry, I hit my &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I’m sorry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; so, I think I already went over.&nbsp; Next Tuesday, June 14th and June 15th, FDA’s VRBPAC will review the submissions by Pfizer and Moderna.&nbsp; We expect FDA’s decision shortly after these meetings.</p>



<p>And then, CDC has announced that ACIP, its advisory committee, will meet on Friday, June 17th, and Saturday, June 18th, after which the CDC director would issue her recommendation.</p>



<p>At that point, after all those actions are taken &#8212; if they are taken &#8212; vaccinations can begin.</p>



<p>As a reminder, Monday, June 20th, is an important federal holiday.&nbsp; So, those are the key dates that we’re tracking for this.</p>



<p>I do want to emphasize, you know, we think it’s important to do this right.&nbsp; That’s what this entire process is about.&nbsp; And we’re not going to prejudge the outcome of the decisions being considered by FDA and CDC.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; So, let’s talk about, you know, if FDA authorizes and CDC recommends one or both of the COVID-19 vaccines for this age group, it would be an historic milestone in the nation’s fight against the virus.&nbsp; It would mean that nearly every American is now eligible for the protection that vaccination provides.</p>



<p>We know that there are many parents who have been eagerly awaiting the opportunity to vaccinate their youngest kids, and we share their eagerness.&nbsp; Therefore, you know, every day, all day, right now, we are focusing on getting ready to have this as accessible as possible to as many families as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re going to immediately launch &#8212; you know, if, in fact, FDA authorizes and the CDC recommends, we’re going to immediately launch a comprehensive nationwide effort to ensure that parents can get their youngest kids vaccinated easily and do so at locations that they know and they trust.</p>



<p>We will also launch an effort to ensure that parents have answers to their questions and the facts that they need to make informed decisions for their kids.</p>



<p>Based on the timeline I outlined, we could see vaccines start to be delivered to sites over that long weekend.&nbsp; We do expect that many pediatricians’ offices will be closed to observe Juneteenth on that Monday.&nbsp; So, realistically, vaccines for our youngest kids could start in earnest as early as Tuesday, June 21st.</p>



<p>Importantly, we know that it will take some time to ramp up.&nbsp; As more doses are delivered and more appointments become available, within a few weeks, parents who want an appointment will be able to make one.</p>



<p>Vaccinations will be available at a variety of trusted locations, but we know that many families will actually turn to their pediatricians and primary care doctors.&nbsp; And we stand ready to support those frontline providers.</p>



<p>We encourage every provider who can take this on to sign up.&nbsp; And we encourage parents to reach out to their pediatricians or family doctors directly to learn more about their plans to offer appointments.</p>



<p>Vaccines.gov will also continue to be an important resource for the families who need it.</p>



<p>We are also ready to leverage federal programs that serve parents and families.</p>



<p>We’re going to be reaching out to millions of children and their parents and guardians nationwide through WIC and SNAP, through Head Start and childcare programs, through HUD-supported housing, and Medicaid, and CHIP.</p>



<p>The administration’s goal on COVID from day one has been to leave no stone unturned and to deploy every capability of the federal government.&nbsp; We will put that into practice and help to vaccinate America’s youngest kids.</p>



<p>Let me close by highlighting the work that we’re doing to reach every parent and child, including those who may have questions.</p>



<p>We’re going to work with trusted organizations like the American Academy of Pediatrics, the Association of Children’s Museums, the American Library Association, the National PTA, the National Diaper Bank Network, and the National Association of Community Health Centers, as well as a number of Black, Latino, AANHPI, and Native American community-based organizations.</p>



<p>These organizations will work on a national and local level to help raise awareness and answer questions through a variety of activities.</p>



<p>We’re also going to activate our 17,000-plus-member HHS COVID-19 Community Corps, which will help provide creative, kid-focused English and Spanish toolkits to trusted local messengers.</p>



<p>This type of work will not always make headlines, but it’s the kind of local, community-by-community, person-to-person approach that has worked to date in getting over twenty- &#8212; 220 million Americans fully vaccinated.</p>



<p>With that, I’m going to turn it over to my colleague, [senior administration official].&nbsp; [Senior administration official]?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], thanks so much.&nbsp; Wonderful to be here.</p>



<p>You know, over the past 16 months, together with our partners, we have managed one of the most complex logistical challenges in our nation’s history: delivering more than 700 million doses of COVID-19 vaccine to more than 90,000 locations nationwide.</p>



<p>Today, as [senior administration official] said, more than 220 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; But we know that our work is not done yet.</p>



<p>As [senior administration official] noted, having COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of five would be a significant milestone in our historic vaccination program, helping extend the protection that vaccines offer to our youngest Americans and some additional peace of mind to parents and guardians.</p>



<p>Our objective is clear: to be ready to swiftly and efficiently deliver vaccines for kids under the age of five to communities nationwide as soon as the FDA grants emergency use authorization.&nbsp; And we are ready.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To achieve our objective, we have engaged state, local, Tribal, and territorial health departments; pediatricians and primary care providers; children’s hospitals and health systems; and pharmacies on operational planning.</p>



<p>These are many of the same partners we have been engaged with on other vaccination and COVID-19 response efforts over the past few years.&nbsp; These partners are on the frontlines and critical to success, and we stand ready to help them in any way that we can.</p>



<p>Last week, we opened up pre-ordering for states, Tribes, territories, and other partners to order in advance.&nbsp; And this would help place initial doses of vaccines to be sent in the first ordering wave.&nbsp; We are making 10 million doses of vaccine available initially, with millions more available in the coming weeks.</p>



<p>This approach allows us to seed communities with enough vaccine so that it is readily accessible and equitably distributed across the county.</p>



<p>We estimate that 85 percent of children under the age of five live within five miles of a potential vaccination site.</p>



<p>We have asked states and other partners to leverage prior pediatric vaccination best practices and tap into existing pediatric vaccination locations as they continue to sign up additional pediatricians and providers.</p>



<p>We have also asked states and other partners to ensure equity, giving priority to sites that will vaccinate children at highest risk for severe COVID-19 disease and considering factors such as hours of operation.</p>



<p>At this point in the Biden administration’s vaccination program, our partners are accustomed to this process, and so are we.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our teams are standing by and will immediately begin shipping vaccines across the country after FDA authorizes a vaccine should FDA authorize a vaccine.</p>



<p>It will take some time to position these vaccines across the country, and vaccinations can’t begin until CDC has made its decision.&nbsp; But we also know many parents have been waiting for a long time, so we will be working 24/7 until every dose is shipped and delivered.</p>



<p>As we have said previously, we are not in the predicting business; we&#8217;re in the planning business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our teams are hard at work planning for the possibility that FDA and CDC will give the green light in the near future.&nbsp; And if and when they do, we will be ready to deliver.</p>



<p>Thanks so much.&nbsp; And back to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Kevin?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s do a few questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Spencer Kimball at CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; So the ordering started last week, you said.&nbsp; How many doses of the initial 10 million have been ordered so far by pharmacies in the states?&nbsp; And how much more vaccine do you expect to come online in the coming weeks?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; So we did open ordering last week.&nbsp; We made 5 million initially available in wave one.&nbsp; Fifty-eight percent of the Pfizer total threshold was ordered.&nbsp; Thirty-four percent of the Moderna threshold was ordered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We had 53 of 62 jurisdictions ordering, and we&#8217;re currently talking to the other jurisdictions to remind them that it would be important to go ahead and get in line and place some orders.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to open a second wave today.&nbsp; So those that have additional space to order, there are another 5 million available of the first 10 million.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re continuing to manage that to make sure that we&#8217;ve got these waves well accounted for and the vaccines seeded appropriately across the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you just &#8212; what did you mean by “thresholds”? I didn&#8217;t quite understand that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve made &#8212; you know, of the 5 million, we&#8217;ve made &#8212; let me make sure I&#8217;ve got this &#8212; we&#8217;ve made half of that.&nbsp; So 2.5 Pfizer doses and 2.5 Moderna doses available.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; (Inaudible) at NPR.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could clarify where kids can get vaccinated.&nbsp; I know that you&#8217;re focusing on pediatricians and doctors’ offices, but, you know, will there also be, like, mass vaccination sites set up for kids?&nbsp; Will there be daycare and preschool campaigns?&nbsp; Like, where is the breadth of places that people can go?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s [senior administration official].&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll take a swing at this, and then [senior administration official] &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; [senior administration official] can fill in any details that I missed.</p>



<p>But, obviously, we believe that most people are going to go to their pediatrician or their primary care provider if they have one.&nbsp; However, we recognize that that&#8217;s not everyone, and so we really do want to reach anybody who wants to get a vaccine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re looking at working with our &#8212; well, we are definitely working with our federal pharmacy partners so that you can get them at pharmacies.&nbsp; We’re also working with state and local health departments in terms of setting up clinics.&nbsp; And then we’re looking at ways to set up other sort of non-traditional sites as well.</p>



<p>And, [senior administration official], do you want to talk a little bit about &#8212; more detail on that?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; So as [senior administration official] said and as you’ll see in the factsheet, I think that just landed in your inbox, a wide variety of sites available based on the preferences of parents and guardians and families.</p>



<p>The one I&#8217;d add to [senior administration official]’s (inaudible) is: Children&#8217;s hospitals and health systems, they will play a critical role in reaching the highest-risk kids in our country and in doing high volume, both through their care locations, both in the inpatient and outpatient setting, as well as through community-based clinics and trusted locations.</p>



<p>As [senior administration official] said &#8212; that we anticipate that as kids get younger, they are less likely to go to large clinics.&nbsp; You want to have that one-on-one time with a provider.</p>



<p>So &#8212; but we do know that these clinics will play some role.&nbsp; And for the sites that are ready, we&#8217;ll be working with childcare sites, we&#8217;ll be working with museums and libraries to set up these clinics in partnerships with &#8212; in partnerships with providers, in partnerships with hospitals, and make sure that communities are getting access in places that they know and trust.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you guys.&nbsp; So I wanted to just quickly go back to those numbers that [senior administration official] had mentioned.&nbsp; It seems like there are still 2.7 million unordered doses then from that first tranche.&nbsp; Is that expected?&nbsp; Do you have any explanation for why that would be lower?&nbsp; Have you had conversations with states about Biden not ordering more?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Our experience has been that people are slow to order, and this has been true across each of the times we&#8217;ve opened up ordering.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I wouldn&#8217;t focus on those early numbers.&nbsp; We &#8212; you know, we &#8212; our experience is that the longer the ordering stays open, the more likely the states come forward.&nbsp; So some of this is a matter of letting them know the ordering is available and that they can begin that process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those are just the early numbers.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not too worried or focused on that, and we&#8217;ll continue to do these outreach.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not, you know, untypical to what we&#8217;ve seen in previous waves.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And about the diff- &#8212; (inaudible) &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I would just quickly add too, from our perspective, it&#8217;s one of the reasons why the federal health centers and rural health clinics program out of HRSA and federal pharmacy program play such a critical role in making sure we&#8217;re able to get directly to these providers in the earliest days of the program launch.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let’s go to Alyssa Rosenberg at Washington Post.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Can you tell us a little bit more about what you&#8217;ve learned from the vaccination campaigns for older kids about the concerns that parents have?&nbsp; And are there ways that you&#8217;re tailoring information and messaging to both parents and providers about the vaccine that build on these previous campaigns and what you&#8217;ve seen about if either parents were enthusiastic or parents were hesitant?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, good question.&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp; And, again, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] in a second.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we have learned from our previous campaigns.&nbsp; And one of the most important lessons that we&#8217;ve learned is that, you know, we know who people listen to when making decisions, and there are trusted people in their lives.&nbsp; And some of them are doctors, some of them are community leaders.&nbsp; We are going to meet people where they are and answer their questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, what we are trying to do is we are trying to ensure that those people in communities, including pediatricians, have the information that they need to answer parents’ questions.</p>



<p>And so, you know, I think our goals are twofold: to make sure that the product is available and to make sure that parents have the information that they need about the vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official]?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, just a little additional detail on some of the exciting stuff we have underway.&nbsp; And, again, you&#8217;ll see this in the factsheet.&nbsp; We&#8217;re really excited about the role that the Community Corps is going to play in this.&nbsp; This is a network of providers and trusted messengers across the United States, and we&#8217;re going to make sure they have a whole host of resources to reach their communities with.&nbsp; You know, these are people communities know and trust.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, two, as [senior administration official] said, working in close partnership with major medical associations, we know that parents look to providers for that trusted medical advice and that they&#8217;ll be looking to providers to answer questions they may have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ll be working with AAP to launch a speakers bureau so that community organizations can request a trusted doc come and visit with communities and partake in community events to answer questions and encourage uptake.&nbsp; Really excited about that one.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see another &#8212; a bunch of other examples in that factsheet as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to follow up on that &#8212; you&#8217;ve talked a lot about the specific &#8212; about the people who are trusted, but are there specific messages that you&#8217;re trying to get out, specific concerns you&#8217;re trying to get ahead of?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think, you know, on the messages, we’ll wait for FDA and CDC to fully review and share their findings on the data.&nbsp; Then we&#8217;ll have more to share on what we can say about safety and efficacy and ways that we can keep kids and their families safe.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let’s go to Alex Tin at CBS News.&nbsp; Alex, you’re unmuted.</p>



<p>All right, we’ll go back to Alex.</p>



<p>Let’s go to Ahmed at Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; So, there are a lot of differences between the Moderna shot and the Pfizer shot for this age group, the biggest being that Moderna is two doses and Pfizer is three.&nbsp; So if both get authorized, do you plan to distribute them differently?&nbsp; Will parents be able to opt for one or the other easily?</p>



<p>And similarly, if the manufacturers decide to do a strain change in the vaccines for adults to an Omicron-specific shot like they&#8217;re talking about, would there be plans to change the pediatric vaccine as well?</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if you want to start there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hello, sorry, I couldn&#8217;t get off mute.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yes.&nbsp; Okay, so, in terms of the question about strain change: I think for right now, you know, we’re just looking at what is under review.&nbsp; You know, it is what it is right now.&nbsp; And I think, you know, at some point down the road there will be discussions.&nbsp; FDA is having discussions about strain changes, but, you know, right now, these are the products that are under review.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of distribution, I don’t &#8212; [senior administration official], do you want to talk about distribution of the doses?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, thanks.&nbsp; Great question.&nbsp; We&#8217;re making the same number of doses available both of Pfizer and of Moderna.&nbsp; So we aren&#8217;t making &#8212; you know, we aren&#8217;t prejudging any decisions made by FDA or CDC on what they might authorize or recommend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in our pre-ordering phase &#8212; which just began Friday, I want to remind everybody &#8212; we&#8217;re making equal numbers available and plan to distribute whatever is ordered.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let’s try Alex again.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Let’s go to Lourdes Torres at Univision.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One, two, three.&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Alex, hello.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Sorry for the tech issues.&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up on something that was mentioned earlier.&nbsp; You said that ordering seemed to be higher for Pfizer than Moderna.&nbsp; What are you hearing from jurisdictions as to why that is?&nbsp; Have you had any conversations about whether that will affect availability of people who prefer, say, Moderna over Pfizer?&nbsp; Thanks so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not in a position to know exactly how this is going to look.&nbsp; Again, the ordering started on Friday.&nbsp; The numbers I shared are very, very early days numbers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what we did see, which is interesting, is we saw some states and jurisdictions only order Moderna.&nbsp; We saw some states and jurisdictions only order Pfizer.&nbsp; And, of course, this is just in those first early days where the second wave of ordering is going to allow these states and jurisdictions to come back and balance out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we, at this point, I think, don&#8217;t have numbers that can tell us one way or the other.&nbsp; And our job is to make both available in equal numbers.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right, let&#8217;s try Lourdes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Given that the numbers are very early in terms of the pre-ordering, would you feel comfortable sharing a list of the ones that have ordered and the ones that have not &#8212; the states that have not, at this point?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re still so early in.&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t want to &#8212; you know, there &#8212; we have those folks that do things on the first day anything opens, and we have those folks that wait until the last minute just by virtue of &#8212; you know, of various differences among all of our states and jurisdictions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are currently working with those that have not placed orders yet, and anticipate each of them placing orders by the end of the ordering period.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re in a position at this point to share those &#8212; those names.&nbsp; If that changes, we&#8217;ll get back to you for sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Last question. &nbsp;Let&#8217;s go to Anita Powell at VOA.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Just quickly: During the Quad summit, two months ago now, the U.S. committed to donating a number of pediatric doses to foreign countries in need.&nbsp; And I was just wondering if that was part of the planning for this, where you are on this.&nbsp; And, yeah, if you could just update us on that pledge.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; [Senior administration official]?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; That plan is still underway.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce on that today, but in the near future, I expect that we will have an announcement on that.</p>



<p>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; And, Anita, those are 5-to-11 doses that we&#8217;ve committed to, just to clarify.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, thank you everybody for joining tonight.&nbsp; You all should all have a factsheet embargoed until 5:00 a.m.&nbsp; This call is embargoed until 5:00 a.m., and a reminder that it’s attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; You know where to find me if you have any questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>5:57 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Tackling Climate Change and Creating Clean Energy Jobs in the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-tackling-climate-change-and-creating/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our hemisphere is facing the devastating impacts and costs of climate change. We must tackle the climate crisis and harness the opportunity for countries in the region to create good-paying jobs, grow clean energy economies, and build resilient communities.&#160;&#160;At the Summit of the Americas, President Biden will affirm the U.S. commitment’s to building an enduring&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Our hemisphere is facing the devastating impacts and costs of climate change. We must tackle the climate crisis and harness the opportunity for countries in the region to create good-paying jobs, grow clean energy economies, and build resilient communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;At the Summit of the Americas, President Biden will affirm the U.S. commitment’s to building an enduring hemispheric partnership to address climate change, create jobs, and advance energy security.</p>



<p><strong>U.S.-Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis 2030 (PACC 2030):&nbsp;</strong>Vice President Harris will launch PACC 2030,&nbsp;a new framework to elevate U.S. cooperation with Caribbean countries to support climate adaptation and strengthen energy security, while building the resilience of critical infrastructure and local economies to the climate crisis.&nbsp;&nbsp;To achieve these objectives, PACC 2030 will organize its activities and programs under four pillars: 1) Improving Access to Development Financing; 2) Facilitating Clean Energy Project Development and Investment; 3) Enhancing Local Capacity Building; and 4) Deepening Collaboration with our Caribbean Partners.&nbsp;&nbsp;PACC 2030 will work towards meeting the objectives of the Paris Climate Agreement and the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).</p>



<p><strong>Strengthening the Clean Energy Economy:&nbsp;</strong>The United States announced it will promote greater trade and investment in clean energy, and increase support for regional cooperation through the Renewable Energy in Latin America and the Caribbean (RELAC) initiative.&nbsp; Five new countries announced on June 9 their intention to join RELAC, joining 15 other countries that have already signed on to this one-of-a-kind collective effort to reach 70% installed capacity for renewable energy generation in the region’s electricity sector by 2030.&nbsp; The Administration is also announcing its intent to provide funding support for technical cooperation on regulatory and policy frameworks under RELAC and to work with regional development banks, private financial institutions, and other partners to mobilize additional resources.</p>



<p><strong>100,000 Strong in the Americas Climate Initiative (100K CLIMA):</strong>&nbsp;100K CLIMA will build on region-wide alliances between industry, governments, and 2,500 higher education institutions to catalyze climate action and collaboration by equipping students with technical and linguistics skills to lead in a clean energy economy.&nbsp;&nbsp;This initiative is supported by the Department of State with leading private sector partners, as well as the CAF Development Bank of Latin America.&nbsp;&nbsp;A diverse array of U.S. colleges and universities will be included in 100K CLIMA, providing critical access to&nbsp;new models of inclusive education exchange programs for students and faculty from Minority Serving Institutions (MSIs), Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) and Hispanic Serving Institutions (HSIs). 100K CLIMA will increase innovative models of social inclusion in training, exchanges, and workforce development programs in the pursuit of a more sustainable future for our hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Mobilizing Climate Finance:&nbsp;</strong>In response to a collective commitment from four regional development banks to make as much as $50 billion available over the next five years to support ambitious climate action, the United States is enhancing coordination with these institutions to mobilize additional financing from the private sector and other sources.&nbsp;&nbsp;The four banks are the Inter-American Development Bank, where the United States is the largest shareholder, the Development Bank of Latin America (CAF), the Caribbean Development Bank (CDB), and the Central American Bank for Economic Integration (CABEI).&nbsp;&nbsp;Several U.S. Government agencies, including the U.S. Department of State, the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, the U.S. Agency for International Development, the U.S. Trade and Development Agency, and the Export-Import Bank of the United States will support this effort.</p>



<p><strong>Amazonia Connect:&nbsp;</strong>In recognition of the potential for forests and other ecosystems to provide as much as one-third of global climate mitigation by 2030, the United States announced its intent to provide $12 million to support Brazil, Colombia, and Peru through Amazonia Connect.&nbsp;&nbsp;This initiative will contribute to the President’s Plan to Conserve Global Forests: Critical Carbon Sinks by reducing commodity-driven deforestation and associated greenhouse gas emissions from agricultural supply chains while conserving biodiversity, improving livelihoods, and enhancing climate resilience.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Announces Operational Plan for COVID-&#8288;19 Vaccinations for Children Under&#160;5</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheetbiden-administration-announces-operational-plan-for-covid-19-vaccinations-for-children-under-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55164</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 strategy, including a historic vaccination program that has gotten 220 million Americans fully vaccinated, over 100 million people a booster shot, and made vaccines free, widely available and convenient—daily COVID-19 deaths are down 90 percent since he took office. COVID-19 vaccines remain the single-most important tool that we have&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Driven by President Biden’s comprehensive COVID-19 strategy, including a historic vaccination program that has gotten 220 million Americans fully vaccinated, over 100 million people a booster shot, and made vaccines free, widely available and convenient—daily COVID-19 deaths are down 90 percent since he took office.<br><br>COVID-19 vaccines remain the single-most important tool that we have to protect people against COVID-19 and its most serious outcomes. Next week, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) will consider whether to authorize and recommend the first COVID-19 vaccines for kids under the age of 5. If FDA authorizes and CDC recommends one or both of the COVID-19 vaccines for this age group, it would be a historic milestone in the nation’s fight against the virus—and would mean nearly every American is eligible for the protection that vaccination provides.<br><br>Today, the Biden Administration is announcing an operational plan that will ensure that vaccines—if authorized by FDA and recommended by CDC—are readily available for our youngest kids and that we continue the critical work of ensuring that all families know the benefits of getting their children vaccinated against COVID-19.<br><br>The Administration’s vaccination program for America’s youngest children will focus on addressing the specific needs of this age group and their families—recognizing that many parents and guardians will choose to get their kids vaccinated through their pediatrician or primary care doctor. As always, state and local governments, health care providers, federal pharmacy partners, national and community-based organizations, and other entities will be critical to the success of this historic, nationwide effort. And, the Administration will continue to work with trusted messengers, including pediatricians, to make a concerted effort to ensure that all families have answers to their questions and know about the importance of getting their children vaccinated.<br><br>As the FDA and CDC conduct their independent review processes, the Biden Administration is planning for all scenarios, including for the first vaccinations to start as early as the week of June 20th—with the program ramping up over time as more doses are delivered and more appointments become available.<br><br>For months, the Administration has been working with a range of stakeholders to get ready. The Administration has made 10 million vaccine doses available for states, Tribes, territories, community health centers, federal pharmacy partners, and others to pre-order. If the FDA authorizes a vaccine, the Administration will immediately begin shipping doses across the country—and will launch an effort to ensure that parents can get their youngest children vaccinated easily. 85 percent of children under the age of five live within five miles of a potential vaccination site.<br><br><strong>The Biden Administration’s plan includes:</strong><br><br><strong><u>Securing vaccine supply for our nation’s children.</u></strong> The Administration has procured a significant supply of vaccines for this age group, with 10 million doses available initially and millions more available in the coming weeks. To ensure that we are able to reach a broad range of pediatric providers—including those in smaller practices and in rural settings—vaccines will be available in package sizes of 100 doses and will come with all of the supplies that health care providers need to serve younger kids, including small needles.<br><br><strong><u>Making vaccinations available in convenient places parents and families know and trust.</u></strong> Working with states, localities, Tribes and territories, the Administration will make vaccinations for our nation’s youngest children widely available at thousands of trusted, accessible sites across the country—with 85 percent of children under the age of five living within five miles of a potential vaccination site. Vaccinations will be available at pediatricians’ and other doctors’ offices, community health centers, rural health clinics, children’s hospitals, public health clinics, local pharmacies, and other community-based organizations. The Administration will also work with state and local public health departments and others to ensure that every child—including those who may not have a pediatrician or primary care provider—has access to the vaccine. And, the Administration will work with states and other entities to make vaccinations available at convenient hours for children, parents and their guardians—including after school and evenings, and on weekends.</p>



<ul><li>Pediatricians and primary care providers: The Administration will make vaccinations available at thousands of pediatric and primary care sites across the country. Pediatricians continue to be one of the most trusted sources of information about COVID-19 for parents and will play a critical role in the nationwide effort to get our youngest children vaccinated—as they are the most common, trusted location for routine childhood vaccines. More than three in four children under the age of five receive their flu vaccine in a doctor’s office. Well-patient visits are also an opportunity for pediatric providers to conduct recommended screenings and provide counseling. The Administration is working hand-in-hand with states, localities, Tribes, and territories to prioritize these providers and ensure that they have the supply, resources, and support they need. The Administration will also continue to make vaccines available directly to health centers and rural health clinics, who together serve more than 2.2 million children under five nationwide.<br></li><li>Children’s hospitals and health systems: The Administration will make vaccinations available at more than 100 children’s hospitals and health systems nationwide. Children’s hospitals play an essential role in our efforts to ensure access for our nation&#8217;s highest-risk kids, including those with obesity, diabetes, asthma or immunosuppression. &nbsp;Through the Administration&#8217;s partnership with the Children&#8217;s Hospital Association, more than 120 children&#8217;s hospitals across 47 states and D.C. will provide pediatric vaccinations across their health care systems and in trusted community sites.<br></li><li>State and local public health clinics and sites: The Administration will build on its longstanding work with state and local health departments across the country to ensure that we are reaching those hardest-to-reach, including families who may not have regular access to a pediatrician, through public health clinics. The Administration will make available federal funding to support states as they stand up and operate these clinics, and will work hand-in-hand with states to maximize vaccination coverage and availability, particularly in the hardest-hit, highest-risk communities.<br></li><li>Local pharmacies: The Administration will make vaccinations for children available at thousands of local pharmacies nationwide through the federal pharmacy program. Participating pharmacies will offer vaccinations for this age group in a more limited set of locations, in many cases at clinics staffed by health care providers with primary care experience. And pharmacies will offer convenient hours and advanced scheduling to best meet the needs of parents and communities.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Leveraging federal programs to reach parents and families with information and advance equity.</u></strong> As with prior vaccination efforts, the Administration will leverage existing federal programs and capabilities to ensure that we are reaching parents and families with the information they need. And, as always, the Administration will remain laser-focused on equity and making sure that we reach those hardest-hit and most at-risk communities.</p>



<ul><li>Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) Program: In addition to other U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) programs, the Administration will engage families through the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) program, which serves over 6 million people, including almost half of all infants born in the United States. A longstanding partner to immunization programs, WIC settings across the country will be provided with tailored resources for talking to families about the COVID-19 vaccine and will continue providing families with referrals to vaccination providers, including those co-located with WIC settings.<br></li><li>Head Start Program: Through the Administration for Children and Families at the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the Administration will work with Head Start grantees to get critical vaccination information to the approximately 1 million families they serve. Head Start has always played a crucial role in improving health outcomes for families, and COVID-19 is no different. The Administration will support training and resources for grantees to learn about vaccines for kids under five and how grantees can talk to families about them, and it will ensure that any Head Start location is ready and able to provide vaccinations to its community gets the help it needs.<br></li><li>Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting (MIECHV) Program: The Administration will engage families through HHS’ Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting (MIECHV) Program, which each year reaches more than 140,000 parents and young children across the country that are at risk for poor maternal and child health outcomes. MIECHV home visitors will leverage these established relationships to help families learn more about COVID-19 and the safety, efficacy, and benefits of COVID-19 vaccines and, upon request, will refer families to local vaccination sites.<br></li><li>Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) programs: The Administration will launch an effort to reach more than 800,000 children age five and under supported by HUD programs, including children in households that receive housing-choice vouchers and children living in public housing and Section 8 housing. Building on successful campaigns with children in other age groups, these efforts will include education events and on-site vaccination clinics near HUD-supported housing where appropriate, in coordination with other vaccination locations in the community.<br></li><li>Medicaid and the Children’s Health Insurance Program (CHIP): The Center for Medicaid &amp; Medicare Services (CMS) will take steps to support and push the message about the importance of vaccinating the millions of children under 5 who are enrolled in Medicaid and CHIP. This outreach will involve engaging states, local jurisdictions, and stakeholders to get the latest information on vaccines for this age group to Medicaid beneficiaries and their families. This effort builds on the work that CMS has already done to require state Medicaid programs to pay health care providers for providing counseling visits to parents and guardians about the importance of kids’ vaccination—giving families the support they need to engage with trusted community providers.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Supporting education and engagement efforts to build trust among parents and families.</u></strong> While many parents are eager to vaccinate their youngest children, others have questions. To ensure that parents and families have answers to their questions and information from sources that they trust, HHS will work with a broad range of national organizations to launch a national public education campaign that reaches parents, guardians, and families with facts and information that they need to make informed choices for both their youngest and their older children.</p>



<ul><li>The HHS COVID-19 Community Corps will reach parents and families about vaccinations for kids under the age of five. Launched last April to empower people and organizations to build vaccine confidence in their communities, the Community Corps now has over 17,000 members, including health care, faith, rural, sports, and youth organizations. The ‘HHS We Can Do This’ campaign will provide a pediatric COVID-19 vaccination toolkit—in both English and Spanish—to trusted messengers, health care providers, and state and local organizations so they can reach people where they are in-person and online. HHS will also provide additional materials for stakeholders, including a superhero-themed toolkit with creative resources for hospitals and pediatricians. And, pending FDA authorization and CDC recommendation, the Administration also plans to release a new public service announcement (PSA) letting parents of children 6 months and older know that the new COVID-19 vaccines are available and offer one more way to keep their children safe. The PSA, filmed in both English and Spanish, will be distributed broadly to local television and radio networks, and would air in early July.<br></li><li>American Academy of Pediatrics (AAP) and American Academy of Family Physicians (AAFP), two leading medical, will provide a “Speaker’s Bureau” of pediatricians and family doctors who will lend their trusted voices to raise awareness, answer common questions among parents, and encourage vaccine confidence through community events, vaccine and health fairs, and other key opportunities to reach parents. AAP and AAFP will also work with HHS to co-brand a toolkit of resources geared toward pediatricians and primary care doctors, providing these and other health care providers the information and materials they need to support vaccine confidence among their patients and parents.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Association of Children’s Museums (ACM), a champion for children’s museums with more than 460 members in 50 states and 19 countries, will work with local member museums to: host vaccine pop-up clinics; provide in-person and virtual events including information sessions, community forums, and other events featuring museum leaders and medical experts to answer parent questions; display a museum exhibit providing educational information about vaccination in English and Spanish; and amplify digital and social content to reach families.<br></li><li>The National Diaper Bank Network, a nationwide organization with more than 200 member diaper bank programs that distributed over 68 million diapers last year, will distribute educational material to parents and caregivers through member diaper banks, packing fact sheets, postcards, and other materials in diaper boxes, sharing resources with local agency partners, and hosting virtual and in-person events with pediatricians and other trusted messengers.<br></li><li>The American Library Association (ALA) will provide resources to assist the nation’s 17,000 public libraries in providing trusted vaccine information to parents and guardians.&nbsp;ALA will conduct a national webinar for librarians and staff featuring a pediatrician from AAP and other trusted messengers to provide information to public librarians and staff on how they can support vaccine education and outreach, share resources through children’s programming, and host in-person events and vaccine pop-up clinics to promote vaccines in their communities. Public libraries have played an important role in the pandemic by equipping their communities with trusted information, supplies like masks and COVID-19 tests, and hosting pop-up vaccine clinics.<br></li><li>The National Parent Teacher Association (PTA) has been hosting dozens of vaccine pop-up clinics to reach parents, teachers, and school staff. The National PTA will continue to engage parents of school-aged children, as well as parents of younger children, by hosting a national symposium for local PTA leaders and affiliates featuring a pediatrician from AAP and other trusted messengers; hosting vaccine pop-up clinics in key geographic markets to reach parents of both school-aged and younger children; and hosting virtual events to reach parents and empower community leaders to act as trusted messengers and amplify vaccine information.&nbsp;<br></li><li>The National Association of Community Health Centers (NACHC), the leading association for community health centers, will provide culturally appropriate and evidence-based training to empower community health centers to act as trusted messengers with parents of school-aged and younger children and other patients in their communities. NACHC will also host virtual events, including webinars, trainings, and podcasts to aid in the dissemination of campaign materials and messaging about the importance of vaccinations for young children, and how community health workers can play a key role in reaching parents with trusted messaging.<br></li><li>Latino community-focused organizations, including the League of United Latin American Citizens (LULAC), the largest and oldest Hispanic serving organization in the US with over 1,000 LULAC Councils, will hold in-person and virtual educational events for parents and caregivers and will design and distribute bilingual, culturally relevant resources (printed and digital) to community members and partner organizations.<br></li><li>Black community-focused organizations, including the W. Montague Cobb Health Institute, a consortium of scholars working toward the elimination of racial and ethnic health disparities within the National Medical Association, will host “Stay Well Health Fairs and Vaccine Clinics,” an ongoing series of health fairs offering free vaccines, educational materials, health screenings, and pediatric roundtables featuring subject matter experts. The Women’s Missionary Society Foundation, with 800,000 members across the African Methodist Episcopal (AME) Church’s boundaries, will host “family fun day” vaccine events reaching Black families and will collaborate with AME Church daycares and pre-schools to share information and messaging about pediatric vaccines.<br></li><li>Asian American, Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander community-focused organizations, including the Asian Community Development Council, The Progressive Vietnamese American Organization, Ethnic Minorities of Burma Advocacy and Resource Center, Chinese Community Center, Filipino Family Health Initiative, and Thai Community Development Center will: engage with local communities in Chinese, Korean, Vietnamese, Tagalog and other languages where possible through in-person engagement, phone banking, social media and written resources; reach families through WIC Market Match, which serves parents with small children who are on WIC; and host weekly vaccine clinics and vaccine education classes and events.<br></li><li>Native American community organizations, including Native Roots Radio, a leading radio station for Native Americans to discuss local, regional, and national Native American news and events will conduct virtual conversations including&nbsp;physicians, community advocates, and Tribal leadership speaking on the COVID-19 pandemic including vaccinations for children, boosters, mental health and long COVID; and the USDA Food Distribution Program on Indian Reservations in partnership with the Great Plains Tribal Leaders Health Board will distribute educational materials to food distribution centers to be packaged in food boxes promoting vaccinations that are regionally and culturally tailored to Native American audiences.</li></ul>



<p>What to Expect, a platform of over 20 million moms, will author a blog series featuring doctors and other trusted experts answering questions about pediatric COVID-19 vaccines, and how moms, expecting moms, and all parents can get the information they need to get themselves and their children vaccinated; author new articles dispelling myths about the COVID-19 vaccine and children; and create and amplify new What to Expect social media content, reaching moms where they are and fighting vaccine misinformation across all platforms.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Proposes New Standards for National Electric Vehicle Charging&#160;Network</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-proposes-new-standards-for-national-electric-vehicle-charging-network/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Investments to Enable Families to Plug-In, Charge Up, and Drive Across America Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new steps to meet President Biden’s goal to build out the first-ever national network of 500,000 electric vehicle chargers along America’s highways and in communities, a key piece of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Investments to Enable Families to Plug-In, Charge Up, and Drive Across America</em></p>



<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new steps to meet President Biden’s goal to build out the first-ever national network of 500,000 electric vehicle chargers along America’s highways and in communities, a key piece of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</p>



<p>The Department of Transportation, in partnership with the Department of Energy, is <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/briefing-room/biden-harris-administration-takes-key-step-forward-building-national-network-user">proposing new standards</a> to make charging electric vehicles (EVs) a convenient, reliable, and affordable for all Americans, including when driving long distances. Without strong standards, chargers would be less reliable, may not work for all cars, or lack common payment methods. The new standards will ensure everyone can use the network –no matter what car you drive or which state you charge in.</p>



<p>The proposed standards, along with new coordinated federal actions on EVs, support President’s Biden’s priorities &nbsp;to lower costs for families, create good-paying jobs, and combat climate change. He is pressing Congress on his plan to provide tax credits that make EVs more affordable, so families’ budgets aren’t hurt by volatile gas prices. The actions will spur good-paying jobs with strong workforce requirements for America’s steelworkers, electrical workers, and laborers to build, install, and maintain the network. And, making chargers and EVs more accessible will help tackle the climate crisis – reducing emissions, increasing cleaner air, and advancing the President’s Justice40 Initiative.</p>



<p>Thanks to President Biden’s bold vision, leadership, and actions EV sales have doubled since he took office, and there are now more than two million EVs and 100,000 chargers on the road. The Biden Administration has positioned the United States to lead the electric future and make it in America:</p>



<ul><li>Secured historic investments in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law – $7.5 billion for EV charging infrastructure and more than $7 billion for the critical minerals supply chains necessary for batteries, components, materials, and recycling.</li><li>United automakers and autoworkers around an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/">ambitious target</a> for 50% of new vehicles sold in 2030 to be electric.</li><li>Triggered a string of investment commitments of over $100 billion from private companies to make more EVs and their parts in America, create jobs for our autoworkers, and strengthen our domestic supply chains.</li><li>Activated the purchasing power of the federal government to procure 100% zero-emission light-duty vehicles by 2027 and all vehicles by 2035.</li><li>Finalized the strongest passenger vehicle emissions and fuel economy standards in history.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Historic Infrastructure Investments in Charging</u></strong></p>



<p>The $7.5 billion for EV charging infrastructure in President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will build a convenient and equitable charging network through two programs. The National Electric Vehicle Infrastructure (NEVI) program will provide $5 billion in formula funding to States to build out charging infrastructure along highway corridors – filling gaps in rural, disadvantaged, and hard-to-reach locations while instilling public confidence in charging. Today’s minimum standards and requirements will guide States on how to spend federal funds in a way that makes chargers function the same from state-to-state, easy to find, use, and pay for, no matter who operates chargers. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law also provides $2.5 billion in competitive grants to support community and corridor charging, improve local air quality, and increase EV charging access in underserved and overburdened communities. &nbsp;DOT will open applications for this program later this year.</p>



<p>These federal charging programs were designed to catalyze additional private sector investments that complement the build-out of a user-friendly, cost-saving, and financially sustainable national EV charging network. Together, President Biden’s leadership is mobilizing public and private charging investment to accelerate the adoption of EVs and create good-paying jobs across manufacturing, installation, and operation. These chargers will also make sure the new renewable electricity sources like solar and wind can power the cars we drive and reduce energy costs for families.</p>



<p><strong><u>Setting the Standard</u></strong></p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law also established a <a href="https://driveelectric.gov/">Joint Office of Energy and Transportation</a> to work hand-in-hand with States, industry leaders, manufacturers, and other stakeholders to meet the President&#8217;s goals. And to ensure that this electric transformation is both timely and equitable, Vice President Harris launched an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-electric-vehicle-charging-action-plan/">EV Charging Action Plan</a> that fast tracks federal investments and targets equity benefits for disadvantaged communities – and the Department of Transportation released a <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/rural/ev/toolkit">Rural EV toolkit</a> to help ensure all Americans, regardless of where they live, have the opportunity to benefit from the lower operating costs, reduced maintenance needs, and improved performance that EVs provide. These investments, steered by the standards proposed today, will create a public charging system that meets our goals of being reliable, affordable, equitable and seamless between states and networks. They will also use workforce standards such as the Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP) to increase the safety and reliability of charging station’s functionality and usability – creating and supporting good-paying, highly-skilled union jobs in communities across the country.</p>



<p><strong><u>Additional Steps to Drive Progress</u></strong></p>



<p>Today, as part of an Administration-wide strategy, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing a fleet of actions from nine federal agencies across the charging ecosystem to complement the NEVI program – creating good-paying jobs in the U.S., reducing emissions, and putting us on a path to net-zero emissions by 2050.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The</strong> <strong>Joint Office of Energy and Transportation</strong> <a href="https://driveelectric.gov/work-with-us/">announced the formation</a> of a new Federal Advisory Committee called the EV Working Group that will be a key advisory body to “make recommendations regarding the development, adoption, and integration of light-, medium-, and heavy-duty electric vehicles into the transportation and energy systems of the United States,” including on infrastructure topics. The 25 members will be selected in the coming months. The joint office also announced a partnership to support EV charging with the American Public Power Association, Edison Electric Institute, and National Rural Electric Cooperative Association to inform electric system investments and support state planning.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Energy </strong><a href="https://www.arpa-e.energy.gov/news-and-media/press-releases/us-department-energy-announces-45-million-develop-more-efficient">announced $45 million</a> through its &#8220;EVs4ALL&#8221; program to develop very fast charging batteries to complement the rollout of the public charging network. They are also <a href="https://eere-exchange.energy.gov/Default.aspx#FoaIdd401a407-9f96-49cc-a6d8-7af4814e78e5">preparing multiple funding topics</a> for projects that offer EV charging solutions for drivers who lack access to home charging or who live in underserved communities. DOE’s Vehicle Technologies Office anticipates up to $30M in funding opportunities to support clean energy mobility pilots and demonstration in underserved and rural areas. The opportunity will seek projects to deploy EV charging solutions for drivers with no home charging and projects that will engage underserved communities to develop community-driven EV charging plans and install EV chargers in locations that maximize benefits to underserved communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Agriculture</strong> developed an <a href="https://www.rd.usda.gov/sites/default/files/508_RD_FS_71EVChargingStations.pdf">EV charging resource guide</a> and funding eligibility infographic for rural property owners, states and territories, Tribes, municipalities, cooperatives, and non- and for-profit entities to assist those looking to make the transition to electric. They also developed a <a href="https://www.rd.usda.gov/sites/default/files/508_RD_FS_LeadingTheChargeSchools.pdf">climate smart schools guide</a> that includes information on funding for charging for rural school districts. In addition, USDA signed a Memorandum of Understanding with the Department of Energy to address EV supply equipment and related charging infrastructure.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The General Services Administration</strong> created <a href="https://www.gsa.gov/about-us/newsroom/news-releases/gsa-awards-new-blanket-purchase-agreements-for-electric-vehicle-supply-equipment-procurement-05032022">Blanket Purchase Agreements</a> for federal agencies and other eligible users to seamlessly acquire an array of EV chargers and services at federally owned, managed, and occupied facilities. They also published a &#8216;Guide to Building Owners&#8217; that details the relationship between EV charging and building electricity loads – ensuring that buildings are equipped to handle new charging infrastructure, and optimize existing chargers. Through their Green Proving Ground program, GSA is working closely with the Department of Energy to install and pilot EV charging innovations, including managed and bidirectional charging, at selected GSA facilities and to accelerate market acceptance. In addition, GSA&#8217;s Public Buildings Service established an Interagency Agreement with the Department of Veterans Affairs to install EV charging stations at approximately 60 Veterans Affairs locations at a value greater than $40 million.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The National Park Service </strong>established an interdisciplinary EV Working Group that is developing a national strategy for electrifying their government fleets, public-serving transit fleets, and public-use charging infrastructure. They are in the process of transitioning Zion National Park&#8217;s transit fleet to battery-electric buses with <a href="https://www.nps.gov/zion/learn/news/zion-national-park-receives-33-million-federal-transit-grant.htm">$33 million in funding</a> from the Department of Transportation&#8217;s Nationally Significant Federal Lands and Tribal Projects program – with plans to pursue the same program to electrify transit at Grand Canyon National Park next year. In addition, NPS is working with State DOTs to fill charging gaps in corridors and routes that serve as gateways to national parks.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Housing and Urban Development</strong> has continued to support the inclusion of EV charging infrastructure as part of its green building standards through several of its housing financing programs. In addition, they are exploring the installation of EV chargers in multi-family rental housing as part of their Green Mortgage Insurance Premium incentive – lowering annual premiums for participants.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Environmental Protection Agency</strong> created a Clean School Bus Program through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to replace the nation&#8217;s fleet of dirty diesel buses, with clean, American-made, zero-emission buses. EPA <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/biden-harris-administration-makes-500-million-available-clean-school-buses-through-epa">released $500 million</a> in the first round of funding for this $5 billion program, and schools can use portions of this funding to build-out needed EV charging infrastructure for these new, clean school buses. In addition, there are now 300 different Level 2 EV charger products available under the EPA&#8217;s ENERGY STAR program.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Defense </strong>launched a pilot project to install 20 Level 2 EV chargers for government fleet vehicles at the Pentagon along with a planning study for future additional installations. The Senior Pentagon Climate Working Group also created a sub-working group focused solely on removing barriers to installing EV charging infrastructure that supports the Department’s zero-emission vehicle acquisition goals.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Commerce</strong> is supporting the build-out of the domestic EV charging supply chain and promoting foreign direct investment in American EV charging and supply equipment manufacturing. At the end of June, they will host the <a href="https://www.selectusasummit.us/">2022 SelectUSA Investment Summit</a> – the highest-profile event promoting foreign direct investment in the U.S. – where they will highlight investment opportunities in EV charging catalyzed by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. In addition, DOC’s Hollings <a href="https://www.nist.gov/mep">Manufacturing Extension Partnership</a> provides hands on assistance to manufactures across 51 centers, in every state and Puerto Rico, to address unmet needs in the EV charging supply chain and help traditional automotive suppliers diversify their customer base and enter into the EV charging market.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
