<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 09:18:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Erdogan of&#160;Turkey</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-erdogan-of-turkey/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 09:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56397</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke by phone today with President Recep Tayyip Erdogan of Turkey. President Biden noted he looks forward to seeing President Erdogan at the NATO Summit in Madrid where leaders will discuss the consequences of Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine for Transatlantic security and other threats to the Alliance such as terrorism,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke by phone today with President Recep Tayyip Erdogan of Turkey. President Biden noted he looks forward to seeing President Erdogan at the NATO Summit in Madrid where leaders will discuss the consequences of Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine for Transatlantic security and other threats to the Alliance such as terrorism, as well as take historic decisions to strengthen the Alliance&#8217;s collective defense and security. <br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Macky Sall of&#160;Senegal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/28/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-macky-sall-of-senegal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 06:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56393</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the G7 Summit, President Biden met with President Macky Sall of Senegal. Senegal is the current chair of the African Union, and the two presidents discussed the impact of Putin’s war against Ukraine on food security in Africa. President Biden discussed the coming G7 announcement on further efforts to support food security. The two also discussed the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>At the G7 Summit, President Biden met with President Macky Sall of Senegal. Senegal is the current chair of the African Union, and the two presidents discussed the impact of Putin’s war against Ukraine on food security in Africa. President Biden discussed the coming G7 announcement on further efforts to support food security. The two also discussed the G7 Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment which includes a new flagship project to invest in a new industrial-scale vaccine manufacturing facility in Senegal which will have the potential to produce hundreds of millions of doses of vaccines annually for COVID-19 and other diseases.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden to Award Medal of&#160;Honor</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/president-biden-to-award-medal-of-honor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 21:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56389</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On July 5, 2022, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will award the Medal of Honor to four U.S. Army Soldiers who fought in the Vietnam War:&#160; Staff Sergeant Edward N. Kaneshiro (posthumous), Specialist Five Dwight W. Birdwell, Specialist Five Dennis M. Fujii, and retired Major John J. Duffy.&#160; &#160;&#160; Staff Sergeant Edward N. Kaneshiro will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On July 5, 2022, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will award the Medal of Honor to four U.S. Army Soldiers who fought in the Vietnam War:&nbsp; Staff Sergeant Edward N. Kaneshiro (posthumous), Specialist Five Dwight W. Birdwell, Specialist Five Dennis M. Fujii, and retired Major John J. Duffy.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Staff Sergeant Edward N. Kaneshiro will receive the Medal of Honor posthumously for acts of gallantry and intrepidity above and beyond the call of duty while serving as an infantry squad leader with Troop C, 1st Squadron, 9th Cavalry, 1st Cavalry Division, near Phu Huu 2, Kim Son Valley, Republic of Vietnam, on Dec. 1, 1966.&nbsp; Staff Sergeant Kaneshiro and his team entered the village of Phu Huu 2 while on a search and destroy mission and were attacked by North Vietnamese.&nbsp; Staff Sergeant Kaneshiro destroyed one enemy group with rifle fire and two others with grenades, which enabled the orderly extrication and reorganization of the platoon and ultimately led to a successful withdrawal from the village.&nbsp; He served in Vietnam between July 18, 1966, until his death on March 6, 1967, as a result of a hostile gunshot wound.<br><br>Specialist Five Dwight W. Birdwell will receive the Medal of Honor for acts of gallantry and intrepidity above and beyond the call of duty while serving with Troop C, 3rd Squadron, 4th Cavalry, 25th Infantry Division, in the Republic of Vietnam on January 31, 1968.&nbsp; That day, a large enemy element initiated an assault on the Tan Son Nhut Airbase near Saigon.&nbsp; They disabled or destroyed many of the unit’s vehicles and incapacitated Specialist Five Birdwell&#8217;s tank commander.&nbsp; Under heavy enemy small-arms fire, Specialist Five Birdwell moved the tank commander to safety and fired the tank&#8217;s weapons at the enemy force.&nbsp; Afterwards, he dismounted and continued fighting until receiving enemy fire to his face and torso.&nbsp; He refused evacuation and led a small group of defenders to disrupt the enemy assault until reinforcements arrived.&nbsp; He then aided in evacuating the wounded until he was ordered to seek attention for his own wounds.&nbsp; He was honorably discharged on December 29, 1968, and today practices law in Oklahoma City.<br><br>Specialist Five Dennis M. Fujii will receive the Medal of Honor for acts of gallantry and intrepidity above and beyond the call of duty while serving as crew chief aboard a helicopter ambulance during rescue operations in Laos and the Republic of Vietnam from February 18 &#8211; 22, 1971.&nbsp; During a mission to evacuate seriously wounded Vietnamese military personnel, Specialist Five Fujii&#8217;s medevac helicopter took on enemy fire and was forced to crash land.&nbsp; Although injured, he waved off a rescue from another helicopter and remained behind as the only American on the battlefield.&nbsp; During that night and the next day, although wounded, he administered first aid to allied casualties. On the night of February 19, he called in American helicopter gunships to assist in repelling an enemy attack.&nbsp; For more than 17 hours, he repeatedly exposed himself to hostile fire as he left the security of his entrenchment to better observe enemy troop positions and to direct air strikes against them until an American helicopter could attempt to airlift him from the area.&nbsp; Upon completion of his tour, he joined the Army Reserve and today resides in Hawaii.<br><br>Major John J. Duffy will receive the Medal of Honor for acts of gallantry and intrepidity above and beyond the call of duty while serving as the senior advisor to the 11th Airborne Battalion, 2nd Brigade, Airborne Division, Army of the Republic of Vietnam, from April 14 &#8211; 15, 1972.&nbsp; Two days earlier, the commander of the 11th Airborne Battalion had been killed, the battalion command post destroyed, and Major Duffy was twice wounded.&nbsp; He refused to be evacuated.&nbsp; In the morning hours of April 14, after a failed effort to establish a landing zone for resupply aircraft, he moved close to enemy anti-aircraft positions to call in airstrikes and was wounded again, but still refused evacuation. &nbsp;In the late afternoon, the enemy began a ground assault from all sides, and Major Duffy moved from position to position to adjust fire, spot targets for artillery and direct gunship fire.&nbsp; In the early morning of April 15, after an enemy ambush, he led evacuees, many of whom were seriously wounded, to an evacuation area, where he directed gunship fire on enemy positions and marked a landing zone for the helicopters. Only after ensuring all evacuees were aboard, did he board as well, assisting a wounded friendly foreign soldier and administering aid to a wounded helicopter door gunner. Major Duffy&#8217;s service included three tours in Vietnam in a myriad of Special Forces assignments.&nbsp; He retired from the Army on May 31, 1977, and currently lives in Santa Cruz, California.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>ADDITIONAL INFORMATION ABOUT THE MEDAL OF HONOR</strong>:<br><br>The Medal of Honor is awarded to members of the armed forces who distinguish themselves conspicuously by gallantry and intrepidity at the risk of their own lives above and beyond the call of duty while:</p>



<ul><li>engaged in an action against an enemy of the United States;</li><li>engaged in military operations involving conflict with an opposing foreign force; or</li><li>serving with friendly foreign forces engaged in an armed conflict against an opposing armed force in which the United States is not a belligerent party.</li></ul>



<p>The meritorious conduct must involve great personal bravery or self-sacrifice so conspicuous as to clearly distinguish the individual above his or her comrades and must have involved risk of life.&nbsp; There must be incontestable proof of the performance of the meritorious conduct, and each recommendation for the award must be considered on the standard of extraordinary merit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on the President&#8217;s National Security Memorandum on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated&#160;Fishing</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/27/background-press-call-on-the-presidents-national-security-memorandum-on-illegal-unreported-and-unregulated-fishing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 19:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 1:42 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; We appreciate your patience with us as we’re running a few minutes behind.&#160; Today we’ll have a few speakers discuss the National Security Memorandum on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and Other Harmful Practices that the President signed this morning. As a reminder, this call is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>1:42 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; We appreciate your patience with us as we’re running a few minutes behind.&nbsp; Today we’ll have a few speakers discuss the National Security Memorandum on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and Other Harmful Practices that the President signed this morning.</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” but the embargo has now been moved up to the conclusion of this call.</p>



<p>For your awareness, not for your reporting, the senior administration officials on this call are [senior administration official], [senior administration official], and [senior administration official].</p>



<p>With that, I will pass it off to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you all for joining for today’s call.&nbsp; Really appreciate your patience with us getting it started, and really look forward to sharing with you that, today, President Biden has signed a National Security Memorandum focused on illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing and associated labor abuses.</p>



<p>This is a great capstone to National Ocean Month.&nbsp; This is following the President’s proclamation of June to be National Ocean Month and a recognition of June 8th as World Ocean Day.</p>



<p>The White House began this month with a series of announcements of the new steps the administration is taking to conserve and restore the health and productivity of the ocean for the benefit of all Americans.&nbsp; And today is the kickoff of the U.N. Ocean Conference in Portugal, which is the time for us to really highlight the international components of our engagements around ocean conservation in particular.</p>



<p>Today, we&#8217;ll be sharing with you a bit more detail around what we&#8217;re doing to combat IUU fishing.&nbsp; Again, that&#8217;s illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>IUU fishing threatens the health and precious biodiversity of our oceans, which is also facing increasing threats posed by climate change, acidification, and human pollution.</p>



<p>Additionally, IUU fishing threatens the food security of coastal communities that may not have the capacity to combat these practices and otherwise prevent overfishing in their waters and depleting of resources.</p>



<p>IUU fishing can be interconnected with a web of other troubling security challenges and criminal activities such as trafficking in persons, forced labor, trade in illicit goods, wildlife trafficking, and other violations of law.&nbsp; Some states also encourage IUU fishing by associated vessels as a method of reinforcing unlawful maritime claims.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. is committed to combating IUU fishing globally, and the National Security Memorandum that the President signed today provides the U.S government with a defined set of actions to address the problem of IUU fishing, including IUU fishing committed by distant-water fishing fleets, and associated criminal activities, such as the use of force labor in the seafood supply chain.</p>



<p>The memorandum, as you&#8217;ll see, directs departments and agencies with a variety of engagement strategies, from increased coordination with diverse stakeholders from public and private and foreign and domestic, to address the challenges in a comprehensive, all-of-government way.&nbsp; It also uses the full range of existing conservation, labor, trade, economic, diplomatic, law enforcement, and national security authorities to address these challenges, and focuses around enhancing coordination and the use of existing tools and authorities to address the challenge of forced labor in the seafood supply chain.</p>



<p>Lastly, it also calls for increased access and diplomatic engagement around training and technical support of foreign partners to carry out engagements in combating this behavior in the fishing industry.</p>



<p>So with that, I am pleased to pass this over to my colleagues from State to share a bit more and then to NOAA.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And hello to everyone.&nbsp; My name is [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>As [senior administration official] was just mentioning, the elements related to combating IUU fishing on the National Security Memorandum that was signed today by the President include diplomatic engagements.</p>



<p>The United States is one of the largest seafood markets.&nbsp; We have one of the largest exclusive economic zones and waters under our jurisdiction in the world.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also a fishing country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we cannot combat IUU fishing alone; it is a global problem.&nbsp; It is involved in the value chain that feeds not only the U.S. market but other important markets.&nbsp; And there are a lot of countries who have been working to combat IUU fishing themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we believe that one of the most important elements of our diplomatic engagement is to combine and partner with all of the countries that are engaged in this work to make sure that we are as successful as possible in addressing IUU fishing but also the related human rights, labor problems, and environmental impacts of IUU fishing.</p>



<p>And so we are very pleased this week to take advantage of the global focus on oceans at the U.N. Ocean Conference.&nbsp; And we will be launching an IUU Fishing Action Alliance to bring together countries to commit to a pledge to take urgent action against IUU fishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This will help us in the international implementation of the actions outlined in the National Security Memorandum, and it will help us capitalize on the resources and commitment of other countries, whether they&#8217;re coastal states, flag states, market states, or all of the above; and really begin to generate increased transparency in terms of fishing operations, increased accountability of fishers to the international rules or the rules of their flag authorities, and to make sure that the seafood products that are coming into the U.S. market are caught in accordance with international rules and national rules.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s one of the major actions we&#8217;ll be taking to begin immediately to bring together the diplomatic efforts necessary to ensure the National Security Memorandum is effectively implemented and does what it is intended to do.</p>



<p>So with that, I&#8217;ll turn things over to [senior administration official] to talk about some actions that NOAA will be taking as well.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>NOAA will be announcing two actions that help to achieve some of the objectives outlined in the National Security Memorandum.</p>



<p>First, today, NOAA is issuing a proposed rule which will enhance and strengthen its capabilities to combat IUU fishing and counter forced labor in the seafood supply chain by implementing several provisions under three different laws.</p>



<p>And I think the key &#8212; the key takeaway is that the &#8212;</p>



<p>what we will be able to do is we&#8217;re changing &#8212; well, we&#8217;re not changing, we are making our definition of IUU fishing consistent with that of the FAO&#8217;s, which will enable us in our comparability findings to both include forced labor and how we determine whether a country has comparable laws to ours, allowing the imports, and whether or not we identify fishing in waters under the jurisdiction of a nation without the permission of that nation or in violation of that nation&#8217;s laws and regulations.&nbsp; And so that will help us to prevent imports of those products into the United States.</p>



<p>I encourage you to look at the full spectrum of the proposed rule for a number of other provisions that are proposed here.</p>



<p>The second announcement that NOAA, together with the 21 agencies that comprise the IUU fishing interagency working group, is &#8212; we are announcing that we are finalizing a strategic &#8212; a five-year strategic plan.&nbsp; And in that strategic plan, we have identified a number of partners that we will be working directly with to combat IUU fishing on the ground.&nbsp; And those partners are Senegal, Ecuador, Panama, Taiwan, and Vietnam.</p>



<p>We’ll be doing capacity building in those countries, not because they are the primary offenders of IUU fishing, but because they have expressed a willingness to work with the United States to combat IUU fishing in their countries.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it back over to [senior administration official] and the NSC.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Keely, can you remind us how to queue up questions, please?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for the call.&nbsp; Just so I&#8217;m clear, could you maybe reiterate or be a little more specific about what the mem- &#8212; memorandum directs the agencies to do?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, as a secondary question, I wonder how much of this is due to concerns about Chinese illegal fishing.&nbsp; And, I mean, China says that it&#8217;s a responsible fishing nation, but how would you characterize China&#8217;s behavior in this area?&nbsp; And has the U.S. ever broached negotiations with China over these issues?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you for that question.&nbsp; So, with additional specificity, the NSM directs departments and agencies to work toward ending human trafficking, including forced labor and IUU fishing, while promoting sustainable use of the ocean in partnership with other nations and the private sector, and advance foreign and trade policies for the benefit of American workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And specifically, it&#8217;s asking departments and agencies to increase the coordination with diverse stakeholders, as I mentioned earlier, to use that full range of tools that I mentioned earlier to you as well, but also to do things like: investigate fishing vessels and operators suspected to be harvesting seafood with forced labor and issue with hold release orders as appropriate; to increase our engagement with key private sector and foreign partners, including by providing training and technical support to these partners; and to carry out research on labor practices in the seafood industry through Department of Labor, for instance, to coordinate more closely with the Department of Defense, the Coast Guard, and other enforcement agencies as well.</p>



<p>Specific to your question about China and our engagements there: The National Security Memorandum is not about any one specific country.&nbsp; All fishing nations, including those with distant-water fishing fleets, carry a range of flag-state responsibilities including monitoring their fleets and enforcing rules to prevent their vessels from engaging in IUU fishing.</p>



<p>It is also critical that all flag states, including the PRC, fully accept and implement their responsibilities to prevent and deter IUU fishing, and ensures sustainable conservation and management of our fishery resources.</p>



<p>The PRC is a leading contributor to IUU fishing worldwide, and it has impeded progress on the development of measures to combat IUU fishing and overfishing in international organizations.&nbsp; And the PRC has a responsibility to uphold these commitments as a flag state and actively monitor and correct the activities of fishing fleet activities in other countries’ waters &#8212; of its fleet fishing activities in other countries’ waters, including preventing its vessels from fishing outside coastal states’ license agreements or without a license to fish at all.</p>



<p>The U.S. has engaged bilaterally with the PRC to identify concerns about IUU fishing, to promote the PRC’s full implementation of flag-state responsibilities, and encourage the PRC’s improved implementation of international measures and in cooperation with agreements like the Port State Measures Agreement that now &#8212; that [senior administration official] mentioned briefly about PSMA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also call on the PRC to fulfill its pledge and actively participating in and support the international community in fighting against IU fishing.</p>



<p>Thanks so much for the question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; I had just some basic nuts-and-bolts questions.&nbsp; Is this the first time there&#8217;s been a national security memo on IUU fishing?&nbsp; And I also was hoping that the representative from NOAA could explain the first measure &#8212; the first action that they&#8217;re taking today in a little bit more detail.&nbsp; It kind of was a little bit confusing to me, and maybe she could walk us through that.</p>



<p>And then, I also just wanted to know &#8212; I didn&#8217;t get a chance to read through the entire memo, but the complaint that I often hear is that there is not enough resources and not enough agents actually, you know, working on these problems inside NOAA, inside CBP to enforce the laws that already are on the books.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m wondering if there&#8217;s any commitment from the Biden administration to increase hiring of people in this field.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to start?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I can start.&nbsp; Thank you for that question.&nbsp; Let me go through the proposed rule and see if I can clarify a little bit more what I stated.</p>



<p>The proposed rule would strengthen NOAA’s ability to address IUU fishing activities when implementing the U.S. Moratorium Protection Act &#8212; a key engagement tool used to identify, consult with, and certify nations and entities whose fishing vessels are engaged in IUU fishing, bycatch of protected living marine resources, or shark catch on the high seas.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re talking about today is really focused on that first part &#8212; the fishing vessels engaged in IUU fishing.</p>



<p>Specifically, the rule proposes to broaden the scope of activities that NOAA can consider when identifying nations for IUU fishing to include, the first thing, fishing in waters under the jurisdiction of a nation without the permission of that nation or in violation of its laws and regulations.&nbsp; And the second piece is: fishing activities in waters beyond any national jurisdictions that involve the use of forced labor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, those are the key provisions that will &#8212; should the rule get finalized with those, would allow NOAA to find a country in violation of that and prevent those products from being imported into our market.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>Regarding your question on the NSM, this is the first time there’s been an NSM addressing IUU fishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And regarding resources, we have been working closely with Congress to ensure there are adequate resources directed at addressing these key issues.&nbsp; And we’ll continue to work closely with Congress on the implementation of the memorandum.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And thank you to our speakers.&nbsp; And thank you for &#8212; you all for joining.&nbsp; Apologies, we have to cut this quick at 2:00.&nbsp; But as a reminder, the embargo now lifts.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Reach out with any other questions.</p>



<p>1:59 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  President&#160;Biden Signs National Security Memorandum to Combat Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and Associated Labor&#160;Abuses</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-national-security-memorandum-to-combat-illegal-unreported-and-unregulated-fishing-and-associated-labor-abuses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden signed a National Security Memorandum (NSM) to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing and related harmful fishing practices. &#160; IUU fishing is among the greatest threats to ocean health and is a significant cause of global overfishing, contributing to the collapse or decline of fisheries that are critical to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden signed a National Security Memorandum (NSM) to address illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing and related harmful fishing practices. &nbsp;</p>



<p>IUU fishing is among the greatest threats to ocean health and is a significant cause of global overfishing, contributing to the collapse or decline of fisheries that are critical to the economic growth, food systems, and ecosystems of numerous countries around the world.&nbsp; Distant water fishing vessels, which engage in industrial-scale fishing operations on the high seas and in waters under other states’ jurisdictions, can be significant perpetrators of IUU fishing and related harmful fishing practices.&nbsp; IUU fishing often involves forced labor, human trafficking, and other crimes and human rights abuses.&nbsp; Left unchecked, IUU fishing and associated labor abuses undermine U.S. economic competitiveness, national security, fisheries sustainability, and the livelihoods and human rights of fishers around the world and will exacerbate the environmental and socioeconomic effects of climate change.</p>



<p>The Biden Administration will address IUU fishing by increasing coordination with diverse stakeholders — public and private, foreign and domestic.&nbsp; The United States Government will use the full range of existing conservation, labor, trade, economic, diplomatic, law enforcement, and national security authorities to address these challenges, including:</p>



<ul><li>Promoting labor rights, human rights, and fundamental freedoms through worker-centered trade policies and working to ensure that supply chains are free from forced labor, including by engaging with international institutions and trade partners to address forced labor and other abusive labor practices in IUU fishing;<br></li><li>Collaborating within international organizations, including regional bodies, and partnering with stakeholders from governments, civil society, and the private sector, to increase global attention on the challenges of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and related abusive labor practices, such as the use of forced labor in seafood supply chains; and<br></li><li>Combatting abuses and strengthening incentives for ethical behavior in the global seafood industry, including by limiting the market for products derived from IUU fishing, forced labor, or other abusive labor practices.</li></ul>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is also taking the following actions to combat IUU fishing, which will be announced throughout this week’s U.N. Ocean Conference.</p>



<ul><li>The United States, the UK, and Canada will launch an <strong>IUU Fishing Action Alliance</strong> aimed at increasing ambition and momentum in the fight against IUU fishing, including <strong>a pledge to take urgent action</strong> to improve the monitoring, control, and surveillance of fisheries, increase transparency in fishing fleets and in the seafood market, and build new partnerships that will hold bad actors accountable.<br></li><li>The <strong>U.S. Interagency Working Group on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing</strong>, comprising 21 Federal agencies, will release its <em>National Five-Year Strategy for Combating Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing (2022-2026)</em> by the end of July.&nbsp; The strategy prioritizes the Working Group’s efforts to combat IUU fishing, curtail the global trade of IUU fish and fish products, and promote global maritime security, while working in partnership with other governments and authorities, the seafood industry, academia, and non-governmental stakeholders.&nbsp; The United States will engage with priority partners, including Ecuador, Panama, Senegal, Taiwan, and Vietnam.&nbsp; Information on the member agencies and activities of the Working Group can be found <a href="https://www.fisheries.noaa.gov/national/us-interagency-working-group-iuu-fishing" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">here.<br></a></li><li>NOAA will also issue a <strong>proposed rule to enhance and strengthen its ability to address IUU fishing activities and combat forced labor in the seafood supply chain</strong>. &nbsp;Specifically, the rule will enhance NOAA’s ability to implement the Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing and the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act.&nbsp; The rule proposes to broaden the scope of activities that NOAA can consider when identifying nations that engage in IUU fishing to include fishing in waters under the jurisdiction of a nation, without the permission of that nation, or in violation of its laws and regulations.&nbsp; This will ensure consistency with the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization’s <em>International Plan of Action to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported and Unregulated Fishing</em>.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>These new actions build on President Biden’s proclamation declaring June as <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-ocean-month-2022/">National Ocean Month</a> and key <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-celebrates-world-ocean-day-with-actions-to-conserve-americas-deepest-atlantic-canyon-cut-plastic-pollution-and-create-americas-first-ever-o/">announcements</a> the White House made earlier this month to conserve and restore the health and productivity of the ocean for the benefit of all Americans. &nbsp;These announcements included initiating the designation process for a new national marine sanctuary to conserve Hudson Canyon in the Atlantic Ocean, a phase out of the sale of single-use plastics in national parks and public lands, the launch of efforts to create America’s first-ever Ocean Climate Action Plan, and the launch of an initiative to center environmental justice in ocean science and technology activities and investments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The White&#160;House Announces Public Tours Will Resume A Full Operating&#160;Schedule</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/the-white-house-announces-public-tours-will-resume-a-full-operating-schedule/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56350</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will resume a full operating schedule from Tuesdays through Saturdays beginning on Tuesday, July 19, 2022. Public tours will be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Tuesdays, Wednesdays, Thursdays, Fridays, and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden-Harris Administration is pleased to announce public tours of the White House will resume a full operating schedule from Tuesdays through Saturdays beginning on Tuesday, July 19, 2022. Public tours will be available from 8:00 AM to 12:30 PM on Tuesdays, Wednesdays, Thursdays, Fridays, and Saturdays, excluding Federal holidays or unless otherwise noted. All White House tours are free of charge. The White House tour schedule is subject to change based on inclement weather or official use<br><br><strong>Public White House Tour Requests</strong></p>



<p>Public tour requests are scheduled on a first come, first served basis and must be submitted through a Member of Congress and their Congressional Tour Coordinator. Constituents may reach your Member of Congress and Congressional Tour Coordinator through the U.S. House of Representative’s Switchboard at 202-225-3121, the U.S. Senate Switchboard at 202-224-3121, or online at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.congress.gov/members">www.congress.gov/members</a>.</p>



<p>Consistent with prior practices, public White House tour requests must be submitted a minimum of 21 days in advance and no more than 90 days in advance of the requested tour date(s). Reservations cannot be accepted for tour dates outside this 21 – 90-day window.&nbsp;Congressional Tour Coordinators will be able to submit tour requests for the full operating schedule on Monday, June 27, 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The White House will continue to closely monitor the COVID-19 situation with guidance based on recommendations from the CDC, and other public health officials and medical experts, and reserves the right to adjust availability of the public tours as necessary to adhere to the latest health guidance. Within the 10 days prior to the public tour, anyone who has tested positive for COVID-19, has had any COVID-19 symptoms, or been in close contact with someone confirmed or suspected to have COVID-19, should stay home. Face masks will be available when entering the White House complex for those who choose to wear them.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Combating Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and Associated Labor&#160;Abuses</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/27/memorandum-on-combating-illegal-unreported-and-unregulated-fishing-and-associated-labor-abuses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 15:54:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Memorandum/NSM-11 MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE ATTORNEY GENERAL &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF COMMERCE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF LABOR &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE UNITED STATES TRADE REPRESENTATIVE &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE REPRESENTATIVE OF THE UNITED STATES &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Memorandum/NSM-11</p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF THE TREASURY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE ATTORNEY GENERAL</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF COMMERCE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF LABOR</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE UNITED STATES TRADE REPRESENTATIVE</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE REPRESENTATIVE OF THE UNITED STATES</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; OF AMERICA TO THE UNITED NATIONS</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE DIRECTOR OF THE OFFICE OF SCIENCE AND</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; TECHNOLOGY POLICY</p>



<p>THE ADMINISTRATOR OF THE UNITED STATES AGENCY</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; FOR INTERNATIONAL DEVELOPMENT</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Combating Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fishing and Associated Labor Abuses</p>



<p>Illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing and related harmful fishing practices are among the greatest threats to ocean health and are significant causes of global overfishing, contributing to the collapse or decline of fisheries that are critical to the economic growth, food systems, and ecosystems of numerous countries around the world.&nbsp; Distant water fishing vessels, which engage in industrial-scale fishing operations on the high seas and in waters under other states&#8217; jurisdictions, can be significant perpetrators of IUU fishing and related harmful fishing practices.&nbsp; IUU fishing often involves forced labor, a form of human trafficking, and other crimes and human rights abuses.&nbsp; Left unchecked, IUU fishing and associated labor abuses undermine U.S.&nbsp;economic competitiveness, national security, fishery sustainability, and the livelihoods and human rights of fishers around the world and will exacerbate the environmental and socioeconomic effects of climate change.</p>



<p>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to address the problem of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and associated labor abuses, including the use of forced labor in the seafood supply chain.&nbsp; I hereby direct executive departments and agencies (agencies) to work toward ending forced labor and other crimes or abuses in IUU fishing; promote sustainable use of the oceans in partnership with other nations and the private sector; and advance foreign and trade policies that benefit U.S. seafood workers.&nbsp; No nation, government entity, or non-governmental organization can address IUU fishing and associated labor abuses single-handedly.&nbsp; I therefore direct agencies to increase coordination among themselves and with diverse stakeholders &#8212; public and private, foreign and domestic &#8212; to address these challenges comprehensively.&nbsp; With this memorandum, I direct agencies to use the full range of existing conservation, labor, trade, economic, diplomatic, law enforcement, and national security authorities to address these challenges.&nbsp; Where applicable, activities will be carried out through or in coordination with the Interagency Working Group on IUU Fishing established pursuant to section 3551 of the Maritime Security and Fisheries Enforcement (SAFE) Act (16 U.S.C. 8031), the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force established pursuant to section 741 of the United&nbsp;States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act (19 U.S.C. 4681), and as appropriate the President&#8217;s Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons established pursuant to section 105 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (22 U.S.C. 7103).</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Forced Labor in the Fishing Industry.&nbsp; The United&nbsp;States is committed to promoting labor rights and human rights and fundamental freedoms through worker-centered trade policies, and to working to eliminate abusive labor practices, in particular forced labor, in supply chains.&nbsp; Agencies shall enhance interagency coordination and the use of existing tools and authorities to address the challenge of forced labor in the seafood supply chain.</p>



<p>(a)  The United States Trade Representative (USTR), in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), and other relevant agencies, shall:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; continue to engage in the World Trade Organization negotiations on fisheries subsidies to seek additional disciplines prohibiting fisheries subsidies that contribute to overcapacity and overfishing, and to seek additional transparency with respect to IUU fishing and the use of forced labor on fishing vessels;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;engage, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, with trade partners, including free trade agreement partners and preference program beneficiaries, to address forced labor and other abusive labor practices in fishing; and</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; seek to collaborate with Mexico and Canada under the United&nbsp;States-Mexico-Canada Agreement to prohibit the importation of goods, including seafood, produced in whole or in part by forced labor.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;The Secretary of State, the Secretary of Labor, the USTR, and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), in coordination with the Administrator of NOAA and other relevant agencies, shall continue to highlight links between IUU fishing and forced labor and other abusive labor practices, with a focus on distant water fishing and vessels using flags of convenience to continue unsustainable fishing practices.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall adjust the mix of United States Government messaging and promotion of non-governmental voices to achieve the greatest effect and shall develop themes and narratives that resonate with target audiences including foreign governments, the private sector, and global and U.S. consumers.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Secretary of Homeland Security, through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and in coordination with the Administrator of NOAA, shall:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;investigate fishing vessels and operators suspected to be harvesting seafood with forced labor and issue withhold release orders, as appropriate;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;at the discretion of relevant CBP officials, share evidence with allies and partners to encourage parallel customs enforcement actions, as appropriate;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; investigate prospective civil penalty cases against importers connected to previously issued fishing vessel withhold release orders, as appropriate;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;in coordination with other relevant agencies, use the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force to monitor United&nbsp;States enforcement of the prohibition under section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1307) to prevent the importation of seafood harvested with forced labor into the United&nbsp;States; and</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;use Maritime Operational Threat Response processes to facilitate interagency notifications, responses, and legal enforcement actions for IUU fishing offenses, including taking appropriate action when forced labor is identified.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and the Treasury shall, as appropriate, consider whether their respective sanctions and visa restriction authorities may be used to address IUU fishing and associated labor abuses.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall consider, as appropriate, whether to share evidentiary packages with allies and partners to facilitate parallel sanctions or visa restriction actions.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; The Secretary of Labor, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID, shall engage financial institutions, business organizations, labor stakeholders, and seafood importers on forced labor in seafood supply chains, including by promoting supply chain transparency and responsible business practices.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall promote dissemination of information on the harms of IUU fishing and associated labor abuses in order to encourage greater corporate and consumer demand for due diligence, mechanisms to certify that seafood supply chains are free of forced labor, and the halting of financial transactions involving forced labor.&nbsp; These heads of agencies are encouraged to apply lessons learned from United States Government policies addressing the use of forced labor in the cotton sector and in other relevant sectors. &nbsp;The Administrator of USAID shall work to build regional networks between civil society organizations, trade unions, migrant worker networks, and recruitment agencies to address exploitation in the seafood industry. &nbsp;These networks should incorporate worker voices, including survivors of forced labor, to counter labor abuses and provide legal aid to migrant workers in the fishing industry.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>(f)&nbsp; The Secretary of Labor shall use labor and development programs to provide training and technical support to national security-focused agencies, including the Department of Defense and the United States Coast Guard, and foreign partners on combating forced labor and other abusive labor practices on fishing vessels.</p>



<p>(g)&nbsp; The Secretary of Labor shall continue to raise public awareness about labor practices in the seafood industry, including by continuing to maintain its list of goods it has reason to believe are produced by forced labor or child labor in violation of international standards.</p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; Multilateral and Regional Solutions That Support Sustainable Fishing.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to revitalize U.S. leadership in multilateral institutions, including regional bodies.&nbsp; I therefore direct agencies to collaborate with these organizations to increase global attention to the challenges of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and related abusive labor practices, such as the use of forced labor in seafood supply chains.&nbsp; My Administration will harness our international partners&#8217; energy and innovative capacity to design and implement solutions.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Labor, the USTR, and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall promote decent work, counter forced labor, and take other actions to address IUU fishing and related harmful fishing practices at the Food and Agriculture Organization (FAO) of the United Nations (UN), the International Labor Organization (ILO), and the International Maritime Organization (IMO).&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall work with the FAO to draft guidelines on social responsibility in fisheries and value chains and shall support ILO research on forced labor in fishing.</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretaries of State and the Treasury shall consider whether to seek funding from the Congress and donors for multi-donor trust funds or regional programs at multilateral development banks to combat IUU fishing.</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of State, the Attorney General, and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall, as appropriate, elevate the issue of IUU fishing at the UN Food Systems Summit.</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; The Attorney General and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall support the International Criminal Police Organization to combat conservation crimes, including those related to IUU fishing, and build capacity for fisheries managers and investigators.</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretaries of State and Labor, the USTR, and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall explore concrete efforts to collaborate with G7 members on addressing forced labor in fishing. &nbsp;The Secretary of State, the Administrator of NOAA, and other relevant agencies shall use the G7&#8217;s focus on addressing unsustainable fishing practices as outlined in the 2030 Nature Compact to increase attention to and pursue efforts to counter harmful fishing practices.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Administrator of NOAA, in coordination with the Secretaries of State and Labor, the Secretary of Homeland Security through the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard, and the USTR, shall engage with regional fisheries management organizations to encourage adoption of measures that identify and counter IUU fishing, including high seas boarding inspection schemes. &nbsp;Additionally, these heads of agencies shall collaborate on regional initiatives to address forced labor and other harmful practices in the seafood industry, which will include:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Administrator of NOAA and other relevant agencies shall promote transatlantic cooperation to counter the use of forced labor in seafood supply chains, including through the United States-European Union (EU) High-Level Dialogue on Fisheries.</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Defense shall collaborate with counterparts in the Quad (which is composed of Australia, India, Japan, and the United States) to design and facilitate the implementation of a multilateral initiative, the Indo-Pacific Partnership for Maritime Domain Awareness, to strengthen maritime domain awareness and maritime security in South Asia, Southeast Asia, and the Pacific Islands using advanced commercial satellite data.&nbsp; The Administrators of NOAA and USAID, the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard, and the Intelligence Community shall support this endeavor as appropriate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp;&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Labor and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall collaborate with the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) to encourage the design of technical assistance programming to address forced labor in fishing, linking these efforts to the US-ASEAN Plan of Action.</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretary of State and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall collaborate with Pacific Island nations, including through the Pacific Islands Forum, to counter IUU fishing and related human trafficking, including forced labor.</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretaries of State and Labor and the Administrator of NOAA shall explore opportunities for cooperation in the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) to begin discussions on forced labor and other abusive practices in fishing, linking these efforts to the APEC Roadmap on Combatting IUU Fishing.</p>



<p>(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretary of State, in collaboration with the Administrators of NOAA and USAID, shall elevate the issue of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and related harmful fishing practices, at any future Our Ocean Conferences and in meetings and working groups of the Organization of American States, APEC, the African Union, relevant African sub-regional bodies, and the Pacific Alliance.</p>



<p>(vii) &nbsp;&nbsp;The Administrator of USAID shall work to initiate partnerships with and support multilateral institutions such as the Southeast Asian Fisheries Development Center and the Coral Triangle Initiative to counter IUU fishing.</p>



<p>(viii)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Defense, in collaboration with the Administrator of NOAA, shall explore opportunities for cooperation between Atlantic Basin African maritime forces and the United States Africa Command to improve West African capacity to detect and counter IUU fishing.</p>



<p>(ix)    The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in collaboration with the Secretaries of State and Commerce and the Administrator of NOAA, shall continue to pursue opportunities through the High Level Panel for a Sustainable Ocean Economy (Ocean Panel) to promote international collaboration to counter IUU fishing and integrate best practices into the National Sustainable Ocean Plans of each Ocean Panel country.</p>



<p>Sec. 4.&nbsp; Partner Engagement, Capacity, and Resilience.&nbsp; The United States benefits from an unparalleled ability to shape global discourse and convene stakeholders from government, civil society, and the private sector.&nbsp; The United States&#8217; track record of conserving fisheries and combating forced labor enables it to lead by the power of example.&nbsp; The United States&#8217; robust network of alliances and partnerships and its broad array of conservation, law enforcement, trade, economic, diplomatic, labor, and other authorities and programs can be used to generate innovative, cross-cutting, and powerful solutions.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to harness these advantages to address the challenge of IUU fishing, including by distant water fishing vessels, and related harmful fishing practices, such as forced labor in the seafood supply chain.</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; The United States has a strong track record of making environmental data, such as data produced by the U.S. Global Change Research Program and its participating agencies, freely available to partners and the general public. &nbsp;The Office of Science and Technology Policy shall support the interagency policy committee process in assessing the best-available evidence concerning fisheries-environment interactions. &nbsp;This may include, for example, identifying regions more likely to be at risk of harmful and unsustainable fishing practices due to climate change and its resulting threats to food security.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Defense and the Administrator of USAID shall work with partners to use all available tools to increase maritime domain awareness to combat IUU fishing, including increasing the use of vessel tracking systems, aerial surveillance, and radio frequency data, as well as utilizing emerging technologies such as advances in machine learning paired with synthetic aperture radar, as appropriate. &nbsp;The Administrator of USAID shall also continue to promote the use of communication technology to improve connectivity and safety for commercial fishing vessels and support ethical and sustainable fishing practices.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Administrator of USAID, in coordination with the Secretaries of State, Commerce, and Labor; the USTR; the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard; and the Administrator of NOAA, shall strengthen alliances with non-governmental organizations, think tanks, organized labor, academia, industry associations, and the business community to highlight and address IUU fishing and associated labor abuses, including forced labor, in the seafood sector, and to develop best practices for combating these abuses, promoting sustainable fisheries, rebuilding fish stocks, and empowering fisheries workers.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall engage with fishers, fish processing workers, port workers, and relevant trade unions to seek input on the real-world impacts of IUU fishing and abusive labor practices.&nbsp; The Administrator of USAID and other relevant agencies shall use development and technical assistance programs, as appropriate, to address corruption in governance systems; support judicial reform and public financial management; and build journalist, trade union, and civil society capacity to raise awareness of IUU fishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretaries of the Treasury, Defense, and Homeland Security; the USTR; the Administrators of NOAA and USAID; the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard; the United States Mission to the European Union; and other heads of departments and agencies as appropriate, shall cooperate with the EU, Japan, other G7 members, and other partner countries, together or individually, to work to counter harmful fishing practices in West Africa, Latin America and the Caribbean, and the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; These heads of departments and agencies shall:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;identify and, as appropriate, seek resources for technical skills training in littoral Africa, including ship inspections, ship maintenance, and oversight of maritime governance programs;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;develop information-sharing networks and arrangements with partner countries to inform a maritime common operating picture to improve regional maritime domain awareness and combat IUU fishing in the South Atlantic, Oceania, Indo-Pacific, Eastern Pacific, and West Africa;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; leverage opportunities to include IUU fishing provisions within existing and new bilateral maritime law enforcement agreements with partner nations, including in Latin America and the Caribbean and Africa; and</p>



<p>(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;use all available intelligence capabilities to identify and enable, as appropriate, interdiction of vessels conducting or engaged in IUU fishing, particularly those that are operating within the exclusive economic zones of nations with which the United States has bilateral maritime law enforcement agreements.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; The Administrator of NOAA, in collaboration with the Secretary of State and the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard, shall encourage adoption of the Agreement on Port State Measures to Prevent, Deter, and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing and shall provide assistance, as appropriate, for its implementation, including training and capacity building, as directed by the Maritime SAFE Act.&nbsp; The Administrator of USAID shall strategically support interagency partners to strengthen Port State Measures programs in individual states.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (f)&nbsp; The Administrator of NOAA shall seek resources, as appropriate, to deploy fisheries enforcement representatives to posts to support regional efforts to counter IUU fishing and to build capacity for monitoring, control, and surveillance to combat IUU fishing and related harmful fishing practices, such as forced labor. &nbsp;</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;The Administrator of NOAA, in collaboration with the Secretary of State and the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard, shall work to improve maritime law enforcement coordination in partner countries to address IUU fishing, related abusive labor practices, and trade of protected marine species.</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; The Secretary of Defense shall use, as appropriate, Maritime Security Initiatives to enhance maritime detection capabilities of eligible countries within their exclusive economic zones, increase maritime domain awareness in the Indo-Pacific and Africa, and develop a common operating picture for regional information sharing.</p>



<p>(g)&nbsp; The Secretary of State and the Administrators of NOAA and USAID shall endeavor to assist developing countries with the establishment and enforcement of marine protected areas to promote the conservation of fish species and sustainable coastal management.</p>



<p>(h)&nbsp; The Secretary of State, the Administrators of NOAA and USAID, and other relevant agencies shall engage with partners to promote legally caught fish and seafood supply chains that are free of forced labor as the preferred option and to highlight its benefits.<strong></strong></p>



<p>Sec. 5.&nbsp; Import Markets. &nbsp;The United States is the world&#8217;s single largest country market for seafood; more than 85 percent of the seafood Americans consume is imported.&nbsp; The United&nbsp;States has taken steps to limit the market for products derived from IUU fishing and forced labor, but additional action is required.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to combat abuses and to strengthen incentives for ethical behavior in the global seafood industry, including by limiting the market for products derived from IUU fishing, forced labor, or other abusive labor practices.&nbsp; Agencies should seek opportunities to leverage the United States&#8217; large seafood import market to advance these objectives and unify public messaging that condemns IUU fishing.&nbsp; Wherever possible, agencies should seek opportunities to coordinate international messaging that condemns IUU fishing with like-minded partners.&nbsp; The United States, the EU, and Japan together account for approximately 55 percent of the global seafood market, providing an opportunity to work with democratic market economies to develop more powerful signals to the global seafood market.</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; By the end of 2022, the Administrator of NOAA shall initiate a rulemaking to expand the Seafood Import Monitoring Program (SIMP) to include additional species and species groups, as appropriate. &nbsp;NOAA shall continue to seek resources and technological tools to improve the effectiveness of SIMP and other efforts to address IUU fishing. &nbsp;NOAA shall pursue its ongoing efforts to conduct risk-based assessments of SIMP species and species groups and continuously expand coverage of the program, as appropriate, to meet the objectives of combating IUU fishing and seafood fraud most effectively.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Administrator of NOAA, the Commissioner of CBP, and other relevant agencies shall work to leverage existing and emerging technologies to detect IUU fishing and prevent or deter illegal seafood imports from entering U.S. markets.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Labor, the USTR, the Administrator of NOAA, the Commissioner of CBP, and other relevant agencies shall explore opportunities to use existing trade tools and authorities to counter forced labor in the seafood supply chain and IUU fishing generally, such as through the use, as appropriate, of countervailing duties, actions pursuant to section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2411), import declarations, certification under the Pelly Amendment to the Fishermen&#8217;s Protective Act of 1967 (22 U.S.C. 1978), and due diligence requirements.&nbsp; These heads of agencies shall work to develop new tools and authorities to address gaps and shall work with partners to take parallel actions.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; The Secretaries of State and Labor and the Administrator of NOAA shall work to build on existing dialogues and cooperation mechanisms with allies, partners, and international organizations to develop joint or complementary approaches to addressing forced labor in the global seafood industry.</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; The Administrator of USAID shall convene leaders from industry, civil society, and government to develop recommendations for improving information flows that create meaningful deterrence, accountability, and remedies for illegality in labor and harvesting practices in wild fisheries.</p>



<p>Sec. 6. &nbsp;General Provisions. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Extending and Expanding Eligibility for Deferred Enforced Departure for&#160;Liberians</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/27/memorandum-on-extending-and-expanding-eligibility-for-deferred-enforced-departure-for-liberians/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 15:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE&#160;&#160; THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY SUBJECT:&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Extending and Expanding Eligibility for Deferred Enforced Departure for Liberians Since 1991, the United States has provided safe haven for Liberians who were forced to flee their country as a result of armed conflict and widespread civil strife, in part through the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Extending and Expanding Eligibility for Deferred Enforced Departure for Liberians</p>



<p>Since 1991, the United States has provided safe haven for Liberians who were forced to flee their country as a result of armed conflict and widespread civil strife, in part through the grant of Temporary Protected Status (TPS).&nbsp; The armed conflict ended in 2003, and TPS for affected Liberian nationals ended effective October 1, 2007.&nbsp; President Bush then deferred the enforced departure of those Liberians originally granted TPS.&nbsp; President Obama, in successive memoranda, extended that grant of Deferred Enforced Departure (DED) to March 31, 2018.&nbsp; President&nbsp;Trump then determined that conditions in Liberia did not warrant a further extension of DED, but that the foreign policy interests of the United States warranted an orderly transition period for Liberian DED beneficiaries.&nbsp; President&nbsp;Trump later extended that DED transition period through March 30, 2020.</p>



<p>In December 2019, the Congress enacted the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (Public Law 116-92) (NDAA), which included, as section 7611, the Liberian Refugee Immigration Fairness (LRIF) provision.&nbsp; The LRIF provision, with limited exceptions, makes Liberians who have been continuously present in the United States since November 20, 2014, as well as their spouses and children, eligible for adjustment of status to that of lawful permanent resident (LPR).&nbsp; The NDAA gave eligible Liberian nationals until December 20, 2020, to apply for this adjustment of status.&nbsp; After the enactment of the LRIF provision, President Trump further extended the DED transition period through January 10, 2021, to ensure that DED beneficiaries would continue to be eligible for employment authorization during the LRIF application period.</p>



<p><a>The LRIF application process was new and complex, resulting in some procedural and administrative challenges.&nbsp; </a>Recognizing these difficulties, the Congress enacted a 1-year extension to the application period in section 901 of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (Public Law 116-260).&nbsp; That legislation, however, did not provide for continued employment authorization past January 10, 2021.&nbsp; Through my memorandum of January 20, 2021 (Reinstating Deferred Enforced Departure for Liberians), DED was subsequently reinstated through June 30, 2022, in order to permit employment authorization for eligible Liberians while they made their applications for adjustment of status under the LRIF provision.</p>



<p>There are compelling foreign policy reasons to extend DED for an additional period for those Liberians presently residing in the United States who were under a grant of DED until June 30, 2022, as well as to defer enforced departure for Liberians who have been continuously present in the United States since May 20, 2017.&nbsp; In addition to updating the continuous presence requirement, I have also determined that it is appropriate to include qualifying Liberians whose LRIF applications have been denied for reasons other than ineligibility under sections&nbsp;7611(b)(1)(C) and (b)(3) of the NDAA in this DED designation.&nbsp; In particular, this includes providing protection from removal to those who arrived in the United States during a time when conditions prevented them from returning safely, including through May 20, 2017, and have since established family and community ties in the United States. &nbsp;Providing protection from removal and work authorization to these Liberians, for whom we have long authorized TPS or DED in the United States, including while they complete the LRIF status-adjustment process, honors the historic close relationship between the United States and Liberia and is in the foreign policy interests of the United States.</p>



<p>Pursuant to my constitutional authority to conduct the foreign relations of the United States, I have determined that it is in the foreign policy interests of the United States to defer through June 30, 2024, the removal of any Liberian national, or person without nationality who last habitually resided in Liberia, who is present in the United States and who was under a grant of DED as of June 30, 2022, as well as any Liberian national, or person without nationality who last habitually resided in Liberia, who has been continuously physically present in the United States since May 20, 2017.&nbsp; I have also determined that any Liberian national, or person without nationality who last habitually resided in Liberia, who was under a grant of DED as of June 30, 2022, or who has been continuously physically present in the United States since May 20, 2017, should have continued employment authorization through June 30, 2024.</p>



<p>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall promptly direct the appropriate officials to make provision, by means of a notice published in the <em>Federal Register</em>, for immediate allowance of employment authorization for those Liberians who held appropriate DED-related employment authorization documents as of June 30, 2022, or those Liberian nationals who have been continuously present in the United States since May 20, 2017.&nbsp; The Secretary of Homeland Security shall also provide for the prompt issuance of new or replacement employment authorization documents in appropriate cases.</p>



<p>This grant of DED and continued employment authorization shall apply to any Liberian DED beneficiary as of June 30, 2022, or any Liberian national who has been continuously present in the United States since May 20, 2017, but shall not apply to such persons in the following categories:</p>



<p>(1)&nbsp; individuals who would be ineligible for TPS for the reasons provided in section 244(c)(2)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, 8 U.S.C. 1254a(c)(2)(B);</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp; individuals who sought or seek LPR status under the LRIF provision but whose applications have been or are denied by the Secretary of Homeland Security due to ineligibility for the LRIF provision under sections&nbsp;7611(b)(1)(C) and (b)(3) of the NDAA;</p>



<p>(3)&nbsp; individuals whose removal the Secretary of Homeland Security determines is in the interest of the United&nbsp;States, subject to the LRIF provision;</p>



<p>(4)&nbsp; individuals whose presence or activities in the United&nbsp;States the Secretary of State has reasonable grounds to believe would have potentially serious adverse foreign policy consequences for the United States;</p>



<p>(5)&nbsp; individuals who have voluntarily returned to Liberia or their country of last habitual residence outside the United&nbsp;States for an aggregate period of 180 days or more, as specified in subsection (c)(2) of the LRIF provision; or</p>



<p>(6)&nbsp; individuals who are subject to extradition.</p>



<p>Accordingly, I hereby direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to take the necessary steps to implement for eligible Liberians:</p>



<p>(1)&nbsp; a deferral of enforced departure from the United&nbsp;States through June 30, 2024, effective immediately;&nbsp;and</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp; authorization for employment valid through June 30, 2024.</p>



<p>The Secretary of Homeland Security is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Amends New Mexico Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/27/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-amends-new-mexico-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 15:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the State of New Mexico by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for debris removal and emergency protective measures undertaken in the State of New Mexico as a result of wildfires and straight-line winds beginning on April 5, 2022, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the State of New Mexico by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for debris removal and emergency protective measures undertaken in the State of New Mexico as a result of wildfires and straight-line winds beginning on April 5, 2022, and continuing.</p>



<p>Under the President&#8217;s order today, the Federal share for debris removal and emergency protective measures, including direct Federal assistance has been increased to 100 percent of the total eligible costs for a 90-day period from the date of declaration.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proclamation on Increasing Duties on Certain Articles from the Russian&#160;Federation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/27/proclamation-on-increasing-duties-on-certain-articles-from-the-russian-federation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 15:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56353</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1.&#160; On April 8, 2022, I signed the Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act (19 U.S.C. 2434 note) (Suspending NTR Act).&#160; Section 3(a) of the Suspending NTR Act suspended nondiscriminatory tariff treatment for products of the Russian Federation and of the Republic of Belarus, and imposed the rates of duty set forth&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1.&nbsp; On April 8, 2022, I signed the Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act (19 U.S.C. 2434 note) (Suspending NTR Act).&nbsp; Section 3(a) of the Suspending NTR Act suspended nondiscriminatory tariff treatment for products of the Russian Federation and of the Republic of Belarus, and imposed the rates of duty set forth in column 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTSUS) on all products of the Russian Federation and of the Republic of Belarus, effective as of April 9, 2022. &nbsp;Section 3(b)(1) of the Suspending NTR Act provides that the President may proclaim increases in the column 2 rates of duty applicable to products of the Russian Federation and of the Republic of Belarus.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2.&nbsp; On April 8, 2022, I signed the Ending Importation of Russian Oil Act (22 U.S.C. 8923 note).&nbsp; Section 2 of the Ending Importation of Russian Oil Act prohibits imports of all products of the Russian Federation classified under chapter 27 of the HTSUS, in a manner consistent with any implementation actions issued under Executive Order 14066 of March 8, 2022.</p>



<p>3.&nbsp; In Executive Order 14066 of March 8, 2022, I prohibited, inter alia, importation into the United States of the following products of Russian Federation origin: &nbsp;crude oil; petroleum; petroleum fuels, oils, and products of their distillation; liquefied natural gas; coal; and coal products.</p>



<p>4.&nbsp; In Executive Order 14068 of March 11, 2022, I prohibited, inter alia, the importation into the United States of the following products of Russian Federation origin: &nbsp;fish, seafood, and preparations thereof; alcoholic beverages; and non-industrial diamonds.</p>



<p>5.&nbsp; In accordance with section 3(b)(1) of the Suspending NTR Act, I have determined that increasing the column 2 rates of duty to 35 percent ad valorem on certain other products of the Russian Federation, the importation of which has not already been prohibited, is warranted and consistent with the foreign policy interests of the United States. &nbsp;These products are listed in Annex A to this proclamation.&nbsp; The United States will monitor the implementation of the increased duties, and I may revisit this determination, as appropriate.</p>



<p>6.&nbsp; Section 604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (19&nbsp;U.S.C. 2483), authorizes the President to embody in the HTSUS the substance of statutes affecting import treatment, and actions thereunder, including the removal, modification, continuance, or imposition of any rate of duty or other import restriction.</p>



<p>Now, Therefore, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United&nbsp;States of America, by the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;3 of the Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act; section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code; and section&nbsp;604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended, do hereby proclaim as follows:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (1)&nbsp; To increase the column 2 rates of duty on imports of certain articles of the Russian Federation as set forth in paragraph 5 of this proclamation, HTSUS heading 9903.90.08 and new U.S. Note 30 to subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS are provided for in Annex A to this proclamation. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp; The modifications to the HTSUS made by clause 1 of this proclamation shall be effective with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on the day that is 30 days after the date of this proclamation and shall continue in effect, unless such actions are expressly reduced, modified, or terminated.</p>



<p>(3)&nbsp; General Note 3(b) to the HTSUS is amended to add the Republic of Belarus and the Russian Federation to the list of countries subject to column 2 duties.&nbsp; This amendment is provided in Annex B to this proclamation.</p>



<p>(4)&nbsp; Any provision of previous proclamations and Executive&nbsp;Orders that is inconsistent with the actions taken in&nbsp;this proclamation is superseded to the extent of such inconsistency.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-seventh day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
