<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 21:47:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the United Efforts of the Free World to Support the People of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/26/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-united-efforts-of-the-free-world-to-support-the-people-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 21:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Royal Castle in WarsawWarsaw, Poland 6:16 P.M. CET THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; Please, if you have a seat, be seated.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; If you don’t, come up on stage. Thank you very much.&#160; It’s a great honor to be here.&#160; Mr. President, they tell me you’re over there somewhere.&#160; There you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The Royal Castle in Warsaw<br>Warsaw, Poland</p>



<p>6:16 P.M. CET<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Please, if you have a seat, be seated.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; If you don’t, come up on stage.<br><br>Thank you very much.&nbsp; It’s a great honor to be here.&nbsp; Mr. President, they tell me you’re over there somewhere.&nbsp; There you are.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp;<br><br>“Be not afraid.”&nbsp; They were the first words at the first public address of the first Polish Pope after his election on October of 1978.&nbsp; They were words that would come to define Pope John Paul II.&nbsp; Words that would change the world.<br><br>John Paul brought the message here to Warsaw in his first trip back home as Pope in June of 1979.&nbsp; It was a message about the power &#8212; the power of faith, the power of resilience, and the power of the people.&nbsp;<br><br>In the face of a cruel and brutal system of government, it was a message that helped end the Soviet repression in the Central land and Eastern Europe 30 years ago.&nbsp; It was a message that will overcome the cruelty and brutality of this unjust war.&nbsp;<br><br>When Pope John Paul brought that message in 1979, the Soviet Union ruled with an iron fist behind an Iron Curtain.<br><br>Then a year later, the Solidarity movement took hold in Poland.&nbsp; And while I know he couldn’t be here tonight, we’re all grateful in America and around the world for Lech Wałęsa.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>It reminds me of that phrase of philosopher Kierkegaard: “[F]aith sees best in the dark.”&nbsp; And there were dark moments.<br><br>Ten years later, the Soviet Union collapsed, and Poland and Central and Eastern Europe would soon be free.&nbsp; Nothing about that battle for freedom was simple or easy.&nbsp; It was a long, painful slog fought over not days and months, but years and decades.<br><br>But we emerged anew in the great battle for freedom: a battle between democracy and autocracy, between liberty and repression, between a rules-based order and one governed by brute force.<br><br>In this battle, we need to be clear-eyed.&nbsp; This battle will not be won in days or months either.&nbsp; We need to steel ourselves for the long fight ahead.<br><br>Mr. President, Mr. Prime Minister, Mr. Mayor, members of the Parliament, distinguished guests, and the people of Poland, and I suspect some people of Ukraine that are here: We’re &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we are gathered here at the Royal Castle in this city that holds a sacred place in the history of not only of Europe, but humankind’s unending search for freedom.<br><br>For generations, Warsaw has stood where liberty has been challenged and liberty has prevailed.<br><br>In fact, it was here in Warsaw when a young refugee, who fled her home country from Czechoslovakia was under&nbsp;Soviet domination, came back to speak and stand in solidarity with dissidents.<br><br>Her name was Madeleine Korbel Albright.&nbsp; She became &#8212; (applause) &#8212; one of the most ardent supporters of democracy in the world.&nbsp; She was a friend with whom I served.&nbsp; America’s first woman Secretary of State.&nbsp; She passed away three days ago.<br><br>She fought her whole life for essential democratic principles.&nbsp; And now, in the perennial struggle for democracy and freedom, Ukraine and its people are on the frontlines fighting to save their nation.<br><br>And their brave resistance is part of a larger fight for an essential democratic principles that unite all free people: the rule of law; free and fair elections; the freedom to speak, to write, and to assemble; the freedom to worship as one chooses; freedom of the press.<br><br>These principles are essential in a free society.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But they have always &#8212; they have always been under siege.&nbsp; They’ve always been embattled.&nbsp; Every generation has had to defeat democracy’s mortal foes.&nbsp; That’s the way of the world &#8212; for the world is imperfect, as we know.&nbsp; Where the appetites and ambitions of a few forever seek to dominate the lives and liberties of many.<br><br>My message to the people of Ukraine is the message I delivered today to Ukraine’s Foreign Minister and Defense Minister, who I believe are here tonight: We stand with you.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Today’s fighting in Kyiv and Mariupol and Kharkiv are the latest battle in a long struggle: Hungary, 1956; Poland, 1956 then again 1981; Czechoslovakia, 1968.&nbsp;<br><br>Soviet tanks crushed democratic uprisings, but the resistance continued until finally, in 1989, the Berlin Wall and all of the walls of Soviet domination &#8212; they fell.&nbsp; They fell.&nbsp; And the people prevailed.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>But the battle for democracy could not conclude and did not conclude with the end of the Cold War.<br><br>Over the last 30 years, the forces of autocracy have revived all across the globe.&nbsp; Its hallmarks are familiar ones: contempt for the rule of law, contempt for democratic freedom, contempt for the truth itself.<br><br>Today, Russia has strangled democracy &#8212; has sought to do so elsewhere, not only in its homeland.&nbsp; Under false claims of ethnic solidarity, it has&nbsp;<s>invalidated</s>&nbsp;[invaded] neighboring nations.<br><br>Putin has the gall to say he’s “de-Nazifying” Ukraine.&nbsp; It’s a lie.&nbsp; It’s just cynical.&nbsp; He knows that.&nbsp; And it’s also obscene.<br><br>President Zelenskyy was democratically elected.&nbsp; He’s Jewish.&nbsp; His father’s family was wiped out in the Nazi Holocaust.&nbsp; And Putin has the audacity, like all autocrats before him, to believe that might will make right.<br><br>In my own country, a former president named Abraham Lincoln voiced the opposing spirit to save our Union in the midst of a civil war.&nbsp; He said, “Let us have faith that right makes might.”&nbsp; “Right makes might.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Today, let us now have that faith again.&nbsp; Let us resolve to put the strength of democracies into action to thwart the denigns [sic] of our &#8212; the designs of autocracy.&nbsp; Let us remember that the test of this moment is the test of all time.<br><br>The Kremlin wants to portray NATO enlargement as an imperial project aimed at destabilizing Russia.&nbsp; Nothing is further from the truth.&nbsp; NATO is a defensive alliance.&nbsp;&nbsp;It has never sought the demise of Russia.<br><br>In the lead-up to the current crisis, the United States and NATO worked for months to engage Russia to avert a war.&nbsp; I met with him in person and talked to him many times on the phone.&nbsp;<br><br>Time and again, we offered real diplomacy and concrete proposals to strengthen European security, enhance transparency, and build confidence on all sides.<br><br>But Putin and Russia met each of the proposals with disinterest in any negotiation, with lies and ultimatums.&nbsp; Russia was bent on violence from the start.<br><br>I know not all of you believed me and us when we kept saying, “They are going to cross the border.&nbsp; They are going to attack.”&nbsp;<br><br>Repeatedly, he asserted, “We have no interest in war.”&nbsp; Guaranteed he would not move.&nbsp;<br><br>Repeatedly saying he would not invade Ukraine.<br><br>Repeatedly saying Russian troops along the border were there for “training” &#8212; all 180,000 of them.&nbsp;<br><br>There is simply no justification or provocation for Russia’s choice of war.&nbsp; It’s an example of one of the oldest of human impulses: using brute force and disinformation to satisfy a craving for absolute power and control.<br><br>It’s nothing less than a direct challenge to the rule-based international order established since the end of World War Two.<br><br>And it threatens to return to decades of war that ravaged Europe before the international rule-based order was put in place.&nbsp; We cannot go back to that.&nbsp; We cannot.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The gravity of the threat is why the response of the West has been so swift and so powerful and so unified, unprecedented, and overwhelming.<br><br>Swift and punishing costs are the only things that are going to get Russia to change its course.&nbsp;<br><br>Within days of its invasion, the West had moved jointly with sanctions to damage Russia’s economy.<br><br>Russia’s Central Bank is now blocked from the global financial systems, denying Kremlin’s access to the war fund it stashed around the globe.<br><br>We’ve aimed at the heart of Russia’s economy by stopping the imports of Russian energy to the United States.<br><br>To date, the United States has sanctioned 140 Russian oligarchs and their family members, seizing their ill-begotten gains: their yachts, their luxury apartments, their mansions.<br><br>We’ve sanctioned more than 400 Russian government officials, including key architects of this war.<br><br>These officials and oligarchs have reaped enormous benefit from the corruption connected to the Kremlin, and now they have to share in the pain.&nbsp;<br><br>The private sector is acting as well.&nbsp; Over 400 private multinational companies have pulled out of doing business in Russia &#8212; left Russia completely &#8212; from oil companies to McDonald’s.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As a result of these unprecedented sanctions, the ruble almost is immediately reduced to rubble.&nbsp; The Russian economy &#8212; (applause) &#8212; that’s true, by the way.&nbsp; It takes about 200 rubles to equal one dollar.&nbsp;<br><br>The economy is on track to be cut in half in the coming years.&nbsp; It was ranked &#8212; Russia’s economy was ranked the 11th biggest economy in the world before this evasion [sic] &#8212; invasion.&nbsp; It will soon not even rank among the top 20 in the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Taken together, these economic sanctions are a new kind of economic statecraft with the power to inflict damage that rivals military might.<br><br>These international sanctions are sapping Russian strength, its ability to replenish its military, and its ability &#8212; its ability to project power.&nbsp;&nbsp;And it is Putin &#8212; it is Vladimir Putin who is to blame, period.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, alongside these economic sanctions, the Western world has come together to provide for the people of Ukraine with incredible levels of military, economic, and humanitarian assistance.<br><br>In the years before the invasion, we, America, had sent over $650 million, before they crossed the border, in weapons to Ukraine, including anti-air and anti-armor equipment.<br><br>Since the invasion, America has committed another $1.35 billion in weapons and ammunition.<br><br>And thanks to the courage and bravery of the Ukrainian people &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the equipment we&#8217;ve sent and our colleagues have sent have been used to devastating effect to defend Ukrainian land and airspace.&nbsp; Our Allies and partners have stepped up as well.<br><br>But as I’ve made clear: American forces are in Europe &#8212; not in Europe to engage in conflict with Russian forces.&nbsp; American forces are here to defend NATO Allies.<br><br>Yesterday, I met with the troops that are serving alongside our Polish allies to bolster NATO’s frontline defenses.&nbsp; The reason we wanted to make clear is their movement on Ukraine: Don’t even think about moving on one single inch of NATO territory.<br><br>We have a sacred obligation &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we have a sacred obligation under Article 5 to defend each and every inch of NATO territory with the full force of our collective power.<br><br>And earlier today, I visited your National Stadium, where thousands of Ukrainian refugees are now trying to answer the toughest questions a human can ask: “My God, what’s going to happen to me?&nbsp; What’s going to happen to my family?”<br><br>I saw tears in many of the mothers’ eyes as I embraced them; their young children &#8212; their young children not sure whether to smile or cry.&nbsp; One little girl said, “Mr. President” &#8212; she spoke a little English &#8212; “is my brother and my daddy &#8212; are they going to be okay?&nbsp; Will I see them again?”&nbsp; Without their husbands, their fathers, in many cases, their brothers or sisters who stayed back to fight for their country.<br><br>I didn’t have to speak the language or understand the language to feel the emotion in their eyes, the way they gripped my hand, and little kids hung on to my leg, praying with a desperate hope that all this is temporary; apprehension that they may be perhaps forever away from their homes, almost with debilitating sadness that this is happening all over again.<br><br>But I was also struck by the generosity of the people of Warsaw &#8212; for that matter, all the Polish people &#8212; for the depths of their compassion, their willingness to reach out &#8212; (applause) &#8212; opening their hearts.<br><br>I was saying to the Mayor they’re preparing to open their hearts and their homes simply to help.&nbsp; I also want to thank my friend, the great American chef, José Andrés, and his team who helped feeling [sic] those &#8212; (applause) &#8212; feeding those who are yearning to be free.&nbsp;<br><br>But helping these refugees is not something Poland or any other nation should carry alone.&nbsp; All the world democracies have a responsibility to help.&nbsp; All of them.&nbsp; And the people of Ukraine can count on the United States to meet its responsibility.<br><br>I&#8217;ve announced, two days ago, we will welcome 100,000 Ukrainian refugees.&nbsp; We already have 8,000 a week coming to the United States of other nat- &#8212; nationalities.<br><br>We’ll provide nearly $300 million of humanitarian assistance, providing tens of thousands of tons of food, water, medicine, and other basic supplies.<br><br>In Brussels, I announced the United States is prepared to provide more than $1 billion, in addition, in humanitarian aid.<br><br>The World Food Programme told us that despite significant obstacles, at least some relief is getting to major cities in Ukraine, but not Metropol [sic] &#8212; no, excuse me, Mar- &#8212; not Mariupol, because Russian forces are blocking relief supplies.<br><br>But we’ll not cease our efforts to get humanitarian relief wherever it is needed in Ukraine and for the people who’ve made it out of Ukraine.<br><br>Notwithstanding the brutality of Vladimir Putin, let there be no doubt that this war has already been a strategic failure for Russia already.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Having lost children myself &#8212; I know that’s no solace to the people who’ve lost family.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But he, Putin, thought Ukrainians would roll over and not fight.&nbsp; Not much of a student of history.&nbsp; Instead, Russian forces have met their match with brave and stiff Ukrainian resistance.<br><br>Rather than breaking Ukrainian resolve, Russia’s brutal tactics have strengthened the resolve.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Rather than driving NATO apart, the West is now stronger and more united than it has ever been.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Russia wanted less of a NATO presence on its border, but now&nbsp;<s>he has</s>&nbsp;[we have] a stronger presence, a larger presence, with over a hundred thousand American troops here, along with all the other members of NATO.<br><br>In fact &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Russia has managed to cause something I’m sure he never intended: The democracies of the world are revitalized with purpose and unity found in months that we’d once taken years to accomplish.<br><br>It’s not only Russia’s actions in Ukraine that are reminding us of democracy’s blessing.&nbsp; It’s our own country &#8212; his own country, the Kremlin, is jailing protestors.&nbsp; Two hundred thousand people have allegedly already left.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a brain drain &#8212; leaving Russia.&nbsp; Shutting down independent news.&nbsp; State media is all propaganda, blocking the image of civilian targets, mass graves, starvation tactics of the Russian forces in Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Is it any wonder, as I said, that 200,000 Russians have all left their country in one month?&nbsp; A remarkable brain drain in such a short period of time, which brings me to my message to the Russian people:<br><br>I&#8217;ve worked with Russian leaders for decades.&nbsp; I sat across the negotiating table going all the way back to Soviet Premier Alexei Kosygin to talk arms control at the height of the Cold War.<br><br>I&#8217;ve always spoken directly and honestly to you, the Russian people.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me say this, if you&#8217;re able to listen: You, the Russian people, are not our enemy.&nbsp;<br><br>I refuse to believe that you welcome the killing of innocent children and grandparents or that you accept hospitals, schools, maternity wards that, for God’s sake, are being pummeled with Russian missiles and bombs; or cities being surrounded so that civilians cannot flee; supplies cut off and attempting to starve Ukrainians into submission.&nbsp;<br><br>Millions of families are being driven from their homes, including half of all Ukraine’s children.&nbsp; These are not the actions of a great nation.&nbsp;<br><br>Of all people, you, the Russian people, as well as all people across Europe, still have the memory of being in a similar situation in the late thirties and forties &#8212; the situation of World War Two &#8212; still fresh in the minds of many grandparents in the region.<br><br>What &#8212; whatever your generation experienced &#8212; whether it experienced the Siege of Leningrad or heard about it from your parents and grandparents &#8212; train stations overflowing with terrified families fleeing their homes; nights sheltering in basements and cellars; mornings sitting through the rubble in your homes &#8212; these are not memories of the past.&nbsp; Not anymore.&nbsp; Because it’s exactly what the Russian army is doing in Ukraine right now.&nbsp;<br><br>March 26, 2022.&nbsp; Just days before &#8212; we’re at the twenty-fir- &#8212; you were a 21st century nation with hopes and dreams that people all over the world have for themselves and their family.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, Vladimir Putin’s aggression have cut you, the Russian people, off from the rest of the world, and it’s taking Russia back to the 19th century.<br><br>This is not who you are.&nbsp; This is not the future reserve &#8212; you deserve for your families and your children.&nbsp; I’m telling you the truth: This war is not worthy of you, the Russian people.<br><br>Putin can and must end this war.&nbsp; The American people stand with you and the brave citizens of Ukraine who want peace.<br><br>And my message to the rest of Europe: This new battle for freedom has already made a few things crystal clear.&nbsp;<br><br>First, Europe must end its dependence on Russian fossil fuels.&nbsp; And we, the United States, will help.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That’s why just yesterday, in Brussels, I announced a plan with the President of the European Commission to get Europe through the immediate energy crisis.<br><br>Over the long term, as a matter of economic security and national security and for the survivability of the planet, we all need to move as quickly as possible to clean, renewable energy.&nbsp; And we’ll work together to help get that done so that the days of any nation being subject to the whims of a tyrant for its energy needs are over.&nbsp; They must end.&nbsp; They must end.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And second, we have to fight the corruption coming from the Kremlin to give the Russian people a fair chance.<br><br>And finally, and most urgently, we maintain absolute unity &#8212; we must &#8212; among the world’s democracies.<br><br>It’s not enough to speak with rhetorical flourish, of ennobling words of democracy, of freedom, equality, and liberty.&nbsp; All of us, including here in Poland, must do the hard work of democracy each and every day.&nbsp; My country as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why &#8212; (applause) &#8212; that’s why I came to Europe again this week with a clear and determined message for NATO, for the G7, for the European Union, for all freedom-loving nations: We must commit now to be in this fight for the long haul.&nbsp; We must remain unified today and tomorrow and the day after and for the years and decades to come.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>It will not be easy.&nbsp; There will be costs.&nbsp; But it’s a price we have to pay.&nbsp; Because the darkness that drives autocracy is ultimately no match for the flame of liberty that lights the souls of free people everywhere.<br><br>Time and again, history shows that it’s from the darkest moments that the greatest progress follows.&nbsp; And history shows this is the task of our time, the task of this generation.<br><br>Let&#8217;s remember: The hammer blow that brought down the Berlin Wall, the might that lifted the Iron Curtain were not the words of a single leader; it was the people of Europe who, for decades, fought to free themselves.<br><br>Their sheer bravery opened the border between Austria and Hungary for the Pan-European Picnic.&nbsp; They joined hands for the Baltic Way.&nbsp; They stood for Solidarity here in Poland.&nbsp; And together, it was an unmistakable and undeniable force of the people that the Soviet Union could not withstand.<br><br>And we’re seeing it once again today with the brave Ukrainian people, showing that their power of many is greater than the will of any one dictator.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So, in this hour, let the words of Pope John Paul burn as brightly today: “Never, ever give up hope, never doubt, never tire, never become discouraged.&nbsp; Be not afraid.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>A dictator bent on rebuilding an empire will never erase a people’s love for liberty.&nbsp; Brutality will never grind down their will to be free.&nbsp; Ukraine will never be a victory for Russia &#8212; for free people refuse to live in a world of hopelessness and darkness.<br><br>We will have a different future &#8212; a brighter future rooted in democracy and principle, hope and light, of decency and dignity, of freedom and possibilities.&nbsp;<br><br>For God’s sake, this man cannot remain in power.&nbsp;<br><br>God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God defend our freedom.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for your patience.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>6:43 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden Call with Opposition Leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of&#160;Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/26/readout-of-president-biden-call-with-opposition-leader-svyatlana-tsikhanouskaya-of-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 19:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49771</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., spoke with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus from Air Force One. He thanked her for attending his speech in Warsaw tonight. The President underscored the continued support of the United States for the Belarusian people in defending and advancing human rights, including freedom of expression, and free and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., spoke with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus from Air Force One. He thanked her for attending his speech in Warsaw tonight. The President underscored the continued support of the United States for the Belarusian people in defending and advancing human rights, including freedom of expression, and free and fair elections.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Meeting With Ukrainian&#160;Refugees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/26/remarks-by-president-biden-after-meeting-with-ukrainian-refugees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PGE Narodowy StadiumWarsaw, Poland 3:28 P.M. CET Q    Mr. President, what do you think about Russia changing its strategy? THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m not sure they have. Q    And what&#8217;s the impact of this on you, Mr. President?  Tell us about what you saw. THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ve been to an awful lot of places like this with a lot of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">PGE Narodowy Stadium<br>Warsaw, Poland</p>



<p>3:28 P.M. CET<br> <br>Q    Mr. President, what do you think about Russia changing its strategy?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m not sure they have.<br> <br>Q    And what&#8217;s the impact of this on you, Mr. President?  Tell us about what you saw.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ve been to an awful lot of places like this with a lot of refugee camps in my life.  And what I &#8212; what I never &#8212; I&#8217;m always surprised by is the depth and strength of the human spirit.  I mean it sincerely.  And it’s incredible.  It’s incredible.<br> <br>You see all those little children?  Just wanted to &#8212; just want a hug.  They just want to say thanks.  I mean, they&#8217;re &#8212; I mean, it’s &#8212; it just makes you so damn proud.  And they&#8217;re wonderful, wonderful, wonderful. <br> <br>And, you know, the Ukrainian people are &#8212; each one of those children said something to the effect, “Say a prayer for my dad, for my grandfather, for my brother who’s back there fighting.”  And I remember what it’s like when you have someone in a war zone.  Every morning you get up and you wonder.  You just wonder.  You pray you don’t get that phone call.  And they&#8217;re an amazing group of people.<br> <br>Q    How does this make you think of &#8212;<br> <br>Q    How do you get into some of these cities like Mariupol that’s got &#8212; you know, that’s got nothing?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Oh, they’ve got nothing.  I met two people from Mariupol.  It’s &#8212; it’s astounding.<br> <br>Q    What were the commitments with Ukraine?<br> <br>Q    What is this &#8212; I mean, you see this in your &#8212; you know, you&#8217;re dealing every day with Vladimir Putin.  I mean, look at what he&#8217;s done to these people.  What does it make you think?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  He&#8217;s a butcher.  That’s what it makes me think. <br> <br>3:29 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Andrzej Duda of&#160;Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/26/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 15:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., met today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland in Warsaw. The leaders discussed ongoing international efforts to impose powerful sanctions on Russia for its unjustified and unprovoked attack on Ukraine. They also discussed their shared commitment to continue supporting the government and people of Ukraine. President Biden thanked President Duda&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., met today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland in Warsaw. The leaders discussed ongoing international efforts to impose powerful sanctions on Russia for its unjustified and unprovoked attack on Ukraine. They also discussed their shared commitment to continue supporting the government and people of Ukraine. President Biden thanked President Duda and the people of Poland for opening their homes and hearts to their neighbors in need, and he pledged continued U.S. support to these humanitarian assistance efforts. President Biden underscored the United States’ unwavering commitment to Article 5 and to the security of all our NATO allies. In addition, the leaders discussed our robust bilateral defense cooperation, US support for Europe’s efforts to reduce its reliance on Russian energy and to meet our climate goals, and the democratic values on which the transatlantic relationship is based.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Andrzej Duda of Poland Before Expanded Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/26/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-before-expanded-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 14:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49762</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential PalaceWarsaw, Poland 1:44 P.M. CET PRESIDENT DUDA:&#160; Excellency Mr. President, distinguished members of the American delegation: I am delighted, and it is an immensely important moment to us to host you here, Mr. President, the President of the United States of America, along with the members of your delegation &#8212; to host you here&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Presidential Palace<br>Warsaw, Poland</p>



<p>1:44 P.M. CET</p>



<p>PRESIDENT DUDA:&nbsp; Excellency Mr. President, distinguished members of the American delegation: I am delighted, and it is an immensely important moment to us to host you here, Mr. President, the President of the United States of America, along with the members of your delegation &#8212; to host you here in Poland, in Warsaw, in this time so immensely important for the whole world.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p>That &#8212; this presence shows in such an excellent way, but also strengthens the fact of extremely strong Euro-Atlantic ties.&nbsp; It also demonstrates the unity of the North Atlantic Alliance and the traditional cooperation in the military sphere, in the economic sphere, and also in the political sphere between the United States of America and Poland.</p>



<p>Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; We are grateful for your yesterday’s visit to Rzeszów, which is of extremely symbolic character to all of us.&nbsp; But it is also of key importance for all of those who are helping and assisting refugees from Ukraine on a daily basis.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Poles, guests from other countries, our volunteers, foreign volunteers &#8212; they are dedicating themselves; they are sacrificing their time, offering all the means and measures in order to help people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you, Mr. President, so much for paying that visit yesterday.&nbsp; It is hugely important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, thank you for all the help and assistance provided by the United States.&nbsp; Thank you for the contribution of the First Lady of the United States, Mrs. Jill Biden.&nbsp; Thank you for her consultations with my wife, for the assistance, and for an excellent atmosphere that you, Mr. President, and your wife create for all our matters in the United States.&nbsp; My wife recently visited New York, and she felt that great atmosphere.&nbsp; So, thank you so much.</p>



<p>But let me stress &#8212; and very strongly, Mr. President &#8212; that although times are very difficult, today, Polish-American relations are flourishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are the first, the biggest customer buying American LNG gas.&nbsp; We have received LNG gas for many years.&nbsp; Our gas terminal in Świnoujście, it helps us to diversify our gas resources in Poland.&nbsp; It is hugely important, given today’s Russia’s aggression Ukraine, given this energy blackmail which Russia has pursued for many years right now.&nbsp; We have built that LNG terminal in Świnoujście precisely to fight this blackmail, to avoid this blackmail.&nbsp; And we are thankful for U.S. support in this respect.</p>



<p>Furthermore, we are grateful for continuing on this path.&nbsp; We started a program on civil nuclear energy &#8212; the construction of U.S. nuclear power plants in Poland, which are indispensable to us to protect the climate and to develop a modern energy sector in our country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I strongly believe that this partnership that we have between the United States and Poland in the development of nuclear energy in our country, in close cooperation between our two states, will be implemented and finalized.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have here with me Minister Piotr Naimski who is responsible on the Polish side for this program.&nbsp; And I do believe that along with American companies, but under a strong patronage of the White House, we will be able to successfully implement in the near future, because Poland badly needs it.</p>



<p>Mr. President, we have very good economic relations.&nbsp; We have got &#8212; in 2021, according to our estimates, we had more than 18 billion U.S. dollars of trade volume, despite the coronavirus pandemic, despite other obstacles that were in the way.&nbsp; This, it makes us really pleased.&nbsp; We&#8217;re happy with all the U.S. investments in Poland.&nbsp; We are happy to welcome them here, just as we are happy to welcome U.S. soldiers who are coming up to us in order to strengthen the eastern flank.&nbsp; We are grateful for this help.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me also stress, Mr. President: We are a serious partner.&nbsp; We are a credible ally.&nbsp; We do everything we can in order to live up to the task of defending our country ourselves.&nbsp; That is why we adopted a new bill, the Act on Defense of the Republic of Poland, and that is why as early as next year we will start to allocate 3 percent of our GDP on defense.&nbsp; That is why I want to, and we want to, increase those spendings also in the years to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We want to equip our armed forces with modern equipment, and that is why, in the future, we want &#8212; we intend to buy well-tested and modern military equipment that is produced in the United States of America.</p>



<p>But, of course, we would be very much interested in establishing a cooperation with the United States in this respect.&nbsp; And we are delighted with every element of this cooperation that is developing, such as the possibility to co-produce, in Poland, Black Hawks.&nbsp; And right now, we would like to have more forms of such cooperation also in the military sphere.</p>



<p>So, Mr. President, all the bonds that I mentioned, all of that is strengthened immensely by your visit, Mr. President, and we&#8217;re so much grateful for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is also important for the representatives of the U.S. business circles.&nbsp; Wherever you can, Mr. President, they feel that this place is safe and secure.&nbsp; So, Mr. President, we are so much grateful for your visit.</p>



<p>But let me stress one thing, sir: This is a very difficult situation, what is happening in Ukraine right now &#8212; this Russian aggression and this huge tragedy of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; All of us, together, are experiencing it with them.&nbsp; And this also creates a great sense of threat for my compatriots, for the Polish people, because we know what Russian imperialism stands for, and we know what it means to be attacked by Russian armed forces, because our grandfathers and great-grandfathers experienced that; sometimes even our parents experienced that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you for your presence.&nbsp; And thank you, first and foremost, for your incredible leadership, strong leadership.&nbsp; Thank you for this very strong voice of the United States which leads us and which very resolutely calls on Russia to stop its aggression against Ukraine.</p>



<p>We stand with the United States.&nbsp; And along with the United States, we want to pursue this policy.&nbsp; And we very much hope for decisive and strong leadership of the United States across the entire NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, we hope that we will further strengthen the Euro-Atlantic bond.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President, once again for your presence.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you very much.&nbsp; Twenty-five years ago, when I spoke at a university here in Warsaw, after having led the effort for Poland to join NATO, I used the phrase &#8212; and my Ambassador reminded me of this &#8212; I said &#8212; started off by saying, “For your freedom and for ours.”&nbsp; “For your freedom and for ours.”&nbsp; I meant it then, and I mean it now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, Mr. President, we have &#8212; the most important thing that binds us together are our values: freedom &#8212; freedom of the press; making sure that people are &#8212; that government is transparent; making sure people have the right to vote, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; we had a very &#8212; and I hope we haven&#8217;t kept you waiting.&nbsp; It’s good to be back in this room again, but I hope we didn’t keep you waiting too long.&nbsp; But we were discussing a lot of things in private, not the least of which was that, as I pointed out &#8212; and my colleagues, I&#8217;m confident, agree with me &#8212; is that America&#8217;s ability to meet its role in other parts of the world rests upon a united Europe and a secure Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have learned from sad experience in two world wars: When we&#8217;ve stayed out of and not been involved in stability in Europe, it always comes back to haunt us, the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I&#8217;ve been saying for a long time &#8212; as a senator who visited here and a member the Foreign Relations Committee, as Vice President for eight years, now as President &#8212; that stability in Europe is critically important to the United States in terms of our interest not only in Europe, but around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, what we talked about is the need for us to stay in constant contact and know what one another are doing.&nbsp; The United States and my colleagues on this side of the table heard me say it many, many times: We take Article 5 as a sacred commitment, not a throwaway &#8212; a sacred commitment that relates to every member of NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the things that I thanked the President for downstairs was the fact that the single-most important criterion in this time of a changing world &#8212; so much has changed, and not just here but in other parts of the world &#8212; is that NATO stay absolutely, completely, thoroughly united; that there be no separation in our points of view; that whatever we do, we do in unison; and everyone &#8212; everyone comes along.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m confident that Vladimir Putin was counting on being able to divide NATO, to be able to separate the eastern flank from the West, be able to separate nations based on past histories.&nbsp; But he hasn&#8217;t been able to do it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve all stayed together.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, I just think it&#8217;s so important that we &#8212; Poland and the United States &#8212; keep in lockstep in how we&#8217;re proceeding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, we do acknowledge that Poland is taking on a significant responsibility that I don&#8217;t think should just be Poland, it should be the whole world &#8212; all of NATO’s responsibility.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact that you have so many &#8212; so many Ukrainians seeking refuge in the &#8212; in this country of Poland, we understand that because we have, in our southern border, thousands of people a day &#8212; literally, not figuratively &#8212; trying to get into the United States.&nbsp; But we believe that we, the United States, should do our part, relative to Ukraine as well, by opening our borders to another hundred thousand people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but that’s &#8212; and in addition to that, I think it&#8217;s important that we are in constant contact as about how we each wish to proceed, relative to what Russia is doing, and how to proceed.</p>



<p>And so, I &#8212; I just want to thank you, Mr. President, for being available, for being so cooperative, for being &#8212; and letting us know exactly what&#8217;s on your mind.&nbsp; It&#8217;s on the mind of the Polish people &#8212; what their concerns are and what they think our responsibilities are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I&#8217;ll end where I began, and that is: We take as a sacred obligation Article 5 &#8212; a sacred obligation, Article 5. &nbsp;And you can count on that.&nbsp; And not just &#8212; I’ll end where I began: for your freedom is ours.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:57 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Kuleba and Defense Minister Reznikov of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/26/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-foreign-minister-kuleba-and-defense-minister-reznikov-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 12:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49755</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin met with Ukraine’s Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba and Minister of Defense Oleksii Reznikov for an update on Ukraine’s military, diplomatic, and humanitarian situation. The President updated the Ministers on U.S. efforts to rally the world in support of Ukraine’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., Secretary of State Antony Blinken, and Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin met with Ukraine’s Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba and Minister of Defense Oleksii Reznikov for an update on Ukraine’s military, diplomatic, and humanitarian situation. The President updated the Ministers on U.S. efforts to rally the world in support of Ukraine’s fight against Russian aggression, including through the President’s meetings this week in Belgium, and the significant military and humanitarian assistance the United States is providing to Ukraine. They discussed further efforts to help Ukraine defend its territory. They also discussed the United States’ ongoing actions to hold President Putin accountable for Russia’s brutal aggression, in coordination with our allies and partners, including through the new sanctions actions announced by the President in Brussels on March 24.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Houthi Attack Against Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-houthi-attack-against-saudi-arabia-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 21:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49752</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We condemn the Houthi attacks launched against Saudi Arabia’s civil infrastructure earlier today. Unprovoked Houthi attacks against Saudi Aramco’s oil storage facilities in Jeddah as well as attacks against civil facilities in Jizan, Najran, and Dhahran are acts of terrorism aimed to prolong the suffering of the Yemeni people.  Today’s attacks, just like the attacks&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We condemn the Houthi attacks launched against Saudi Arabia’s civil infrastructure earlier today. Unprovoked Houthi attacks against Saudi Aramco’s oil storage facilities in Jeddah as well as attacks against civil facilities in Jizan, Najran, and Dhahran are acts of terrorism aimed to prolong the suffering of the Yemeni people.  Today’s attacks, just like the attacks against water treatment plants and energy infrastructure on March 19 and 20, were clearly enabled by Iran in violation of UN Security Council resolutions prohibiting the import of weapons into Yemen.  Saudi Arabia and the Yemeni Government have endorsed multiple UN calls for ceasefires and de-escalation over the last year. The Houthis continue to reject these calls and respond with terrorist acts and military offensives, all of which extend the Yemen conflict and the consequent humanitarian crisis.  It is time to bring this war to a close and relief to the Yemeni people but that can only happen if the Houthis agree to cooperate with the United Nations and its envoy working on a step-by-step process to de-escalate the conflict. The United States stands fully behind those efforts, and we will continue to fully support our partners in the defense of their territory from Houthi attacks. We call on the international community to do the same.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at St. Jude Children&#8217;s Research&#160;Hospital</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/25/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-st-jude-childrens-research-hospital/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 21:19:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Memphis, TN Thank you, Ashley, clearly you were called to your profession and your story is such a good reminder that small acts of kindness can really save us when we’re going through the hardest times. And now you’re paying that kindness forward for today’s patients. Thank you for that. It’s wonderful to be back&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Memphis, TN</p>



<p>Thank you, Ashley, clearly you were called to your profession and your story is such a good reminder that small acts of kindness can really save us when we’re going through the hardest times. And now you’re paying that kindness forward for today’s patients. Thank you for that.</p>



<p>It’s wonderful to be back in Tennessee, but especially here at St. Jude.</p>



<p>Like most Americans I’ve known the work of this world-renowned institution, but to see just how special this place is firsthand is simply breathtaking. You all think of everything! And, your research is saving lives.</p>



<p>Marlo, thank you for welcoming us today. It is my honor to stand with you and truly celebrate your father’s legacy.</p>



<p>Congressman Cohen, Mayors Strickland and Harris, and our dear friend, Joyce, thank you for being with us.</p>



<p>Before I begin, I want to say that our hearts are with the families in New Orleans who have been hurt by the storms earlier this week. Please keep those families in your prayers.</p>



<p>Parents—we would do anything to keep our children safe.</p>



<p>That’s why one of the hardest parts of a cancer diagnosis is the paralyzing sense of helplessness.</p>



<p>But here at St. Jude, hearing about so many cutting-edge approaches to this disease, we are reminded that we aren’t helpless. In fact, we’re living in a time of incredible possibility.</p>



<p>Dr. Downing, thank you for showing me around—I’m inspired by the work that happens here.</p>



<p>We can end cancer as we know it. That’s what the Cancer Moonshot is all about.</p>



<p>It’s about listening to patients and survivors and their families, and finding new ways to ease the burden they face.</p>



<p>It’s about delivering new, effective treatments, including for childhood cancers, that turn a diagnosis from a moment of devastation into hope.</p>



<p>And it’s about bringing the brightest minds and fiercest hearts to the table, to learn, and collaborate, and discover together.</p>



<p>St. Jude understands that, and you support the entire family through this process.</p>



<p>With world-class care at no cost, and a tireless commitment to researching treatments and cures for childhood cancers, you have saved countless young lives. You offer healing and hope, care and community, a place of refuge for those facing the worst.</p>



<p>Like all of us, my heart has ached watching videos of Ukraine. The unthinkable bombing of a maternity ward. The theatre sheltering families, turned to debris and dust. Parents weeping over their children’s broken bodies in the streets.</p>



<p>The senselessness of it all is staggering.</p>



<p>That’s why Joe is working night and day to bring the world together to support Ukraine—with diplomacy and crippling sanctions against Russia. In fact, yesterday he attended a NATO Summit to discuss the defense of our Allies.</p>



<p>And today, he’s in Poland, where he met with our troops and humanitarian partners, seeing our efforts on the ground, and learning more about what we, and others, can do to support the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>As part of our support, Joe announced yesterday that the U.S. will welcome up to 100,000 Ukrainians and others fleeing Russia’s aggression.</p>



<p>But when I learned that St. Jude was working with hospitals in Europe to bring some of the Ukrainian children with cancer and their families here—I felt so proud and I wanted join you in welcoming them. We stand with Ukraine and we’re praying for their families.</p>



<p>So thank you to St. Jude and everyone who helped bring these children to safety.</p>



<p>We often hear that the measure of a society is how we treat our most vulnerable members. We know that we have a responsibility to care for children. But anyone who has held a tiny life—who has looked into those saucer eyes and felt impossibly strong fingers wrap around your own—knows that it is so much more than an obligation.</p>



<p>It is a joy, a gift – the honor of a lifetime.</p>



<p>And, not just our children—but all children. Because inside each one is a world of possibility, of hope, of all the better tomorrows we pray will come.</p>



<p>We owe them an end to cancer as we know it. We owe them safety and health.</p>



<p>We owe them happiness and joy—the chance to be a kid.</p>



<p>Together, we can give them that.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Andrzej Duda of Poland in Briefing on the Humanitarian Efforts for&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/25/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-in-briefing-on-the-humanitarian-efforts-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 18:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rzeszów-Jasionka Airport    Rzeszów, Poland 4:48 P.M. CET PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Madam Ambassador, thank you very much.  And, Mr. President, thanks for the welcome.  Thanks for having us here.  And to &#8212; and we sent you our best.  We sent you Brzezinski as our ambassador, and I’m glad he’s here as well. And, you know, as you and I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rzeszów-Jasionka Airport<br>    Rzeszów, Poland</p>



<p>4:48 P.M. CET<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Madam Ambassador, thank you very much.  And, Mr. President, thanks for the welcome.  Thanks for having us here.  And to &#8212; and we sent you our best.  We sent you Brzezinski as our ambassador, and I’m glad he’s here as well.<br> <br>And, you know, as you and I have spoken before, Mr. Ambassador &#8212; excuse me, Mr. President &#8212; the single-most important thing that we can do from the outset is keep the democracies united in our opposition and our effort to curtail<br>the devastation that is occurring at the hands of a man who, quite frankly, I think is a war criminal.  And I think it will meet the legal definition of that as well.<br> <br>But I want to thank everyone for &#8212; and I think it’s been a surprise &#8212; about how we’ve all stayed together across the board.  The most severe punishing sanctions in the history of the world &#8212; economic sanctions &#8212; have been imposed.  And there&#8217;s more that will come.<br> <br>But, you know, there&#8217;s still an awful lot of suffering.  I, like many of you, in the past have been through refugee camps all around the world, literally, and seen the devastation as a consequence of people who were abandoned and &#8212; in war-ravaged regions of the world, whether it&#8217;s in the Middle East, or Africa, or wherever. <br> <br>I mean, it&#8217;s just devastating to see those little babies, little children, who are looking at mothers who &#8212; you don&#8217;t have to understand the language they speak &#8212; you just see in their eyes the pain.  And I mean, literally, the pain of watching their children.<br> <br>I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s anything worse for a parent than to see a child suffering &#8212; their child suffering.  I mean that sincerely.  It’s not hyperbole.  I mean it from the bottom of my heart.<br> <br>And so what you, the humanitarian community, are doing is of such enormous consequence.<br> <br>Brother, this is what we say we&#8217;re about.  This is what we say that our obligations are.  But you&#8217;re living up to it.  We&#8217;re doing it every day, all of you who are sitting at this table.<br> <br>And so, you know, I&#8217;m here in Poland to see firsthand the humanitarian crisis.  And quite frankly, part of my disappointment is that I can&#8217;t see it firsthand, like I have in other places &#8212; they will not let me, understandably; I guess it would cross the border &#8212; and take a look at what’s going on in Ukraine. <br> <br>But, you know, I’m eager to hear from you, the humanitarian community, about what you see, what you’re doing, and where you think we go from here &#8212; because you’re doing it every day.<br> <br>As has been pointed out, 10 million people have been displaced thus far; 3.8 million people to other countries, including more than a million children.  And according to the U.N., there are thousands of civilian casualties, 12 million in need of assistance, but hundreds of thousands &#8212; hundreds of thousands of people who are being cut off from help by Russian forces and are in &#8212; besieged in places like Mariupol.  I mean, it’s not stopping.  It’s like something out of a science fiction movie.  You turn on the television and see what these towns look like, and the cities. <br> <br>And I want to thank each one of you and your organizations.  Excuse me.  (Takes sip of a drink.)  When I was visiting our troops, they had pizza pie with hot peppers on it.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>But, you know, you’re helping millions of people &#8212; millions of people.  And we must &#8212; have to continue to scale up that assistance and coordinate it closely with the government of Ukraine, which is really &#8212; I think even you Poles, who know Ukraine so well, have to be a little bit surprised at how what &#8212; how much courage and capacity for resiliency of the Ukrainian people.  When you see a 30-year-old woman standing there in front of a tank with a rifle &#8212; I mean, talk about what happened in Tiananmen Square; that’s Tiananmen Square squared.  <br> <br>And, look, the &#8212; whether it&#8217;s food or a blanket or cash or the care for medical teams that we send in, or child welfare specialists, they need it now.  They need it as rapidly as we can get it there.<br> <br>And so, yesterday I announced, on behalf of the American people, we’re prepared to provide another 1 billion, as the Ambassador pointed out &#8212; 1 billion dollars for those who fled and those who are affected around the world as a consequence of the negative impact of this war on food security. <br> <br>The bad news is they’re &#8212; been the breadbasket of the world, Ukraine and Russia.  But we, the United States, are going to do our part because we’re the third-largest producer of wheat in the world.  And our Canadian friends are going to do the same thing.  But we&#8217;re going to try very hard.<br> <br>But in the meantime, the suffering that is taking place now is at your doorstep.  You&#8217;re the ones who are risking, in some cases, your lives and risking all you know to try to help.  And the American people are proud to support your efforts.  <br> <br>And today, I want to hear from all of you.  The problem is I know they&#8217;re going to tell me I have to get on the plane, and I’m going to have to leave.  But I have a lot of questions because I &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; I learned a great deal from you and your counterparts as I’ve traveled the world in the last 30 years. <br> <br>And so, I&#8217;m honored that President Duda is here today.  And I’m joined by Secretary Blinken &#8212; he’s an old friend, as well as my Secretary of State; and our USID &#8212; USAID Administrator, Samantha Powers, who, like my sister &#8212; whatever I say, she says, “It&#8217;s not enough.”  “It&#8217;s not enough.  I don&#8217;t get to do more.”  And this is a workhorse. <br> <br>So &#8212; but now going to turn it back to her so we can get to the question-and-answer period.<br> <br>ADMINISTRATOR POWER:  Thank you so much.  Thank you, Mr. President. <br> <br>President Duda, I’d love &#8212; if you’d like to say a few words.  And before you do though, just &#8212; I think, on the behalf of the entire humanitarian community, we just want to extend our thanks to you for the way that you and the Polish people have opened your borders, your hearts, your homes.  The generosity and the show of solidarity has been breathtaking.  Thank you so much, sir.  Over to you. <br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  Thank you very much, Madam Ambassador.<br> <br>Excellency, Mr. President; Mr. Secretary; Madam Ambassador; Polish and American friends: Please, if you can take these electronic devices and use it &#8212; channel two is English &#8212; because I would like to speak in my mother tongue, Polish.<br> <br>(As interpreted.)  Your Excellency, Mr. President; dear American and Polish friends; ladies and gentlemen: Thank you so much to you, Mr. President, and to the whole U.S. delegation for coming to Poland.  But first and foremost, thank you for coming here to Rzeszów, to the region of Podkarpackie, which is very close &#8212; which is located directly to the Polish-Ukrainian border. <br> <br>Thank you for coming to the place where this influx of refugees to Poland is the biggest.  Your presence here, Mr. President, first of all, sends a very big sign of unity.  This is a huge sign of support and Euro-Atlantic unity &#8212; unity with my country, with Poland.  It demonstrates great friendship between Poland and the United States, and a very profound alliance. <br> <br>This is an evidence of great support and care for our mutual relations, but also &#8212; a thing of importance to me &#8212; it is a sign and a message that you care about the security of Poland. <br> <br>Today, Mr. President, you met with U.S. soldiers who are deployed here and who watch over our security.  They also help in this very difficult work, which is receiving millions of refugees who are crossing the border to our country right now.  But first and foremost, they are guarding the security of the Polish border and guarding the security also of the entire Euro-Atlantic community of the whole of NATO &#8212; because, today, the eastern flank of NATO &#8212; and I do not hesitate to say this; I also said it yesterday at NATO summit &#8212; this is a front line today, the eastern flank. <br> <br>I&#8217;m very happy to have you here, Mr. President, because as I said, your presence here sends a great signal and evidence of unity &#8212; unity within NATO.  It demonstrates a huge support and also a big significance attached by the United States to the stability and world peace, to reinstating the peace where difficult situations are happening in places where somebody resorts to acts of aggression against other democratic and free nations, as it is happening today against Ukraine where the Russian aggression, unfortunately, happening for a month now is effect.<br> <br>But your presence, Mr. President, here today in the city of Rzeszów is also a great sign of support to us &#8212; support in terms of humanitarian assistance, which today is provided to the refugees from Ukraine, but also it is provided to us Poles who are receiving guests &#8212; because this is the name we want to apply to them.  We do not call them “refugees.”  They are our guests, our brothers, our neighbors from Ukraine who today are in a very difficult situation where 12 million people have fled their houses by the war, by the Russian attacks.  More than 3.5 million have already fled abroad.  They crossed different borders, but first and foremost, they have crossed the border with Poland.<br> <br>Today, we have got 2.5 million people in Poland, and the number is growing all the time.  So, the number &#8212; exceeding 2 million right now &#8212; is still growing.  And all signs are that if the Russian aggression continues, those numbers will continue to grow.  <br> <br>So, first and foremost, this &#8212; it gives me an opportunity to extend my gratitude to you, Mr. President, to our guests from the United States, but also to the NGOs, both from my country &#8212; starting from the organizations which are present here at this table today &#8212; but also, I want to express my gratitude to all NGOs &#8212; Polish NGOs who are involved. <br> <br>But also, I would like to thank the U.S. organizations.  A big number of them is already present in Poland, and a lot of them sends assistance to our country.  And in this context, I&#8217;m so much grateful to you, Mr. President, for your support.  <br> <br>But also, I would like to ask you to convey my personal words of thanks to the First Lady of the United States, to Mrs. Jill Biden &#8212; your spouse, Mr. President.  And please convey very heartfelt greetings from my wife to your wife.  Both ladies had a conversation a couple of days ago.  My wife gave an account of the situation in Poland.  Both ladies exchanged their views on the possibilities of help.  Then my wife paid a visit to the United States.  And from the United States, she brought &#8212; in order to support Ukraine; in order to support Ukraine hospitals and also centers here in Poland, which treats children from Ukraine, also wounded children from Ukraine &#8212; she brought from the United States a number of medical equipment and medicines from the United States. <br> <br>So, thank you so much for this very swift assistance.  Thank you so much.  And please convey these words of greetings and these words of thanks to your wife.  And also, please convey very heartfelt wishes from my wife to your wife.  <br> <br>So, ladies and gentlemen, this presents a huge challenge.  This assistance is something unprecedented, because within a couple of weeks, more than 2 million people have come to our country.  We have never experienced anything like that throughout our history.  This is the first time.<br> <br>But I would also like to thank all my compatriots who have opened their hearts and opened their houses, who have welcomed refugees &#8212; but as I said, first and foremost, our neighbors, our brothers from Ukraine &#8212; who are in a difficult position today, who are in need today.  And all of us want to help them so much.  They are staying in private houses, and they&#8217;re staying in different facilities.  Very often, these people are very much affected by the war &#8212; wounded persons, ill persons.  Many of them have undergone mental trauma after the experiences they had. <br> <br>Recently we have received people without any belongings to Poland.  They fled from bombs.  So the situation is extremely difficult.  That is why we are so much thankful for any help and assistance, because this is what we very much need today.  <br> <br>On our part, we are doing everything we can with huge dedication and devotion.  NGOs have also demonstrated huge dedication.  Also volunteers, firefighters.  So there is a lot of assistance from NGOs, from churches &#8212; Catholic church, but also other churches in our country and religious communities. <br> <br>There is a lot of support offered from all different sides, also from abroad.  And once again, we&#8217;re so much grateful for that.  This presents a huge challenge to us, but it is also a huge challenge to the whole free world as we understand it, and we all have to live up to it. <br> <br>Once again, thank you for this visit.  And I&#8217;m so happy and delighted with the conversation that we can have.  All the authorities in Poland are involved in providing assistance.  It&#8217;s not only the government, NGOs, and volunteers, but also local governments.  <br> <br>Tomorrow, Mr. President, you will meet refugees in Warsaw.  But also, the Prime Minister of the Polish government will be present there, Mr. Mateusz Morawiecki.  The Mayor of Warsaw, Mr. Rafał Trzaskowski, will be there.  And they will share with you, sir, all the activities that are being conducted in Poland in order to live up to this difficult situation, in order to solve the problem.<br> <br>So, once again, we are delighted with the visit you are paying here, sir, and a very warm welcome to our country. <br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I&#8217;m going to get in real trouble if I don&#8217;t &#8212; I forgot to say something: My wife sends her best as well.  She also went to St. Jude&#8217;s Hospital, which is a cancer hospital in the United States, to see those young Ukrainian children who were brought over seeking serious, serious help with the cancers they have.  And she said to give her best to your wife.  That&#8217;s why she&#8217;s not with me today.  She’s out west doing that.  So, thank you.  Thank you for saving me.<br> <br>ADMINISTRATOR POWER:  (Laughs.)  Thank you, Mr. President.  And thank you, President Duda, so much.  If I may just ask now the media to leave the room &#8212; thank you so much for being &#8212; so we can commence our discussion on the humanitarian circumstances.  Thank you so much.<br> <br>(The press departs.)<br> <br>5:04 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden During Visit with Service Members of the 82nd Airborne&#160;Division</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/25/remarks-by-president-biden-during-visit-with-service-members-of-the-82nd-airborne-division/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 17:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49736</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[G2A ArenaRzeszów, Poland 4:07 P.M. CET &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Mr. Secretary.&#160; Don&#8217;t jump.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; You guys are used to jumping.&#160; Don&#8217;t jump. Anyway, thanks for letting me come and say hello to you all.&#160; You know, I&#8217;ve been saying this a long time &#8212; and the people who travel with me know that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">G2A Arena<br>Rzeszów, Poland</p>



<p>4:07 P.M. CET</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Secretary.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t jump.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You guys are used to jumping.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t jump.</p>



<p>Anyway, thanks for letting me come and say hello to you all.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;ve been saying this a long time &#8212; and the people who travel with me know that because I was a senator for 36 years, the Foreign Relations Committee, traveled around the world, and 8 years as Vice President, and now President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, a couple things: First of all, thank you. You represent 1 percent of the American people.&nbsp; None of you have to be here.&nbsp; You all decided to be here for your country.&nbsp; Every one of you volunteered.&nbsp; Every single one of you stepped up.&nbsp; And the rest of the 99 percent of the rest of the country, including me, owes you and owes you big, number one.</p>



<p>Number two, you know, we’re a unique country in many ways.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re the only country &#8212; the only country in the world not based &#8212; organized based on geography or ethnicity or religion or race or anything else; we&#8217;re based on an idea.&nbsp; Literally the only country in the world based on an idea that we hold these truths to be self-evident, that all women and men are created equal, endowed by their Creator with certain inalienable rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sounds corny, but it’s the truth of who we are.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never lived up to it, but we never walked away from it.&nbsp; And the rest of the world looks to us.&nbsp; Because, you know, we not only lead by the example of our power, but by the power of our example.&nbsp; And your generation combines both.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The rest of the world looks at you and sees who you are.&nbsp; They see you are a multi-ethnic group of Americans that are, in fact, together and united into one so- &#8212; resolve: to defend your country and to help those who need help.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why you&#8217;re here.</p>



<p>I spent a lot of time in Ukraine when I was a senator and Vice President.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spoken to the Rada in the days when they, in fact, didn&#8217;t have what you&#8217;d call a democracy, and was there in the Maidan when the former leader had to take off and head into Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; so, you know, with the Ukrainian people &#8212; Ukrainian people have a lot of backbone.&nbsp; They have a lot of guts.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;re observing it.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t mean just their military, which is &#8212; we&#8217;ve been training since back when they &#8212; Russia moved into the &#8212; in the southeast &#8212; southeast Ukraine &#8212; but also the average citizen.&nbsp; Look at how they&#8217;re stepping up.&nbsp; Look at how they&#8217;re stepping up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;re going to see when you&#8217;re there.&nbsp; And you &#8212; some &#8212; some of you have been there.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to see &#8212; you&#8217;re going to see women, young people standing &#8212; standing the middle of &#8212; in front of a damn tank, just saying, “I&#8217;m not leaving.&nbsp; I&#8217;m holding my ground.”&nbsp; They&#8217;re incredible.&nbsp; But they take a lot of inspiration from us.</p>



<p>And, you know, the woman who just died &#8212; the Secretary of State &#8212; used to have an expression.&nbsp; She said, “We are the essential nation.”&nbsp; It sounds like a bit of a hyperbole, but the truth of the matter is you are the organizing principle around which the rest of the world is &#8212; the free world is moving.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re in the midst of &#8212; and I don&#8217;t want to sound too philosophic here &#8212; but you&#8217;re in the midst of a fight between democracies and oligarchs.&nbsp; Xi Jinping &#8212; who I&#8217;ve spent more time with, they tell me, than any other world leader &#8212; points out to me that he believes, in China, that democracies can&#8217;t succeed in the 21st century.&nbsp; The reason is things are moving so fast, change is happening so quickly that democracies require consensus and we can&#8217;t put together consensus as quickly as autocrats can.</p>



<p>So what&#8217;s at stake &#8212; not just in what we&#8217;re doing here in Ukraine to try to help the Ukrainian people and keep the massacre from continuing &#8212; but beyond that, what&#8217;s at stake is: What&#8217;s &#8212; what&#8217;s &#8212; what are your kids and grandkids going to look like in terms of their &#8212; their freedom?&nbsp; What&#8217;s happening?&nbsp; The last 10 years, there have been fewer democracies that have been formed than we&#8217;ve lost in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is &#8212; what you&#8217;re engaged in is much more than just whether or not you can alleviate the pain and suffering of the people of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re in a new phase &#8212; your generation.&nbsp; We&#8217;re at an inflection point.&nbsp; About every four or five generations, there comes along a change &#8212; a fundamental change takes place.&nbsp; The world ain’t going to be the same &#8212; not because of Ukraine, but &#8212; not going to be the same 10, 15 years from now in terms of our organizational structures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the question is: Who is going to prevail?&nbsp; Are democracies going to prevail on the &#8212; and the values we share?&nbsp; Or are autocracies going to prevail?&nbsp; And that&#8217;s really what’s at stake.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what you&#8217;re doing is consequential &#8212; really consequential.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I said to the group in the dining room &#8212; you call it the chow, mess hall &#8212; the fact of the matter is that you are the finest &#8212; this is not hyperbole &#8212; you are the finest fighting force in the history of the world.&nbsp; Let me say it again: the finest fighting force in the history of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Part of the reason is you&#8217;ve had to fight so much for the last 20 years.&nbsp; It’s for real.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not many generations &#8212; you know, the Greatest Generation was my father&#8217;s generation, your grandparents’ generation &#8212; World War Two generation.&nbsp; But nobody &#8212; no other generation has had to be in a battle, have your buddy blown up, wipe the blood off the HMMWV, and get back in and saddle up and go for another six months.</p>



<p>The second time I&#8217;ve flew in &#8212; I’ve been in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan about 40 times &#8212; 30-something times &#8212; 38 times.&nbsp; And every time I&#8217;d go in, I&#8217;d see &#8212; like the last time I flew in &#8212; and I flew in on the &#8212; I went up in the cockpit.&nbsp; I was landing Bagram.&nbsp; And I &#8212; there were six people who came up with the cargo, basically &#8212; was what I was flying.&nbsp; And I said, “How many of you is this tour first tour of duty?”&nbsp; Not one person raised their hand.&nbsp; “Second tour?”&nbsp; Not one person.&nbsp; “Third tour of duty?”&nbsp; Three.&nbsp; “Fourth?”&nbsp; One.&nbsp; “Fifth one and sixth one?”&nbsp; That’s never happened before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One thing to go in and be in the middle of a battle, go home, and get sent back again.&nbsp; And so, one of the things that I’ve said &#8212; and I’ve gotten in trouble for saying it, but not anymore &#8212; I’ve been saying it since I got elected: We have a sacred obligation &#8212; only one obligation in this government.&nbsp; We have a lot of obligations to the elderly, the poor, children, et cetera, but only one sacred obligation: to equip those that we send to war and to care for them and their families when they come home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you all are amazing group of women and men, and I just want to thank you for your service.&nbsp; As your Commander-in-Chief, I mean it from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I said, it&#8217;s not new to me.&nbsp; I &#8212; my son spent a year in Iraq.&nbsp; He spent six months in Kosovo.&nbsp; He won the Bronze Star, the Conspicuous Service Medal, and other awards.&nbsp; Proudest thing he ever did was put that uniform on.</p>



<p>Like many of you, he didn’t have to go either.&nbsp; He was the Attorney General of the State of Delaware and in the Delaware National Guard.&nbsp; And what happened was, when his unit was going to be sent overseas, he had to go to Washington to get a &#8212; an equivalent of a dispensation because you either had to be federal property or state property.&nbsp; He was the Attorney General of the state; he had to give up the office in order to be able to go with his troops.</p>



<p>The point is that there are hundreds of thousands of people like my son, like all of you.&nbsp; So thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s not only what you&#8217;re doing to help the Ukrainian people, it&#8217;s not only what you&#8217;re doing to help Europe begin to gain &#8212; regain its confidence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reason why, when the general &#8212; when the Secretary of State asked me if I’d send another 12,000 troops along to the United States, I said, “Yeah” &#8212; from the United States &#8212; we have 100,000 American forces here in Europe; we haven&#8217;t had that long, long time &#8212; because we are the organizing principle for the rest of the world.</p>



<p>And I said, “We’ve sent the best &#8212; the best available in America.”&nbsp; And that&#8217;s all of you women and men.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I&#8217;m here.&nbsp; I came for one simple, basic reason &#8212; not a joke: to say thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you for your service.&nbsp; Thank you for who you are.&nbsp; And thank you for what you&#8217;re doing.</p>



<p>And as my grandfather would say every time I walked out of his house &#8212; he’d yell at me, “Joey” &#8212; in Scranton &#8212; he said, “Keep the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandmother &#8212; my grandmother would yell, all kidding aside &#8212; this is serious &#8212; she’d yell, “No, spread it.”&nbsp; You&#8217;re spreading the faith.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you all and keep you safe.&nbsp; May God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p> 4:16 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
