<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 04:57:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NEC Director Brian Deese and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on New Digital Assets Executive&#160;Order</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/statement-by-nec-director-brian-deese-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-new-digital-assets-executive-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to establish the first-ever comprehensive federal digital assets strategy for the United States. The E.O. will help position the U.S. to keep playing a leading role in the innovation and governance of the digital assets ecosystem at home and abroad, in a way that protects consumers, is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to establish the first-ever comprehensive federal digital assets strategy for the United States. The E.O. will help position the U.S. to keep playing a leading role in the innovation and governance of the digital assets ecosystem at home and abroad, in a way that protects consumers, is consistent with our democratic values and advances U.S. global competitiveness.</p>



<p>This E.O. marks an intensification of our efforts to promote responsible innovation in the digital assets space – innovation that works for all Americans, protects our national security interests, and contributes to our economic competitiveness and growth. Fundamentally, an American approach to digital assets is one that encourages innovation but mitigates the risks to consumers, investors, and businesses, broader financial stability, and the environment. We are clear-eyed that “financial innovation” of the past has too often not benefited working families, while exacerbating inequality and increasing systemic financial risk. This history underscores the need to build robust consumer and economic protections into digital asset development.</p>



<p>The approach outlined in the E.O. will reinforce U.S. leadership in the global financial system and safeguard the long-term efficacy of critical national security tools like sanctions and anti-money laundering frameworks. To these ends, the Order identifies the Administration’s policy priorities, both for cryptocurrencies and any future U.S. central bank digital currency, to help guide the evolution of the digital asset ecosystem in a way that is consistent with our values. Governments alone cannot solve these problems, and definitely not a government that operates in siloes. This E.O. is the product of months of work with stakeholders across government, industry, advocacy, academia, and international allies and partners – to identify actions we can take to foster responsible innovation in the digital asset ecosystem. Its implementation will leverage the knowledge and distinct expertise of a broad range of stakeholders across the White House and Executive departments and agencies, and regulatory agencies. We remain committed to working with allies, partners, and the broader digital asset community to shape the future of digital asset systems in a manner that is safe, inclusive, and consistent with our democratic values. As this ecosystem evolves, so too will our approach.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Sign Executive Order on Ensuring Responsible Innovation in Digital&#160;Assets</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/09/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-sign-executive-order-on-ensuring-responsible-innovation-in-digital-assets/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Outlines First Whole-of-Government Strategy to Protect Consumers, Financial Stability, National Security, and Address Climate Risks Digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, have seen explosive growth in recent years, surpassing a $3 trillion market cap last November and up from $14 billion just five years prior. Surveys suggest that around 16 percent of adult Americans – approximately 40&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Outlines First Whole-of-Government Strategy to Protect Consumers, Financial Stability, National Security, and Address Climate Risks</em></p>



<p>Digital assets, including cryptocurrencies, have seen explosive growth in recent years, surpassing <a href="https://coinmarketcap.com/headlines/news/crypto-market-cap-surpasses-3-trillion/">a $3 trillion</a> market cap last November and up from $14 billion just five years prior. Surveys suggest that around 16 percent of adult Americans – approximately 40 million people – have invested in, traded, or used cryptocurrencies. Over 100 countries are exploring or piloting Central Bank Digital Currencies (CBDCs), a digital form of a country’s sovereign currency.<br><br>The rise in digital assets creates an opportunity to reinforce American leadership in the global financial system and at the technological frontier, but also has substantial implications for consumer protection, financial stability, national security, and climate risk. The United States must maintain technological leadership in this rapidly growing space, supporting innovation while mitigating the risks for consumers, businesses, the broader financial system, and the climate. And, it must play a leading role in international engagement and global governance of digital assets consistent with democratic values and U.S. global competitiveness.<br><br>That is why today, President Biden will sign an Executive Order outlining the first ever, whole-of-government approach to addressing the risks and harnessing the potential benefits of digital assets and their underlying technology. The Order lays out a national policy for digital assets across six key priorities: consumer and investor protection; financial stability; illicit finance; U.S. leadership in the global financial system and economic competitiveness; financial inclusion; and responsible innovation.</p>



<p>Specifically, the Executive Order calls for measures to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Protect U.S. Consumers, Investors, and Businesses </strong>by directing the Department of the Treasury and other agency partners to assess and develop policy recommendations to address the implications of the growing digital asset sector and changes in financial markets for consumers, investors, businesses, and equitable economic growth. The Order also encourages regulators to ensure sufficient oversight and safeguard against any systemic financial risks posed by digital assets.<br></li><li><strong>Protect U.S. and Global Financial Stability and Mitigate Systemic Risk </strong>by encouraging the Financial Stability Oversight Council to identify and mitigate economy-wide (i.e., systemic) financial risks posed by digital assets and to develop appropriate policy recommendations to address any regulatory gaps.<br></li><li><strong>Mitigate the Illicit Finance and National Security Risks Posed by the Illicit Use of Digital Assets </strong>by directing an unprecedented focus of coordinated action across all relevant U.S. Government agencies to mitigate these risks. It also directs agencies to work with our allies and partners to ensure international frameworks, capabilities, and partnerships are aligned and responsive to risks.<br></li><li><strong>Promote U.S. Leadership in Technology and Economic Competitiveness to Reinforce U.S. Leadership in the Global Financial System </strong>by directing the Department of Commerce to work across the U.S. Government in establishing a framework to drive U.S. competitiveness and leadership in, and leveraging of digital asset technologies. This framework will serve as a foundation for agencies and integrate this as a priority into their policy, research and development, and operational approaches to digital assets.<br></li><li><strong>Promote Equitable Access to Safe and Affordable Financial Services </strong>by affirming the critical need for safe, affordable, and accessible financial services as a U.S. national interest that must inform our approach to digital asset innovation, including disparate impact risk. Such safe access is especially important for communities that have long had insufficient access to financial services.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury, working with all relevant agencies, will produce a report on the future of money and payment systems, to include implications for economic growth, financial growth and inclusion, national security, and the extent to which technological innovation may influence that future.<br></li><li><strong>Support Technological Advances and Ensure Responsible Development and Use of Digital Assets </strong>by directing the U.S. Government to take concrete steps to study and support technological advances in the responsible development, design, and implementation of digital asset systems while prioritizing privacy, security, combating illicit exploitation, and reducing negative climate impacts.<br></li><li><strong>Explore a U.S. Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC) </strong>by placing urgency on research and development of a potential United States CBDC, should issuance be deemed in the national interest. The Order directs the U.S. Government to assess the technological infrastructure and capacity needs for a potential U.S. CBDC in a manner that protects Americans’ interests. The Order also encourages the Federal Reserve to continue its research, development, and assessment efforts for a U.S. CBDC, including development of a plan for broader U.S. Government action in support of their work. This effort prioritizes U.S. participation in multi-country experimentation, and ensures U.S. leadership internationally to promote CBDC development that is consistent with U.S. priorities and democratic values.</li></ul>



<p>The Administration will continue work across agencies and with Congress to establish policies that guard against risks and guide responsible innovation, with our allies and partners to develop aligned international capabilities that respond to national security risks, and with the private sector to study and support technological advances in digital assets.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden on the Return of American Detainees from&#160;Venezuela</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/08/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-return-of-american-detainees-from-venezuela/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 04:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tonight—two Americans who were wrongfully detained in Venezuela will be able to hug their families once more. We are bringing Gustavo Cardenas and Jorge Fernandez home. Cardenas was arrested in 2017 as part of the so-called CITGO-6, and he has endured five years of hardship and imprisonment at the hands of an unjust system. Fernandez&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Tonight—two Americans who were wrongfully detained in Venezuela will be able to hug their families once more.</p>



<p>We are bringing Gustavo Cardenas and Jorge Fernandez home.</p>



<p>Cardenas was arrested in 2017 as part of the so-called CITGO-6, and he has endured five years of hardship and imprisonment at the hands of an unjust system. Fernandez was arrested last year on spurious charges. These men are fathers who lost precious time with their children and everyone they love, and their families have suffered every day of their absence. I am grateful to Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs Roger Carstens and our entire diplomatic team for their tireless efforts to secure their release and reunite these families.</p>



<p>Unjustly holding Americans captive is always unacceptable. And even as we celebrate the return of Cardenas and Fernandez, we also remember the names and the stories of every American who is being unjustly held against their will—in Venezuela, in Russia, in Afghanistan, Syria, China, Iran, and elsewhere around the world. My Administration will keep fighting to bring them all home.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Supporting Veterans as Part of the Unity&#160;Agenda</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/08/remarks-by-president-biden-on-supporting-veterans-as-part-of-the-unity-agenda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Resource Connection of Tarrant CountyFort Worth, Texas 4:05 P.M. CST    THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Please, please, sit down.&#160; Thank you.&#160; I don&#8217;t know who’s coming.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160;I want to thank you, Councilwoman Beck.&#160; You know, look, what I said to her on the way out: The thing that bothers me the most when veterans aren’t looked&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Resource Connection of Tarrant County<br>Fort Worth, Texas</p>



<p>4:05 P.M. CST   </p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Please, please, sit down.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know who’s coming.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank you, Councilwoman Beck.&nbsp; You know, look, what I said to her on the way out: The thing that bothers me the most when veterans aren’t looked out for, because of what we owe them, is every single, solitary veteran deserves to be treated with dignity.&nbsp; They shouldn’t have to ask for a damn thing.&nbsp; It shouldn’t be, “Can you help me?”&nbsp; It’s, “I&#8217;ve got a problem.”&nbsp; And we should say, “How can we help?”<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I thank you for your service.&nbsp; I thank you for all of you who are here for your service.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I hope &#8212; I hope that hearing &#8212; hearing you will inspire more veterans to do exactly what you’re doing: sign up &#8212; sign up for the benefits and support you have earned.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I found with my son, what I found with my friends, what I found with the generation of Vietnam: There’s this notion that you never have to &#8212; you shouldn’t ask for anything.&nbsp; You’re military &#8212; you don’t ask for anything; you just serve.<br>&nbsp;<br>You should be asking.&nbsp; You should be letting us know.&nbsp; You should let us know what is bothering you, what is the problem &#8212; because we owe it to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>It’s great to be here in Fort Worth at the Resource Connection.&nbsp; And I’m able to spend time with Mayor Parker earlier, very briefly.&nbsp; And I want to thank her for the passport into town.&nbsp; And I also want to thank Judge &#8212; Judge Whitley, all &#8212; and all the city and council members &#8212; city council and county council members as well here today.&nbsp; I want to thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I often tell the story: I got elected to the county council in my state. &nbsp;We have a &#8212; we’re like a miniature Illinois.&nbsp; We have one state with 60 percent of the population, so a councilman has a district seven times as big as a House member and three times a big as a state senator.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I did not want to run, but I ran just to show the flag.&nbsp; And, unfortunately, I won.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And they reapportioned me.&nbsp; It was in 1970.&nbsp; I got reapportioned from a four-year term to a two-year term because my &#8212; the opposition party saw more in me than I saw in me.&nbsp; And I was forced into, what we say in public life, “up or out.”&nbsp; And I ended up running for the Senate before I was old enough to be sworn in.&nbsp; I didn’t expect to win that either.&nbsp; And here I am.&nbsp; You’re stuck with me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But &#8212; (applause) &#8212; but the reason I ran for the United States Senate was it was too hard being a county councilman.&nbsp; You’d knock on the door and say, “My name is Joe Biden, Democratic candidate for the county council.”&nbsp; And they’d look at you like &#8212; and you know what they’re thinking.&nbsp; Well, you know part of what they were thinking: “What does county council do?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, you affect people’s lives as much as anybody else.&nbsp; And people go, “County council?”<br>&nbsp;<br>Anyway.&nbsp; But I just think that &#8212; Jake, you’re a fighter pilot.&nbsp; You get this stuff.&nbsp; I mean &#8212; you know what I mean.&nbsp; You can smile, Jake.&nbsp; It’s okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It’s okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Jake is a Republican, but I like the hell out of him.&nbsp; He’s got &#8212; no, I’m serious.&nbsp; This guy is the real deal.<br>&nbsp;<br>The three congressmen you have here &#8212; two of them look like they could &#8212; they really could and did play ball.&nbsp; And the other one looks like he could bomb you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And &#8212; that’s &#8212; it’s a tough group but a good group.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, I want to thank you and your staffs for welcoming us to town.&nbsp; It’s a one-stop shop connection for people in this county to the services and benefits they need.&nbsp; And that’s important.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’m here today to talk about the critical community it serves: our veterans, their families, caregivers, and survivors.<br>&nbsp;<br>I’m joined today by the bipartisan group of Texas Reps that are here and who care deeply about these issues.&nbsp; Congressman Marc Veasey is &#8212; I want to thank him so much for giving me the passport into his district here.&nbsp; And I want to let them know how proud I am to sign into law the bill to create a national monument to Medal of Honor winners and recipients and the values they represented.&nbsp; It was a very important thing you did.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And, Congressman Colin Allred, I want to thank you for your work in the Veterans Affairs committee in the House of Representatives, particularly your leadership dealing with veterans mental health issues.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Congressman Jake Ellzey, a member of the House Veterans Affairs committee, a veteran himself, served 20 years in the United States Navy and multiple combat tours as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Congressmen, thank you all for being here and for allowing me to be with you and continuing to serve our country.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I’ve often said &#8212; and I mean it sincerely, from the bottom of my heart &#8212; veterans are the backbone, the spine, and sinew of who we are in this country.&nbsp; One percent of you these days &#8212; one percent of you serves all the rest of us.&nbsp; And the 99 percent who aren’t with you deserve to treat you with the dignity and respect in service that you deserve.&nbsp; You’re the best of us, and we owe you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ve always believed that &#8212; and I’ve said this from the time I was a young senator &#8212; we have many obligations in the United States Senate and the United States Congress, the President of the United States to the American people &#8212; to the elderly, to the poor, to those in need.&nbsp; But we only have one truly sacred obligation, and I mean this &#8212; sacred obligation &#8212; and that is to train and equip those who we send into harm’s way and care for them and their families when they come home.<br>&nbsp;<br>Only a small percentage, as I said, deserve and can claim the title of veteran.&nbsp; More than 1.4 million of them are living here in Texas.&nbsp; That’s about 6.5 percent of your population.&nbsp; And to be a veteran is to have endured the survival &#8212; and survived challenges most Americans will never know.&nbsp; And you have done it, and you’ve done it for all of us.&nbsp; All of us.<br>&nbsp;<br>A week ago, during my State of the Union message in Washington, I spoke about the bipartisan Unity Agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>Four big things that I think all of us &#8212; Democrats, Republicans, and independents &#8212; can agree on and rally around.<br>&nbsp;<br>One is dealing with the opioid epidemic, which is stealing the lives of so many people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Two: mental health for our children in the wake of all that&#8217;s happened because of COVID and all the &#8212; all the consequences.&nbsp; There&#8217;s over a million people out there who are no longer sitting at the kitchen table this morning because of COVID.&nbsp; And people worry about that &#8212; and the kids particularly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Third is ending cancer as we know it, which I&#8217;m confident we can do.<br>&nbsp;<br>And fourth is supporting our veterans &#8212; fully supporting them.<br>&nbsp;<br>These are the issues that unite us because they impact Americans in every single solitary state &#8212; issues that go beyond partisan politics because they’re about people &#8212; about people, our neighbors.<br>&nbsp;<br>Caring for our veterans has been a central focus of my administration since day one.&nbsp; And for the last year, the Department of Veterans Affairs, led by Secretary McDonough, has been the linchpin &#8212; the linchpin of our government-wide push to make life better for American veterans, providing assistance through this pandemic like job training and housing.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re helping lower-income veterans access VA care debt-free.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re expanding access to healthcare services for women veterans and the LGBTQ community veterans.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re implementing a plan to bring down the rate of suicide among service members and veterans.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s sad to say, but to this day, we average 17 veterans a day commit suicide every single day.&nbsp; More than get killed in combat every single day.&nbsp; It’s an absolute tragedy that demands not only a whole-of-government approach but a whole-of-country working together to deal with this issue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Texas is one of those states particin- &#8212; participating in the Governor&#8217;s and Mayor&#8217;s Challenge to take on this crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as I announced in my State of the Union message, we’re focusing on meeting the specific care and needs for all our veterans who suffer because of their service &#8212; for all our veterans.<br>&nbsp;<br>We learned a horrible lesson after Vietnam.&nbsp; It was harm &#8212; the harmful effects of Agent Orange, which was dropped upon so many thousands of veterans, and the years it took to manifest illnesses in veterans.&nbsp; Because then the veteran had to prove that whatever his problem was was directly a consequence of Agent Orange.<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, we passed a law that I was proud to be a co-sponsor of a long time ago saying that if you were &#8212; if you had Agent Orange drop upon you, it was presumed that the illness you had was a consequence of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And how we were even slower to connect the dots of what&#8217;s happening to those too many Vietnam veterans living in the lurch, unable to access the care they needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>It was only in the past year that we added bladder cancer and conditions of un- &#8212; underactive thyroid and Parkinson&#8217;s to the list of conditions tied to Agent Orange exposure, as science told us more, decades after the exposure took place.<br>&nbsp;<br>It took far too long to reach that decision, in my view.&nbsp; And I refuse to repeat the mistake when it comes to the veterans of our Iraq and Afghans- &#8212; Afghan wars.<br>&nbsp;<br>Not only they &#8212; they faced the dangers on battlefield, but they were breathing toxic smoke in burn pits where they&#8217;re &#8212; near where they were based.&nbsp; I was in and out of Afghanistan and Iraq 23 times.&nbsp; I spent a fair amount of time there as a United States senator and as Vice President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The burn pits that incinerate the wastes of war &#8212; medical and hazardous material, jet fuel, and so much more &#8212; just dug in big pits where &#8212; not far from &#8212; the hooch is not far from where our veterans were sleeping.<br>&nbsp;<br>And when our troops came home, the fittest among them, the greatest fighting force in the history of the world, too many of them were not the same.&nbsp; Headaches, dizziness, numbness, dizziness, cancer.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we know &#8212; we don’t yet know enough about the connection between burn pits and each of these diseases so many of our veterans are now facing.&nbsp; But I’m committed &#8212; I&#8217;m committed that America make the commitment to find out everything we can.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m committed to the families like Danielle Robinson, the widow of Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson, who joined my wife Jill in the Vice Pre- &#8212; in the First Lady&#8217;s box at the State of the Union.<br>&nbsp;<br>Sergeant Robinson was born a soldier.&nbsp; National &#8212; Army National Guard.&nbsp; Combat medic in Kosovo and Iraq.&nbsp; Stationed at the same bases and at around the same exact time as my son Major Beau Biden, United States Army.<br>&nbsp;<br>In Baghdad, Sergeant Robinson was stationed yards from burn pits the size of football fields.<br>&nbsp;<br>And back home in Ohio, Danielle and their little girl waited for him to come home &#8212; to coach the soccer team, to build Legos.&nbsp; But when he finally came home, cancer &#8212; likely caused by prolonged exposure to the burn pits &#8212; ravaged his lungs and his body.<br>&nbsp;<br>A soldier who could bench press 315 pounds, squat 400 pounds, and run two miles in 12 minutes would be bent over in the bathroom, gasping for air.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Danielle, working full-time, turned to become a 24/7 caregiver, scared to leave him alone for even a minute.<br>&nbsp;<br>He was just 39 years old when he was held &#8212; she held his hand as he took his last breath.<br>&nbsp;<br>But Daniel [sic] said he &#8212; Danielle said he never stopped fighting and neither did she.&nbsp; She kept fighting for his memory, in his memory &#8212; for our veterans and their families that are going through the same thing today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Families like hers, like so many of yours &#8212; you’re the reason why we’re doing everything we can.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ve increased funding for VA research to study the health effects of toxic exposure in the military.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re speeding up the process to identify and address adverse impacts of military-related environmental exposures.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re following the science in every case, but we’re also not going to force veterans to suffer in limbo for decades if the science is eve- &#8212; even if it&#8217;s evenly divided.<br>&nbsp;<br>When the evidence doesn’t give a clear answer one way or another, the decision we should favor is caring for veterans while we continue working to learn more &#8212; not waiting, not waiting.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I directed &#8212; I directed the VA to move quickly to review more of the cancers and provide determinations of whether or not they are presumed to be service-connected within 90 days.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, by the way, you saw what happened in the &#8212; what happened when &#8212; at 9/11 when the buildings went down in New York.&nbsp; You saw the thousands of firefighters who, in fact, were &#8212; because of the toxic smoke they inhaled &#8212; finally, finally, because of some of the people in the media and in entertainment insisted that they be compensated for.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, when diseases are so rare that there isn’t enough evidence, we’ll examine other factors as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>And this week, Secretary McDonough is developing a new rule that will add several rare respiratory cancers to the list of presumptive conditions for certain veterans.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also need to know more about which of our veterans may have been exposed to burn pits in the first place or other environmental toxins during their service, to record possible exposures before service members separate from the military.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we’re building a more comprehensive database from the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs to use to track access to exposures.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re working hard to educate everyone across the VA system about the potential impact of specialized care needed for burn pit exposure, urging veterans to sign up for the VA burn pit registry and to make sure we know about them &#8212; they know about the benefits that may be available to them.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, what I’ve found about veterans as we worked for those who are trying to deal with the mental health problems, is they’re used to always giving &#8212; you don’t think you have a right to ask for anything.&nbsp; You don’t think you have a right to ask.&nbsp; We’re asking you &#8212; asking you to tell us.&nbsp; Tell us where you’ve been.&nbsp; Tell us what your needs are.&nbsp; It&#8217;s nothing to be ashamed of; it’s to be proud of.&nbsp; We owe you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Improving training for VA providers to make sure they’re equipped to diagnose and treat exposures to related conditions.<br>&nbsp;<br>And this year, launching a new wo- &#8212; network of special care &#8212; specialized care providers and call centers to help connect veterans with questions about exposure to care that is consistent, comprehensive, and high quality.<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, these are the kinds of steps that can make a difference in getting the proper care for more patients and providing support for veterans, especially those facing a cancer diagnosis.<br>&nbsp;<br>And every one of you know the earlier cancer is diagnosed, the greater the prospect of dealing with it, the greater the pa- &#8212; the prospect of curing it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It reinforces the new goal of my Cancer Moonshot to cut cancer deaths &#8212; the death rate by 50 percent over the next 25 years at a minimum, to create a more supportive experience for all the patients and families.<br>&nbsp;<br>Secretary McDonough is part of my newly formed Cancer Cabinet.&nbsp; The Department of Veterans Affairs is an essential part of our whole-of-government initiative because we’re going to invest billions of dollars solving this problem &#8212; to turn cancers from death sentences into treatable diseases.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These are all things my administration is moving on.&nbsp; We’re not waiting.&nbsp; We’re not waiting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But some of the most important next steps need congressional action.&nbsp; Both the United States House of Representatives and the Senate have bills in motion that would extend the eligibility period for VA care for burn pit-related health impacts from 5 years after leaving the military to a minimum of 10 years.&nbsp; That would open enrollment to all veterans who served in Iraq and Afghanistan.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, in February, the Senate passed their bill to do just that, unanimously &#8212; Democrat and Republican.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the House bill that passed just last week would do even more: expanding healthcare, mandating research, reforming the process for determining presumptions, and adding more conditions to the list of presumptive care.<br>&nbsp;<br>Both these bills have bipartisan support.&nbsp; These are bills that unite the American people.&nbsp; These are the bills that will deliver necessary care for our veterans and their families.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let’s get those bills to my desk so I can sign them immediately &#8212; immediately.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, we have a sacred obligation as a nation.<br>&nbsp;<br>I promised Danielle Robinson and I promise all of you here today that we’ll do better.&nbsp; We must.&nbsp; We owe you.&nbsp; We owe you.<br>&nbsp;<br>I can&#8217;t say enough about the veterans community.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a famous expression by a famous English poet who said, “They also serve who only stand and wait.”<br>&nbsp;<br>To every husband and wife of the deployed &#8212; of the deployed husband or wife, to every child with a mom or dad deployed: We owe you.&nbsp; We owe you, because they also serve who only stand and wait.<br>&nbsp;<br>I remember the head of the National Guard in the State of Delaware wife used to say a prayer.&nbsp; When my son got deployed &#8212; my wife was a school teacher who got up earlier than I did to get to school.&nbsp; I&#8217;d get to the train &#8212; the 7:30 train.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d walk downstairs.&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t be &#8212; I&#8217;d just be &#8212; I’d just had shaved and have my trousers on to get a cup of coffee.&nbsp; She&#8217;d be standing over the sink, like many of you have done, looking out the window mouthing a prayer that she was given by the commander’s wife &#8212; a prayer &#8212; a prayer for her son who was in harm’s way.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All of you did that.&nbsp; All of you do that.&nbsp; All of you worry about that call.&nbsp; So, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Concluding point I’ll make &#8212; and we talked about it, the Congressman and I, on the way down: You know, this is an incredible generation &#8212; the 9/11 generation that fought.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They served in a way, I think, that maybe they&#8217;re right up there with the Greatest Generation, because they not only got deployed once, but sometimes twice, three, four times into harm’s way.&nbsp; They&#8217;d come home and go back, and after knowing that they cleaned off the blood of the seat of that up-armored Humvee that they &#8212; where they lost somebody.&nbsp; And they’d have to saddle up and go back out again.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>An enormous generation.&nbsp; An incredible generation.<br>&nbsp;<br>I was telling the guys on the way down I remember flying into Iraq one of those times, and I went up in the cop- &#8212; the cockpit.&nbsp; And there were, I believe, seven members &#8212; six members: five men and one women &#8212; one woman.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I asked the question of all of them.&nbsp; I said, “How many is this your first tour of duty?”&nbsp; Nobody raised their hand.&nbsp; “Second tour of duty?”&nbsp; Nobody.&nbsp; “Third tour?”&nbsp; Two of them.&nbsp; “Fourth tour?”&nbsp; Two of them.&nbsp; “Fifth tour?”&nbsp; One.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>No other generation has been deployed, redeployed, and redeployed, and redeployed.&nbsp; It takes nothing away from the World War One and World War Two and Vietnam generations.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s one thing to serve and come home and then go back, and go back, and go back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we owe you.&nbsp; We owe you all, every veteran in here and every family member of a veteran.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops. Thank you for all you do.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>4:25 P.M. CST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Shooting at East High&#160;School</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/08/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-shooting-at-east-high-school/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48683</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday afternoon, as the school day was coming to a close, three students were shot in a drive-by shooting outside East High School in Des Moines, Iowa. One young man—just 15 years old—was tragically killed. Jill and I pray for his family and for everyone impacted by yet another senseless act of gun violence. A&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday afternoon, as the school day was coming to a close, three students were shot in a drive-by shooting outside East High School in Des Moines, Iowa. One young man—just 15 years old—was tragically killed. Jill and I pray for his family and for everyone impacted by yet another senseless act of gun violence.</p>



<p>A half dozen suspects have been arrested for their alleged involvement in the shooting, and we are grateful to Des Moines law enforcement and first responders for their quick work and professionalism.</p>



<p>But these swift arrests cannot obscure the reality that too many families have had to bury a piece of their soul after yet another tragic shooting. It comes less than a month after we marked four years since the shooting at Marjorie Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida, and three months after the shooting at Oxford High School in Oakland County, Michigan. Between these tragedies are shootings that happen every day without making headlines.</p>



<p>Enough. Our young people should be safe in and around school, in their neighborhoods, and in their homes. Every American should be able to visit a house of worship, a grocery store, a night club, or any other place without fear of being gunned down. That too many cannot is a stain on our national character and an urgent call to action.</p>



<p>Last June, I put forward a comprehensive national strategy to reduce gun violence. In carrying out this strategy, I have taken more executive action to reduce gun violence than any other president in their first year in office—more than a dozen necessary actions, from cracking down on gun trafficking and rogue gun dealers, to promoting safe firearm storage, to reining in the proliferation of hard-to-trace “ghost guns” that can be bought online and made at home.  Now, Congress must do its job. As I reiterated in my State of the Union address last week, it is up to Congress to pass proven measures to reduce gun violence—including universal background checks, a ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, and a repeal of the liability shield protecting gun manufacturers who knowingly put weapons of war on our streets. These laws don’t infringe on the Second Amendment, but they will save lives.<br>May God bless the lives that have been lost or forever altered.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Air Force One&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/08/remarks-by-president-biden-after-air-force-one-arrival-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 22:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48674</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Naval Air Station Fort Worth Joint Reserve BaseWestworth Village, Texas &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, do you have a message for the American people on gas prices? &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; They&#8217;re going to go up.&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; What can you do about it? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Can&#8217;t do much right now. &#160;Russia is responsible.  END]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Naval Air Station Fort Worth Joint Reserve Base<br>Westworth Village, Texas</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you have a message for the American people on gas prices?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to go up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What can you do about it?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Can&#8217;t do much right now. &nbsp;Russia is responsible.</p>



<p> END</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Deputy National Security Advisor for Cyber and Emerging Technology Anne Neuberger on President&#160;Biden’s Cyber Executive&#160;Order</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/08/statement-by-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-cyber-and-emerging-technology-anne-neuberger-on-president-bidens-cyber-executive-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 22:08:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48671</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President’s Executive Order, Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity, charted a new course for nation’s cybersecurity. And, we have begun implementation of one of the most important components of the Executive Order. As of yesterday, every company that sells software to the government must have a rigorous software security program in place.&#160;The requirement covers traditional commercial&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President’s Executive Order, <em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/12/fact-sheet-president-signs-executive-order-charting-new-course-to-improve-the-nations-cybersecurity-and-protect-federal-government-networks/">Improving the Nation’s Cybersecurity</a></em>, charted a new course for nation’s cybersecurity. And, we have begun implementation of one of the most important components of the Executive Order. As of yesterday, every company that sells software to the government must have a rigorous software security program in place.&nbsp;The requirement covers traditional commercial on-premise software, software provided as a service, as well as any included open source software components.</p>



<p>We know Americans are concerned about cybersecurity – we’ve seen the cost of ransomware attacks to businesses of all sizes and the disruption it has caused to critical services in countries around the world. And we know that a foundational part of building cyber resilience is building in security throughout the lifecycle of a product, from the initial design phase through deployment. We buy a car with pre-installed seatbelts and airbags. We should be able to buy software with security baked in. With the implementation of this component of the Executive Order, the federal government is leveraging its procurement power to improve the security of the software that we all use – including software we install in some of our nation’s most critical infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We thank NIST and our private sector partners for their collaboration to develop the Secure Software Development Framework (SSDF) which NIST published last month.&nbsp;The SSDF contains a set of practices that create the foundation for developing secure software, which every company that sells software to the government must now follow. We also thank OMB for working with the private sector over the next 60 days to outline guidance for how companies will attest their compliance with the SSDF, as they sell software to the United States Government.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Chile to Attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Gabriel Boric&#160;Font</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/08/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-republic-of-chile-to-attend-the-inauguration-of-his-excellency-gabriel-boric-font/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to Valparaíso, Chile to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Gabriel Boric Font as President of the Republic of Chile on March 11, 2022. The Honorable Isabella Casillas Guzman, Administrator of the U.S. Small Business Administration, will lead the delegation. Members of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to Valparaíso, Chile to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Gabriel Boric Font as President of the Republic of Chile on March 11, 2022.<br><br>The Honorable Isabella Casillas Guzman, Administrator of the U.S. Small Business Administration, will lead the delegation.<br><br><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong><br><br>Mr. Richard Glenn, Chargé d’Affaires, a.i., U.S. Embassy Santiago<br><br>The Honorable Brian A. Nichols, Assistant Secretary for Western Hemisphere Affairs, U.S. Department of State<br><br>Ms. Isabel Allende, Award-winning Chilean-American Author and Chilean National Literature Prize Recipient</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/08/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 21:27:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Fort Worth, Texas 2:08 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Hello.&#160; Okay, welcome to our trip to Fort Worth, Texas.&#160; Just a couple items for you at the top.&#160; As I mentioned yesterday, this week we are marking the one-year anniversary of the American Rescue Plan.&#160; Today, we’re focusing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Fort Worth, Texas</p>



<p>2:08 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Okay, welcome to our trip to Fort Worth, Texas.&nbsp; Just a couple items for you at the top.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I mentioned yesterday, this week we are marking the one-year anniversary of the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Today, we’re focusing on the historic tax relief in the American Rescue Plan which is helping lower costs faced by working Americans.</p>



<p>Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, Americans have received the largest-ever Child Tax Credit, the largest-ever Earned Income Tax Credit for workers without dependent children, and the largest-ever Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit, which will help families meet the high cost of care. </p>



<p>Today, we’re providing new state-by-state analysis of how many families and children will be reached by this historic tax relief.&nbsp; And we’ll have more tomorrow.</p>



<p>Also, as you all know, last week, in the President’s State of the Union address, he talked about the sacred obligation we have as a country to our veterans.&nbsp; And that could be &#8212; not be more true or relevant than right now.</p>



<p>Addressing veterans’ health issues is a bipartisan issue and a core pillar of the President’s Unity Agenda.&nbsp; He’s pushing for us to understand more about military exposures and their relation to nine additional rare cancers, and called on Congress to send him a bill he will &#8212; him a bill he will sign.</p>



<p>Today, he is traveling with a bipartisan group of lawmakers to address this important, unifying issue.&nbsp; We think it shows how seriously he takes this and that he’s following through on a key commitment to unifying the country.&nbsp; Texas is home &#8212; and he’s actually meeting with a number of them right now on the plane.</p>



<p>Texas is home to the second-largest population of veterans in the United States, many of whom rely upon the VA for services and benefits.  Nearly 55 percent of veterans in Texas served in the era when burn pits were used.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Finally, one year ago today, on International Women’s Day, the President issued an executive order establishing the White House Gender Policy Council and charged it with leading a government-wide effort to advance gender equity and equality both at home and abroad.</p>



<p>In the year since, the Biden administration has taken significant steps to advance equal rights and opportunity &#8212; from taking on gender-based violence wherever it occurs, to protecting women’s health, to ensuring that women and families have economic security &#8212; and laid out an ambitious agenda in the first-ever National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality.</p>



<p>And today, we announced that the President’s FY23 budget will request $2.6 billion for foreign assistance programs that promote gender equality worldwide, more than doubling the amount requested just last year.</p>



<p>Josh, why don’t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Americans right now know that they&#8217;re paying a higher price because of the sanctions against Russia.  Oil was up 7 percent when we boarded Air Force One on the day.  What is the specific price that the ban puts on Putin, and how does it deter him in a way that the previous sanctions did not?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that Americans are paying a higher price at the pump because of the actions of President Putin.&nbsp; This is a Putin spike at the gas pump, not one prompted by our sanctions.</p>



<p>We have seen, since President Putin and the Russian military lined up earlier this year troops at the border, an increase of about 75 cents on average across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of what impact this will have, this is continuing to build on the steps that the President has taken in coordination with our European partners to squeeze the financial system in Russia, to squeeze the circle around President Putin, and to send a clear message that we are going to continue to press and squeeze on the system to hopefully change the behavior over the course of time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a dollar amount that you think you&#8217;re able to extract from the Russian economy through the ban?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t have a prediction along those lines, Josh.&nbsp; I certainly understand why you&#8217;re asking.&nbsp; I think, as you know and others who track the Russian markets closely know, they have not even opened the stock market.&nbsp; The ruble is at a record low.&nbsp; They have enormous financial challenges.&nbsp; They&#8217;re heading into, you know, a version of a financial recession in Russia, according to outside economists.</p>



<p>So this step is meant to build on the steps we have taken to date from the United States and from the global community.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, what can the administration do to protect Americans against the kind of price gouging that the President spoke about today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say one of the steps we can take is to make clear what is and isn&#8217;t impacting gas prices and what the oil companies can do and have a responsibility to do.&nbsp; And you heard the President talk about that today.</p>



<p>So let me give you an example: There have been some, including the American Petroleum Institute, who have claimed that this is an issue of having access or funds.  The oil and gas industry has a lot of permits; onshore alone, more than 9,000 unused approved permits to drill. </p>



<p>And I would note that only 10 percent of drilling is happening on federal lands; the other 90 percent is on private lands.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m talking about the 10 percent in that case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the argument that there are just no opportunities to drill for oil is just not true.&nbsp; The phenomenon that we&#8217;re actually seeing is much more about firms wanting to return cash to investors than about a lack of opportunity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, part of what the President can do and we can all do is inform and educate the American public about what the facts are here.&nbsp; This is not a lack of places to drill.&nbsp; This is not a lack of access to oil.&nbsp; In fact, last year, we produced more oil and gas in the United States than the first year of the Trump administration.&nbsp; Next year is predicted to be the largest year on record of oil and gas production.&nbsp; That is not the issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s really up to the oil companies to determine whether they are going to &#8212; as well as Wall Street &#8212; whether they&#8217;re going to reinvest these war profits from high prices back into the economy, raise production, and lower prices to American consumers.  And that pressure should be on them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the timeframe for implementation of these new restrictions on imports?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So it will ban new contracts.&nbsp; And then for contracts that are existing, it will be &#8212; they’ll have 45 days to deliver on those.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another question on House Democrats seeming to plan to still move forward with their bill that will &#8212; that has an energy component to it that sounds very similar to what the President announced, as well as a piece on looking at Russia&#8217;s involvement with the WTO and some expansion of Magnitsky.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What is the administration&#8217;s take on what the House Democrats are doing?&nbsp; And did the President feel at all pressured by members of Congress of both parties and in both chambers to move fairly quickly on his own lest he be boxed in by legislation that might be more complicated to implement than what he was proposing?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, we welcome the support of members of Congress for the President&#8217;s announcement this morning &#8212; Democrats and Republicans who have announced support for his efforts.&nbsp; We are working in close coordination with Speaker Pelosi and other leaders in Congress on a shared objective, which is to take steps that will maximize the impact on President Putin and the Russian economy, and minimize it on the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What the President’s priority and focus has been from the beginning and he has discussed with a range of members is ensuring that we are taking steps in close coordination with the Europeans, our partners.&nbsp; Now, we did not expect nor did we ask them to take the same step that we announced this morning.&nbsp; They have a &#8212; you know, different capabilities and different capacities than we do.</p>



<p>Even if you look at data that is &#8212; we have available, which is from 2021, we only imported about 10 percent of our oil from Russia.&nbsp; The Europeans, it&#8217;s more like a third; it&#8217;s much higher &#8212; about 450 barrels &#8212; million barrels per day as opposed to 700,000 for the United States.&nbsp; We recognize that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But at the same time, taking steps to act in a coordinated way to ensure we&#8217;re discussing with them the steps we&#8217;re considering in taking, and doing that in a way that does not add to greater, you know, volatility in the oil markets is a shared objective.&nbsp; So, we welcome the steps they&#8217;ve taken.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, in terms of the WTO specifics, Ambassador Tai has been obviously engaging with other WTO countries.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a unilateral step the United States could take or the President could take, but we will continue those conversations as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you outline some of the things that the administration is considering to help blunt the impact on consumers of these higher fuel prices?&nbsp; Do they include waiving the gasoline tax?&nbsp; Do they include waiving the Jones Act?&nbsp; Do they include lifting environmental specs on fuel?&nbsp; Are those things that you are considering as you look at trying to help consumers?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, there are a range that we are considering.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give you a nod or a wink to any specifics, other than to say that &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, come on.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; there are a range of options on the table.&nbsp; As you all know, we are engaging in ongoing conversations with large, global energy suppliers as a part of it.&nbsp; Part of that effort has also been to do this coordinated release of what will be 90 million barrels from the Strategic Petroleum &#8212; Petroleum Reserve &#8212; excuse me &#8212; this fiscal year, including the initial announcement and then the one we just made last week, I believe it was.&nbsp; So those conversations are ongoing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would also note that part of our &#8212; the capacity out here is with the oil companies who have these approved permits that are unused, where they could do more.&nbsp; Now, some CEOs have indicated that they do plan to increase production, and that&#8217;s something that, to meet the supply needs we have now, we certainly would welcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say the last piece of this, in addition to a range of domestic options we&#8217;ll continue to consider and discuss, is that we&#8217;re working with Europe to ensure we&#8217;re &#8212; we are all diversifying our energy security measures.&nbsp; And this is maybe a longer-term step, but this is a reminder of how important it is to do that &#8212; to reduce our dependence on fossil fuels, on foreign oil, on Russia, and on the whims of dictators, as we have found ourselves in in this moment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One question about Iran as well.&nbsp; They &#8212; their negotiator has said that they are going to stick with their red lines.&nbsp; And one thing that they have asked or &#8212; they want some certainty that if they do end up going through with this agreement, that another administration can&#8217;t come in and walk out of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What &#8212; how does the U.S. guarantee that?&nbsp; Is that even possible?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s an interesting question, Jeff.&nbsp; I mean, I think that, you know, if you look at what&#8217;s happened over the last several years, you had &#8212; obviously, it was &#8212; it was &#8212; the Iran nuclear deal was initially approved and moved forward under the Obama-Biden administration.&nbsp; When former President Trump pulled out of the deal, we&#8217;ve seen the dire impact that that has led to, including a lack of visibility into their program; they have made significant progress toward acquiring a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think that, hopefully, Democrats and Republicans of all stripes will recognize what a mistake that was.&nbsp; And if we are &#8212; do get back into the Iran nuclear deal &#8212; something we are close on, although it&#8217;s always final details that you have to work through &#8212; you know, certainly our hope would be and the message we&#8217;d be sending to the world is that this is in not only global interests but in our U.S. national interest regardless of who is sitting in the White House.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;Secretary Blinken is finishing up a five-day trip to Europe.&nbsp; He&#8217;s meeting with Macron today.&nbsp; He met with the leaders of Baltic states, Moldova, Poland, the Israeli Foreign Minister.&nbsp; What would you say are the accomplishments of this trip?&nbsp; And are these diplomatic efforts going to extend to U.S. adversaries like Venezuela?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think those are slight &#8212; well, let me take the first question first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re broadly, of course, supportive of efforts of our partners and allies &#8212; including France, Germany, Israel, Turkey, and others &#8212; to seek a diplomatic resolution.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A number of the countries and leaders you&#8217;ve mentioned the Secretary of State has met with recently over the last couple of days but also we&#8217;ve been in touch with either prior to or following &#8212; or both, in many cases &#8212; their conversations with both Russians as well as Ukrainians, who we&#8217;re encouraging them to also engage with.&nbsp; And we maintain open and regular high-level channels of communications with all of these partners.</p>



<p>As it relates to Venezuela, I would say &#8212; I would take that question slightly separately, in that, you know, there are a range &#8212; there was obviously a recent trip that was reported and we confirmed.&nbsp; There were a range of topics discussed during that trip, including the health and welfare of detained U.S. citizens.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But beyond that, those conversations are ongoing and I just don&#8217;t have anything to update you on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re flying to Texas.&nbsp; There are a couple of Texans who are held in Russia right now: Trevor Reed and Brittney Griner.&nbsp; Is the White House involved at all in negotiating their release, getting their release?&nbsp; And also, does the White House fear that more Americans are going to be used as pawns in this global conflict?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, on the second individual you named, we&#8217;ve obviously seen the reports.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a Privacy Act waiver, so I cannot speak to that case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the case of Trevor Reed, I can tell you that our National Security Advisor met with his family back in the fall and that we are working on a time for the President to meet with his family over the short term as well.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a time or date on that or anything like that, but that is something we are going to work toward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, there is a question from the print pool on that.&nbsp; Why isn&#8217;t the President meeting with Trevor Reed’s family today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that we are working toward setting up a meeting with his family.&nbsp; The President is looking forward to doing that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And again, our National Security Advisor met with his family back in the fall, but it wasn&#8217;t &#8212; we weren&#8217;t able to make it happen on this trip.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to Venezuela.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been significant bipartisan concern expressed about the fact that there are even conversations happening with the Maduro government at this stage.&nbsp; Can you be more specific about what the conversations are with respect to energy and any tradeoffs that might be on the table to encourage Venezuela to produce more oil?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are really not specifics &#8212; additional specifics I can add at this point.&nbsp; I would just note that any conversation about the health and wellbeing of American citizens happens through different channels.&nbsp; So I wouldn&#8217;t see it as a tradeoff, as you said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note also that you may have seen Maduro announced this morning his intention to go back into talks with the opposition.&nbsp; So, I would just note that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It feels like, with Saudi &#8212; like, I want to ask you about Saudi Arabia because it feels like, especially compared to Venezuela, that&#8217;s a country with much greater capacity to backfill global energy supplies than Venezuela.&nbsp; Is there disappointment or are there ongoing talks with the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia about freeing up more reserves, potentially, to enable Europe to go further with cutting off Russian energy?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that, as you know, the President spoke with King Salman last month, made clear that we share important interests: deterring Iranian proxy attacks against civilians, ending the war in Yemen, ensuring the stability of global energy supplies as part of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he is very focused on &#8212; the President is very focused on the situation in front of us and what he can do to improve the security and prosperity of Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I would also note that, in addition to that call, Brett McGurk and Amos Hochstein traveled to the region and had a conversation about all of those topics just a few weeks ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those conversations are going, they will continue, but I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you at this point.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) more recent conversations, though, since the war in Ukraine began.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out for you at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, you spoke yesterday about the United States&#8217; openness to backfill planes to Poland if they send jets to Ukraine.&nbsp; Is that something that the Vice President will be discussing, helping to negotiate or coordinate while she&#8217;s in Poland this week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, the Vice President&#8217;s trip to Poland and to Europe is part of our effort to show our strong support for our NATO Allies and partners, the security assistance they&#8217;ve been providing, their role in accepting and welcoming refugees from Ukraine.&nbsp; This is certainly a topic that has been discussed by the President with his counterpart as recently as a couple days ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note, as I said yesterday, it&#8217;s obviously a decision by Poland, a sovereign country, to make about delivering planes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There were some logistical questions &#8212; important ones &#8212; that were still under discussion about where those planes would take off from and land, and then there are questions that are probably best &#8212; best suited for the Department of Defense about the procurement of planes to backfill, because typically that takes a couple of years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President mentioned today that he sent Secretary Blinken to the border of Poland and Ukraine to see firsthand what was happening.&nbsp; Will he also send the Vice President to that same border while she&#8217;s on her trip to report back firsthand to him?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, Francesca.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have the details on her trip at this point in time.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure they will be doing a backgrounder on additional steps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, the important role that Poland has been playing as a neighboring country in welcoming hundreds of thousands of refugees from Ukraine into their country is something that the Vice President will note and will thank them for personally when she is on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, Senator Grassley has expressed some concerns about the pace at which Chairman Durbin and Leader Schumer are planning to move ahead on the Supreme Court confirmation process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, I know that the White House has in the past been very supportive of that.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;re closely coordinated, so I assume the same is true now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But do you think that there should be a return to a pace more like the pre-Barrett pace?&nbsp; And, yes, I know that some of the others in the past were in this 25-ish-day range, but do you think that &#8212; is there any consideration in the White House of just slowing things down a bit, just by a few days or a week, to kind of stave off some of that criticism?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, if you look at the data and numbers from the past nominees and how long it has &#8212; took, we are much close- &#8212; what we&#8217;re doing is much closer to the timeframe for Justice Ginsburg, which was about 28 days.&nbsp; Justice Barrett was 13.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s slower than Sandra Day O&#8217;Connor&#8217;s, which was 21 days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the pace through which &#8212; and we are working, of course, in lockstep and close coordination with leaders on the Hill &#8212; is very much in line with the majority of nominees in recent history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Irish Times had a report that the United Nations communications office was telling its employees not to call what&#8217;s going on in Ukraine a &#8220;war&#8221; or an &#8220;invasion.&#8221;&nbsp; Does the White House have any advice for the United Nations or anyone else on what to call what is happening in Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the United Nations has put out a clarifying statement on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on oil.&nbsp; Is the White House prepared for the oil price to go as high as $200 a barrel or something really, really high like that?&nbsp; And if so, what preparations are you making to help the American economy against that kind of a hit?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you encourage Americans to stay home the same way they might’ve been doing through the pandemic so that they&#8217;re just driving less or working from home, for instance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re neither going to make a prediction nor are we going to tell Americans to stay home.&nbsp; What the President is focused on is taking a range of steps to mitigate the impact.</p>



<p>Obviously, we&#8217;ve seen, as I noted a little bit earlier, an increase since President Putin invaded Ukraine of about 75 cents.&nbsp; That is &#8212; you know, over the course of the timeline, we&#8217;ve seen that in relation to, you know, concern in the oil mar- &#8212; in the global oil markets about what they&#8217;re seeing, which is an invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but we believe that the impact of this oil ban we announced today will be not long term.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re working to do is to take steps to mitigate it, which is, in part, the release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, continuing to coordinate and communicate with global energy suppliers, and continuing to consider a range of options.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Today, Judge Jackson is meeting with some Republicans, including Senator Scott as well as Senator Collins.&nbsp; Does the White House realistically think that those Republicans will vote for Judge Jackson?&nbsp; And besides those one-on-one meetings, what is the White House doing to earn support from Republicans?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that, first, Judge Jackson has been doing her homework and hard at work since the moment she was announced as the nominee.&nbsp; She started prepping for hearings and prepping for these meetings even the weekend after she announced, which probably doesn&#8217;t surprise anyone given her exemplary record and background.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She has conveyed and expressed an openness, as has the team, to meeting with a broad range of Democrats and Republicans, of course, on the committee and beyond.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s up to them to decide who they&#8217;re going to vote for, of course, but she is somebody who has been confirmed three times by the Senate in a bipartisan manner.&nbsp; She is someone who has ruled in favor of Democrats and Republicans, served under Democrats and Republicans, and very much in the model of Justice Breyer.</p>



<p>So, we believe she deserves bipartisan support.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s was a letter from former national security officials talking about a limited no-fly zone over humanitarian corridors.&nbsp; Is that something that the White House would consider if it&#8217;s not considering a full-on no-fly zone over all of Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, a limited no-fly zone would still require implementation of a no-fly zone, even if it&#8217;s a smaller geography, which would still require shooting down Russian planes if they fly into your no-fly zone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that would still have &#8212; we would still have concerns about that being an escalatory action that could lead us into a war with Russia, which is not something the President intends to do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, there was a line in the readout yesterday of the President&#8217;s conversations with the German, French, UK leaders about the leaders downloading, essentially, their respective engagements with President Zelenskyy as well as President Putin.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve been clear that the U.S does not believe now is the time for President Biden to engage directly with President Putin, but is President Macron essentially acting as an intermediary at this point?&nbsp; Is the President using his conversations with President Macron to send messages to President Putin in any way?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t say that the President &#8212; there are a range of global leaders who are engaging directly with President Putin.&nbsp; President Macron is one of them, but so is Prime Minister Bennett.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(The plane experiences turbulence.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Whoa.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen &#8212; so &#8212; sorry, that was quite a &#8212; for those listening, that was a little bit of a lurch there.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve seen a number of leaders express an openness to, plans to engage.&nbsp; And we welcome that and encourage that.&nbsp; And we have been, through the process, very closely coordinated with all of these leaders who have been engaging directly with President Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we have been doing is encouraging them &#8212; and for the most part, they&#8217;ve done this &#8212; to also engage directly with President Zelenskyy as they, you know, play any role in diplomacy.</p>



<p>But I wouldn&#8217;t put it on one leader.&nbsp; There are a range of leaders who are playing important roles here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any opportunity through the P5+1 conversations &#8212; are U.S. officials engaging with their Russian counterparts on any matters related to Ukraine, even in the context of those discussions with Iran?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Those conversations are about the Iran nuclear deal and preventing Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon, which even as we have significant, serious concerns about the horrific and barbaric invasion that President Putin is leading, we believe we do share a desire to prevent Iran from acquiring a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President spoken to any European leaders since that joint call yesterday morning?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve put out the readouts of any calls he&#8217;s had.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he said this morning, when he was going into the event, that he had just gotten off the phone.&nbsp; So those weren&#8217;t with world leaders?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I believe that was with members of Congress this morning.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can double check, but we have put out readouts for any calls he&#8217;s had.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are the next steps on the anti-lynching bill?&nbsp; When does the President intend to sign?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me just give you a little bit more on this for your records.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s long past time that our federal laws recognize lynching for the abomination and the stain on the soul of this country that it is.&nbsp; And yesterday, Congress, for the first time in more than 100 years, after more than 200 tries, made lynching a federal crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This historic moment would not have happened without the bipartisan efforts that started with the Vice President &#8212; then Senator Harris; Senator Booker; and Congressman Bobby Rush, who worked to build support in the House and Senate to make this day a reality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President looks forward to signing this historic bill into law with the Vice President by his side.&nbsp; As you know, he&#8217;s obviously traveling today.&nbsp; She&#8217;s traveling.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have an update on exactly when, but hopefully it will be &#8212; the plan would be for it to be when they can both be there in person.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a COVID question.&nbsp; I know the White House released yesterday that the President had tested negative again for the coronavirus.&nbsp; Now that we’re in a more maskless environment &#8212; I’m sure the President will largely not be wearing one today &#8212; is there plans for the White House to test the President more regularly and disclose the results of those tests more regularly?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He is tested on a regular basis.&nbsp; The last time was Sunday.&nbsp; It&#8217;s typically about once a week, but it&#8217;s a determination made by his doctor.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of any changes to that protocol.&nbsp; The only protocol that&#8217;s changed is masking.</p>



<p>Let me give you a little bit of an update on today because there&#8217;s just different rules in different facilities too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, outside, the President will not be masking.&nbsp; At the VA facility, he will abide by the VA facility’s mask requirement and wear a mask, as we all will as well.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll join him in the masking requirement.&nbsp; And at the community center, he will not be masking.&nbsp; So, some of this is there are different restrictions and requirements in different facilities, which we’ll continue to abide by.&nbsp; And this is a “yellow zone” that we are traveling to.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, do you have a comment on the Supreme Court ruling yesterday upholding congressional maps in Pennsylvania and North Carolina?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me check and see if there&#8217;s something we have to offer you on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And staying on the subject of Texas for a moment, is there anything more you can tell us about the Biden administration&#8217;s efforts to keep the state of Texas from implementing a directive on care for transgender children?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that the steps we&#8217;ve seen in Texas and Florida are deeply concerning and are having &#8212; are discriminating against exactly the kind of kids who we need to be loving and supporting.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; and I reference Florida because, as you know, they just recently passed a similar hateful bill that hurt some of the students most in need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of any legal actions, I&#8217;d obviously point you to the Department of Justice.&nbsp; But I would just note that the President, the Secretary of Education, many members of the administration have spoken out about the discriminatory nature of these bills and our deep concerns about the message they&#8217;re sending to LGBTQ kids and families.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned Florida.&nbsp; The Department of Education said today in a statement on the Florida legislature’s Parental Rights in Education Bill that, quote, “all schools receiving federal funding must follow federal civil rights laws, including Title IX’s protections.”&nbsp; End quote.&nbsp; Is the administration considering halting the flow of Title IX funding to Florida if it moves forward with that legislation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to update you on, on that front.&nbsp; We can check if there&#8217;s more to report on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The United Kingdom announced that it was also going to have restrictions on the importation of Russian oil and gas.&nbsp; Was there coordination with the White House to time these announcements at the same time?&nbsp; And do you think the UK’s decision to wait until the end of the year to implement that is the right one?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say every country will make their own decisions.&nbsp; We did not expect nor did we request for the European countries to follow suit.&nbsp; I’m not sure what the import numbers are for the United Kingdom.&nbsp; I believe they are low, as are ours.&nbsp; And ours were about 10 percent last year.&nbsp; So, they may have looked at it through a different prism, as we did, through many other European countries &#8212; or countries in Europe who have much larger percentages of imports and have lower capacities for production.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, certainly, it&#8217;s a step we took.&nbsp; There have been a range of conversations with Prime Minister Boris Johnson.&nbsp; But again, these are steps taken by individual countries.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the administration’s feeling on the European Commission&#8217;s announcement that the plan now is to cut its Russian energy imports by two thirds by the end of the year?&nbsp; Is that something that the White House applauds?&nbsp; Or are there also concerns about the potential impact on global supplies of Europe, which is so much more dependent on Russian oil?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We welcome efforts for Europe &#8212; by Europe and other countries to diversify their energy sources.&nbsp; There is no question about that.&nbsp; There are also steps &#8212; I mean, the oil market &#8212; oil is a global marketplace, right?&nbsp; So, we are working in lockstep with our European partners to ensure that the supply on the marketplace is meeting what the demand is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of efforts to diversify, we certainly welcome that.&nbsp; We’re doing &#8212; we’re working to do something similar.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a couple more, sorry.&nbsp; On Judge Jackson, she&#8217;s also meeting with Democrats today.&nbsp; Is the White House confident it will get the support of the entire Democratic Caucus for Judge Jackson?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We believe Judge Jackson is an eminently qualified nominee who has been approved three times by bipartisan &#8212; a bipartisan Senate.&nbsp; And, you know, certainly we believe she warrants and deserves bipartisan support.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, on Texas, does the President have any plans to meet with Beto O&#8217;Rourke, the Democratic gubernatorial candidate for governor?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On this trip, I don&#8217;t believe so.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And what &#8212; why did he choose Texas for this trip &#8212; and veterans &#8212; first?&nbsp; This is the first stop on his Unity Agenda tour, as you could call it.&nbsp; So, why Texas?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think as I said at the beginning, Texas is home to the second-largest population of veterans in the United States, many of whom rely on the VA for services and benefits.&nbsp; And nearly 55 percent of veterans in Texas served in the era when burn pits were used.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is an opportunity also for the President to travel with a bipartisan group, which showcases to the country and the people of Texas and the veterans community of Texas how important this is to the President and how committed he is to continuing to make proc- &#8212; progress on his Unity Agenda.</p>



<p>All right.  Thanks, everyone.                                         </p>



<p>2:40 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/08/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-8/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 20:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48661</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: David Applegate, of Pennsylvania, to be Director of the United States Geological Survey, vice James Reilly. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Joseph Goffman, of Pennsylvania, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, vice William L. Wehrum. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Kate Elizabeth Heinzelman, of New York, to be General Counsel of the Central Intelligence Agency, vice&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>     David Applegate, of Pennsylvania, to be Director of the United States Geological Survey, vice James Reilly.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Joseph Goffman, of Pennsylvania, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, vice William L. Wehrum.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Kate Elizabeth Heinzelman, of New York, to be General Counsel of the Central Intelligence Agency, vice Courtney Elwood.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Paul M. Rosen, of California, to be Assistant Secretary of the Treasury for Investment Security, vice Thomas Peter Feddo.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Evelyn Wang, of Massachusetts, to be Director of the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy, Department of Energy, vice Lane Genatowski.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Robert A. Wood, of New York, to be an Alternate Representative of the United States of America to the Sessions of the General Assembly of the United Nations, during his tenure of service as Alternate Representative of the United States of America for Special Political Affairs in the United Nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
