<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 03:37:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/02/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-81/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 03:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 3:08 P.M. EST MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good afternoon, and thanks for joining us.&#160;Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on Omicron, Dr. Fauci will present the latest science, and Dr. Murthy will discuss Pfizer’s vaccine application for kids under the age of five.&#160; And then I’ll cover operational planning so that we’re ready for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>3:08 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good afternoon, and thanks for joining us.&nbsp;Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on Omicron, Dr. Fauci will present the latest science, and Dr. Murthy will discuss Pfizer’s vaccine application for kids under the age of five.&nbsp; And then I’ll cover operational planning so that we’re ready for that age group.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, over to Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to start by walking you through today’s data.&nbsp;<br><br>The current seven-day daily average of cases is about 446,400 cases per day, a decrease of about 36 percent over the previous week.<br><br>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 17,100 per day, also a decrease of about 14 percent over the previous week.&nbsp;<br><br>And the seven-day average daily deaths are about 2,300 per day, which is an increase of about 4 percent over the prior week.<br><br>While we continue to see large decreases in average daily case counts across the country, hospitalizations remain high, stretching our healthcare capacity and workforce to its limits in some areas of the country.&nbsp; And daily deaths also remain quite high.&nbsp;<br><br>And with the mixed news above, similar to other waves during the pandemic, our data continue to reinforce the critical importance of vaccination.<br><br>Last week, I shared data from our surveillance studies demonstrating the effectiveness of vaccination, including boosters, on decreasing cases, emergency department visits, and hospitalizations.&nbsp;<br><br>Additional new data continue to support these findings.&nbsp; On this slide, you can see data from 25 U.S. jurisdictions that report cases and deaths linked to vaccination status.&nbsp;<br><br>Similar to what I showed you last week, vaccination and booster doses substantially decrease the risk of death from COVID-19.&nbsp; Looking at the data from the week ending December 4th, the number of average weekly deaths for those who are unvaccinated was 9.7 per 100,000 people, but only 0.7 per 100,000 people for those who were vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>This means the risk of dying from COVID-19 was 14 times higher for people who were unvaccinated compared to those who received only a primary series.&nbsp;<br><br>For those who were boosted, the average of weekly deaths was 0.1 per 100,000 people, meaning that unvaccinated individuals were 97 times more likely to die compared to those who were boosted.&nbsp;<br><br>I also want to share new data from CDC’s COVID-NET hospital surveillance network to further show how essential vaccination and boosting is in preventing hospitalization from COVID-19.<br><br>On this slide, you can see data comparing the percentage of people age 65 and older who are unvaccinated and boosted in the general population &#8212; in blue &#8212; and those who are hospitalized &#8212; in green.&nbsp;<br><br>As shown on the slide, only 12 percent of those age 65 and over remain unvaccinated in the general population.&nbsp; But when we look at those over the age of 65 who are in the hospital for COVID-19, 54 percent are unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>In stark contrast, now let&#8217;s look at those who have been boosted &#8212; on the bottom.&nbsp; Here, 57 percent of those over age 65 are boosted in the general population.&nbsp; And only 8 percent of those over the age of 65 and in the hospital for COVID-19 have received a booster dose.&nbsp;<br><br>These same trends are seen across all age groups.&nbsp; These data show us that the percent of people who are currently hospitalized due to COVID-19 are disproportionately unvaccinated and disproportionately not boosted.<br><br>Additionally, these data confirm that vaccination and boosting continue to protect against severe illness and hospitalization, even during the Omicron surge.<br><br>If you are not up to date on your COVID-19 vaccinations, you have not optimized your protection against severe disease and death, and you should get vaccinated and boosted if you are eligible.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn it over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp;<br><br>What I&#8217;d like to do over the next couple of minutes is to address a common misperception and the result of misinformation, and that is whether vaccination negatively impacts people trying to conceive &#8212; namely does it have a negative impact on fertility.&nbsp;<br><br>The data are clear.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>I will show a couple of representative studies.&nbsp; This published just a week and a half ago in the American Journal of Epidemiology, which is a prospective cohort study of vaccination and SARS infection and fertility.&nbsp;<br><br>The study is an NIH-funded pregnancy study online &#8212; or “PRESTO” for short &#8212; of couples who are trying to conceive through intercourse.&nbsp; It enrolled participants before pregnancy and collected data on vaccination and other variables during the pre-conception period, and then collected data on subsequent fertility.&nbsp;<br><br>There were over 2,000 females between the ages of 21 and 45 in the U.S. or Canada.&nbsp; They were enrolled between December 2020 and September 2021, and they were followed through November 2021.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>But data are clear: COVID-19 vaccination in male or female partners did not affect the likelihood of conception.&nbsp; Couples were 18 percent less likely to conceive if the male partner had been infected with SARS-CoV-2 within 60 days before a menstrual cycle.&nbsp; That is “infected,” not “vaccinated.”<br><br>However, the COVID-19 disease only temporarily reduced male fertility.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>In another study &#8212; published, again, about a week and a half ago &#8212; this was in an in vitro fertilization clinic.&nbsp; And the question that was asked: that with people vaccinated, in this case, either with the Pfizer or the Moderna product had similar responses to ovarian stimulation, which is used to stimulate the ovary in preparation for in vitro fertilization.&nbsp; And similar pregnancy outcomes compared with unvaccinated people.<br><br>The reproductive potential does not appear to be affected by vaccination in people who undergo in vitro fertilization.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>So, what&#8217;s our takeaway message about vaccination and conception?&nbsp; New data add to previous studies that indicate that COVID-19 vaccination does not negatively impact fertility.<br><br>CDC and professional medical organizations serving people of reproductive age emphasize, as shown on this website, that there&#8217;s no evidence that vaccination impairs fertility.&nbsp;<br><br>And, of course, as we&#8217;ve all said over and over again, vaccination is recommended for people who are trying to get pregnant now or might become pregnant in the future, as well as their partners.&nbsp; And anyone who&#8217;s vaccinated and pregnant, breastfeeding, trying to get pregnant now or might become pregnant in the future should also get a booster shot when eligible.<br><br>Final slide.<br><br>The message is the same: Get vaccinated and get boosted for so many reasons.&nbsp;<br><br>Now over to you, Dr. Murthy.<br><br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Well, thank you so much, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s good to be with everyone again today.&nbsp;<br><br>As many of you know, the FDA has now received Pfizer&#8217;s application for a vaccine for children age six months through four years.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, Jeff is going to talk more about how we&#8217;re preparing for the possibility of this milestone, but first I want to walk you through the process.<br><br>Pfizer&#8217;s application will now undergo the same independent, rigorous, and transparent review process that was used to authorize the vaccines that now more than 250 million Americans have received, including millions of children ages five and up.<br><br>It will involve the FDA receiving the full data from Pfizer, posting that data publicly, and then convening its advisory committee for a transparent discussion of the data.<br><br>The FDA will then render its opinion, after which the CDC and its advisory group will assess the data and make their recommendation.&nbsp; This is the same rigorous process that was used to assess numerous vaccines long before the pandemic began.<br><br>I know how eager parents and caregivers are for the good news on this front.&nbsp; For much of this pandemic, millions of parents have carried with them an added layer of worry knowing that their children under five didn&#8217;t have protection from COVID the way older vaccinated children do.<br><br>I felt this worry too as a father of a four-year-old daughter who is not yet eligible to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I&#8217;m hopeful that we may be one step closer to having an added layer of protection for our younger children, and one less worry for their parents.<br><br>A vaccine for children under five would mean we would have vaccines available for essentially all age groups in America.&nbsp; This would be a major milestone.<br><br>Now there are a number of steps ahead to determine if the vaccine is both safe and effective for our kids under five.&nbsp; And please know that the FDA will not cut any corners in their review process.&nbsp; They know that they are the gold standard that all of us rely on.<br><br>If and when the FDA and CDC decide to move forward, we will work closely with our trusted community partners to ensure that families have accurate science-based information about the vaccine so they can make the best decisions for their children.<br><br>And as we await this review process, I want to emphasize once more just how important it is that the rest of us get vaccinated and get our kids five and older, who are already eligible, vaccinated as well.&nbsp; If you are 12 and up and you&#8217;re vaccinated, please get boosted as soon as you&#8217;re eligible.&nbsp;<br><br>And all of us should wear high-quality masks when in public indoor settings. &nbsp;This is how we can continue to create a wall of protection around our children under five as we look to safeguard their health.<br><br>Thanks so much for your time today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll pass it to Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thanks, Doctors.&nbsp; If the FDA authorizes and CDC recommends this vaccine, 18 million children under the age of five will become eligible for protection from COVID-19.<br><br>Before we open up for questions, I want to share how we&#8217;re preparing now, just as we did with vaccines, for kids ages 5 to 11 so that we are ready and we hit the ground running following decisions from FDA and CDC.<br><br>Importantly, this vaccine is specifically formulated for kids under the age of five.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re working closely with states, local health departments, pediatricians, families, doctors, and pharmacies to ensure the vaccine is available at thousands of locations nationwide.<br><br>We&#8217;ve already secured ample doses and the necessary needles and supplies specially made for kids in this age group.<br><br>Following FDA authorization, we would immediately begin packing and shipping doses to states and healthcare providers.&nbsp; And in short order following CDC recommendations, parents will be able to get their kids under five vaccinated at convenient locations, locations they know and trust.<br><br>While we know many parents are eager to get their kids the protection of the vaccine, we know others have questions.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re working with our partners to ensure all parents have access to the facts and information they need to make the right decision.<br><br>And as always, we&#8217;re laser-focused on equity and making sure we reach the hardest-hit and most at-risk communities and families.<br><br>A year ago, we stood up a historic nationwide vaccination program that&#8217;s now gotten 75 percent of adults in the U.S. fully vaccinated.<br><br>We then launched a boosters program that&#8217;s gotten almost 90 million Americans their booster shot.<br><br>And we established the vaccination program, specifically for kids ages 5 to 11, that has protected millions of kids around the country.<br><br>Now with the potential vaccine for kids under five on the horizon, our message to parents and families is simple: We&#8217;re doing everything we can to prepare now.&nbsp; We&#8217;re taking all of the best practices and applying all of the lessons learned over the last 12 months to ensure getting kids under five the protection of vaccine is easy and convenient.<br><br>And we&#8217;ll be ready to start getting shots in arms soon after FDA and CDC make their decisions.<br><br>With that, let&#8217;s open it up for some questions.&nbsp; Kevin?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; We have time for a few questions.&nbsp; Please keep your questions to one.&nbsp; First, let&#8217;s go to Laura Santhanam at PBS.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Can &#8212; thinking about long COVID treatment, can you tell me just sort of latest updates with research about treatment availability and accreditation of clinics offering that treatment?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci?&nbsp; Long COVID treatments.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah, there is a very large study that&#8217;s been initiated some time ago &#8212; the RECOVER study &#8212; at the NIH in collaboration with other agencies looking at the incidence, the prevalence, and hopefully understanding the pathogenic mechanisms of long COVID.<br><br>Right now, the data are starting to come in.&nbsp; It&#8217;s too early to make any definitive statements.&nbsp; But for those individuals &#8212; and, as you know, long COVID means the persistence of signs and symptoms that are not explainable by any readily recognizable pathogenic process following the recovery from the acute infection.&nbsp; There have been subjec- &#8212; some suggestions that it is an aberrant inflammatory response, perhaps some element of autoimmunity, perhaps some elements of persistence of nucleotide fragments from the virus.&nbsp; All of these now are being actively pursued.<br><br>But before we can make any definitive statements, we need to learn a lot more about it, with the ultimate goal of figuring out how we might be able to mitigate or prevent some of those symptoms.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Jeff Mason at Reuters.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; My question is about the data and about habits.&nbsp; With regard to data &#8212; for Dr. Fauci or Dr. Walensky &#8212; what is your take on why the booster rate seems to be lagging?&nbsp; Why would people who have decided to get vaccinated, the first and second doses, not be getting more boosters?<br><br>And secondly, with regard to your &#8212; the data today with cases going down and hospitalizations going down, Dr.&nbsp;Lawensky [sic] &#8212; Walensky, do you think people should start to change their habits, and it&#8217;s okay now to maybe gather in groups more or to go out to bars and restaurants?&nbsp; Or what is the overall guidance right now, in terms of &#8212; in terms of gathering in groups?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Hey, Jeff.&nbsp; This is Jeff.&nbsp; Why don’t we just start with the baseline on where we are in the booster data.&nbsp; And that is that about half of all Americans who are eligible for a booster have gotten a booster.&nbsp; Eligibility is five months or greater for the mRNA vaccines &#8212; Pfizer and Moderna &#8212; and two months for J&amp;J.&nbsp; And importantly, about 70 percent of seniors &#8212; those over 65 &#8212; have gotten a booster.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know, boosters are widely available.&nbsp; They&#8217;re at convenient locations around the country, and they&#8217;re free.&nbsp; And obviously, the impact of a booster, as Dr. Walensky said, is really important.&nbsp; So, we obviously want to continue to drive that number higher and higher &#8212; the percent of Americans who have boosters.&nbsp;<br><br>But over to you, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; And then, over to you, Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, Jeff, you know, I&#8217;m really not sure you&#8217;re asking a good question.&nbsp; It&#8217;s almost a psychological or sociological question: Why would people who had enough understanding of the risk to go ahead and get the primary series &#8212; why we don&#8217;t have more getting the booster.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t have an easy explanation for that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the reasons why we keep trying to put the data out.&nbsp; Because, as Dr. Walensky showed in her slide, the data are really stunningly obvious why a booster is really very important.<br><br>You first need to get vaccinated before you get boosted, that&#8217;s for sure.&nbsp; But when you look at the difference of how a booster, for everything you ask it to do &#8212; to reconstitute, from an immunological and from a clinical standpoint, the diminished protection that you get not only with waning naturally of immunity, but also the negative impact on some of the variants that elude the immune response &#8212; fortunately for us, when you boost with the standard vaccine, which is against the original viral sequence, that you get such a good response.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the only thing that we can do is to continue to come out with the data and to make sure the American public appreciates why it is so important for optimal protection to get boosted.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; And maybe I&#8217;ll just add in there: With regard to where cases and hospitalizations are, I think we are all cautiously optimistic as we&#8217;re seeing cases come down week over week; down 36 percent over the last week.&nbsp;<br><br>I do think we have to use an important metric as a barometer, which is: How are our hospitals doing?&nbsp; And our hospitalization rates are still quite high and certainly having hospital capacity challenges in many parts of the country still.</p>



<p>So, with that barometer, we’ve said before, Omicron &#8212; “milder” does not mean “mild.”&nbsp; And so, we really do have to look to our hospitalization rates and our death rates to look to when it is time to lift some of these mitigation efforts.</p>



<p>We will continue to reevaluate, and we know people are anxious.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Jeannie Baumann at Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I was hoping, Jeff, you could be a little more &#8212; when you said “short order” for the availability of those kid vaccines, I was hoping &#8212; do you mean like a week or a few days?</p>



<p>And then, Dr. Fauci, I was hoping you could talk a little bit about the Pandemic Preparedness Plan that NIAID released today, and, you know, how the lessons from COVID helped drive some of those plans, and what type of funding do you need to implement it.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Yeah, so, on the vaccines for kids under five, we’re doing all the preparation now that we can do to be ready so that it’ll be available at trusted locations as soon as possible, post &#8212; I want to emphasize again &#8212; FDA and CDC recommendations.</p>



<p>We cannot begin actually packing and shipping until the FDA authorization, and then there’s the CDC ACIP process, which generally takes place a matter of days after the FDA.</p>



<p>So, we’re talking, you know, a matter of several days to a week or so, based on the 5- to 11-year experience from FDA authorization to when the first doses will start to be shots in arms.&nbsp; But we’ll move as fast as possible, pending the decision of CDC and FDA.&nbsp; And I think the preparation we’re doing now will enable us to do so.<br><br>The second part of your question?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;ll answer that, Jeff.&nbsp; She was asking about the Pandemic Preparedness Plan.</p>



<p>You know, very briefly, Jeannie, it is really founded on what we&#8217;ve been talking about for some time now, which is the prototype pathogen approach where you get fundamental information, data, and preparedness on each of the multiple families that are projected to be as a risk.</p>



<p>For example, fortunately for us, we had been doing that with the coronaviruses when we got a lot of information from SARS-CoV-1 and MERS, and were already involved in the preparation of both platform technology and immunogen design.&nbsp; We planned to do that by selecting out anywhere from 10 to 20 families of viruses in which we can find common denominators within the family and do the immunological background to do the development of phase-one-type vaccines so that we could hit the ground running.</p>



<p>The second part of the program relates to both the development and the discovery of antiviral drugs &#8212; those that are already around, namely, have been used for other purposes &#8212; that we might apply them to whatever of the families that I mentioned a moment ago.&nbsp; But the other is to use the replication cycle of the virus &#8212; similar to what we did with HIV and what we&#8217;re doing with COVID-19 &#8212; to be able to develop antivirals against the whole family.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s just, kind of, a snapshot of the plan that the NIH just recently put out.</p>



<p>With regard to the budget, I mean, obviously it&#8217;s too early to talk about that because we&#8217;re in negotiations right now for what our budgetary needs are.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Meg Tirrell at CNBC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; One for Dr. Fauci and one for Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>For Dr. Fauci: Are you expecting we&#8217;ll see an efficacy update with the data for kids under five?&nbsp; I think a lot of parents are (inaudible) unsure about how optimistic they should be feeling right now, when the last update we got was that the immune-bridging study didn&#8217;t meet goals.&nbsp; So, are you expecting to see that we&#8217;ll actually see this prevent cases of COVID?</p>



<p>And then, for Dr. Walensky, can you give us an update on BA.2 &#8212; its prevalence and your expectation for how it could affect, sort of, the curve of this Omicron wave?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah, Meg, thank you.&nbsp; I mean, obviously, we are anticipating that we will get a good efficacy signal for the use of vaccines in children under five years old.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, right now, as you know, the FDA is looking at the data very carefully and, in their typical fashion, they will be very careful in scrutinizing the data and making a recommendation and a decision based on that data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of them.&nbsp; But, of course, we&#8217;re anticipating we will get a vaccine efficacy signal that would allow for the use of this vaccine in children.&nbsp; But let&#8217;s wait for the FDA determination and, ultimately, the CDC recommendation.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, great.&nbsp; Thank you, Meg, for that question.</p>



<p>So, our genomic surveillance now is detecting BA.2 projecting around 1.5 percent in this country.&nbsp; Of course, that varies for different parts of the country, but around one of &#8212; 1.5 percent projection of the sequences that we&#8217;re seeing.</p>



<p>What we know about BA.2 so far is that it does have a modest transmission advantage over BA.1.&nbsp; However, it&#8217;s not nearly the transmission advantage that we&#8217;ve seen between Omicron and Delta.</p>



<p>In terms of early studies, we have not seen any studies that suggest it’s more severe, nor have we seen studies that suggests that it will evade our vaccines any more so than Omicron has already &#8212; and, in fact, that our vaccines will work just like it has with Omicron.<br><br>So, in terms of how we anticipate this will impact cases: In many places we&#8217;ve seen BA.2 so far, cases have continued to come down, although at a slower rate.</p>



<p>In some case &#8212; in some countries, like Denmark, cases have gone up associated with BA.2, but that&#8217;s also in the context of relaxing mitigation strategies, mitigation measures, which is why we&#8217;re currently keeping those in place, among the reasons.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp;&nbsp;Thanks.</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Jeff, can I add though &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp;&nbsp;Please, Dr. Murthy.</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; &#8212; one point to Meg’s question?</p>



<p>Meg, at the heart of your question I think is something that many parents may be wondering about, which is: What&#8217;s changed between December when Pfizer shared their news and now?</p>



<p>And they&#8217;re &#8212; it&#8217;s a big change that&#8217;s happened, which is we experienced the Omicron surge.&nbsp; And with many children in particular, as well as adults, being infected and ending up in the hospital during the Omicron surge, it turns out that has actually facilitated the collection of important clinical data, additional clinical data that we did not have in December.&nbsp; Whether that changes the risk-benefit profile is what the FDA will be assessing.&nbsp; But there has been developments since December on the data front.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Jacqueline Howard at CNN.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; I understand that, earlier this week, governors who met with the President expressed that they were seeking more clear guidelines from the White House on what the transition out of the pandemic and into a greater state of normality might look like.</p>



<p>Obviously, I know we&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp; But my question is: When might we see such guidance?&nbsp; And can you give us any insight into if and how those guidelines will be prepared?&nbsp; What metrics will be considered?&nbsp; And how will that guidance be communicated to state leaders and to the public?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, as you as you can see from the discussion today, right now our focus is on fighting Omicron.&nbsp; While cases are coming down, as Dr. Walensky pointed out, there&#8217;s still a high level of hospitalization, largely driven, as the data shows, by the unvaccinated.</p>



<p>At the same time, we are always, you know, planning for the future.&nbsp; The most important thing that we have now, when comparing to a year ago, are the tools to protect people:<br><br>The vaccines and the effectiveness that we&#8217;ve talked about, particularly with boosters that offer the highest level of protection; a pediatric vaccine on the horizon; and treatments, including pills that are highly effective against severe disease and hospitalization.</p>



<p>So, we are in a much stronger position than a year ago.&nbsp; We have 210 million people fully vaccinated, including 75 percent &#8212; three out of four &#8212; of every adult.&nbsp; We had less than a percent when the President took office a year ago &#8212; people vaccinated.&nbsp; So, from 1 percent up to 75 percent of adults.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ninety-eight, ninety-nine percent of schools are open.&nbsp; That number was 46 percent when the President took office.</p>



<p>We have free tests, free masks, and booster shots widely available.</p>



<p>So, our progress over the last year and the tools we now have certainly allow us to get closer to a time when COVID doesn&#8217;t disrupt our daily lives but is something we protect against and treat.</p>



<p>And as we make more progress against Omicron, we&#8217;ll, you know, get closer to that point.</p>



<p>Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Zeke with AP.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I was wanting to follow up on Jeff’s last point there and maybe get the doctors’ input as well.</p>



<p>In terms of that pathway to that vision of a point where COVID-19 doesn&#8217;t alter Americans&#8217; daily lives, you know, for many over the past couple of years it feels a little bit like, you know, the Charlie Brown football here, where it&#8217;s, you know, “Get vaccinated.&nbsp; (Inaudible) you need to get a booster.&nbsp; But even if you&#8217;re vaccinated and boosted, you still need to wear your mask to protect people who aren’t vaccinated.”<br><br>Is there a sense yet that you can offer the American public based upon your studies, based upon what you now know about Omicron &#8212; you know, is this the last wave?&nbsp; Is there enough that you can say, by a point certain, COVID will not impact people&#8217;s daily lives anymore?&nbsp; And if not, you know, why not?&nbsp; What else do you need to know?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, we have to be totally honest that we don&#8217;t know whe- &#8212; we believe that we are now going in the right direction.&nbsp; And the best-case scenario, as I and my colleagues have often described, is that with the tools that we have &#8212; the vaccination, the boosting, the testing, the masking, and all the other mitigations that we know about &#8212; when you have a level of community protection, which is the level of immunity throughout the community, that we will reach a stage &#8212; and I hope that it&#8217;s sooner rather than later &#8212; when, as you have said, this will not dominate our lives.&nbsp; In other words, it will be similar to the assimilation of this virus, in the group of viruses that we have learned to live with, without disruption of our society.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, the RSVs, the parainfluenzas &#8212; the influenzas where it&#8217;s there, it&#8217;s present, it hasn&#8217;t been eradicated, it hasn&#8217;t been eliminated, but it isn&#8217;t at a level that it essentially dominates what we do and dramatically influences our lives.&nbsp;<br><br>We believe we will get there.<br><br>We can&#8217;t guarantee that there will not be another variant that challenges us, but the best that we can do with that is to be prepared for it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doing all the things that we&#8217;re doing with regard to getting better, more advanced vaccine. &nbsp;For example, different platforms, different immunogen designs, development and discovery of new drugs &#8212; all of that will be part of the armamentarium that will ultimately, even with the appearance of additional variants, will get us to the point where we will not be dominated by this virus; where we can return to a degree of normality that we all crave for.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, time for a couple more questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Sheryl Stolberg at the New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for taking this question.&nbsp; It&#8217;s for Jeff and for Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Senators Murray and Burr have proposed a legislation that would create a task force to examine the initial emergence of the coronavirus and also assess the United States’ response across both the Trump and Biden administrations.&nbsp; It would be appointed by Congress, not by the White House.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering &#8212; to Jeff: Is this something that the President supports?&nbsp; And for Dr. Fauci: Do you think it&#8217;s necessary to conduct an inquiry into the origins of the virus?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, Sheryl, thanks for the question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s start with &#8212; you know, we share the senators’ focus.&nbsp; A lot of the bill is about building stronger public health systems.&nbsp; And we appreciate the bipartisan goals to ensure the country is better prepared for outbreaks in the future, like COVID.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, as we&#8217;ve been talking about, our, you know, focus is 100 percent on fighting Omicron and COVID.&nbsp; And while cases are coming down, the hospitalizations, as we discussed, are still quite high.&nbsp;<br><br>And across time, we do look forward to engaging with Congress and reviewing lessons learned from this pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think that right now our focus is on Omicron, but we appreciate the work the senators have done and look forward to working with them.<br><br>Dr. Fauci?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Sheryl, I think it&#8217;s important to look at every aspect of this outbreak for lessons learned that is not only what the origin of the virus and the origin of the outbreak is, but many other things that we could learn from in the future so that we can prevent something like this happening or respond better if and when it does.</p>



<p>One of those is understanding what the origin of the virus is.&nbsp; And it’s very important.&nbsp; For example, studies were done with the first SARS-CoV-1 that we experienced in 2002 and 2003, and there was a mystery about how that happened.&nbsp; And then finally, after a lot of studies that actually took years to finally show that the origin was from a bat to an intermediate host to a human, very likely in a wet-market-type situation.</p>



<p>That was very important because that led to things that unfortunately were not followed, namely a better control in regulation of the wild animal trade and the interface between humans and animals.</p>



<p>The other one was MERS, in which it was shown finally that this was a bat reservoir that very likely infected camels and camels to human.</p>



<p>That also provides public health guidelines for the interaction of an animal-human interface.&nbsp; So, it would be, obviously, important to be able to determine how this went from what was very likely an animal reservoir &#8212; given the similarity with bat viruses &#8212; how that happened to go into humans to lead to this outbreak.</p>



<p>Understanding that will help us to prepare for any future outbreak, as well as prepare for a response.&nbsp; So, I’m definitely in favor of that.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Kevin?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let’s go to Peter Sullivan, The Hill.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; There’s &#8212; a group of Democrats in Congress have called for $17 billion in the next appropriations package for global vaccinations and other aspects of the global response.</p>



<p>I’m wondering if the White House supports that, and are you planning to, you know, ask Congress for that in the next package.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, we have what we need in this current fight against Omicron, and we’ve done a lot to prepare for what’s ahead.&nbsp; We have boosters for all Americans, we’ve secured 20 million doses of the highly effective Pfizer pill.&nbsp; We’ve expanded supplies and stockpiles of PPE, including masks and gloves.</p>



<p>So, while we have enough money, enough funding for the current, immediate needs, we need to continue &#8212; as we’ve talked about &#8212; to stay ahead of the virus.&nbsp; And we are looking at a future where we will likely need funding for treatments and pills; we’ll need funding to continue to expand testing and to continue to lead the effort, as we’ve done with 1.2 billion doses donated to the world, but to continue to lead that effort to vaccinate the world.<br><br>So, we will be working with Congress as needed to make sure we have the funding to continue to fight this virus.<br><br>I want to thank everybody for the questions and look forward to the next briefing.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>3:44 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at an Event to Reignite the Cancer&#160;Moonshot</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/02/remarks-by-president-biden-at-an-event-to-reignite-the-cancer-moonshot/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:06 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; I&#8217;m Joe Biden, Jill Biden’s husband.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; I want to thank you, Doctor, for that introduction.&#160; But I want to thank you more for all the effort you put in to change, save, alter people’s lives and your dedication to it. And&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>2:06 P.M. EST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m Joe Biden, Jill Biden’s husband.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I want to thank you, Doctor, for that introduction.&nbsp; But I want to thank you more for all the effort you put in to change, save, alter people’s lives and your dedication to it.<br><br>And as we used to &#8212; I used to say in the Senate and I think it’s still said in the Senate &#8212; &#8220;if you excuse the point of personal privilege,&#8221; I&#8217;d like to &#8212; see that doctor on the end there?&nbsp; That&#8217;s the man who spent 18 months trying to save our son&#8217;s life.&nbsp; Doctor, I love you.&nbsp; The whole family loves you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, the doctor’s optimism and fearlessness embodies what our Cancer Moonshot is all about.&nbsp;<br><br>And, of course, I want to thank Jill and Kamala and Doug.&nbsp; They just shared how personal it is for them and our families and &#8212; like so many of you.&nbsp; Every one of you have a story.&nbsp; Every one of you have a story.<br><br>And our message today is this: We can do this.&nbsp; I promise you we can do this.&nbsp; For all those we lost, for all those we miss, we can end cancer as we know it.&nbsp;<br><br>I committed to this fight when I was Vice President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s one of the reasons why, quite frankly, I ran for President.&nbsp; Let there be no doubt: Now that I am President, this is a presidential White House priority &#8212; period.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>You know, with the bipartisan members of Congress &#8212; and I’ve &#8212; I don’t want to start, because I&#8217;ll leave somebody out.&nbsp; (Laughter).&nbsp; But, you know, Congress is here.&nbsp; And this is, they can tell you, one of the truly bipartisan issues in the United States Congress.&nbsp;<br><br>I know there are votes, but that includes Senator Patrick Leahy, Michael Bennet, Amy Klobuchar, Chris Van Hollen, Sanford Bishop, Representative Joyce Beatty, Barbara Lee, Jim McGovern, Donald Payne, Debbie Wasserman Schultz, Bonnie Watson Coleman, Tom Cole, Brian Higgins &#8212; I said I wasn’t going to do this &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; Terry Sewell &#8212; Terry Sewell.<br><br>And it can be truly an American moment if it’s &#8212; I&#8217;m sure I&#8217;ve left somebody out, for which I apologize.&nbsp; But this can really be an American moment that proves to ourselves and, quite frankly, to the world that we can do really big things.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, we&#8217;ve made enormous progress in the past 50 years since Congress passed the President &#8212; and President Nixon signed into law the National Cancer Act and declared war on cancer.&nbsp; We learned cancer is not a single disease.&nbsp; We used to think, at that time, it was a single disease.&nbsp; There are over 200, as you all know &#8212; 200 different types of cancer caused by different genetic mutations in our cells.<br><br>We discovered new medicines, therapies, early detection and prevention measures that extend lives and save lives.<br><br>In the first 25 years since the National Cancer Act, the death rate from cancer was largely unchanged.&nbsp; Then things began to change.&nbsp; The progress over the last 25 years &#8212; the death rate has fallen by more than 25 percent.<br><br>But here’s the deal: Despite the progress of lives extended and lives saved, cancer is still the number-two cause of death in America, second only to heart disease.<br><br>In the last two years of COVID-19 pandemic, it’s taken more than &#8212; the pandemic has taken more than 800,000 American lives.&nbsp; But that same period of time, cancer has claimed 1.2 million American lives year in and year out.<br><br>For too many patients and their families on &#8212; diagnosed with cancer, instead of hope, there’s also bewilderment.&nbsp;<br><br>Remember, Doc, you telling the family that you had to be able &#8212; we had to be able to ask questions and you were available, because it&#8217;s a hard road to understand and traverse:</p>



<p>The feeling of being on your own, a <s>static</s> [statistic] adrift in a sea of patients, frustrated that hospitals and doctors can&#8217;t only &#8212; easily share your medical records or help find answers when there&#8217;s &#8212; minutes count.<br><br>Having to advocate for even the most basic care and attention for your loved one.<br><br>A flood of information &#8212; a completely different language, in many cases &#8212; with no one to help you decipher it.<br><br>Being within reach of therapy &#8212; a therapy that&#8217;s too expensive or your insurance won&#8217;t cover it.<br><br>Despite all the progress, there&#8217;s still a sense of powerlessness, guilt that maybe you&#8217;re not doing enough because you don&#8217;t know enough, and fear.<br><br>So, when President Obama asked me to launch our Cancer Moonshot in our administration, our goal was to bring a new sense of urgency to make the system of prevention, research, and patient care to take advantage of the 21st century science and technology.<br><br>We began the process.&nbsp; Many of you in this room were a part of that.&nbsp; We harnessed the resources of the federal government to change the culture, increase cooperation among scientists, and break down some of the silos.<br><br>I&#8217;d note, parenthetically &#8212; I remember I wanted to transfer a particular scan from a hospital in Pennsylvania to a hospital in D.C., and I was told they couldn&#8217;t do it &#8212; wasn’t able to do it.&nbsp; Could transfer just about anything else in the world, but they couldn&#8217;t do it because the hospitals didn&#8217;t want the other hospitals to have access to their &#8212; because the patients could change their mind with all the records.<br><br>That included everything from making federally funded cancer research more accessible to the public, instead of hiding behind a paywall.&nbsp; We launched Trials.Cancer.gov so everyone can look up cancer clinical trials across the country and around the world.<br><br>I traveled the country, bringing together leaders of<br>healthcare, technology, education, business, and technology.<br><br>I visited most of the major cancer centers, literally, in the world; met with heads of state in those countries; and decided how we could work together to try to make progress.&nbsp; I remember a particularly good meeting in Australia.<br><br>One of the final pieces of legislation that President Obama signed into law was the bipartisan 21st Century Cures Act with the help of members of Congress, particularly &#8212; I don’t know if &#8212; is Fred Upton here?&nbsp; Fred, are you here?&nbsp; Well, Fred Upton was part of it and Diana DeGette in the House.<br><br>It streamlined the Food and Drug Administration –- the FDA &#8212; so that new cancer treatments can be evaluated faster.<br><br>It provided seven years of new funding, including research on cancer disparities, trial networks to discover new drugs, and new efforts for childhood cancer.<br><br>The president of the Senate &#8212; as president of the Senate, I presided over the overwhelming vote, after the election had already taken place &#8212; the presidential election &#8212; when everything is supposed to come to a screeching halt &#8212; a bipartisan vote to fund over $6 billion.&nbsp;<br><br>And I watched my friend &#8212; and he is my friend; we disagree a lot &#8212; Mitch McConnell stand there and ask unanimous consent to name the cancer provisions after our son Beau.<br><br>The Cancer Moonshot brought the country and the world closer together on this issue.<br><br>And when we left office, Jill and I knew we had to keep it going.&nbsp; So, we took &#8212; and a lot of you &#8212; we had five Nobel laureates and others who were involved, through the cancer &#8212; the Biden Cancer Initiative.&nbsp; We focused on turning the Moonshot into a movement to create the cancer research and care system that most people think we already have and that they all deserve, but they don’t know they don’t &#8212; we don’t have it until they try to deal with it.<br><br>And everywhere we’d go, people would share their stories &#8212; in grocery stores, airports, rope lines.&nbsp; And while we heard stories of loss and despair, the stories began to change just a little bit &#8212; a change of feeling, real hope.<br><br>But not because of me and Jill, but because of all of you in this room and so many more at home: doctors, researchers, advocates, caregivers, patients, survivors.</p>



<p>And that’s why, today, I’m proud to announce our plan to supercharge the Cancer Moonshot as a central effort of the Biden-Harris administration.<br><br>It’s bold.&nbsp; It’s ambitious.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s completely doable.<br><br>Just as we harnessed the science to develop cutting-edge COVID-19 vaccines and treatments, we&#8217;ll bring a fierce sense of urgency to the fight against cancer.<br><br>The goal is to cut the cancer death rate in half in the next 25 years &#8212; at least by 50 percent &#8212; and to turn more cancers from death sentences into chronic diseases that people can live with; to create a more supportive experience for patients and their families; and, by doing these things and more, to end cancer as we know it.<br><br>And here’s what we’re fighting and how we know what cancer looks like today: a disease where we often diagnose it too late and we have too few effective ways to prevent it.<br><br>The stark inequities based on race, disparity, ZIP Code, sexual orientation, gender identity, and other factors still persist.</p>



<p>And we know too little about why treatments work in some patients and the exact same &#8212; that same patient with the exact same diagnosed cancer, it doesn’t work in that patient.</p>



<p>Where we still lack strategies to develop treatments for some cancers.&nbsp;<br><br>Where we don’t do enough to help patients and their families navigate through the process.<br><br>Where we don’t learn enough from patients&#8217; experience &#8212; experiences or their data.<br><br>In fact, when we first started this work, one of the first things we did was make sure that doctors and researchers work together, share information, allow patients to share their data<br>with other doctors and researchers to help others.&nbsp; But there’s so much more to do.</p>



<p>I remember when we were going through this in the Moonshot, and my saying that &#8212; I was told that “Well, patients don’t want to share their data.”&nbsp; They all want to share their data.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Sometimes you all don’t want to share what you know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And for each &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and for each of the ways we know cancer today, we know we can change its trajectory.<br><br>For example, to prevent cancer, scientists are exploring if the new mRNA vaccine technology that brought us safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines could also be used to stop cancer cells when they fail &#8212; when they first arise, get them then.<br><br>To target the right treatments to the right patients, we’re learning more about how to use genetics, immune response, and other factors to tell which combinations of treatments that are likely to work best for a particular individual.<br><br>To address inequities, we can target prevention, detection, and treatment efforts so that all Americans &#8212; whether they’re urban, rural, or Tribal communities &#8212; have equal access to cancer diagnostics, therapeutics, clinical trials.&nbsp; There’s so much more we can do.&nbsp;<br><br>And as I said at the beginning, this is a presidential priority.<br><br>I will do my part on funding and using my authorities as President to break logjams and speed breakthroughs.<br><br>I challenge and encourage all of you &#8212; all of you to continue to do your part.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This will be bipartisan.&nbsp; This will bring the country together and, quite frankly, other nations as well.</p>



<p>Here are some of the actions that I’m announcing today:</p>



<p>First, I’ve formed a new Cancer Cabinet, which is convened in the com- &#8212; we will convene in the coming weeks, to include members of the Cabinet who are here today &#8212; all of the people sitting on the stage here.&nbsp; They’ll drive a whole-of-government effort to unleash every possibility within our &#8212; within our power, within their jurisdictions.<br><br>The White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, led by senior scientist and advisor, Dr. Eric Lander &#8212; sitting on the end there &#8212; will chart the path for the Cancer Moonshot for 2022 and beyond.<br><br>And I’m calling on Congress to fund my proposed ARPA-H &#8212; the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health.&nbsp; This will be a new kind of entity within the National Institute of Health &#8212; the NIH &#8212; with autonomy and authorities to drive unprecedented progress in biomedicine.</p>



<p>It’s based on DARPA.&nbsp; Most everybody knows, in this town, what DARPA is.&nbsp; That’s the Defense Department’s Advanced Research Project Agency that has led to breakthrough technologies that protect our national security &#8212; from the Internet, to GPS, and so much more.<br><br>ARPA-H will have a singular purpose: to drive breakthroughs to prevent, detect, and treat diseases, including cancer, Alzheimer’s, and diabetes, and other diseases.</p>



<p>And I think there’s strong bipartisan support for this, but it costs money.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s the best &#8212; these are the best dollars we could spend.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve got to get it done, and we got to get it done now and not wait any longer.<br><br>I&#8217;m also calling on the scientific and medical communities to bring the boldest thinking to this fight.&nbsp;<br><br>I’m calling on the private sector to develop and test new treatments, make drugs more affordable, and share more data and knowledge that can inform the public and benefit every company’s research.<br><br>And I’m respectfully calling on people living with cancer and caregivers and families to keep sharing their experience and pushing for progress.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll have a voice and a seat at the table, I promise you.&nbsp;<br><br>And here’s one thing we can all do: Americans have missed more than 900 &#8212; 9 million cancer screenings in the last two years because of COVID.&nbsp; Nine million.&nbsp; We have to get cancer screenings back on track and make sure that they are accessible to all Americans.<br><br>So, today, I’m announcing a call to action for cancer screening and early detection.<br><br>If you were supposed to get a cancer screening during the pandemic, call your primary care doctor today.</p>



<p>If you’re that doctor, talk to your patients.&nbsp; Get a screening scheduled, whether it’s in the office, at home, or through a telehealth visit.&nbsp; Because the Affordable Care Act now <s>will cover</s> [requires] most private insurance plans, as well as Medicare and Medicaid, to cover the recommended preventive care screenings free of charge.<br><br>I’m calling on companies, healthcare providers, non-profits, and others to step up, including developing mobile units and pop-up clinics to reach people where they live.<br><br>And if you’re putting off a screening because you’re afraid of what you’ll find &#8212; they&#8217;ll find &#8212; let me say this &#8212; and so many people are &#8212; put it off: Last November, I got a colon cancer screening.&nbsp; I’m glad I did.&nbsp; Trust me, I know cancer is scary.&nbsp; Going to the doctor’s can be scary.&nbsp; But screening is how you catch it early, before it’s too late.&nbsp; The earlier you get it, the better shot you have.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me close with this: There’s a quote that &#8212; when I made one of these speeches, years ago &#8212; five, six years ago &#8212;&nbsp;attributed &#8212; it was attributed to Yo-Yo Ma.&nbsp; I later was informed it was attributed to Vince Lombardi.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But whoever the hell gave the quote &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; it makes sense.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s the quote, &#8220;Practice makes permanent.&nbsp; Only perfect practice makes perfect.&#8221;<br><br>My challenge to everyone involved in this fight against cancer: Take a hard look at your practice.&nbsp; Ask yourself, are you practicing perfectly or am I practicing to make the old way permanent?&nbsp; Old practices created data silos, minimized the role of patients, fostered the wrong kind of competition instead of the right kind of collaboration.<br><br>And I know we can get this right &#8212; I&#8217;m positive we can &#8212; by not losing sight of the ultimate goal: the patient’s health.&nbsp; And by not losing sight of something else I also believe: America is the single place on Earth &#8212; single country that can be defined, as I told Xi Jinping, by one word, “possibilities.”&nbsp; Possibilities.&nbsp;<br><br>When we work together in America, there is nothing &#8212; nothing beyond our capacity.&nbsp; Nothing.&nbsp; So, let’s show the world what’s possible.&nbsp; Let’s show the world that we&#8217;re committed.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s show that we can do big things &#8212; that in the United States of America, when we work together, there’s nothing beyond our grasp &#8212; I mean nothing beyond our grasp.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know of nothing, as I think my colleagues would say, that&#8217;s more bipartisan than take on this fight and fundamentally change cancer as we know it.<br><br>It&#8217;s a mission that can truly unify the nation, that shows us at our best, working together, and &#8212; rather than working against one another.<br><br>For every patient asking for one more day &#8212; I remember I&#8217;ve met &#8212; I met with over 3,000 researchers in the various organizations, and they&#8217;re good.&nbsp; They&#8217;re devoting their whole lives to try to save (inaudible).&nbsp; And they work really long hours, but they&#8217;re not practitioners.&nbsp; They’ve not had that patient come up and say, &#8220;Doc, can you give me just two more weeks so I can see my daughter married.&#8221;&nbsp; &#8220;Doc, all I need &#8212; can you do anything to give me just six more months to see the baby born.&nbsp; That’s all I&#8217;m asking for, Doc.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s a sense of overwhelming urgency &#8212; overwhelming urgency if you’re patient or a family member of a patient.&nbsp; Every patient asking just for one more day.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not asking to “cure me.”&nbsp; One more day.&nbsp; One more week.&nbsp; &#8220;Can I get another year to be able to do &#8212; boom.&#8221;<br><br>For survivors and caregivers who carry the physical and mental scars of treatments and recovery, and for those who have lost, and for the ones we can save: Let’s end cancer as we know it.&nbsp;<br><br>I refuse to believe &#8212; I refuse to believe this is beyond our capacity.&nbsp; I refuse to believe it.<br><br>You know, when I put together the Cancer Moonshot, I was Vice President, and the President gave me authority to task anyone in the administration.&nbsp; And when they found out I had the Department of Energy and Ernie Moniz, when they found out I had NASA and a lot of other agencies, they looked at me like, &#8220;What&#8217;s the matter with you?&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>I said, &#8220;Guess what?&nbsp; NASA knows more about radiation than all of you.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Seriously.&nbsp; And Ernie Moniz &#8212; we were at a place where you got a billion, billion calculations per second.&nbsp; And it goes on.&nbsp;<br><br>Skills people never thought would impact on this can do it.&nbsp;<br><br>So, my plea to you scientists is: Share data as best you can.&nbsp; My plea to my members in Congress is: Let&#8217;s fund this particular program and focus on it until we beat it.&nbsp;<br><br>And to the American people: Keep the hope alive.&nbsp; There is hope.&nbsp; There is hope.<br><br>And I&#8217;m confident &#8212; absolutely confident &#8212; if we make all our effort to deal with it, we can make fundamental changes in people&#8217;s lives and change the families in this country &#8212; in a much better position than they are today with regard to cancer.</p>



<p>Thank you all for being here.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Thanks, everybody.<br><br>Every time I&#8217;d walk out of my Grandpop Finnegan&#8217;s house in Scranton, he&#8217;d yell, &#8220;Joey, keep the faith.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And my grandmother would yell, &#8220;No, Joey, spread it.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>Go spread the faith, guys.&nbsp; We can do this.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>(The President departs the podium and walks past the press.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, any comment on your decision to deploy troops to Eastern Europe?<br><br>MR. PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It was totally consistent with what I told Putin in the beginning: As long as he is acting aggressively, we&#8217;re going to make sure we reassure our NATO Allies and Eastern Europe that we&#8217;re there and Article Five is a sacred obligation.</p>



<p>2:30 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, February 2,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/02/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-february-2-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 01:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:35 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, as you know, today marks the second day of Black History Month.&#160; The President and Vice President are committed to fighting for equity, opportunity, and dignity for all Black Americans each and every day. And yesterday, a couple of people asked&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:35 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, as you know, today marks the second day of Black History Month.&nbsp; The President and Vice President are committed to fighting for equity, opportunity, and dignity for all Black Americans each and every day.</p>



<p>And yesterday, a couple of people asked me what we were doing, so I just wanted to give you a quick overview.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Monday, the President issued a proclamation calling on the nation to celebrate the contributions of Black Americans, honor the legacies and achievements of generations past, reckon with centuries of injustice, and confront those injustices that still fester today.</p>



<p>The President, and Vice President, and First Lady, Second Gentleman, Cabinet officials, and White House staff will host meetings and activities this month centered around the 2022 Black History Month theme: “Black Health and Wellness.”&nbsp; This includes a focus on physical wellness, mental health, environmental justice, economic growth, and spiritual wellness.</p>



<p>White House senior staff will also host important stakeholder discussions on diversity in media, veteran wellness, and increased support for HBCU students.</p>



<p>Last but certainly not least, we will celebrate and acknowledge the invaluable role Black faith leaders have played in communities across the nation, particularly during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>This is, of course, just brief overview.&nbsp; Stay tuned for more announcements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Zeke, with that, why don’t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; With the announcement this morning that the President authorized the deployment of 3,000 troops to Europe &#8212; the President previewed that announcement last week and then ordered it today.&nbsp; Is there something &#8212; some new piece of information or intelligence that he saw in the last few days that sort of went from being a notional thing to something that to &#8212; to an actual deployment?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would not read this as a decision made based on any events over the last 48 hours or couple of days.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been in discussion and under discussion with our partners and Allies in the region where these troops are going for several weeks now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would just outline for you &#8212; I know some of you may have watched John Kirby&#8217;s briefing, but just to give some more specifics: A thousand service members from the U.S. Army&#8217;s 2nd Cavalry Regiment, which is based in Germany, will reposition to Romania in the coming days.&nbsp; Secretary Austin had discussed this possibility and this deployment to Romania last week in his conversation with the Romanian Defense Minister.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, we are moving 1,700 service members from Fort Bragg to Poland, and approximately 300 service members from Fort Bragg to Germany.&nbsp; Both of these moves are to supplement existing U.S. force presence in Poland and Germany.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These forces are separate and in addition to the 8,500 personnel in the United States on heightened alert position &#8212; posture that we announced last week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I would also note, Zeke, just to finish &#8212; the answer &#8212; answering your question that, you know, the President has been clear since the beginning of the escalation and the building of troops at the border, and been directly clear with President Putin in &#8212; as he was in really December: If Russia stays on an escalatory path, which they clearly have, we will make force posture adjustments to deter and defend against any aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is not troops that will go into Ukraine.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not fighting in Ukraine.&nbsp; These &#8212; this is us &#8212; this is the United States abiding by our commitments under Article 5 to support, reassure our partners in the region.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And for &#8212; what is the milestone the President is looking for to &#8212; for those troops to come back home?&nbsp; What is the &#8212; is it if Russia de-escalates, those troops would go back to their &#8212; to their bases?&nbsp; Is that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as you touched on, it&#8217;s not permanent.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not intended to be permanent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, again, we already had a troop presence in all of these countries where we are doing an increase in troops.&nbsp; So, I can&#8217;t give you an evaluation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, if Russia decides to de-escalate &#8212; to take de-escalatory steps, then certainly that would impact what the force posture needs are in other parts of the region.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Senator Hawley was out with a statement today saying that the &#8212; that the President should, sort of, take NATO membership off the table for Ukraine and that it wasn&#8217;t in U.S. interests to do that.&nbsp; Do you think that sort of rhetoric or, sort of, position by a U.S. senator right now is helpful in this &#8212; in this showdown between the West and Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, if you are just digesting Russian misinformation and parroting Russian talking points, you are not aligned with longstanding, bipartisan American values, which is to stand up for the sovereignty of countries &#8212; like Ukraine, but others: their right to choose their own alliances and, also, to stand against, very clearly, the efforts or attempts or potential attempts by any country to invade and take territory of another country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That applies to Senator Hawley, but it also applies to others who may be parroting the talking points of Russian propagandist leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On a different topic, there&#8217;s been a lot of reporting in the last couple of days about how the U.S. is sitting, at per &#8212; on a per capita basis, with peer developed countries.&nbsp; The death rate in United States is far outpacing what’s being seen abroad, largely as a result of the lower vaccination and boosting rates here, as well as some other comorbidities and the like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But does the President feel that he bears responsibility that, you know, a year into office, with this new wave, that the U.S. wasn&#8217;t better prepared and that more people are dying here on a per capita basis than are &#8212; than in Europe, for instance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the buck always stops with the President, and he would say that.&nbsp; But I would also tell you, Zeke, that the steps that we have taken to make progress, to prepare in the United States far outweigh what almost any other country in the world has done to date.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That includes ensuring that 87 percent of the population has had at least one dose; inclu- &#8212; continuing to increase the number of people who are boosted; ensuring we are taking steps to keep our schools open, to make sure communities that have surges have the federal resources they need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, of course, we are still at war with a virus; that is continuing.&nbsp; And it &#8212; and that is the President&#8217;s top priority.&nbsp; He has said that before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I would also note all of those steps that we have taken to ensure we are prepared as we have ups and downs in this pandemic.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, sorry, just one last one.&nbsp; Yesterday, you mentioned that it’s the policy of the administration not &#8212; to no longer comment on conversations with Joe Manchin about &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I didn’t say “Joe Manchin.”&nbsp; I said &#8212; you were often asking me about Joe Manchin, so I think that was the context of the question, which is absolutely fine.&nbsp; But it is our policy to not give specifics or to &#8212; to try not to give specifics of private conversations the President is having with members of the Senate, members of Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are times &#8212; I know, yesterday, of course, we had Senator Grassley and Senator Durbin here, and we did a pool spray of that.&nbsp; So, you may say that&#8217;s contradictory, but our effort and our focus is on making progress, and sometimes that means keeping those conversations private &#8212; oftentimes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m just curious because this is a shift from where you were a few months ago.&nbsp; Is that only because the Build Back Better bill failed?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that why this policy has changed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s a recognition that a lot more progress can be made when you&#8217;re having private discussions, and that the President&#8217;s focus &#8212; in terms of what we&#8217;re publicly communicating, how he&#8217;s speaking to the American people &#8212; needs to be on what he&#8217;s doing to make their lives better, not constant updates on the legislative process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On the troops that were deployed today &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you’ve said that they aren’t going to be fighting; they&#8217;ll be there to offer support.&nbsp; Can you offer any details about exactly what they will be doing there?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, about the distribution to these specific countries &#8212; why these three places?&nbsp; And why the 2,000 versus 1,000?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, well, what &#8212; to be clear, they&#8217;re not going to Ukraine to fight, right?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In a &#8212; so, I know that&#8217;s what you were asking, but just for clarity for the transcript purposes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this &#8212; our effort and our objective here has been to ensure we are ready for every contingency, and force posture increases as part of that preparedness.&nbsp; It&#8217;s to reassure our Allies &#8212; to whom, as I&#8217;ve said, we have a sacred obligation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This force &#8212; or these forces who have gone are trained and equipped for a variety of missions: to deter aggression, and to reassure and defend our Allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of why the specific numbers, I&#8217;d really point you the Department of Defense, who makes the recommendations and, ultimately, you know, proposes for the President to sign off.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would note that a number of our NATO Allies have recently announced troop movements as well, similar to what was announced this morning &#8212; so, including the United Kingdom, France, Spain, Denmark, and the Netherlands &#8212; of their intent to deploy additional forces to reinforce NATO&#8217;s easter flank &#8212; eastern flank as well.&nbsp; So, this is a reflection of our robust capabilities and our ability to distribute them across Europe, but it&#8217;s also consistent with a lot of &#8212; what a lot of our NATO partners are doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; John Kirby said that the Pentagon has not ruled out deploying additional troops.&nbsp; Under what conditions would that happen?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; These, again, are &#8212; these decisions were based on close consultations with our partners in the region; the countries where these troops have been deployed to, of course; and also, the escalatory actions by Russia.&nbsp; But, you know, obviously the President is meeting with his national security team on nearly a daily basis and will make evaluations as needed.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then changing the topics: Senator Luján has been hospitalized after suffering a stroke.&nbsp; In addition to offering well wishes, of course, some of his Democratic colleagues have said this is a reminder that in such a close Senate, any unexpected development could be a challenge to moving forward their agenda.&nbsp; So, has the President spoken with Senator Luján?&nbsp; And does he share similar concerns?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not at this point.&nbsp; I &#8212; let me just reiterate &#8212; I know you referenced them &#8212; but that we have all been thinking of Senator Luján and his family.&nbsp; I know his team put out an update on his recovery last night.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s 49 years old, so I would also note that.&nbsp; But I would point you to them for any specifics on his status.&nbsp; Of course, we&#8217;re thinking about him, his family, his entire team at this point in time.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not sure what you&#8217;re referring to in terms of concerns about &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For example, Senator Coons brought up yesterday that, you know, this could be a challenge for moving forward since they &#8212; you know, that 50-50 split is so critical.&nbsp; So, is that something that the President has also considered?&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>MS.&nbsp; PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, life is precious, as we know.&nbsp; You&#8217;re most familiar with the average age of senators in the Senate, but that is true on both sides of the aisle.&nbsp; So, I would just say, we spend most of our time engaging in good faith about the President&#8217;s agenda and not making those calculations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just one more on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Given the President&#8217;s commitment to diversify it, will he make similar pledges should he have another opportunity to nominate someone?&nbsp; For example, there&#8217;s never been an Asian American justice or an LGBTQ justice.&nbsp; So, will he make a similar pledge?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that &#8212; about judges or just in general, I would say that if you look at the President&#8217;s record of judges &#8212; circuit court judges, lower court judges &#8212; it speaks for itself.&nbsp;<br><br>He has had a enormous number of justices he &#8212; judges he has nominated who are people of color, who are women.&nbsp; He has nominated and confirmed an extraordinarily diverse bench of qualified individuals to serve on the courts.&nbsp; And that is certainly a priority for him.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t have any new pledges to announce for you.&nbsp; But I think I would point you to his record, which speaks to his commitment to ensuring the court is more diverse &#8212; lower courts are more diverse, the higher courts are more diverse &#8212; and that that is something he certainly will continue to look at as a priority.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, sorry.&nbsp; I’ll come back to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s okay.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was just going to ask another follow-up on the troop movements.&nbsp; Is President Biden concerned that Putin might use them as a pretext to act against Ukraine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what&#8217;s important to be very clear about here is that there is one aggressor here &#8212; that aggressor is Russia.&nbsp; They are the ones who have gathered tens of thousands of troops on the border.&nbsp; They are the ones who are threatening to invade a sovereign country.&nbsp;<br><br>NATO is a defensive alliance.&nbsp; The steps and actions we are taking are to provide reassurance and readiness to our partners in the region.&nbsp;<br><br>If Putin &#8212; President Putin and the Russians decide to de-escalate, that would be a welcome step.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a follow-up on the energy issue.&nbsp; Qatar has said it will divert cargoes if needed but needs the U.S. to help mediate changes in supply contracts.&nbsp; Who is the U.S. talking to about diverting supplies?&nbsp; And are any countries willing to forego their Qatari supplies to help Europe?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly understand the question.&nbsp; I would just note that we&#8217;re talking to a range of countries and suppliers, not any one individual country.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, Qatar is a large supplier of oil in the world, so that is certainly a statement of fact.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any private &#8212; anything about our private conversations to read out from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just a quick final one: Does Biden plan to watch the Olympics &#8212; U.S. athletes competing?&nbsp; I think it starts Friday.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, absolutely.&nbsp; We all do.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to rule out an Olympics outfit here.&nbsp; I would encourage all of you to do the same.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Yes, we are looking forward to it and to cheering on our American athletes who will be competing.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more on the troop movements.&nbsp; Can you explain a bit more why the President decided to move unilaterally before NATO approved a multilateral deployment?&nbsp; I mean, you&#8217;ve talked often in here about how fiercely united the U.S. is with our NATO Allies.&nbsp; Is there a concern that this undercuts that sense of unity?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; And this is an important question because a lot of our NATO partners have done something &#8212; taken a similar step.&nbsp; In fact, five other of our NATO Allies have taken steps; the United Kingdom, France, Spain, Denmark, and the Netherlands have all said they have the intent to deploy additional forces to reinforce NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.&nbsp;<br><br>So, these decisions can be made on a unilateral basis by the United States or any of our NATO partners to boost up support.&nbsp; And obviously, the NATO Alliance as a whole would decide if there was going to be a movement of the NATO Alliance forces.&nbsp;<br><br>So, this is something that we have always had the capability to do, as an &#8212; as all these other countries do as well, and it&#8217;s an option, in addition to what we&#8217;ve done to support and plus up our NATO Alli- &#8212; our NATO partners &#8212; our NATO Alliance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I think it&#8217;s still not clear though that &#8212; why?&nbsp; I mean, I know you&#8217;ve &#8212; we’ve been &#8212; you’ve been addressing this here.&nbsp; But why now, then &#8212; given that you&#8217;re saying there&#8217;s no new evidence that&#8217;s come to light, necessarily?&nbsp; It&#8217;s not that you have a sense that Putin is going to invade any more so than you thought a few days ago.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s true.&nbsp; But &#8212; and I just noted that &#8212; that it wasn&#8217;t an event, because I think the way Zeke asked the question &#8212; “in the last day or two” or “over the weekend” or something like that.<br><br>There &#8212; this has been under discussion for some time now with our NATO partners and, of course, within the administration.&nbsp;<br><br>There &#8212; it is also true that it is &#8212; there’s no question that Russia and President Putin has continued to take escalatory, not de-escalatory, steps.&nbsp;<br><br>So, it is not that it is one moment.&nbsp; It is &#8212; we are looking at events over the course of time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And at the risk of sounding like a broken record: On the Supreme Court search, has the President made any plans to meet in person with any of the nominees?&nbsp; Has he had any direct conversations with any of these potential candidates yet?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re just not going to provide updates from here on the process.&nbsp; Certainly, meeting with the nominees will be &#8212; well, obviously, with the nominee &#8212; but meeting with candidates will be a part of the process.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t expect we&#8217;d provide a play-by-play on that from here.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Kaitlan.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Two weeks ago, at his press conference, the President said quote, “We&#8217;re going to actually increase troop presence in Poland, in Romania…if in fact he moves,” referring to President Putin.&nbsp; He has not moved yet to invade Ukraine, as far as we know.&nbsp; So, can you explain, in the last two weeks, why that calculus has changed for President Biden?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I wouldn&#8217;t say the calculus has changed, as much as we look at a range of events over the course of time.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no question that if you look at President Putin&#8217;s actions, they have been escalatory, not de-escalatory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But clearly, he&#8217;s been &#8212; this has been a topic of discussion from &#8212; among our national security team and also between our national security team and their counterparts for some time now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President worried that Putin is going to try to invade a NATO Ally?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President wants to &#8212; we&#8217;re certainly hopeful he would not.&nbsp; But the President wants to take steps to reassure our &#8212; countries in the region that are part of the NATO Alliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, Russia is a country, President Putin is a leader who has invaded two sovereign countries in the last several &#8212; several years.&nbsp; You know, he&#8217;s somebody who has used chemical weapons.&nbsp; He&#8217;s somebody who has pushed propaganda around the world. &nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re not predicting that he has made a decision; we don&#8217;t know that.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also taking the steps to be ready and to be prepared.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are removing these forces that are now being deployed &#8212; is that contingent on Putin removing his troops from Ukraine&#8217;s border?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Removing &#8212; oh, these troops &#8212; troops in Eastern Europe?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The 3,000 troops that the President is sending to NATO Allies that he signed off on yesterday, is that contingent on Putin de-escalating &#8212; not just de-escalating but actually removing his troops from the Ukrainian border?</p>



<p><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, if President Putin took de-escalatory steps, that certainly would impact our calculus.</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t have anything to outline from here.&nbsp; That&#8217;s obviously a decision and recommendations that would be made by the Department of Defense.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And one last question.&nbsp; Last week, I believe, in here, you said that you &#8212; the assessment still was that a Russian invasion is “imminent.”&nbsp; That&#8217;s the word that you used before, that other officials have used, and you used it last week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But yesterday, the Ambassador to the United Nations, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, said she would not use the word “imminent.”&nbsp; She said she does not think a Russian invasion of Ukraine is imminent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I guess we just need some clarification on where that assessment stands right now.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I used that once.&nbsp; I think others have used that once.&nbsp; And then we stopped using it because I think it sent an &#8212; a message that we weren&#8217;t intending to send, which was that we knew that President Putin had made a decision.&nbsp;<br><br>I would say the vast majority of times I&#8217;ve talked about it, we said, “He could invade at any time.”&nbsp; That&#8217;s true; we still don&#8217;t know that he&#8217;s made a decision.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, so you&#8217;re not using that word (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I used it once last week.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the decision now is that you&#8217;re not describing it as “imminent” anymore?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t in over a week.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Just another question, first on President Putin and, sort of, the message coming from Russia.&nbsp; He, yesterday, expressed hope for diplomacy.&nbsp; And after the U.S. announcement on troops today, the Russian Deputy Foreign Minister called the move “unjustified” and “destructive.”&nbsp; So how do you &#8212; what is your response to, sort of, their rhetoric of, you know, calling for diplomacy here, given what their posture is on the border of Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say: Be very open-eyed about Russian propaganda and what they&#8217;re putting out there.&nbsp; We know what is happening on the border.&nbsp; Everybody can open their eyes and see they have gathered more than 100,000 troops at the border.&nbsp; They have also built up troops in Belarus at another border.&nbsp; That has not changed.&nbsp; We have not seen de-escalatory actions.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, we don&#8217;t know that President Putin has made a decision to act, and that ensures &#8212; means that we are going to, of course, continue to leave the door open to diplomacy.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to discuss and engage where we can find common ground with Russia &#8212; with Russian leaders.&nbsp; That doesn&#8217;t mean that we are going to bow to what their demands are on issues like NATO and what &#8212; and the right of any sovereign country to be able to choose which alliances they pursue.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been clear on that from the beginning.<br><br>But, you know, diplomacy means you agree on some things, you disagree on others, you try to figure out where you have common ground, and that&#8217;s the process that we&#8217;re still undergoing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On another subject, the House is working through the China bill right now, and there were some amendments that were released last night.&nbsp; There&#8217;s an effort by some House members to attach guardrails to CHIPS funding, which would mean they wouldn&#8217;t be able to get U.S. taxpayer dollars while also investing in China.&nbsp; Does the administration have a view on that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get into any specifics about the negotiations that are ongoing.&nbsp; Certainly, the President is eager to sign the competition bill into law.&nbsp;<br><br>I would also note that Mr. McCarthy made clear he was going to whip against this bill, and let&#8217;s just think about how ludicrous that is.&nbsp; He is a leader in the Republican House.&nbsp; This is a bill that would help address supply chain issues.&nbsp; It would help make us more competitive with China.&nbsp; It would provide more than $50 billion in funding to ensure there&#8217;s chips manufacturing here in the United States &#8212; which would help, by the way, reduce and prevent inflation over time in an industry where one third of inflationary pressure is coming from, which is the car industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there are important discussions happening right now, but the whipping against this legislation &#8212; legislation that warranted a great deal of bipartisan support in the Senate &#8212; is certainly a question that hopefully House Republicans will have to answer for.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just another China question on a little bit of a different subject, which is the COVID tests that are being sent out by the federal government.&nbsp; The Chinese company Andon Health owns iHealth, which is one of the providers.&nbsp; They have a &#8212; they signed a $1.3 billion contract with the Pentagon last month for these tests.</p>



<p>Is the administration concerned about, sort of, both the &#8212; the, sort of, optics and messaging of sending something to Americans&#8217; homes that says &#8212; says &#8220;Made in China&#8221; on it at the same time that you&#8217;re, you know, doing this thing that you consider to be a positive good for Americans, and just kind of the overall, you know, philosophy of giving federal contracts to China?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say our objective continues to be to increase U.S. manufacturing capacity of tests.&nbsp; We also needed to meet a need that we had in this country for more tests and a shortage of tests and the understandable demand from people across this country to get tests and make them free and accessible, which required us purchasing some of those tests from China in order to meet that demand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that doesn&#8217;t change our commitment to increasing our U.S. manufacturing to ensure that we will be able to meet that demand with products made here in the United States over the course of time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Yesterday, the national debt passed $30 trillion for the first time.&nbsp; Does the administration see that as a problem?&nbsp; Or do you share the view of some economists that debt doesn&#8217;t matter?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President believes we need to have a sustainable and responsible fixed fiscal policy, which is why he put forward ways to pay for his major proposals.&nbsp; He&#8217;s committed to a sustainable and responsible policy in ensuring that our long-term investments are fully paid for, like Build Back Better.</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note that this stands in significant contrast from the previous administration and Republicans in Congress, which passed a $1.5 trillion tax cut for wealthy taxpayers in 2017 and didn&#8217;t pay for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we look to the debt, which obviously the President wants to be lower, it&#8217;s important to note that more than 95 percent of the national debt was incurred before he took office.&nbsp; The national debt increased by $7.8 trillion during former President Trump&#8217;s presidency, which accounts for about 30 percent of its total.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are working to address, we are working to be fiscally responsible, and that certainly is a priority to the President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; One more on Afghanistan.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a new report out from the U.N. that says that more than 100 former members of the Afghan government and other Afghan allies of the U.S. have been killed since the Taliban returned to power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are additional reports that thousands of Afghan allies of the U.S. are still in Afghanistan.&nbsp; They&#8217;re hiding out.&nbsp; They can&#8217;t get to the U.S. because of issues with a Special Immigrant Visa.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Does the administration consider it a priority to get these people out of Afghanistan?&nbsp; And if so, why are they still there six months after we withdrew?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We absolutely do.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve &#8212; we have also helped thousands of our Afghan partners leave Afghanistan since our full withdrawal at the end of August.</p>



<p>As has been reported, there was a delay in &#8212; or there was a gap where there were not flights.&nbsp; Those have resumed, which is a good sign, which will hopefully enable us to continue to get more people out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, the President also met with the Qatari leader earlier this week.&nbsp; They have been an important partner here, as we don&#8217;t have the diplomatic presence, as you well know, that we had prior.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would just note that from the beginning, we&#8217;ve been able to evacuate more than 120,000 people from Afghanistan &#8212; some American citizens, many of them Afghan partners and allies, people who have fought alongside us during the 20-year war.&nbsp; And that is the largest evacuation since the Vietnam War.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I would say we are still committed to doing this.&nbsp; We are not naïve about the challenges, nor are we naïve about the conditions on the ground, which is why we are so focused on getting humanitarian assistance to the people in Afghanistan through trusted and reliable sources.</p>



<p>But it is a good sign that the flights have resumed.&nbsp; Obviously, this was a topic of discussion with the Qataris earlier this week as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just on schools: New Orleans became the first major district in the country to have a vaccine mandate for all students go into effect yesterday.&nbsp; We know how you guys feel about the need to get vaccinated.&nbsp; But will the White House press other districts to follow in New Orleans&#8217;s steps?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will always &#8212; we believe that it&#8217;s up to school districts to make decisions about what steps they put in place, and we would certainly advise all of them to follow CDC guidance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the mandate: There are a number of exemptions that parents can apply for.&nbsp; It&#8217;s pretty easy to get an exemption.&nbsp; Does the White House think that sort of defeats the purpose of the mandate or is that okay?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have exemptions that we implement in the federal government as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Staying on education: Yesterday, also, before the President paused student loan debt repayments &#8212; or, I guess, extended the pause in late 2021 &#8212; it was supposed to resume yesterday.&nbsp; Is the Department of Education pushing forward any other steps to make sure that when those payments relaunch in May, borrowers will be able to make them?&nbsp; Or will the President extend that pause again?&nbsp; Or is he still considering executive action to forgive student loan debt again?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I would note that no one has been required to pay a single dime of federal student loans since the President took office.&nbsp; As you noted, he extended that pause to May to give breathing room to borrowers who are still coping with the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He certainly also supports Congress for providing $10,000 in debt relief &#8212; a bill he would be happy to sign into law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have any additional executive orders to predict at this point in time.&nbsp; But certainly, in May, if these &#8212; if this resumes, the Education Department &#8212; the Education Department will continue working to ensure a smooth transition to repayment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Last week, President Biden and President Zelenskyy discussed a macroeconomic package of assistance for Ukraine.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the status of those negotiations?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the scope and scale of that package?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the holdup, given that the economic damage is happening in real time from the Russian threat and the U.S. already announced its economic package?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, we have been discussing with the Ukrainians an economic &#8212; a package of economic assistance.&nbsp; That package and discussion has been underway, obviously, with &#8212; at the leader level but also beyond.&nbsp; At this point in time, I think the discussion is with other counterparts from our government and theirs about next steps.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, this was not the first economic package that we are providing to the Ukrainians.&nbsp; We have provided a significant amount of assistance &#8212; not just security assistance, but humanitarian and other economic assistance &#8212; over the course of time, so that would certainly build on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of a next step, I can check and see if there&#8217;s any &#8212; anything specific to update you on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And just to follow up on the troop levels, why did the President authorize a deployment specifically to Poland and Romania?&nbsp; Are they considered the most vulnerable of the eastern flank countries &#8212; compared to, say, Hungary or the Baltics?&nbsp; And is it because the negotiations with the other countries haven&#8217;t worked out, or is it because these are considered the most vulnerable members?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think as my colleague, John Kirby, conveyed, we&#8217;re also &#8212; we&#8217;ve left the door open to additional &#8212; I&#8217;ve nothing to predict on that front.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this was based on &#8212; or this announcement and deployment was based on consultations and conversations with these countries where we have sent these troops.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more details about behind-the-scenes conversation to lay out from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Senator Graham and Congressman Clyburn have been calling for educational diversity on the Court, suggesting the President should choose someone who attended a public university rather than an Ivy League school, for example.&nbsp; As the graduate of a public university &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Me too.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; does the President &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Who else here?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; does the President have any &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Public schools.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) about the President.&nbsp; Does he have any thoughts on that as a graduate of a public university?&nbsp; Will that factor into his consideration at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, I certainly understand the question.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve seen their comments.&nbsp; I would say the President&#8217;s &#8212; and we certainly appreciate Senator Graham&#8217;s thoughts and, of course, those of Mr. Clyburn.</p>



<p>What the President&#8217;s focus is on is choosing from a wealth of deeply qualified candidates who bring to bear the strongest records, credentials, and abilities that anyone could have for this role.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, he has nominated judges who do not &#8212; have not gone to Ivy League schools.&nbsp; So I think that speaks to his value for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of the credentials, I don&#8217;t have any more specifics to lay out for you today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And related to that, though, I also just wanted to ask about candidates who have already gone through a judicial confirmation process &#8212; either for the district court level or the appeals court level.&nbsp; Is that something the President is going to be taking into consideration: whether they&#8217;ve already made it through the Senate Judiciary Committee once before?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President’s focus is, again, choosing from a wealth of highly qualified candidates who bring to bear strong records, credentials, and abilities to serve on the Court in a lifetime appointment.&nbsp; That is his focus &#8212; and also doing that through consultation with Republican and Democratic members of the Senate and experts, not on navigating the legislative process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And shifting gears to one infrastructure question.&nbsp; The &#8212; a number of Florida Republicans have complained about the implementation of the new infrastructure law.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Who?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, certainly Governor DeSantis, Senator Rubio.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What are their complaints?&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t even seen them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, among the things they have complained about is they&#8217;ve suggested the state was shortchanged on bridge funding, that it should’ve gotten a bigger distribution.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve complained that the Everglades funding that was announced the other week should have been higher.&nbsp; Coming from Senators Rubio, Scott, and members of the House delegation who voted against the bill.&nbsp; Does the White House have any response to lawmakers who opposed the bill in the first place complaining that their share of the bill isn&#8217;t higher?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s pretty rich, isn&#8217;t it?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would say, first, I think the Everglades funding &#8212; I don&#8217;t have it in front of me, but I believe it&#8217;s in the billions, if I&#8217;m correct. You may have the exact number.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; $1.1 billion.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; There is also an enormous &#8212; I mentioned this a little bit yesterday: About 90 percent of the competitive funding that&#8217;s available will go to localities, territories, others who can apply for it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we put out this big book just a few days ago: so people know the criteria where they can apply for that funding.</p>



<p>You know, I think Mitch Landrieu, when he was here, quoted, I think, a Nancy Pelosi quote, so I&#8217;m just going to quote it.&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; you know, now I can&#8217;t even remember it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the point is, even if you vote against it, you still want the money.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that over the course of time.&nbsp; That&#8217;s speaks to how political a lot of these votes were, given this is funding that will help rebuild a lot of these communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the President will certainly be making clear who was with him and who wasn&#8217;t with him.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last week, the Vice President&#8217;s appeal to governors to help with the defense of voting rights &#8212; does the administration feel that the effort for national voting rights legislation is dead?&nbsp; And if so, is it now going to focus its efforts at state level?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have to do both.&nbsp; So, federal legislation is important for a number of reasons, including that it creates a baseline of requirements &#8212; requirements or standards in states so people can know, who are fearful, about how they can vote; when they can vote &#8212; if you&#8217;re a mom of three kids, you should have a lot of options for dropping off your ballot or going to vote early; and ensuring those requirements are standard across states.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It also ensures that for states that have histories of voter suppression, that they would have to seek approval from the Department of Justice to make changes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a good thing.</p>



<p>So, we are going to have to &#8212; we&#8217;re still fighting for those.&nbsp; The President has said he will fight for those until his last breath.</p>



<p>At the same time, what I think the Vice President was talking about and she will be playing a vital role in is working with states and localities on how we can fight against oppressive voter suppression &#8212; voter laws that are popping up in states; how we can empower and engage populations to ensure they know what their rights are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re ha- &#8212; we’re going to do both, and it&#8217;s important to do both.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Mitch McConnell said today, given the current COVID facts and science, “It is time for the state of emergency to wind down.”&nbsp; Does the President agree with that?&nbsp; And is that still possible when there&#8217;s that hardcore of anti-vaccination people?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I didn&#8217;t see the full context of Mr. McConnell&#8217;s comments.&nbsp; I will say that the President&#8217;s view is that we&#8217;re not going to live like this forever; we don&#8217;t want to live like this forever.&nbsp; And our objective and our goal is on ending this pandemic as we know it today so we don&#8217;t have it &#8212; it is &#8212; so it&#8217;s not something that&#8217;s disrupting our daily lives.</p>



<p>We do more &#8212; we&#8217;ll do more and more to protect people and accelerate the path out of this pandemic.&nbsp; There is a lot of progress that&#8217;s been made.&nbsp; Two hundred and ten million people are fully vaccinated; that&#8217;s nearly 75 percent of adults.&nbsp; We had less than 1 percent vaccinated when the President took office.&nbsp; About 98 percent of schools are open.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we understand the sentiment that I think he&#8217;s expressing, even if I haven&#8217;t seen the full context.&nbsp; We&#8217;re of course looking at, when the time comes, what it will mean to end the pandemic as we know it today.&nbsp; But right now, what our focus is on is ensuring we&#8217;re implementing the tools that we know that work as we&#8217;re still continuing to fight the virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, in the back.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The Pentagon says that Poland and Romania requested U.S. troops &#8212; U.S deployment.&nbsp; Have you received similar requests from other eastern flank countries, Baltic states?&nbsp; And what will trigger additional troops&#8217; deployment to the eastern flank?&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to have one more.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m just not going to detail those private diplomatic conversations.&nbsp; I would point you to the Pentagon if they want to share any more detail; I&#8217;d be surprised if they did.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But certainly we &#8212; those conversations are continuing; they&#8217;re not done. &nbsp;And I think my colleague, John Kirby, made that clear during his briefing today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more.&nbsp; Has President Biden consulted this decision with the leaders of the Republican Party, and how does he feel about their support?&nbsp; Because there were some voices of the American Right questioning President Biden&#8217;s policy towards the Russia-Ukraine crisis.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that we have had an enormous amount of &#8212; we&#8217;ve done an enormous amount of briefing and engagement with Democratic and Republican leaders about the decision-making and how we&#8217;re approaching the escalatory nature of Russia&#8217;s behavior on the border.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Leader McCo- &#8212; or Senator McConnell made some comments in that regard last week.&nbsp; And this is an issue, in our view, that should not be partisan.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re doing here is we&#8217;re standing up for what have long been bipartisan American values, which is standing up for the sovereignty of a country; ensuring that they have the right and the ability to choose their own alliances; supporting them with a range of economic, humanitarian, and security assistance; and doing that in a way that&#8217;s coordinated with our partners and Allies.</p>



<p>There are some from the Republican Party who have not &#8212; not voiced support for that.&nbsp; And again, as I said a little bit earlier in the briefing, if you are echoing &#8212; if you are digesting Russian misinformation and parroting Russian propaganda, you may be on the wrong side of this issue.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Two questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The first: Does the President know who Leonard Peltier is?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure he does, but I have not discussed it with him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Just call me and let me know if he knows.</p>



<p>Is he aware of the push by Democratic senators and members of Congress and Native state legislators &#8212; and even Pope Francis, at one point &#8212; to send Peltier home from prison?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not discussed this with him specifically.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to see if there&#8217;s any more follow-up.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then my second question is about the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Some Republican senators, like Ted Cruz, are criticizing Biden for saying he&#8217;ll pick a Black woman for the Supreme Court. He said it’s, quote, unquote, “offensive,” because somehow the Black woman he chooses wouldn&#8217;t be the most qualified for the job.</p>



<p>But Republicans like Cruz also celebrated when Trump picked Amy Coney Barrett for the Supreme Court, with Cruz telling Barrett during her confirmation hearing, quote, “Your children have been wonderfully well behaved.&nbsp; I think you&#8217;re an amazing role model for little girls.&nbsp; What advice would you give little girls?”</p>



<p>So, my question for you is: Why do you think Republicans like Ted Cruz are acting so angry about Biden picking a Black woman for the Supreme Court, when they were very happy when Trump picked Amy Coney Barrett for the Court?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: I read that exact quote yesterday.&nbsp; I&#8217;m glad lots of people are following it.&nbsp; You know, I think that&#8217;s really a question for Senator Cruz.&nbsp; But it is important to note, as you just did in your question, that there has never &#8212; there was never an objection by Senator Cruz to Donald Trump promising he&#8217;d nominate a woman in 2020.&nbsp; You noted what he said to the woman he nominated in the hearing and how he applauded her in the hearing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The notion &#8212; the President&#8217;s view is the notion that there has not been a Black woman ever on the Supreme Court in 230 years is a problem with the process, not a lack of qualified, credentialed people to consider and nominate.</p>



<p>And, you know, that&#8217;s his view, but I think that&#8217;s a question best for Senator Cruz.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why do you think &#8212; what&#8217;s the difference between Trump picking Amy Coney Barrett and saying he&#8217;d pick a woman in advance, and Biden picking a Black woman and saying &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly why I called out this issue yesterday.&nbsp; But I am blissfully not a spokesperson for Senator Cruz, so he can best answer that question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, just a quick question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Senator Schumer is apparently coming here today to meet with the President about the Supreme Court pick and process.&nbsp; Can you confirm that?&nbsp; Do you have any other information on what their conversation (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I believe it was under discussion to figure out how they could connect, whether it was on the phone or in person.&nbsp; Let me see if I can get more details on it, but it&#8217;s part of the consultation process that you&#8217;ve seen take place over the past couple of days.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.</p>



<p>1:14 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr.’s Call with President Emmanuel Macron of&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-s-call-with-president-emmanuel-macron-of-france-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:34:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France regarding Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. The two leaders affirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and reviewed our ongoing coordination on both diplomacy and preparations to impose swift and severe economic costs on Russia should it further&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France regarding Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. The two leaders affirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and reviewed our ongoing coordination on both diplomacy and preparations to impose swift and severe economic costs on Russia should it further invade Ukraine.  President Biden and President Macron agreed their teams will stay in close touch, including in consultation with NATO Allies and EU partners, on our coordinated and comprehensive approach to managing these issues.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 23:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Stephanie Dawkins Davis, of Michigan, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Sixth Circuit, vice Helene N. White, retiring. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stephanie Dawkins Davis, of Michigan, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Sixth Circuit, vice Helene N. White, retiring.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Additional Advisors for Supreme Court&#160;Process</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/president-biden-announces-additional-advisors-for-supreme-court-process/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 22:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46453</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As President Biden considers a range of deeply qualified potential nominees for the Supreme Court and seeks the advice of lawmakers in both parties as well as legal experts across the country, he is adding three new advisors for the nomination and confirmation process. These advisors bring decades of experience to the table and will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As President Biden considers a range of deeply qualified potential nominees for the Supreme Court and seeks the advice of lawmakers in both parties as well as legal experts across the country, he is adding three new advisors for the nomination and confirmation process.</p>



<p>These advisors bring decades of experience to the table and will join the White House team working with the President on the selection of the nation’s first Black woman to the Supreme Court, reporting to White House Counsel Dana Remus as the President continues to review candidates.</p>



<p>The White House officials currently advising the President on his selection are the Vice President, White House Chief of Staff Ron Klain, Remus, Director of Legislative Affairs Louisa Terrell, White House Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond, Deputy Director of Legislative Affairs Reema Dodin, Senior Counsel to the President Paige Herwig, Counsel to the Vice President Josh Hsu.</p>



<p><strong>Doug Jones, Nomination Advisor for Legislative Affairs</strong></p>



<p><strong>Doug Jones&nbsp;</strong>is a former United States Senator from the State of Alabama. He will advise President Biden on navigating the Senate confirmation process.&nbsp; The first Democratic Senator from Alabama in a quarter century, Jones passed dozens of bipartisan bills into law and started a bipartisan tradition of reading Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.’s “Letter from a Birmingham Jail” in the Senate chamber.&nbsp; Jones was previously the U.S. Attorney for the Northern District of Alabama, where he prosecuted and won the conviction of two Ku Klux Klan members for the 1963 Birmingham church bombing that killed four African-American girls.&nbsp; A native of Fairfield, Alabama, Jones is a graduate of the University of Alabama and Samford University.</p>



<p><strong>Minyon Moore, Nomination Advisor for Engagement</strong></p>



<p><strong>Minyon Moore</strong>&nbsp;is a top public affairs strategist and organizer tapped by President Biden to mobilize a nationwide engagement effort focused on confirmation. &nbsp;Moore currently leads Dewey Square Group’s State and Local Affairs and Multicultural Strategies practices, where she helps clients build coalitions and engage on public policy goals.&nbsp; Moore previously served as President Clinton’s Director of White House Political Affairs and Director the White House Office of Public Liaison, as well as Chief Operating Officer of the Democratic National Committee. &nbsp;Moore coauthored <em>For Colored Girls Who Have Considered Politics</em>&nbsp;in 2018. &nbsp;A Chicago native, she attended the University of Illinois at Chicago and graduated from the Boston University Digital Filmmaking Program (DC).</p>



<p><strong>Ben LaBolt, Nomination Advisor for Communications</strong></p>



<p><strong>Ben LaBolt</strong> is a leading communications strategist joining the White House to advise President Biden on communications and messaging around the confirmation process.  LaBolt is a partner at Bully Pulpit Interactive who served as an advisor to the Biden-Harris Transition. He was previously the national press secretary for President Obama’s re-election campaign and a White House Assistant Press Secretary.  LaBolt has two decades of experience advising for national, state, and local elected officials and campaigns, and served as the White House spokesman on the team to confirm Justice Sonia Sotomayor and Justice Elena Kagan.  A native of LaGrange, Illinois, LaBolt is a graduate of Middlebury College.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at an Event to Reignite the Cancer&#160;Moonshot</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/02/remarks-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-an-event-to-reignite-the-cancer-moonshot/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 22:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room, The White House  1:49 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE FIRST LADY:&#160; Hi &#8212; well, hello.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Please be seated. Gosh, so many friends here.&#160; It&#8217;s so nice to see all of you.&#160; And you&#8217;re getting me so emotional before I have to speak&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room, The White House </p>



<p>1:49 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Hi &#8212; well, hello.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Please be seated.</p>



<p>Gosh, so many friends here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s so nice to see all of you.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re getting me so emotional before I have to speak about cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, anyway, welcome to the White House.</p>



<p>And, you know, certain words have the power to make time stop: Malignant.&nbsp; Aggressive.&nbsp; Terminal.&nbsp; Cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Like a spell, they still the air around us.&nbsp; Frozen in place, we feel the world we knew slipping away.&nbsp; In the span of a breath, a thousand questions fill our minds.&nbsp; &#8220;What can I do?&nbsp; How do I tell people?&nbsp; Why did this happen?&#8221;</p>



<p>And when the hands of the clock begin to move once again, we are not the person we once were, but someone changed: a mother imagining all of the things she might not be there to teach her daughters, a husband wondering how he will juggle chemotherapy appointments with work and childcare, a son trying to be strong for the parents who could outlive him.</p>



<p>It’s not just patients; cancer changes everyone it touches.&nbsp; And in some ways, it touches us all.</p>



<p>For Joe and me, it has stolen our joy.&nbsp; It left us broken in our grief.&nbsp; But through that pain, we found purpose, strengthening our fortitude for this fight to end cancer as we know it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Almost 30 years ago, four of my friends were diagnosed with breast cancer in one year.&nbsp; And one of my dear friends, Winnie, lost her battle.&nbsp; Winnie inspired me to take up the cause of prevention and education.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And since then, I’ve seen the darkness of this disease: financial devastation, confusion over care, and far too many families mourning loved ones.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yet, I’ve also seen hope.</p>



<p>In just this last year, I met a woman whose life was saved by determined nurses who just wouldn’t let her skip her screening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I met a doctor who was inspired to become a cancer researcher because she survived her own diagnosis as a child.</p>



<p>I’ve seen people come together from rival companies or opposite political parties, sharing knowledge and finding common cause, united by the chance to save lives.</p>



<p>A cancer diagnosis today may still leave us feeling hopeless, but we are not hopeless and we are not helpless.</p>



<p>We are living in a golden age of research and discovery.&nbsp; We can end this terror, and all of us have a role to play.</p>



<p>Because this isn’t just about hoping that one person will decipher the answers alone; it’s about listening to patients and survivors and their families, and easing the burden they face.</p>



<p>It’s about the individual choices we can make to stop this disease before it’s too late: to get screenings, to be vigilant with our health.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s about federal and state governments, the business community, and non-profit organizations all helping to make those screenings more available and accessible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s about bringing the brightest minds and the fiercest hearts to the table to learn and to collaborate and to discover together.</p>



<p>Yes, cancer has the power to rewrite our lives.&nbsp; But we have the power too &#8212; more than we even know.&nbsp; We can stop it in its tracks.&nbsp; We can comfort and discover and dream our way past its paralysis.&nbsp; We can come together and rewrite the story that cancer tells.</p>



<p>Now, as your First Lady, I’m deeply proud to be a partner in the commitments we’re making to the Cancer Moonshot today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re ensuring that all of our government is ready to get to work.&nbsp; We’re going to break down the walls that hold research back.&nbsp; We’re going to bring the best of our nation together &#8212; patients, survivors, caregivers, researchers, doctors, and advocates &#8212; all of you &#8212; so that we can get this done.</p>



<p>And I want you to know that I’ll be there working right beside you.</p>



<p>So, I’m so honored to welcome all of you here to the White House today to take this next step.</p>



<p>Together, we will give Americans a reason to hope.&nbsp; We will use this power of this White House to make your life better.&nbsp; And we will build a future where the word &#8220;cancer&#8221; forever loses its power.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, it’s my pleasure to welcome out next speaker.</p>



<p>Vice President Harris knows the heartache of cancer, but she also knows how much hope can be found in our scientific community.&nbsp; She knows it because she saw it firsthand in her brilliant mother who dedicated her life to researching breast cancer.</p>



<p>Kamala, you honor your mom’s memory every single day, but I believe she’s especially proud of you today.</p>



<p>Please welcome the Vice President of the United States, Kamala Harris.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 1:57 P.M. EST</p>



<figure class="wp-block-table"><table><tbody><tr><td class="has-text-align-left" data-align="left"></td></tr></tbody></table></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Makes Fourteenth Judicial Nominations&#160;Announcement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/president-biden-makes-fourteenth-judicial-nominations-announcement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 20:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46445</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing a judicial nominee, who is extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. This choice continues to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing a judicial nominee, who is extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. This choice continues to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>Stephanie Dawkins Davis is the President’s nominee to the Sixth Circuit of the U.S. Court of Appeals.&nbsp; Judge Davis would be the first Black woman to serve on the Sixth Circuit from Michigan and only the second Black woman to serve on the Sixth Circuit.</p>



<p>This is President Biden’s fourteenth announcement of nominees for federal judicial positions, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 84.</p>



<p>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies.</p>



<p>CIRCUIT COURT<br><strong><u>Stephanie Dawkins Davis: Nominee for the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Stephanie Dawkins Davis has served as a federal judge on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan since December 2019. Judge Davis previously served as a Magistrate Judge for the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan from 2016 to 2019. From 1997 to 2016, Judge Davis served in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Michigan as Executive Assistant United States Attorney from 2010 to 2015 and as an Assistant United States Attorney from 1997 to 2010. During her tenure, she also served as Deputy Chief of the Controlled Substances Unit from 2007 to 2010. Judge Davis began her career as an associate at Dickinson, Wright PLLC in Detroit, Michigan, from 1992 to 1997. Judge Davis received her J.D. from Washington University School of Law in 1992 and her B.S. from Wichita State University in 1989.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on President&#160;Biden’s Plans to Reignite the Cancer&#160;Moonshot</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/02/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-president-bidens-plans-to-reignite-the-cancer-moonshot/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 17:28:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46405</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Via Teleconference 6:32 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MR. MUNOZ:&#160; Hey, everybody.&#160; Thank you for joining tonight’s call on how the President plans to reignite the Cancer Moonshot to end cancer as we know it.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; As a reminder, this call will be attributable to “senior administration officials” and be embargoed until tomorrow a.m. &#8212; at 5:00&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"> Via Teleconference</p>



<p>6:32 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Hey, everybody.&nbsp; Thank you for joining tonight’s call on how the President plans to reignite the Cancer Moonshot to end cancer as we know it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As a reminder, this call will be attributable to “senior administration officials” and be embargoed until tomorrow a.m. &#8212; at 5:00 a.m.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Joining us on tonight’s call is [senior administration official].&nbsp; Also joining us is [senior administration official].&nbsp; We have some remarks at the top from both of them, and we’ll have time for questions at the end.&nbsp; And we ask that you keep questions relevant to the Cancer Moonshot.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with that, I will turn it to [senior administration official].<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Welcome, everybody.&nbsp; I’m [redacted].&nbsp; I’m joined by [senior administration official, who [redacted].&nbsp; [Redacted] and will have lots to say, and we’ll both speak back and forth on the effort.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, today, we’re going to preview this announcement that the President will be making tomorrow.&nbsp; You’ve got the factsheet.&nbsp; And just to confirm, we’ll be speaking on background, and the news is under embargo until 5:00 a.m. Eastern tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;So, just to set the stage, you will all recall that as Vice President, in 2016, Joe Biden led the Cancer Moonshot with the mission of accelerating the rate of progress against cancer.&nbsp;&nbsp;And the cancer community and the patient community and medical researchers responded with tremendous energy and ingenuity.&nbsp;&nbsp;And there’s been a lot of progress that has come since then.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;And because of that and because of the amazing possibilities ahead, tomorrow, in remarks here at the White House, President Biden is going to reignite the Cancer Moonshot.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;So, [senior administration official]?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;&nbsp;Yeah, I’ll give a little bit of a preview of what the event will look like.&nbsp;&nbsp;It will take place in the East Room of the White House.&nbsp;&nbsp;The First Lady and the Vice President will also give remarks.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we will lay out, as [senior administration official] said, the President’s plan, this administration’s plan around the Cancer Moonshot.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In attendance in the room will be about 100 members of the cancer community, from patients and survivors, their caregivers and families, advocacy organizations, research organizations and individual researchers, and those from the healthcare community, representatives from industry, members of Congress, members of the Cabinet, and beyond.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we’ll have a big event, really setting the stage for this announcement.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, why is the President reigniting the Cancer Moonshot?&nbsp; Well, because a lot has changed that makes it possible to set really ambitious goals right now.<br><br>The Cancer Moonshot was launched five years ago, and lots has happened.&nbsp; In addition, I have to say that the scientific advances that we saw from the COVID-19 pandemic, from the response to it, also points to things that are possible today.<br><br>So, for all those reasons, the President is going to set some very ambitious goals: Number one, to reduce the death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent over the next 25 years &#8212; I’ll put that in context in a moment of what that means &#8212; and to really substantially improve the experience of people and their families living and surviving with cancer.&nbsp; And by doing these things and more &#8212; two, as the President likes to say and will say: to end cancer as we know it today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, the President and the First Lady are also going to announce, very importantly, a call to action on cancer screening to jumpstart progress on screenings that were missed as a result of the pandemic, and help ensure that everybody equitably benefits from the tools that we already have to prevent and detect and diagnose cancer, which are extremely valuable and we need to get everybody to be able to take full advantage of those.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, let me &#8212; let me review, just very briefly, how we got here, what’s come before.&nbsp; And then I will turn it a little bit, after [senior administration official] leaves (inaudible), to what exactly we mean by “end cancer as we know it.”<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212; but let’s go back.&nbsp; You know, 50 years ago, the National Cancer Institu- &#8212; the National Cancer Act was passed.&nbsp; And, you know, for the first 25 years or so, you really didn’t see much change in the death rate from cancer &#8212; this age-adjusted death rate that gets measured.&nbsp; It was pretty flat for a long time.&nbsp; And then we began to see a decrease.<br><br>And over the last 20 or so years, the age-adjusted death rate from cancer has fallen by about 25 percent.&nbsp; And that is really remarkable.&nbsp; It had been flat, and now it fell by 25 percent, which means many more people are surviving cancer, living longer after being diagnosed with cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>And it wasn’t one thing; it was progress on multiple fronts.&nbsp; It includes:</p>



<ul><li>Treatments that target specific mutations; it used to be all the cancer drugs were just cellular poisons.&nbsp; But, specifically, targeted mutation drugs became developed about 20 or so years ago.</li><li>Therapies that use our immune system to detect and kill cancer cells; this was a new idea that really came into full force within the last 10 years or so.</li><li>Cancer vaccines, like the HPV vaccine, that go to the heart of protecting you against those cancers &#8212; at least seven of them &#8212; that are caused by a specific virus.</li><li>And then, new tools, like low-dose CT scans and more refined uses of&nbsp;colonoscopies, and pretty impressive progress against tobacco use through public health campaigns.</li></ul>



<p>All these things together led to this decrease and led to the point that we see even more on the horizon, and the President is prepared to set pretty exciting and ambitious goals.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And we want to kind of place tomorrow’s announcement in what the administration has already done.&nbsp; This is not the first time that the administration has policies or budgets were focused on cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>In the last year, the Biden-Harris Administration has maintained our commitment to ending cancer as we know it.&nbsp; For example, in the President’s first budget, he sustained strong funding for biomedical and health research with increased funding for the National Institutes of Health and the National Cancer Institute, and full funding for the 21st Century Cures Act, including the funding for cancer research at the NCI, named the Beau Biden Cancer Moonshot Initiative.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President also proposed a bold, new vision for biomedical and health research in the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health, or ARPA-H. &nbsp;Its goal is to improve the U.S. government’s capabilities to speed research that can improve human health, to improve our ability to prevent, detect, and treat a range of diseases including cancer, Alzheimer’s disease, and other.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;President Biden committed to a bilateral effort in the spring of last year with the United Kingdom to take on the challenges of cancer together.&nbsp;&nbsp;This has already resulted in a November 2021 U.S.-UK Cancer Scientific Meeting of leadership, patient advocates, and oncology research experts which produced recommendations for how the two nations can work together in partnership to make even more urgent progress on cancer.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;First Lady Jill Biden’s advocacy for cancer education and prevention began decades ago, in 1993, when four of her friends were diagnosed with breast cancer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Following that year, she launched the Biden Breast Health Initiative to educate Delaware high school girls about the importance of cancer prevention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;As First Lady, she continues her work emphasizing early detection efforts and the patient, family, and caregiver experience with cancer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;She will also stress the importance of cancer screenings, especially those delayed or put off due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and will urge government partners, the business community, and non-profit sectors to help make screenings more accessible and available to all.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;So we just really wanted to reiterate the Biden-Harris administration has prioritized this from the beginning, in addition to prioritizing strengthening healthcare for the American people in a number of other ways, by lowering healthcare costs and expanding coverage.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;&nbsp;So, let me turn to what the President is going to lay out as goals and to what they mean.<br><br>So, President Biden tomorrow is going to set national goals for the Cancer Moonshot, as I said, by working together over the next 25 years to cut today’s age-adjusted death rate from cancer by at least 50 percent from where we are today, and to improve the experience of people and their families living with and surviving cancer.&nbsp;&nbsp;And again, taken together with these and other actions, it would drive us to ending cancer as we know it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, how do we know cancer?&nbsp;&nbsp;To explain what we mean by that, we have to ask, &#8220;How do we know cancer today?&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp;Well, I&#8217;m going to give you seven ways we know cancer today that we think we can make really substantial progress in changing pretty dramatically.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Number one, you know, we know cancer is a disease where we have too few effective ways to prevent it.&nbsp;&nbsp;There are some: Don&#8217;t smoke, for example.&nbsp;&nbsp;But we don&#8217;t have lots of effective ways right now to prevent cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Number two, this is a disease where we just usually diagnose it too late.&nbsp;&nbsp;Early diagnosis is so important.&nbsp;&nbsp;But way too often, we diagnose it too late.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number three, it&#8217;s a disease where we know too little about why treatments work well for some patients and fail to work for other patients.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number four, we still have too many cancer types for which we still lack good strategies for developing treatments.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number five, we still have stark inequities in diagnosis, access to treatments and clinical trials, and inequities in patient outcomes based on race, on region, on resources.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Number six, a disease where we leave most patients and families to have to navigate the disease and its aftermath on their own.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And number seven, we know cancer today is a disease where we just don&#8217;t learn from most patients&#8217; experiences.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; These are seven concrete ways in which we know cancer today.&nbsp; And every one of them, there is a lot to do to change.&nbsp; Some of them are about science; there&#8217;s new scientific opportunities that are possible.&nbsp; Some of them are about policy.&nbsp; And some of them are just about being absolutely determined to work some of these problems until they get solved.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, let me elaborate on some of these seven ways which we cancer.&nbsp; I said we have few effective ways to prevent it.&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s everything from expanding screening for inherited cancer risk, figuring out who&#8217;s inherited a cancer gene.&nbsp; We do that in some cases, but it&#8217;s not really broadly done.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But at a scientific end, we can also take lessons from the mRNA vaccines that were developed against the COVID-19 &#8212; the virus that causes COVID-19 &#8212; by asking, &#8220;Can we make mRNA vaccines that teach your immune system to recognize the distinctive mutations that occur in cancer cells?&#8221;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of thinking right now that things like that could cause your body to be able to recognize and attack those early cancer cells before there&#8217;s even any tumor to see and could decrease the overall incidence.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We diagnose too late.&nbsp; What can you do about that?&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s a lot of &#8212; a lot of work going on right now about ideas like maybe an annual blood test to detect dozens of cancers simultaneously based on free-floating DNA in the blood.&nbsp; You know, ideas like that will take a lot of work.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to have to be clinically tested to prove that they really save lives and they&#8217;re going to have to be affordable enough to roll out to the American people.&nbsp; But there is real, concrete work to do that could lead to prevention, that can lead to early diagnosis,<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, stark inequities.&nbsp; We really have to target prevention and early detection to those who need it most and those who just can&#8217;t take advantage of it usually, for lots of reasons.&nbsp; There are all sorts of reasons that people can&#8217;t, say, participate in clinical trials if it means having to go to a major academic medical center.&nbsp; But, well, you even learned from the pandemic that clinical trials can happen out in community hospitals, and telehealth and local sample collection can make a big difference.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there are people who can&#8217;t take advantage of diagnosis and treatment because just the out-of-pocket costs can be a real barrier &#8212; just transportation, time off from work, childcare.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So taking on those inequities which affect &#8212; you know, which are associated with higher mortality rates in different populations &#8212; in the Black population for certain cancers, in rural populations for certain cancers.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, I said where we know too little about why they work in some patients and not others &#8212; there are ways now to figure out, if we really apply our tools, which treatments work for which patients, but we&#8217;ve got to collect that data and we&#8217;ve got to share those data.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Strategies for developing treatments against some kinds of cancers &#8212; the President is very committed to his proposal of an ARPA-H agency at the NIH to take on bold, transformative projects for hard problems like this.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mentioned patients and their families having to navigate cancer on their own.&nbsp; We need to consider navigation services &#8212; equitable navigation services, navigation services that meet the needs of patients &#8212; as really part of cancer care.&nbsp; They&#8217;re very important.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then last of all, failing to learn from most patients&#8217; experiences.&nbsp; I got to say &#8212; and I know this personally and the President knows it even better: Most patients want their experiences to be of value to future patients.&nbsp; Most &#8212; not every one of them &#8212; but most of them want to share that information, and we got to make sure patients have the right and the ability to contribute their information and data to help others if they choose to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I could go into details on that, and we will in the coming weeks, and we&#8217;re going to gather the community together to flesh this out far better than the ideas we&#8217;ve already put down.&nbsp; But we are convinced that under each of these seven headings, there is a lot that can be done.&nbsp; And by reigniting the Moonshot, it&#8217;s going to bring people together &#8212; patients, advocates, researchers, physicians, companies, and many, many others &#8212; to really make sure that we make each of these things no longer the barriers that they are today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, [senior administration official], let&#8217;s talk about some of the actions that will take place.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; So, [senior administration official] just laid out some of the promise and opportunity in these areas that we&#8217;re defining under ending cancer as we know it.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re really talking about, from the administration side, is mobilizing the entire government behind this effort as a presidential priority.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Under the Biden-Harris administration, the Cancer Moonshot specifically will reestablish White House leadership with a focused White House Cancer Moonshot Coordinator in the Office of the President.&nbsp; This will demonstrate the President and First Lady&#8217;s personal commitment to making progress and to really leverage this whole-of-government approach and national response that the challenge of cancer demands.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We will form a Cancer Cabinet, which will be convened by the White House, bringing together departments and agencies across government to deliver &#8212; to address cancer on multiple fronts.&nbsp; This includes, for example, the Departments of Health and Human Services, Veterans Affairs, Defense, Energy, the Department of Agriculture, EPA, and many others, including the Office of the Vice President, Office of the First Lady, and Office of Science and Technology Policy, and Domestic Policy Council here at the White House.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President and First Lady will issue a call to action on cancer screening and early detection.&nbsp; As [senior administration official] touched on, we need to get back on track after more than nine and a half million missed cancer screenings in the United States as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With regular recommended screenings, we can often catch cancer when there may be even more effective treatment options or prevent it from developing by removing precancerous tissue.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To help ensure equitable access to screening and prevention, we will promote at-home screening where it&#8217;s possible, especially with tools for colon cancer and HPV, with mobile screening and communities without easy access to a clinic, through the community health networks that have been so important and have built and strengthened during the COVID-19 pandemic, and other ways to really bring screening and early detection to people where they are.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also as a part of this screening call to action, NCI will organize &#8212; the National Cancer Institute, NCI &#8212; will organize the collective efforts of their cancer centers and other networks, such as their Community Oncology Research Network, to offer new access points to compensate for these millions of delayed cancer screening and with a focus on reaching the individuals most at risk.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Federal agencies will develop a focused program &#8212; as [senior administration official] said, the promise in studying multi-cancer detection tests, and really understanding the promise for patients and in extending life there.&nbsp; We’ll develop a focused program to expeditiously study and evaluate multi-cancer detection tests, like we&#8217;ve done for COVID-19 diagnostics.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Department of Health and Human Services will accelerate efforts to nearly eliminate cervical cancer through cervical cancer screening and HPV vaccinations &#8212; again, with a particular focus on reaching those communities outside of the reach currently and most at risk.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s Cancer Panel, tomorrow, will release a report entitled “Closing Gaps in Cancer Screening,” laying out recommendations focused on connecting people, community, and systems to increase equity and access.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s on the call to action on cancer screening and early detection.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Additionally, among the specific commitments from this administration on the Cancer Moonshot, we will host a White House Cancer Moonshot Summit, bringing together agency leadership; patient organizations; biopharmaceutical companies; the research, public health, and healthcare communities; and others to highlight innovation and progress and new commitments towards ending cancer as we know it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We will build on an already existing White House Coun- &#8212; White House Cancer Roundtable Series that we&#8217;ve hosted over the last six months.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll expand the topics to the seven pillars that [senior administration official] outlined for us, and include additional communities and perspectives to make sure that this mission and this agenda is being built by those most impacted by this disease and with the most experience and knowledge to help us identify priorities.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, the President will call for an all-hands-on-deck approach, calling on the private sector, foundations, academic institutions, healthcare providers, and all Americans to take on the mission of reducing the deadly impact of cancer and improving patient experiences in the diagnosis, treatment, and survival of cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As I said, progress will be informed by people directly experiencing this disease &#8212; cancer patients, caregivers, and families &#8212; and contributed by all parts of the oncology community and beyond.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Tomorrow, we&#8217;ll be launching a website where people can engage and interact with the Cancer Moonshot.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; So, I will wrap up so we can take questions.&nbsp; But let me just say: You&#8217;ve heard what the President is going to lay out tomorrow.&nbsp; You know that for the President and the First Lady, it&#8217;s very personal.&nbsp; Both will speak tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s also personal for the Vice President.&nbsp; The Vice President&#8217;s mother, as I&#8217;m sure many of you know, was a breast cancer researcher.&nbsp; She taught at public universities, worked at a national laboratory, published research papers, and collaborated with NIH and scientists around the world.&nbsp; And in 2008, after a lifetime of researching cancer, she was diagnosed with colon cancer and died of the disease the following year.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I could say it&#8217;s personal for me and it&#8217;s personal for [senior administration official] and, I don&#8217;t know, even on a call with 65 journalists, I&#8217;m going to say I bet it&#8217;s personal for the majority of you too &#8212; that all of us come to this less in our official jobs than as people whose lives have been touched by cancer.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s why the administration is lifting up cancer with such a bold goal.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we&#8217;re happy to take your questions now.&nbsp; And then I know we&#8217;re only to be able to take a handful of questions, but if you have specific questions after the President&#8217;s remarks tomorrow or want to request an interview, we&#8217;re happy to do that.&nbsp; But the way to do it would be to email us at Press@OSTP.EOP.Gov.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be glad to talk more about it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, with that, let&#8217;s turn back to the White House Communications staff to figure out how we&#8217;re going to take questions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you for doing this call.&nbsp; I have a couple of questions.&nbsp; First, when President Obama announced the Cancer Moonshot in 2016, his goal was to make a decade&#8217;s worth of advancements in five years.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering: Has that goal been achieved, and do you think the new goal is more ambitious?&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then secondly, on money, Congress authorized $1.8 billion over seven years in 2016 and about $400 million is left.&nbsp; So, is there any new money over and above that behind this Cancer Moonshot?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much for those questions.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, look, I think the Cancer Moonshot that was launched in 2016 was tremendously successful.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen all sorts of new possibilities be created &#8212; those kinds of research advances.&nbsp; I would say it&#8217;s fair to say that we saw a decade&#8217;s worth of research advances occur in those past five years.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it&#8217;s precisely because of that that I think we can talk about setting goals like actually decreasing death rates from cancer over the next 25 years.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s clear now that all sorts of possibilities, like I was talking about &#8212; vaccines &#8212; prophylactic preventative vaccines against cancer &#8212; not something we could have thought of five years ago.&nbsp; And now, you can sit down and write out a plan for how you’d do it and how you might do a clinical trial to observe that you are really preventing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not easy, but you can do that today.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can &#8212; five years ago, it was not plausible to think about doing these annual blood tests that might screen for cancer.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of work that&#8217;s become possible; now we actually have to do it.&nbsp; We got to reduce this to practice and get it out there.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think the same is true for many of these other areas where we&#8217;ve gotten a really clear understanding of the need to share data and ways to do it that are effective.&nbsp; I think the issues around equity are really clear and urgent right now.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I think that did its work.&nbsp; And it would not have been possible, not have been plausible to have set out these kinds of goals of decreasing the death rate by 50 percent and taking on these specific categories before, and it is possible now.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, yeah.&nbsp; And I am very confident that there will be robust funding going forward because, I got to say, in these times of disagreements, there&#8217;s certainly one thing on which we all agree on across party, across everything, which is the effect of cancer on their lives.&nbsp; I know of nothing that unites us more and that is more bipartisan.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Sheryl, thank you so much for that really great question.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s try Josh one more time.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], the questions that Josh had are if there are any new funding commitments to be announced, and what the start date for the 50 percent reduction over 25 years is.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not going to have a funding commitment tomorrow.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to announce what the plan is, because it&#8217;s pretty important to bring together the Cancer Cabinet, bring together the community.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve laid out a set of ideas.&nbsp; I want to make sure that we have got everybody at the table contributing those ideas and a plan.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But so, that&#8217;s the answer there.&nbsp; But again, I am very confident there&#8217;s robust support for it.&nbsp; But I’m also very certain that we want to start this by listening and expanding the circle for ideas on these important seven pillars and more.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when does that start?&nbsp; It starts about now.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; you know, I guess this year, let&#8217;s say, for the 25; we’ll start with 2022 and measure 25 years from now.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s probably precise enough.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t &#8212; it won&#8217;t get down to the day, but they measure this in years.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see where we are at the end of this year, and that&#8217;s a target for us to really decrease from.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I believe that&#8217;s possible.&nbsp; We cut it by 25 percent &#8212; research and patient-driven solutions and medicine cut it by 25 percent.&nbsp; I think this will make a huge difference if we can achieve this.&nbsp; And it is going to be a shared bipartisan effort over time.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And one thing to add, [senior administration official]: Setting the goal 25 years out doesn&#8217;t mean that we can&#8217;t start measuring our progress soon.&nbsp; So, taking the death rate by cancer down 50 percent in 25 years is going to take work now, and we&#8217;re going to start to see the results in that year-over-year decrease that we have to keep at the level it is now and even accelerate it.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s not pushing the measurement out; it&#8217;s just setting a really ambitious goal in the future that we can work really hard now towards making progress on.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a really &#8212; it&#8217;s a really great point.&nbsp; The curve is not going to be a cliff in the 24th year.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s be really clear: It&#8217;s going to be steady decline over this period &#8212; targeting that.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you know, we&#8217;re all going to be looking at that accountably and saying, &#8220;Are we making the quantitative progress to land there?&#8221;&nbsp; So, even though Josh has had trouble connecting, you know, verbally, I appreciate the question being delivered in absentia.&nbsp; So, thank you, Josh, for the great question.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks, Kevin.&nbsp; And thank you, [senior administration officials], for doing the call.&nbsp; So, President Obama and Vice President Biden &#8212; in 2015, they both used the word “cure” and the phrase “cure cancer” when they rolled out the original Cancer Moonshot.&nbsp; And then-candidate Biden, I think, was criticized for doing the same in 2019 and 2020.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve heard either of you use that word or that phrase in this call.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering whether it&#8217;s fair to read into that as kind of a &#8212; you know, taking a more measured approach using existing interventions and technologies as opposed to making pledges, promises about really remarkable scientific progress that we all hope for but is hard to guarantee.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, no, I wouldn&#8217;t read that into it, because I think the words “cure cancer” needs to be understood in the following way: When they talked then about curing cancer, they recognized that the way we decreased the death rate in cancer is we have to start curing cancers for some patients.&nbsp; We have immunotherapies right now that it&#8217;s fair to say are cures; we do not have a recurrence in 5 years, in 10 years.&nbsp; You know, you never want to use the word “cure,” but those are cures.&nbsp;<br><br>We are going to bite off piece by piece &#8212; I don&#8217;t think they said, “We&#8217;re going to cure all cancer all at once.”&nbsp; But you cure cancer by curing them one at a time, a patient at the time, a hundred patients at a time.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think the idea of &#8212; and we&#8217;re not using the words “cure cancer” because it could be misunderstood by some people as just “get a cure for cancer.”&nbsp; But, Lev, as you know, there&#8217;s 200 types of cancer we need to get therapies for and therapies that extend life long enough to turn into cures for.&nbsp; But we’ve focused on this very measurable thing of decreasing that death rate 50 percent.&nbsp;<br><br>But, no, I would not think that he&#8217;s walking back the words; I think we&#8217;re speaking with a precision.&nbsp; But along that way, the 50 percent is going to be a lot of cures along the way.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, anyway, that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s it.&nbsp; No walking back, but using words carefully and precisely so that we can hold ourselves accountable.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I think, as you heard [senior administration official] detail how we got to where we are, some of the big things &#8212; some of the big advancements that delivered a change in the death rate by cancer weren&#8217;t on the treatment side; they were on the prevention side, on the early detection side.&nbsp; So, by opening up the frame and talking about “ending cancer as we know it,” it gives us the leverage and the place to really make progress in those areas.&nbsp;<br><br>Because I know having a treatment for cancer &#8212; I was dia- &#8212; if I was diagnosed with cancer, I&#8217;d want to know there was a treatment.&nbsp; But even better is not ending up being diagnosed with that cancer in the first place.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; If we end up with vaccines that can help prevent cancers from ever occurring in the first place &#8212; I guess [senior administration official] is right, that&#8217;s not curing anything, but, boy, it would have a huge impact.&nbsp; So, I think we&#8217;re just trying to use words carefully because we want to be open to the whole portfolio of approaches.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s a great question, Lev.&nbsp; I appreciate your clarifying that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; You had mentioned ARPA-H and I think had said “in NIH.”&nbsp; Is that decided that that&#8217;s where that agency would be &#8212; inside the NIH instead of its own independent agency?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, when the President first described ARPA-H in the spring as part of &#8212; well, I mean, he’s described it in speeches.&nbsp; But in the speeches and in the budget, he has requested that and proposed that to be a new kind of division within the NIH &#8212; something independent and autonomous, something that has different authorities and different cultures and things like that, but connected to and part of the broader NIH community there.&nbsp;<br><br>So, yes, that&#8217;s how the President has proposed it for sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks.&nbsp; Thank you, Rachel, for the question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], for the new goals you just announced, do you expect the Cancer Cabinet &#8212; to charge it with the agenda?&nbsp; Or will NCI continue to provide central leadership for these efforts &#8212; for the Moonshot &#8212; as the institute has been since 2016?&nbsp; And if so, are there efforts in the works to request funds to support these goals?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, the answer is both.&nbsp; Some of these things, squarely are in the remit of the NCI, but there’ll be other things.&nbsp; Some of the things that need to be done, other agencies have a critical role in.&nbsp; If we&#8217;re going to be deploying &#8212; oh, let&#8217;s say, vaccines that can prevent cervical cancer, and head and neck cancer, these HPV vaccines, that&#8217;s going to be other agencies that will be playing that &#8212; the CDC, for example.&nbsp;<br><br>Some of these questions about, “How do we make sure everybody has access to clinical trials and they can be reimbursed for their out-of-pocket costs and other things?”&nbsp; That might involve CMS.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think NCI could not be more central.&nbsp; But the idea that this is just limited to cancer research, rather than all of the agencies &#8212; and not just the agencies in HHS.&nbsp; I think VA, DOD, DOE all have contributions to make.&nbsp;<br><br>So, there will obviously be huge work at NCI, but we&#8217;re pulling together a Cancer Cabinet to make sure that we get the benefit of all the levers that might be pulled.<br><br>[Senior administration official], do you want to?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s important to emphasize that [senior administration official] had just added VA and DOD.&nbsp; And not only do they have important research programs and research goals, but they also run health systems.&nbsp; And so, they&#8217;re very much a part of the work here, as they were in 2016.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I mean, the VA has health information systems that we&#8217;ve learned tremendous amounts from.&nbsp; There are medical records from which you can learn a tremendous amount.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just note, I saw a study on multiple sclerosis.&nbsp; It just underscores that we can learn a lot in a lot of places, and we want no stone unturned in this effort.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, Matt, for the question.&nbsp; Really good question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys, thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; Can you guys go into a little more detail about how you see the First Lady&#8217;s role?&nbsp; Obviously, for the vaccine efforts, she&#8217;s traveled around the country.&nbsp; Do you see her doing that, sort of, same kind of work?&nbsp; And will she be, sort of, the face of a piece of this initiative?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, the First Lady has &#8212; is very much a part of this.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a part of the event tomorrow.&nbsp; And as you mentioned, she has been out there with public health messages since the start of the administration.&nbsp; She has spent some time in the last year doing work specifically on cancer, especially around cancer screening and early detection.&nbsp; And we expect &#8212; not only in that area, but we expect her to have some leadership role there with more to come. &nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I think she is excited and committed to this, and brings a tremendous amount to it.&nbsp;<br><br>So, Nikki, thank you for that question.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know we&#8217;ve run out of time for questions, but I&#8217;m really grateful for everybody who&#8217;s here tonight.&nbsp; I&#8217;m excited about it.&nbsp; And we will be able to follow up with you at Press@OSTP.EOP.Gov after the President&#8217;s speech, because, you know, this embargo lifts at 5:00; the President will speak tomorrow.&nbsp; And afterwards, I&#8217;m sure there&#8217;ll be lots of great opportunities for follow up.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you for coming.&nbsp; Thank you for caring about this.&nbsp;<br><br>7:12 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration’s Commitment to Global&#160;Health</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/02/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-commitment-to-global-health/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 13:22:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46373</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States Government is proud to be the largest donor for global health. As we work to end the COVID-19 pandemic, we remain committed to strengthening health systems and institutions; advancing global health security; combatting HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis; advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights, and maternal, neonatal, and child health; closing gaps&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States Government is proud to be the largest donor for global health. As we work to end the COVID-19 pandemic, we remain committed to strengthening health systems and institutions; advancing global health security; combatting HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis; advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights, and maternal, neonatal, and child health; closing gaps in nutrition and non-communicable diseases; and accelerating efforts towards universal health coverage and the Sustainable Development Agenda. In Fiscal Year (FY) 2021, the United States appropriated over $9 billion in global health programs, in addition to almost $16 billion in emergency supplemental funding for COVID-19.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We continue to lead the global community toward a safer, more equitable future. Over the last year, the Biden-Harris Administration has renewed the U.S. leadership in global health, and taken decisive steps to advance global health priorities, including:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting and strengthening the WHO.</strong> Among his first acts in office one year ago, President Biden declared the United States would reengage with the World Health Organization (WHO), highlighting our nation’s commitment to advancing multilateral cooperation in a time of international health crisis. Last week, the United States once again demonstrated that commitment, by leading a successful decision at the WHO Executive Board meeting to strengthen the International Health Regulations (2005). This strengthening will enhance the world’s ability to prevent, detect, and rapidly respond to infectious disease outbreaks in the future. Beyond COVID-19, the United States is collaborating with global partners through WHO on a wide range of global health challenges such as childhood immunization, nutrition, polio eradication, strengthening the global health workforce to achieve universal health coverage, and tackling the threat that climate change poses to health. These and other issues remain critical priorities, especially in the wake of COVID-19, and demonstrate the importance of strong, equitable health systems that serve those most at risk.<br></li><li><strong>Leading the global COVID-19 response. </strong>Under President Biden’s leadership, the United States has committed to donate 1.2 billion doses of safe and effective vaccine to the world, more than any other nation. To date, we have shipped over 400 million of those vaccines to 112 countries around the world, all for free, with no strings attached or promises extracted. We were the first nation to purchase doses solely for the purpose of donation, with the historic purchase of 1 billion doses of Pfizer vaccine. We were the first nation to step out of the queue for Moderna vaccines, allowing the African Union quicker access to tens of millions of doses. We were the first to broker access to doses for individuals in humanitarian crises. And now, we are leading the push to turn vaccines into vaccinations, with the creation of the Global Vaccine Initiative. To date, the United States is providing nearly $16 billion for life-saving health, economic, and humanitarian COVID-19 assistance to our partners to fight this virus and its impacts. These funds are delivering shots in arms, lifesaving supplies to hospitals, and support that reaches the most vulnerable communities.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights. </strong>One of President Biden’s first actions was issuing a Presidential Memorandum on Protecting Women’s Health at Home and Abroad, which revoked the expanded Mexico City Policy and directed agencies to resume funding to the United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) in support of its essential work to prevent maternal deaths, expand access to voluntary family planning, and prevent and respond to gender-based violence around the world. The Administration continues to advance sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR) for all in the face of continued threats. The White House Gender Policy Council released the first-ever <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/10/National-Strategy-on-Gender-Equity-and-Equality.pdf">National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality</a>, which emphasizes the core role of advancing SRHR to achieve gender equality. As the largest bilateral donor to family planning, the United States also leads globally by advancing SRHR in multilateral fora and with bilateral partners. As we address the indirect impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic on health systems and vulnerable populations, the United States has supported increased access to SRHR services, particularly in emergency contexts.<br></li><li><strong>Continued global leadership on addressing HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis.</strong> Last week, the U.S. President&#8217;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) celebrated its nineteen-year anniversary. Since its inception and with bilateral support, the U.S. Government has invested $100 billion to transform the global AIDS response. PEPFAR has saved more than 21 million lives, prevented millions of HIV infections, and helped countries build a strong foundation to prevent, detect, and respond to other health threats, including COVID-19. Across 55 countries, PEPFAR invests over $1 billion annually in local health systems strengthening to respond to HIV. At the end of FY21, PEPFAR supported 63.4 million people with HIV testing services, and 18.96 million people with antiretroviral treatment. With $250 million in funding through the American Rescue Plan Act, PEPFAR has continued to advance HIV gains and supported the global COVID-19 response. The U.S. President’s Malaria Initiative invested $770 million in 2020 to forge forward in the fight against malaria, despite the COVID-19 pandemic, reaching almost 60 million people with malaria medicine and protecting more than 7.5 million pregnant women with preventive treatment for malaria. Through the most recent five-year U.S. Government Global TB Strategy, U.S. government investments led to the treatment of 15.7 million people with TB, starting 438,000 individuals with drug resistant TB on second-line drug therapy, and accomplished a treatment success rate of almost 90 percent.<br></li><li><strong>Building health security capacities.</strong> The United States continues to work with partners across the globe, including 19 intensive support partner countries, to provide assistance to better prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease threats and to meet the target of the multilateral Global Health Security Agenda. The need for these capacities has never been more clear, and robust interagency efforts helped address numerous outbreaks including Ebola, Anthrax, Influenza, Rabies, Polio, Cholera, and more. The U.S. Government’s global health security programs also pivoted to support critical COVID-19 response activities.<br></li><li><strong>Sustaining commitments in maternal and child health. </strong>The United States’ sustained commitment, financial investment, and adaptability has ensured that critical health services continue reaching women, children, and families. In 2020, the United States helped more than 92 million women and children access essential—and often lifesaving—care. The U.S. Government’s investments towards polio eradication have also helped ensure over 400 million children are vaccinated against polio each year; last year was a significant milestone as Africa was declared wild polio free.</li></ul>



<p>In the coming year, the Administration will take the following steps to continue to advance global health priorities:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Continue supporting and strengthening the World Health Organization</strong>. The United States looks forward to rejoining the WHO Executive Board in May 2022, and will launch a Strategic Dialogue with WHO to ensure our mutual priorities are fully aligned. The United States will continue to work closely with WHO and partners around the world, to ensure that the prevention of sexual exploitation and abuse, and support for victims and survivors, remain priority issues.<br></li><li><strong>Accelerate global COVID-19 response efforts. </strong>The U.S. Government will continue to roll out the Initiative for Global Vaccine Access (Global VAX) to accelerate global efforts to get COVID-19 shots into arms and enhance international coordination. This whole of government effort will bolster cold chain supply and logistics, service delivery, vaccine confidence and demand, human resources, data and analytics, local planning, and vaccine safety and effectiveness. The United States has committed more than $1.6 billion in funding to help get shots into arms around the world.<br></li><li><strong>Advance health security and pandemic preparedness. </strong>The United States will continue to advance health security and pandemic preparedness abroad, including through strengthening WHO, working with partners towards targeted IHR amendments and a new pandemic instrument, building country capacities towards the Global Health Security Agenda target, strengthening sustained financing including establishing a new financial intermediary fund at the World Bank, building back better biosafety and biosecurity norms and mitigating biotechnological risks, innovating our science and technological capabilities to shorten the cycle for development of safe, effect, and affordable vaccines, therapeutics, and diagnostics, and more.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Continue investments to strengthen health systems.</strong> The United States will continue to advance the newly launched <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/global-health/health-systems-innovation/health-systems/Vision-HSS-2030">Vision for Health System Strengthening</a> and will work to align global partners toward shared commitments for the health workforce. The United States has committed to supporting and protecting health workers, and affirmed support for WHO’s Gender Equal Health and Care Workforce Initiative, which aim to address gender inequities and inequalities health workers face globally. The United States will continue to invest resources and provide assistance to strengthen countries’ disease surveillance and laboratory detection capacities, continue to lead efforts to eradicate polio, and also strengthen immunization systems and vaccine delivery to ensure a world where people live healthier, safer lives.<br></li><li><strong>Continue championing and expanding sexual and reproductive health and rights. </strong>In addition to maintaining strong financial support, the United States will continue to collaborate with allies and partners through multilateral, bilateral and civil society partnerships to expand progress and leadership to advance sexual and reproductive health and rights. Federal agencies are developing SRHR implementation plans and the National Security Council will continue to elevate and expand SRHR as a core component of our global health policy.<br></li><li><strong>Continue the fight against HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis.</strong> This year, President Biden will host the Global Fund’s Seventh Replenishment Conference, advancing global efforts to address HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis, alongside the U.S. government’s programs.&nbsp; PEPFAR is saving lives and curbing new HIV infections while supporting the health systems infrastructure in countries that continue to serve as a backbone of the COVID-19 response. PEPFAR’s assets can be further leveraged to support the COVID-19 response, while protecting and expanding HIV services and serving the most vulnerable populations around the world. PMI is reshaping its fight against malaria, focusing on reaching the unreached, further building community health systems, and increasing the impact of community health workers as part of its new “<a href="https://www.pmi.gov/home/pmis-strategy/">End Malaria Faster</a>” Strategy. Current investments are building countries’ capacities to respond to both tuberculosis and COVID-19 with support for bi-directional testing approaches for both diseases, joint contact investigations and community screenings, stigma reduction and community empowerment, and expanding infection prevention and control measures—providing vital platforms to address both diseases and respond to future airborne pandemics.<br></li><li><strong>Continue demonstrating strong global leadership on nutrition.</strong> At the 2021 Tokyo Nutrition for Growth Summit, the United States announced a financial commitment of up to $11 billion over three years to combat global malnutrition. The United States also launched the <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/global-health/health-areas/nutrition/usgplan">Global Nutrition Coordination Plan</a>, which will guide the collaborative work of seven U.S. government agencies engaged in scaling up proven approaches to better nutrition.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
