<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 22:26:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in Meeting on Western Wildfires</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/30/remarks-by-president-biden-in-meeting-on-western-wildfires/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 11:11 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Audio turned off.) (In progress) &#8212; proud of our Cabinet.&#160; And they&#8217;re all here today.&#160; They all want to be engaged.&#160; They all want to help.&#160; And so, hopefully we’re going to get into some exchanges going down the line here.&#160; I want to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>11:11 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Audio turned off.) (In progress) &#8212; proud of our Cabinet.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re all here today.&nbsp; They all want to be engaged.&nbsp; They all want to help.&nbsp; And so, hopefully we’re going to get into some exchanges going down the line here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank you all again for being in the support meetings.&nbsp; So thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; And, Governor Newsom, you trying to make us feel bad, listening in that magnificent background you have over there, and while I&#8217;m sitting in here in the &#8212; in the White House?&nbsp; God love you.</p>



<p>Anyway, it&#8217;s good to see you all, really.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>For years, the President has received a briefing at the beginning of the hurricane season, looking at the trends that are coming to get a sense of what&#8217;s coming so that the country can be better prepared.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when I received that briefing this year, I asked for a second briefing that &#8212; that does the same thing, but now we&#8217;re doing it about wildfire season.&nbsp; And we know this is &#8212; this is becoming a regular cycle, and we know it&#8217;s getting worse.&nbsp; In fact, the threat of western wildfires this year is as severe as it&#8217;s ever been.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I wanted to convene this group of governors &#8212; of western state governors, key members of my Cabinet, FEMA leadership and the leadership from utility industries, and senior members of our White House team to make sure we&#8217;re doing everything &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; we&#8217;re doing everything possible to help you prepare for what&#8217;s coming, and some is already there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The truth is we&#8217;re playing catch up.&nbsp; This is an area that has been under-resourced, but that&#8217;s going to change, if we have anything to do with it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We can&#8217;t cut corners when it comes to managing our wildfires or supporting our firefighters.&nbsp; And this briefing is going to be an annual event to make sure we&#8217;re focusing on preventing fires &#8212; the fire threats in the first place &#8212; as well as responding when they arise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But right now, we have to act and act fast.&nbsp; We&#8217;re late in the game here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re remembering the horrific scenes from last year: orange skies that looked like end of days; smoke and ash that made the air dangerous to breathe; more than 10 million acres burned; billions of dollars in economic damage; families that lost their homes and everything they own; and too many &#8212; too many lost lives.</p>



<p>And this year, we &#8212; they could be even tougher, based on the weather patterns.&nbsp; You know, California and some other places, drought conditions are twice that&#8217;s &#8212; what they &#8212; what they were last year.&nbsp; And right now, we&#8217;re seeing record heat in Portland and across the West.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this [last] year, you know, 21 large, uncontained fires were burning.&nbsp; This year, there are 36 that are uncontained and burning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are already about 9,000 firefighters deployed across the region &#8212; from California to New Mexico, to Utah and Nevada &#8212; and it&#8217;s only June.</p>



<p>I know &#8212; I&#8217;ve realized I&#8217;m preaching to the choir here.&nbsp; I know you all know this better than any other people in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fire season, traditionally, lasts through October.&nbsp; But with climate change &#8212; climate change driving the dangerous confluence of extreme heat and prolonged drought &#8212; we&#8217;re seeing wildfires in greater intensity that move with more speed, la- &#8212; you know, and lasts well beyond traditional months &#8212; the traditional months of the fire season.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a problem for all of us.</p>



<p>Wildfizers [sic] are &#8212; wildfires are not a partisan phenomenon.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t stop at a county or a state line &#8212; or country line, for that matter.&nbsp; We need a coordinated, comprehensive response with all the federal working &#8212; all the federal government working in close cooperation to support you, the states.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what this is about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We want to know what you &#8212; the states and localities and Tribal governments and those in the frontlines &#8212; are facing in this danger and what you think would help the most.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, we&#8217;re taking critical steps to help protect American communities right away.&nbsp; First, we&#8217;re going to make sure that we have enough firefighters on call who are trained, equipped, and ready to respond for all this fire season.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re &#8212; and we&#8217;re going to pay them.&nbsp; They &#8212; I mean, the idea these folks are running into &#8212; anyway, we should pay them.</p>



<p>Last week, I learned that some of our federal firefighters are being paid less than $13 an hour.&nbsp; Come on, man.&nbsp; This is &#8212; that&#8217;s unacceptable to me.&nbsp; And I immediately directed my team to take decisive action to fix it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So today we&#8217;re announcing what I still think is not enough: This year we&#8217;re going to provide retention incentives that&#8217;s going to ensure federal wildland fires are &#8212; firefighters are making at least $15 an hour and provide for additional 10 percent bonuses for those working on the frontlines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But a one-time boost is not enough.&nbsp; These courageous women and men take an incredible risk of running toward the fire, and they deserve to be paid and paid good wages.&nbsp; You know that old expression, “God made man.&nbsp; Then he made a few firefighters”?&nbsp; Well, it’s true.&nbsp; They&#8217;re incredible.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spent a lot of time, my whole career, with them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; so we&#8217;re going to work with Congress, and I know many of your senators and representatives have been working hard on this for &#8212; to permanently get federal firefighters a better deal, including improvements in their compensation, their benefits, and their work-life balance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The federal government is also offering funding, when governors request it, to train and equip National Guard members so they have a &#8212; they&#8217;re &#8212; they&#8217;re ready to provide a surge of firefighting capacity<a>.</a></p>



<p>You know, one of the things I learned over the years, being so deeply involved with the firefighters, is the only thing that saves a firefighter&#8217;s life is another firefighter.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the single most consequential thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, one of the hardest speeches I&#8217;ve ever had to make &#8212; and you&#8217;ve all &#8212; we&#8217;ve all made difficult speeches &#8212; was at the funeral of the 19 Granite Mountain Hotshot firefighters, when the Prescott, Arizona, Fire Department got clobbered.&nbsp; That tragedy happened eight years ago today.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the reason I mention it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard to remember &#8212; of all the costs that firefighters risk when they do their job and their bravery to step up and do the job.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, traditionally, federal firefighting has been a seasonal job, but because of climate change &#8212; and I know you all know it, and I hope your constituents know it: there is climate change &#8212; it&#8217;s no longer a seasonal job.&nbsp; This is a year-round mission.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve made sure seasonal firefighters can stay on the job, as long as they are needed this year, by allowing them to work beyond their term.&nbsp; And for next year, we&#8217;re working to make more than &#8212; of those positions, permanent positions so &#8212; so that when fires aren&#8217;t burning, we have a workforce of experienced hands enhancing our forest management, reducing the risk of future fire in the future fire season.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second thing: We are harnessing new tools and technologies to better identify and respond before new fires grow into large, uncontrolled conflagrations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, for example, the National Oceano- &#8212; the National Oceangram- &#8212; Ocean &#8212; Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration &#8212; NOAA &#8212; has satellite technology that is able to see from space when new fires start, while they&#8217;re still small, even as small as the size of your dining room table.</p>



<p>Similarly, the Department of Energy has a sensor array computer analysis capability that can detect in real time the lightning strikes that might set off a blaze.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re going to use those tools to identify fires that start in remote places and share that information so the firefighters on the ground can respond immediately before a fire has spread out of control.&nbsp; I know that&#8217;s not a full answer but it&#8217;s real.&nbsp; It will improve things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re also going to make sure that the people have a &#8212; the information to better protect themselves and their families from smoke and fire risks.&nbsp; This will include launching a new apt [sic] &#8212; a new app on &#8212; from EPA, so individuals can easily access the latest information on air quality, smoke plumes, and public health guidance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, we also have to make investments in our future.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework investment of about $50 billion in the &#8212; in the &#8212; my so-called &#8212; anyway, I won&#8217;t go into it.&nbsp; But a bill that&#8217;s caused a little attention &#8212; infrastructure bill &#8212; is going to build re- &#8212; build resilience to extreme weather events like wildfires.&nbsp; Fifty billion dollars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, I&#8217;m announcing a $37 million federal grant to Sonoma County, California, in support of fire mitigation efforts that are underway.&nbsp; This grant is part of FEMA&#8217;s BRIC program &#8212; Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities.</p>



<p>My administration doubled BRIC funding to support local efforts to strengthen resilience.&nbsp; And because Sonoma knows all too well the devastation wrought by fires, they were the first to apply for fire mitigation funding.&nbsp; I encourage more communities to do so next year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, I want to note that the extreme heat we&#8217;re seeing in the West is not only a risk amplifier for wildfires, it&#8217;s a threat in and of itself. &nbsp;People are hurting.&nbsp; It&#8217;s more dangerous for kids to play outside.&nbsp; Roads are buckling under the heat.&nbsp; I need not &#8212; again, I need not tell all of you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need people to check on their neighbors, especially seniors who may need a helping hand; outdoor laborers, like our farm and construction workers who are going to need frequent water breaks and shade.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank the governors and local leaders for providing information to citizens and the resources like cooling centers where people can go to get relief from the heat.</p>



<p>And to our utility leaders: We are ready to work with you to make sure that people have the access to power, including air conditioning, under these extreme demand conditions while continuing to advance our climate goals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, I&#8217;m eager to hear from each of you &#8212; each of the governors &#8212; as to what the experience has been in your state and what we can do better to be helpful.&nbsp; Because this is an area where investing in prevention and preparation today is going to deliver invaluable returns tomorrow.&nbsp; And the federal government is going to have to do &#8212; have your backs.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s going to &#8212; that&#8217;s my intention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll close by just saying thank you to everyone from the Forest Service, to the Department of Interior and Agriculture, to FEMA, to state and local and Tribal partners, and most importantly, our firefighters for all your incredible work.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve asked so much of the firefighters already, and I know you&#8217;re going to continue to step up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now I&#8217;m going to ask Vice President Harris to say a few words and then we&#8217;ll move on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Madam Vice President, the floor is yours.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; First, I just want to thank the President for prioritizing this for his administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a personal issue for me as a daughter of California.&nbsp; And I say hello to my governor, Gavin Newsom.&nbsp; I grew up with drought warnings.&nbsp; My brother-in-law is a California firefighter.&nbsp; As a senator, I have visited the scene, while the embers were still smoldering &#8212; of the fires &#8212; Paradise, for example, California.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when I arrived there, a whole community had been wiped out by the fire.&nbsp; The families still hadn’t been let back in.&nbsp; But the only thing standing in that community were the chimneys, which looked, in that scene, like tombstones.</p>



<p>The firefighters that were there pointed out to me: If you look at the driveway, it may be a tragic situation if the cars are in the driveway because that means the folks didn’t get out in time.</p>



<p>We have so much work to do on this.&nbsp; My &#8212; my home &#8212; our family home was under an evacuation order in Los Angeles.&nbsp; So I&#8217;ve been in that experience of also saying, &#8220;Look, the most things we can grab that are the most valuable are family photographs.&nbsp; Everything else doesn&#8217;t matter.&#8221;</p>



<p>So, when I think about the challenges that we face as a nation, I know they are real.&nbsp; I also know that we&#8217;re in a different climate, as the President said, on every level than we were even 10 years ago, and there&#8217;s a lot of work to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And part of the leadership of this administration has been to also recognize that the federal government&#8217;s role in this regard has to be more than just putting out fires.&nbsp; It needs to be, obviously, supporting our firefighters, especially at the federal level, who are not getting paid enough, but it&#8217;s also about investing in resilience.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about investing in adaptation, diversifying water policy in a way we are thinking about the storage of water, both above ground and underground. We&#8217;re thinking about recycling and all that we know is available to us to actually be smarter, in terms of the conservation of this diminishing and valuable resource called &#8220;water.&#8221;</p>



<p>So, I want to thank everyone for your leadership because you all are giving people a sense of confidence while you are trying to bring limited resources to what needs to be addressed in this growing threat of these wildfires.</p>



<p>And the bottom line is that: As the President has said &#8212; his bipartisan framework for infrastructure &#8212; it&#8217;s going to address a lot of these challenges.&nbsp; But there is other work to be done, and so I look forward to staying in touch with all of you.&nbsp; And again, thank you for your leadership.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; Governor Brown, if you&#8217;d be willing, you could give us an overview of what you &#8212; the challenges are you western governors are facing and what you think we should be doing and can do to help.&nbsp; The floor is yours.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR BROWN:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Mr. President and Madam Vice President, for having us here for this incredibly important conversation.</p>



<p>As you well know, we western governors &#8212; our states are truly on the frontlines when it comes to drought, fires, and our rapidly changing climate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We were talking earlier before you got on.&nbsp; Just this weekend, my state of Oregon experienced three consecutive days of record-breaking high temperatures across the Willamette Valley, reaching upwards of 117 degrees.&nbsp; It is unprecedented. And, unfortunately, it follows one of the most devastating wildfire seasons in our state&#8217;s history.</p>



<p>Last year, we had more than 2,000 fires that burned over a million acres.&nbsp; Entire communities were literally wiped off the map in minutes.&nbsp; We lost nine lives, more than 4,000 homes, and nearly 2,000 other structures.&nbsp; As you well know, the impact on our communities and our local economies will last for years to come.</p>



<p>Oregonians have been through a lot in the last 18 months. We&#8217;ve had four federal disaster declarations in my state since April of 2020.&nbsp; But what last year&#8217;s fire season underscored is that, most often, those who can least afford the impacts are hurt the most &#8212; our communities of color, our rural and low-income communities were disproportionately impacted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our disaster preparedness and recovery services must be available to everyone, regardless of the language they speak, the color of their skin, their economic situation, whether they own a home or not, or their immigration status.&nbsp; Everyone impacted by a disaster should be eligible for FEMA assistance, including our undocumented families.&nbsp; It&#8217;s absolutely the right thing to do.</p>



<p>Our local communities are increasingly challenged to respond on their own to disasters of the scales we are seeing. We&#8217;ve been preparing for this year&#8217;s fire season by investing millions of dollars, shoring up additional resources and staffing at our Office of Emergency Management so they then can support our local and our Tribal partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, Mr. President, Madam Vice President, we still have a number of concerns, and it includes whether there will be available wildfire and non-fire federal resources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know, as we&#8217;re entering this wildfire season, our eastern counterparts are preparing for a very difficult hurricane season, and so we may not be able to rely on other regions to help out this year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that in mind, I do want to say thank you for approving our cost-share adjustment related to our 2020 Labor Day wildfires at 100 percent for Oregon, treating this the same as COVID-19 and the same as what happened in Louisiana for their hurricane recovery efforts.</p>



<p>I would also ask that federal Individual Assistance be approved for disaster mitigation activities for wildfire just as FEMA recently approved for hurricanes.</p>



<p>And then, finally &#8212; and I just have to say, gratefully &#8212; our Good Neighbor Authority &#8212; we have partnered with the federal government over the years to reduce wildfire risk on federal lands through collaborative processes, including prescribed burns, removing dead trees and underbrush.&nbsp; With the recent passage of our state legislation, we have an opportunity to fund even more of these Good Neighbor Authority projects together.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a win, win, win.&nbsp; It creates jobs, creates healthy landscapes, and reduces wildfire risk.&nbsp; And we have the dollars to invest now.</p>



<p>So, we look forward to partnering for you &#8212; with you, and we are incredibly grateful, Mr. President, for your leadership.</p>



<p>Back over to you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, Madam Governor, I &#8212; I&#8217;m not being solicitous when I say we&#8217;re grateful for your leadership.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And one of the things that I&#8217;d like to ask before we move on is:&nbsp;What &#8212; what would you be looking for us to do at the federal level to strengthen this agreement to build off the lessons that &#8212; you know, the Good Neighbor agreement?&nbsp; And is there anything in particular that is &#8212; you&#8217;ve learned from last season that would be added to the needs of this season?</p>



<p>GOVERNOR BROWN:&nbsp; Well, you mentioned it in your remarks, Mr. President: Making sure we have resources to train our National Guardsmen and women prior to fire season has been extremely helpful the last two fire seasons.&nbsp; This should be universal practice nationwide.&nbsp; It&#8217;s incredibly helpful.&nbsp; We have relied on our National Guard every step of the way throughout the pandemic, and we certainly rely on them in support activities and firefighting.</p>



<p>The other piece &#8212; and I see Chief Christiansen there &#8212; in terms of the Good Neighbor Authority, this has been extraordinary in our ability to put people back to work in our timber-dependent rural communities, in our ability to create healthy landscapes, in our ability to provide timber for the mills, and, frankly, our ability to reduce wildfire risk.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so more resources to collaborate and provide what you describe as &#8220;comprehensive, collective efforts&#8221; to reduce wildfire risk would be extremely helpful.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, we ought to get &#8212; not at this moment &#8212; but we&#8217;re ought to get, no pun intended, deeply in the weeds as to specifically what can be done.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;d ask my appropriate Cabinet members to be working with your people as to what we can do along those lines because it seems to be self-evident that that makes a lot of sense.</p>



<p>And &#8212; but we have a lot of other things to cover here, but I look to Dr. Sherwood: Are we moving to &#8212;</p>



<p>DR. SHERWOOD-RANDALL:&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to move shortly.&nbsp; If you want to ask any further questions of governors, we can move, with the press departing, and we&#8217;ll continue our discussion.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me ask the Vice President if she has any questions and/or any Cabinet member if they have any questions for the governor.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What I&#8217;m interested &#8212; it&#8217;s really a follow-up to what the President asked: What &#8212; with each consecutive wildfire season &#8212; and they are growing in terms of the enormity &#8212; what are we learning?&nbsp; And how can the federal government address the challenges and the gaps that you have seen with each fire season, in terms of the resources but also the approach?</p>



<p>And &#8212; for example, including the public education piece; including the piece that is about encouraging the private sector, where appropriate, to be engaged around resilience and adaptation.&nbsp; On the issue of water policy, what kind of resources do you need that are also preventative as well as reactive to the wildfires themselves?</p>



<p>PARTICIPANT: Governor Newsom, do you want to pick that one up?</p>



<p>GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, first, if I could just make a little indulgence &#8212; and thank you, Madam Governor and Madam Vice President &#8212; Mr. President, I&#8217;ve been waiting almost four and a half years to hear a President say what you just said.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s profoundly important, every word you spoke.&nbsp; And I mean it.&nbsp; We &#8212; look, it goes without saying: In California, we were &#8212; you know, we were engaged in a relationship with the federal government, vis-à-vis the Vice President&#8217;s question, that was more like a &#8212; you know, sparring partners, not working partners.</p>



<p>So, we have an opportunity here to turn the page on the finger-pointing and the rhetoric.&nbsp; We were debating raking policies, literally &#8212; debating raking policies in this country in the last few years.</p>



<p>But we &#8212; our eyes are wide open.&nbsp; By the way, I&#8217;m here in your forests, our forests &#8212; federal forests in Klamath and Siskiyou County &#8212; two of the largest wildfires that we&#8217;ve had, year to date in this region.&nbsp; We were up here yesterday. Thank you, Mr. President, I didn&#8217;t have to make a call to you to get the FMAG approved yesterday, up here in Siskiyou County, for the largest of the wildfires &#8212; the Lava Fire, which is a few miles away from me.</p>



<p>But the hots are getting hotter; the dries are getting drier.&nbsp; The (inaudible) realities of climate change are here, and they&#8217;re here decades ahead of when we had anticipated.</p>



<p>So, across the board &#8212; across the board, we have to disabuse ourselves of the old timelines and the old frames of engagement.&nbsp; I mean, the seriousness of this cannot be underscored.&nbsp; We had, last year, a heat dome over the West Coast of the United States &#8212; not just some of the one we&#8217;re experiencing north of where I am and Governor Brown and Inslee experienced most acutely.&nbsp; But that led to 12,000 lightning strikes in 24 hours and five of the most destructive wildfires &#8212; five of the six largest in our history concurrently in last year&#8217;s wildfire season.&nbsp; We were burning up.&nbsp; We were choking up.&nbsp; We aren&#8217;t just heating up.</p>



<p>And I should just say this: With due respect to those that don&#8217;t believe in science, you got to believe your own damn eyes &#8212; observed evidence.&nbsp; You know, when you look at that thermometer &#8212; 117, 119 degrees up north.&nbsp; We were 123 down in Palm Springs two days ago; 111 just 48 hours ago.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no Republican thermometer, no Democratic thermometer.&nbsp; These realities are here with us today.</p>



<p>So, Madam Vice President, across the board, we can&#8217;t just double down.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the old stale rhetoric.&nbsp; We have to have a sense of intentionality and responsibility to radically change our vegetation forest management policies; our suppression policies; our pre-positioning policies; the strategies we&#8217;re engaging the President just laid out on technology; strategies and opportunities to develop partnerships not only with Interior and not only with FEMA, but with the Department of Defense &#8212; some of those new satellite technologies that have been around, but opportunities to engage in new partnerships with those satellite technologies.</p>



<p>The mutual aid system has been stretched in this country.&nbsp; Governor Brown, how many times I called you last year for resources?&nbsp; Inslee, Sisolak, Polis &#8212; all of you on there &#8212; thank you.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re stretched.&nbsp; We were calling folks in Australia. &nbsp;We were calling folks in Canada.&nbsp; We had the pleasure of having folks &#8212; firefighters &#8212; from Israel come because we were that stretched.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Mr. President, just in closing, forgive me for being long-winded, I just want to say this: Music to my ears, “We got to pay our firefighters, federally, more.”&nbsp; Because we don&#8217;t have enough firefighters &#8212; period, full stop.&nbsp; Bureau of Land Management, same thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need to really invest in our human resources and the infrastructure that you have been preaching over the course of the last few weeks.&nbsp; Because this is also an incredible economic opportunity to completely transform our economy and to get off of carbon &#8212; or at least drive, but with a carbon-free engine &#8212; and to change the way we produce and consume energy.</p>



<p>And so I &#8212; I just want to applaud you &#8212; final words &#8212; for recognizing not only this moment of urgency, situationally, but the sustainable mindset to start thinking anew about how we can reimagine the future &#8212; not go back to the 19th century, but truly dominate the future.&nbsp; And your infrastructure program is a big part of that as well.&nbsp; These things are connected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I just want to say we respect and appreciate your leadership, and we&#8217;re just grateful and humbled that you took the time today to be with all of us.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, Gov, this is a &#8212; I&#8217;m not doing anybody any favor.&nbsp; I just think if &#8212; if I were sitting in your seat or Governor Brown’s seat, what I&#8217;d be &#8212; I mean, this is &#8212; this is urgent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And one of the things that I have found since becoming President is how often I&#8217;m required to call in the National Guard.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The National Guard.&nbsp; I spent yesterday &#8212; well, that&#8217;s not true &#8212; two days ago &#8212; meeting with &#8212; with our military.&nbsp; What they&#8217;ve done is just astounding.&nbsp; I &#8212; I just met with the general who had coordinated probably the largest effort to lo- &#8212; the largest logistical effort in American history getting all these COVID vaccines out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, think about what &#8212; how we’re relying on the military in ways we never, ever, ever anticipated.&nbsp; And now I got my briefing at NOAA on what was going on in hurricane season.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s, you know &#8212; and we&#8217;re looking for the National Guard there, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so we just have to think differently, like you all have been talking about.&nbsp; And I promise you, when we get down to the nitty gritty &#8212; and a lot of this we&#8217;re already getting down there &#8212; you got to tell us what you need.&nbsp; And we can debate it.&nbsp; We can discuss it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think this is a &#8212; you know, that old overused expression &#8212; a &#8220;wake-up call&#8221; to the rest of the public, who all of a sudden is saying &#8212; I&#8217;ve had people say to me, when I&#8217;ve been on the road the last month &#8212; less than that; probably the last three weeks &#8212; “Oh, my God.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t think things would really change that much.&nbsp; I saw those &#8212; those photographs of the reservoirs in California, and &#8212; oh, my God &#8212; they&#8217;re really &#8212; there&#8217;s no water?”&nbsp; Or people saying, “One hundred and seventeen degrees and &#8212; you know, in Portland?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think this is both &#8212; you know, the old expression &#8212; we&#8217;ve got to make lemonade out of lemons here.&nbsp; We have a chance to do something that not only deals with the problem today, but allows us to be in a position to move forward to make and &#8212; and create real good jobs, by the way &#8212; generate economic growth in all &#8212; in all the process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>11:39 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: S.J.Res. 13, S.J.Res. 14, S.J.Res. 15</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/bills-signed-s-j-res-13-s-j-res-14-s-j-res-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 22:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22721</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Wednesday, June 30, 2021, the President signed into law: S.J.Res. 13, which nullifies the EEOC rule titled &#8220;Update of Commission&#8217;s Conciliation Procedures&#8221;; S.J.Res. 14, which provides for Congressional disapproval of the Environmental Protection Agency rule relating to &#8220;Oil and Natural Gas Sector:&#160; Emission Standards for New, Reconstructed, and Modified Sources Review&#8221;; and S.J.Res. 15,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Wednesday, June 30, 2021, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S.J.Res. 13, which nullifies the EEOC rule titled &#8220;Update of Commission&#8217;s Conciliation Procedures&#8221;;</p>



<p>S.J.Res. 14, which provides for Congressional disapproval of the Environmental Protection Agency rule relating to &#8220;Oil and Natural Gas Sector:&nbsp; Emission Standards for New, Reconstructed, and Modified Sources Review&#8221;; and</p>



<p>S.J.Res. 15, which nullifies the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency&#8217;s rule titled <a>&#8220;</a>National Banks and Federal Savings Associations as Lenders&#8221;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 2441</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/bill-signed-h-r-2441/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 21:33:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22705</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Wednesday, June 30, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 2441, the “Sgt. Ketchum Rural Veterans Mental Health Act of 2021,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to expand the Rural Access Network Growth Enhancement program.&#160; Thank you to Representatives Cindy Axne (IA-03), Ashley Hinson (IA-01), Mariannette Miller-Meeks (IA-02), Randy Feenstra (IA-04), Tim&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Wednesday, June 30, 2021, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 2441, the “Sgt. Ketchum Rural Veterans Mental Health Act of 2021,” which requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to expand the Rural Access Network Growth Enhancement program.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Cindy Axne (IA-03), Ashley Hinson (IA-01), Mariannette Miller-Meeks (IA-02), Randy Feenstra (IA-04), Tim Ryan (OH-13), and Ed Case (HI-01), as well as Senators Jon Tester (MT), Jerry Moran (KS), and Joni Ernst (IA) for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the White House Eviction Prevention Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/readout-of-the-white-house-eviction-prevention-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today the White House hosted a first of its kind virtual Eviction Prevention Summit. The Summit included two parts: a public plenary on best practices on eviction prevention and a series of breakout sessions for local public officials, court officials, legal services organizations, local bar associations, community-based organizations, landlord associations, tenant advocates, emergency rental assistance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today the White House hosted a first of its kind virtual Eviction Prevention Summit. The Summit included two parts: a public plenary on best practices on eviction prevention and a series of breakout sessions for local public officials, court officials, legal services organizations, local bar associations, community-based organizations, landlord associations, tenant advocates, emergency rental assistance administrators, and local philanthropies representing 46 cities across the country to develop eviction prevention action plans for their local areas. Following the CDC’s announcement last week of a final, one-month extension of the eviction moratorium until July 31st, the Administration announced <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/">a series of actions</a> to stabilize families and prevent evictions, including steps to encourage state and local governments to disburse the more than $46 billion in emergency rental assistance made available to assist households in need.</p>



<p>Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice opened the Summit by welcoming participants, emphasizing the President’s commitment to assisting renters, and highlighting the whole-of-government approach being implemented by the Administration. Deputy Secretary of the Treasury Wally Adeyemo highlighted the importance of emergency rental assistance to prevent evictions among the most vulnerable. &nbsp;White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling made the case for why eviction diversion programs are the best immediate intervention to prevent a wave of new evictions. Matthew Desmond, one of the country’s leading researchers on evictions, presented an overview of the latest research, including on the risk of evictions following the end of the CDC moratorium and how diversionary programs could mitigate these risks.</p>



<p>The President of the American Bar Association, Patricia Lee Refo, then moderated a panel to provide examples of how eviction diversion programs can be paired with emergency rental assistance to keep people housed. Panelists included Rasheedah Phillips, Managing Attorney of Housing Policy, Community Legal Services of Philadelphia, the head of the largest legal services provider in Philadelphia; Rene Solis, Chief Program Officer at BakerRipley, the Emergency Rental Assistance provider in Houston-Harris County; Hon. Bridget Mary McCormack, Chief Justice, Michigan Supreme Court; and Gilbert Winn, CEO of WinnCompanies, a national landlord with a robust housing stability strategy.<br><br>Following the panel, Associate Attorney General Vanita Gupta highlighted recent recommendations and best practices <a href="https://www.justice.gov/asg/page/file/1405886/download">from a letter</a> she sent to chief justices of state supreme courts and state court administrators, and Secretary Marcia Fudge concluded the first session of the Summit by highlighting the Department of Housing and Urban Development’s work to prevent evictions and underscoring the importance of keeping people housed.<br><br>Speakers at the second session included Erika Poethig, Special Assistant to the President for Housing and Urban Policy, White House Domestic Policy Council; Clarence Wardell, Chief Data and Equitable Delivery Officer, White House American Rescue Plan Implementation; Diane Yentel, President and CEO, National Low Income Housing Coalition; Emily Benfer, Visiting Professor of Law, Wake Forest University School of Law; and Danielle Hirsch, Principal Court Management Consultant, National Center for State Courts. Following their remarks, attendees split into groups with others from their city to develop eviction prevention action plans before sharing their commitments with the larger group and concluding the Summit.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call Previewing the President&#8217;s Wildfire Preparedness Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/30/background-press-call-previewing-the-presidents-wildfire-preparedness-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 19:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22649</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (June 29, 2021) MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; And hi, everyone.&#160;&#160;Thank you all for joining this call tonight to preview the President’s Wildfire Preparedness Meeting tomorrow.&#160;&#160;As a reminder of the ground rules, this call is on background, attributable to a senior administration official.&#160; And the contents of this call are under embargo until&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(June 29, 2021)</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; And hi, everyone.&nbsp;&nbsp;Thank you all for joining this call tonight to preview the President’s Wildfire Preparedness Meeting tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As a reminder of the ground rules, this call is on background, attributable to a senior administration official.&nbsp; And the contents of this call are under embargo until 6:00 a.m. Eastern Time tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>And with that, I’ll turn it over to [senior administration official] to provide opening remarks and take a few questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hello, everyone, and thank you for joining us this evening.&nbsp; Tomorrow, President Biden is convening governors from western states, private sector partners, and Cabinet officials to discuss how we can all work together to strengthen prevention, preparedness, and response efforts for this wildfire season.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In the meeting, the President will ask participants what additional resources they need and what actions can be taken immediately to protect communities, improve emergency preparedness, and address the growing wildfire threat facing our communities.&nbsp; That threat is being fueled by climate change and the devastating intersection of severe drought and extreme heat that is impacting western communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Before we go further and preview the topics of discussion in tomorrow’s meeting, and outline some of the actions that we’ll be announcing, I want to explain a little more about the genesis of this meeting.&nbsp; Historically, American presidents have had briefings at the beginning of hurricane season to look at the trends and get a sense of what the hurricane season will be like in order to ensure that the federal government is prepared, that emergency operations are ready, and that hurricane disaster relief is poised where it needs to be, pre-deployed if it’s necessary to be utilized.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden had his hurricane briefing this year on May 24th when we went over to FEMA headquarters to discuss the Atlantic hurricane outlook and the federal government’s preparedness efforts.&nbsp; Afterward, he noted to me that hurricanes aren’t the only kind of extreme weather threatening American communities.&nbsp; We’re seeing record levels of extreme heat in the Pacific Northwest right now, severe drought, and wildland fire dangers across much of the western United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Decades of shifting development patterns, land and fire management decisions, and climate change have resulted in wildfires that move with a speed, intensity, and reach that was previously unseen.&nbsp; This has created conditions where wildfires too often overwhelm response capabilities, resulting in billions of dollars in economic losses, damage to natural resources, devastation to communities, and, tragically, losses of human life.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Since 2015, the United States has experienced on average roughly 100 more large wildfires every year than the year before, and this wildfire season is already outpacing last season in terms of the number of large fires to date.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, recognizing all of those developments, President Biden asked me to arrange a wildfire briefing, too.&nbsp; He is taking this threat seriously because wildfires are obviously getting worse.&nbsp; They’re threatening more communities across the western part of our country and resulting in more devastation.&nbsp; And the President strongly believes that it’s time the federal government stopped underinvesting in prevention and mitigation efforts and that we started investing in our response capabilities and in our firefighting personnel so that we can better protect the people of this country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He tasked our Homeland team to take a series of actions to respond to wildfires this year to make sure we’re doing whatever we can to mitigate fires before they occur and respond effectively when they do.&nbsp; To make sure we’re doing all that we can to protect communities from devastation and to save lives is our mission.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In preparation for tomorrow’s briefing, I’ve held a series of meetings with emergency preparedness officials and with state and local governments on wildfire preparedness and prevention and response efforts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And tomorrow we will be announcing a series of actions to help fight fires this year and address this growing threat and improve our wildfire response capabilities over both the short and the longer term.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll summarize some of those for you today, and tomorrow morning, with a factsheet that we’ll release, there will be additional information provided.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, we will invest in our firefighting personnel, providing retention incentives and raising firefighter pay to ensure no firefighter makes less than $15 an hour.&nbsp; As the President said last week, it’s ridiculous that federal firefighters get paid $13 an hour, and we are going to change that.&nbsp; We will be providing additional bonuses to those working on the frontlines while working with Congress to get a better deal long term because firefighters must be fairly paid for the grueling and risky work that they are willing to take on.<br>&nbsp;<br>We will also extend seasonal hiring of firefighters, hire additional firefighters, and add surge capacity by training and equipping more federal employees and military personnel to be ready to quickly support wildland fires when they happen.&nbsp; Because of climate change, fire seasons are becoming more of a year-round mission, so we are accelerating our plans to transition to a more permanent firefighting workforce.<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ll also increase our wildfire response capabilities through increased aviation capacity and additional resources, and by making critical new investments to protect communities, build communities’ resilience, and do pre-disaster mitigation efforts.&nbsp; We are preparing for the potential impacts that our power grid may face as a result of wildfires and improving our emergency capabilities to respond if there is a grid or electrical equipment failure or if power shutoffs happen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will also be leveraging the latest science and new and emerging technologies, including satellites, to improve early detection efforts so we know in real time when wildfires begin.&nbsp; We’ll use new tools to improve our wildfire mitigation activities, enhance our wildfire response capabilities, and protect our firefighters and residents from smoke, dangerous air, and fire risk.<br>&nbsp;<br>That means providing actionable information for the American people in real time.&nbsp; We’re developing new apps, maps, and resources so people can check their phones, get more information, and stay safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’ll be talking about all of this and more tomorrow with the President, with the governors, with private sector partners, and with members of the Cabinet, and we wanted to give you this preview tonight of the actions we’re taking to protect public safety, prepare for wildfire season, and be ready to deliver assistance to people in times of urgent need.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I noted, we’ll also be releasing a factsheet tomorrow with more information on everything I just talked about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, I’m glad to open it up to a couple of questions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; And we have time for three quick questions if you want to open the lines.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I just want to be clear on whether &#8212; you know, how these governors are going to be attending.&nbsp; When I asked in the press briefing on Friday, Jen said &#8212; used language suggesting there would be some folks there in person.&nbsp; Well, this &#8212; now I’ve been told by Governor Inslee’s team that this is entirely virtual.&nbsp; Is that correct?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, I’m happy to answer that question.&nbsp; All the western governors are convening for their own Western Governors Association Conference that begins tomorrow afternoon.&nbsp; It will all be virtual.&nbsp; And as a result, our meeting with the governors will be virtual.&nbsp; They will all be on the screen with the President and the Vice President.&nbsp; We’ll also have Cabinet members in person here.&nbsp; The private sector partners will be on Zoom, and some of our additional leaders across the federal enterprise will be on Zoom.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I would say it’s a hybrid convening that reflects the nature of our times, and we have set up the technology that we anticipate will work effectively for the President and the Vice President to interact with all the participants.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; I have a question on the pay issue.&nbsp; So, is this going to raise salaries to $15 an hour, or is this going to be made up for in bonuses, as you said, or the bonus is an addition?&nbsp; And just to follow up on that, where is this money coming from for the higher salaries?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I want to leave it to providing more detail on that tomorrow morning, and that’s one of these embargoed points.&nbsp; The way this is going to be done this year will involve the provision of bonuses that will enable the pay for these firefighters to rise to the equivalent of $15 per hour, which they’re currently not being paid.&nbsp; And, in addition, our permanent firefighters working on the frontlines will receive up to a 10 percent retention incentive.&nbsp; And temporary workers who commit to continuing this season will also be able to receive some incentive pay.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The goal here in this year, because we have a very short runway &#8212; we have had a very short runway in getting prepared &#8212; has been to find ways to address what we learned, which is that there is this challenge with respect to both recruitment and retention of the firefighters that we need across the nation.&nbsp; And so we’re doing everything we can within the confines of this cycle to enhance pay and encourage people to both join the firefighting and be retained as firefighters in the force.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Going forward, we’re going to work on additional measures with Congress to move beyond these short-term solutions to address longer-term needs with respect to compensation and benefits and work-life balance reforms for federal wildland firefighters.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for having this briefing.&nbsp; I was curious what more you can tell us about the pre-disaster mitigation projects that are going to be announced tomorrow.&nbsp; Is there going to be anything that is going to be able to be implemented to try to mitigate fire risk this season, or is it kind of too late for that and this is funding for programs going forward next year and years to come?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, this is part of the BRIC program, the program that we have to build resilient infrastructure and communities via FEMA.&nbsp; And in FY2020, $500 million was made available through BRIC to support states and communities with pre-disaster mitigation.&nbsp; Communities applied for these grants, and we are about to announce a full set of grants to communities across the country for this pre-disaster mitigation.&nbsp; We will announce one of those tomorrow that is a pre-disaster mitigation project that will be responsive to an application from a western state.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>However, realistically, I think you’re right that this can’t be applied by the time this season unfolds, as we are living it already.&nbsp; The money will be granted, and then the program will have to be built for the mitigation work to be done.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we are beginning that process with the summer 2020 grants, and as you may know, we have doubled BRIC funding for 2021 to $1 billion available in FY2021 for grant applications to be received.&nbsp; And one of the things I anticipate the President will do tomorrow is encourage our western state partners to look at the opportunity to apply for resilience grants through this process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a very important way that we can do preventive work.&nbsp; Those of us who focus on emergency preparedness and response know that prevention is far less expensive than response in so many ways.&nbsp; And so, if we can get ahead of these challenges and do more work on resilience in communities, we then are being &#8212; we do all that we can to protect our communities and also preserve the extraordinary resource of those who are our first responders who are in such demand in these extraordinary times.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And thank you.&nbsp; That is unfortunately all we have time for, so I’ll turn it back over to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the Generation Equality Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/30/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-generation-equality-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 19:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22687</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via TeleconferenceSouth Court Auditorium 10:27 A.M. EDT VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Greetings from the White House.  President Macron, President López Obrador, Mis- &#8212; (applause) &#8212;  PRESIDENT MACRON:  Big applause to welcome you.  VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  (Laughs.)  Merci beaucoup.  It is &#8212; it is wonderful to be with you.   President Macron, Mr. Secretary-General, Madam Executive Director,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>10:27 A.M. EDT<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Greetings from the White House.  President Macron, President López Obrador, Mis- &#8212; (applause) &#8212; <br><br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Big applause to welcome you. <br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  (Laughs.)  Merci beaucoup.  It is &#8212; it is wonderful to be with you.  <br><br>President Macron, Mr. Secretary-General, Madam Executive Director, Shantel, and the Youth Task Force: Thank you for convening this forum.<br><br>Twenty-six years ago, government and civil society leaders from around the world came together in a forum not unlike this one.  In Beijing, in 1995, Hillary Rodham Clinton issued a clarion call to the world, and the United States became one of 189 nations to adopt the ambitious &#8220;Platform for Action.&#8221;  These are points of profound pride for our nation.  <br><br>And for me, it is an honor to be here with you now, as we recommit to make gender equality a reality.<br><br>Over the past five months, I have met many world leaders, and we have discussed some of the most pressing issues of our time: COVID-19, climate change, threats to security, and threats to democracy.  <br><br>And in these meetings, I have often made it a point to raise the importance of equal participation of women and girls, because I believe, as you all do, that addressing gender equity and equality is essential to addressing every other challenge we face, which is certainly true in light of the current threats to democracy.  <br><br>Around the world, democracy is in peril.  Strong men have become stronger.  Human rights abuses have multiplied.  Corruption is undermining progress as misinformation is undermining public confidence.  <br><br>And who gets hurt when democracies fall, when democracies falter?  Who gets hurt when democracies fail to live up to their promise?  Well, women and girls are among those who suffer.<br><br>At the G7 Summit, just weeks ago, world leaders pledged to unite against the threat of autocracy.  World leaders pledged to unite behind the principles of democracy.  And as we move forward, I believe that if we want to strengthen democracy, we must fight for gender equality.  <br><br>Because here&#8217;s the truth: Democracy is strongest when everyone participates, and it is weaker when people are left out.  And we&#8217;ve seen this here in the United States.  <br><br>When women have access to capital to start a small business, they can participate more fully and our democracy grows stronger.  <br><br>When women have access to reproductive healthcare to stay healthy, they can participate more fully and our democracy grows stronger.  <br><br>When women live free from the fear of violence, they can participate more fully and our democracy grows stronger. <br><br>Throughout my career, I have worked to protect women from violence and exploitation.  I know what happens when women are supported.  I know what happens when women are heard.  When women are heard, whether that is in the courtroom, in the workplace, in the halls of government, or at the ballot box, democracy is more complete.  <br><br>So I know, without doubt, gender equality strengthens democracy.  And, for our part, the United States will make a number of commitments today to reinforce our own institutions.  And these commitments have one thing in common: They will yield results &#8212; real, tangible results &#8212; that improve the lives of women in the United States and women around the world.  <br><br>So, in closing, I will address the young leaders who are participating in Generation Equality: I remain hopeful and optimistic because of you.  Our world needs your leadership.  And in that role, there are two things I want you to remember.  <br><br>First, remember to use the tools of democracy, whether that is the freedom of speech or the freedom to vote.  And if you do not yet have those freedoms, fight for them and know we will fight alongside you.  <br><br>And the second thing I want you to remember is this: Listen to those people who are not being heard.  Respect and embrace those whose experiences are different from your own, and recognize who is not in the room and invite them in.  And do not forget the power of your own story.  <br><br>When we bring people in &#8212; when we bring in all the people &#8212; we are more successful, our results are more impactful because democracy is strongest, because our world is stronger when everyone participates.  <br><br>Thank you.  Thank you all very much.  <br><br> 10:33 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the 50th Anniversary of the 26th Amendment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/30/a-proclamation-on-the-50th-anniversary-of-the-26th-amendment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 16:37:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Our Constitution recognizes that, as a Nation, we are constantly learning. &#160;Our Founders built that recognition into&#160;its original design, providing a mechanism to amend our Constitution as our Nation evolved.&#160; On July 1, 1971, our Nation ratified the 26th Amendment to the Constitution, lowering the voting age to 18.&#160; At the time, 18-, 19-, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Our Constitution recognizes that, as a Nation, we are constantly learning. &nbsp;Our Founders built that recognition into&nbsp;its original design, providing a mechanism to amend our Constitution as our Nation evolved.&nbsp; On July 1, 1971, our Nation ratified the 26th Amendment to the Constitution, lowering the voting age to 18.&nbsp; At the time, 18-, 19-, and 20-year-old Americans were fulfilling their civic duties: &nbsp;paying taxes, serving in our Armed Forces, acting as first responders, laboring in fields, factories, and service jobs across the country, and pursuing higher education. &nbsp;They were participating in our democracy and all of the responsibilities of citizenship in all ways except for one: &nbsp;they could not vote. &nbsp;A broad coalition, following in the footsteps of the suffragettes of the early 20th century and the civil rights activists of the 1960s, advocated, educated, and prevailed in persuading our Nation that those younger Americans were entitled to the right to vote.&nbsp; We&nbsp;also made a national commitment that the right to vote would never be denied or abridged for any adult voter based on their age.</p>



<p>My first race for the Senate was one of the first elections in which 18-year-olds could vote, and the energy and passion of Delaware&#8217;s young people helped propel me to an unlikely victory.</p>



<p>Fifty years later, younger voters remain essential to our civic infrastructure.&nbsp; They are not only voting in our elections &#8212; including at record rates in 2020 &#8212; but winning them.&nbsp; Younger Americans are lending their talent and vision to school boards, city councils, and county commissions; teenagers are serving as State legislators and mayors, and we are the better for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Younger voters are not waiting to inherit the future; they are building the future themselves.&nbsp; Young Americans have been on the front lines in the fight to defend the right to vote and&nbsp;expand access to the ballot box for all eligible voters.&nbsp; Their civic engagement extends beyond voting &#8212; with young Americans leading the calls for racial justice, climate action, gun violence prevention, and immigration reform among many other issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite the progress we have made, there remain persistent gaps in turnout between younger voters and their older counterparts. &nbsp;There is still more that we can and must do to deliver on the promise of the 26th Amendment.&nbsp; My Administration has made public service and civic education a priority, engaging younger Americans in our shared struggle for continual progress.&nbsp; I have directed Federal agencies to consider ways to make it easier to vote and to learn about voting, and to focus on the various ways that the Federal Government engages younger Americans, online and off.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s youth are more diverse than past generations &#8212; and laws aimed at suppressing voter turnout in Black and Brown communities also impact young voters. &nbsp;My Administration supports the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act to protect the fundamental right to vote and make our democracy more equitable and accessible for all Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, we honor the bipartisan expansion of voter enfranchisement.&nbsp; Let us continue our work to make the 26th Constitutional Amendment ever more meaningful in the months and years ahead.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim July 1, 2021, as the 50th Anniversary of the&nbsp;26th Amendment.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to participate in&nbsp;ceremonies and activities that honor the 26th formal modification of our national Charter, that recognize the contributions made by voters enfranchised by its terms, and that&nbsp;work toward full participation of all who are eligible to&nbsp;vote.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirtieth day of June, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-Harris Administration Acts to Address the Growing Wildfire Threat</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-acts-to-address-the-growing-wildfire-threat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22615</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The National Interagency Fire Center forecast predicts above normal fire potential for much of the West, in large part driven by severe drought conditions that are impacting nearly ninety percent of the region. &#160;Since 2015, the United States has experienced, on average, roughly 100 more large wildfires every year than the year before – and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The National Interagency Fire Center forecast predicts above normal fire potential for much of the West, in large part driven by severe drought conditions that are impacting nearly ninety percent of the region. &nbsp;Since 2015, the United States has experienced, on average, roughly 100 more large wildfires every year than the year before – and this wildfire season is already outpacing last season in terms of the number of large fires to date.&nbsp;Climate change is driving the devastating intersection of extreme heat, drought, and wildland fire danger across the United States.&nbsp; Decades of shifting development patterns, land and fire management decisions, and climate change have resulted in wildfires that move with a speed and intensity previously unseen.&nbsp; This has created conditions in which wildfires overwhelm response capabilities, resulting in billions of dollars in economic losses, damage to natural resources, devastation to communities, and the tragic loss of human life.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In preparation for this wildfire season, the Biden Administration has convened a series of meetings on wildfire preparedness and prevention efforts to determine what more can be done to prepare for and prevent wildfires.&nbsp; President Biden met last week with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell and his White House Homeland preparedness team to discuss ongoing efforts to prevent, prepare for and respond to extreme weather events and to underscore the importance of prompt delivery of support to communities in need.<br><br>Today, President Biden and Vice President Harris will meet with Governors from Western states, Cabinet officials and private sector partners to discuss specific actions the public and private sector are each taking to strengthen prevention, preparedness, mitigation, and response efforts – and to protect communities across our country from wildfires and their devastating impacts.&nbsp; During today’s meeting, the President will direct a number of actions, in close coordination with State and local governments and the private sector, to ensure the Federal Government can most effectively protect public safety and deliver assistance to our people in times of urgent need.&nbsp;<br><br>The President will also highlight the need to invest in wildfire prevention and risk mitigation efforts, including the nearly $50 billion in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework.&nbsp;<br><br><strong><u>The Biden-Harris Administration Is Taking Action to Respond to Wildfires this Year:</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><em>Building a More Responsive and Resilient Wildland Firefighting Workforce</em></strong><br><br><strong>Bolster firefighter pay.</strong>  Firefighters must be fairly paid for the grueling work they are willing to take on.  From supporting COVID-19 efforts to fighting wildfires, our Federal wildland firefighters have been on nearly nonstop deployments since January 2020.  That is why today we are announcing that we are fulfilling the President’s commitment that firefighters will not make less than $15 an hour this year.  In addition, permanent firefighters working on the front lines paid at up to a GS-9 level will receive up to a 10 percent retention incentive and temporary workers who commit to continue this season would receive a $1000 Spot/Star Award this year.  These are short-term solutions to support our Federal wildland firefighters, especially due to the multiple impacts of COVID and climate change this year.  The Administration will work with Congress on longer-term much needed compensation, benefit, and work-life balance reforms for Federal wildland firefighters.<br><br><strong>Extend hiring of temporary firefighters to ensure effective response throughout this year’s fire season.  </strong>To mitigate concerns about Federal firefighter capacity this year, today we are announcing that the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) has approved an exemption to extend seasonal Department of Agriculture (USDA) and Department of Interior (DOI) wildland fire employees to work additional hours beyond their term.  Because of climate change, wildland firefighting is no longer a seasonal endeavor.  Fires are burning later into the season and temporary employees often reach their limited hours earlier in the year.  This week, OPM also approved an extension of the Forest Service’s (USFS) direct hire authority for wildland firefighters and support personnel.  These proactive personnel management actions will help sustain the Nation’s vital Federal wildland firefighting capacity.  We also recognize the need for a sustainable long-term staffing approach into the future that offers more permanent, stable employment.<br><br><strong>Continue transition to a more permanent firefighting workforce.  </strong>With fire seasons turning into fire years, it is imperative to have a year-round workforce that is available to respond at any time, that is supported and equitably compensated, and is available to undertake preventive actions like hazardous fuels management treatments during periods of low fire activity.  DOI has committed to hiring 210 new employees and converting 575 employees from career seasonal to full-time employees during this fiscal year.  Additionally, DOI is providing funding for 42 new tribal positions and the conversion of 153 tribal positions from career seasonal to full-time employees to support wildfire response.  USFS will continue to prioritize expanding its permanent wildland firefighting workforce.<br><br><strong><em>Improving Wildfire Response Capabilities</em></strong><br><br><strong>Provide robust response through 15,000 Federal firefighters and additional surge capacity.  </strong>Wildland firefighting is a complex, multi-agency effort, and our Federal firefighters work side-by-side with their State, Tribal, and local counterparts on a daily basis.  USFS and DOI maintain a capacity of over 15,000 Federal firefighters who are able to respond to wildfires across the nation.  USFS and DOI can also activate up to 13,000 additional employees throughout their departments to support wildfire response.  These surge employees provide additional capacity to the response, ranging from firefighting capabilities for qualified employees, to critical response support through incident management, acquisition, and human resources.  USFS and DOI have additional capacity to call 11,000 administratively determined personnel from outside their departments to support the response.  These employees are generally retired agency personnel who can be dispatched to support incident management teams and other firefighting functions.<br><br><strong>Train and equip military personnel to be ready to quickly support wildland fires as needed.  </strong>Congress made Federal funding available to train and equip the National Guard to conduct firefighting operations to support state response to wildfires.  All eleven states who requested this support have received the funding and training is underway.  The Department of Defense (DOD) has also pre-identified two military units, with 200 personnel each, to receive training and specialized equipment to support firefighting operations if required. <br><br><strong>Increase aviation capacity to support immediate response.  </strong>Aviation assets are critical in the management of wildfires to slow or decrease the intensity of the fire and enable safe operations for firefighters on the ground.  This year, the USFS has increased the overall capacity of airtankers and helicopters to ensure their availability during peak fire activity.  USFS and DOI share aviation resources, which includes up to 34 air-tankers and over 200 helicopters to boost our Nation’s wildfire response capabilities.  When needed, DOD is able to provide aviation support through National Guard and Air Force Reserve C-130 crews and helicopter transport crews and equipment to support medical evacuation or water drops for fire response.     <br><br><strong>Provide critical financial support to assist in wildfire response.  </strong>This Administration is ready to assist communities at the start of severe fires with critical Fire Management Assistance Grants (FMAGs).  Issued through the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), FMAGs assist states, local, and tribal governments with the mitigation, management, and control of fires which threaten such destruction as would constitute a major disaster.  FEMA has approved 9 FMAGs since the start of 2021. <br><br><strong><em>Utilizing Data and Technology to Protect Communities</em></strong><br><br><strong>Leverage satellite and emerging technologies to rapidly detect new, often remote, wildland fires.  </strong>The Federal government has a number of new, innovative ways to detect and notify emergency personnel when wildfires start.  The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) uses satellite-based early wildfire detection to provide initial location information to first responders, allowing them to attack fires more quickly.  NOAA is partnering with other Federal Departments and Agencies and state governments to expand the use of this technology and its associated notification system.  The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/budget_fy22.pdf">FY 2022 President’s Budget</a> includes $15 million to support fire weather activities, including a new NOAA Fire Weather Testbed to provide improved operations, service delivery, and decision making based on the latest science and research.  This virtual and onsite infrastructure will bring together fire weather community researchers, operational experts, and emergency managers across Federal, state, local, territorial, and tribal governments, academia, and the private sector to develop new, impact-based decision support tools, products, and models to address wildfires. The President’s Budget also proposes a new wildfire applications program within NASA to develop innovative tools and applications using satellite data and the latest science to assist with wildland fire management. Working with the wildland fire management agencies, this program will support community-based consortiums to co-develop and pilot applications in all phases of wildfires.<br><br><strong>Use research to improve early detection wildfire sensors.</strong>  The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) is also focusing its research agenda on innovations that will improve the Nation’s ability to predict, detect, and control wildfires.  Just two weeks ago, DHS Science and Technology <a>announced</a> successful Phase II trials of four prototype early detection wildfire sensors.  Through a variety of sampling sensors and advanced algorithms, these technologies, once deployed, will provide early warning to fire-vulnerable communities, ultimately providing valuable time that will aid responders and save lives. <br><br><strong>Use the latest science and technologies to enhance our wildfire response.  </strong>The Federal government manages all fires using a risk-based suppression strategy.  As we head into the peak of a long, arduous season, it is more important than ever we deploy firefighters when they have the highest probability of success.  USFS and DOI are using the latest science and technologies to enhance our operational capability and decision making so when firefighting resources are used, they are able to work safely and effectively and protect critical infrastructure and natural resources. USFS researchers have specifically created a mapping unit called “Firesheds” that aggregates areas that have similar fire behavior and community risk characteristics, allowing USFS to more effectively prioritize hazardous fuel treatments.  The Department of Energy (DOE), through the National Labs, have a variety of programs underway to develop sensors and patches to help prevent structural energy infrastructure failures that have the potential to ignite wildfires. <br><br><strong>Prepare to address potential power impacts as a result of wildfires.  </strong>Approximately 10 percent of wildfire ignitions are sparked by faults on electrical grid infrastructure or electric equipment failures.  There is also a growing risk of intentional power shutoffs in anticipation of or due to wildfires.  In order to minimize rolling blackouts during extreme heat and wildfire risk, DOE is prepared to authorize utilities to run power plants at their maximum capacity to best meet emergency needs.  DOE also uses its Environment for Analysis of Geo-Located Energy Information (EAGLE-I) tool to give first responders and State Emergency Management Officials information on the status of the power grid, which is critical in facilitating response and recovery efforts.  Finally, DOE will leverage the analytical capabilities of the National Laboratories to provide tools for damage assessments, predictive analysis, and grid management to support response efforts.  This tool is available to Federal, state, local, tribal governments and first responders and will include wildfire data in its analysis in 2022.<br><br><strong>Use research and modeling to protect firefighters and residents from smoke and dangerous air.  </strong>Wildfires can lead to smoke and water quality concerns that may impact public health, and the Administration is undertaking a number of efforts to mitigate these concerns.  NOAA uses satellite data and models to forecast smoke and communicate areas of dangerous air quality and low visibility.  During a wildfire, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) also monitors and models smoke, develops smoke outlooks, and supports community public health notifications and guidance.  EPA is developing and expanding availability of the Vehicle Add-on Mobile Monitoring System (VAMMS) for use in heavy smoke impacted areas to provide ground truth on smoke plume and air quality models.  EPA is also evaluating how filtration devices, such as facemasks and portable air cleaners, can reduce exposures during smoke episodes.  With funding from the American Rescue Plan, EPA is piloting a project with Western states to use schools as clean air shelters and cooling centers during heat and smoke events.<br><br><strong>Provide actionable information to help Americans stay safe during a wildfire. </strong><br>FEMA recently redesigned its Wildland Urban Interface website to highlight resources and information to assist states and local communities in preventing and preparing for wildfires.  EPA developed a wildfire smoke guide, in collaboration with a range of Federal and State partners, to provide specific information on the impacts of smoke and actions individuals can take to reduce their exposure.  EPA and the USFS launched the <a href="https://fire.airnow.gov/">AirNow Fire and Smoke Map</a>, which combines data from EPA’s air monitoring network with data from low-cost sensors, to improve air quality and smoke information available to the public during fire events.  In July, the EPA will add the Fire and Smoke Map to the AirNow mobile app, making this information more readily available to the public.<br><br><strong><em>Reducing the Risk of Wildfires throughHazardous Fuels Management and Mitigation Investments</em></strong><br><br><strong>Provide assistance to mitigate the impacts of future wildfires and protect communities</strong>. The Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities (BRIC) program provides a critical opportunity for governments to invest in resilience before a disaster.  In FY 2020, $500 million was made available through the BRIC program to support states, local communities, tribes, and territories for pre-disaster mitigation.  In May, the Administration doubled FEMA BRIC program resources – to $1 billion – for FY 2021.  Today, FEMA is announcing that one of the FY 2020 BRIC projects selected will provide $37 million in federal funds for an innovative wildfire mitigation project in Sonoma, CA that focuses on mitigation activities at both the large wildland-scale and the neighborhood-scale in order to build more resilient communities.  FEMA will soon announce additional FY 2020 BRIC projects selected for Federal funding. FEMA also provides assistance to mitigate future wildfires under the Hazard Mitigation Grant Program (HMGP) Post-Fire for communities.  FEMA Regional offices are coordinating with state and tribal partners to highlight the opportunities made available through these grant programs.<br><br><strong>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework invests nearly $50 billion to build resilience to wildfires and helps western communities prepare for droughts. </strong> Last year, the United States faced 22 extreme weather and climate-related disaster events with loses over $1 billion – a cumulative price tag of nearly $100 billion.  The bipartisan infrastructure framework will help the country prepare for those events by investing in forest management and upgrades to critical infrastructure &#8212; like elevating buildings, roads, and bridges, hardening physical infrastructure, and winterizing the power grid – as well as funding state and local infrastructure improvements and emergency response strategies, such as planning grants to support development of evacuation routes or upgrading community shelters.  The Framework will also make it easier for low-income families to buy flood insurance.  And it will help Western farmers, ranchers, tribes, families, and communities better prepare for future droughts. It will invest in ecosystem restoration, such as the restoration of wetlands that can reduce flood risk for communities.<br><br><strong>Invest in extreme wildfire protection through the FY 2022 Budget.  </strong>The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/budget_fy22.pdf">FY 2022 President’s Budget</a> includes over $30 billion in FY 2022 to support wildfire management and related activities and disaster relief.  This funding is necessary in order to ensure we have the resources necessary to better prepare and respond to wildfires and protect communities.<br><br><strong>More effective treatment of hazardous fuels.  </strong>This Administration understands the need to address forest management in the prevention of wildfires.  The President’s FY 2022 Budget has proposed a 62% increase in hazardous fuels funding across USFS and DOI.  This funding is used to reduce wildfire hazards by addressing the excessive accumulation of biomass (i.e., “hazardous fuels”) in targeted locations.  Investments in FY 2022 will be informed by a scientific, outcome-based national investment model that targets land treatments to areas where they can be most effective in protecting communities.  The USFS and DOI have identified more than 4 million acres that could be treated this year with the funding requested in the FY 2022 Budget.  The Administration looks forward to working with Congress to fully fund this critical program.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: United States to Announce Commitments to the Generation Equality Forum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-united-states-to-announce-commitments-to-the-generation-equality-forum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the United States joined global partners – including governments, civil society, and the private sector – in making commitments to the Generation Equality Forum, reasserting U.S. leadership on gender equity and equality on the world stage. The Generation Equality Forum (GEF), convened by UN Women and co-hosted by the governments of France and Mexico,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Today, the United States joined global partners – including governments, civil society, and the private sector – in making commitments to the Generation Equality Forum, reasserting U.S. leadership on gender equity and equality on the world stage.</em></p>



<p>The Generation Equality Forum (GEF), convened by UN Women and co-hosted by the governments of France and Mexico, marks the anniversary of the United Nation’s Fourth World Conference on Women held in Beijing over 25 years ago, where the world recognized that “women’s rights are human rights” and adopted an ambitious Platform for Action to achieve equality and opportunity for women around the world.&nbsp; While tremendous progress has been made since the Beijing Conference, serious gaps remain, which have been exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic. The Generation Equality Forum offers an opportunity to make bold, measurable commitments to build back better and accelerate progress towards the Beijing Platform and the Sustainable Development Goals.</p>



<p>The U.S. commitments reflect the Biden-Harris Administration’s domestic and global priorities, including policy and resource commitments to:</p>



<ul><li>Prevent and respond to all forms of gender-based violence;</li><li>Strengthen women’s economic security; and</li><li>Protect and advance sexual and reproductive health and rights.</li></ul>



<p>Our participation in the Generation Equality Forum is an important part of broader U.S. efforts to advance gender equity and equality, including in areas beyond the scope of commitments announced today, such as climate, science and technology, leadership and democracy, and education. This includes efforts underway to support the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/fact-sheet-president-biden-and-g7-leaders-launch-build-back-better-world-b3w-partnership/">Build Back Better World</a>&nbsp;Partnership to meet the tremendous infrastructure needs of low- and middle-income countries, particularly across the areas of gender equity and equality, climate, health and health security, and information and communications technology. Finally, as part of Generation Equality, we have also signed on to the Compact on Women, Peace, and Security and Humanitarian Action and will continue our robust implementation of the U.S. Women, Peace, and Security Act, which strengthens our efforts to prevent, mitigate, and resolve conflict by improving the participation of women in peace and security processes.<br><br>Our Generation Equality Forum commitments include:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Prevent and Respond to Gender-Based Violence</strong></span><br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><br></span>Preventing and responding to gender-based violence is a significant pillar of the Biden-Harris Administration’s work on gender equity and equality. The “shadow pandemic” of alarming increases in rates of gender-based violence in the U.S. and globally underscore the urgency of our collective efforts.</p>



<p><strong><em>Domestic efforts to combat gender-based violence</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Create the first U.S. National Action Plan on Gender-Based Violence, led by the White House Gender Policy Council, to be launched in 2022.&nbsp; This plan will establish a whole-of-government approach to preventing and addressing gender-based violence (GBV) domestically and globally, with significant input from civil society.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Provide $450 million in supplementary funding through the President’s&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/American-Rescue-Plan-Fact-Sheet.pdf">American Rescue Plan</a>&nbsp;to prevent and respond to domestic violence and sexual assault. This includes $200 million for domestic violence services and support; $198 million for sexual assault services programs; and $49.5 million for a new program to fund culturally specific community-based organizations to improve access to services and safety for survivors in historically marginalized communities, with a primary focus on racial and ethnic minority communities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Reauthorize and strengthen the Violence Against Women Act (VAWA), which passed the U. S. House of Representatives this spring with bipartisan support and is pending in the U.S. Senate.&nbsp; First passed in 1994 with then-Senator Biden as its champion, the VAWA is a landmark piece of bipartisan legislation that has transformed the nation&#8217;s response to gender-based violence, bringing critically needed resources to States, Territories, Tribes, and local communities to help prevent and improve the response to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Request, as part of the FY 2022 President’s Budget, an historic investment of $1 billion to support VAWA programs coordinated through the U.S. Department of Justice—a 95% increase over FY 2021 enacted levels.&nbsp; Also request $463.5 million to be administered through the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, including $250 million to provide cash assistance to survivors of domestic violence to support their short and long-term transition to safety and stability.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Improve prevention and response to sexual assault and harassment in the U.S. military, including by establishing an Independent Review Commission (IRC) on Military Sexual Assault, which conducted a thorough review and recently made significant recommendations on accountability, prevention, climate and culture, and victim support to the U.S. Secretary of Defense and the President.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Strengthen the U.S. National Action Plan on Trafficking in Persons to integrate the administration’s commitments to gender and racial equity.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Propose “safe leave” as part of the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/28/fact-sheet-the-american-families-plan/">American Families Plan</a>, a comprehensive paid family and medical leave program that would permit workers eligible to receive paid leave for reasons pertaining to sexual assault, stalking, dating or domestic violence.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>International efforts to combat gender-based violence</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Update and strengthen the 2016 U.S. Strategy to Prevent and Respond to Gender-Based Violence Globally,&nbsp;in coordination with the development of the first-ever U.S. National Action Plan to End Gender-Based Violence.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Request, as part of the FY 2022 President’s Budget, $175 million to prevent and respond to gender-based violence globally, as part of a $1.2 billion request for gender programming abroad.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Host the Fourth Trilateral Working Group on Violence Against Indigenous Women and Girls with the Governments of Mexico and Canada. The Biden-Harris Administration will relaunch this regional collaboration, which presents an opportunity to continue to improve and reaffirm our respective national and regional commitments to exchanging information about policies, programs and promising practices to prevent and respond to violence against Indigenous women and girls through increased access to justice and services, with a human rights and culturally-responsive approach.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Double the annual investment by the President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief in DREAMS–Determined, Resilient, Empowered, AIDS-Free, Mentored, Safe Partnership–which supports programs focused on economic strengthening, gender-based violence prevention, post-GBV care, and&nbsp;sexual and reproductive health services in Haiti and 14 African countries. The U.S. government will seek to continue this increased level of support during FY2022, pending Congressional notification and approval.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Announce U.S. commitments to the Call to Action on Protection from Gender-Based Violence in Emergencies 2021-2025 Road Map. The U.S. will strengthen its leadership role in addressing GBV within the humanitarian system to ensure this issue is prioritized and resourced from the outset of emergencies. Through the joint State/USAID Safe from the Start initiative, the U.S. will implement Call to Action commitments that seek to strengthen the quality of GBV programming, support improved GBV risk mitigation efforts, and improve resource tracking and accountability for GBV programming as part of humanitarian assistance.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Co-sponsor a resolution on “Ending violence against children through health systems strengthening and multisectoral approaches” during the 2021 World Health Assembly, which was passed by consensus. This resolution prioritizes WHO Member State actions on child protection, to prevent and address early, child, and forced marriage, child trafficking, exploitation and abuse of children and other actions that threaten the emotional, mental, and physical health of children.</li></ul>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Advance Women’s Economic Security and Promote Economic Justice&nbsp;</span></strong></p>



<p>The Biden Administration has taken critical steps to strengthen women’s economic security through the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/American-Rescue-Plan-Fact-Sheet.pdf">American Rescue Plan</a>&nbsp;and has proposed once-in-a-generation investments as part of the American Jobs Plan and American Families Plan. The Administration is also committed to advancing women’s economic opportunity and security around the world.</p>



<p><strong><em>Domestic efforts to strengthen women’s economic security</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Provide immediate relief for women and families through the American Rescue Plan (ARP), helping hard-hit households recover from the economic impacts of the COVID-19 pandemic. The ARP expands the Child Tax Credit, allowing more families to benefit, increasing the size of the benefit, and distributing benefits monthly. And it includes a historic investment of more than $40 billion in child care and early learning. States, tribes, and territories can use these investments to help child care providers—who are disproportionately women of color—avoid potential closure and ensure that they can operate safely and increase pay and benefits for care workers, who are also disproportionately women of color. These funds can also be used to help parents better afford high-quality child care.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Propose, as part of the American Jobs Plan, a major investment in care infrastructure, including a $400 billion investment in expanding access to home- or community-based care, expanding access to long-term care services under Medicaid, and additional investments to modernize schools and child care facilities.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Strengthen the workforce pipeline for all, including more women and communities of color, to access in-demand jobs through the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/03/31/fact-sheet-the-american-jobs-plan/">American Jobs Plan</a>, including by investing in apprenticeships and other workforce development programs like Women in Apprenticeship in Non-Traditional Occupations. This commitment includes ensuring jobs with fair and equal pay, safe and healthy workplaces, and workplaces free from racial, gender, and other forms of discrimination and harassment.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Propose, through the American Families Plan (AFP), a $1 trillion commitment to working families, helping cover basic expenses that families need and care most about: making child care and higher education more affordable, lowering the cost of health care over the long term, and continuing to reduce child poverty and put money in parents’ pockets by extending the historic expansion of the Child Tax Credit in the American Rescue Plan. This investment in working families also includes establishing a comprehensive national paid family and medical leave program.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Work with Congress to pass key legislation for women’s employment in addition to the American Jobs Plan and American Families Plan, including the Pregnant Workers Fairness Act, which passed the U.S. House of Representatives this spring with bipartisan support.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>International efforts to strengthen women’s economic security</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Mobilize at least $12 billion—an average $2.4 billion per year, from January 2021 through December 2025—as part of the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation’s new 2X commitment to invest in businesses that advance gender equity in emerging markets.&nbsp; These funds will support 15 million women and girls, including from marginalized communities and fragile and post-conflict settings.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Announce that the Development Finance Corporation will establish 2X Technical Assistance Pilot Program to help private sector clients advance gender equity in their businesses, such as by increasing the number of women in leadership or developing products or services designed specifically to meet the differentiated needs of their women clients.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Establish the Gender Equity and Equality Action (GEEA) Fund—with $100 million in FY 2021 and a request of $200 million in the FY 2022 President’s Budget—to advance economic security for women and girls globally, prevent and respond to gender-based violence, and support underserved and marginalized populations. In addition, the GEEA Fund will help address the disproportionate impact that COVID-19, climate change, and conflict and crisis have on women and girls.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Promote women’s entrepreneurship around the world, including through grants to grassroots and community-led organizations through the Inter-American Foundation and grants to gender-inclusive digital services for women-owned businesses through the U.S.-African Development Foundation.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Commit $33 million in FY 2020 funds to advance gender equity and equality in the Northern Triangle by increasing women’s economic access, agency, and power while reducing gender-based violence in the community, workplace, and household. In addition, commit $2.2 million in FY 2020 funding to small grants for 15 local organizations in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras that advance women’s economic participation through the Inter-American Foundation.</li></ul>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline"><strong>Protect and Expand Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights</strong></span><br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><br></span>The Biden Administration is committed to advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights in the U.S. and around the world. Everyone should have access to quality, affordable health care regardless of their income or where they live.</p>



<p><strong><em>Domestic efforts to protect and expand sexual and reproductive health and rights</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Remove, as part of the President’s first budget, the Hyde Amendment restriction from government spending bills, reflecting the President’s support for expanding access to health care, including reproductive health care, through Medicaid and other federally-funded programs.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Review rules for Title X of the Public Health Services Act, which provides Federal funding for family planning services that primarily benefit low-income patients, to ensure access to family planning and other preventive health care. The Department of Health and Human Services published a notice of proposed rulemaking related to the Title X program entitled &#8220;Ensuring access to equitable, affordable, client-centered, quality family planning services.&#8221; This proposed rule revises the 2019 rules by readopting the 2000 regulations, with several modifications needed to strengthen the program and ensure access to equitable, affordable, client-centered, quality family planning services for all clients, especially for low-income clients.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Direct $50 million in supplemental funding to the Title X Family Planning Program through the American Rescue Plan, in addition to a&nbsp;proposed $340 million to the Title X Program in the President’s discretionary budget request.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Expand Medicaid postpartum coverage from 60 days to 12 months, ensuring that more new mothers can retain health coverage and stay healthy.</li><li>Propose, as part of the President’s FY 2022 discretionary budget request, $200 million to reduce maternal mortality rates and end race-based disparities, and as part of the American Families Plan, a $3 billion investment to further address the maternal health crisis in the United States, which has a particularly significant impact on Black and Indigenous women, by growing and diversifying the perinatal workforce, improving data collection to better understand the causes of maternal death and complications from birth, and investing in community-based organizations.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>International efforts to protect and expand sexual and reproductive health and rights</em></strong></p>



<ul><li>Issued a Presidential Memorandum on January 28, 2021 to protect and expand access to comprehensive reproductive health services and care, which rescinded the harmful Mexico City Policy, among other actions.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Propose, as part of the President’s FY 2022 budget request, resuming funding for the UN Population Fund (UNFPA), including $56 million in the FY 2022 President’s Budget, a 72% increase over the FY 2021 enacted level. Funding for UNFPA would directly support the provision of sexual and reproductive health services in fragile contexts, where access to such services is limited.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Support the World Health Organization’s (WHO) strengthening of internal operations, including efforts to prevent and address sexual exploitation and abuse within their workforce and the broader health sector, and to bolster WHO’s capacity to deliver critical services and technical guidance, including in emergency contexts.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Assess the current status of HRP (the UN Development Programme/UN Population Fund/UN Children’s Fund/WHO/World Bank Special Programme of Research, Development and Research Training in Human Reproduction) and how U.S. expertise can align to support its work. The HRP is the primary instrument within the United Nations system for research in human reproduction, and U.S. engagement will help advance critical research, including building research capacity of lower income countries.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Commit publicly with like-minded countries to a series of progressive meetings on continuing and expanding essential sexual and reproductive health service delivery on the margins of WHA and WHO regional committees, the UN General Assembly, World Economic Forum, and World Bank fall meetings, among others.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Commit to supporting women in the global health workforce and affirm U.S. support of the Gender Equal Healthcare Workforce Initiative and its pillars, which aims to minimize and address inequities and inequalities female health workers face globally. This includes harassment and violence, pay inequities, and lack of opportunities for professional training and advancement.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Names Fifth Round of Judicial Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/president-biden-names-fifth-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing eight new candidates for the federal bench and one new candidate&#160;for District of Columbia courts, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As he continues to move at an historic pace with respect to judicial nominees, the President is announcing eight new candidates for the federal bench and one new candidate&nbsp;for District of Columbia courts, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.<br><br>For example, this slate includes:</p>



<ul><li>A woman who would be the first federal judge of South Asian descent in Michigan</li><li>A labor lawyer and former union organizer who would also be the first AAPI judge from Oregon on the Ninth Circuit</li><li>An Assistant U.S. Attorney who would be the second woman of color to ever serve on the federal bench in Virginia</li><li>A former prosecutor with the Department of Justice’s Public Integrity Section who would be the first Hispanic judge on the Court of Federal Claims</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-left">This is President Biden’s fifth round of names for federal judicial positions, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 32.<br><br>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move at an unparalleled speed with respect to judicial nominations. His first judicial nominations announcement was made faster than that of any new President in modern American history, and today’s announcement continues that trend.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>CIRCUIT COURTS</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>TOBY J. HEYTENS</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Toby Heytens has served as the Solicitor General for the Commonwealth of Virginia since his appointment in 2018. Mr. Heytens previously served as a Professor of Law at the University of Virginia School of Law from 2014 to 2018 and as an Associate Professor of Law from 2010 to 2014 and from 2006 to 2007. During his tenure at the University of Virginia School of Law, he also frequently served as a co-director of its Supreme Court Litigation Clinic. From 2007 to 2010, Mr. Heytens served as an Assistant to the Solicitor General at the U.S. Department of Justice. From 2003 to 2006, Mr. Heytens worked in the Supreme Court and Appellate Practice Group at O’Melveny &amp; Myers LLP in Washington, D.C. Mr. Heytens served as a Bristow Fellow in the Office of the Solicitor General at the U.S. Department of Justice from 2001 to 2002. Mr. Heytens served as a law clerk for Justice Ruth Bader Ginsburg on the U.S. Supreme Court from 2002 to 2003 and for Judge Edward R. Becker on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit from 2000 to 2001.<br><br>Mr. Heytens received his B.A. from Macalester College in 1997 and his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 2000.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>JENNIFER SUNG</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Jennifer Sung has been a member of the Oregon Employment Relations Board since her appointment in 2017. Previously, she was a partner at McKanna Bishop Joffe LLP in Portland, where she worked from 2013 to 2017. From 2007 to 2013, Ms. Sung worked at Altshuler Berzon LLP in San Francisco. While in private practice, she was a litigator specializing in labor, employment, and constitutional law, and she represented labor organizations and employees in arbitrations, administrative proceedings, and civil litigation in state and federal courts. From 2005 to 2007, Ms. Sung was a Skadden Fellow at the Brennan Center for Justice at New York University School of Law. Ms. Sung served as a law clerk for Judge Betty Binns Fletcher on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from 2004 to 2005. Before law school, she was an organizer with the Service Employees International Union Local 1199 from 1998 to 2001 and with the Service Employees International Union Local 74 from 1996 to 1998.<br><br>Ms. Sung received her J.D. from Yale Law School in 2004 and her B.A. from Oberlin College in 1994.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">DISTRICT COURTS</span></strong><br><br><strong>JANE M. BECKERING<br><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the Western District of Michigan</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Judge Jane M. Beckering has served on the Michigan Court of Appeals since 2007, where she oversees both civil and criminal proceedings. Judge Beckering is the Chief Judge Pro Tempore of the Court. She is also President-Elect of the Grand Rapids Bar Association and previously served on the Michigan Supreme Court Committee on Model Civil Jury Instructions. Prior to becoming a judge, Judge Beckering was a trial lawyer in private practice for 17 years. She founded the law firm of Buchanan &amp; Beckering, PLC in Grand Rapids, Michigan, primarily focused on representing plaintiffs in civil litigation. She began her law career as an associate with McDermott, Will &amp; Emery, P.C. in Chicago. Judge Beckering received her J.D. from the University of Wisconsin in 1990 and her B.A. from the University of Michigan in 1987.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>PATRICIA TOLLIVER GILES</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Patricia Tolliver Giles has served in the U.S. Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Virginia since 2003, and currently serves as Managing Assistant U.S. Attorney. She previously served as an Assistant U.S. Attorney in the Major Crimes Unit from 2003 to 2019. She also serves on the Attorney General’s Transnational Organized Crime Task Force, MS-13 Subcommittee. From 2000 to 2003, Ms. Giles was an associate at Cooley Godward LLP. Her work included a wide variety of commercial cases in the areas of contracts, intellectual property, securities, and employment law. Ms. Giles served as a law clerk for Judge Gerald Bruce Lee on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia from 1998 to 2000. Ms. Giles received her J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1998 and her B.A. from University of Virginia in 1995.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SHALINA D. KUMAR</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Chief Judge Shalina D. Kumar has served on the Oakland County Sixth Circuit Court since 2007. She was appointed Chief Judge of the Circuit Court by the Michigan Supreme Court in January of 2018. In addition to her chief judge duties, Judge Kumar retains a full caseload covering both civil and criminal matters. Throughout her years on the bench, Judge Kumar has served as a presiding judge of the Adult Treatment Court, the Chairperson of the Oakland County Criminal Assignment Committee, the bench liaison to the Oakland County Bar Association Circuit Court Committee, a member of the Michigan State Bar Professionalism Committee, and a member of the Executive Committee of the Michigan Judges’ Association. Prior to taking the bench, Judge Kumar was a civil litigator in private practice from 1997 to 2007, including as an associate with Weiner &amp; Cox P.L.C. from 2004 to 2007 and Sommers, Schwartz, Silver &amp; Schwartz P.C. from 2000 to 2004. Judge Kumar graduated from the University of Michigan in 1993 and the University of Detroit-Mercy School of Law in 1996.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><strong>MICHAEL S. NACHMANOFF</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Judge Michael S. Nachmanoff has served as a U.S. Magistrate Judge for the Eastern District of Virginia since 2015. Before his appointment to the bench, Judge Nachmanoff served for 13 years in the Office of the Federal Public Defender for the Eastern District of Virginia, serving as Chief Federal Public Defender from 2007 to 2015, Acting Federal Public Defender from 2005 to 2007, and First Assistant Public Defender from 2002 to 2005. Prior to serving as a federal defender, Judge Nachmanoff was a partner at Cohen, Gettings &amp; Dunham, P.C. He joined the firm as an associate in 1996 and was a partner from 2000 to 2002. At the firm, Judge Nachmanoff’s practice consisted of complex civil litigation, white collar federal criminal defense, and state court criminal cases. Judge Nachmanoff served as a law clerk for Judge Leonie Brinkema on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia from 1995 to 1996. Judge Nachmanoff received his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1995 and his B.A. from Wesleyan University in 1991. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>COURT OF FEDERAL CLAIMS</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>ARMANDO O. BONILLA<br><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Federal Claims</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Armando O. Bonilla has been the Vice President of Ethics and Investigations at Capital One since 2018. Bonilla previously served at the U.S. Department of Justice in a variety of roles from 1994 to 2018. He served as Associate General Counsel for the U.S. Marshals Service from 2017 to 2018; as Associate Deputy Attorney General from 2010 to 2017; as a prosecutor in the Public Integrity Section of the Criminal Division from 2002 to 2010 and in the Asset Forfeiture and Money Laundering Section of the Criminal Division from 2001 to 2002; and as a trial and appellate attorney in the Civil Division’s Commercial Litigation Branch from 1994 to 2001. Mr. Bonilla served as a law clerk for Judge Garrett E. Brown, Jr. on the U.S. District Court for the District of New Jersey from 1992 to 1994.<br><br>Mr. Bonilla received his J.D., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from Seton Hall University School of Law in 1992 and his B.A. from West Virginia University in 1989.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>CAROLYN N. LERNER</strong><br><strong><em>Nominated to the United States Court of Federal Claims</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Carolyn N. Lerner is currently the Chief Circuit Mediator for the U.S. Courts of the D.C. Circuit, a position she has held since 2017. She was previously unanimously confirmed to head the U.S. Office of Special Counsel, where she served from 2011 to 2017. Ms. Lerner is an adjunct law professor at Georgetown University Law Center, and was previously an adjunct law professor at George Washington University Law School. Ms. Lerner was a founding partner of the civil rights and employment law firm Heller, Huron, Chertkof, Lerner, Simon &amp; Salzman, where she practiced from 1997 to 2011. While at her law firm, from 2003 to 2005, Ms. Lerner served as the federal court-appointed Special Inspector for the Office of Special Inspector at the D.C. Department of Corrections. From 1991 to 1996, Ms. Lerner was a litigation attorney at Kator, Scott, Heller &amp; Huron, a civil rights and employment law firm. She began her legal career as a law clerk for Chief Judge Julian Abele Cook, Jr. on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Michigan.<br><br>Ms. Lerner received her J.D. from New York University Law School in 1989, where she was a Root-Tilden Scholar, and her B.G.S, with distinction, from the Honors College at the University of Michigan in 1986.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>LOCAL D.C. COURTS</u></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>SEAN C. STAPLES<br><em>Nominated to the Superior Court of the District of Columbia</em></strong></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Judge Sean C. Staples is a Magistrate Judge assigned to the Criminal and Domestic Violence Divisions on the Superior Court of the District of Columbia. Before his appointment to the bench, Judge Staples was an attorney with the Children’s Law Center from 2006 to 2013, last serving as the Guardian ad Litem Project Director. From 2000 to 2006, Judge Staples was a clinical professor in the Criminal Division of the D.C. Law Students in Court Program, supervising law students in the representation of adults and juveniles in D.C. Superior Court. Judge Staples served as a law clerk for Judge Robert E. Morin of the D.C. Superior Court from 1998 to 1999. Judge Staples received his J.D. from the Catholic University of America Columbus School of Law in 1996 and his B.S. from Syracuse University in 1991.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
