<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 20:36:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-72/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 20:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Randy W. Berry, of Colorado, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Namibia. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Anjali Chaturvedi, of Maryland, to be General Counsel, Department of Veterans Affairs, vice Richard&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Randy W. Berry, of Colorado, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Namibia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Anjali Chaturvedi, of Maryland, to be General Counsel, Department of Veterans Affairs, vice Richard A. Sauber.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Robert William Forden, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Cambodia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thomas E. Harvey, of Florida, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Moshe Z. Marvit, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission for a term expiring August 30, 2028, vice Arthur R. Traynor III, term expiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Arati Prabhakar, of California, to be Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, vice Eric S. Lander, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Robert E. Primus, of New Jersey, to be a Member of the Surface Transportation Board for a term expiring December 31, 2027.&nbsp;&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rolfe Michael Schiffer, of New York, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Jonathan Nicholas Stivers.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lucy Tamlyn, of Rhode Island, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Democratic Republic of the Congo.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; Pamela M. Tremont, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Zimbabwe.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Gas Prices and Putin&#8217;s Price&#160;Hike</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/22/remarks-by-president-biden-on-gas-prices-and-putins-price-hike/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 20:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 2:03 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I&#8217;d like to talk to you about the actions I’m announcing to bring down gas prices. First, today I’m calling on Congress to suspend the federal gas tax for the next 90 days, through the busy summer season &#8212; busy travel&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>2:03 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to talk to you about the actions I’m announcing to bring down gas prices.<br><br>First, today I’m calling on Congress to suspend the federal gas tax for the next 90 days, through the busy summer season &#8212; busy travel season.</p>



<p>Here’s what that means: Every time you go to the gas station to fill your tank, the federal government charges an 18-cent tax per gallon of gas that you purchase and a 24-cent tax per gallon of diesel you purchase.&nbsp; It’s a tax that’s been around for 90 years.</p>



<p>It’s important because we use it for the Highway Trust Fund to keep our highways going.&nbsp; But what I’m proposing is suspending the federal gas tax without affecting the Highway Trust Fund.</p>



<p>And here’s how we do that: With the tax revenues up this year and our deficit down over $1.6 trillion this year alone, we’ll still be able to fix our highways and bring down prices of gas.&nbsp; We can do both at the same time.</p>



<p>By suspending the 18-cent gas tax &#8212; federal gas tax for the next 90 days, we can bring down the price of gas and give families just a little bit of relief.</p>



<p>I call on the companies to pass this along &#8212; every penny of this 18-cents reduction &#8212; to the consumers.&nbsp; This is &#8212; there&#8217;s no time now for profiteering.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are a number of other proposals by Democrats in the House and the Senate, and I hope my call for action can help move those proposals forward as well.&nbsp; But we can also cut gas prices even more in another way.</p>



<p>That’s why the second action I’m taking is calling on states to either suspend the state gas tax as well or find other ways to deliver some relief.</p>



<p>State gas taxes average [another] 30 cents per gallon.&nbsp; Already, some states have acted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Connecticut and New York, the governors have temporarily suspended their gas tax as well.</p>



<p>In Illinois and Colorado, governors delayed theirs to give families a bit more breathing room as well.</p>



<p>In Minnesota, Governor Walz proposes using state budget surpluses to give households a rebate that will help them pay for gas at the pump or other essential needs.</p>



<p>I’m calling on more states and local governments to take actions like these.</p>



<p>Thanks to our historic economic recovery, which fortified state budgets that had been hurt in the pandemic, states are now in a strong position to be able to afford to take some of these actions.</p>



<p>Now, I fully understand that a gas tax holiday alone is not going to fix the problem, but it will provide families some immediate relief &#8212; just a little bit of breathing room &#8212; as we continue working to bring down prices for the long haul.</p>



<p>Third, I’m calling on the industry to refine more oil into gasoline and to bring down gas prices.</p>



<p>Let me explain.&nbsp; I know my Republican friends claim we’re not producing enough oil and I’m limiting oil production.&nbsp; Quite frankly, that’s nonsense.</p>



<p>Here’s the truth: Just this month, America produced 12 million barrels of oil per day.&nbsp; That’s the highest &#8212; that’s higher than average under my predecessor.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; we’re on track to set a new record for production next year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Plus, I’ve added to that supply of oil by releasing a record 1 million barrels of oil per day from what’s called the Strategic Petro- &#8212; Petroleum Reserve.</p>



<p>In fact, I just led the world to coordinate the largest release of global oil reserves in history, including from other countries.&nbsp; In total, that’s 240 million barrels to boost global supply.<br><br>And Republicans falsely claim that I’m blocking production on federal lands.&nbsp; But again, that’s nonsense.</p>



<p>The industry has more approved permits for production on federal lands than they can possibly use.&nbsp; That’s a fact.</p>



<p>My administration also directed the sale of gasoline using homegrown biofuels &#8212; ethanol, E15 &#8212; this summer, which will boost gasoline supplies and lower the price at thousands of gas stations across America.</p>



<p>And I welcome the recent announcement from what’s known as the OPEC+, a group of nearly two dozen oil-producing nations, to increase global oil supply.</p>



<p>The bottom line is: We are setting records in terms of American energy production.&nbsp; We’re supplementing that supply with a release from our oil reserves.&nbsp; So the issue isn’t oil production alone; the problem is the refining of that oil into gas at the pump.</p>



<p>During the pandemic, some oil and gas companies shut down refining facilities.</p>



<p>Last week, I sent a letter to the CEOs of the largest oil-refining companies asking them to work with my administration to bring refineries back online to get more gas to the pump at lower prices.</p>



<p>The Secretary of Energy, Jennifer Granholm, and members of my team will be meeting with many of these refining companies tomorrow.&nbsp; And I hope they’ll come up to the table with some real ideas and practical steps in the near term.</p>



<p>And I’m prepared to act quickly and decisively on their recommendations if they make sense to address the immediate challenge in front of us and the American people.</p>



<p>Finally, when the cost of oil does come down, we need the price at the gas stations &#8212; that they &#8212; what they charge at the pump &#8212; to come down as well.</p>



<p>For example, in the last two weeks, the price of oil has fallen by more than $10.00 a barrel.&nbsp; Normally, this would reduce the cost at the pump about 25 cents a gallon.&nbsp; Yet, so far, gas stations have only reduced prices by a few cents a gallon.&nbsp; Some haven’t reduced prices at all.</p>



<p>I’ve heard plenty of explanations from companies and economists about why it normally takes time for these price reductions to reach the consumer.&nbsp; I might note that when the price of a barrel of oil goes up, it doesn&#8217;t make &#8212; ta- &#8212; take much time for the price at the pump to go up.</p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s be honest with one another.&nbsp; My message is simple.&nbsp; To the companies running gas stations and setting those prices at the pump: This is a time of war, global peril, Ukraine.&nbsp; These are not normal times.</p>



<p>Bring down the price you are charging at the pump to reflect the cost you are paying for the product.&nbsp; Do it now.&nbsp; Do it today.&nbsp; Your customers, the American people, they need relief now.</p>



<p>So, let me summarize:&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I’m calling for a federal gas tax holiday, state gas tax holiday <s>for</s> [or] the equivalent relief to consumers; oil companies to use their profits to increase refining capacity rather than buy back their own stock; gas stations to pass along the decree &#8212; excuse me, not the decree, but the decrease in oil prices to lower prices at the pump.</p>



<p>And together, these actions could help drop the price at the pump by up to $1.00 a gallon or more.&nbsp; It doesn’t reduce all of the pain, but it would be a big help.</p>



<p>I’m doing my part.&nbsp; I want the Congress, the states, and the industry to do their part as well.</p>



<p>And let’s remember how we got here: Putin invaded Ukraine.&nbsp; Putin invaded Ukraine with 100,000 forces.</p>



<p>Just look at the facts: Since the start of the war in Ukraine this year, gas prices have risen by almost $2.00 a gallon in the United States, and sometimes more, around the world.</p>



<p>But it wasn’t just Putin’s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; It was the refusal of the United States and the rest of the free world to let Putin get away with something we haven&#8217;t seen since World War Two.</p>



<p>I said at the time: Siding with Ukraine during the most serious aggression in Europe since World War Two &#8212; defending freedom, defending democracy &#8212; was not going to go without cost for the American people and the rest of the free world.&nbsp; We were going to have to pay a price as well &#8212; in the cost of military equipment, economic assistance, humanitarian relief.&nbsp; And sanctioned Russian banking industries.</p>



<p>Russia is also the largest oi- &#8212; one of the largest oil producers in the world.&nbsp; We cut off Russian oil into the United States, and our partners in Europe did the same, knowing that we would see higher gas prices.</p>



<p>We could have turned a blind eye to Putin’s murderous ways, and the price of gas wouldn’t have spiked the way it has.</p>



<p>I believe that would have been wrong.&nbsp; I believed it then &#8212; I believed then and I believe now: The free world had no choice.</p>



<p>America could not stand by and the West could not have stood by &#8212; although some suggested at the time &#8212; and just watch Putin’s tanks roll into Ukraine and seize a sovereign country.</p>



<p>If we did stand by, Putin wouldn’t have stopped.&nbsp; Putin would’ve kept going, and we’d face an even steeper price.</p>



<p>And it wasn’t just me.&nbsp; The American people understood.&nbsp; The American people rose to the moment.&nbsp; The American people did what they always have done: defend freedom around the world.&nbsp; They chose to stand with the people of Ukraine.</p>



<p>We had near unanimous support in the Congress &#8212; Democrats, Republicans, and independents &#8212; for supporting Ukraine, knowing full well the cost.</p>



<p>So, for all those Republicans in Congress criticizing me today for high gas prices in America, are you now saying we were wrong to support Ukraine?&nbsp; Are you saying we were wrong to stand up to Putin?&nbsp; Are you saying that we would rather have lower gas prices in America and Putin’s iron fist in Europe?&nbsp; I don’t believe that.</p>



<p>Look, I get the easy politics of the attack.&nbsp; I get that.&nbsp; But the simple truth is gas prices are up almost $2.00 a gallon because of Vladimir Putin’s ruthless attack on Ukraine, and we wouldn’t let him get away with it.&nbsp; And we’re doing everything we can to reduce this pain at the pump now.</p>



<p><br>And if those experiences has shown us anything, it’s that we need to grow and harness more energy here at home.</p>



<p>Let’s lower the price of electric vehicles so we never have to pay at the pump in the first place.<br><br>Major auto companies are preparing for 50 percent of future sales to be electric vehicles by 2030, 100 percent by 2035.&nbsp; We’re already building secure supply chains to build these electric vehicles here in America.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re investing almost $100 billion in public transit and rail, for all the studies show that it will take millions of cars off the road and significantly reduce pollution if there’s a serious transportation system available.</p>



<p>Let’s keep accelerating our deployment of homegrown resources &#8212; sources of energy like solar and wind and nuclear and hydrogen and carbon capture and storage &#8212; and keep developing battery technologies so we can store that power we need when the sun doesn’t shine or the wind doesn’t blow.</p>



<p>Folks, let’s make sure we’re never again forced to pay the price of a menacing dictator halfway around the world.</p>



<p>We can deal with the imme- &#8212; this immediate crisis of high gas prices and still seize the clean energy future.</p>



<p>We’re Americans.&nbsp; We can do both.&nbsp; We have the most qualified people in the world.</p>



<p><br>Let me close with this: Even as we lead the world in defending democracy and standing up to a brutal autocrat, there are actions we can take to help American families now.&nbsp; We have taken them.&nbsp; We are taking them.&nbsp; The federal gas tax holiday, state gas tax holiday.&nbsp; Bringing back refineries, putting them back online.</p>



<p>We just have to keep going.&nbsp; I promise you I’m doing everything possible &#8212; everything possible to bring the price of energy down, gas prices down.&nbsp; And I want to make sure we all work on this together.</p>



<p>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p><br>2:16 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:  Anjali Chaturvedi, Nominee for General Counsel, U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs Patrice H. Kunesh, Nominee for Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Kristina A. Kvien,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration: </p>



<ul><li>Anjali Chaturvedi, Nominee for General Counsel, U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Patrice H. Kunesh, Nominee for Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Kristina A. Kvien, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Armenia</li><li>Robert William Forden, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Cambodia</li><li>Lucy Tamlyn, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Republic of the Congo</li><li>Randy W. Berry, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Namibia</li><li>Pamela M. Tremont, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Zimbabwe</li><li>Manuel P. Micaller, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Tajikistan</li><li>Kimberly McClain, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Congressional and Intergovernmental Relations, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Rolfe Michael Schiffer, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Asia, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Moshe Marvit, Nominee for Member of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission</li><li>Robert E. Primus, Nominee for Member of the Surface Transportation Board</li><li>Thomas E. Harvey, Nominee for Member of the Veterans Affairs Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Anjali Chaturvedi, Nominee for General Counsel, U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Anjali Chaturvedi is a Deputy Assistant Attorney General in the Criminal Division of the U.S. Department of Justice.&nbsp;During her career, Chaturvedi has worked in all three branches of the government and in private practice.&nbsp;Prior to returning to government service, Chaturvedi was the Assistant General Counsel and Director of Investigations for Northrop Grumman Corporation, leading the company’s global investigations team.&nbsp;She earlier served as an Assistant General Counsel at British Petroleum and as a partner at the Washington, DC law firm of Nixon Peabody. Before entering private practice, Chaturvedi was a federal prosecutor. During her time at the Justice Department, she served both in the District of Columbia and the Northern District of California US Attorneys’ Offices, including as Deputy Chief of the Felony Trial Section and Chief of the Organized Crime Strike Force, and a detail as Counsel to Senator Dianne Feinstein on the Senate Judiciary Committee. She began her legal career clerking for the Honorable Gregory E. Mize of the District of Columbia Superior Court. Chaturvedi also taught trial advocacy and criminal procedure as an Adjunct Professor at Georgetown University and Hastings College of Law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Born in Cortland, New York, Chaturvedi is a first-generation American. She is a graduate of the Georgetown University Law School and Cornell University.&nbsp;She is also a certified yoga teacher and leadership coach.&nbsp;She lives in Chevy Chase, MD with her husband and son.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Patrice H. Kunesh, Nominee for Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Patrice H. Kunesh, of Standing Rock Lakota descent, has committed her career to public service, including several positions at the tribal, state, and federal level. Kunesh recently returned to the Native American Rights Fund, where she began her legal career. Since then, she has served as in-house Counsel to the Mashantucket Pequot Tribal Nation and on the faculty at the University of South Dakota School of Law. Kunesh also held appointments as the Deputy Under Secretary for Rural Development at the U.S. Department of Agriculture and as the Deputy Solicitor for Indian Affairs at the U.S. Department of the Interior. In addition, she established the Center for Indian Country Development, an economic policy research initiative, at the Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis.</p>



<p>Kunesh recently founded Peȟíŋ Haha Consulting, a social enterprise committed to fostering culturally-centered Native economic development, and she was appointed to the US Treasury Community Development Advisory Board (CDFI Fund) as the representative for Native communities. She holds a JD from the University of Colorado School of Law and an MPA from the Harvard Kennedy School of Government.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kristina A. Kvien, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Armenia</u></strong></p>



<p>Kristina A. Kvien, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, serves as Deputy Chief of Mission at U.S. Embassy Kyiv. She was previously Chargé d’Affaires ad interim from 2020-2022.&nbsp;Prior to that, Kvien served as Minister-Counselor for Economic Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in Paris, France and as Economic Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in Bangkok, Thailand.&nbsp;In both Paris and Bangkok, she served more than one year as Acting Deputy Chief of Mission.&nbsp;She also served as Economic Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in London.&nbsp;Earlier in her career, Kvien was detailed to the National Security Council in Washington, D.C. as Director for EU, Ukraine and Belarus affairs.&nbsp;Other overseas assignments include the U.S. Embassy in Moscow, Russia; the U.S. Mission to the EU in Brussels; and the U.S. Embassy in Manila, Republic of the Philippines.&nbsp;Domestic assignments include the Office of European and Regional Affairs, and the Office of Central European Affairs, both in the Bureau of Europe and Eurasian Affairs.&nbsp;Kvien, a native of California, holds a BA from Occidental College and an MS from the U.S. Army War College.&nbsp;She is a recipient of multiple State Department performance awards and speaks Russian and French.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Robert William Forden, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Cambodia</u></strong></p>



<p>Robert Forden is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor.&nbsp;He currently serves as a Senior Advisor in the East Asian and Pacific Affairs Bureau at the Department of State in Washington, D.C.&nbsp;Prior to that, he was the Deputy Chief of Mission and also Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim of the U.S. Embassy in the People’s Republic of China.&nbsp;Earlier, Forden was the Deputy Director of the American Institute in Taiwan and before that the Economic Counselor of the U.S. Embassy in Tel Aviv, Israel.&nbsp;He was also Deputy Economic Counselor of the U.S. Embassy in Beijing and, in Washington, the Deputy Director of the Office of Chinese and Mongolian Affairs in the State Department’s Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs.&nbsp;Among his other assignments, Forden was Chief of the Kaohsiung Branch of the American Institute in Taiwan and an Economic Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Hanoi, Vietnam.&nbsp;Forden earned his Bachelor’s degree from the University of California, Santa Cruz.&nbsp;He speaks Chinese (Mandarin) and Vietnamese.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lucy Tamlyn, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Republic of the Congo</u></strong></p>



<p>Lucy Tamlyn, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is currently the Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim at the U.S. Embassy in Khartoum, Sudan.&nbsp;Previously, she served as U.S. Ambassador to the Central African Republic, U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Benin, and as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassies in Portugal and in Chad.&nbsp;Earlier she had assignments as Economic Counselor at the U.S. Mission to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, as a Provincial Reconstruction Team Leader in Erbil, Iraq, and as Director of the Office of the Special Envoy for Sudan and South Sudan in the State Department’s Bureau of African Affairs. Among other postings during her four decades of diplomatic service, Tamlyn has worked as Alternate Permanent Representative, Deputy Director, Economic and Social Council Section at the U.S. Mission to the UN, New York and as Alternate Permanent Representative, U.S. Mission to the UN Agencies for Food and Agriculture in Rome, Italy. She earned a Bachelor’s degree from St. John’s College, Annapolis, Maryland and a Master’s degree from Columbia University School of International Affairs. Tamlyn is the recipient of numerous State Department awards, including the Secretary’s Award for Expeditionary Service. She speaks French and Portuguese.</p>



<p><strong><u>Randy W. Berry, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Namibia</u></strong></p>



<p>Randy Berry is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister.&nbsp;He currently serves as the U.S. Ambassador to Nepal. Prior to that, Berry was Deputy Assistant Secretary in the State Department’s Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor and, before that, the State Department’s first Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBTI Persons. Berry served as Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy, Kathmandu, and was twice a Principal Officer and Consul General &#8212; first at the U.S. Consulate General in Auckland, New Zealand and then at the U.S. Consulate General in&nbsp;Amsterdam, The Netherlands.&nbsp;His other assignments include service as Deputy Principal Officer, U.S. Consulate General, Cape Town, South Africa; Senior Desk Officer for South Africa, Bureau of African Affairs, Department of State; and as Political Section Chief, and then Regional Refugee Coordinator at the U.S. Embassy in Kampala, Uganda. Early in his career Berry was Vice Consul at the U.S. Embassy in Dhaka, Bangladesh, and then at the U.S. Embassy in Cairo, Egypt. Berry earned his B.A. from Bethany College, Lindsborg, Kansas.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Pamela M. Tremont, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Zimbabwe</u></strong></p>



<p>Pamela Tremont is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor. She currently is assigned as the Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Stockholm, Sweden and had the additional responsibility of serving as Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim for 18 months. Previously, Tremont was assigned first as Assistance Coordinator and then as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Kyiv, Ukraine.&nbsp;Prior to that, she served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Nicosia, Cyprus.&nbsp;Among her other roles, Tremont has been Deputy Director for NATO Policy in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs at the State Department, the Political/Economic Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in Lusaka, Zambia, and a Political Military Officer in the U.S. Embassy in London, United Kingdom. Tremont also served as Political Military Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Ankara, Turkey, as a Desk Officer for South Africa in the Bureau of African Affairs, and as a Watch Officer in the State Department’s Operations Center. Tremont earned B.A. and M.A. degrees from Baylor University and a Master’s degree from the Dwight D. Eisenhower School at the National Defense University.&nbsp;She speaks French and Turkish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Manuel P. Micaller, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Tajikistan</u></strong></p>



<p>Manuel P. Micaller, Jr. is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor.&nbsp;He currently serves as the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Kathmandu, Nepal.&nbsp;Prior to that, Micaller was Deputy Chief of Mission (and Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim) at the U.S. Embassy in Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia.&nbsp;Micaller also served as the Deputy Director of the Office of India Affairs in the State Department’s Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs in Washington, D.C and held assignments as the Political – Economic Section Chief at the U.S. Embassy in Dushanbe, Tajikistan and as an Economic Officer in the South and Central Asian Affairs Bureau’s Office of Regional Affairs.&nbsp;Earlier, Micaller was an Economic Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Rabat, Morocco, worked in the State Department Executive Secretariat and Operations Center, and was posted to positions in Russia and Tajikistan.&nbsp;Micaller earned his Bachelor’s degree from The Johns Hopkins University and his Master’s in Business Administration from George Washington University.&nbsp;He also received a Master’s degree from the National Defense University.&nbsp;His foreign languages include Russian and Tajik.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kimberly McClain, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Congressional and Intergovernmental Relations, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Kimberly McClain currently serves in the Biden-Harris Administration as the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Congressional and Legislative Affairs at the Department of Veterans Affairs. In this position she advises the Secretary, Deputy Secretary, Under Secretaries and Assistant Secretaries on matters involving congressional and legislative affairs. Throughout her 30-year career, McClain has served in a variety of legislative affairs, international affairs, and policy positions in the public and private sectors. Prior to being appointed to the Biden-Harris Administration, McClain served as Director for Congressional Strategy for the Department of the Air Force, where she led teams charged with planning, execution, and management of the Department’s congressional engagement strategy. Her public service career includes several legislative roles in the Air Force, including Legislative Advisor to the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, and also several roles in the Department of Defense, including serving as Director of the Defense Senior Leader Program in the Office of the Undersecretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness.</p>



<p>In the private sector, McClain served as Senior Executive Communications Advisor to the Chief Executive Officer for Accenture Federal Services and its clients. She also served for two years as a Corporate Training and Development Executive for Sonic Restaurant Industries and as Risk Operations Manager for Capital One Financial Services. A retired Air Force Reserve Officer, McClain earned her Bachelor of Arts in Psychology and a minor in Sociology from the University of Texas. McClain also earned a Master of Science in Human Relations and International Business with Latin America concentration from Amberton University and a Ph.D. in International Business with a concentration in Africa and Brazil from Northcentral University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rolfe Michael Schiffer, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Asia, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Rolfe Michael Schiffer is Senior Advisor and Counselor on the Democratic Staff of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee. He formerly served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for East Asia in the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Asian and Pacific Security Affairs. Before joining the Department of Defense, he was a Program Officer at the Stanley Foundation, responsible for the Foundation`s Asia programs as well as a range of other U.S. national and global security issues and also was a Council on Foreign Relations Hitachi International Affairs Fellow in Japan. Prior to that, worked on the staff of U.S. Senator Dianne Feinstein (D-CA), including as her Senior National Security Adviser and Legislative Director. Prior to that, he was Director of International Security Programs at New York University`s Center for War, Peace, and the News Media, and Co-Manager of the Poipu Bed and Breakfast Inn in Kauai. Schiffer received his undergraduate degree from Georgetown University and graduate degrees from the London School of Economics and New York University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Moshe Z. Marvit, Nominee for Member of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Moshe Z. Marvit has worked for the last decade with the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission (FMSHRC), where he currently serves as a Supervisory Attorney Advisor. In this capacity, he manages the Pittsburgh field office, writes decisions for federal Administrative Law Judges, and mediates cases between mine operators and the Mine Safety and Health Administration. He is also a fellow at The Century Foundation, where he researches and writes on workers’ rights issues. His writings have been published widely in a variety of law reviews. He has been awarded the Labor and Employment Relations Association Ken May Media Award and the Sidney Hillman Award for his writings in the field of workers’ rights. Prior to coming to FMSHRC, he worked in private practice, representing the United Steelworkers, and employees in pension and discrimination matters.</p>



<p>Marvit has served as a member of the faculty of the University of Pittsburgh School of Law, the Duquesne University School of Law, the Pennsylvania State Unemployment Compensation Advisory Council, and the Steel Valley Authority. He received his JD from Chicago-Kent College of Law, where he also earned a Certificate in Labor and Employment Law. Marvit served on the Employee Rights and Employment Policy Journal, and received a Peggy Browning Fellowship to work at the National Labor Relations Board. He has an M.A. from the University of Chicago, an M.A. from Carnegie Mellon University and a B.A. from the Pennsylvania State University. He lives in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania with his wife and son.</p>



<p><strong><u>Robert E. Primus, Nominee for Member of the Surface Transportation Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Robert E. Primus is a Member of the Surface Transportation Board. Primus previously served in the office of Congressman Tony Cárdenas (D-CA), first as his Senior Advisor and then as Chief of Staff. Prior to this, Primus served as Senior Advisor to Congressman Tim Ryan (D-OH) and Chief of Staff to Representative Nanette Diaz Barragán (D-CA). Primus formerly served in the Office of Representative Michael Capuano (D-MA), first as Legislative Director and then as Chief of Staff. In addition to his Chief of Staff duties, Primus advised Representative Capuano on national security, health care, transportation and Coast Guard-related matters. Primus spent four years at Van Scoyoc Associates, Inc. where he represented and advised firm clients on budgetary, appropriations, transportation, and national security matters. Primus also served on the staffs of Representative Mel Reynolds (D-IL), Representative Carrie Meek of (D-FL), and Senator Frank Lautenberg (D-NJ).</p>



<p>Primus is a native of Madison, New Jersey.&nbsp;He graduated with honors from Hampton University in 1991, receiving a Bachelor of Science degree in Marketing.&nbsp;Additionally, Primus received a certificate from Harvard University’s John F. Kennedy School of Government in 2007 for his participation in the school’s Executive Education Program.&nbsp;He is married and has three children.</p>



<p><strong><u>Thomas E. Harvey, Nominee for Member of the Veterans Affairs Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Tom Harvey, an Army veteran who served two and a half years in the Infantry in Vietnam, is the recipient of the Silver Star, Purple Heart and a dozen other decorations for valor and service. He arrived in Washington, DC in 1977 as a White House Fellow and spent much of his career in positions caring for his fellow veterans. He served as Chief Counsel and Staff Director of the U.S. Senate Veterans Affairs Committee on two different occasions, Deputy Administrator of the Veterans Administration, and Assistant Secretary of the Department of Veterans Affairs for Congressional Relations. He also held a number of senior positions within the Department of Defense and the United States Information Agency. Harvey is married with two grown children. He resides in Palm Beach, Florida.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the June National Climate Task Force&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/readout-of-the-june-national-climate-task-force-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 18:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Task Force Discussed Tackling Extreme Heat, Bolstering Resilience, and Lowering Energy Costs Yesterday, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the 12th meeting of the National Climate Task Force to discuss President Biden’s commitment to protecting the most vulnerable Americans from extreme heat, strengthening the nation’s resilience to extreme weather events, and lowering energy costs for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Task Force Discussed Tackling Extreme Heat, Bolstering Resilience, and Lowering Energy Costs</em></p>



<p>Yesterday, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the 12<sup>th</sup> meeting of the National Climate Task Force to discuss President Biden’s commitment to protecting the most vulnerable Americans from extreme heat, strengthening the nation’s resilience to extreme weather events, and lowering energy costs for families.</p>



<p>The Task Force received a science briefing on this summer’s forecasted extreme heat, drought and wildfires in the West and flood risk across the East. The Task Force discussed how these climate and weather extremes disproportionately impact historically disadvantaged communities across America, and how the Task Force is taking action to fight back by weatherizing homes; updating building codes to boost resilience; setting flood-risk reduction standards to protect homeowners and businesses; shielding workers from extreme heat exposure on the job; increasing federal firefighters pay across the country to fight wildfires; and accelerating construction of grid-strengthening clean energy projects that will cut consumer costs.</p>



<p>In addition, the Task Force discussed efforts to leverage domestic climate action to spur international efforts, including recent successes advanced through the President’s action-focused <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-galvanize-global-action-to-strengthen-energy-security-and-tackle-the-climate-crisis-through-the-major-economies-forum-on-energy-and-climate/">call to world leaders</a> at last week’s Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate.</p>



<p>As outlined by President Biden’s January 27&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/">Executive Order on Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad</a>, the Task Force is chaired by the National Climate Advisor and includes Cabinet-level leaders from more than 25 federal agencies to mobilize the Biden-Harris Administration’s implementation of a whole-of-government approach.</p>



<p>Task Force membership is comprised of the following government officials:</p>



<ul><li>National Climate Advisor (Chair)</li><li>Secretary of the Treasury</li><li>Secretary of Defense</li><li>Attorney General</li><li>Secretary of the Interior</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture</li><li>Secretary of Commerce</li><li>Secretary of Education</li><li>Secretary of Labor</li><li>Secretary of Health and Human Services</li><li>Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Secretary of Transportation</li><li>Secretary of Energy</li><li>Secretary of Homeland Security</li><li>Administrator of General Services</li><li>CEO of AmeriCorps</li><li>Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality</li><li>Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration</li><li>Administrator of the Small Business Administration</li><li>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</li><li>Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs</li><li>Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism</li><li>Assistant to the President for Economic Policy</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on the Earthquake in&#160;Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-the-earthquake-in-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 16:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is deeply saddened to see the devastating earthquake that took the lives of at least 1,000 people in Afghanistan. President Biden is monitoring developments and has directed USAID and other federal government partners to assess U.S. response options to help those most affected. The United States is proud to be the single largest&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States is deeply saddened to see the devastating earthquake that took the lives of at least 1,000 people in Afghanistan. President Biden is monitoring developments and has directed USAID and other federal government partners to assess U.S. response options to help those most affected. The United States is proud to be the single largest donor of humanitarian aid to Afghanistan, and our humanitarian partners are already delivering medical care and shelter supplies on the ground. We are committed to continuing our support for the needs of the Afghan people as we stand with them during and in the aftermath of this terrible tragedy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Tenth Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/president-biden-announces-tenth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 15:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56056</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate trucking shipment of approximately 16 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Gerber® Good Start® Gentle infant formula this weekend Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing trucking, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Gerber infant formula from Mexico&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate trucking shipment of approximately 16 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Gerber® Good Start® Gentle infant formula this weekend</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing trucking, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Gerber infant formula from Mexico to Fort Worth, Texas starting on June 24. This delivery will include approximately 1 million pounds of Gerber Good Start Gentle infant formula, the equivalent of approximately 16 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available through retail channels.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Nestlé can export additional infant formula into the U.S. &nbsp; Nestlé plans to export approximately 42 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. By June 26, Operation Fly Formula flights will have completed 32 flights and imported almost 19 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of infant formula.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png" alt="" class="wp-image-56061" width="298" height="298" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png 596w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png?resize=1200,1200 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 298px) 100vw, 298px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Ninth Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/president-biden-announces-ninth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 15:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56052</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport&#160;Bubs Australia&#160;infant formula from Melbourne, Australia to Los Angeles, California on June 26 and to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania on July 5. These two deliveries will include in total approximately&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing flights, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport&nbsp;Bubs Australia&nbsp;infant formula from Melbourne, Australia to Los Angeles, California on June 26 and to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania on July 5. These two deliveries will include in total approximately 320,000 pounds of Bubs Organic Infant Formula S1, Bubs Organic Follow On Formula S2, Bubs Supreme Infant Formula Supreme Follow On Formula, Bubs Goat Milk Infant Formula S1, Bubs Goat Milk Follow On Formula S2, the equivalent of approximately 5.5 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available through Target, Albertsons, Kroger, Walmart and other retailers.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Bubs Australia can export additional infant formula into the U.S.&nbsp;Bubs Australia will import both standard and specialty infant formulas to the U.S. including&nbsp;Bubs Organic Grass Fed, Bubs Supreme A2 Beta-Casein Protein and Bubs Easy-digest Goat Milk. Bubs plans to export approximately 27.5 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. By June 26, Operation Fly Formula will have completed 32 flights and imported almost 19 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of infant formula.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1432" height="449" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF9.jpg?w=640" alt="" class="wp-image-56055" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF9.jpg 1432w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF9.jpg?resize=615,193 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF9.jpg?resize=768,241 768w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF9.jpg?resize=1270,398 1270w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF9.jpg?resize=1180,370 1180w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF9.jpg?resize=1038,325 1038w" sizes="(max-width: 1432px) 100vw, 1432px" /></figure>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Eighth Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/president-biden-announces-eighth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 15:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56046</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 1.65 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Nestlé NAN Supremepro 2 infant formula this weekend Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport&#160;Nestlé&#160;infant formula from Germany to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"> <em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 1.65 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Nestlé NAN Supremepro 2 infant formula this weekend</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport&nbsp;Nestlé&nbsp;infant formula from Germany to Fort Worth, Texas on June 26. This delivery will include over 110,000 pounds of Nestlé SupremePro 2 formula, the equivalent of approximately 1.65 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available through Gerber.com and other online retailers.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Nestlé can export additional infant formula into the U.S.&nbsp;Nestlé will import both standard and specialty infant formulas including&nbsp;Nestlé&nbsp;NAN SupremePro 1, Nestlé NAN SupremePro 2, Nestlé Health Science Alfamino/Alfamino, Jr., Gerber® Good Start® Gentle and Gerber® Good Start® Extensive HA®. Nestlé plans to bring approximately 42 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. By June 26, Operation Fly Formula will have completed 32 flights and imported almost 19 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of infant formula.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/off8.png" alt="" class="wp-image-56050" width="318" height="318" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/off8.png 414w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/off8.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/off8.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/off8.png?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/off8.png?resize=1200,1200 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 318px) 100vw, 318px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on the 50th Anniversary of the Federal Pell Grant&#160;Program</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/22/a-proclamation-on-the-50th-anniversary-of-the-federal-pell-grant-program/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56047</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160; For 50 years, the Federal Pell Grant program has been the cornerstone of our Nation&#8217;s efforts to create a financial pathway for tens of millions of low- and middle-income students to attend college.&#160; Established by the Congress in 1972 and named after former United States Senator from Rhode Island Claiborne Pell, a champion&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; For 50 years, the Federal Pell Grant program has been the cornerstone of our Nation&#8217;s efforts to create a financial pathway for tens of millions of low- and middle-income students to attend college.&nbsp; Established by the Congress in 1972 and named after former United States Senator from Rhode Island Claiborne Pell, a champion of higher education with whom I served in the United States Senate, Pell Grants are awarded to students based exclusively on their financial need. &nbsp;Since the program&#8217;s creation, Pell Grants have helped more than 80&nbsp;million students attend college and pursue their dreams.<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp; Today, Pell Grants form the foundation of many students&#8217; financial assistance packages &#8212; especially for students of color.&nbsp; As the single largest source of grants for postsecondary education, Pell Grants were awarded to more than one-third of undergraduate students last academic year.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration is committed to ensuring that higher education is equitable, accessible, and affordable for every student across the country.&nbsp; That is why, earlier this year, I signed a bill that includes the largest Pell Grant increase in over a decade. &nbsp;My Fiscal Year 2023 Budget calls for another historic increase in Pell Grants for academic year 2023-2024 and would double the maximum Pell Grants provided by 2029.&nbsp; Together, these investments will make it possible for more students from all backgrounds to pursue a postsecondary education that prepares them for quality employment and helps our Nation compete in the 21st century.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration has also significantly expanded the Second Chance Pell Initiative, which enables students who are incarcerated to receive this critical grant aid so they can participate in postsecondary education programs, supporting their success and helping them make greater contributions to society upon their release. &nbsp;First established in 2015 by the Obama-Biden Administration, the Initiative has expanded under my Administration to 73 additional schools, providing access to education to thousands of additional students, reducing recidivism rates, and improving public safety.&nbsp; This will help the Department of Education prepare for the full expansion of Pell Grant eligibility to incarcerated students in July 2023.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this 50th anniversary, our Nation pays tribute to the importance of Federal Pell Grants and the opportunities they afford millions of students across our Nation. &nbsp;Today, let us recommit to expanding access to quality education so that all of our citizens are empowered to achieve their professional goals and contribute to the success and prosperity of America.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 23, 2022, as the 50th Anniversary of the Federal Pell Grant Program.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this milestone and to recognize the significant contribution Pell Grants have made to strengthen our Nation&#8217;s prosperity by making a college education more available to all of our children.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-second day of June, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Calls for a Three-Month Federal Gas Tax&#160;Holiday</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/fact-sheet-president-biden-calls-for-a-three-month-federal-gas-tax-holiday/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56040</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The price of gas is up dramatically around the world, and by almost $2 per gallon in America, since Putin began amassing troops on the border of Ukraine. President Biden understands that high gas prices pose a significant challenge for working families. That’s why he has taken action in recent months to boost the supply&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The price of gas is up dramatically around the world, and by almost $2 per gallon in America, since Putin began amassing troops on the border of Ukraine. President Biden understands that high gas prices pose a significant challenge for working families. That’s why he has taken action in recent months to boost the supply of oil and gas, including an historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, and encouraging oil companies and refiners to boost capacity and output to get more supply on the market.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, he is calling on Congress and states to take additional legislative action to provide direct relief to American consumers who have been hit with Putin’s Price Hike. Specifically, he is calling on Congress to suspend the federal gas tax for three months, through September, without taking any money away from the Highway Trust Fund. And he is calling on states to take similar action to provide some direct relief, whether suspending their own gas taxes or helping consumers in other ways.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><em>Federal Gas Tax Holiday</em></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>Right now, the federal government charges an 18 cent tax per gallon of gasoline and a 24 cent tax per gallon of diesel. Those taxes fund critical highways and public transportation, through the Highway Trust Fund. But in this unique moment, with gas prices near $5 a gallon on average across the country, President Biden is calling on Congress to suspend the gas tax for three months – until the end of September – to give Americans a little extra breathing room as they deal with the effects of Putin’s war in Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is also calling on Congress to make sure that a gas tax holiday has no negative effect on the Highway Trust Fund. With our deficit already down by a historic $1.6 trillion this year, the President believes that we can afford to suspend the gas tax to help consumers while using other revenues to make the Highway Trust Fund whole for the roughly $10 billion cost. This is consistent with legislation proposed in the Senate and the House to advance a responsible gas tax holiday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden understands that a gas tax holiday alone will not, on its own, relieve the run up in costs that we’ve seen. But the President believes that at this unique moment when the war in Ukraine is imposing costs on American families, Congress should do what it can to provide working families breathing room.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><em>State and Local Action</em></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to federal gas tax relief, the President is calling on state and local governments to provide additional consumer relief. Already, some states and local governments have acted: for example, in Connecticut and New York, governors temporarily suspended their gas taxes, and in Illinois and Colorado, governors delayed planned tax and fee increases. And, around the country, in states like Michigan and Minnesota, states and local leaders are considering a number of forms of consumer relief – from temporary suspensions and pauses on state sales tax on gas to consumer rebates and relief payments. The President believes more states and local governments should do so.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><em>Ongoing Actions to Blunt the Impact of the Putin Price Hike</em></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>Today’s announcements follow a series of actions the President has taken to lower gas prices for American families.</p>



<ul><li>The President announced the release of a record 1 million barrels per day from our Strategic Petroleum Reserve, which just last week a leading oil market analyst confirmed has been critical to keeping prices from rising even more.</li><li>He rallied international partners to join us, releasing a combined 240 million barrels of oil on the market.</li><li>He expanded access to biofuels like E15—gasoline that uses a 15 percent ethanol blend—to increase supply and lower prices at thousands of gas stations across the country.</li><li>He and his Administration are engaging with oil and refining companies to ask them to work with the Administration to bring forward concrete solutions that increase refinery capacity and output. Secretary Granholm is meeting with these CEOs this week.</li></ul>



<p><br>Already, the United States produced more oil under the first year of this Administration than it did under the first two years of the prior Administration, and is on track to set new records next year. At the same time, the President understands that our efforts to increase energy production in the near-term must be coupled with medium- and long-term efforts to transition our economy away from fossil fuels produced by autocrats and to clean energy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
