<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 23:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President Biden Announces Historic Vaccine Donation: Half a Billion Pfizer Vaccines to the World’s Lowest-Income Nations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/10/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-historic-vaccine-donation-half-a-billion-pfizer-vaccines-to-the-worlds-lowest-income-nations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[500 million life-saving vaccines to be delivered by June of next year, including 200 million to be delivered by the end of 2021 Donation will serve as the foundation for a coordinated effort by the world’s democracies to vaccinate people around the world   Today, President Biden will announce that the United States will purchase&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>500 million life-saving vaccines to be delivered by June of next year, including 200 million to be delivered by the end of 2021<br><br>Donation will serve as the foundation for a coordinated effort by the world’s democracies to vaccinate people around the world  </em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Today, President Biden will announce that the United States will purchase and donate half a billion Pfizer vaccines to 92 low- and lower middle-income countries and the African Union, an historic action that will help supercharge the global fight against the pandemic. This is the largest-ever purchase and donation of vaccines by a single country and a commitment by the American people to help protect people around the world from COVID-19. President Biden will also call on the world’s democracies to do their parts in contributing to the global supply of safe and effective vaccines. The goal of today’s donation is to save lives and end the pandemic and will provide the foundation for additional actions to be announced in the coming days.</p>



<p>Thanks to the success of our vaccination program, the United States is beating COVID-19 here at home. 64% of adult Americans have received at least one shot in just four and a half months, daily death rates are lower than at any point in the pandemic, and our economy is rebounding. Now, the United States is using the power of our democracy, the ingenuity of American scientists, and the strength of American manufacturing to beat the pandemic globally by helping to vaccinate the world.</p>



<p>Today’s historic announcement comes on the heels of President Biden’s donation of at least 80 million vaccines from the United States’ supply by the end of June. Additionally, the United States has contributed two billion dollars to COVAX, more than any other nation—and is supporting local production capacity abroad for safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines, including through the Quad initiative.</p>



<p>President Biden has been clear that borders cannot keep this pandemic at bay and has vowed that our nation will be the arsenal of vaccines. The historic step the President will announce today therefore protects the health of the American people and the people throughout the world who will benefit from these life-saving vaccines.</p>



<p>Specifically, the actions the President will announce today will:</p>



<p><strong><u>PROVIDE A HALF BILLION PFIZER VACCINES TO LOW-INCOME NATIONS AROUND THE WORLD:</u></strong> Today, President Biden will announce that the U.S. government will purchase half a billion doses of Pfizer–BioNTech COVID-19 vaccines and donate to 92 low- and lower middle-income countries and economies as defined by <a href="https://www.gavi.org/news/media-room/92-low-middle-income-economies-eligible-access-covid-19-vaccines-gavi-covax-amc">Gavi’s COVAX Advance Market Commitment (AMC)</a> and the African Union. The vaccines will start shipping in August 2021.&nbsp; 200 million doses will be delivered by the end of this year and the remaining 300 million will be delivered in the first half of 2022. The U.S. will allocate these doses to low and lower-middle income nations around the world, working through COVAX to deliver them.</p>



<p><strong><u>GIVE LOWER INCOME NATIONS MORE ACCESS TO HIGHLY EFFECTIVE mRNA VACCINES:</u></strong> Today’s announcement will provide mRNA vaccines that have proven to be highly effective against COVID-19, including against all known variants. Tens of millions of Americans have benefited from these safe and effective vaccines and this historic donation will bring the life-saving benefits these vaccines provide to some of the most vulnerable populations around the world.</p>



<p><strong><u>HARNESS THE POWER OF AMERICAN MANUFACTURING TO HELP SAVE LIVES AROUND THE WORLD.</u></strong> Pfizer plans to produce these half a billion doses in the U.S. at their facilities in Kalamazoo, Michigan, which employs more than 3,000 American workers; McPherson, Kansas, which employs almost 2,000 workers; Chesterfield, Missouri, and Andover, Massachusetts, which employ 700 and 1,800 workers. The American workers who produced vaccines to save American lives will now produce those same vaccines to save the lives of hundreds of millions of people around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden to U.S. Air Force Personnel and Families Stationed at Royal Air Force Mildenhall</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-to-u-s-air-force-personnel-and-families-stationed-at-royal-air-force-mildenhall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 23:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Royal Air Force MildenhallMildenhall, United Kingdom 8:45 P.M. BST THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, Mildenhall! Colonel, thank you for that introduction and your service leading this team in such a difficult time.  Because we know that it’s the whole family who serves; I also want to Melissa.   I know &#8212; I know your next assignment at U.S.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Royal Air Force Mildenhall<br>Mildenhall, United Kingdom</p>



<p><br>8:45 P.M. BST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, Mildenhall!<br><br>Colonel, thank you for that introduction and your service leading this team in such a difficult time.  Because we know that it’s the whole family who serves; I also want to Melissa.   I know &#8212; I know your next assignment at U.S. Transportation Command starts soon.  So congratulations, and thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>And, Sydney, you&#8217;re 14 years old.  When I was 14 &#8212; please, at ease.  I keep forgetting I&#8217;m President.  (Laughter.)  When I was 14 years old, I would have been &#8212; I mean this sincerely &#8212; scared to death to stand up in front of a microphone, in a large crowd or small crowd.  See, when I was a child, I used to stutter badly &#8212; for real.  I had great difficulty speaking in front of other people.  And &#8212; so I expect that when you&#8217;re President, you’ll remember me.  (Laughter.)  You&#8217;ll remember me.   You’re, really, quite a polished young woman.  Thank you.<br><br>And, you know, it&#8217;s got to be hard to have your dad deployed to Afghanistan.  And I also know how proud you are of him and your mom, Chief Master Sergeant, for being part of the leadership team here.<br><br>Our son Beau served as a U.S. attorney for a while in &#8212; in Kosovo for a while.  Matter of fact, they erected a war monument to him.  And &#8212; and then he went on and he joined the National Guard.  Gave up his job as attorney general of the State of Delaware so he can go with his unit to Iraq for a year.  And when he got promoted to Major, I said, “Beau, you&#8217;re now a field-grade officer.”  I was in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan about 28 times.  And I said, “You&#8217;re now a field-grade officer.”  He said, “Dad, I have no illusions.  I know who runs the military: chief master sergeants.”  (Laughs.)  (Applause.)  So, I just want you to know we know.  Okay? <br><br>Thank you for your incredible dedication and service.  And, you know, I want to thank you all &#8212; all of you &#8212; all your families &#8212; for the sacrifices they&#8217;ve made.  And congratulations to having just a wonderful child.<br><br>There’s an awful lot of history at this base, a proud history for the British people &#8212; the bravery and heroism of the Royal Air Force pilots fighting to defend their nation.<br><br>I’m sure everyone here knows the history, but just six hours after Britain and France declared war on Germany in 1939, three Wellington bombers took off from Mildenhall and bombed Nazi battleships. <br><br>And over the course of World War Two, out of this base, RAF bombers dropped nearly 28,000 tons of bombs on Nazi Germany, flying more than 8,000 sorties.  This base has been a significant source of British air power &#8212; a proud, proud history of a proud nation. <br><br>But I also know there’s also an awful lot of American Air Force pride in this room tonight.  World War Two was when the U.S. Army Air Force formed the 100th Bombardment Group. <br><br>And, by the way, my &#8212; just so you know &#8212; although my uncle, who was killed in World War Two in New Guinea was Army &#8212; he was the Army Air Corps.  He got shot down in a reconnaissance flight.  And he would &#8212; he&#8217;s looking down and thinking, “All these years, my God, what this Air Force has become.”  It&#8217;s incredible. <br><br>The 100th also ran more than 8,000 sorties into hostile territory and supported operations from D-Day to the Battle of the Bulge, where another uncle of mine served.<br><br>And when they first arrived in the UK in ’43, the unit took such heavy losses, it earned the moniker that has been passed down to this day: “The Bloody Hundredth.”  The Bloody Hundredth.  <br><br>So let me hear it for the 100th Air Wing &#8212; Air Refueling Wing, AKA &#8212; known as the “The Bloody Hundredth.”  (Applause.)<br><br>And what about the 352nd Special Operations Wing?  (Applause.) <br><br>There&#8217;s Team &#8212; Team Reconnaissance.  Members of the Air Mobility Command.  (Applause.)<br><br>Do we have any folks from the 48th Fighter Wing, over from RAF &#8212; (Applause.)  By the way &#8212; I think maybe.<br><br>The 501st Combat Support Wing from RAF Alconbury.  (Applause.)<br><br>And this may be a historic first for an Air Force base, but I hear there just might be a few members of the United States Army here tonight with us.  (Applause.)  Come on, man.<br><br>To all of you airmen and soldiers, I want to just say thank you.  We owe you.  We’re so damn proud of you.  So proud.  And I only wish my Major was here to thank you as well.  Thank you &#8212; everything you do, for everything you are. <br><br>There’s nothing that Jill and I enjoy more than spending time with our troops and their families, wherever we go in the world.<br><br>I had the great honor of being in and out of Afghanistan and Iraq well over 27, 28 times.  I think Jill is the only Second Lady in American history who has gone into a warzone &#8212; into Baghdad with me as well. <br><br>You&#8217;re the best &#8212; you’re the best of our country.  That&#8217;s not hyperbole.  You&#8217;re the ones who sign up and run toward danger when duty calls.  Less than 1 percent of Americans make the choice that you make &#8212; that you made.  But the rest of us &#8212; the other 99 percent of us &#8212; we owe you.  We owe you big.<br><br>I’ve long said that, as a nation, we have many obligations,<br>but we only have one truly sacred obligation &#8212; only one &#8212; and that’s to properly prepare and equip the women and men we send into harm’s way, and to care for you and your families, both while you’re deployed and when you come home.<br><br>And now that I have the incredible honor of serving as your Commander-in-Chief, I believe that even more strongly.  You know &#8212; and I want to give an extra special thank you to all the families. <br><br>As you heard from Jill, we Bidens are a proud military family, and we know there&#8217;s not just the person who wears the uniform who serves; the whole family has to step up, the whole family makes sacrifices.  There&#8217;s a famous Irish poet who said, “They also serve who only stand and wait.”<br><br>I watched all those months Beau was in Kosovo.  And then I watched all those &#8212; that year he was in &#8212; in Iraq.  She would stand at that sink, leaving for school, drinking her coffee, and I could see her lips moving, saying that prayer, hoping that car never drove up in front of the house, hoping you never got that phone call. <br><br>And that&#8217;s even more true this past year during the lockdowns and safety precautions to curb the spread of COVID-19.  Everyone in this room knows that our military families are essential &#8212; essential to our strength.<br><br>It’s the key reason Jill relaunched Joining Forces: to make sure we’re doing everything we can to support our military spouses and children, and their mothers and fathers as well, just like they support all of you.<br><br>You know, you not only did an amazing job keeping COVID-19 under control on the base; you took care of each other and your mental health throughout the initiatives like your Spouse-to-Spouse Connection and your Wellness Advocacy Team.  (Cheers.)  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  As you all know, this is a team sport. <br><br>And my mother would kill me if she were here.  She&#8217;d say, “Joey, you shouldn’t have…&#8221; &#8212; I should’ve turned around and apologized for by back to you.  I apologize.  (Laughter.)  I haven’t figured out how to turn in 360 yet.  (Laughter.)<br><br>But, folks, thousands of hours spent volunteering to make sure everyone got through this.  It was so important.<br><br>I know that these last 15 months added a lot of new pressure, but all of you rose to the task together as one team &#8212; Team Mildenhall.  And you never let up on your mission.<br><br>And I’m so proud to be here with all of you to kick off my first overseas trip as President.  I&#8217;ve been in and out of here many, many times.  I’ve visited well over 100 countries as President or as Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee &#8212; or I meant as Vice President or Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee.  This is my first overseas trip as President of the United States. <br><br>I&#8217;m heading to the G7, then to the NATO Ministerial, and then to meet with Mr. Putin to let him know what I want him to know.  (Laughter and applause.)<br><br>And at every point along the way, we’re going to make it clear that the United States is back and democracies of the world are standing together to tackle the toughest challenges and the issues that matter most to our future; that we’re committed to leading with strength, defending our values, and delivering for our people.<br><br>America is better positioned to advance our national security and our economic prosperity when we bring together like-minded nations to stand with us.  These nations that have shed blood alongside of us in defense of our shared values.  Our unrivaled network of alliances and partnerships that are the key to American advantage in the world and have been.  They&#8217;ve made the world safer for all of us, and they are how we are going to meet the challenges of today, which are changing rapidly.  We&#8217;re going to meet it, though, from a position of strength. <br><br>Our alliances weren&#8217;t built by coercion or maintained by threats.  They&#8217;re grounded on democratic ideals and a shared vision of the future and where every voice matters &#8212; (applause) &#8212; where the rights &#8212; where the rights of all people are protected. <br><br>It’s the same reason so many of you signed up to serve, to proudly defend and honor the democratic values that are the wellspring of our national strength. <br><br>If our British friends will excuse me quoting the Declaration of Independence &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; America is unique in all the world in that we are not formed based on geography, or ethnicity, or religion, but on an idea &#8212; an idea.  The only nation in the world founded on the notion of an idea. <br><br>“We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men and women are created equal, endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights,” including “life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.”  We mean it.  No nation can defeat us as long as we stick to our values. <br><br>It&#8217;s our American creed.  It’s what makes us who we are.  And it’s what draws friends and partners to our side.  And for hundreds of years, American patriots have fought, and sometimes died, defending those values.<br><br>Folks, look, I&#8217;m often quoted by the press as saying, “America leads not by the example of its power, but by the power of our example.”  All of you &#8212; our service members stationed around the world &#8212; you are the solid steel spine of America around which alliances are built and strengthened year after year. <br><br>These partnerships have hardened and have been hardened in the fire of war, and generations of Americans and service members who fought them, like the original Bloody Hundredth and those <s>RFA</s> [RAF] pilots, and their shared mission in World War Two &#8212; flying, fighting, winning.  It was done together. <br><br>These bonds of history and shared fi- &#8212; sacrifice run deep and are strong, based on values.  And they endure. <br><br>The connections and camaraderie between our troops, this community of American citizens stationed in the UK &#8212; U.S. visiting forces and families, 20,000 strong &#8212; are not only warriors, you’re diplomats and you’re bridge-builders.  You are the essential part of what makes up this Special Relationship between Great Britain and the United States. <br><br>Over the next few days, as I said, I&#8217;ll be participating in meetings with many of our closest partners at the G7 in Cornwall, and then on to Brussels and NATO Summit of the EU &#8212; and the EU Summit. <br><br>This diplomacy is essential, because no single nation acting alone can meet all the challenges we face today because the world is changing.  To quote another Irish poet, he said, “The world&#8217;s changed, changed utterly.  A terrible beauty has been born.” <br><br>We&#8217;re in a different place than we were 10 years ago &#8212; a better position but a different place.  We have to build the shared future we seek: a future where nations are free from coercion or dominance by more powerful states; where the global commons &#8212; the seas, the air, the space &#8212; and space &#8212; remain open and accessible for the benefit of all. <br><br>To tackle this century&#8217;s most pressing challenges, we have to do it together.  We have to end COVID-19, not just at home &#8212; which we&#8217;re doing &#8212; but everywhere.  There&#8217;s no wall high enough to keep us safe from this pandemic or the next biological threat we face &#8212; and there will be others.<br><br>It requires coordinated, multilateral action.  We must all commit to an ambitious climate action if we&#8217;re going to prevent the worst impacts of climate change, limiting global warning [sic] &#8212; warming to no more than 1.5 degrees Celsius, and lead the global &#8212; the global transition to clean energy technology. <br><br>You know, when I went over in the Tank in the Pentagon, when I first was elected Vice President, with President Obama, the military sat us down to let us know what the greatest threats facing America were &#8212; the greatest physical threats.  And this is not a joke: You know what the Joint Chiefs told us the greatest threat facing America was?  Global warming.  Because there&#8217;ll be significant population movements, fights over land, millions of people leaving places because they’re literally sinking below the sea in Indonesia; because of the fights over what is arable land anymore. <br><br>With the G7, we plan to launch an ambitious effort to support resilience and development around the world by investing in high-quality, high-standard physical, digital, and health infrastructures. <br><br>We have to make sure that new technologies and norms of conduct in cyberspace are established, including addressing the growing threat of ransomware attacks that are governed by our democratic values, not by the autocrats who are letting it happen. <br><br>These are all critical national security issues in 2021, and we&#8217;re going to be driving this agenda together with our G7 partners.<br><br>In Brussels, I will make it clear that the United States’ commitment to our NATO Alliance and Article 5 is rock solid.  It&#8217;s a sacred obligation that we have under Article 5.<br><br>The U.S. and the UK are both founding members of NATO &#8212; the strongest military and political alliance in the history of the world.  And that&#8217;s not hyperbole.<br><br>Our troops have stood shoulder-to-shoulder around the world, including serving bravely in the mountains of Afghanistan for the past 20 years.<br><br>Our NATO Allies have had our backs when it mattered, just like we&#8217;ve had theirs when it’s mattered.  And now we need to modernize our Alliance, investing on our critical infrastructure, our cyber capabilities, and to keep us secure against every threat that we’ve faced over the last decade, and the new challenges we&#8217;re about to face as well.<br><br>With the European Union leaders, I&#8217;ll discuss how the United States can work with Europe to address the full range of issues that require the full strength of our transatlantic partnership, including working together to shape the new rules for the 21st century economies. <br><br>And only after these meetings with our closest democratic partners to develop a common agenda and renewed purpose, I’ll travel to Geneva to sit down with a man I&#8217;ve spent time with before: President Vladimir Putin. <br><br>We&#8217;re not seeking conflict with Russia.  We want a stable, pretictable [sic] &#8212; predictable relationship.  Our two nations share incredible responsibilities, and among them ensuring strategic stability and upholding arms control agreements.  I take that responsibility seriously. <br><br>But I&#8217;ve been clear: The United States will respond in a robust and meaningful way when the Russian government engages in harmful activities.  We&#8217;ve already demonstrated that.  I&#8217;m going to communicate that there are consequences for violati- &#8212; for violating the sovereignty of democracies in the United States and Europe and elsewhere. <br><br>I&#8217;m going to be clear that the Transatlantic Alliance will remain vital &#8212; a vital source of strength for the UK, Europe, and the United States.  And I’m going to make sure there&#8217;s no doubt as to whether the United States will rise in defense of our most deeply held values and our fundamental interest. <br><br>Here&#8217;s why this all matters so much right now: I believe we&#8217;re at an inflection point in world history &#8212; the moment where it falls to us to prove that democracies will not just endure, but they will excel as we rise to seize the enormous opportunities of a new age. <br><br>We have to discredit those who believe that the age of democracy is over, as some of our fellow nations believe.  We have to expose as false the narrative that decrees of dictators can match the speed and scale of the 21st [century] challenges. <br><br>You know and I know they’re wrong.  But it doesn&#8217;t mean we don&#8217;t have to work harder than ever to prove that democracy can still deliver for our people.<br><br>For the many who think things are changing so rapidly, democracies cannot get together and form a consensus to respond like autocrats can, but you know better than anyone that democracy doesn&#8217;t happen by accident.  We have to defend it.  We have to strengthen it, renew it. <br><br>And I know that the American people are up to this job.  I know because I look around this hangar and what I see is I see America.  I see America &#8212; people of different backgrounds coming together in a share mission.  Our democracy has never been perfect.  Never been perfect.  But Americans of all races, religions, sexual orientation, immigrants, Native Americans all have spilled their blood to defend the values that we talk about.<br><br>Generation after generation of American heroes have signed up to be part of the fight because they understand the truth<br>that lives in every American heart: that liberation, opportunity, justice is far more likely to come to pass in a democracy than in the emerging autocracies in the world.<br><br>I promise you that’s what this is going to be all about for your generation and those of your children.  And here’s what else I know beyond a doubt: There is not a single thing &#8212; nothing &#8212; nothing beyond America’s competence to accomplish when we do it together, when we do it as one people.  You’re proof of that.  You’re proof of that every single day.  Your bravery, your decency, your honor, your commitment to duty. <br><br>You can send more fuel through a boom of a KC-135R in eight minutes than a civilian gas pump can pump in 24 hours, and you do it in midair, and it’s all a normal day for this team.  So don’t tell me we can’t win our race to the future across the board. <br><br>We’re the country that cracked the physicals and the physics of human flight, then crashed through the sound barrier, then put a man on the Moon and flew a helicopter on Mars.  I could go on and on and on.  There is nothing, nothing, nothing beyond our capacity.<br><br>So, I want to thank you again for welcoming Jill and me today.  It’s great to be here in the UK, but it’s greater being here and seeing you first.  Seeing all of you is the best possible way to start this trip. <br><br>Let me end where I began: by saying “thank you.”  I mean it from the bottom of my heart.  I give you my word.  Thank you all for what you do.  Thank you all for your understanding that we’re a nation based on values.  Thank you all for protecting us all. <br><br>May God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.  Thank you, and God bless.  (Applause.) <br><br>9:09 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Suffolk, England</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/09/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-suffolk-england/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Suffolk, England 6:56 P.M. BST&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Okay.&#160; Okay.&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; We are on our way, almost arriving on the President’s first foreign trip.&#160; We have a very special guest for our gaggle today.&#160; Our National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, will take some questions, and then once you’re done with that,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Suffolk, England</p>



<p>6:56 P.M. BST<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; We are on our way, almost arriving on the President’s first foreign trip.&nbsp; We have a very special guest for our gaggle today.&nbsp; Our National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, will take some questions, and then once you’re done with that, I’m happy to take some as well.&nbsp; But you may have mostly for him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, do you want to talk a little bit about the President’s plan for boosting the global vaccine supply?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I do not want to get ahead of the President, who will be speaking to this issue tomorrow.&nbsp; And we’ll be able to talk about additional steps the United States is taking to help donate more doses to poor countries around the world and also to leverage what the United States is doing to help get the world’s democracies to increase their commitment to supplying vaccines to the developing world to help end this pandemic once and for all.&nbsp; But that announcement that he will make, he will &#8212; I will let him make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then the G7, we’ll make a combined announcement on this issue, and it won’t simply be about vaccines &#8212; though vaccines will be a part of it &#8212; but it will be a comprehensive plan to help end this pandemic as rapidly as possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the incentive for doing this?&nbsp; Is this about countering China and Russia?&nbsp; The President has talked about their vaccine diplomacy.&nbsp; Why is he trying to rally Western democracies, in particular, on this issue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’d say three things about this:<br>&nbsp;<br>First, the President is focused on helping to vaccinate the world because believes it is the right thing to do; it’s what Americans do in times of need.&nbsp; When we have the capacity, then we have the will, and we step up and we deliver.&nbsp; And he said in his joint session that we were the arsenal of democracy in World War Two, and we’re going to be the arsenal of vaccines over the course of the next period to end this pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, it’s the smart thing to do, because if variants continue to proliferate and get worse, ultimately one could break through.&nbsp; And he wants to make sure we end the pandemic before that happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, third, he does want to show &#8212; rallying the rest of the world’s democracies &#8212; that democracies are the countries that can best deliver solutions for people everywhere.&nbsp; And that goes for COVID-19, it goes for climate change, it goes for economic recovery, and it goes for the basic human rights and human dignity of all people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about the working groups that are being launched to reopen travel within the G7?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We’ve established two working groups of experts &#8212; public health experts: one with the United Kingdom and one with the European Union.&nbsp; The point of these working groups is to share data and set out both milestones and criteria to enable a reopening of travel between our two countries as swiftly as possible, consistent with public health guidance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we expect any announcement on that front, during the trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think the working groups will have finished their work by the time the trip is through.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not currently anticipating any specific announcements because we&#8217;re being guided by science; we&#8217;re being guided by what the public health experts tell us is the right condition and the right timeframe for reopening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect that the EU&#8217;s refusal of the vaccine patent waiver to be a point of contention between the President and the other leaders?&nbsp; Is the President going to push them to waive &#8212; patent waivers?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t anticipate contention on the issue of vaccines.&nbsp; I anticipate convergence, because we&#8217;re all converging around the idea that we need to boost vaccine supply in a number of ways: sharing more of our own doses &#8212; and we&#8217;ll have more to say on that; helping get more manufacturing capacity around the world &#8212; we&#8217;ll have more to say on that; and, of course, doing what&#8217;s necessary across the chain of custody from when the vaccine is produced to when it gets in someone&#8217;s arms in the rural developing world, and we&#8217;ll have more to say on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I don&#8217;t foresee any clash or contest between the U.S. and our democratic partners on this issue.&nbsp; I see a unity of effort and a unity of commitment.&nbsp; And I think the results are going to end up speaking for themselves.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How prominent is the conversation with Putin going to be on Syria humanitarian aid passage and keeping that route to Idlib open?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, second, on that: With the decision to end the sanctions waiver for the American oil company that was operating there, that Russia very much against, was that sort of a fig leaf or playing out something for Putin to sort of smooth the talks on that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Syria will be on the agenda, and our position on the humanitarian access issue is well understood.&nbsp; We believe there has to be cross-border humanitarian access to save lives.&nbsp; And so that certainly will be something that the two presidents discuss.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to get into the details on it at this point because we want to give space for those conversations to play out in the run-up to Geneva and then between the two presidents.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve got nothing more for you today on the oil field issue in eastern Syria.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can you talk about strategic stability being a key part of the discussion?&nbsp; How are you defining that?&nbsp; Is it in the traditional nuclear arms control definition?&nbsp; Is it the mix of arms control/cyber vulnerabilities for the (inaudible)?&nbsp; Is it something broader involving the way the Russians are acting on their borders?&nbsp; What’s your concept?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We believe the starting point for strategic stability talks should be the very complex set of nuclear arms issues that face our two countries.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve extended New START for five years.&nbsp; But what comes after that, how do we deal with the fact that the INF Treaty is no more, how do we deal with our concerns about Russia&#8217;s new nuclear systems, and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) deployed you mean, but that Putin keeps showing.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; (Inaudible) development.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; And these are issues that we have raised publicly and we&#8217;ve raised privately with the Russians.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the starting point.&nbsp; Whether additional elements get added to strategic stability talks in the realm of space or cyber or other areas, that&#8217;s something to be determined as we go forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, there&#8217;s been an uptick in ransomware attacks recently.&nbsp; Is that going to be a point of discussion when the President meets with President Putin?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, 100 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What can you do about it?&nbsp; I mean, is retaliation on the table, off the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, our basic view on this is that all ransomware attacks are crimes.&nbsp; They should be prosecuted to the full extent of the law, and every responsible nation should take action against the criminals who are conducting them and should not harbor them in any way.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Ransomware attacks against critical infrastructure are of an even higher order of magnitude of concern for us, whether that&#8217;s about a pipeline or meat supply or a hospital system or other areas of critical infrastructure.&nbsp; The President will talk to President Putin about our concerns on this front.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We do not judge that the Russian government has been behind these recent ransomware attacks, but we do judge that actors in Russia have.&nbsp; And we believe that Russia can take and must take steps to deal with it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;m not going to be in the business of telegraphing our punches publicly or issuing threats publicly; I&#8217;m just going to say that we believe Russia has a responsibility.&nbsp; And, of course, any country that doesn&#8217;t act, then the United States will have to consider what its options are, following that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you think is causing the uptick?&nbsp; Why do you think now?&nbsp; Why do you think there&#8217;s been an uptick in attacks now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first of all, let&#8217;s be clear that this is not strictly a U.S.-Russia issue.&nbsp; Ireland has faced the &#8212; a catastrophic attack on its healthcare system.&nbsp; The JBS attack started in a computer system; it came from Russia, hit first a computer system in Mexico, affected Australia and Canada, as well as the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is a global problem and it&#8217;s being driven by a variety of factors, including increasing technical capability, and also, unfortunately, including the fact that many elements of the private sector globally have not brought their cybersecurity standards up to snuff.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of our messages has been &#8212; to the private sector in the United States and globally &#8212; that it is &#8212; it&#8217;s very important to lock your house, to make sure that it is more difficult for these criminals to get inside and hold them hostage or disrupt their operations.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the President will discuss the Nord Stream pipeline with the German chancellor and/or the Russian president?&nbsp; Will it come up?&nbsp; Do you expect them to raise it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I expect Nord Stream 2 will come up in conversations with the Germans.&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t want to negotiate publicly on this issue.&nbsp; They understand well our concerns.&nbsp; But we do want to talk to them about what the implications of this pipeline are for energy security in Europe and for Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, what is the message that President Biden will deliver to Prime Minister Boris Johnson on Brexit and the Northern Ireland &#8212; the Good Friday Agreement?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; President Biden has been crystal clear about his rock-solid belief in the Good Friday Agreement as the foundation for peaceful coexistence in Northern Ireland.&nbsp; That agreement must be protected, and any steps that imperil or undermine it will not be welcomed by the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Johnson taking steps to imperil it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to characterize that at this point.&nbsp; I&#8217;m only going to say that President Biden is going to make statements in principle on this front.&nbsp; He&#8217;s not issuing threats or ultimatums; he&#8217;s going to simply convey his deep-seated belief that we need to stand behind and protect this protocol.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What else does he want to talk to Boris Johnson about?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;ll be talking to Boris Johnson about COVID-19; about climate change, as the UK is hosting COP26 in Glasgow later this year; about their joint commitment to developing an infrastructure financing mechanism for the developing world that is climate friendly, high standards, and transparent.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll talk to him about Afghanistan and our collective desire to maintain a strong embassy security &#8212; or embassy presence in Afghanistan after the troop drawdown.&nbsp; And, of course, there&#8217;s a whole global set of issues, from the Indo-Pacific to the Middle East, that the two leaders will cover.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, finally &#8212; you&#8217;ll see this when they meet tomorrow &#8212; there&#8217;ll be a refresher of the Atlantic Charter, which is now 80 years old.&nbsp; So there will be an updated statement of principles between the U.S. and the UK as free societies and free peoples speaking out about what we believe in in this 21st century.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, the President has talked about personal relationships in driving foreign policy.&nbsp; He had this meeting 10 years ago with Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; What did he learn from that meeting, and what is he bringing from that meeting?&nbsp; And has he been reflecting on it at all in the preparation for this upcoming meeting?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Bottom line: He believes you need to be clear, direct, and straightforward in every aspect of the engagement with Vladimir Putin, and that&#8217;s what he intends to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he ever consider having a joint press conference with him?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he &#8212; did the President ever consider having a joint press conference with Putin, or was it out of the question from the start?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I will defer to my press colleagues about the individual modalities of the press-related issues.&nbsp; But he does want to have an opportunity after that meeting to read it out and speak about his impressions and what he sees as the way forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you tell us what your views are on the 232 tariffs that remain in place?&nbsp; Do you expect them to come in and &#8212; like, do you think that those 232 tariffs are a national security issue?&nbsp; That was the guise or umbrella under which they were imposed in the first place.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, you know, in a real spirit of constructive engagement, the U.S. and the EU have agreed to a pause in the escalation of tariffs in response to the 232.&nbsp; That has given time and space for a negotiation to hopefully produce an outcome that meaningfully addresses the problem of Chinese overcapacity.&nbsp; And we regard that as a serious challenge that affects both Europe and the United States and must be dealt with effectively.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe there&#8217;s an outcome possible on this trip, or is that a longer-term discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s going to take some time to work out, which is why that stand-down on the tariffs was so important &#8212; because it gives us the time and space for us to be able to (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;But you&#8217;re not rolling back tariffs? &nbsp;You’re not rolling back tariffs? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; (Shakes head no.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak a little bit about Iran and what the President will ask President Putin, in terms of supporting the JCPOA?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Russia is a member of the P5+1.&nbsp; The American negotiating team is working with the Russian negotiating team in Vienna.&nbsp; They have worked together in a productive and constructive way, to a large extent.&nbsp; And so this will be an opportunity for the two presidents to be able to consult on where we think we are in those talks and what needs to be done to get them across the line.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on Iran &#8212; just continuing on that same line: The Secretary has frequently said we need something longer and stronger, and so forth.&nbsp; Do you have any reason to believe that after &#8212; if you get the agreement that is now basically in blue, that the Iranians have any interest in going to something that is longer and stronger?&nbsp; And what is that evidence?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t underestimate the difficulty of any nuclear negotiation with the Iranians, since we&#8217;ve been through them.&nbsp; But we do believe that there is scope for follow-on negotiations to deal with what &#8212; to build on the JCPOA once we are back in it.&nbsp; And we believe the Iranians will ultimately be prepared to engage in those negotiations.&nbsp; There are things for them to gain, because there are many aspects of our sanctions that are &#8212; are not necessarily part of the original JCPOA.&nbsp; And, of course, we retain all of the right and capacity to take additional steps if they&#8217;re not prepared to negotiate in good faith.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’ve talked before about the ransomware side.&nbsp; But, you know, a few months ago, if this meeting was happening, it would have been pretty much all about SolarWinds and state-sponsored actions.&nbsp; So is that now behind you, having done the sanctions and whatever unseen activities?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the President&#8217;s message on that?&nbsp; What kind of guardrails might use that (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have had the opportunity to engage with the Russians, through several channels, on the SolarWinds issue, both before and after we imposed costs in response to it.&nbsp; But that doesn&#8217;t mean that issue is behind us, of course. &nbsp;The issue of state-sponsored cyberattacks of that scope and scale remains a matter of grave concern to the United States.&nbsp; It will be a topic of conversation between the presidents.<br>&nbsp;<br>And us talking ransomware is not going to come to the exclusion of us talking about the cyber threat in multiple other domains.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) him to some understanding with Putin, to some understanding of what&#8217;s off limits.&nbsp; Can you tell us a little bit about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to leave that to the two presidents to discuss for now.&nbsp; You know, sort of, depending on how that conversation goes at the highest level and where we come out, we will be in a better position to be able to talk about our expectations, as well as our capacities at that point.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t want to front-run that today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has there been any developments on Airbus during this time at all?&nbsp; The Airbus dispute &#8212; the Boeing Airbus dispute.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;m not going to say one way or the other on that.&nbsp;&nbsp;All I will note is that the negotiations are ongoing, that we also there bought space with the mutual stand-down on tariffs as well that runs out much sooner than the 232.&nbsp;&nbsp;And so, I think there has been good progress in those negotiations, but I&#8217;m making no promises about what might happen over the course of the (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jumping ahead to the NATO meeting, does the President feel the need to restate U.S. support for Article 5?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, of course.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will he do that in Brussels?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He feels the need to restate support for Article 5 as often as he is able to do so, because for him, it&#8217;s an article of faith &#8212; for President Joe Biden and for the United States of America.&nbsp; And so he will proclaim that loudly and proudly, as he just did with the Secretary General when he was in town a couple of days ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, you know, he&#8217;s not just going to speak about principle; he&#8217;s going to speak about the practicalities of what&#8217;s required to make Article 5 real, including the work that needs to be done between now and 2030 on every aspect of transatlantic defense and security.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, in the last G7, there was not a communiqué because of disagreements between President Trump and the other leaders.&nbsp; Can we expect a communiqué at this G7?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to jinx it, but yes, I think you can expect a communiqué at this G7.&nbsp; And &#8212; you know.&nbsp; But you never know.&nbsp; I hope so.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right, I’m going to let Jake go back.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you can speak a little bit more about the format of<br>the bilaterals between President Biden and Putin, that would be great.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I mean, what I can tell you is we&#8217;re still discussing, so we don’t have a final conclusion yet.&nbsp; That what I can confirm for you is that you will have the opportunity to ask questions of President Biden.&nbsp; And we certainly hope that you&#8217;ll also have the opportunity to ask questions of President Putin.&nbsp; What that format looks like, we&#8217;ll know in the next couple days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so it’s still being negotiated with the Russians?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Still being &#8212; still being discussed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it’s still two bilats &#8212; a small and an extended one?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s right.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Talk about infrastructure a little bit.&nbsp; We saw the statement.&nbsp; Has the President now decided to go it only with Democrats to pass the bill?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So I talked to the President about this, this morning, and his view is that there are multiple paths forward.&nbsp; He feels it&#8217;s encouraging to see multiple proposals put out there, both from Republicans in the House and the Problem Solvers Caucus, as well as a bipartisan group that&#8217;s working on a proposal.&nbsp; Both will have increased numbers over what we&#8217;ve seen and been negotiating to date.&nbsp; Those are all positive steps.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, Steve, we&#8217;re also &#8212; the Senate is also moving forward with a budget process.&nbsp; That, by the way, is how government should work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an opportunity to move, through that vehicle, a bunch of his bold economic ideas, as well as corporate tax reform &#8212; something that, of course, will pay for a number of his proposals but also something that will make us more competitive and he thinks is long overdue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President, with Senator Capito, pivoted to talking about a 15 percent minimum corporate tax as opposed to a 28 percent corporate tax rate.&nbsp; Of course, they’re not mutually exclusive, but is he resetting at all, now that he&#8217;s pivoting to the bipartisan group?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has always felt that corporate tax reform and raising the corporate rate to 28 percent &#8212; which he proposed and is in his budget, as you know &#8212; is something that is good for &#8212; good for our competition, good for our economy, good for workers in this country, and also will help pay for proposals.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you also know, the 15 percent minimum tax was an additional proposal that he put forward in the American Jobs Plan and also is in his budget.&nbsp; But it is a proposal that would not violate the red line the Republicans have put forward on the 2017 tax cuts.&nbsp; So, that, which would help pay for proposals, as well as the IRS going after individuals to ensure they&#8217;re paying for &#8212; they’re paying their fair share and they&#8217;re paying what they owe &#8212; are payfors that do not violate the 2017 taxes.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why he reelevated those.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think those corporate tax changes are more or less likely with this bipartisan group of senators than they were with Senator Capito’s group?&nbsp; Are they more on the table or less on the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll certainly see.&nbsp; But our view and the President&#8217;s view is that they should be on the table for all of them because they do not violate their red line; because &#8212; unless they feel that these corporations shouldn&#8217;t pay any taxes at all.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just suggesting they should pay 15 percent, which isn&#8217;t even what the tax rate he&#8217;s proposing for most corporations around the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did the President spend any time on the flight over, or even in the short time between when he woke up this morning, getting to talk to people and do some of this reach-out that he said he&#8217;s going to be doing on infrastructure, while (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m not sure even any of his close friends would like a call from him at 6:00 a.m.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But he will certainly be engaged on this trip with his domestic agenda, including having conversations with Democrats and Republicans back at home.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On this trip, he was primarily focused on having discussions with his national security team about the foreign trip &#8212; his first foreign trip overseas &#8212; but he will be having those conversations.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll keep you abreast of those.&nbsp; He&#8217;s also asked his Jobs Cabinet to run point and be closely engaged with all of these members of both parties who are interested in being part of the infrastructure negotiations moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know you guys &#8212; I know he can walk and chew gum, or whatever metaphor you want to use, but is there any disappoint, just not having that done before getting started with this also very important agenda item?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that what we see are a number of signs of progress.&nbsp; One, the Senate just passed a China competition bill just yesterday.&nbsp; We&#8217;re eager for the House to move forward on that; that&#8217;s a positive step forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>While we&#8217;re on this plane &#8212; on this flight, Congressman DeFazio is helping oversee the markup of the Surface Transportation bill that has a great deal of overlap with the American Jobs Plan. &nbsp;And in addition to the Senate moving forward on a budget process that can be a vehicle for his economic ideas and corporate tax reform, we&#8217;ve also seen multiple options of proposals come forward in a bipartisan manner.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s quite familiar with the fact that this process can take &#8212; it takes some patience at times; that there are going to be moments where we&#8217;re near death, and then it comes back.&nbsp; That&#8217;s always how policymaking, lawmaking, bill making happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212; but he&#8217;s been encouraged by the progress, encouraged by the interest by not just Republicans and Democrats in the country, but also in Congress, on working together to get an infrastructure bill passed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say what Jake meant by a “refresher” of the transatlantic charter?&nbsp; &nbsp;Can you tell us a little bit more about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; It will be something that we will put out.&nbsp; it will update the charter that, as he noted, is several decades old &#8212; I believe is what he said.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll put that out publicly and it will &#8212; you know, it will confirm and be clear &#8212; and will be consistent with what our challenges are today and opportunities today.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll put that out publicly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk to us about what can we expect with the bilat with President Erdoğan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, this is a relationship, obviously a NATO partner, where there are areas where we feel it&#8217;s important to continue to constructively work together where there&#8217;s opportunity, and also areas where we have strong disagreement.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an opportunity to have that face-to-face diplomacy, which the President felt was important to do as a priority bilateral meeting during his first trip overseas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what are the specific issues?&nbsp; Like, Syria or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure they will discuss issues of regional security; issues, of course, that are impacting the global community, including the economy, including COVID-19.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more, I&#8217;m sure, as we get closer to the bilateral meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he going to have bilats with other leaders at the G7, or, like, pull-asides individually?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He will certainly have pull-asides.&nbsp; I will look back at the schedule and what we’ve confirmed publicly.&nbsp; As you all know, from covering these international summits, there are &#8212; the schedules are quite packed, but there is an opportunity often to have, kind of, pull-aside conversations, and he&#8217;ll look for the opportunity to do that on the ground as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s rumors that he&#8217;s going to be having a pull-aside with the Belarusian opposition leader. &nbsp;Is that correct?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not seen &#8212; I am not aware of that plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On infrastructure &#8212; back to infrastructure: Leader Schumer suggested that the bill could possibly pass partially through reconciliation, partially through bipartisan.&nbsp; Is that something that the administration is open to?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I mean, the point is it&#8217;s moving on several paths.&nbsp; So even as we negotiate an infrastructure bill &#8212; right? &#8212; or portions of the American Jobs Plan, it’s already moving forward on several fronts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then there are components of the Amer- &#8212; of the President’s proposals, including the extension of the Child Tax Credit, making pre-K universal, making community college free, that are not a part of the negotiations now, so they would be natural components that would be added into a budget process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Jen, a couple of weeks ago, we heard the President agreeing to the statement that President Putin is a killer.&nbsp; Do you think that’s going to make things awkward coming into the summit?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has known President Putin for a long time.&nbsp; He has never held back in voicing his concerns or issues where their behavior is not aligned with democratic values, and he will certainly be straightforward in doing that in this meeting as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is not about friendship.&nbsp; It’s not about trust.&nbsp; It’s about what’s in the interest of the United States.&nbsp; And, in our view, that is moving toward a more stable and predictable relationship.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the China bill, you now have to get to the House.&nbsp; What’s the strategy there?&nbsp; It looks like that may be a tougher climb than the Senate.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That &#8212; that may be the case.&nbsp; Look, the President was certainly encouraged by the fact that it passed the Senate.&nbsp; We’ve seen concerns expressed publicly by some members of the House, including some high up.&nbsp; And we’re going to take a look at what the legislation looks like, hear their concerns.&nbsp; We’ll be engaged, of course, in discussing how we can move this forward, you know, from a staff level.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a schedule for that, or not?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have a schedule or a timeline to predict.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the global minimum tax &#8212; some of the Republicans came out against it this week.&nbsp; Does that complicate the plan at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the world stage?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; No &#8212; yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, our view is that this is in the interest of America’s competition of our economy, of the global economy to have that global minimum tax, and felt it was a very positive sign that there was agreement among finance ministers at the G7.&nbsp; So we are encouraged by that, and, you know, it’s a positive sign.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) the EU and U.S. have a &#8212; their draft statement, as of now, includes a reference to the origins &#8212; the investigation into the origins of the coronavirus.&nbsp; Why is the U.S. seeking, sort of, support from European allies on this issue of getting to the bottom of where that virus came from?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that even as we pursue our own 90-day review, and &#8212; where we are going to tap into every resource we have available in the U.S. government, we also recognize that in order to send a clear message to China and to the WHO, of course, who’ve been a constructive partner, that it’s important that they are transparent, that they release all the available data, that we move forward on the second stage of this investigation.&nbsp; Doing that from a united front and doing that in partnership with our European partners is a vital part of this process.&nbsp; So, it’s an indication of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will there be a similar line in the G7 communiqué?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to predict for you on that quite yet.&nbsp; You’ll know soon enough.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you comment again on the vaccine patent waiver?&nbsp; The U.S. has just joined the G20 &#8212; I’m sorry, the APEC &#8212; to support the patent waivers.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the President be pushing this issue with European leaders who prefer to do compulsory licensing instead?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is an ongoing process that our ambassador &#8212; our USTR ambassador is running point on.&nbsp; It’s a long process, as you know &#8212; several months to negotiate what the best format will look like.&nbsp; Whether it’s coming up &#8212; going to come up in conversations, I’m sure we can &#8212; that will be reflected in readouts.&nbsp; But I would suspect we will leave it at the level of the U.S. ambassador.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the President doesn’t plan to put his diplomatic weight behind a patent waiver?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has certainly spoken about his support on the waiver.&nbsp; He believes it’s import- &#8212; an important component of addressing the global threat of COVID.&nbsp; And he will continue to play a constructive role.&nbsp; But I don’t have anything to preview for you or predict in terms of how it will come up in these conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>All right, thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Have a good landing.<br>&nbsp;<br>7:25 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/09/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION&#160;SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Jayme Ray White, of Washington, to be a Deputy United States Trade Representative (Western Hemisphere, Europe, the Middle East, Labor, and Environment), with the rank of Ambassador, vice Michael N. Nemelka. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION&nbsp;SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jayme Ray White, of Washington, to be a Deputy United States Trade Representative (Western Hemisphere, Europe, the Middle East, Labor, and Environment), with the rank of Ambassador, vice Michael N. Nemelka.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Five Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/09/president-biden-announces-five-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following five individuals to serve in key roles: Amanda Howe, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Mission Support, Environmental Protection Agency Guy Kiyokawa, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Enterprise Integration, Department of Veterans Affairs Damon Smith, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Housing and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following five individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Amanda Howe, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Mission Support, Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Guy Kiyokawa, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Enterprise Integration, Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Damon Smith, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>William Eugene Holloway, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the National Institute of Building Sciences</li><li>Javier Ramirez, Nominee for Director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service</li></ul>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Amanda Howe, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Mission Support, Environmental Protection Agency</span></strong><br>Amanda Howe is a career public servant, helping lead progressive change in government, politics, and the non-profit sector. She served in the role of Chief Operating Officer for the Kamala Harris For The People presidential campaign in 2019 and for the Democratic National Committee before, during, after President Barack Obama’s 2012 re-election campaign. In the past year, she’s been a senior advisor to the President of Everytown for Gun Safety and for the Maya Wiley for Mayor campaign in New York City. Howe served as Deputy and then Acting Chief of Staff to New York City Mayor Bill de Blasio, and after, as a consultant to the city, helped plan the first-ever ticker tape parade for a women’s team for the U.S. Women’s Soccer Team World Cup win and for the official visit of Pope Francis and his procession through Central Park.  She served as Vice President of the non-profit American Council on Renewable Energy in Washington, D.C.  In Virginia, Howe served as Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Trade for then-Governor Mark R. Warner and led the planning for then-Governor Tim Kaine of the Virginia portion of the most recent official visit to the U.S. of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II and Prince Phillip in 2007. Howe holds a bachelor’s degree in political science from Dalhousie University in Nova Scotia.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Guy Kiyokawa, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Enterprise Integration, Department of Veterans Affairs</span></strong><br>Mr. Guy Kiyokawa is currently the Deputy Director of the Defense Health Agency (DHA), Falls Church, VA. The DHA is a joint Combat Support Agency supporting Army, Navy, and Air Force medical services, and it administers the TRICARE Health Plan providing worldwide medical, dental and pharmacy programs to more than 9.6 million uniformed service members, retirees and their families. Prior to his selection to the Senior Executive Service in 2015, Mr. Kiyokawa completed a 29-year career in the United States Army with leadership experience in multiple roles ranging from aeromedical evacuation pilot to health facility engineering to healthcare administration.  He culminated his career as the Chief of Staff for the newly formed Defense Health Agency, and retired at the rank of Colonel in 2015.<br><br>Mr. Kiyokawa was born and raised in Honolulu, Hawaii. He holds a Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering from the University of Southern California, and is a 1995 graduate of the US Army-Baylor University Program with a Master’s Degree in Health Administration.  Mr. Kiyokawa graduated from the U.S. Army War College in Carlisle Barracks, PA where he completed the War College Fellowship with the Department of Veterans Affairs in Washington, DC.  He currently resides in Vienna, Virginia with his wife and three kids.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Damon Smith, Nominee for General Counsel, Department of Housing and Urban Development</span></strong><br>Damon Smith currently serves as the Principal Deputy General Counsel at the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD).  He joined the Biden-Harris Administration after serving as Senior Director of Advocacy and Counsel at the Credit Union National Association (CUNA), representing the nation’s cooperatively-owned, not-for-profit credit unions in housing, telecommunications and financial security matters.  Prior to joining CUNA, Smith was a Partner at Jenner and Block LLP in Washington, D.C. where he provided counsel to companies facing complex compliance, government regulation and enforcement matters.<br><br>Smith previously served as the Senior Counsel and Acting General Counsel at the U.S. Department for Housing and Urban Development during the Obama-Biden Administration, where he provided legal and policy guidance on a range of programs and activities and set the Department’s litigation strategy and regulatory agenda. Before his government service, he taught property and local government law as an Associate Professor at Rutgers-Camden Law School and a Visiting Professor at the American University Washington College of Law.  Smith began his legal career as a real estate Associate at Arnold &amp; Porter in Washington, D.C., and worked prior to law school as an urban planner in East St. Louis, Illinois and St. Louis, Missouri. <br><br>Smith is a graduate of Harvard Law School and holds a bachelor’s degree in English and a master’s degree in urban planning from the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign<br><br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">William Eugene Holloway, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the National Institute of Building Sciences</span></strong><br>Bill Holloway is Vice President, Principal, and Director of Delaware Operations for Bernardon, an award-winning regional architecture, interior design and landscape architecture firm with offices in Wilmington, Delaware and West Chester and Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Spanning 39 years of practice, his professional accomplishments include significant projects in the public works, institutional, and healthcare markets. Among Holloway’s notable projects are the Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Train Station in Wilmington, the restoration of the historic Old State House in Dover, Delaware, and renovations to over twenty-seven facilities for the Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia.  Currently, Holloway is working on a major addition to the Delaware Division of Public Health Laboratory in Smyrna, Delaware.<br><br>In recognition of his service to the profession of Architecture, the American Institute of Architects (AIA) named him a Richard Upjohn Fellow at the national level for his service on the Institute’s board.  In honor of his successful tenure as president of AIA Delaware, Holloway was made a member of the chapter’s G. Morris White Society.  He was also voted to be accepted to the membership of the Carpenters’ Company of the City and County of Philadelphia, a prestigious organization of builders, architects, and engineers originally chartered in 1724.<br><br>Bill earned his Bachelor of Architecture degree from The Pennsylvania State University where he was awarded the College of Arts &amp; Architecture Medal for Creative Achievement and the Alpha Rho Chi Medal for leadership, service and merit in architecture.  He is also quite proud of his years as a member of the sousaphone rank in the Penn State Blue Band. In the community and beyond, Bill serves as a longtime member of the Executive Board of the Del-Mar-Va Council Boy Scouts of America; a member of the Easter Seals Society of Delaware and the Eastern Shore Board of Trustees; and a member of the executive committee of the New Castle County Chamber of Commerce.  Bill also continues his avocation in music as a member of the Aldersgate Brass Ensemble. Bill and his wife of 37 years, Cathy, reside in Chadds Ford, Pennsylvania and together they have two adult children, Megan Holloway and Ben Holloway, both of Wilmington, Delaware.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Javier Ramirez, Nominee for Director of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service</span></strong><br>Javier Ramirez began his FMCS career as a Commissioner in 2005 and is currently the Executive Manager of the Division of Agency Initiatives.  This office bears responsibility for the Office of Conflict Management &amp; Prevention, Office of Strategy &amp; Development, the Center for Conflict Resolution and Education, the FMCS Institute for Conflict Management, and the DC and Northern Virginia (HQ) Commissioners.  <br><br>Javier mediated disputes in all sectors of the economy (except air and rail) in professions such as the performing arts, public safety, professors, hospitality, hospitals, manufacturing, and packing houses.  Javier facilitated and mediated multi-party disputes in manufacturing, construction, and education.  He was on the facilitation team for several regulatory negotiations, including the Department of Energy (DOE) negotiations that resulted in the largest energy-saving rule in DOE history.  Javier also trained and successfully facilitated parties in various collaborative bargaining models.  Notably, Javier collaborated with colleagues to create the FMCS Affinity Bargaining model.  He represented the agency in international tri-partite training efforts in Bangladesh and trained all New Zealand labor mediators on collaborative bargaining. Javier has been the recipient of multiple FMCS performance awards in recognition of his work, including the Director’s Award.<br><br>Additionally, Javier is regularly asked to present at national and regional conferences on conflict management topics.  He guest lectured on labor relations and dispute management at the University of Illinois, University of Colorado Boulder, National Defense University, Cornell, and other universities.<br><br>Prior to FMCS, Javier spent over fourteen years in labor relations, negotiating contracts and resolving disputes in areas such as immigration, contract administration, communication, staffing, and politics at the federal, state, and local level.  His efforts have been featured in Rolling Stone, Chicago Tribune Magazine, and Chicago Lawyer Magazine; cited in the New York Times Best Seller Fast Food Nation; and recognized by the College of Labor and Employment Lawyers.<br><br>Javier enjoys the performing arts or exploring the great outdoors with his wife and two adult children.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Executive Order Protecting Americans’ Sensitive Data from Foreign Adversaries</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-protecting-americans-sensitive-data-from-foreign-adversaries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 14:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Biden Administration is committed to promoting an open, interoperable, reliable and secure Internet; protecting human rights online and offline; and supporting a vibrant, global digital economy. Certain countries, including the People’s Republic of China (PRC), do not share these values and seek to leverage digital technologies and Americans’ data in ways that present unacceptable&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Biden Administration is committed to promoting an open, interoperable, reliable and secure Internet; protecting human rights online and offline; and supporting a vibrant, global digital economy. Certain countries, including the People’s Republic of China (PRC), do not share these values and seek to leverage digital technologies and Americans’ data in ways that present unacceptable national security risks while advancing authoritarian controls and interests.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to further address the ongoing national emergency declared in E.O. 13873 of May 15, 2019 with respect to the threat posed to the United States’ information and communications technology and services (ICTS) supply chain. President Biden revoked and replaced three E.O.s that aimed to prohibit transactions with TikTok, WeChat, and eight other communications and financial technology software applications; two of these E.O.s are subject to litigation. In their place, this E.O. directs the use of a criteria-based decision framework and rigorous, evidence-based analysis to address the risks posed by ICTS transactions involving software applications that are designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons that are owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction of a foreign adversary, including the People’s Republic of China, that may present an undue or unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States and the American people.<br><br>Specifically, the E.O. the President signed today:<br><br><strong>Enables&nbsp;the U.S. to take strong steps to protect Americans’ sensitive data:&nbsp;</strong>This E.O. revokes&nbsp;and replaces&nbsp;E.O.s 13942, 13943, and 13971.&nbsp;The new E.O. directs the Department of Commerce to instead evaluate foreign adversary connected software applications under the rules published to implement E.O. 13873 and take action, as appropriate.<br><br><strong>Provides criteria for identifying software applications that may pose unacceptable risk:</strong> This E.O. provides criteria for consideration, consistent with the criteria set forth in E.O. 13873 and the implementing regulations, for identifying and evaluating ICTS transactions involving foreign adversary connected software applications that may pose an unacceptable risk to U.S. national security and the American people. For example, ICTS transactions involving software applications may present a heightened risk when the transactions involve applications that are owned, controlled, or managed by persons that support foreign adversary military or intelligence activities, or are involved in malicious cyber activities, or involve applications that collect sensitive personal data.<br><br><strong>Develops further options to protect sensitive personal data and address the potential threat from certain connected software applications:</strong> This E.O. directs the Department of Commerce, in consultation with other U.S. departments and agencies, to make recommendations to protect against harm from the sale, transfer of, or access to sensitive personal data, including personally identifiable information and genetic information – to include large data repositories – to persons owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, foreign adversaries. Additionally, the Department of Commerce will make recommendations for additional executive and legislative actions to further address the risk associated with foreign adversary connected software applications.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on Protecting Americans’ Sensitive Data from Foreign Adversaries</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/09/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-protecting-americans-sensitive-data-from-foreign-adversaries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 14:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), I hereby report that I&#160;have issued an&#160;Executive Order addressing the threat from certain connected software applications designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a foreign&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.), I hereby report that I&nbsp;have issued an&nbsp;Executive Order addressing the threat from certain connected software applications designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a foreign adversary, to include the&nbsp;People&#8217;s Republic of China, among others.<br><br>I have determined that additional consideration must be given in&nbsp;addressing the national emergency declared in Executive Order&nbsp;13873 of May 15, 2019 (Securing the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain), including the threat posed by certain connected software applications designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a foreign adversary.<br><br>I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Sincerely,<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Protecting Americans’ Sensitive Data from Foreign Adversaries</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/09/executive-order-on-protecting-americans-sensitive-data-from-foreign-adversaries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 14:23:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act&#160;(50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.), and section 301 of title 3, United&#160;States Code, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act&nbsp;(50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq.</em>), and section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code,</p>



<p>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of&nbsp;America, find that it is appropriate to elaborate upon measures to address the national emergency with respect to the information and communications technology and services supply chain that was declared in Executive Order 13873 of May 15, 2019 (Securing the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain). &nbsp;Specifically, the increased use in the&nbsp;United States of certain connected software applications designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, a foreign adversary, which the Secretary of Commerce acting pursuant to Executive Order 13873 has defined to include the People&#8217;s Republic of China, among others, continues to threaten the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States.&nbsp; The Federal Government should evaluate these threats through rigorous, evidence-based analysis and should address any&nbsp;unacceptable or undue risks consistent with overall national security, foreign policy, and economic objectives, including the preservation and demonstration of America&#8217;s core values and fundamental freedoms.</p>



<p>By operating on United States information and communications technology devices, including personal electronic devices such as smartphones, tablets, and computers, connected software applications can access and capture vast swaths of information from users, including United States persons&#8217; personal information and proprietary business information. &nbsp;This data collection threatens to provide foreign adversaries with access to that information.&nbsp; Foreign adversary access to large repositories of United States persons&#8217; data also presents a&nbsp;significant risk.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In evaluating the risks of a connected software application, several factors should be considered.&nbsp; Consistent with the criteria established in Executive Order 13873, and in addition to the criteria set forth in implementing regulations, potential indicators of risk relating to connected software applications include: &nbsp;ownership, control, or management by persons that support a foreign adversary&#8217;s military, intelligence, or proliferation activities; use of the connected software application to conduct surveillance that enables espionage, including through a foreign adversary&#8217;s access to sensitive or confidential government or business information, or sensitive personal data; ownership, control, or management of connected software applications by persons subject to coercion or cooption by a foreign adversary; ownership, control, or management of connected software applications by persons involved in malicious cyber activities; a lack of thorough and reliable third-party auditing of connected software applications; the scope and sensitivity of the data collected; the number and sensitivity of the users of the connected software application; and the extent to which identified risks have been or can be addressed by independently verifiable measures.</p>



<p>The ongoing emergency declared in Executive Order 13873 arises from a variety of factors, including the continuing effort of foreign adversaries to steal or otherwise obtain United States persons&#8217; data.&nbsp; That continuing effort by foreign adversaries constitutes an unusual and extraordinary threat to&nbsp;the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States. &nbsp;To address this threat, the United States must act to protect against the risks associated with connected software applications that are designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned or controlled by, or&nbsp;subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, a foreign adversary.</p>



<p>Additionally, the United States seeks to promote accountability for persons who engage in serious human rights abuse. If persons who own, control, or manage connected software applications engage in serious human rights abuse or otherwise facilitate such abuse, the United States may impose consequences on those persons in action separate from this order.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Accordingly, it is hereby ordered that:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Section 1.</span>  <span style="text-decoration: underline">Revocation of Presidential Actions.</span>  The following orders are revoked:  Executive Order 13942 of August 6, 2020 (Addressing the Threat Posed by TikTok, and Taking Additional Steps To Address the National Emergency With Respect to the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain); Executive Order 13943 of August 6, 2020 (Addressing the Threat Posed by WeChat, and Taking Additional Steps To Address the National Emergency With Respect to the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain); and Executive Order 13971 of January 5, 2021 (Addressing the Threat Posed by Applications and Other Software Developed or Controlled by Chinese Companies).</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 2.</span>  <span style="text-decoration: underline">Implementation.</span>  (a)  The Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the heads of executive departments and agencies (agencies) shall promptly take steps to rescind any orders, rules, regulations, guidelines, or policies, or portions thereof, implementing or enforcing Executive Orders 13942, 13943, or 13971, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, including the Administrative Procedure Act, 5 U.S.C. 551 <em>et seq.</em>  In addition, any personnel positions, committees, task forces, or other entities established pursuant to Executive Orders 13942, 13943, or 13971 shall be abolished, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law.<br>     (b)  Not later than 120 days after the date of this order, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of National Intelligence, and the heads of other agencies as the Secretary of Commerce deems appropriate, shall provide a report to the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor with recommendations to protect against harm from the unrestricted sale of, transfer of, or access to United States persons&#8217; sensitive data, including personally identifiable information, personal health information, and genetic information, and harm from access to large data repositories by persons owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, a foreign adversary.  Not later than 60 days after the date of this order, the Director of National Intelligence shall provide threat assessments, and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide vulnerability assessments, to the Secretary of Commerce to support development of the report required by this subsection.<br>     (c)  Not later than 180 days after the date of this order, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the heads of other agencies as the Secretary of Commerce deems appropriate, shall provide a report to the Assistant to the President and National Security Advisor recommending additional executive and legislative actions to address the risk associated with connected software applications that are designed, developed, manufactured, or supplied by persons owned or controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of, a foreign adversary.  <br>     (d)  The Secretary of Commerce shall evaluate on a continuing basis transactions involving connected software applications that may pose an undue risk of sabotage or subversion of the design, integrity, manufacturing, production, distribution, installation, operation, or maintenance of information and communications technology or services in the United States; pose an undue risk of catastrophic effects on the security or resiliency of the critical infrastructure or digital economy of the United States; or otherwise pose an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons.  Based on the evaluation, the Secretary of Commerce shall take appropriate action in accordance with Executive Order 13873 and its implementing regulations.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 3.</span>  <span style="text-decoration: underline">Definitions.</span>  For purposes of this order:<br>     (a)  the term &#8220;connected software application&#8221; means software, a software program, or a group of software programs, that is designed to be used on an end-point computing device and includes as an integral functionality, the ability to collect, process, or transmit data via the Internet;<br>     (b)  the term &#8220;foreign adversary&#8221; means any foreign government or foreign non-government person engaged in a long-term pattern or serious instances of conduct significantly adverse to the national security of the United States or security and safety of United States persons;<br>     (c)  the term &#8220;information and communications technology or services&#8221; means any hardware, software, or other product or service primarily intended to fulfill or enable the function of information or data processing, storage, retrieval, or communication by electronic means, including transmission, storage, and display;<br>     (d)  the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity; and<br>     (e)  the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sec. 4.</span>  <span style="text-decoration: underline">General Provisions.</span>  (a)  Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>          (i)   the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>          (ii)  the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>     (b)  This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>     (c)  This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. &nbsp;</p>



<p><br>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; June 9, 2021.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before Air Force One Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George&#8217;s County, Maryland 8:26 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; You dropped your phone.&#160; You dropped your phone.&#160; Watch out for the cicadas.&#160; I just got one &#8212; it just got me. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; What’s your main goal today when you get over there? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Strengthening the alliance and make it clear to Putin&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews<br>Prince George&#8217;s County, Maryland</p>



<p>8:26 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You dropped your phone.&nbsp; You dropped your phone.&nbsp;<br><br>Watch out for the cicadas.&nbsp; I just got one &#8212; it just got me.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What’s your main goal today when you get over there?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Strengthening the alliance and make it clear to Putin and to China that Europe and the United States are tight, and the G7 is going to move.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you expect to come out with a vaccine strategy for the world?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I have one and I’ll be announcing it.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect that Putin will be able to work out any kind of understanding with you on the cyberattacks?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Who knows at this point.&nbsp; It’s going to be a subject of our discussion.<br><br>8:27 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the United States’ Commitment to Open Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-united-states-commitment-to-open-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 23:46:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20061</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Open Investment Policy of the United States is a pledge to treat all investors fairly and equitably under the law. As Governors, CEOs, and other public and private sector leaders come together at the 2021 SelectUSA Summit this week, I want to reiterate my administration’s commitment to ensuring that the United States remains the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Open Investment Policy of the United States is a pledge to treat all investors fairly and equitably under the law. As Governors, CEOs, and other public and private sector leaders come together at the 2021 SelectUSA Summit this week, I want to reiterate my administration’s commitment to ensuring that the United States remains the most attractive place in the world for businesses to invest and grow, thus creating jobs here at home, strengthening supply chains across the country, and deepening our relationships with allies and partners.<br><br>America has the most productive workforce in the world. We have an unmatched business environment strengthened by our culture of innovation and entrepreneurship, outstanding educational institutions, and commitment to transparency, protection of intellectual property, flexible and efficient capital markets, and the rule of law. We believe that our country – and our world – are safer, more resilient, and more prosperous because of the investment of foreign-owned companies in the United States.<br><br>As we continue to advance our agenda to revitalize American manufacturing, build an inclusive 21st century workforce, and maintain our competitive edge, the United States welcomes foreign investment. Today, U.S. subsidiaries of foreign-owned companies directly employ almost 8 million Americans and help boost U.S. innovation by investing $70 billion in research and development. They contribute to all sectors of the U.S. economy and are responsible for nearly 24% of all U.S. goods exports.<br><br>We will always protect our national security, and certain foreign investments will be reviewed by the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States for this purpose. But, we will also maintain a level playing field. As the United States faces increasing competition for the jobs and industries of the future, we will remain the destination of choice for investors around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
