<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 22:28:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at a Celebration to Mark Black History&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/28/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-a-celebration-to-mark-black-history-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 22:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48021</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:29 P.M. EST&#160;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Dr. Biden.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Please have a seat, everybody. Well, good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; It is so good to meet so many folks and to see so many folks.&#160; It’s nice to be together, under one roof together, isn’t it? And, of course, it is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>East Room</em></p>



<p>2:29 P.M. EST&nbsp;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Biden.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Please have a seat, everybody.</p>



<p>Well, good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; It is so good to meet so many folks and to see so many folks.&nbsp; It’s nice to be together, under one roof together, isn’t it?</p>



<p>And, of course, it is an honor to be here with our incredible President, Joe Biden &#8212; (applause); First Lady Dr. Jill Biden &#8212; (applause); and the first Second Gentleman of the United States, my husband, Doug Emhoff.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>It is wonderful to be here this afternoon, joined by the members &#8212; the most esteemed members of the Congressional Black Caucus.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And as a former member of the CBC, I know firsthand that the members of the CBC are truly the conscience not only of the Congress but of our country.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Thank you, also, to all the clergy joining us today, who continue to lift the spirits and the condition of so many people in our country.&nbsp; And to the community organizers, who work day in and day out to make a difference in the lives of all people in our nation.&nbsp; We are so grateful for you.</p>



<p>And we are gathered, then, at a critical moment in the history of our nation and our world &#8212; a moment in which our democratic principles have come under threat.<br><br>Today, the eyes of the world are on Ukraine and the brave people who are fighting to protect their country and their democracy.&nbsp; And their bravery is a reminder &#8212; a most recent reminder &#8212; that justice, equality, and freedom must never be taken for granted by any of us.<br><br>So, friends, Black History Month was established to teach the history that too often has not been taught: the history of Black excellence and leadership in America &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and also the history of resistance and resilience in America.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we are clear: Black history is American history.&nbsp; It is living, breathing history &#8212; history we create every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, of course, our nation faces many great challenges.&nbsp; Among the greatest is the assault on the freedom to vote &#8212; the freedom from which all others flow.&nbsp;<br><br>It will take an all-hands-on-deck approach to safeguard and strengthen the freedom to vote.&nbsp; And the President and I are committed to securing that freedom, as is everyone here.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And that is why I felt such pride and such hope &#8212; understanding how votes lead to action through elections, it is why I felt such pride and such hope this past Friday when President Joe Biden nominated Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson &#8212; (applause) &#8212; when he nominated her to sit on the United States Supreme Court.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Because, as we all know, elections matter.&nbsp; And when folks vote, they order what they want.&nbsp; And in this case, they got what they asked for.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I went off script a little bit.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And Judge Jackson, of course, will make a phenomenal Justice.&nbsp; She is brilliant.&nbsp; She has a brilliant mind and a record of excellence &#8212; a record that proves she will administer equal justice.&nbsp; And I don’t have to tell everybody here, she has been confirmed on a bipartisan basis three times and deserves, therefore, a swift confirmation now.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And Judge Jackson will be the first Black woman to sit on our nation&#8217;s highest court.&nbsp; And as Dr. Jill Biden mentioned, it is with that spirit also that we know she will not be the last.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>So, there is a lot to celebrate.&nbsp; There is a lot to look forward to.&nbsp; There is a lot to work toward.&nbsp; And in remembering our history, we remember those great American heroes who continue to inspire and motivate us, who continue to remind us through our memory of them and their contribution and sacrifice what our role and responsibility is at this moment in history.<br><br>And speaking of that, then, when everyone walked in to the White House today, I&#8217;m sure that you may have seen an exhibit celebrating great Black Americans.<br><br>On display is a campaign poster from Shirley Chisholm &#8212; Barbara Lee, I saw you here today &#8212; books by Toni Morrison, Zora Neale Hurston, and Maya Angelou; and a display honoring Dr. Mae Jemison, who I just talked with last week &#8212; you know I’m the head of the Space Council &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; about her life and her work and her enduring commitment to helping young people find their own path to the stars.<br><br>In the exhibit, there is also an Ella Fitzgerald vinyl &#8212; we used to call it an &#8220;album&#8221;; and a Jacob Lawrence painting, which hangs right here in this White House on a permanent basis; and, especially significant in this moment, a judicial oath signed by Justice Thurgood Marshall, whose life&#8217;s work influenced my own.&nbsp; In fact, his portrait hangs currently in the official office of the Vice President of the United States.&nbsp; And &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and a bust of his figure sits in my ceremonial office as well.<br><br>So, as we gather here today, and as we prepare to confirm<br>another historic first to our nation&#8217;s highest court, let us always remember: We stand on the shoulders of giants &#8212; giants in our history, giants in American history, and giants right here in this room.&nbsp;<br><br>This Black History Month, let us recommit to honoring<br>their legacy with action.&nbsp; Let us continue their fight and our fight for justice and equality and opportunity for all so that generations to come may stand on our shoulders and reach even greater heights.<br><br>And history, as I have said many times before, I do believe it to be a relay race.&nbsp; We have been each passed a baton with which we run our part in our pursuit of progress and we will then pass the baton to the next generation.&nbsp;<br><br>And in that spirit, it is now my pleasure to introduce a young, brilliant leader who is leading our nation forward with bravery, creativity, and grace, and excellence.<br><br>Please welcome Cateo Hilton.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2:38 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 22:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48019</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; William Brodsky, of Illinois, to be a Director of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation for a term expiring December 31, 2023, vice Anthony Frank D&#8217;Agostino, term expired. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Kathryn Huff, of Illinois, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Nuclear Energy), vice Rita Baranwal. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Ketanji Brown Jackson, of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; William Brodsky, of Illinois, to be a Director of the Securities Investor Protection Corporation for a term expiring December 31, 2023, vice Anthony Frank D&#8217;Agostino, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kathryn Huff, of Illinois, to be an Assistant Secretary of Energy (Nuclear Energy), vice Rita Baranwal.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ketanji Brown Jackson, of the District of Columbia, to be an Associate Justice of the Supreme Court of the United States, vice Stephen G. Breyer, retiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; William A. LaPlante, Jr., of Massachusetts, to be Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, vice Ellen M. Lord.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden on the Passing of Dick&#160;Blum</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-dick-blum/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 21:56:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48016</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I were saddened to learn of the passing of Dick Blum, a successful businessman and proud son of California who dedicated much of his public life to fighting poverty around the globe. For 16 years, I had the honor of serving on the Senate Judiciary Committee alongside Dick’s wife — and one of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I were saddened to learn of the passing of Dick Blum, a successful businessman and proud son of California who dedicated much of his public life to fighting poverty around the globe.</p>



<p>For 16 years, I had the honor of serving on the Senate Judiciary Committee alongside Dick’s wife — and one of America’s true trailblazers — Senator Dianne Feinstein. During that time, Jill and I came to know Dick as a friend. He was first and foremost dedicated to his family. He turned his lifelong fascination with Mt. Everest into the American Himalayan Foundation, which he created to help construct schools and hospitals in the Tibetan community. And here at home, Dick bled Berkeley blue — he was fiercely loyal to his alma mater, the University of California, where he established the Blum Center for Developing Economies to seek innovative solutions to the challenges of global poverty.</p>



<p>Jill and I will miss our friend. Our prayers are with Senator Feinstein, their family, and all those who knew and loved Dick Blum.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  The Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Advances Equity and Opportunity for Black People and Communities Across the&#160;Country</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-advances-equity-and-opportunity-for-black-people-and-communities-across-the-country-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 21:25:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From the first day in office and every day since, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken an historic approach to advancing racial equity, including directing every agency across the whole of the federal government to address the lasting impacts of systemic racism on Black communities. For generations, entrenched disparities in our society and economy, at times&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>From the first day in office and every day since, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken an historic approach to advancing racial equity, including directing every agency across the whole of the federal government to address the lasting impacts of systemic racism on Black communities. For generations, entrenched disparities in our society and economy, at times facilitated by the federal government, have made it harder for Black Americans to have a fair shot at the American dream. Centuries of injustice and decades of disinvestment in Black communities not only undermine the American promise of equal opportunity, but also keep our entire nation from reaching its potential.</p>



<p>After just one year in office, the Administration has delivered real and lasting change and continues to work each day to deliver equitable outcomes and opportunity for Black Americans.</p>



<p><strong>Economic Opportunity for Black Families and Communities.</strong> By signing into law the historic American Rescue Plan (ARP) and Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and implementing robust regulatory reform, President Biden has helped create new economic opportunities for Black Americans and made long overdue investments in Black communities. These transformative policies and programs include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing Immediate Relief to Black People and Families through the American Rescue Plan.</strong> The <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=5f43ffef0d&amp;e=cf669202c8">ARP</a> provided cash relief directly to low- and middle-income Americans last year, and cut Black child poverty by <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/610831a16c95260dbd68934a/t/61ea09926280d03df62aa31d/1642727841927/Monthly-poverty-December-2021-CPSP.pdf">33.3</a>%, lifting more than 1 million Black children out of poverty in December 2021 alone. The President’s plans call for extending this critical tax cut, which expired in December.  In addition, the ARP increased Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) benefits by 15% through September 2021. Beginning on October 1, 2021, USDA&#8217;s Thrifty Food Plan update increased SNAP benefits by $36.30 per person per month.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reversing Decades of Disinvestment Through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</strong> For years, politicians have talked about investing in our national infrastructure, but up until now they have failed to follow through. The lack of investment has fallen most heavily on Black and other communities of color. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will replace lead pipes, increase access to good-paying jobs, expand affordable high-speed internet, reliable public transit, clean drinking water, reconnect Black neighborhoods divided by legacy highway infrastructure and other resources to finally give Black communities a fair shot at the American Dream.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law permanently authorizes the Minority Business Development Agency (MBDA) for the first time since its inception and elevates the agency head to the position of Under Secretary, granting the agency expanded power to support Black and other minority-owned businesses. The President’s plans would supercharge MBDA by funding it at $1.6 billion through 2029.<ul><li>EPA announced that it will allocate <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=f840c7c7b9&amp;e=cf669202c8">$2.9 billion</a> in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding to states, Tribes, and territories for lead service line replacement in 2022. The 2022 allocation is the first of five years of nearly $15 billion in dedicated EPA funding for lead service lines that states will receive through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. EPA will encourage states to use these funds to advance proactive lead line replacement programs with a particular focus on disadvantaged communities. Moving forward, EPA will prioritize communities with the highest lead levels and those with environmental justice concerns.</li></ul><ul><li>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law delivers the largest investment in tackling legacy pollution in American history by cleaning up Superfund and brownfield sites, reclaiming abandoned mine land, and capping orphaned oil and gas wells. More than one in four Black Americans live within 3 miles of a <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=406ac95a00&amp;e=cf669202c8">Superfund site</a>– a higher percentage than for Americans overall. No community deserves to have contamination near where they live, work, play, pray, and go to school.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Leveraging Federal Procurement to Narrow the Racial Wealth Gap for Black Entrepreneurs and Families.</strong> Recognizing that the federal government spends more than $650 billion each year on purchasing goods and services, President Biden has directed agencies to use federal purchasing power to grow federal contracting with underserved small businesses. He has set a goal of increasing the share of federal contracting dollars to small disadvantaged businesses by 50% by 2025— projected to translate to an additional $100 billion to minority-owned businesses, and helping more Americans realize their entrepreneurial dreams. In December 2021, The Administration further <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=3914654cd1&amp;e=cf669202c8">announced</a> reforms to the federal procurement process to help meet the President’s ambitious target and deliver new opportunities for Black owned and other small disadvantaged businesses.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Extending a Lifeline to Struggling Small Businesses.</strong> The American Rescue Plan provided emergency grants, lending, and investment to hard-hit small businesses – including Black businesses – so they can rehire and retain workers and purchase the health and sanitation equipment they need to keep workers safe. This includes the new $10 billion State Small Business Credit Initiative, which will provide growth capital to early stage companies and main street small businesses in economically disadvantaged areas, including minority-owned businesses.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring Black Homeowners Get Full Value for their Homes.</strong> In June 2021, President Biden directed the launch of a first-of-its-kind interagency effort to address inequity in home appraisals and conduct rulemaking to aggressively combat housing discrimination. The effort, led by the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Secretary Marcia Fudge and Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, is developing a set of policy actions and recommendations for President Biden to redress racial bias in home appraisals that will soon be released.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Protecting Black Americans’ Access to Housing by Combating Housing Discrimination.</strong> Following President Biden’s Presidential Memorandum directing his Administration to address racial discrimination in the housing market, HUD published an interim final rule in the Federal Register entitled “Restoring Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing Definitions and Certifications” that requires HUD funding recipients to complete an assessment of fair housing issues, identify fair housing priorities and goals, and then commit to meaningful actions to meet those goals and remedy identified issues.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Helping Black Americans Stay in their Homes.</strong> President Biden’s American Rescue Plan has helped millions of Americans, including Black Americans, stay in their homes by providing emergency rental assistance. Of the $25 billion in rental assistance that was spent in 2021, Black Americans represented more than 40% of aid recipients. In addition, the ARP is helping struggling homeowners catch up with their mortgage payments and utility costs through the Homeowner Assistance Fund. And, it provided additional funding for families and individuals who are recovering from or at risk of homelessness.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Assisting Black Land Owners in Resolving Title Issues. </strong>An estimated 60% of Black-owned land in the South is heirs’ property—property that passes through inheritance without a will and that, as a result, has historically rendered owners ineligible for U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) programs, including lending. In July 2021, the USDA rolled out the Heirs’ Property Relending Program, which primarily aids underserved communities, including Black Americans. The new program provides funds to assist heirs in resolving ownership and succession issues on farmland with multiple owners.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Dismantling Barriers to Accessing USDA Programs and Services.</strong> The ARP provides funding for USDA to establish one or more equity commissions to address historical discrimination and disparities in the agricultural sector. In February 2022, USDA announced the membership of its 15-member Equity Commission Advisory Committee and Equity Commission Subcommittee on Agriculture. The Equity Commission Advisory Committee will advise the Secretary of Agriculture by identifying USDA programs, policies, systems, structures, and practices that contribute to barriers to inclusion or access, systemic discrimination, or exacerbate or perpetuate racial, economic, health and social disparities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reducing Barriers for Black Communities Facing Natural Disasters. </strong>In <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=acd8fa07ee&amp;e=cf669202c8">September</a> 2021, FEMA implemented policy changes to reduce barriers that contributed to disparities experienced by Black Americans through programs that provide individual assistance to disaster survivors. These included changes to FEMA policies to make it easier for people living on heirs’ property – which is estimated to be the majority of Black-owned land in the South – to apply for disaster aid.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring that Federal Grants Don’t Support Discriminatory Activities.</strong> In June 2021, the Department of Transportation (DOT) <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=b916425fbf&amp;e=cf669202c8">issued an Order</a> requiring its offices to review the potential discriminatory impact of grantees’ proposed activities before awarding federal funds. Under the Order, the agency won’t award federal financial assistance unless and until the agency determines that the activities will not be discriminatory in intent or effect. Similarly, in September 2021, the Department of Justice (DOJ) began a review of its grantmaking programs, to ensure that federal funds are not distributed to agencies that engage in racial discrimination in violation of Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Improving the Customer Experience and Service Delivery. </strong>In December, President Biden signed the Transforming Federal Customer Experience and Service Delivery to Rebuild Trust in Government <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=6c2917d192&amp;e=cf669202c8">Executive Order</a> – a commitment from federal agencies to remove red tape on critical government services like claiming retirement benefits or filing taxes and streamline and increase access to these services for all Americans.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reducing Child Care Cost for Black Families. </strong>The American Rescue Plan secured a $39 billion lifeline to help child care providers stay open and compensate early childhood educators, disproportionately Black Americans, as they provide safe and healthy environments for children and help parents work. Black families are nearly two times more likely than white parents to have to quit, turn down, or make a major change in their job due to child care disruptions. The pandemic exacerbated child care disruptions, and by March 2021, had already led to 9% of child care providers closing. The ARP also included an expansion of the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit; a median income family with two kids under age 13 will receive up to $8,000 towards their child care expenses when they file taxes for 2021, compared with a maximum of $1,200 previously.</li><li><strong>Advancing Equitable Employment Outcomes and Boosting Wages for Black Federal Workers. </strong>In June, President Biden signed an Executive Order on Advancing Diversity, Equity, Inclusion, and Accessibility (DEIA) in the Federal Workforce. This Executive Order launched a whole-of-government initiative to cultivate a federal workforce that draws from the full diversity of the Nation and that advances equitable employment opportunities for workers from underserved communities. Further, in 2021 the President signed a series of executive actions leading to a $15 minimum wage for employees of federal contractors and federal employees. These actions will ensure that all federal workers, including Black federal workers, have fair access to federal employment opportunities, and will also represent a step towards addressing longstanding wage disparities.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensuring Equitable Educational Opportunity in K-12 Schools and an Education Beyond High School. </strong>As we continue to recover from the COVID-19 pandemic, President Biden has delivered the support necessary to enable every school to <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=85fcff5ad8&amp;e=cf669202c8">safely reopen</a> for full-time, in-person instruction; accelerate academic achievement; address the mental health needs of students; and build school communities where all students feel they belong. At the same time, President Biden has worked to ensure equitable access to high-quality education for Black students. These policies and programs include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Historic Investments to Safely Reopen Schools and Address the Needs of Students. </strong>The ARP provided $130 billion to help elementary and secondary schools safely reopen and address the academic, social and emotional and mental health needs of all students, with funding set-aside to address the needs of students disproportionately impacted by the pandemic, including Black students. The Administration’s efforts to encourage all schools to adopt the CDC&#8217;s recommendations on masking, vaccinations, and other COVID-19 protocols, have been particularly critical to the safe reopening of schools in Black communities hit hard by COVID-19. In addition to funding the implementation of COVID-19 protocols, these funds are being used to hire counselors and social workers, provide tutors, establish and expand summer and after-school programming, and provide a wide range of supports that address the needs of Black students. It also provided funds to every Head Start grantee, which disproportionately serve Black children and families, so that grantees could safely open safely for in-person services and support children and families through the pandemic.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Protecting Students from Funding Cuts.</strong> The ARP’s Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief program includes a first of its kind maintenance of equity requirement to ensure that high-poverty school districts and schools are protected in the event of future funding cuts. The Department of Education has provided resources and technical assistance to states and school districts as they implement this new requirement, which will ensure that school districts and schools serving a large share of students from low-income backgrounds will not experience disproportionate cuts, and that school districts with the highest poverty levels do not experience any decrease in state per-pupil funding below their pre-pandemic level.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Historic Support for Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs).</strong> The Biden-Harris Administration has delivered an historic $5.8 billion cumulative investment in and support for HBCUs, including:</li></ul>



<ul><li>The ARP and other pandemic relief programs have provided approximately $3.7 billion to HBCUs since President Biden took office.<ul><li>Additionally, in April, the Department of Education provided approximately $1.6 billion in debt relief to 45 HBCUs, including 13 public institutions and 32 private institutions.</li></ul><ul><li>In July and August, the Department of Education awarded more than $500 million in grant funding to HBCUs for academic capacity-building and fiscal stability.</li></ul><ul><li>President Biden signed an <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=9bb56d7abd&amp;e=cf669202c8">Executive Order</a> establishing the White House Initiative on Advancing Educational Equity, Opportunity, and Excellence through HBCUs, which will create a government-wide approach to support the needs of HBCUs and the communities they serve and eliminate systemic barriers impeding HBCU participation in Federal programs, and in February 2022, appointed Dietra Trent, former Virginia Deputy Secretary of Education, as the Initiative’s Executive Director.</li></ul><ul><li>During HBCU week, President Biden named Tony Allen, President of Delaware State University, as Chair of the President’s Board of Advisors on HBCUs. The President has also named Glenda Glover, President of Tennessee State University as Vice Chair of the Board. The Board, established by the Carter Administration, is meant to advance the goals of the HBCU Initiative.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong>Improving Health Outcomes for Black Communities.</strong> Facing a once-in a century pandemic that highlighted and exacerbated pre-existing racial disparities in our health care system, President Biden took swift action to promote better health access and outcomes for Black families. The ARP lowered health care costs for millions of lower- and middle-income Black families and invested billions to promote equitable vaccine distribution and provide critical supplies to stop the spread of COVID-19. These policies and programs include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Lowering Health Care Costs.</strong> Millions of lower- and middle-income Black families enrolled in health insurance marketplaces saw their premiums lowered or eliminated as a result of the ARP and will continue to benefit through the end of 2022. <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/documents/08307d793263d5069fdd6504385e22f8/black-americans-coverages-access-ib.pdf">Thanks to the ARP</a>, 76% of uninsured Black Americans could find a plan for less than $50 a month, and 66% could find a plan for free a month in 2021 with those subsidies. In addition, millions of uninsured Americans gained coverage during the Administration’s 2021 Special Enrollment Period (SEP). Of those newly signing up for HealthCare.gov coverage who attested to race or ethnicity, <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/2021-sep-final-enrollment-report.pdf">15%</a> were Black Americans, up over 60% from 2019.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Improving Black Maternal Health.</strong> The Administration is also committed to improving maternal health outcomes, including addressing the unacceptably high rates of maternal mortality and morbidity that disproportionately impact Black mothers and families. The President’s FY 22 budget request includes more than $200 million to bolster Maternal Mortality Review Committees, implement implicit bias training for health care providers, and create State pregnancy medical home programs, among other actions. It also includes $6 billion for the critical Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) program to help vulnerable families put healthy food on the table and address racial disparities in maternal and child health outcomes.<ul><li>The President’s plans includes a historic $3 billion investment in maternal health focused on growing and diversifying the perinatal workforce, improving data collection and maternal health risk monitoring, addressing the social factors that contribute to poor maternal health outcomes, addressing substance use disorders that impact maternal health, promoting increased maternal health research, improving postpartum coverage, and better coordinating care. This includes sparking innovation by allowing states to establish maternal health homes to better coordinate health care for individuals before, during, and following birth.</li></ul><ul><li>It would also require all states to provide continuous Medicaid coverage for 12 months postpartum, eliminating potentially deadly gaps in health insurance at a critical time for individuals. Currently, states are only required to provide coverage for 60 days postpartum, despite research showing that many deaths and complications occur more than 60 days following delivery.</li></ul><ul><li>The Administration has already approved a number of Medicaid demonstrations to expand postpartum coverage, including in Illinois, Virginia, and New Jersey; these states will provide full Medicaid benefits for 12 months postpartum (other states have expanded to six months postpartum coverage or expanded coverage to 10 months for those with substance use disorders). The ARP gives states an easier pathway to extend coverage for pregnant women from 60 days to 12 months postpartum; the Administration is working to encourage all states to take up this option so women can get the care they need to stay healthy.</li></ul><ul><li>In April 2021, President Biden issued the first ever <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=3c9546a4cd&amp;e=cf669202c8">Presidential Proclamation on Black Maternal Health Week</a>, calling on all Americans to recognize the importance of addressing the crisis of Black maternal mortality and morbidity.</li></ul><ul><li>Further, in December 2021, Vice President Harris <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=42a57fd1ee&amp;e=cf669202c8">issued</a> a nationwide call to action to both public and private sectors to improve health outcomes for Black mothers and their children. As part of this call to action, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services issued new guidance to help states provide 12 months (up from 60 days currently) of continuous postpartum coverage through their Medicaid programs. If every state adopted an extension — as required in the President’s plans —then the number of Americans getting coverage for a full year postpartum would roughly double, extending coverage for an estimated 720,000 people in a given year. HHS also announced plans to create a new “Birthing Friendly” hospital designation, which would be the first-ever hospital quality designation by HHS specifically focused on maternity care.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Building the Pipeline of Black Health Care Providers.</strong> The Administration has made a historic $1.5 billion investment to help grow and diversify the nation’s health care workforce, and bolster equitable health care in the communities that need it most during the COVID-19 pandemic and in the years to come. This funding is supporting the National Health Service Corps, Nurse Corps, and Substance Use Disorder Treatment and Recovery programs. These programs address workforce shortages and health disparities by providing scholarship and loan repayment funding for health care students and professionals, in exchange for a service commitment in hard-hit and high-risk communities.&nbsp; With funding from the American Rescue Plan, the investment supports over 22,700 providers—the largest field strength in history for these programs and a record number of skilled doctors, dentists, nurses, and behavioral health providers committed to working in underserved communities during a moment when we need them the most. Only about 5 percent of physicians in the United States identify as Black despite the fact that Black Americans account for 12 percent of the nation’s total population; over 13 percent of physicians serving through the National Health Service Corps identify as Black.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring an Equitable Pandemic Response.</strong> Nationwide, Black people have died from COVID-19 at 1.4 times the rate of White people. The ARP provided $160 billion for the vaccines, tests, personal protective equipment, and public health workforce needed to address the spread of COVID-19, an investment that is helping to drive down racial disparities in prevention and care. Due to the ARP and the President’s other investments in equitable access to the COVID-19 vaccine, multiple studies show that the gap in COVID vaccination rates in Black Americans compared to Whites and Latinos has closed. Data as of February 2022 show that 84% of Black adults, 87% of Latinos and 85% of White adults have received at least one shot, compared to 56%, 57%, and 65%, respectively, in May 2021. Additionally:<ul><li>FEMA surged resources to vaccinate all eligible Americans, including by standing up 500 vaccine sites in underserved communities. These emergency measures have helped deliver community-based and culturally competent care. In fact, over 50% of vaccines administered at the federally-run community vaccination centers went to Black Americans and other people of color, and more than 75% of people vaccinated at Community Health Centers are people of color.</li></ul><ul><li>In January 2021, President Biden signed an <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=03fb5b89f7&amp;e=cf669202c8">Executive Order</a> on Ensuring an Equitable Pandemic Response and Recovery, creating a COVID-19 Health Equity Task Force to provide specific recommendations to the President for mitigating the health inequities caused or exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic and for preventing such inequities in the future. The Task force transmitted its final report to the White House Office of the COVID-19 Response in November 2021, including recommendations related to interpersonal stress linked to racism, addressing the behavioral health consequences of the pandemic in communities of color, and vaccine, testing, and therapeutics access and confidence. By the end of 2021, the Administration had begun action on over 80 percent of the Task Force recommendations, and remains committed to engaging these recommendations within the historic initiatives and programs built to promote and sustain equity across the federal government. Federal agencies are now developing implementation proposals related to the policies and priorities recommended by the Task Force, which will be submitted no later than March 10.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong>Taking Strong Action to Reform Our Criminal Justice System.</strong> From investing in community violence interventions, to reforming law enforcement, to reducing mass incarceration practices, to supporting reentry, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken concrete actions to reform the criminal justice system and address racial disparities. These policies and programs include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Reforming Law Enforcement Practices.</strong> In September 2021, the Department of Justice (DOJ) announced a ban on use of chokeholds and carotid restraints except where deadly force is necessary, and new restrictions on no-knock warrants—implementing reforms for federal law enforcement administratively that the President had called on Congress to enact nationwide through the George Floyd Justice in Police Act. The Department also implemented a new policy requiring federal agents to wear body cameras when executing search warrants and pre-planned arrests. These changes make real the policy reform the country must undertake to prevent tragic killings like those of George Floyd and Breonna Taylor in the future. The directives apply to all agencies overseen by the Department including the FBI, Drug Enforcement Agency, and U.S. Marshal’s Service. In September, the Department of Homeland Security announced the formation of the Law Enforcement Coordination Council (LECC)—the Department’s first unified law enforcement coordination body, chaired by the Secretary—to comprehensively review and revise its policies and training on use of force, compliance with civil rights and privacy interests, and other matters. In July 2021, the Department of the Interior created a task force to study and recommend reforms for its law enforcement agencies, including the U.S. Park Police.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring Constitutional Policing.</strong> The Department of Justice (DOJ) rescinded guidance issued in the previous Administration that curtailed the use of consent decrees, including within investigations into patterns or practices of discrimination and misconduct by police departments. Pattern and practice investigations and consent decrees are critical tools to promote constitutional policing in jurisdictions where reform is warranted. DOJ has opened four such investigations in Minneapolis, Louisville, Phoenix, and Mount Vernon, New York.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Improving Prosecutorial Guidance to Prevent Unduly Harsh Sentencing.</strong> The DOJ withdrew guidance issued in the previous Administration that required prosecutors to always charge the harshest sentences, replacing it with guidance that restored discretion to make decisions about charging, plea agreements, and advocacy at sentencing based on an individualized assessment of relevant facts.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting Legislation to End Racial Disparities in Cocaine Sentencing.</strong> The President endorsed the EQUAL Act, which would eliminate the racially discriminatory crack-powder cocaine sentencing disparity and make the change fully retroactive.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Support for Community Violence Intervention (CVI) Programs.</strong> The President ordered DOJ not to renew contracts for privately-operated criminal detention facilities, covering the Bureau of Prisons (BOP) and U.S. Marshals Service (USMS). When completed, this will result in up to 14,000 people in BOP custody and 10,000 people in USMS custody being moved out of private prisons. To date, the administration has closed a total of 7 contracts, resulting in more than 4,000 people moved out of private prisons.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Support for Community Violence Intervention (CVI) Programs.</strong> Black boys and young men ages 15-34 make up 2% of the population but are 37% of homicide victims, and homicide is the leading cause of death for Black men under the age of 45. Until this Administration, however, CVI programs like violence interrupters and hospital-based programs, which are demonstrated to reduce violence by up to 60%, have been badly underfunded. Under President Biden, the Treasury Department and Education Department issued guidance stating that CVI programs are eligible uses of American Rescue Plan funds—both the $350 billion in aid to state, Tribal, and local governments and the $122 billion to school districts. The Administration pivoted 26 existing grant programs across five agencies to support CVI. And President Biden continues to seek $5 billion in dedicated funding for CVI programs. These historic funds would help curtail the epidemic of gun violence that hits Black communities hardest.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Support for Reentry of Returning Citizens.</strong> In February 2021, President Biden expanded access to Paycheck Protection Program loans by removing restrictions for entrepreneurs with certain past criminal records, bringing long overdue help to small businesses previously unable to access these funds. In June 2021, the Department of Labor awarded $85.5 million to help formerly incarcerated adults and young people in 28 communities transition out of the criminal justice system and connect with quality jobs. The President issued an Executive Order directing the Office of Personnel Management to evaluate the existence of any barriers that formerly incarcerated individuals face in accessing federal employment, and to evaluate how to expand federal employment opportunities for formerly incarcerated individuals. OPM provided its findings and a summary of actions to expand employment for this population to the President in October. Further, in September 2021 the Labor and Treasury Departments released new resources to help employers leverage tax credits and other federal programs to incentivize the hiring of formerly incarcerated persons. HUD clarified that returning citizens are eligible for the 70,000 emergency housing vouchers created by the ARP. Further, President Biden’s plans include an additional $1.6 billion of workforce development and job training funding to invest in re-entry employment efforts.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Addressing Domestic Violent Extremism.</strong> President Biden directed the U.S. government to assess the threat of domestic violent extremism in the United States. In January, Secretary of the Department of Defense (DOD) Lloyd J. Austin III ordered a DOD-wide stand down to discuss the problem of extremism in the ranks, and in April he established a countering extremism working group, directing DOD officials to review and update the definition of extremism contained in <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=ed5a029c91&amp;e=cf669202c8">DOD Instruction 1325.06</a>, and calling on the services to update transition instructions to prevent those leaving the military from being recruited by extremist groups. In March 2021, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence released the unclassified executive summary of the comprehensive assessment acknowledging that enduring domestic violent extremism motivations stem from biases against minority populations. In April 2021, Department of Homeland Security (DHS) Secretary Alejandro Mayorkas ordered an internal review to root out white supremacy and extremism within DHS.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Using Executive Authority to Protect Voting Rights, Democracy, and Access to Justice. </strong>These policies and programs include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Signing Executive Order Promoting Access to Voter Registration and Voting.</strong> On the 2021 anniversary of Bloody Sunday, President Biden signed an <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=1d4d1ebc06&amp;e=cf669202c8">Executive Order</a> to leverage the resources of the federal government to provide information about the election process and increased access to voter registration opportunities. Agencies across the federal government have <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=87561df6a0&amp;e=cf669202c8">announced steps</a> they are taking to respond to the President’s call for an all-of-government action to enhance the ability of all eligible Americans to participate in our democracy, including the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services’ <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=280f4a922c&amp;e=cf669202c8">recent commitment</a> to make it easier for consumers using HealthCare.gov to connect to voter registration services.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring Compliance with Voting Rights Laws.</strong> The Department of Justice has taken a variety of steps to help protect the right to vote, including doubling the number of voting rights attorneys, taking steps to ensure compliance with voting rights statutes, launching a task force to combat the increase of threats against election officials and election workers, and issuing guidance on (1) the civil and criminal statutes that apply to post-election audits, (2) methods of voting, including early voting and voting by mail, and (3) the vote-dilution protections that apply to all jurisdictions under Section 2 of the Voting Rights Act as they engage in redistricting.</li></ul>



<ul><li>To expand the promise of equal justice under law, the President issued a Presidential Memorandum in May 2021 that <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=32f2f54d32&amp;e=cf669202c8">asked</a> the Attorney General to consider expanding the Department of Justice’s access to justice work. In October 2021, the Attorney General announced the reestablishment of the Office for Access to Justice as a standalone component within the Justice Department dedicated to improving the federal government’s understanding of and capacity to address the most urgent legal needs of communities across America. The President’s May 2021 Memorandum also reinvigorated the White House Legal Aid Interagency Roundtable to prioritize and expand access to legal services and federal programs, including in the areas of criminal indigent defense, civil legal aid, and pro bono services. In September 2021, the Roundtable released its Access to Justice in the Age of COVID-19 report highlighting the urgent need to prioritize and expand access to legal services and federal programs as a result of the Covid-19 crisis.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Appointing and Confirming Black Judges.</strong> President Biden is committed to ensuring that the judiciary is filled with highly qualified individuals who bring both personal and professional diversity to the bench. Since January 2021, President Biden has nominated a total of 84 individuals for federal judgeships, 25 of whom are African American, and 13 individuals for local judgeships in Washington, D.C., 5 of whom are African American. In February, he announced his intention to nominate Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson to serve as Associate Justice of the Supreme Court. Of the 48 individuals who have been confirmed to positions on federal courts, 14 are African American.</p>



<p><strong>Restoring Fairness and Humanity to Our Immigration System.</strong>&nbsp; President Biden is committed to reforming our immigration system, promoting racial equity in our immigration policies, and providing legal protections for noncitizens, including Black noncitizens who call this country home.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Extending and Redesignating Haiti and Somalia for Temporary Protected Status (TPS).</strong>&nbsp; The Administration extended legal protections to Haitian and Somalian nationals who have lived in our country for years.&nbsp; TPS is a form of immigration relief available to noncitizens in the United States who cannot return home due to dangerous conditions in their home countries; it enables those individuals to live with their families and work in our communities without fear of removal.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Restarting the Haitian Family Reunification Parole Program (HFRP).</strong> The Obama-Biden Administration created the HRFP in 2014, allowing U.S. citizens and green card holders to apply for parole on behalf of family members in Haiti who have approved immigrant visa petitions.&nbsp; The prior Administration announced the termination of this program in 2019.&nbsp; The Biden-Harris Administration restored HFRP and remains committed to helping Haitian-American families reunify in our country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting Immigration Reform Legislation.</strong>&nbsp; President Biden remains committed to passing legislation to finally reform our broken immigration system.&nbsp; These reforms would promote racial equity by providing a pathway to citizenship to millions of undocumented individuals, including Black noncitizens.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>&nbsp;The President is not done. The Biden-Harris Administration continues to advance equity and racial justice, including for Black Americans, as we build back better. These policies and programs include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>President Biden’s Proposed Plan Will Promote Investment and Economic Opportunity in Black Communities</strong>. President Biden’s plans will reverse decades of disinvestment and wealth extraction in Black communities, other communities of color and rural communities, and drive good jobs and opportunity to every corner of the country, making long needed, once-in-a-generation investments in underserved communities: The President intends to make universal preschool a reality, cut child care costs and increase access to high-quality child care, reduce housing costs and increase the supply of affordable housing, lower health care costs, improve maternal health, expand coverage to millions of low-income Americans by closing the Medicaid coverage gap, and extend the ARP’s historic child tax credit expansion. The Presidents’ plans also include a $3 billion investment focused on improving maternal health in this country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Sustained Investment in HBCUs.</strong> President Biden’s plans seek sustained investments in HBCUs and their students. These include $10 billion to HBCUs, Tribal Colleges and Universities (TCUs), and minority-serving institutions (MSIs). Of that total, $2 billion is dedicated specifically for HBCUs—a five-fold increase from the amounts HBCUs typically receive annually through existing funding streams to address a wide range of needs, including student financial aid, infrastructure upgrades, and campus services. HBCUs can compete for another $4 billion of these funds to support research and development programs.<ul><li>Additionally, President Biden’s FY22 budget request for the Department of Education includes a total of $807 million in discretionary funding to HBCUs, an increase of $72 million over last year’s funding level, which will substantially increase key HBCU funding streams to support research, infrastructure, and student support services, amongst other programming.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Unwavering Support for the Fundamental and Sacred Right to Vote.</strong> President Biden has firmly and repeatedly called for Congress to enact the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act and the Freedom to Vote Act, which would together set national standards that make it easier to vote, and deliver new tools to prevent voting discrimination. The President urged the Senate to change the rules, including getting rid of the filibuster, to pass these critical pieces of legislation. And the President will continue to use every tool at his disposal to protect the right to vote in free, fair, and secure elections.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Transforming Public Education with Historic Funding Increases.</strong> Black students are less likely to have access to high-quality preschool, resulting in disparate outcomes before students even enter kindergarten. They are more likely to attend rundown and unsafe schools. They are taught by less experienced teachers. And they have lower college completion rates and higher student loan debt burdens than their white peers. The President has outlined a <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=a758d3c8cb&amp;e=cf669202c8">far-reaching agenda</a> that will transform public education, advancing equity for Black students and prepare all students to succeed.</p>



<ul><li>The President’s plans would provide universal, high-quality preschool for all three- and four-year-olds; invest in school infrastructure so all students learn in safe and healthy school buildings with the technology and labs they need to prepare for the jobs of the future; and strengthen and diversity the teacher pipeline.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The President’s FY22 budget proposal includes a $20 billion increase in Elementary and Secondary Education Act (ESEA) Title I funding, which would more than double funds available under the flagship program for students in high-poverty schools, while providing meaningful incentives for states to address inequitable school funding systems and close gaps in access to rigorous coursework, like advanced math and science courses. Over 80% of Black students attend a Title I-eligible school, and there is a $23 billion annual funding gap between majority white and majority non-white school districts.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Through the President’s plans and his FY22 budget, the President has requested a $950 increase to the maximum Pell Grant for students enrolled in public and private non-profit colleges, benefitting <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=248e202884&amp;e=cf669202c8">75% of HBCU students</a> who receive them.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Addressing Police Misconduct.</strong> The President strongly supported the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act. He is disappointed that legislation has not yet reached his desk, and continues to urge Congress to act, while also examining ways to advance meaningful police reform through executive action.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Allies and&#160;Partners</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-allies-and-partners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 21:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48005</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden hosted a secure conference call today with Allies and partners about our unified response to Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war on Ukraine. The leaders recognized the bravery of the Ukrainian people in the face of Russian aggression and discussed&#160;their&#160;continued support to Ukraine, including security, economic, and humanitarian assistance. They also discussed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden hosted a secure conference call today with Allies and partners about our unified response to Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked war on Ukraine. The leaders recognized the bravery of the Ukrainian people in the face of Russian aggression and discussed&nbsp;their&nbsp;continued support to Ukraine, including security, economic, and humanitarian assistance. They also discussed their coordinated efforts to impose&nbsp;severe costs and consequences to hold Russia accountable while working to maintain global economic stability, including with regard to energy prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Joining President Biden on the call were Prime Minister Trudeau of Canada, European Commission President von der Leyen, European Council President Michel, President Macron of France, Chancellor Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Draghi of Italy, Prime Minister Kishida of Japan, NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg, President Duda of Poland, President Iohannis of Romania, and Prime Minister Johnson of the United Kingdom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Highlight Clean Energy Manufacturing and Deployment Investments that Cut Consumer Costs, Strengthen U.S. Energy Sector, and Create Good-Paying&#160;Jobs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-highlight-clean-energy-manufacturing-and-deployment-investments-that-cut-consumer-costs-strengthen-u-s-energy-sector-and-create-good-paying-jobs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden campaigned on a bold vision of tackling the climate crisis with the urgency that science demands by seizing the opportunity to build a strong domestic energy sector that can manufacture and deploy clean energy for the benefit of all Americans—with lower costs for families, good-paying jobs for workers, and healthier air and cleaner&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden campaigned on a bold vision of tackling the climate crisis with the urgency that science demands by seizing the opportunity to build a strong domestic energy sector that can manufacture and deploy clean energy for the benefit of all Americans—with lower costs for families, good-paying jobs for workers, and healthier air and cleaner water for communities.</p>



<p>Since Day One, he has delivered. After rejoining the Paris Agreement, restoring scientific integrity, and reinvigorating U.S. leadership on the world stage, President Biden <strong>mobilized every federal agency to achieve groundbreaking goals:</strong> reducing greenhouse gas emissions 50-52% below 2005 levels in 2030, reaching 100% carbon pollution-free electricity by 2035, and delivering 40% of the benefits from federal investments in climate and clean energy to disadvantaged communities. The President formed the first-ever National Climate Task Force, bringing together Cabinet leaders to drive decisive action toward those goals.</p>



<p>Alongside historic executive actions, President Biden also <strong>made climate action and environmental justice a centerpiece of his Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</strong>—which includes the largest federal investments ever in upgrading the power grid, improving public transit and investing in zero-emission transit and school buses, installing a nationwide EV charging network, cleaning up legacy pollution, delivering clean water and replacing lead pipes, demonstrating innovative climate technologies, and increasing climate resilience to safeguard against extreme weather, which last year caused more than $145 billion in damages from the biggest 20 disasters alone.</p>



<p><strong><u>CALLING ON CONGRESS TO DELIVER</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden knows that we need to move even faster to combat climate change—and that to meet the moment and fully seize the economic opportunity in front of us, Congress must act. <strong>In his first State of the Union address, the President will call on Congress to deliver on a legislative&nbsp;agenda for clean energy and climate action </strong>that has overwhelming support from the American people—Republicans, Democrats, and Independents.</p>



<p>Specifically, the President will lift up the benefits we can secure for American consumers, companies, and communities by enacting critical investments and tax credits for domestic clean energy manufacturing and deployment. He will also highlight how the investments and tax credits would cut energy costs for American families an average of $500 per year.</p>



<p>As part of the President’s unwavering support for climate solutions, these investments will reduce emissions, lower costs for families, create good-paying jobs for workers, and advance environmental justice.</p>



<p><strong><u>BOLD ACTIONS TWO MONTHS INTO 2022</u></strong></p>



<p>As the President works with Congress to deliver on this legislative agenda, he will continue taking decisive and bold action—building on the surge of momentum he has spearheaded to tackle the climate crisis. <strong>During just the first two months of 2022</strong>, the Biden-Harris Administration:</p>



<ul><li>Announced <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/12/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-races-to-deploy-clean-energy-that-creates-jobs-and-lowers-costs/">actions</a> from seven agencies on <strong>clean energy deployment</strong>, including new investments and partnerships to advance offshore wind; steps to fast-track solar, onshore wind, and geothermal energy on public lands; and the “Building a Better Grid” initiative to build out long-distance transmission lines and unlock clean energy resources.</li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-launches-coalition-of-states-and-local-governments-to-strengthen-building-performance-standards/">Launched</a> the <strong>Building Performance Standards Coalition</strong> with more than 30 state and local governments to reduce emissions, create good-paying union jobs in energy efficiency and electrification, and lower energy bills, with federal assistance for policy design and implementation.</li><li>Built on the<strong> Methane Emissions Reduction Action Plan</strong> by <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/31/fact-sheet-biden-administration-tackles-super-polluting-methane-emissions/">announcing</a> an initial $1.15 billion to clean up orphaned oil and gas wells, <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-administration-announces-nearly-725-million-create-good-paying-union-jobs">$725 million to reclaim abandoned mine lands</a>, a new interagency initiative on measurement and monitoring of methane and other greenhouse emissions, enforcement efforts to minimize methane emissions from pipeline systems, and more.&nbsp;</li><li>Advanced America’s <strong>electric vehicle future</strong>, standing with CEOs to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-ensuring-future-is-made-in-america/">announce</a> new manufacturing facilities for electric vehicles, batteries, and chargers and issuing state allocations and guidance for the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s $5 billion National Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Formula Program.</li><li>Convened a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/09/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-roundtable-with-ceos-of-electric-utilities-to-discuss-his-build-back-better-agenda/">roundtable</a> of <strong>electric utility CEOs</strong> to discuss their support for Congressional investments in clean energy to reduce costs for families, make the power grid more resilient and reliable, and advance American innovation, job creation, and economic competitiveness.</li><li>Took <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-advances-cleaner-industrial-sector-to-reduce-emissions-and-reinvigorate-american-manufacturing/">major steps</a> to <strong>reduce industrial emissions and advance clean manufacturing</strong>, including clean hydrogen investments, the first Buy Clean Task Force for federal purchasing of low-carbon construction materials, progress on carbon-based trade policies to reward clean steel and aluminum manufacturing, guidance on responsible deployment of Carbon Capture, Utilization, and Sequestration technologies, and new initiatives to ensure that industrial innovation benefits American workers and communities.</li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2022/02/18/ceq-publishes-draft-climate-and-economic-justice-screening-tool-key-component-in-the-implementation-of-president-bidens-justice40-initiative/">Released</a> the <strong>Climate and Economic Justice Screening Tool</strong> for public feedback, to help agencies deliver benefits to disadvantaged communities and fulfill the President’s Justice40 commitment.</li><li>Announced <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/fact-sheet-securing-a-made-in-america-supply-chain-for-critical-minerals/">major investments</a> to secure a <strong>Made in America supply chain for critical minerals </strong>and sustainably source key inputs (including lithium and rare earth elements) for clean energy technologies like batteries, electric vehicles, wind turbines, and solar panels. This includes taking action to <a href="https://www.doi.gov/sites/doi.gov/files/biden-harris-administration-fundamental-principles-for-domestic-mining-reform.pdf">update</a> outdated mining regulations and laws to ensure that extraction and production adheres to strong environmental, labor, and community and Tribal engagement standards.</li><li><a href="https://www.energy.gov/policy/securing-americas-clean-energy-supply-chain">Released</a> <strong><em>America’s Strategy to Secure the Supply Chain for a Robust Clean Energy Transition,</em> </strong>a first-of-its-kind energy sector industrial base strategy, which includes the creation of a new Manufacturing and Energy Supply Chains Office at the Department of Energy to strengthen, secure, and modernize the nation’s energy infrastructure and support clean energy manufacturing jobs.</li><li>Held a <strong>record-shattering offshore wind auction</strong> in the New York Bight, with winning bids for six lease areas <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-sets-offshore-energy-records-437-billion-winning-bids-wind">totaling $4.37 billion</a>, signaling the arrival of a strong American industry that’s here to stay. Innovative lease stipulations will promote projects built with union labor and Made in America materials, and these projects will generate clean electricity to power millions of homes.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>HISTORIC YEAR OF PROGRESS</u></strong></p>



<p>This wave of climate action to kick off 2022 builds on historic progress President Biden achieved during his first year in office, when he:</p>



<ul><li>For the first time, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/22/fact-sheet-president-biden-sets-2030-greenhouse-gas-pollution-reduction-target-aimed-at-creating-good-paying-union-jobs-and-securing-u-s-leadership-on-clean-energy-technologies/">set</a> an official target to reach <strong>net-zero greenhouse gas emissions</strong>, economy-wide, by no later than 2050 and cut greenhouse gas pollution by more than half in 2030.</li><li><strong>Fast-tracked clean energy</strong>, setting <a href="https://cleanpower.org/blog/despite-a-global-pandemic-and-supply-chain-constraints-clean-power-has-record-year/">national records</a> with hundreds of new solar, wind, and storage projects—which are creating good-paying, union jobs and lowering energy costs.</li><li>Launched the <strong>American offshore wind industry</strong>, with the <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-approves-first-major-offshore-wind-project-us-waters">first approvals</a> of large-scale projects and <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-outlines-ambitious-offshore-wind-leasing-strategy">new lease areas</a> in the Atlantic and the Pacific.</li><li>Jumpstarted an <strong>electric transportation future</strong> that’s Made in America, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/05/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-steps-to-drive-american-leadership-forward-on-clean-cars-and-trucks/">uniting automakers and autoworkers</a> to get to 50% electric vehicle sales share in 2030 and spurring investments of over $100 billion in the American EV and battery manufacturing industry.</li><li>Tackled<strong> major sources of emissions</strong>, with actions to reduce super-polluting <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/23/fact-sheet-biden-administration-combats-super-pollutants-and-bolsters-domestic-manufacturing-with-new-programs-and-historic-commitments/">hydrofluorocarbon emissions</a> by 85% within 15 years, a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/US-Methane-Emissions-Reduction-Action-Plan-1.pdf">Methane Emissions Reduction Action Plan</a> with more than 40 actions across agencies, and the <a href="https://www.epa.gov/newsreleases/epa-finalizes-greenhouse-gas-standards-passenger-vehicles-paving-way-zero-emissions">strongest-ever passenger vehicle standards</a>.</li><li><strong>Transformed hundreds of federal programs</strong> to deliver on the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/26/fact-sheet-a-year-advancing-environmental-justice/">Justice40 Initiative</a> and drove more than $2.8 billion federal resources to support <a href="https://energycommunities.gov/the-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-tops-off-a-banner-year-of-investment-in-energy-communities/">economic revitalization in hard-hit energy communities</a>.</li><li>Established <strong>whole-of-government initiatives</strong> to: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-catalyzing-americas-clean-energy-economy-through-federal-sustainability/">lead by example</a> across the federal vehicle fleet, buildings, and procurement; <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-celebrates-expansion-of-locally-led-conservation-efforts-in-first-year-of-america-the-beautiful-initiative/">conserve 30% of U.S. lands and waters</a> by 2030; and build resilience to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/20/fact-sheet-biden-administration-mobilizes-to-protect-workers-and-communities-from-extreme-heat/">extreme heat</a>, <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/white-house-launches-drought-relief-working-group-address-urgency-western-water-crisis">drought</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-acts-to-address-the-growing-wildfire-threat/">wildfires</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2021/08/27/readout-of-the-first-white-house-flood-resilience-interagency-working-group-meeting-on-implementation-of-the-federal-flood-risk-management-standard/">floods</a>, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ceq/news-updates/2021/07/30/readout-of-the-white-house-coastal-resilience-interagency-working-group-convening/">coastal impacts</a>.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on New Economic Restrictive Measures on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/28/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-new-economic-restrictive-measures-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 7:04 A.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining us early this morning.&#160; This is a background press call to discuss an update on the Russia economic restrictive measures that we announced on Saturday with Allies and partners. &#160; This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” And&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>7:04 A.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining us early this morning.&nbsp; This is a background press call to discuss an update on the Russia economic restrictive measures that we announced on Saturday with Allies and partners. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” And the content of this call are embargoed until 7:30 a.m. Eastern.</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, the speakers on this call are [senior administration officials].&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to take &#8212; we&#8217;re going to have some remarks at the top and then just take a few questions at the end.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Good morning, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll kick off and then hand it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve been saying it as clearly as we can: This is an unjustified, unprovoked, and premeditated war of choice by Putin and that, alongside Allies and partners across the world, we would make this choice a strategic failure for Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We said if Putin continued to escalate, we would escalate.&nbsp; We said all options are on the table, including the most severe sanctions ever contemplated against Russia.&nbsp; We said that as we implement these costs, we would impose them in an historic and unprecedented show of coordination with countries across the world that wish to defend the core principles that underpin peace and security.</p>



<p>And so, that&#8217;s the context in which our actions to sanction the Russian Central Bank should be seen.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing exactly what we said we’d do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I&#8217;ve mentioned before, no country is sanctions-proof when we act together.&nbsp; Our sanctioning of the Russian Central Bank, which we&#8217;re taking with Germany, France, the UK, Italy, Japan, Canada, the European Union, and others &#8212; with the culmination of months for planning and preparation across our respective governments; across technical, diplomatic, and political channels, including at the highest levels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We were ready, and that&#8217;s what allowed us to act within days, not weeks or months, of Putin’s escalation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to emphasize the importance of relationships in taking this collective action.&nbsp; It takes trust and solidarity to sanction the central bank of a one and a half trillion-dollar economy, multiples larger than Iran’s or Venezuela’s.</p>



<p>We built that trust and solidarity over time in dozens of phone calls, meetings, and video conferences since November.</p>



<p>With respect to the impact this action will deliver:</p>



<p>As I mentioned, no &#8212; no country is sanctions-proof.&nbsp; Putin’s war chest of $630 billion in reserves only matters if he can use it to defend his currency, specifically by selling those reserves in exchange for buying the ruble.&nbsp; And after today&#8217;s actions, that will no longer be possible, and Fortress Russia will be exposed as a myth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Already, you&#8217;ve seen the Russian Central Bank more than doubled its policy rate this morning to 20 percent.&nbsp; That’s the highest in almost two decades.&nbsp; The ruble is in freefall, and soon you’ll see inflation spike and economic activity contract.</p>



<p>This is a vicious feedback loop that&#8217;s triggered by Putin’s own choices and accelerated by his own aggression.&nbsp; <a>It&#8217;s a very raw deal Putin is giving to the Russian people as the world disconnects Russia from the global financial system and all its benefits, but it&#8217;s exactly what we said would be the consequences of his actions.</a></p>



<p>At the same time that we&#8217;re following through on our commitment to deliver overwhelming force, I want to emphasize that we and our Allies will continue to limit the impact back home.&nbsp; And in particular, we&#8217;ll continue to scope our measures to allow for steady energy supplies to global markets &#8212; [senior administration official] will say more on this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And lastly, I want to remind everyone that, today, we’ll also fully block the Russian Direct Investment Fund and its CEO, Kirill Dmitriev.&nbsp; This fund and its leadership are symbols of deep-seated Russian corruption and influence peddling globally.&nbsp; Some of you may know it spun off from V.E.B. &#8212; Putin’s slush fund bank that we fully blocked last week &#8212; and it&#8217;s known to be intimately connected to kleptocracy at the highest levels of the Russian government.</p>



<p>This action will also limit RDIF’s ability to leverage corrupt ties to universities and organizations in the U.S. and the West more broadly.</p>



<p>Let me stop there and turn it to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, all of you, for joining. I want to briefly walk through the impact of these actions and why we&#8217;re taking them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The steps we&#8217;re taking today are part of the strategy that the President asked Secretary Yellen to design in order to hold Russia accountable for an invasion in the Ukraine.</p>



<p>Our strategy, to put it simply, is to make sure that the Russian economy goes backwards as long as President Putin decides to go forward with his invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;re accomplishing this objective by taking a variety of steps targeting Russia&#8217;s financial institutions, elites, and now the Russian Central Bank.</p>



<p>These are all sources of the wealth the Kremlin draws on to fund destabilizing activity.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s actions represent the most significant actions that the U.S. Treasury has taken against an economy of this size and assets of this size.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would &#8212; I want to point out that what also makes this action significant is not just the amount of assets or the size of the country we&#8217;re targeting, but the speed at which our partners and Allies have worked with us to enact this response.</p>



<p>[Senior administration official] is right that we&#8217;ve been coordinating with these Allies since November on actions related to Russia.&nbsp; But since the beginning of President Biden&#8217;s term, we&#8217;ve been working closely with these Allies on various issues related to the international financial system, which built the trust that was necessary for us to take these actions today.</p>



<p><a>Now, a few things to note about the economic impact on Russia of today&#8217;s announcements: It&#8217;s clear that when Russia prepared for an invasion of Ukraine, they were counting on using their Central Bank assets to mitigate any economic hardship that came from sanctions.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Russia has hundreds of billions of dollars of assets in jurisdictions all over the world.&nbsp; And ever since the leaders made their announcement on Saturday, the Russian Central Bank has been attempting to bring those assets back to Russia or to safe havens so they can be used to support their economy and their currency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today&#8217;s announcement to prohibit transactions with the Central Bank of Russia and the National Wealth Fund will significantly hinder their ability to do that and inhibit their access to hundreds of billions of dollars in assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From our actions alone, they will not be able to access assets that are either in the United States or in U.S. dollars. And as you&#8217;ve seen, the EU has taken actions that prohibit Central Bank&#8217;s transactions in their jurisdiction as well, and we expect the rest of the &#8212; our G7 partners to take similar actions.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important to note that with today&#8217;s actions, we&#8217;re also constricting Russia’s access of those they might turn to for a bailout since we&#8217;re also targeting its Ministry of Finance and its rainy-day fund, the National Wealth Fund.&nbsp; And our directive also makes clear that Russia can&#8217;t turn to other banks or companies and use them as agents to evade these prohibitions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a result of today&#8217;s coordinated announcement, Russia will experience even further economic consequences.&nbsp; They will be forced to deplete their limited domestic rainy-day fund far more quickly; experience a weakening of their currency, making funding their war of choice much more expensive; create a real squeeze on Russia&#8217;s ability to fund their priorities like invasion in Ukraine; constrict the Central Bank&#8217;s routine functions and make financing more difficult since it is locked out of using foreign reserves; and exacerbate liquidity issues.</p>



<p>As with our other actions, we&#8217;ve been calibrated and deliberate to ensure our sanctions cost maximum consequences for Russia, while mitigating harm to America and our partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President made very clear to us it was critical that we target our sanctions in a way that would impose costs on Russia if they continued the invasion, while mitigating those costs on the American people, on our Allies and partners.&nbsp; And consistent with that, Treasury will issue a general license to authorize certain energy-related transactions by exempting energy-related transactions for preventing unnecessary harm for consumers and preventing spikes in prices that would only pad the pockets of President Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I mentioned at the top, these are serious consequences for Russia&#8217;s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, and we wouldn&#8217;t hesitate to level more if necessary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I said in the beginning, our objective is to make sure that the Russian economy goes backwards if President Putin decides to continue to go forward with an invasion in Ukraine. And we have the tools to continue to do that.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll end my remarks and hand it back to our host.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Could we please queue up the directions to ask a question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, good morning.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Can you confirm that basically all the assets of the Central Bank, National Wealth Fund, the Finance Ministry are essentially frozen as a result of this action?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then can you say a word about the kind of coordination with the Allies?&nbsp; Did they move forward on this more quickly than you might have been expecting, or was this all already scripted ahead of time?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to take the first and I can &#8212; I can do the second?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;m happy to do that.&nbsp; So what we&#8217;re doing today in the United States is that we are prohibiting transactions with the Russian Central Bank in dollars.&nbsp; So what that means is that if a U.S. financial institution has Russian Central Bank assets, they can&#8217;t do anything with them; they are stuck in that institution.&nbsp; If an institution outside of the United States has dollars for the Russian Central Bank, they can&#8217;t do anything with them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those funds are immobilized.&nbsp; And the reality is that like any central bank around the world, the Russian Central Bank holds a great number of their assets in dollars.&nbsp; But in addition to dollars, they&#8217;re clearly diversified and they hold assets in euros, in yens, in pound sterling. &nbsp;And because of the work that we&#8217;ve done in coordinating, it means that those assets are also immobilized and unavailable for their use.</p>



<p>But let me turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk a little bit about the work we&#8217;ve done over the course of the last several months to coordinate with our Allies and partners so we&#8217;d be in a position to take an action like the one that we&#8217;re announcing today.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, and I&#8217;ll &#8212; I&#8217;ll touch on the first question as well, because we always thought of Russia&#8217;s Central Bank reserves &#8212; its $630 billion of foreign reserves &#8212; as an insurance policy for Russia.&nbsp; And that insurance policy was meant for exactly a circumstance like this.&nbsp; In other words, if their currency was plummeting, they could use those reserves to support the ruble and to defend it.&nbsp; And so, what this &#8212; what this action does is it removes, it negates, it nullifies that insurance policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;ve been talking about taking this action for months.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been conceiving of the circumstances in which it would get deployed, the mechanisms by which we could apply it, the coordination that will be required to give it force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, as we saw the events unfold last week, we sent clear signals to the world about our willingness to take the most severe actions in our toolkit, and we deployed them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very much for doing this.&nbsp; I just wanted to ask if you could comment on anything related to, you know, action with Belarus &#8212; any future sanctions action &#8212; and reports that they&#8217;re preparing to get involved in this conflict.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Alan &#8212; [senior administration official], I&#8217;ll just start with this one &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re watching those events very carefully.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve said if &#8212; to the extent Belarus continues to aid and abet Russia&#8217;s aggression in Ukraine, they will also face consequences.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already rolled out some of those measures.&nbsp; Those costs will continue to ratchet much higher.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering if you could talk a little bit about the timing of this.&nbsp; You&#8217;re taking this action today.&nbsp; How quickly will it actually kick in?&nbsp; Is there any danger of Russia taking actions before these measures actually go into effect that would, you know, make these actions not as forceful and damaging to Russia?&nbsp; And how quickly do you expect that these measures will actually have an impact on the Russian economy and potentially start to change Putin&#8217;s calculus here?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Let me just make this clear that these actions will be effective immediately.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking to you now because we wanted to put these actions in place before our markets opened, because what we learned over the course of the weekend from our Allies and partners was that the Russian Central Bank was attempting to move assets and there would be a great deal of asset flight starting on Monday morning from institutions around the world.</p>



<p><a>So, we took these ac- &#8212; we&#8217;re taking these actions in a way that they will be effective immediately.&nbsp; And I think the thing &#8212; to [senior administration official’s] earlier point, the Russian government, after the actions we took in 2014 &#8212; and I was here in 2014 when we took those actions &#8212; decided that they were going to try and build a war chest to try and defend against the actions that we may take if they were to take further actions in Ukraine or elsewhere in the world.</a></p>



<p>We knew that this existed and we knew that, ultimately, one of the things that we would need to do to ensure that our sanctions would be effective is at some point take &#8212; go after that war chest.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;ve done today.</p>



<p>And you &#8212; you asked a question as to how soon will this be effective, and we&#8217;re seeing the effect of that today: The Russian stock market isn’t open.&nbsp; The ruble has depreciated a great deal.&nbsp; Russia is taking unprecedented actions to try and support their economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what I would say is that we have always thought about how we would escalate as President Putin moved forward with the invasion in Ukraine.&nbsp; And we continue to have additional steps that we could take that will continue to have an impact on the Russian economy, because as they move forward with the invasion, we&#8217;re committed to working with our Allies and partners to make sure that their economy continues to move backwards so that they have less money to fund their projections of power going forward.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll just &#8212; I&#8217;ll just add a little bit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, as [senior administration official] said perfectly right, the &#8212; these actions are immediately effective, and the impact is also immediate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I think the ruble is already more than 30 percent weaker today<a>.&nbsp; The Central Bank already more than doubled its policy rate from 9 and a half percent </a>to 20 percent.&nbsp; There&#8217;s talk about Russia imposing capital controls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That &#8212; these choices that Russia has been forced into are a reflection of the fact that inflation is now very likely to spike, purchasing power is likely to plummet, investment is likely to plummet.&nbsp; These are &#8212; this is a negative and vicious feedback loop that Putin has triggered.</p>



<p>And as to whether it affects his calculus: I mean, all we can do is make sure this is a strategic failure.&nbsp; And the evidence of this failure is becoming more clear by each moment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, there.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Can you say how much of the $630 billion is affected by the U.S. moves?&nbsp; In particular &#8212; in other words, how much of that 630 is either, I guess, linked to U.S. companies or held in U.S. dollars?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And can I ask &#8212; on a separate but related issue on the measures with regards to SWIFT: Can you give us an update on the latest on that and, in particular, whether you&#8217;re considering adding restrictions to new banks beyond those amounts previously?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Let me start with &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; What I can tell you is that &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, do you want &#8212; I’ll take Central Bank, [senior administration official], and handover SWIFT to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, great.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, what we know is that the Russian Central Bank, like all central banks around the world, has their assets diversified, with hundreds of billions of dollars located outside of Russia in central banks, in financial institutions around the world.</p>



<p>After the invasion of Crimea, Russia decided to move a great deal of its assets out of the United States &#8212; but to keep them in dollars but to move them into other jurisdictions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we&#8217;ve done today is not only preventing them from using those dollars in the United States, but preventing them from being able to use those dollars in other places, like Europe or Japan, to defend their currency and prop up their institutions.</p>



<p>And our goal was to make sure that not only would they not have access to dollars, but also not have access to other currencies that would be critical to their ability to support their economy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why doing this in a multilateral way with our Allies and partners is so important and is so crippling for the Russian Central Bank, which is now struggling to figure out ways to continue to support its economy in the face of these sanctions.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the SWIFT question: We’re &#8212; we remain in close consultations with our EU partners to finalize the list of banks that will be cut off from the SWIFT system.&nbsp; There are several banks that Europe and the U.S. have fully blocked; those will be the first ones considered.</p>



<p>Just as a regulatory matter, the list of banks will get finalized by the EU because SWIFT is under Belgian authority. And so, once the list is finalized, the Europeans will issue a directive that will go to Belgium for a vote of the SWIFT Board of Directors and then the de-SWIFTing will be complete.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Quick question is: Is the Bank for International Settlements part of this?&nbsp; And also, is the Swiss government part of this?</p>



<p>And as a broader question: Are you worried about any kind of ripple effects for the financial system?&nbsp; The &#8212; you know, are dollar funding markets likely to come under pressure from this?&nbsp; What are some of the possible kind of ripple effects and blowbacks?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, Neil, let me start with the second part of your question.&nbsp; I think one of the things that we&#8217;ve been doing in addition to coordinating and collaborating with our Allies and partners is telling &#8212; is telling our regulators the actions that we&#8217;ve been contemplating.</p>



<p>Since the end of last year, the Secretary and I have been spending time with regulators, both talking to them about the actions that the President is contemplating in order to better understand some of the impacts that you just mentioned and working with our team to make sure that we scenario plan for these actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With regard to the Bank of International Settlements and other institutions, our prohibition applies to &#8212; any U.S. dollar that exists in an institution around the world is now &#8212; cannot be transacted with the Russian Central Bank.&nbsp; That is applicable to international institutions, as well as foreign countries, as well as financial institutions &#8212; foreign financial institutions that have dollars.&nbsp; So, effective immediately as &#8212; when this directive goes out, transactions with the Russian Central Bank in dollars by anyone is prohibited.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing the call.&nbsp; I guess this first one is for [senior administration official].&nbsp; On the carveouts, you know, including all the banks that are being sanctioned, can you share what percentage of the carveouts, particularly for energy &#8212; what percentage of those make up the overall transactions?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, I guess, for [senior administration official]: I wanted to ask &#8212; you mentioned again &#8212; or maybe it was [senior administration official]; I apologize &#8212; that, again, it will miti- &#8212; and energy impacts will be mitigated.&nbsp; Considering, you know, the moves in Germany and just support in Europe overall, is there potential or is it being considered to take a more stronger action against Russia&#8217;s energy sector?&nbsp;</p>



<p>But first, the percentage of the carveouts if you could.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;&nbsp; So the energy market is an important one, and it&#8217;s a place where Russia plays a major role.&nbsp; But the truth is that, for these financial institutions, that the &#8212; they are doing billions of transactions each day, many of which are not energy related.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to be frank, the fact that it will take them time to figure out how to segregate those actions will lead to additional disruption of the Russian economy.</p>



<p>Look, while the carveout will make sure that people are able to get &#8212; to make energy payments, it&#8217;s not going to stop the &#8212; stop the impact that we&#8217;re seeing on the Russian economy.</p>



<p>Today, you&#8217;ve seen European headlines talking about the fact that there&#8217;s been a run on Sberbank, Russia’s European affiliate, which is under pressure because of deposit withdrawals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, part of what we&#8217;ve done is, when we looked at the Russian financial system, we decided to take a variety of actions against the top 10 institutions.&nbsp; We did some &#8212; we did some debt and equity blocking.&nbsp; We did some full blocking.&nbsp; And we did some dollar-clearing blocking in order to make sure that the Russian Central Bank wasn’t in a position where they could find a one solution to each one of these challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for the full-blocked institutions, they&#8217;re not able &#8212; their assets have been frozen.&nbsp; For those where dollar clearing has been blocked, we&#8217;re starting to see runs on those institutions by depositors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in addition to the fact that we may have the energy carveout, which is providing the ability for energy to flow &#8212; energy to flow and to help mitigate some of the risks both to Europe but also to the global energy markets, the variety of actions we&#8217;ve taken are still ensuring that these &#8212; each one of these institutions are under a variety of different types of pressure, which, because of the actions we&#8217;re taking against the Central Bank today, the Central Bank is going to be unable to mitigate in a meaningful way.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the &#8212; on the second question, Franco: We have a &#8212; we have a collective interest in ensuring that the current supply of energy to the world remains steady, A, because we want to support the global economic recovery, but, B, because we don&#8217;t want prices to spike for the benefit of President Putin as a major energy exporter.</p>



<p>Over the long term, though &#8212; and this is important &#8212; we also have a collective interest to degrade Russia&#8217;s capacity to be a leading energy supplier over the long term.&nbsp; And over the long term, that requires critical technology inputs that allow &#8212; that would allow Russia to remain a leader in energy production.&nbsp; And there you&#8217;ve already seen some actions taken by the EU and a scenario we&#8217;re exploring actively.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining today.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And the embargo lifts in about a minute.&nbsp; Have a good rest of your day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>  7:30 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Background on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Remarks on the Economy During His First State of The Union&#160;Address</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-background-on-president-bidens-remarks-on-the-economy-during-his-first-state-of-the-union-address/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden ran for office with a new economic vision: to grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out, not the top down. On Tuesday, the President will make a strong case that the Biden-Harris economic strategy is producing historic results, and lay out his plan to tackle the economic challenges ahead.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden ran for office with a new economic vision: to grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out, not the top down. On Tuesday, the President will make a strong case that the Biden-Harris economic strategy is producing historic results, and lay out his plan to tackle the economic challenges ahead. He will underscore that during his first year in office, due in large part to the American Rescue Plan, entrepreneurship and business investment rebounded, the economy achieved its fastest job growth in American history, the fastest economic growth in nearly 40 years, and a faster recovery than every other advanced economy. And, he will emphasize that this progress is occurring amidst an historic shift from the old, outdated trickle-down approach to one that centers on workers, families, and small businesses.</p>



<p>During his first State of the Union Address, the President will also make clear that there is more work to do to rebuild the economy towards resilience, security, and sustainability. Too many families continue to feel the squeeze of higher costs. The President will make clear that price increases that become entrenched are pernicious, and eat away at the economic progress the country is making. The President will lay out his plan to lower costs for American families while continuing an historically strong economic recovery by:<br><br></p>



<ul><li>Making more things in America, strengthening our supply chains, and moving goods faster and cheaper;<br><br></li><li>Reducing the cost of everyday expenses working families face and reducing the deficit;<br><br></li><li>Promoting fair competition to lower prices, help small businesses thrive, and protect consumers; and<br><br></li><li>Eliminating barriers to good-paying jobs for workers all across America.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Making more things in America, strengthening our supply chains, and moving goods faster and cheaper:</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden will make clear that he believes one of the best ways to lower costs over the long run is to increase the productive capacity of our economy—put simply, to make more things in America with more American workers contributing and earning a good living. He will describe the emerging manufacturing comeback, with American companies betting on America again because of the Administration’s commitment to domestic industrial revitalization and technological development. He will note that in just the last year, the economy added 375,000 manufacturing jobs and companies announced nearly $200 billion in investments for semiconductor, electric vehicle, battery, and critical mineral production and manufacturing in the United States. He will recount how Intel recently announced a new $20 billion factory outside of Columbus, Ohio that will create 7,000 construction jobs and another 3,000 permanent jobs – another sign of the strength of the American economy.</p>



<p>President Biden will also announce specific goals for implementation of his landmark Bipartisan Infrastructure law (BIL), a once-in-a-generation investment in our nation’s economic competitiveness that will strengthen supply chains and move goods to market faster and more efficiently, encouraging more companies to choose America. Over the next year:<br><br></p>



<ul><li>States, territories, Tribes and local governments will start to improve 65,000 miles of roads and 1,500 bridges with federal funding, representing a 44% and 50% increase respectively from average annual improvement levels over the past six years.<br><br></li><li>The Federal Aviation Administration will be able to invest in over 600 airport infrastructure projects, including preserving 400 pavement projects on taxiways and runways.<br><br></li><li>Communities will invest in an estimated 15,000 new buses, ferries and subway cars, improving commutes for working Americans, families, and students across the country and reducing greenhouse emissions.<br><br></li><li>The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers will advance over 500 projects across 52 states and territories to strengthen supply chains, improve waterways, and reduce flooding.<br><br></li><li>The Environmental Protection Agency will work with state and local governments to fund more than 400 new water projects from replacing lead service lines to improving drinking water systems.<br><br></li><li>States, Tribes, and other partners will use BIL funds to reclaim over 15,000 acres of abandoned mine lands, as well as launch new reclamation efforts that will ultimately address tens of thousands of additional acres across the country.<br><br></li><li>The Interior Department’s new Orphan Well Program will start work plugging, capping, and remediating over 8,000 abandoned oil &amp; gas well sites in communities across the country.<br><br></li><li>The Interior Department will increase its work to reduce the risk of wildfires to communities by more than 30 percent – removing over 300,000 acres of burnable fuels in the places where communities and wildlands meet – as well as the start of work to reduce wildfire risk on an additional 250,000 acres across the country.<br><br></li><li>The Department of Energy will take steps to launch a first-of-its kind $140 million demonstration facility to extract and separate rare earth elements and other critical minerals from coal ash, mine tailings, acid drainage, and other legacy fossil fuel waste to sustainably produce materials key to next-generation clean energy technologies.<br><br></li><li>The Department of Energy will make available nearly $3 billion to bolster domestic manufacturing of advanced batteries for electric vehicles and energy storage.</li></ul>



<p>To build on these investments and spur more private-sector investment in the United States, the President will also call on Congress to send him bipartisan competitiveness legislation like the COMPETES and USICA bills that have passed the House and the Senate to invest in innovation, manufacturing, and economic development capacity across all of America so America can outcompete China and the rest of the world in the industries of the future.</p>



<p><strong><u>Reducing the cost of everyday expenses working families face:</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden will call on Congress to send him legislation that lowers costs of everyday expenses working families face and lowers the deficit by rewarding work, not wealth. He will lay out specific, practical measures that would reduce costs for families right now, including prescription drug costs and health care premiums, child care and pre-k costs, and energy costs. He will point to the other ideas he has proposed on areas ranging from housing to care for seniors and people with disabilities to higher education affordability to direct tax relief for families. These efforts build on the support provided in the American Rescue Plan that has helped reduce the cost of health care, helped more than 5000 universities and community colleges make higher education more affordable, made work pay better for low-income workers through an expanded Earned Income Tax Credit, and provided historic middle class tax relief for tens of millions of working families through an expanded Child Tax Credit.</p>



<p>The President will make clear that we can lower costs while lowering the deficit by rewarding work, not wealth. He will outline proposals to make sure corporations and the wealthiest Americans pay their fair share, while making clear that no one making under $400,000 a year should see their taxes increased.</p>



<p>The President will call on Congress to send him a bill that lowers costs and lowers the deficit without delay. American families need relief from higher costs, and they need it now.</p>



<p><em><br></em><strong><u>Promoting fair competition to lower prices, help small businesses thrive, and protect consumers:</u></strong><em><u></u></em></p>



<p>President Biden will explain that we can also lower costs by promoting fair competition in the U.S. economy. The Administration has taken decisive actions in the first year to stop the trend of corporate consolidation, increase competition, and deliver concrete benefits to America’s consumers, workers, farmers, and small businesses. He will also announce new actions the Biden-Harris Administration is taking this year to tackle some of the most pressing competition and consumer protection problems across our economy. Specifically, he will announce new steps to:<br><br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Lower consumer prices and level the playing field for American businesses in ocean shipping.</strong> The President will explain that most traded goods—everything from the housewares you buy online to the agricultural products that American farmers market overseas—are transported by oceangoing vessels. However, the ocean shipping industry is now dominated by just a small number of giant, foreign-owned companies. Three global alliances—groups of ocean carriers that work together—now control 80% of global container ship capacity and 95% on the critical East-West trade lines. And, since the beginning of the pandemic, these carriers have been increasing shipping costs through higher rates and fees. The President will note that the foreign carriers are now seeing record profits, while prices for American consumers and businesses have risen. To combat this problem, the President will announce steps to lower consumer prices and level the playing field for American businesses in ocean shipping, including launching a new Federal Maritime Commission and Department of Justice initiative to promote competition in the ocean freight transportation system. He will also note that the Federal Maritime Commission is ramping up its oversight of the global shipping industry to address complaints about the unfair fees the carriers charge to American businesses. <em>Read the full Biden-Harris Plan to Lower Consumer Prices and Level the Playing Field in Ocean Shipping here.</em><strong><br><br></strong></li><li><strong>Protect seniors and other nursing home residents by cracking down on unsafe nursing homes. </strong>The President will explain that while the federal government spends tens of billions of taxpayer dollars on nursing homes annually, these federal funds too often flow to nursing homes with bad track records and dangerous conditions. He will explain that <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/over-200000-residents-and-staff-in-long-term-care-facilities-have-died-from-covid-19/">200,000 residents</a> and staff in nursing homes have died from COVID-19, representing nearly 23% of all COVID-19 deaths in the United States. He will also stress that despite well-documented, widespread health and safety violations, there has been little or no accountability. To protect seniors and crack down on unsafe nursing homes, President Biden will call on Congress to provide nearly $500 million to CMS Survey and Certification, a 24% increase, to support health and safety inspections at nursing homes. He will also announce that the Biden-Harris Administration will, among other new initiatives, establish a new minimum staffing ratio to protect residents, expand penalties for poor performing nursing homes and beef up scrutiny, improve transparency and Americans’ ability to comparison shop for the best home, strengthen value-based payment to ensure taxpayers pay for quality care, and continue to provide COVID-19 testing and vaccinations at nursing homes across the country.<em> Read the full Biden-Harris Plan to Protect Seniors by Cracking Down on Unsafe Nursing Homes here.</em><br><br></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Eliminating barriers to good-paying jobs for workers all across America:</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden will reflect on one of the strongest labor market recoveries in American history. Specifically, the President will note that during his first year in office, the economy added more than 6.6 million jobs; the unemployment rate fell at its fastest pace on record; the number of number of workers filing for unemployment insurance declined by more than 70 percent; and millions of Americans have entered and reentered the labor force, with the largest increase in the labor force participation rate in more than 25 years. He will highlight the important role that the American Rescue Plan played in positioning employers to hire and workers to rejoin the labor force and find higher quality jobs. Earlier this year, he directed the Secretary of Labor to work with states to reinstate work search requirements for unemployment insurance recipients.<br><br></p>



<p>To further our economic recovery and increase the productive capacity of our economy, the President will announce his Administration’s plan to ensure everyone who wants to work should have the opportunity to find a high-quality job. Specifically, he will express his support for:<br><br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Enacting the Protecting the Right to Organize Act.</strong> President Biden will express his firm belief that every worker in every state must have a free and fair choice to organize or join a union, and the right to bargain collectively with their employer, without fear of intimidation, coercion, threats, and anti-union propaganda. He will reiterate that the middle class built America and unions built the middle class. And, he will emphasize that empowering workers is central to the Biden-Harris strategy to grow our economy from the bottom up and the middle out. The President will call on Congress to pass the Richard L. Trumka Protecting the Right to Organize (PRO) Act and the Public Service Freedom to Negotiate Act, ensuring that more private-sector workers and many more public-sector workers nationwide have a genuine right to organize and bargain collectively.<br><br></li><li><strong>Expanding skills-based hiring and increasing access to registered apprenticeships and training. </strong>President Biden will reiterate his commitment to creating pathways to the middle class for all Americans. He will stress that millions of Americans without a college degree are needlessly disadvantaged in the pursuit of good jobs, even when they have the skills and knowledge employers need. To support skills-based hiring, President Biden will announce that his Administration will explore using federal and procurement dollars to by hire based on skills rather than educational qualifications alone, , including through boosting hiring of people from Registered Apprenticeships and labor-management partnership training programs. Additionally, the Administration remains committed to strengthening the pipeline for more underserved communities to access these opportunities. As an example, the Administration has supported and increased access to quality trucking jobs by expanding Registered Apprenticeship programs for drivers; and developing more seamless paths for veterans and underrepresented communities, such as women, to access good driving jobs. He will state that the Administration is supporting and challenging employers to move towards skill-based hiring, including through a new budget proposal to invest in skills-based hiring research tools and technical assistance. This effort builds on the American Rescue Plan’s critical workforce investments in the past year – with more than half of states already committing Fiscal Recovery Funds to training and apprenticeships and efforts to hire and retain critical workers – and catalyzing investments in place-based regional workforce strategies through the Commerce Department’s Good Jobs Challenge.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding programs in high-demand fields at Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs), Tribal Colleges and Universities (TCUs), and Minority-Serving Institutions (MSIs).</strong> President Biden will explain that research has found that HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs are vital to helping underrepresented students achieve economic mobility, including in STEM fields. However, he will also stress that these institutions have significantly fewer resources than other top colleges and universities, undermining their ability to grow and support more students. To address this persistent problem, and building on the progress made by the American Rescue Plan providing the largest investment through the Department of Education ever in these institutions, the President will call on Congress to expand existing institutional aid grants to HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs, which can be used by these institutions to strengthen their academic, administrative, and fiscal capabilities, including by creating or expanding educational programs in high-demand fields (e.g., STEM, computer sciences, nursing, and allied health).<br><br></li><li><strong>Providing up to more than $2,000 in additional assistance to low-income students by increasing the Pell Grant award. </strong>President Biden will note that broad access to education beyond high school is increasingly important for economic growth and competitiveness in the 21st century, but also remind us that higher education has become unaffordable for too many families. Over 6 million students depend on Pell Grants to finance their education, yet the amount of money in these grants has not kept up with the rising cost of college and DREAMers still do not have access. During his State of the Union Address, President Biden will call on Congress to increase the maximum Pell Grant award by more than $2,000.<br><br></li><li><strong>Supporting paycheck fairness. </strong>President Biden will note that women in the U.S. who work full-time, year-round are paid only 83 cents for every dollar paid to their male counterparts, on average. He will also express his belief that ensuring equal pay is essential to advancing America’s values of fairness and equity as well as our economic strength here at home and our competitiveness abroad. President Biden will use his State of the Union Address as an opportunity to call on Congress to pass the Paycheck Fairness Act, which will take important steps towards the goal of ending pay discrimination.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Raising the minimum wage to $15 per hour.</strong> President Biden will recount that throughout the pandemic, millions of American workers have put their lives on the line to keep their communities and country functioning, including the 40 percent of frontline workers who are people of color. The President will express his belief that hard-working Americans deserve sufficient wages to put food on the table and keep a roof over their heads, without having to work multiple jobs. The President already issued executive actions to ensure 370,000 federal employees and employees of federal contractors are paid a minimum of $15 per hour – because investing in workers also makes employers, including the government, work better and faster. The President will call on Congress to raise the minimum wage to $15 per hour, and end the tipped minimum wage and sub-minimum wage for people with disabilities so that workers across the country can have a little breathing room and provide opportunity for their families.<br><br></li><li><strong>Creating a national comprehensive paid family and medical leave program. </strong>President Biden will stress that nearly four of five private sector workers – and 90 percent of the lowest wage workers – have no access to paid family leave, which is a critical input for economic growth and competitiveness in the 21st century. He will call on Congress to pass comprehensive paid family and medical leave legislation so millions of American workers can take time to bond with a new child, care for a seriously ill loved one or heal from their own serious illness.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Protecting Seniors and People with Disabilities by Improving Safety and Quality of Care in the Nation’s Nursing&#160;Homes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-protecting-seniors-and-people-with-disabilities-by-improving-safety-and-quality-of-care-in-the-nations-nursing-homes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All people deserve to be treated with dignity and respect and to have access to quality medical care. And in no case should a health care facility be causing a patient harm. The President believes we must improve the quality of our nursing homes so that seniors, people with disabilities, and others living in nursing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>All people deserve to be treated with dignity and respect and to have access to quality medical care. And in no case should a health care facility be causing a patient harm. The President believes we must improve the quality of our nursing homes so that seniors, people with disabilities, and others living in nursing homes get the reliable, high-quality care they deserve. That’s why he is announcing a set of reforms—developed by and implemented through the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS)—that will improve the safety and quality of nursing home care, hold nursing homes accountable for the care they provide, and make the quality of care and facility ownership more transparent so that potential residents and their loved ones can make informed decisions about care.</p>



<p>To do this, the reforms the President is announcing will ensure that:</p>



<ul><li>every nursing home provides a sufficient number of staff who are adequately trained to provide high-quality care;</li><li>poorly performing nursing homes are held accountable for improper and unsafe care and immediately improve their services or are cut off from taxpayer dollars; and</li><li>the public has better information about nursing home conditions so that they can find the best available options.</li></ul>



<p>The pandemic has highlighted the tragic impact of substandard conditions at nursing homes, which are home to many of our most at-risk community members. More than 1.4 million people live in over 15,500 Medicare- and Medicaid-certified nursing homes across the nation. In the past two years, more than <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/over-200000-residents-and-staff-in-long-term-care-facilities-have-died-from-covid-19/">200,000 residents</a> and staff in nursing homes have died from COVID-19—nearly a quarter of all COVID-19 deaths in the United States.  </p>



<p>Despite the tens of billions of federal taxpayer dollars flowing to nursing homes each year, too many continue to provide poor, sub-standard care that leads to avoidable resident harm. In fact, failure to comply with Federal guidelines at nursing homes is widespread. The Government Accountability Office found that, from 2013 to 2017, <a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-20-576r.pdf">82% of all inspected nursing homes</a> had an infection prevention and control deficiency, including a lack of regular handwashing, that was identified through Medicare and Medicaid surveys. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Without decisive action now, these unacceptable conditions may get worse. Private equity firms have been buying up struggling nursing homes, and research shows that private equity-owned nursing homes tend to have significantly worse outcomes for residents. Private equity firms’ investment in nursing homes has <a href="https://www.ineteconomics.org/uploads/papers/WP_118-Appelbaum-and-Batt-2-rb-Clean.pdf">ballooned</a> from $5 billion in 2000 to more than $100 billion in 2018, with about <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2772306">5</a>% of all nursing homes now owned by private equity firms. Too often, the private equity model has put profits before people—a particularly dangerous model when it comes to the health and safety of vulnerable seniors and people with disabilities. <strong>Recent research has found that resident outcomes are significantly worse at private equity-owned nursing homes</strong>:</p>



<ul><li>A <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama-health-forum/fullarticle/2786442">recent study</a> found that residents in nursing homes acquired by private equity were 11.1% more likely to have a preventable emergency department visit and 8.7% more likely to experience a preventable hospitalization, when compared to residents of for-profit nursing homes not associated with private equity.</li><li><a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28474/w28474.pdf">One working paper</a> examining 18,000 nursing home facilities over a seventeen-year period found that private equity ownership increased excess mortality for residents by 10%, increased prescription of antipsychotic drugs for residents by 50%, decreased hours of frontline nursing staffing by 3%, and increased taxpayer spending per resident by 11%. That suggests an additional 20,150 lives lost as a result of private equity ownership.</li><li>Another <a href="https://ourfinancialsecurity.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/AFREF-NJ-Private-Equity-Nursing-Homes-Covid.pdf">study</a> found that private equity-backed nursing homes’ COVID-19 infection rate and death rate were 30% and 40% above statewide averages, respectively.</li></ul>



<p>Research also suggests that, <strong>despite depriving residents of quality care, private equity-owned nursing homes actually led to an </strong><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama-health-forum/fullarticle/2786442"><strong>uptick in Medicare costs</strong></a><strong>, too.</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new steps by Department of Health &amp; Human Services (HHS) through its Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), to improve the quality and safety of nursing homes, to protect vulnerable residents and the health care heroes who care for them, and to crack down on bad actors. </strong>The Administration is committed to these urgent actions as first steps toward fulfilling a broader commitment to ensure taxpayer dollars go toward the safe, adequate, and respectful care seniors and people with disabilities deserve—not to the pockets of predatory owners and operators who seek to maximize their profits at the expense of vulnerable residents’ health and safety.</p>



<p><strong>Ensuring Taxpayer Dollars Support Nursing Homes That Provide Safe, Adequate, and Dignified Care</strong></p>



<p>CMS is launching four new initiatives to ensure that residents get the quality care they need—and that taxpayers pay for. These initiatives will help ensure adequate staffing, dignity and safety in their accommodations, and quality care.</p>



<ul><li><em>Establish a Minimum Nursing Home Staffing Requirement</em>. The adequacy of a nursing home’s staffing is the measure most closely linked to the quality of care residents receive. For example, a <a href="https://agsjournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/jgs.16689">recent study</a> of one state’s nursing facilities found that increasing registered nurse staffing by just 20 minutes per resident day was associated with 22% fewer confirmed cases of COVID-19 and 26% fewer COVID-19 deaths. CMS intends to propose minimum standards for staffing adequacy that nursing homes must meet. CMS will conduct a new research study to determine the level and type of staffing needed to ensure safe and quality care and will issue proposed rules within one year. Establishing a minimum staffing level ensures that all nursing home residents are provided safe, quality care, and that workers have the support they need to provide high-quality care. Nursing homes will be held accountable if they fail to meet this standard.</li><li><em>Reduce Resident Room Crowding</em>. Most nursing home residents prefer to have private rooms to protect their privacy and dignity, but shared rooms with one or more other residents remain the default option. These multi-occupancy rooms increase residents’ risk of contracting infectious diseases, including COVID-19. CMS will explore ways to accelerate phasing out rooms with three or more residents and to promote single-occupancy rooms.</li><li><em>Strengthen the Skilled Nursing Facility (“SNF”) Value-Based Purchasing (“VBP”) Program. </em>The SNF-VBPprogram awards incentive funding to facilities based on quality performance. CMS has begun to measure and publish staff turnover and weekend staffing levels, metrics which closely align with the quality of care provided in a nursing home. CMS intends to propose new payment changes based on staffing adequacy, the resident experience, as well as how well facilities retain staff.</li><li><em>Reinforce Safeguards against Unnecessary Medications and Treatments</em>. Thanks to CMS’ National Partnership to Improve Dementia Care in Nursing Homes, the nation has seen a dramatic decrease in the use of antipsychotic drugs in nursing homes in recent years. However, inappropriate diagnoses and prescribing still occur at too many nursing homes. CMS will launch a new effort to identify problematic diagnoses and refocus efforts to continue to bring down the inappropriate use of antipsychotic medications.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Enhancing Accountability and Oversight</strong></p>



<p>Holding nursing homes accountable for their performance requires a robust compliance program—a program that has adequate funding to perform inspections and that imposes meaningful penalties when deficiencies are found. Federal taxpayer dollars should not flow to nursing homes that are unsafe.</p>



<ul><li><em>Adequately Fund Inspection Activities</em>. For over seven years, funding to conduct health and safety inspections has remained flat while the number of complaints about nursing homes has surged. To protect residents and crack down on unsafe nursing homes, President Biden will call on Congress to provide almost $500 million to CMS, a nearly 25% increase, to support health and safety inspections at nursing homes.</li><li><em>Beef up Scrutiny on More of the Poorest Performers</em>. CMS’s Special Focus Facility (SFF) program identifies the poorest-performing nursing homes in the country for increased scrutiny in an effort to immediately improve the care they deliver. The SFF program currently requires more frequent compliance surveys for program participants, which must pass two consecutive inspections to “graduate” from the program. The SFF program will be overhauled to more quickly improve care for the affected residents, including changes that will make its requirements tougher and more impactful. CMS will also make changes that allow the program to scrutinize more facilities, by moving facilities through the program more quickly. Facilities that fail to improve will face increasingly larger enforcement actions, including termination from participation in Medicare and Medicaid, when appropriate.</li><li><em>Expand Financial Penalties and Other Enforcement Sanctions</em>. CMS will expand the instances in which it takes enforcement actions against poor-performing facilities based on desk reviews of data submissions, which will be performed in addition to on-site inspections. In July 2021, CMS rescinded a Trump Administration change that lowered penalty amounts on bad actor nursing homes for harmful deficiencies by imposing only a one-time fine, instead of more aggressive per-day fines that charge for each day a facility is out of compliance. CMS will now explore making such per-day penalties the default penalty for non-compliance. CMS will also use data, predictive analytics, and other information processing tools to improve enforcement. President Biden is also calling on Congress to raise the dollar limit on per-instance financial penalties levied on poor-performing facilities, from $21,000 to $1,000,000.</li><li><em>Increase Accountability for Chain Owners of Substandard Facilities</em>. President Biden is calling on Congress to give CMS new authority to require minimum corporate competency to participate in Medicare and Medicaid programs, enabling CMS to prohibit an individual or entity from obtaining a Medicare or Medicaid provider agreement for a nursing home (new or existing) based on the Medicare compliance history of their other owned or operated facilities (previous or existing). He is further calling on Congress to expand CMS enforcement authority at the ownership level, enabling CMS to impose enforcement actions on the owners and operators of facilities even after they close a facility, as well as on owners or operators that provide persistent substandard and noncompliant care in some facilities, while still owning others.</li><li><em>Provide Technical Assistance to Nursing Homes to Help them Improve</em>. CMS currently contracts with Quality Improvement Organizations that help providers across the health care spectrum make meaningful quality of care improvements. CMS will ensure that improving nursing home care is a core mission for these organizations and will explore pathways to expand on-demand trainings and information sharing around best practices, while expanding individualized, evidence-based assistance related to issues exacerbated by the pandemic.</li></ul>



<p><br><strong>Increasing Transparency</strong></p>



<p>For too long, corporate owners and operators have not been held to account for poor nursing home performance. CMS will improve the public transparency of facility ownership and safeguard nursing home residents.<strong></strong></p>



<ul><li>. CMS will create a new database that will track and identify owners and operators across states to highlight previous problems with promoting resident health and safety. This registry will use information collected through provider enrollment and health and safety inspections to provide more information about prospective owners and operators to states. Giving the public a resource to better understand owners’ and operators’ previous violations will empower states to better protect the health and safety of residents.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Improve Transparency of Facility Ownership and Finances</em>. CMS will implement Affordable Care Act requirements regarding transparency in corporate ownership of nursing homes, including by collecting and publicly reporting more robust corporate ownership and operating data. It will also make this information easier to find on the Nursing Home Care Compare website.</li><li><em>Enhance Nursing Home Care Compare</em>: CMS will implement a range of initiatives to improve Nursing Home Care Compare, the rating website designed to help families pick a facility for their loved ones. Under the Biden-Harris Administration’s leadership, CMS has already published new measures on Care Compare, which allow users to consider nursing home staff turnover, weekend staffing levels, and other important factors in their decision-making process. &nbsp;When the new minimum staffing requirement comes online, Care Compare will also prominently display whether a facility is meeting these minimum staffing requirements. CMS will further improve Care Compare by improving the readability and usability of the information displayed—giving you and your family insight into how to interpret key metrics. Finally, CMS will ensure that ratings more closely reflect data that is verifiable, rather than self-reported, and will hold nursing homes accountable for providing inaccurate information. The President is calling on Congress to give CMS additional authority to validate data and take enforcement action against facilities that submit incorrect information.</li><li><em>Examine the Role of Private Equity. </em>As described above, private equity investors are playing a growing role in the nursing home sector, and published research increasingly indicates that facility ownership by investment groups leads to worse outcomes while costing taxpayers more—particularly as these owners have sought to cut expenses at the cost of patient health and safety, including during the COVID-19 pandemic. HHS and other federal agencies will examine the role of private equity, real estate investment trusts (REITs), and other investment ownership in the nursing home sector and inform the public when corporate entities are not serving their residents’ best interests. <strong></strong></li></ul>



<p><strong>Creating Pathways to Good-paying Jobs with the Free and Fair Choice to Join a Union</strong></p>



<ul><li><em>Ensure Nurse Aide Training is Affordable. </em>Lowering financial barriers to nurse aide training and certification will strengthen and diversify the nursing home workforce. CMSwill establish new requirements to ensure nurse aide trainees are notified about their potential entitlement to training reimbursement upon employment. CMS will further work with states to ensure reimbursement is being distributed and that free training opportunities are widely publicized.</li><li><em>Support State Efforts to Improve Staffing and Workforce Sustainability. </em>Strengthening the nursing home workforce requires adequate compensation as well as a realistic career ladder. CMS will develop a template to assist and encourage States requesting to tie Medicaid payments to clinical staff wages and benefits, including additional pay for experience and specialization.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Launch National Nursing Career Pathways Campaign. </em>CMS, in collaboration with the Department of Labor, will work with external entities—including training intermediaries, registered apprenticeship programs, labor-management training programs, and labor unions—to conduct a robust nationwide campaign to recruit, train, retain, and transition workers into long-term care careers, with pathways into health-care careers like registered and licensed nurses.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensuring Pandemic and Emergency Preparedness in Nursing Homes</strong></p>



<ul><li><em>Continued COVID-19 testing in long-term care facilities.</em> Throughout the pandemic, the Biden-Harris Administration has provided approximately 3 million tests per week to all Medicare- and Medicaid-certified nursing homes and thousands more assisted living facilities, supporting outbreak testing and regular testing of staff. HHS will continue to support this key mitigation strategy for vulnerable residents and the staff that care for them.</li><li><em>Continued COVID-19 vaccinations and boosters in long-term care facilities.</em> The Biden-Harris Administration has provided the full support of the federal government to states in ensuring that staff and residents across long-term care facilities have access to vaccinations and booster shots. Today, facilities are required to ensure staff are vaccinated and more than 87.1% of residents have received their primary series. CDC continues to offer all facilities the ability to be matched with a federal pharmacy partner to host an on-site vaccination clinic. CMS has reached out to thousands of these facilities directly to offer support, and the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality has made a wide set of tools available. HHS will continue to promote access to these clinics and efforts to integrate vaccinations into routine services, incentivize vaccinations through provider quality payment programs, and continue to provide a full range of resources to continue to build confidence in the vaccine.</li><li><em>Strengthen Requirements for On-site Infection Preventionists</em>. CMS will clarify and increase the standards for nursing homes on the level of staffing facilities need for on-site infection prevention employees, undoing the Trump Administration’s changes to these requirements to help improve resident health and safety.</li><li><em>Enhance Requirements for Pandemic and Emergency Preparedness</em>. Both the pandemic and the increase in natural disasters have demonstrated how critical proactive emergency preparedness is to keeping residents of nursing homes safe. CMS is examining and considering changes to emergency preparedness requirements and is working to bolster the resiliency of the health care sector as part of an Administration-wide effort to be ready for the next pandemic and the next weather-related emergencies.</li><li><em>Integrate Pandemic Lessons into Nursing Home Requirements. </em>The pandemic has underscored the need for resident-centered updates to nursing homes’ requirements of participation in Medicare and Medicaid. CMS will integrate new lessons on standards of care into nursing home requirements around fire safety, infection control, and other areas, using an equity lens<em>.</em></li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Lowering Prices and Leveling the Playing Field in Ocean&#160;Shipping</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-lowering-prices-and-leveling-the-playing-field-in-ocean-shipping/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing an historic agreement between the Department of Justice and the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) to make sure that large ocean freight companies cannot take advantage of U.S. businesses and consumers. Right now, three global alliances, made up entirely of foreign companies, control almost all of ocean freight shipping, giving them power&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing an historic agreement between the Department of Justice and the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) to make sure that large ocean freight companies cannot take advantage of U.S. businesses and consumers. Right now, three global alliances, made up entirely of foreign companies, control almost all of ocean freight shipping, giving them power to raise prices for American businesses and consumers, while threatening our national security and economic competitiveness.</p>



<p>Most traded goods—everything from the housewares you buy online to the agricultural products American farmers market overseas—are transported by ocean freight companies. <strong>These companies have formed global alliances—groups of ocean carrier companies that work together—that now control </strong><a href="https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/docs/impact-alliances-container-shipping.pdf"><strong>80</strong></a><strong>%</strong><strong> of global container ship capacity and control </strong><a href="https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/docs/impact-alliances-container-shipping.pdf"><strong>95</strong></a><strong>%</strong><strong> of the critical East-West trade lines.</strong> This consolidation happened rapidly over the last decade. From 1996 to 2011, the leading three alliances operated only about <a href="https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/docs/impact-alliances-container-shipping.pdf">30</a>% of global container shipping. Significant consolidation occurred in the years running up to the Pandemic. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since the beginning of the pandemic, these ocean carrier companies have been dramatically increasing shipping costs through rate increases and fees. <strong>They increased spot rates for freight shipping between Asia and the United States by 100% since January 2020, and increased rates for freight shipping between the United States and Asia </strong><a href="https://fbx.freightos.com/freight-index/FBX01"><strong>by over 1,000%</strong></a><strong> over the same period.</strong> Oftentimes cargo owners are charged fees—known as “detention and demurrage” fees—even when they can’t get access to their containers to move them. The FMC estimates that from July to September of 2021, eight of the largest carriers charged customers fees totaling $2.2 billion—a 50% increase on the previous three-month period.</p>



<p>These historically large shipping price increases translate into higher prices for American consumers. Based on research by the <a href="https://www.kansascityfed.org/ten/2017-spring-ten-magazine/shipping/#:~:text=Kansas%20City%20Fed%20economists%20Nicholas,core%20inflation%20after%20one%20year.">Kansas City Fed </a>and the <a href="https://www.ecb.europa.eu/pub/economic-bulletin/focus/2021/html/ecb.ebbox202103_01~8ecbf2b17c.en.html">European Central Bank</a>, these shipping cost increases are expected to contribute to approximately a 1% increase in consumer prices over the next year.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the ocean carrier companies are experiencing elevated profits and soaring profit margins. Estimates suggest that the container shipping industry made a record <a href="https://www.drewry.co.uk/news/is-it-time-for-investors-to-exit-the-container-shipping-space">$190</a> billion in profits in 2021, a <a href="https://fortune.com/2021/12/03/shipping-container-record-profit-supply-chain-breakdown/#:~:text=Container%20shipping%20pre%2Dtax%20profit,to%20The%20Journal%20of%20Commerce.">seven-fold increase</a> from the previous year and five times what it made over the <a href="https://phaata.com/en/logistics-market/container-shipping-lines-report-record-profits-in-the-third-quarter-of-2021-1096.html">entire period from 2010-2020</a>. Profit margins have increased by even larger amounts. <strong>In the third quarter of 2021, the average operating margin of the major carriers was about </strong><a href="https://globalmaritimehub.com/shipping-profit-margins-accelerate.html"><strong>56</strong></a><strong>%, compared to an average operating margin of 3.7% two years earlier</strong>:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="680" height="383" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-47993" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg 680w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg?resize=615,346 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg?resize=304,171 304w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg?resize=608,342 608w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg?resize=1200,675 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></figure>



<p>Beyond price increases, several specific business practices of many large ocean carrier companies are hurting American businesses and farmers. For example, because of their market power, these alliances are able to cancel or change bookings and impose additional fees without notice. These unpredictable practices undermine American business’ ability to deliver orders on time. <a href="https://www.agri-pulse.com/articles/17129-usda-to-boost-ag-export-capacity-at-port-of-oakland">All too often</a>, ocean carriers are effectively <a href="https://www.agri-pulse.com/articles/17129-usda-to-boost-ag-export-capacity-at-port-of-oakland">refusing</a> to take American exports altogether, preferring to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/26/shipping-carriers-rejected-us-agricultural-exports-sent-empty-containers-to-china.html">speed back to China</a> with an empty ship to make a quick turnaround rather than transport American exporters’ cargo or dock at American ports. This is especially difficult to our farmers, who have spent decades building relationships internationally, only to find that now they can’t transport their agricultural products overseas with any reliability or predictability.</p>



<p>The carriers have also continued to pursue practices that directly contribute to port congestion, such as imposing “box rules” that require truckers to use only certain trailers to haul their containers—thus forcing truckers to wait for the “right” kind of trailer to become available. That leads to lower pay and longer wait times for our nation’s truck drivers, who get paid per box, and allows the ocean carriers to generate even higher detention and demurrage fees.</p>



<p>A century ago, in the original Ocean Shipping Act, Congress provided for utility-style regulation of ocean carriers, paired with antitrust immunity for ocean carrier alliance agreements only when the alliance was in the “public interest.” But Congress <a href="https://www.justice.gov/atr/file/823411/download">steadily deregulated</a> the industry—expanding the antitrust immunity while weakening ocean carriers’ obligations to publicly disclose prices and fees and treat businesses and their customers fairly. That is how we have arrived at the point where three alliances can dominate the market for ocean shipping and squeeze American businesses and consumers.</p>



<p><strong><u>The Biden-Harris Administration is taking steps to lower consumer prices and level the playing field in ocean shipping:</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Today, the FMC and the Department of Justice (DOJ) are </strong><a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-and-federal-maritime-commission-reaffirm-and-strengthen-partnership"><strong>announcing</strong></a><strong> a new joint initiative to promote competition in the ocean freight transportation system. </strong>Under the new initiative, DOJ will provide the FMC with the support of attorneys and economists from the Antitrust Division for enforcement of violations of the Shipping Act and related laws. The FMC will provide the Antitrust Division with support and maritime industry expertise for Sherman Act and Clayton Act enforcement actions. The agencies’ announcement explains that competition in the maritime industry is integral to lowering prices, improving quality of service, and strengthening the resilience of supply chains.</li></ul>



<p>This initiative grew out of the “whole of government” approach to competition established by the President’s July Executive Order on Promoting Competition. The FMC and the DOJ are both part of the White House Competition Council established by the Order. Their partnership builds on an information-sharing Memorandum of Understanding that the agencies <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-and-federal-maritime-commission-sign-memorandum-understanding-support">entered into in July</a>.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The FMC will continue ramping up oversight of the global ocean shipping industry. </strong>Since last summer, the FMC has established a <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/fmc-establishes-ocean-carriers-audit-program/">new audit program</a> backed by an audit team to address complaints about carriers charging unfair fees, <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/commission-questions-shipping-lines-about-surcharges/">demanded justification</a> from the carriers about their fees, launched 42 cases investigating port congestion charges, and took steps to <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/fmc-policy-statements-provide-guidance-on-complaints-process/">address barriers to filing complaints</a> at the FMC and to prevent retaliation against complainants. It also launched a <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/commissioner-bentzel-hosts-inaugural-meeting-of-fmc-data-initiative/">new data initiative</a> to identify data constraints that are adding to supply chain congestion. This month, the FMC also <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/commission-invites-comments-on-benefits-of-new-demurrage-detention-rule/">sought comments</a> on reforms to how carriers charge shippers fees.<br><br>The Administration, led by Port Envoy John Porcari, has also worked with the Ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach to develop new fees on ocean carrier companies for letting cargo sit on the docks for over nine days. These long-dwelling import containers had been causing delays in getting goods to shelves while increasing port congestion. Since the announcement of the proposed fee, the number of long-dwelling containers on the docks has fallen more than 70 percent. Building on the success of the proposed carrier fee, the Administration is working with the ports on charging the carriers for long-dwelling empty containers that have been clogging the docks. There has been a more than 25 percent drop in the number of empty containers on the docks at the Port of Los Angeles since that announcement.</li></ul>



<p>The need for reform to our ocean freight transportation system to improve fluidity and fairness, particularly for our agricultural exporters, was underscored last week in reports released by the <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/supplychains">Department of Transportation</a> and <a href="https://www.ams.usda.gov/supply-chain">the Department of Agriculture (USDA)</a> as part of the Administration’s six supply chain <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/the-biden-harris-plan-to-revitalize-american-manufacturing-and-secure-critical-supply-chains-in-2022/">industrial base reports</a> published on the one-year anniversary of the President’s supply chain executive order.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The President is calling on Congress to pass robust reforms to the ocean shipping industry, including reforms that address the current antitrust immunity for ocean shipping alliances.</strong> In addition to the important administrative actions announced today, the President believes Congress should provide additional tools for the Administration to address problems in the ocean shipping industry. The President is encouraged by action in both Houses of Congress to address these problems. He is calling on Congress to also address the immunity of alliance agreements from antitrust scrutiny under current law.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
