<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 20:26:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary to the Vice President Kirsten&#160;Allen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/statement-by-press-secretary-to-the-vice-president-kirsten-allen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50683</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jamal Simmons, the Vice President’s Communications Director, tested positive for COVID-19 today. Jamal was in close contact to the Vice President as defined by CDC guidance. &#160;Jamal is&#160;isolating and working from home. The Vice President will follow CDC guidance for those that have been in close contact with a positive individual and will continue to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jamal Simmons, the Vice President’s Communications Director, tested positive for COVID-19 today. Jamal was in close contact to the Vice President as defined by CDC guidance. &nbsp;Jamal is&nbsp;isolating and working from home.</p>



<p>The Vice President will follow CDC guidance for those that have been in close contact with a positive individual and will continue to consult with her physician. The Vice President plans to continue with her public schedule.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Carol Spahn, Nominee for Director of the Peace Corps Robin Hutcheson, Nominee for Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administrator, Department of Transportation Jaime Lizárraga, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission Mark Uyeda,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Carol Spahn, Nominee for Director of the Peace Corps</li><li>Robin Hutcheson, Nominee for Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administrator, Department of Transportation</li><li>Jaime Lizárraga, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission</li><li>Mark Uyeda, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission</li><li>Vincent Logan, Nominee for Member of the Farm Credit Administration</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Carol Spahn, Nominee for Director of the Peace Corps</u></strong></p>



<p>Carol Spahn is serving as Chief Executive Officer of the Peace Corps, and was officially Acting Director from January 20, 2021 until November 16, 2021. Under her leadership, the agency is returning Volunteers to overseas service after being evacuated for two years due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Additionally, the agency created a domestic service initiative for only the second time in Peace Corps’ history, working with the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to support vaccination campaigns across the United States, and launched a new strategic plan which focuses on re-imagining service, advancing equity, and delivering quality. Prior to serving as Acting Director, Spahn served as Chief of Operations in the Africa Region covering Eastern and Southern Africa, and before that, served a five-year term as Country Director of Peace Corps Malawi. Her Peace Corps roots extend back to her service, with her husband, as a Volunteer from 1994 to 1996 in Romania where she served as a Small Business Advisor shortly after the fall of communism.</p>



<p>Before returning to the Peace Corps as Country Director, Spahn was Senior Vice President of Operations at Women for Women International. Prior to that, she served as Executive Director of Accordia Global Health Foundation. She also served as Vice President, Chief Financial Officer, and Treasurer of Small Enterprise Assistance Funds. Spahn has held positions at leading private sector institutions, including GE Capital and KPMG Peat Marwick. She holds a bachelor’s degree from the Catholic University of America and a master’s degree in international development from the George Washington University Elliott School of International Affairs.</p>



<p><strong><u>Robin Hutcheson, Nominee for Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administrator, Department of Transportation</u></strong></p>



<p>Robin Hutcheson currently serves in the Biden-Harris Administration as the Deputy Administrator and Acting Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA). She was previously appointed as the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Safety Policy for the U.S. Department of Transportation where she led the development of the National Roadway Safety Strategy and was instrumental in the development of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, especially the new Safe Streets and Roads for All program.</p>



<p>Prior to being appointed to the Biden-Harris Administration, Hutcheson was the Director of Public Works for the City of Minneapolis, overseeing a team of 1,100 people across nine divisions including drinking water, surface waters and sewers, solid waste and recycling, fleet management, and all transportation functions. Prior to her appointment in Minneapolis, she served as the Transportation Director for Salt Lake City, UT, working to improve all modes of transportation. Hutcheson also has served as a transportation consultant, and has worked throughout the western United States, and in Europe. Hutcheson served for seven years on the Board of Directors for the National Association of City Transportation Officials (NACTO), most recently serving as its President. She received a bachelor’s degree from the University of Colorado Boulder and a master’s degree from the University of Utah.</p>



<p><a><strong><u>Jaime Lizárraga, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission</u></strong></a></p>



<p>Jaime Lizárraga currently serves as Senior Advisor to Speaker of the House Nancy Pelosi. In this role, he oversees issues relating to financial markets, housing, international financial institutions, immigration, and small business policy. He also serves as the Speaker’s liaison to the Congressional Hispanic Caucus. Throughout his 31-year public service career, Lizárraga has advised Congressional leaders and heads of executive agencies on policy and legislative strategy. He previously served on the Democratic staff of the House Financial Services Committee, and as a presidential appointee at the U.S. Department of the Treasury and the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>



<p>Lizárraga has played key roles in numerous successful legislative initiatives, including the Build Back Better Act, the American Rescue Plan, COVID relief legislation, omnibus appropriations bills, the Dream and Promise Act, the PROMESA Act, the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010, the Economic Emergency and Stabilization Act of 2008, and many others. Lizárraga graduated from the University of California, San Diego with high honors, and earned a master’s degree from the Lyndon B. Johnson School of Public Affairs at the University of Texas. The son of immigrant farm workers, Lizárraga was raised in San Diego. He lives in Virginia with his wife and five children.</p>



<p><strong><u>Mark T. Uyeda, Nominee for Commissioner of the Securities and Exchange Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Mark T. Uyeda is a career attorney with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). He is currently on detail from the SEC to the U.S. Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, where he serves as Securities Counsel on the Committee’s Minority Staff. He has over 25 years of experience in corporate and securities law, including 18 years of public service working in federal and state government. Uyeda joined the SEC in 2006 and has worked in various capacities, including as Senior Advisor to Chairman Jay Clayton and Acting Chairman Michael S. Piwowar, and as Counsel to Commissioner Paul S. Atkins. He has also served as Assistant Director and Senior Special Counsel in the SEC’s Division of Investment Management. Uyeda has been recognized with multiple SEC awards, including the SEC Chairman’s Award for Excellence and the SEC Capital Markets Award. He is a past Chair of the SEC Asian Pacific American Employees Committee.</p>



<p>From 2004 to 2006, Uyeda served as Chief Advisor to the California Corporations Commissioner, the state’s securities regulator. Before entering public service, Uyeda was an attorney in private practice with O’Melveny &amp; Myers LLP in Los Angeles, and Kirkpatrick &amp; Lockhart LLP in Washington, D.C. He is a past President of the Asian Pacific American Bar Association of the Greater Washington, D.C. Area. Uyeda received his law degree with honors from Duke University and his undergraduate degree in business administration from Georgetown University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Vincent Logan, Nominee for Member of the Farm Credit Administration</u></strong></p>



<p>Vincent Logan, a member of the Osage Nation, currently serves as the Chief Financial Officer and Chief Investment Officer for the Native American Agriculture Fund (NAAF). NAAF is the largest U.S. philanthropic organization focused exclusively on the needs of Native American farmers and ranchers. Nominated by President Obama and confirmed by the U.S. Senate in 2014, Logan served as the Special Trustee for American Indians at the U.S. Department of the Interior. During his tenure, he was appointed to the Department of the Treasury’s Financial Literacy Education Commission.</p>



<p>Logan has worked in New York in both asset-based financing as a lawyer and in asset management as an investment advisor. As a lawyer, he practiced in aircraft, shipping, and equipment finance. As an investment advisor, he worked with institutional clients in developing investment policies, diversification strategies, and sovereign wealth funds. He is an Oklahoma State University Foundation Governor, Director for The Christensen Fund, and serves on the Board of Directors for the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis, Little Rock Branch. He has mentored numerous professionals, guiding them through careers in law and the securities industry. Logan was educated at Oklahoma State University, the University of Oklahoma College of Law, and the School of International and Public Affairs at Columbia University. His partner is Dr. Steven Lieberman of New Jersey.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris On Extending the Pause on Student Loan Repayment Through August 31st,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/statement-by-vice-president-kamala-harris-on-extending-the-pause-on-student-loan-repayment-through-august-31st-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50681</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the President announced that our Administration is pausing federal student loan repayments through August 31, 2022. This pause will help 41 million people keep up with their monthly bills and meet their basic needs. It will give borrowers some urgently needed time to prepare for a return to repayment.   This is personal for me.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the President announced that our Administration is pausing federal student loan repayments through August 31, 2022. This pause will help 41 million people keep up with their monthly bills and meet their basic needs. It will give borrowers some urgently needed time to prepare for a return to repayment.  <br><br>This is personal for me. I had student loans. Each month, I would sit at the kitchen table, fill out paperwork, and send a check to pay down my balance. Later, as California Attorney General, I took on predatory for-profit colleges and won $1 billion for defrauded veterans and students. President Biden and I understand that student loan debt adds stress for borrowers and their families.<br><br>We have made strong progress as a country in the face of a global pandemic and an economic downturn, but there is still work to do. Today’s announcement will make a meaningful difference as we continue moving forward. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress, on Prohibiting New Investment in and Certain Services to the Russian Federation in Response to Continued Russian Federation&#160;Aggression</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/a-message-to-the-congress-on-prohibiting-new-investment-in-and-certain-services-to-the-russian-federation-in-response-to-continued-russian-federation-aggression/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701&#160;et seq.), the National Emergencies Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1601&#160;et seq.), and section 301 of title 3, United&#160;States Code, I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order in order to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701&nbsp;<em>et seq</em>.), the National Emergencies Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1601&nbsp;<em>et seq</em>.), and section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code, I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order in order to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024 of April 15, 2021, with respect to the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States posed by specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;The order prohibits the following:&nbsp;&nbsp;(i)&nbsp;new investment in the Russian Federation by a United States person, wherever located; (ii) the exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United&nbsp;States person, wherever located, of any category of services as may be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to any person located in the Russian Federation; and (iii)&nbsp;any approval, financing, facilitation, or guarantee by a United States person, wherever located, of a transaction by a foreign person where the transaction by that foreign person would be prohibited by this section if performed by a United States person or within the United States.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>&nbsp;        April 6, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prohibiting New Investment in and Certain Services to the Russian Federation in Response to Continued Russian Federation&#160;Aggression</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/06/prohibiting-new-investment-in-and-certain-services-to-the-russian-federation-in-response-to-continued-russian-federation-aggression/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 19:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50672</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701&#160;et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601&#160;et seq.), and section 301 of title 3, United&#160;States Code, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701&nbsp;<em>et seq</em>.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601&nbsp;<em>et seq</em>.), and section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code,<br><br>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, in order to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024 of April&nbsp;15, 2021,&nbsp;expanded by Executive Order 14066 of March 8, 2022, and relied on for additional steps taken in Executive Order 14039 of August&nbsp;20, 2021, and Executive Order 14068 of March 11, 2022, hereby order:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;Section&nbsp;1.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;The following are prohibited:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i) &nbsp;new investment in the Russian Federation by a United States person, wherever located;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii) &nbsp;the exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United States person, wherever located, of any category of services as may be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to any person located in the Russian Federation; and<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(iii)&nbsp;any approval, financing, facilitation, or guarantee by a United States person, wherever located, of a transaction by a foreign person where the transaction by that foreign person would be prohibited by this section if performed by a United States person or within the United States.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; (b)&nbsp;&nbsp;The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or license or permit granted prior to the date of this order.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;2.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;3.&nbsp;&nbsp;Nothing in this order shall prohibit transactions for the conduct of the official business of the Federal Government or the United Nations (including its specialized agencies, programs, funds, and related organizations) by employees, grantees, or contractors thereof.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;4.&nbsp;&nbsp;For the purposes of this order:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(b)&nbsp;&nbsp;the term&nbsp;&#8220;person&#8221;&nbsp;means an individual or entity;&nbsp;and<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(c)&nbsp;&nbsp;the term&nbsp;&#8220;United States person&#8221;&nbsp;means any United&nbsp;States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;5.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.&nbsp;&nbsp;The&nbsp;Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury.&nbsp;&nbsp;All executive departments and agencies of the United&nbsp;States shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to implement this order.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Sec.&nbsp;6.&nbsp;&nbsp;(a)&nbsp;&nbsp;Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (b)&nbsp;&nbsp;This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (c)&nbsp;&nbsp;This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p> THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>    April 6, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on New Economic Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/06/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-new-economic-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 18:29:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50666</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 10:05 A.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining us today. So, as a quick reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call. For your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>10:05 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining us today.</p>



<p>So, as a quick reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker on the call today is [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you for some opening remarks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [moderator].&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;ll say a few things at the top, and then happy to jump into your questions.</p>



<p>The sickening brutality in Bucha has made tragically clear the despicable nature of the Putin regime.&nbsp; And today, in alignment with G7 allies and partners, we’re intensifying the most severe sanctions ever levied on a major economy.</p>



<p>All of you have seen the factsheet, so I&#8217;m going to step back and just explain the rationale for choosing these actions in the context of the five pillars that underpin our sanctions strategy.</p>



<p>So, number one, as all of you know, we’ve sought to generate a financial shock by cutting off Russia’s largest banks and its central bank from doing any business with the U.S. and freezing any of its assets that touch the U.S. financial system or those of our allies.</p>



<p>And today, we’re dramatically escalating the financial shock by imposing full blocking sanctions on Russia’s largest financial institution, Sberbank, and its largest private bank, Alfa Bank.</p>



<p>Sberbank is the main artery in the Russian financial system.&nbsp; By itself, it holds nearly one third of Russia’s total banking sector assets; that&#8217;s over $500 billion.&nbsp; That’s roughly twice the size of the second-largest Russian bank, which we previously fully blocked.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in total, we’ve now fully blocked more than two thirds of the Russian banking sector, which, before the invasion, held $1.4 trillion in assets.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, we said we would cut off cutting-edge exports to Russia to disable Putin’s military and deny him the ability to diversify and modernize his economy.</p>



<p>So, today, in alignment with the G7 and the EU, we&#8217;re announcing a ban on new investment in Russia, which President Biden will implement with an executive order.&nbsp; And this will make sure that the mass exodus from Russia that we’re seeing from the private sector, which is now over 600 multinational companies and growing &#8212; that it will endure.</p>



<p>And without investment from our private sector, Putin will lose private sector know-how and skills that travel with investment, and the knock-on effects to the ongoing brain drain from Russia will be profound.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, we&#8217;ve said we&#8217;re methodically ejecting Russia from the international economic order to deny the privileges and benefits it once enjoyed, such as its most-favored-nation trading status, its borrowing privileges from the IMF and the World Bank.</p>



<p>And in that spirit, on Monday we cut off Russia’s ability to use its frozen central bank funds to make debt payments.&nbsp; And so, Russia will now have to find new sources of dollars from outside the U.S. and to find a new payment route, other than U.S. banks, to avoid falling into default. &nbsp;And that&#8217;s Russia&#8217;s choice as to how it proceeds.</p>



<p>And of course, even if Russia taps into other sources of hard currency to remain current on its debt obligations, that will translate into fewer resources available to Putin to fund his war machine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fourth, we’ve said we’d degrade Russia’s status as a leading energy supplier and thereby cut off its largest source of export and budget revenue.&nbsp; We’ve done that previously by banning U.S. imports of Russian oil, gas, and coal; by working with the Germans and the EU to shut down Nord Stream 2; and by cutting off energy technologies that Russia needs to sustain its oil and gas production.</p>



<p>And today, just as a preview, you’ll hear more from the EU on their efforts to take this a step further.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lastly, we said we’d expose Russia’s kleptocracy and show that Putin and his cronies have been ripping off the Russian people for decades.&nbsp; Already, before today, we had sanctioned more than 140 oligarchs and their family members, and over 400 Russian government officials.&nbsp; These are the key architects of the war.</p>



<p>And today, we’re sanctioning Putin’s adult children, Minister Lavrov’s wife and his daughter, and members of Russia’s Security Council.</p>



<p>In terms of impact &#8212; and we can get into this in the questions if you&#8217;d like &#8212; I mean, as all of you have seen, these sanctions are generating the impact we warned Putin about for months prior to the invasion.&nbsp; Russia&#8217;s GDP is projected to shrink by double digits this year.&nbsp; And to put that in perspective, that’s more than twice the contraction it suffered after it defaulted in 1998.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But unlike then, when Russia was in the process of getting integrated into the global economy, it’s now in the process of being isolated as a pariah state.</p>



<p>The economic shock this year alone is projected by the IEF to wipe out the past 15 years of economic gains.  Russia used to be the 11th-largest economy in the world.  It&#8217;s now very likely to drop out of the top 20. </p>



<p>Inflation: The latest print this week was that inflation in Russia is already above 15 percent and projected to hit 20 percent or more.&nbsp; Interest rates in Russia are already 20 percent.</p>



<p>And so, this combination of sky-high inflation and interest rates will cripple Russia&#8217;s long-term growth potential and so will the exit of the more than 600 companies that I referenced earlier. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And the sad reality is Putin&#8217;s war will make it harder for Russians to travel abroad. &nbsp;It means their debit cards may not work. &nbsp;They may only have the option to buy knockoff phones and knockoff clothes.&nbsp; The shelves at stores may be empty. &nbsp;The reality is the country is descending into economic and financial and technological isolation. &nbsp;And at this rate, it will go back to Soviet-style living standards from the 1980s.</p>



<p>But look, don&#8217;t take my word for it: Putin himself has said the sanctions will require deep structural changes to the Russian economy to deal with the new realities, including inflation and unemployment.&nbsp; Minister Lavrov has said “no one could have predicted” the central bank actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They simply weren&#8217;t prepared for their economic fortress to crumble. &nbsp;And that&#8217;s what&#8217;s happened.</p>



<p>Let me stop there and take your questions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Could we cue up the directions to ask a question please?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q    Thanks for doing this.  My question is about India.  You were [redacted], and that&#8217;s been reported on extensively.  Where does India stand on the second set of sanctions?  And how far have they come towards convergence on the U.S. view regarding the sanctions (inaudible) applied?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; You know, India is our friend; India is our partner.&nbsp; And we share &#8212; we share interests, and we share core principles that are at stake in this conflict.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve had extensive discussions about ways to further our cooperation on global food security, on global energy supplies, and certainly in terms of recognizing that Putin&#8217;s brutality affects all of us.&nbsp; And the geopolitical implications of Russia&#8217;s actions do have ripple effects.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we &#8212; India is not part of the G7.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a guest country this year.&nbsp; So, we will certainly collaborate with India and share the details of our measures.&nbsp; And, of course, we remain hopeful that we can have alignment to the maximum extent possible.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering if you could clarify on Putin&#8217;s adult children.&nbsp; Are you sanctioning his two daughters, Mariya Putina and Katerina Tikhonova?&nbsp; Or are there any additional children that you have identified that you are applying sanctions to?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, you’ve got it right.&nbsp; Those are the two.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thank you for taking our questions.&nbsp; Can you speak a little bit more about these full blocking sanctions come on the major SOEs that are coming tomorrow?&nbsp; Is that, sort of like, all major SOEs or a certain major?&nbsp; Are there particular sectors?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So these are not all Russian SOEs.&nbsp; And they will not be energy &#8212; they will not be SOEs in the energy sector.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll hear more from Treasury tomorrow on the specific institutions, and that will likely come later today or tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; I wanted to just ask if you could say whether you saw, currently, that China is complying with sanctions that you&#8217;ve implemented so far, and what the thinking is on applying secondary sanctions to Chinese or other foreign companies or entities.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So as I think everyone is aware, we&#8217;ve had a series of private consultations, going up to the highest level of our government and China&#8217;s government, about the importance of respecting the sanctions regime that we’ve put in place as well as the export controls.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have anything new to tell you, other than we&#8217;ve been really clear about the consequences of any efforts to circumvent or backfill those sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;ve seen, I think, in the public rhetoric from China that they&#8217;re not, openly at least, indicating any intention to do so.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re watching that very closely.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much for doing this call.&nbsp; Can you tell us whether you think these sanctions and all the impact on Russia will actually stop Russia&#8217;s military advances given the projection to Congress yesterday from General Milley that this war could last years?&nbsp; And Vladimir Putin &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t seem signs of slowing down.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think &#8212; yeah, thanks, Andrea.&nbsp; I mean, I&#8217;ll say it this way: I mean, sanctions are never a standalone solution.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t impose these costs as an end to themselves.&nbsp; And, you know, in our judgment, sanctions work when they&#8217;re embedded in a broader strategy, and you referenced this.&nbsp; It has to &#8212; these sanctions have to work alongside doing all we can to support Ukraine&#8217;s fight for freedom.&nbsp; They work alongside doing all we can to help the rest of the world deal with the spillovers of Putin&#8217;s war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve surged supplies of energy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why we&#8217;re coming together to welcome the millions of refugees that are fleeing Ukraine, and trying to come together with the rest of the world to deal with the disruptions to global food supply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if we execute on all those fronts &#8212; and that&#8217;s our that&#8217;s our plan; that&#8217;s our strategy &#8212; that&#8217;s how we create staying power in these sanctions.&nbsp; And staying the course is how we think we’ll create leverage for the outcome that we&#8217;re seeking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’ll &#8212; let me add one more point on the sanctions impact: I mean, even an autocrat like Putin has a social contract with the Russian people.&nbsp; He took away their freedom in exchange for promising stability.&nbsp; And so he&#8217;s not giving them stability at the moment; he&#8217;s giving them instability and insecurity, and he&#8217;s imposing that upon them.&nbsp; And at some point, that ought to matter to any leader if only because they care about staying in power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the question really is not so much, “What can we do and when will that have an effect?”&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s, “What&#8217;s the endgame here for Putin?&nbsp; What&#8217;s he playing for?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is very clearly becoming a failure for him.&nbsp; And at some point, he will have to recognize that reality.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Earlier, you mentioned that you have worked with senior Chinese officials regarding those sanctions.&nbsp; Do you also find that China is also learning how United States and allies are using the financial sanctions right now and possibly find ways to counter those measures in the future if, one day, China has to face similar sanctions?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, I think, you know, China has become &#8212; has gained an economic prominence by engaging with the world, by integrating itself with the global economy and with the global financial system.</p>



<p>And the United States &#8212; because of the quality of our financial markets, the transparency of our regulations, the effectiveness of our corporate governance, and really the soft power that we’ve enjoyed for decades and decades &#8212; is the central player in the global financial system.&nbsp; And so we will remain integrated with China as long as it continues to engage with the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, that’s the way in which we have leverage with financial sanctions.&nbsp; And we don’t use that leverage in an arbitrary way.&nbsp; We use that leverage when we’re defending a core international principle.&nbsp; And that’s certainly what’s going on in the crisis in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re using these sanctions because we want to demonstrate resolve and say, “You can’t redraw your neighbors’ borders at the barrel of a gun.&nbsp; You can’t subjugate their free will.&nbsp; Countries have the right to set their own course and choose their own destiny.”&nbsp; That’s &#8212; those are the conditions in which we use these sanctions.&nbsp; We know how severe they are.&nbsp; And our message to China is: We hope you respect those principles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you guys for doing the call.&nbsp; I just had a more, sort of, technical question.&nbsp; Could you clarify specifically the sanctions that are being placed on Sberbank: how those differ or what is being done, compared to what had already been put on them earlier this month?&nbsp; I&#8217;m just unclear on that.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And thanks for asking that, because previously we had imposed what are called “dollar-clearing prohibition” with Sberbank, which meant that any transactions that Sberbank tried to undertake with a U.S. financial institution using dollars would not be allowed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So now, this is a full blocking sanction, which means that any transaction in any currency with a U.S. person or a U.S. institution is prohibited, and also any of Sberbank’s assets that touch the U.S. financial system are now frozen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a much more severe action.&nbsp; This is the most severe action we can take in terms of financial measures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in practice, the history of sanctions show us that when we impose a full blocking sanction on a financial institution, that the rest of the world, even in other jurisdictions that have not yet imposed a full blocking sanction, they respect the regime and so there tends to be a multiplier effect.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we expect to happen here as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, thank you.&nbsp; And to be clear, there&#8217;s no carve-outs there?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I should have said there is a carve-out for energy, yes.&nbsp; Just like the other full block &#8212; full blocking sanctions.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the same carve-out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks very much.&nbsp; I was wondering if there has been discussion of the downside effects of so detaching the Russians from the global economy that their investment in it over the long term basically becomes so diminished that they become more interested in disruptive action than any hope that they would get back in?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, I mean, I would say this, David &#8212; is the sanctions are designed to be quite flexible.&nbsp; We can escalate and we can de-escalate depending on the circumstances.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but really, the way to think of it, if you want a metaphor, it&#8217;s a negative feedback loop.&nbsp; So, we deny capital, we deny technology, we deny talent that can flow into Russia.&nbsp; And the combination of the steps that we&#8217;re taking create this downward spiral that accelerates the more that Putin escalates.</p>



<p>And if he were to change course, someday, that negative feedback loop would slow and could possibly reverse.&nbsp; None of this is permanent. &nbsp;The only aspect that&#8217;s permanent are the lives that he&#8217;s taken away, and he can never bring those back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the sanctions &#8212; the sanctions are designed to be able to respond to the conditions on the ground and to create leverage for the outcome we seek.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks again for doing the call.&nbsp; About the sanctions against Putin&#8217;s daughters: Are these symbolic sanctions or do you have reason to believe that they do have assets either in the U.S. or in Europe?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, we have reason to believe that Putin and many of his cronies and the oligarchs hide their wealth, hide their assets with family members, that place their assets and their wealth in the U.S. financial system but also many other parts of the world.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the coordination &#8212; the coordinated effort to freeze their assets and seize their physical luxury goods &#8212; their cars, their yachts, their homes, et cetera &#8212; that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that we act together.</p>



<p>But to answer your question directly: Yes, we believe that many of Putin&#8217;s assets are hidden with family members, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re targeting them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; So, thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Given the call is ending a little bit earlier than 10:30, we&#8217;re going to go ahead and lift the embargo on the factsheet as well.&nbsp; So, now that the call has ended, you know, both the content of the call and the factsheet embargo will lift.</p>



<p>And as a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; So, thanks, everyone, for joining.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>10:25 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States, G7 and EU Impose Severe and Immediate Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/fact-sheet-united-states-g7-and-eu-impose-severe-and-immediate-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50640</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the United States, with the G7 and the European Union, will continue to impose severe and immediate economic costs on the Putin regime for its atrocities in Ukraine, including in Bucha. We will document and share information on these atrocities and use all appropriate mechanisms to hold accountable those responsible. As one part of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the United States, with the G7 and the European Union, will continue to impose severe and immediate economic costs on the Putin regime for its atrocities in Ukraine, including in Bucha. We will document and share information on these atrocities and use all appropriate mechanisms to hold accountable those responsible. As one part of this effort, the United States is announcing devastating economic measures to ban new investment in Russia, and impose the most severe financial sanctions on Russia’s largest bank and several of its most critical state-owned enterprises and on Russian government officials and their family members. These sweeping financial sanctions follow our action earlier this week to cut off Russia’s frozen funds in the United States to make debt payments. Importantly, these measures are designed to reinforce each other to generate intensifying impact over time.</p>



<p>The United States and more than 30 allies and partners across the world have levied the most impactful, coordinated, and wide-ranging economic restrictions in history. Experts predict Russia’s GDP will contract up to 15 percent this year, wiping out the last fifteen years of economic gains. Inflation is already spiking above 15 percent and forecast to accelerate higher. More than 600 private sector companies have already left the Russian market. Supply chains in Russia have been severely disrupted. Russia will very likely lose its status as a major economy, and it will continue a long descent into economic, financial, and technological isolation. Compared to last year, U.S. exports to Russia of items subject to our new export controls have decreased 99 percent by value – and the power of these restrictions will compound over time as Russia draws down any remaining stockpiles of spare parts for certain planes, tanks, and other resources needed for Putin’s war machine.</p>



<p>As long as Russia continues its brutal assault on Ukraine, we will stand unified with our allies and partners in imposing additional costs on Russia for its actions. Today, the United States is announcing the following actions:</p>



<p><strong>Full blocking sanctions on Russia’s largest financial institution, Sberbank, and Russia’s largest private bank, Alfa Bank.</strong> This action will freeze any of Sberbank’s and Alfa Bank’s assets touching the U.S financial system and prohibit U.S. persons from doing business with them. Sberbank holds nearly one-third of the overall Russian banking sector’s assets and is systemically critical to the Russian economy. Alfa Bank is Russia’s largest privately-owned financial institution and Russia’s fourth largest financial institution overall.</p>



<p><strong>Prohibiting new investment in the Russian Federation. </strong>President Biden will sign a new Executive Order (E.O.) that includes a prohibition on new investment in Russia by U.S. persons wherever located, which will further isolate Russia from the global economy. This action builds on the decision made by more than 600 multinational businesses to exit from Russia. The exodus of the private sector includes manufacturers, energy companies, large retailers, financial institutions, as well as other service providers such as law and consulting firms. Today’s E.O. will ensure the enduring weakening of the Russian Federation’s global competitiveness.</p>



<p><strong>Full blocking sanctions on critical major Russian state-owned enterprises.</strong>&nbsp;This will prohibit any U.S. person from transacting with these entities and freeze any of their assets subject to U.S. jurisdiction, thereby damaging the Kremlin’s ability to use these entities it depends on to enable and fund its war in Ukraine. The Department of Treasury will announce these entities tomorrow.</p>



<p><strong>Full blocking sanctions on Russian elites and their family members, including sanctions on: President Putin’s adult children, Foreign Minister Lavrov’s wife and daughter, and members of Russia’s Security Council including former President and Prime Minister of Russia Dmitry Medvedev and Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin.</strong> These individuals have enriched themselves at the expense of the Russian people. &nbsp;Some of them are responsible for providing the support necessary to underpin Putin’s war on Ukraine. This action cuts them off from the U.S. financial system and freezes any assets they hold in the United States.</p>



<p><strong>The U.S. Treasury prohibited Russia from making debt payments with funds subject to U.S. jurisdiction.</strong> Sanctions do not preclude payments on Russian sovereign debt at this time, provided Russia uses funds outside of U.S. jurisdiction. However, Russia is a global financial pariah — and it will now need to choose between draining its available funds to make debt payments or default.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Commitment to supporting sectors essential to humanitarian activities.</strong> As we continue escalating our sanctions and other economic measures against Russia for its brutal war against Ukraine, we reiterate our commitment to exempting essential humanitarian and related activities that benefit the Russian people and people around the world: ensuring the availability of basic foodstuffs and agricultural commodities, safeguarding access to medicine and medical devices, and enabling telecommunications services to support the flow of information and access to the internet which provides outside perspectives to the Russian people. These activities are not the target of our efforts, and U.S. and Western companies can continue to operate in these sectors in Russia. When necessary, relevant departments and agencies will issue appropriate exemptions and carveouts to ensure such activity is not disrupted.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">***</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden Extending the Pause on Student Loan Repayment Through August 31st,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/statement-by-president-biden-extending-the-pause-on-student-loan-repayment-through-august-31st-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50632</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In January 2021, on my first day in office, I directed the Department of Education to pause federal student loan repayments through September of that year. At the time, our economy was barely growing. Fewer than 1 percent of Americans were fully vaccinated. Millions of Americans were struggling to stay afloat. Because of that pause&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In January 2021, on my first day in office, I directed the Department of Education to pause federal student loan repayments through September of that year. At the time, our economy was barely growing. Fewer than 1 percent of Americans were fully vaccinated. Millions of Americans were struggling to stay afloat. Because of that pause in repayments, 41 million Americans were able to breathe a little easier during some of the toughest days of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Today, America is stronger than we were a year ago—and we will be stronger a year from now than we are today. Thanks to our plan to build the economy from the bottom up and the middle out, the economy has created 7.9 million jobs since I took office—the greatest year of job growth on record. We’ve seen the fastest economic growth in nearly 40 years. More than 217 million Americans are now fully vaccinated, and 2 out of 3 eligible adults are boosted. We have the tools we need to move forward safely and return to more normal routines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, as I recognized in recently extending the COVID-19 national emergency, we are still recovering from the pandemic and the unprecedented economic disruption it caused. If loan payments were to resume on schedule in May, analysis of recent data from the Federal Reserve suggests that millions of student loan borrowers would face significant economic hardship, and delinquencies and defaults could threaten Americans’ financial stability.</p>



<p>Accordingly, to enable Americans to continue to get back on their feet after two of the hardest years this nation has ever faced, my Administration is extending the pause on federal student loan repayments through August 31<sup>st</sup>, 2022. That additional time will assist borrowers in achieving greater financial security and support the Department of Education’s efforts to continue improving student loan programs. As part of this transition, the Department of Education will offer additional flexibilities and support for all borrowers.</p>



<p>I’m asking all student loan borrowers to work with the Department of Education to prepare for a return to repayment, look into Public Service Loan Forgiveness, and explore other options to lower their payments. Vice President Harris and I are focused on supporting borrowers in need, and believe that this pause will provide a continued lifeline as we recover and rebuild from the pandemic.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and HHS Public Health Officials &#124; April 5,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/05/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-hhs-public-health-officials-april-5-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 01:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 3:06 P.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:  Good afternoon.  Thanks for joining us.  Today, Dr. Walensky will share the latest on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Fauci will discuss the effectiveness of additional booster shots, and Secretary Becerra will provide an update on our work to address the long-term impacts of COVID. First, I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>3:06 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:  Good afternoon.  Thanks for joining us.  Today, Dr. Walensky will share the latest on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Fauci will discuss the effectiveness of additional booster shots, and Secretary Becerra will provide an update on our work to address the long-term impacts of COVID.</p>



<p>First, I want to discuss where we stand on funding for the COVID-19 response.</p>



<p>We’ve made tremendous progress in our fight against the virus.&nbsp; We have 217 million Americans fully vaccinated, two out of three eligible adults boosted, a medicine cabinet full of highly-effective treatments, and convenient tests.</p>



<p>But, as we’ve made clear for months, there’s more work to do.&nbsp; The country urgently needs additional funding from Congress to continue our fight against COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The administration requested emergency funds to ensure our medical tools like vaccines, treatments, and tests remain readily available to the American people and, importantly, funding for our global response so we can get more shots in arms around the world.</p>



<p>We are encouraged by the Senate’s work on a bipartisan plan to help meet some of our most immediate domestic needs.&nbsp; But, as we’ve made clear, we need more for our domestic response: to stay up to date on vaccines, to procure monoclonal antibody treatments and antiviral pills, to provide protection for the immunocompromised, and to sustain our testing capacity.</p>



<p>And it is a real disappointment that there is no global funding in this bill.&nbsp; This virus knows no borders, and it’s in our national interest to vaccinate the world and protect against possible new variants.</p>



<p>Without additional funding for our global response, we won’t have resources to help get more shots in arms in countries in need.&nbsp; We will lack funding to provide oxygen and other lifesaving supplies.&nbsp; And our global genomic sequencing capabilities will fall off and undermine our ability to detect any emerging variants around the world.</p>



<p>As we know, this virus is unpredictable.&nbsp; Time is of the essence, so we urge Congress to move promptly on the $10 billion emergency funding package developed in the Senate.</p>



<p>This bill is a start.&nbsp; It should pass immediately.&nbsp; But it’s exactly that: just a start.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congress must keep working to immediately provide additional funding for our remaining domestic needs so that we’re prepared for whatever comes, and, importantly, to act with urgency to fund our global COVID-19 response so that we can accelerate our efforts to turn vaccines into vaccinations around the world.</p>



<p>As we work with Congress to fund our global response, we will continue doing all we can to vaccinate the world.</p>



<p>At President Biden’s direction, we have done more than just lead the global vaccination effort: We have pioneered the global vaccination effort.</p>



<p>The U.S. was the first country in the world to donate a significant amount of our own vaccine supply, creating the model for other countries to do the same.</p>



<p>The U.S. was the first country to strike a deal with a major vaccine manufacturer to purchase doses solely to donate to other countries in need &#8212; 1 billion Pfizer vaccine doses.</p>



<p>We were the first, and remain the only, country to broker a deal with a U.S. manufacturer and COVAX to get vaccines into humanitarian zones to reach people displaced by war, famine, and other crises.</p>



<p>And we were the first, and are still the only, country to give up our place in line for delivery of doses, enabling the African Union to more quickly access over 100 million Moderna vaccine doses.</p>



<p>Today, we’re adding to our list of firsts, announcing that we will be the first nation to donate tens of millions of pediatric COVID-19 vaccines to low- and lower-middle income countries for free, with no strings attached.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These countries around the world are eager to get these doses.&nbsp; In fact, more than 20 low- and lower-middle income countries have approached the U.S., asking us to provide vaccines for their young children.</p>



<p>We’re now ready to answer their call.&nbsp; It’s the right thing to do.</p>



<p>The U.S. has now delivered over a half-billion adult vaccines to 114 different countries.&nbsp; And because of President Biden’s leadership, vaccine supply is no longer the constraint to getting shots in arms around the world.</p>



<p>In fact, countries need funding and assistance to turn vaccines into vaccinations.&nbsp; That’s why Congress must step up and provide critical funding to help countries in need get shots into arms.</p>



<p>In the meantime, any low- and lower-middle income country that wants adult doses from the U.S. can get those doses, again, for free with no strings attached.</p>



<p>And now with more than enough supply for adults, we’re working with Pfizer to make pediatric doses available to donate as part of our ongoing commitment to donate 1.2 billion vaccines.</p>



<p>Thanks to this historic action, children in countries most in need will soon have access to safe, effective vaccines and parents will gain the peace of mind that their children are protected.</p>



<p>Again, this virus knows no borders, so getting more people vaccinated is one of the best ways to protect people here at home and around the world.</p>



<p>And today, we’re making clear that the U.S. will continue to lead and pioneer the global effort to get both adults and children vaccinated.</p>



<p>With that, I’ll turn it over to Dr. Walensky.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; And good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Let’s walk &#8212; start by walking through today’s data.&nbsp; The current seven-day daily average of cases is about 25,000 cases per day, a decrease nationally of about 4 percent over the previous week and remains relatively stable over the past few weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 14,000 per day, a decrease of about 17 percent over the previous week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the seven-day average daily deaths are about 570 per day, which is a decrease of nearly 16 percent over the prior week.</p>



<p>New national estimates released today show the Omicron sublineage, BA.2 &#8212; indicated by light pink in this U.S. map by HHS regions &#8212; is now projected to account for 72 percent of circulating variants nationally, with all regions of the country reporting that BA.2 is now the dominant variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we’ve previously shared about the BA.2 variant, there is no evidence that BA.2 results in more severe disease compared with the BA.1 variant, nor does it appear to be more likely to evade immune protection than BA.1.&nbsp; But BA.2 does appear to be more transmissible than BA.1.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The high level of immunity in the population from vaccines, boosters, and previous infection will provide some level of protection against BA.2.&nbsp; However, we strongly encourage everyone to be up to date on their COVID-19 vaccines.</p>



<p>Looking across the country, we see that 95 percent of counties are reporting low COVID-19 community levels, which represent over 97 percent of the U.S. population.</p>



<p>If we look more closely at the local level, we find a handful of counties where we are seeing increases in both cases and markers of more severe disease, like hospitalizations and in-patient bed capacity, which have resulted in an increased COVID-19 community level in some areas.</p>



<p>While on the national level cases remain relatively low compared to prior points in the pandemic, we continue to look to COVID-19 community levels which were developed to work locally at the county level.</p>



<p>As we move forward, we encourage local jurisdictions to closely monitor their own COVID-19 community levels and to follow additional metrics that are &#8212; that they may have available as leading indicators of disease, for example, wastewater and syndromic surveillance.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important for communities and health officials to use these measures to help inform prevention strategies for their local area &#8212; like masking, testing, and plans for treatment &#8212; should they move into higher COVID-19 community levels.</p>



<p>Now as we continue to closely monitor COVID-19 in the United States, we&#8217;re reminded of the critical need to have a sustainable and resilient public health workforce in place that can effectively respond to both emerging threats and ongoing public health needs.</p>



<p>During the decade prior to COVID-19, the public health workforce lost an estimated 60,000 jobs nationwide, despite the continued demands to respond to multiple chronic public health threats, like H1N1, Zika, and Ebola.</p>



<p>As we look to building back this much-needed workforce, we must prioritize a public health workforce that is as diverse as the communities they serve, culturally competent, and equipped with skills to meet the public health needs of communities across the nation.</p>



<p>One way we&#8217;re working to build this workforce is through Public Health AmeriCorps &#8212; a groundbreaking initiative that supports the recruitment, training, and development of our nation&#8217;s next generation of public health leaders.&nbsp; Public Health AmeriCorps is supported through investments from the American Rescue Plan and is anticipated to fund up to 5,000 positions over the next five years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This week, AmeriCorps will award over 80 grants to the first round of Public Health AmeriCorps programs across 32 states and territories that will allow the recruitment of nearly 3,000 Public Health AmeriCorps members.</p>



<p>The work of these initial members will help to address public health needs in our nation&#8217;s inner cities, to build Tribal public health capacity, to address health disparities in rural America, and to bolster public health resources in our U.S. territories.</p>



<p>Recruitment, training, and development of public health personnel is a key part of building our nation&#8217;s public health workforce, allowing us to better respond to current and future public health threats.</p>



<p>And now I will turn it over to Dr. Fauci.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Fauci.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; I would like to now discuss the COVID-19 boosters, particularly in the context of the fourth dose of an mRNA boost.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s take a very quick update and an overview of the situation that we&#8217;re in right now.&nbsp; So, several studies have shown that COVID-19 vaccine booster shots protect against serious illness, hospitalizations, and even death.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a well-established fact now.&nbsp; And the CDC recommends everyone aged 12 and older to receive a COVID-19 vaccine booster after completing their primary vaccination series.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And certain individuals can now receive two booster doses: people who are moderately or severely immune compromised, as well as adults 50 years of age or older.</p>



<p>Next slide.</p>



<p>And as we know, on March 29th, the FDA authorized second booster doses of two COVID-19 vaccines for older and immunocompromised individuals.&nbsp; And the CDC recommended, that same day, that additional boosters can now be used for certain individuals.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s take a look at the data behind those decisions.&nbsp; So, the first doost- &#8212; the first booster doses restore the waning vaccine effectiveness of a primary vaccine series, including against severe disease.&nbsp; The effectiveness of the first booster dose, we know, wanes over time.&nbsp; And growing evidence indicates that a second COVID-19 dose can restore vaccine effectiveness for certain populations and, albeit, the data now &#8212; at least for the short term.&nbsp; And we look forward to longer-term data.</p>



<p>Next slide.</p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s take a look at some of the Israeli studies.&nbsp; There are a few of them that are really quite telling.&nbsp; One from Bar-On, looking at more than 1 million people who are age 60 or older and eligible for the fourth dose.&nbsp; And in that look at &#8211;in that study, an additional booster dose of the Pfizer product at four months resulted in a 2-fold lower rate of confirmed infection and a 4.3-fold lower rate of severe illness.</p>



<p>In another study &#8212; next slide &#8212; again, from Israel by &#8212; there it is &#8212; by Arbel, about a half a million members of a health services group, again age &#8212; 60 years of age or older.&nbsp; And now during an Omicron surge, individuals who received a second booster dose of the Pfizer product at four months had a 78 percent reduction in death compared to those who received only the first boost.</p>



<p>And on the next slide, this is rather dramatically shown by this Kaplan-Meier shot, where you see here in the pink-red, the first booster &#8212; namely, a third dose.&nbsp; And then in the lighter blue color, you look at the mortality rate of individuals who receive the second booster or the fourth dose.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And yet again, in another study by Gazit, in almost 100,000 people at a different healthcare service, when you looked at the fourth dose and compared it to the third dose, there was an 86 percent vaccine effectiveness against severe disease.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.</p>



<p>Now, what we&#8217;re doing at the NIH &#8212; looking forward &#8212; about fourth doses that might be available for people in the longer range: We want to do better than just what we have.&nbsp; So there is now a new study that we just recently launched called COVAIL.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;ll be doing is assessing different fourth doses that are either ancestral strain or variant specific &#8212; in the first phase of the study.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the second phase of the study, we&#8217;re planning on looking at different vaccine platforms for the purpose of getting a great durability than we currently have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And let me close by, again, just bringing to the attention of the audience: Covid.gov, where we can get one-stop shopping of all the information that you will need to help you navigate decisions about vaccines and about testings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll hand it over now to Secretary Becerra.</p>



<p>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; When it comes to COVID, we have more tools than ever before to stay safe, from vaccines and boosters, to treatments and tests.&nbsp; All widely available at no cost to the American people thanks to our national COVID response over the past year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we also know that many people continue to feel the physical and the mental burden of this pandemic.&nbsp; We have to ensure that people with disabilities, older Americans, and people who are immunocompromised aren&#8217;t left behind, and that they continue to have the tools and resources that they need to stay safe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just yesterday, we expanded coverage of free over-the-counter COVID tests to the tens of millions of Medicare beneficiaries.&nbsp; People with Medicare now have access each month to up to eight easy-to-use, at-home COVID-19 tests at no cost.&nbsp; This is all a part of our overall strategy to ensure access to tests free of charge.</p>



<p>In the past year, we have more than tripled the number of sites where people can get COVID-19 tests for free and delivered close to 250 million free at-home, rapid tests to Americans who have ordered them.</p>



<p>President Biden has been clear, we must ensure that no one is left behind as we work to move forward in the fight against COVID-19.&nbsp; That also means taking on big and complex physical and mental health challenges caused by COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Americans of every age and background are experiencing Long COVID.&nbsp; Americans have experienced the loss of a loved one due to COVID, including over 200,000 children who&#8217;ve lost a parent or caregiver.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Americans nationwide are grappling with mental health and substance-use challenges caused by or exacerbated by the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s be clear, we are going to use every tool we have to be there for these Americans.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made significant investments in mental healthcare, as well as substance-use prevention, treatment, and recovery support.&nbsp; That is especially important for people dealing with COVID and COVID-related loss.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve launched efforts across the NIH, the CDC, and the Veterans Administration, including the landmark $1.1 billion recovery initiative, to better understand Long COVID and accelerate scientific progress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we are providing Americans experiencing Long COVID information about where they can access the resources and support they need, as well as helping them understand, if they have a disability, and educating them on their rights.</p>



<p>Long COVID is real, and there is still so much we don&#8217;t know about it.&nbsp; Millions of Americans may be struggling with lingering health effects, ranging from things that are easier to notice, like troubling &#8212; trouble breathing or irregular heartbeat, to less apparent but potentially serious conditions related to the brain or mental health.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the President&#8217;s direction, the Department of Health and Human Services will be leading a government-wide response to Long COVID focused on three main goals: improving care services and other support for individuals with Long COVID; enhancing education and outreach among the public-private sector and the medical community; and advancing research to support both goals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, of course, we&#8217;ll collaborate with academic, industry, and state and local partners to better understand Long COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Through it all, we’ll continue to assess and highlight the long-term effects of COVID-19 on our hardest-hit and highest-risk communities, and make sure they receive the support they need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To do this, we&#8217;re launching the first-ever interagency national research agenda on Long COVID &#8212; a National Research Action Plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>HHS will lead a government-wide interagency coordinating council, which will involve experts from the Department of Defense, Veterans Administration, the Labor Department, and many entities across government to coordinate both public- and private-sector work to advance our understanding of Long COVID and to accelerate efforts to prevent, detect, and treat it.</p>



<p>In real time, we will share lessons on how to prevent, detect, and treat Long COVID.&nbsp; And this coordinated effort will help ensure our research is being directed toward the people who need care the most.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We continue to focus on improving care.&nbsp; If we receive additional financial support for it from Congress, we will launch new centers of excellence in communities across the country to provide high-quality care to individuals experiencing Long COVID and to get best practices out there to physicians across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re determined as a nation, as the President has said, to not leave anyone behind.&nbsp; And that includes our loved ones suffering from Long COVID and related conditions.&nbsp; We see you.&nbsp; We&#8217;re focused on you.&nbsp; And we are committed to advancing our nation&#8217;s capacity to understand and treat your conditions.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll end with this: We know the best way to prevent Long COVID is to prevent you from getting COVID in the first place.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so critical to get vaccinated and boosted, which is our best tools that we have to prevent COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I continue to encourage everyone eligible to get vaccinated and boosted to go do it so we can all move forward safely together.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Back to you, Jeff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thanks, Secretary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, Kevin, let&#8217;s open it up for some questions.&nbsp; Kevin?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; We only have time for a few questions today.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Sabrina Siddiqui at Wall Street Journal.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, as always, for doing the briefing.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about COVID funding.&nbsp; Republicans are trying to insert an amendment into the COVID deal to reinstate Title 42.&nbsp; There are even some Democrats, such as Arizona Senator Mark Kelly, who have said that they&#8217;re open to considering such an amendment.&nbsp; Is the administration concerned that the decision to lift Title 42 could now threaten COVID funding?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; Look, Title 42 is a public health authority.&nbsp; And therefore, it&#8217;s always been a decision made by the scientists and public health experts at the CDC.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s based on the public health conditions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it should remain independent of the urgently needed funding that we talked about today to sustain our COVID response here domestically and our global response.&nbsp; So this should not be included on any funding bill.&nbsp; The decision should be made by CDC, which it has been.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s where it belongs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Erin Billups at Spectrum News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thanks so much for taking my question.&nbsp; For Dr. Walensky and Secretary Becerra &#8212; just wondering, with this increased focus on Long COVID, if Type 2 diabetes is being considered a part of the Long COVID problem.&nbsp; There was a new study published in The Lancet last month that finds a link between COVID infections and an increased risk of being diagnosed with diabetes.&nbsp; And experts I&#8217;ve spoken to say there&#8217;s an urgent need to aggressively screen the U.S. population for diabetes and get more people into diabetes management programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Are you looking for funding for that as well?&nbsp; Have there&#8217;s been any discussions about that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, why don’t you go first here?&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for that question.&nbsp; First, let me say we &#8212; the science is definitely starting to demonstrate this link between people who previously had COVID and increasing rates of new diabetes diagnoses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Certainly, public health infrastructure will assist in not only screening for diabetes, but also for nutrition and diabetes care.&nbsp; And I think as we consider the menu of many things that could incorporate &#8212; be incorporated into post-COVID conditions, diabetes certainly should be one of those conditions considered.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Secretary Becerra?</p>



<p>SECRETARY BECERRA:&nbsp; And I’ll simply add, based on what Dr. Walensky has said and our scientists are telling us, we need to work as aggressively as we can to make sure that no American is left behind.&nbsp; So that means that if we need more funding to address Long COVID, we&#8217;re going to fight to get that from Congress because we understand that COVID is having effects long after the actual virus has escaped us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Go to Tamara Keith at NPR.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; By my very rudimentary math, you&#8217;re getting about 60 percent of the money that you asked for, for domestic COVID programs.&nbsp; So what takes the hit?&nbsp; How &#8212; what do you do with only 60 percent of the money?</p>



<p>Additionally, is there any thought of changing the requirements of testing for international travel and masks on planes?&nbsp; If we could get an update on that.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, on your second question: No, there are no plans to change the international travel requirements at this point.</p>



<p>We asked &#8212; your math is good math here.&nbsp; We asked for $22.5 billion, and Congress is working to pass $10 billion &#8212; only a fraction of the immediate need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that immediate need is immediate.&nbsp; It&#8217;s for vaccines, therapeutics, and tests.&nbsp; The $10 billion for domestic efforts funds some of these urgent needs, but we still need additional funding for both our domestic effort and our global efforts where there&#8217;s no additional funding in the $10 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, every dollar we requested is critical to both our domestic and global response.&nbsp; HHS, under the Secretary, will work through how to best deploy these very limited resources to satisfy the most urgent of the urgent needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, yes, we need Congress to pass the $10 billion and then get immediately back to work to get more money for domestic and get money for our global response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next question, please.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Zeke Miller at the AP.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Two questions.&nbsp; First, with the lack of the COVID funding for international vaccine sharing, what impact will that have on the U.S. capacity to (inaudible) the number of doses and meet its international commitments through the end of the year?</p>



<p>And then, for the doctors, do you have any update on plans and timeline for pediatric vaccines for kids under five?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll go first.&nbsp; On the &#8212; on the globe &#8212; on then impact on not having any funding &#8212; additional funding at this point for the global response.&nbsp; Look, the lack of global funding has real implications on our efforts to vaccinate the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without the additional global funding, USAID does not have the resources it needs to help countries get more shots in arms.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be forced to scale back the work that we do to provide oxygen and other lifesaving supplies to countries that need them.&nbsp; Our global genomic sequencing capabilities will fall off, and that undermines our ability to detect emerging variants beyond our borders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And speaking of borders, as I&#8217;ve said, you know, the virus knows no borders, and it&#8217;s in our national interest to vaccinate the world and protect against any possible future variants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s a real disappointment to not have any global funding in this bill.&nbsp; It has real implications.&nbsp; We need funding as quickly as possible. Congress needs to act with urgency to fund our global response so that we can accelerate our efforts to turn vaccines &#8212; we do have vaccine supply &#8212; we need to turn those vaccines into vaccinations around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Fauci.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah, with regard to the vaccines for children, I believe you&#8217;re referring to where are we with the six months to five-year vaccine approval or emergency use authorization.</p>



<p>As you well know, two companies have submitted or are submitting data to the FDA regarding children of various ages, including within that cohort of six months up to five years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The data are being analyzed right now.&nbsp; And I &#8212; we&#8217;re very sensitive to the fact that many parents out there are waiting for a decision on this.&nbsp; And the message we have to them is that we want to make sure that when you&#8217;re dealing with vaccines for anyone, particularly for children, that we get the data, we look at the data &#8212; and when I say “we,” I&#8217;m talking first the FDA for the authorization and then the CDC for the recommendation &#8212; so that we know that they&#8217;re safe.&nbsp; And thus far, there has to be &#8212; appears to be no safety signal whatsoever that would get anyone worried.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the question is: What &#8212; what is the right dose and the dose regimen?&nbsp; And that would likely be different for the two companies that are now involved in putting their data in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we ask people to please be patient, because when a decision is be made, you can be sure that it’s a decision based on the good science that&#8217;s being collected and analyzed by the agencies involved.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Kevin.&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; A couple more questions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Sharon LaFraniere at New York Times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; This is a question for Dr. Walensky, please.&nbsp; So last week, you said that the option of a second booster was especially important for those 65 and up and 50 and up with underlying medical conditions.&nbsp; So does that &#8212; does “especially important” mean that you recommend it or you encourage it for those population groups, and you do not recommend it or encourage it for, say, healthy people 50 to 65?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if &#8212; if it doesn&#8217;t mean that, can you give people some clearer sense of how they should decide whether to get the second booster since many people don&#8217;t have doctors to consult with?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for that question.&nbsp; So we have made the fourth shot &#8212; the second booster &#8212; available to everyone over the age of 50 because everybody does have individual, you know, risk assessment as to how they&#8217;re approaching this vaccine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we really would encourage people who are over 50 who have underlying medical conditions, those over the age of 65, to go ahead and get that next shot.&nbsp; And also, to recognize that they may very well need another shot come the fall, and that will be the subject of an FDA meeting discussion tomorrow.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Kevin, last question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Josh Wingrove at Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit more about the announcement on the pediatric vaccines?&nbsp; Are you able to provide a number?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And is the fact that they&#8217;re essentially sort of subbing in for adult vaccines is &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen Jen Psaki speak to this, but also COVAX &#8212; that demand is waning in developing countries for the adult vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Is that the reason why you&#8217;re essentially swapping?&nbsp; Or is it more a case of you wanting to hold back a little bit more adult vaccine just in case we need, more widely, fourth shots in the U.S. and just in case Congress doesn&#8217;t deliver more funding?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Yeah. &nbsp;So, Josh, good questions.&nbsp; I mean, these donations are part of the billion Pfizer doses that we previously secured.&nbsp; So this is international supply.&nbsp; This has nothing to do with our domestic supply, where we do have enough vaccine supply for the booster doses &#8212; the fourth doses that Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky just talked about that have been recently authorized both for immunocompromised people and for people over 50.</p>



<p>On the domestic front, we do not have sufficient supply if the science dictates that all Americans get boosted sometime later in the year or if we were to need a vaccine-specific variant &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, I&#8217;m sorry, a variant-specific vaccine &#8212; a different formulation than what we have today.&nbsp; We do not have the funding for that.</p>



<p>So on the pediatric international, there are plenty of doses available for adults, which gives us the opportunity to provide 100 million or more doses of Pfizer&#8217;s vaccine for 5-to-11-year-olds to donate in the upcoming months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I mentioned, 20 countries have already asked, including Pakistan and Vietnam &#8212; have made requests to vaccinate their children and to get vaccines to do so.&nbsp; None of this will undermine the position that we have right now, which is that we have plenty of supply in the U.S. to send abroad and other countries around the world to do the same to make sure that we have plenty of vaccines for adults across the world.</p>



<p>So we are now able to help lead the world in vaccinating both adults and children in those countries that are in need.</p>



<p>So before we close, this is likely my last briefing.&nbsp; I just want to say it&#8217;s been the honor of a lifetime to serve in this role.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we enter this new moment in the pandemic, I can&#8217;t think of a better person to hand the baton to than Dr. Jha.&nbsp; I want to thank the Secretary, Dr. Fauci, Dr. Walensky for your partnership and continued leadership.&nbsp; And I want to thank the COVID-19 Response Team here at the White House, everyone inside and outside of government who has worked together tirelessly in our fight against the virus.</p>



<p>And finally, and importantly, to the members of the press: As always, thank you for joining these briefings, asking the questions you ask.&nbsp; And most importantly, thank you for all the important, critical work you do to provide information to the public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So bottom line, thank you.</p>



<p>3:40 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/COVID-Press-Briefing_4.05.22.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/COVID-Press-Briefing_4.05.22.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 5,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/05/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-5-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:52:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:58 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  It’s a busy day here, I would say.  Okay.  Today, as you all know, we announced new actions to cut healthcare costs through the Affordable Care Act. Thanks to President Obama and President Biden, America is more covered than before and well on its way&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:58 P.M. EDT<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Hi, everyone.  It’s a busy day here, I would say. <br> <br>Okay.  Today, as you all know, we announced new actions to cut healthcare costs through the Affordable Care Act.<br> <br>Thanks to President Obama and President Biden, America is more covered than before and well on its way to finally treating healthcare as a right and not a privilege.  This &#8212; thanks to the steadfast leadership, America is better off &#8212; of both of them &#8212; than it was 12 years ago.<br> <br>Through today’s proposed rule to fix the “family glitch,” we’ll expand access to 200,000 uninsured Americans and reduce costs for nearly 1 million Americans.<br> <br>This is no small feat.  This will make for the most significant administrative action to improve implementation of the Affordable Care Act since its enactment.<br> <br>Outside experts have said this action is the boldest thing we can do to expand coverage without congressional action.<br> <br>Already, nearly 6 million Americans have gotten access to affordable healthcare through President Biden’s work to expand access to healthcare.<br> <br>And with congressional action, we can build on the monumental progress we’ve made to date to expand coverage and cut costs for Americans by making the &#8212; the healthcare component in the American Rescue Plan permanent.  And, of course, the 12 states that have not expanded Medicaid could certainly choose to do that as well. <br> <br>With that, Zeke &#8212; oh, let me just note too: All of you know Angela.  But for those of you who don&#8217;t know Angela, she is one of our press assistants.  She went to Georgetown.  I did not get into Georgetown.  So, she&#8217;s very smart, obviously.  (Laughter.)  She&#8217;s also the funniest person on the team.  And she&#8217;s amazing and incredible, and I just wanted to call her out today too. <br> <br>You all know Vedant.  I’ve already done this &#8212; I’ve done this around Vedant.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>So, cheers for Angela for everything she does.  (Applause.)<br> <br>Okay, Zeke.  Sorry to &#8212; sorry to get you off track there.  Go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Administration officials said that, tomorrow, the President is going to extend the student &#8212; pause on student loan repayment for another three months through August.  That would put it &#8212; restarting a couple of months before the midterm elections.  Is that a &#8212; is the President willing to sort of end that pause and have borrowers need to make payments that close to a midterm election?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I &#8212; to not get too ahead to where you are, at this point in time, it expires in May.  Obviously, we&#8217;ll have a formal announcement to make before that timeline.  I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point in time.  <br> <br>Obviously, we look at and assess what the needs are for the people who are impacted by the payment of student loans as we make these assessments. <br> <br>I would note that no one has been required to pay a single dime of federal student loans since the President took office.  And, of course, the Department of Education will continue to communicate directly with borrowers about federal student loan repayment and servicers as we make this final decision.<br> <br>Q    On a different topic &#8212; we’ve heard a lot from the administration about the lack of international COVID relief funding for vaccinations.  Does the President believe that without this money, he can meet his pledge to the world (inaudible) global vaccine sharing?  And does he have to recalibrate now that Congress seems unwilling to provide the necessary funding to get there?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, no, we can&#8217;t meet our commitments and cannot continue to be the arsenal of vaccines to the global community.  Without global funding, USAID won&#8217;t have resources to get more shots in arms, we’ll be forced to scale back our work providing oxygen and antiviral pills, and we will lack the funding to provide rapid testing to countries in need. <br> <br>It&#8217;s not just about vaccine doses, of course &#8212; I know that&#8217;s kind of the question you asked &#8212; ot&#8217;s also about providing the know-how and the individuals at times, the training to be able to get shots in arms.  And those are programs that we fund through our global efforts as well.  And we need that funding in order to continue these programs.<br> <br>Q    And just lastly from me: General Milley had some pretty sobering testimony on the Hill today regarding the state of the world, sort of a grim outlook, saying that “the potential for significant international conflict…is increasing, not decreasing.”  Is that an assessment the President shares?  And is that sort of the assessment of the U.S. government on, sort of, the state of the world right now is darker than it was when the President took office?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, certainly the &#8212; General Milley speaks for the assessment of the U.S. military, and I think that&#8217;s what he was testifying on, and, you know, he speaks on behalf of the administration.  <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    General Milley also said that he thinks the war in Ukraine will be measured in years; that this will be a long, protracted conflict.  Can you clarify?  Do you mean that the ground war will be lasting years?  And is the U.S. committed to aiding Ukraine for as long as this drags on?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we&#8217;re certainly committed to continuing our historic support of Ukraine, whether that is military assistance, humanitarian assistance, economic assistance.  <br> <br>Without further parsing General Milley’s words &#8212; and, certainly, I would point you to the Department of Defense and to him directly &#8212; I think we also understand that the recovery from this war, the rebuilding in Ukraine &#8212; people who have lost their homes, communities that have been destroyed &#8212; is going to take some time, and the United States will certainly continue to be a part of that.<br> <br>Q    And President Zelenskyy, today, effectively asked, you know, what&#8217;s the point of the U.N. Security Council if they can&#8217;t find a way to hold Russia accountable, given Russia&#8217;s veto power?  He suggested the Council was powerless and outdated.  Does he have a point?  And does the White House think the Security Council needs to be reformed?  And is that even possible?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think he&#8217;s certainly referring to &#8212; obviously, he can speak for himself &#8212; but his frustration, which we share, that Russia is a permanent member of the U.N. Security Council.  We don&#8217;t see that changing.  <br> <br>And so what our objective is at this point in time is on a couple of fronts.  One is to continue to provide a range of security assistance to Ukraine &#8212; directly to Ukraine, to the military that is serving boldly and bravely on their behalf. <br> <br>I can provide you a little bit of an update on that.  That, in addition to the deliveries of the $200 million package announced on March 12th &#8212; which are almost complete &#8212; deliveries of the $800 million package the President announced on March 16th are actively occurring.  And, obviously, the Department of Defense has also announced a range of equipment that is being provided. <br> <br>I&#8217;d also note that there are a range of mechanisms as it relates to accountability.  And, you know, that relates to the President&#8217;s strong statements about his view and belief that Russia and President Putin are guilty of war crimes and, obviously, the atrocities that have taken place.  And they are not necessarily through the U.N. mechanisms.  And there are obviously challenges to that, given Russia is a permanent member.  <br> <br>But there are ample examples in the past of other international bodies, and we will continue to support those efforts as well. <br> <br>Q    And just one more.  The sanctions that are coming tomorrow &#8212; being announced by the U.S. and European partners &#8212; are expected to in part target Russian government officials and their family members.  Is this also expected to include Putin’s daughters?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have more specifics to detail or preview for you at this point in time.  It is expected &#8212; or you can expect, I should say, as many of you have reported, that they will target Russian government officials, their family members, Russian-owned financial institutions, also state-owned enterprises. <br> <br>It&#8217;s a part of the continuation of our efforts to put consequences in place, hold &#8212; hold Russian officials accountable.<br> <br>And, again, those announcements will be made tomorrow. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Secretary of State Blinken earlier today said that the killings in Bucha are not a random act by a rogue unit but that it is a deliberate campaign by Russia to commit these atrocities.  But he did not offer any evidence the U.S. has to back up this claim.  I’m wondering if the White House can share any evidence to that effect?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think what the Secretary was referring to is the fact that we have predicted and laid out very clearly the intention of President Putin and the Russian military to commit atrocities.  That&#8217;s what they have done.  We have seen with our own eyes what they have done.  That is consistent with but a little different from a question about a process, which is a process that would take place on the &#8212; through an international mechanism, on &#8212; to have a review or have a investigation into war crimes.  That is a process that we would certainly be supporting &#8212; supporting in a range of ways. <br> <br>But what he was speaking to is the fact that we had predicted it; what we predicted has unfortunately happened.  And we&#8217;ve only seen, potentially, the tip of the iceberg because of where we have had access to.  We have not acc- &#8212; had access to an expanse of the country where they have likely also committed atrocities.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.  And one quickly on sanctions.  We&#8217;ve sort of increasingly seen evidence that Russia is turning to China to circumvent Western sanctions.  We just had a report that Reuters said today about Russia turning to China for microchips.  They&#8217;re also &#8212; they have a payment card that they have now issued in conjunction with China&#8217;s UnionPay, which is an alternative payment system, as you&#8217;re aware. <br> <br>And I&#8217;m wondering if what is going to be announced tomorrow will, you know, have anything to do with making China comply with Western sanctions.  I mean, if you can &#8212; if you can speak to that.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  That continues to be not just our expectation, but what we&#8217;ve conveyed directly.  But these sanctions are related to Russia. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    First, on sanctions: Last night, the Treasury Department shifted their general licenses a little bit in terms of payments &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; from foreign reserves in U.S. institutions.  Is it fair to say that the goal right now is to have a sovereign default with Russia in terms of how you want to impose costs?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  The goal is to force them to make a choice.  So, Russia does not have unlimited resources &#8212; especially now, given the crippling sanctions we&#8217;ve put in place &#8212; and they are going to be forced to choose between draining remaining valuable dollar reserves or new revenue coming in or default. <br> <br>Part of our objective here &#8212; the biggest part of our objective here is to deplete the resources that Putin has to continue his war against Ukraine.  And, obviously, causing more certainty &#8212; uncertainty and challenges to their financial system is a part of that.  But it is forcing them to choose those options and to also deplete the resources, making it more difficult for him to continue to fight the war.<br> <br>Q    Longer term &#8212; Jake yesterday said something along the lines of, “This is not the time for complacency.”  I understand the alliance that&#8217;s been put together over the last six months doesn&#8217;t have a lot of precedent.  But how real is the concern that if this is protracted &#8212; if this is months, not weeks &#8212; that fractures could end up coming to pass in the alliance you guys have put together?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  We have been very clear-eyed about that possibility from the beginning, which is why there has been so much effort on the diplomatic front to work at it, including, obviously, the President&#8217;s trip to Europe.  Secretary Blinken is on his way, or maybe he&#8217;s there now, in Europe.  There are calls that happen every single day, through nearly every national security official, to continue to work towards that coordinated unity that has been so effective to date.  <br> <br>It is also true, though, that “unity” does not mean “identical.”  And as we&#8217;re looking at the consequences people are putting in place, the actions they&#8217;re taking, our expectation is not that it is identical.  It is just our effort to do everything we can to make sure it&#8217;s coordinated and it’s unified as it possibly can be. <br> <br>Q    And then, last one real quick.  I think you addressed it yesterday, so I apologize.  But when you talk about the bridge, from the SPR perspective &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; is it a bridge to &#8212; do you believe the domestic industry will be able to fill that gap within the next six months?  Or is it a bridge to domestic plus Canada plus the Middle East?  How are you guys see what that is a bridge to in terms of production?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  A combination, I would say, Phil.  As you know, the oil market is a global market.  And we certainly understand and have seen that, obviously, the actions of President Putin has led to an increase in gas prices, not just here in the United States but in other countries in the world. <br> <br>We also know that as other countries make decisions about energy sanctions, that could have an impact on the amount of supply in the marketplace. <br> <br>So we are taking steps that &#8212; obviously, a historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve over the next six months &#8212; to hopefully give a bridge to domestic &#8212; increase domestic production, to your point, which we know could take a little bit of time. <br> <br>But also, during that time, we&#8217;re also working with other countries around the world.  You saw the announcement many of them made last week about their increased releases, but also to see what they can do to increase their supply into the marketplace as we&#8217;re filling that gap. <br> <br>Go ahead, Weijia.<br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  Today, Secretary Blinken also said that the U.S. was continuing to gather evidence and will continue to support Ukraine and the U.N. Human Rights Council as it relates to a possible war crime trial.  <br> <br>I know yesterday Jake said the U.S. was looking at a variety of mechanisms.  But since the U.S. is not party to the ICC, other than a supportive role, what can it do to facilitate a trial?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, let me give you an update on where we are.  And I would also &#8212; let me first point to the fact that, historically, we have provided evidence to the ICC even though we are not a party member.  <br> <br>So if you look back in 2004, the State Department collected evidence indicating that the Sudanese military and militias were committing specific acts of violence against members of non-Arab groups in Darfur.  And the Secretary of State at the time, Colin Powell, determined that what was happening was a genocide, and we worked with ICC and the U.N. Security Council to hold accountable.  So I would just note there is historic reference.  <br> <br>Now, also, as you&#8217;re thinking about the timeline of this, the historic reference for that is also important because that liter- &#8212; that was 2004, and it is just starting now.  So, it takes time.  <br> <br>Now, it doesn&#8217;t always take that amount of time.  But just &#8212; you know, as you&#8217;re looking at the history here.<br> <br>But right now, there are a number of efforts already underway to hold any Russians accountable for atrocities and war crimes.  <br> <br>Over the past few weeks, we established investigations through the U.N. Human Rights Council and the OSCE of possible violations by Russia.  We&#8217;re also supporting the work of the war crimes unit under the Office of the Ukrainian Prosecutor General and a team of international prosecutors who are working with them, and also supporting Ukraine&#8217;s authorities and civil society organizations who are working on the ground to document atrocity crimes for prosecution.  <br> <br>And we also welcome the investigation opened by the ICC Prosecutor, in particular his focus on preserving evidence of possible atrocity crimes. <br> <br>And as you noted, Jake outlined the specific ways that we can help in those efforts, including through intelligence sources, and gathering and sharing that with our partners, including helping Ukrainians and what they&#8217;re doing on the ground to develop their case.  Third is working through international organizations.  And the fourth, as he noted yesterday, is all of you and the range of important reporting and sharing of images and information gathering that&#8217;s happening out there.  <br> <br>But those are the different &#8212; different options and different mechanisms we&#8217;re working through now.  But it has not yet been determined what the international mechanism is.  <br> <br>Q    And you mentioned that&#8217;s going to take a lot of time.  It seems that you&#8217;ve also indicated that every sanctions package is not meant to be an on and off switch to stop Putin &#8212; that that will also take time.  Is there anything that can be done to stop Putin now, in the immediate?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say first, on sanctions, we have a couple of objectives.  One of them is to put consequences in place, put a marker down and make very clear it&#8217;s absolutely unacceptable, horrific, and there should be consequences. <br> <br>The second is to make it more difficult to fund the ongoing war.  And that is a very important component.  And the question Phil asked earlier &#8212; about the bond payments and the bond payment that is due &#8212; is an example of that and the mechanisms we have through our economic resources to do exactly that. <br> <br>And the third is to make clear and make it evident to President Putin and Russian leadership in the world that he is a pariah, and now is &#8212; and will be held accountable and treated in that way on the global stage.  <br> <br>But what we&#8217;re &#8212; what we feel is the most effective thing we can do now, in addition to that, is to continue to provide military assistance, security assistance, equipment on the ground.  <br> <br>I would note, again, the Department of Defense announced a series of additional military pieces of equipment that they had not priv- &#8212; previously delivered that they were delivering to the ground.  And we are focusing that effort on ensuring it is equipment that the Ukrainians are trained on and that they have already been using effectively in this war to fight the Russians. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    And just to follow up on Weijia’s question, you guys are adding more sanctions, saying that the sanctions are going to take time to have an impact.  How much time do you guys think that these innocent Ukrainians have?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think what&#8217;s important to note here is sanctions are just one component of the tools that we have at our disposal.  What we are doing and we&#8217;re already seeing effectively happen is the financial system in Russia is near the brink of collapse.  I mean, they&#8217;re projecting 15 percent inflation &#8212; a contraction of 15 percent &#8212; in their economy.  Private sector businesses are pulling out of the country.  <br> <br>It is more and more difficult for President Putin to fund this war every single day.  That has an impact. <br> <br>But what we&#8217;re also doing is providing a historic amount of military and security assistance, which is what they&#8217;ve been using effectively over the last few weeks to fight this war and push back the Russians.  <br> <br>Q    But do you guys assess that anything you&#8217;ve done so far has prevented a war crime from happening?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, Peter, I would say that everything we&#8217;re doing to date is to support the Ukrainians in this war and in this effort.  And that is something the President is proud of, we are proud of, including rallying and leading the global community and standing up against Russia.<br> <br>Q    Okay.  On another topic: A lot of stories about Hunter Biden surfacing this week.  So, to ensure the independence of the investigation, would the President support the appointment of a special counsel?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, the President has never had a conversation with the Department of Justice about any investigations into any member of his family.  He said that during the campaign, and he will continue to abide by that.  So, I would point you to the Department of Justice for any additional steps they would take.  They would make those decisions independently.<br> <br>Q    Is there any concern that they&#8217;re not going to be necessarily seen as being able to make the decisions independently if the White House Chief of Staff is out saying that the President is confident his son did not break the law?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, that&#8217;s something the President has said and certainly we would echo.  But in the same answer to that question, Peter &#8212; during an interview this week on ABC, Ron Klain also said the Justice Department is independent and they will make their own decisions.<br> <br>Q    And the President has said that he never spoke to his son about his overseas business dealings.  Is that still the case?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yes. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    So, tomorrow, you&#8217;re going to announce &#8212; the White House is going to announce new sanctions.  The administration will have new sanctions on Russia in some form.  Should we view those sanctions as a response to Bucha?  Or how should we view those when they’re announced?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, unfortunately, the photos &#8212; the horrific photos we&#8217;ve seen from Bucha are not the first violation of war crimes or atrocities that we&#8217;ve seen take place on the ground.  So, in part, yes.  But they have been in the works and part of our process of putting in place consequences.<br> <br>Q    Which is to say there may be more?  Should we anticipate more in terms of reaction to Bucha?  This wouldn&#8217;t be in isolation?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Correct.  We are continuing to assess and make decisions additional consequences and steps we can put in place.<br> <br>Q    So, given these awful videos and pictures we’re seeing of the atrocities that took place in Bucha right now.  Is the U.S. policy still one of no regime change in Russia?  And if so, why should someone like Vladimir Putin be viewed by the U.S. as someone who should be allowed to stay in power? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think our policy is: No, we are not calling for regime change.  And that has not been our policy and continues not to be our policy.  <br> <br>But again, Peter, our view is that he is a war criminal, and he is somebody who should be looked at by the international system who evaluates war crimes.<br> <br>Q    I guess the question &#8212; people say, “Then why not?  If he&#8217;s a war criminal, why should he be allowed to stay in power?”  <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, our policy is not to call for regime change.  We&#8217;re not calling for regime change.  But again, he is somebody who&#8217;s committed atrocities against the people in his country; he&#8217;s a pariah in the world.  And every step we&#8217;ve taken has made that clear to the global community.<br> <br>Q    Very quickly, can you pull back the curtain on what happened upstairs when we weren&#8217;t watching between the former President and the current President over lunch?  Did they talk about Putin, Ukraine?  Did they do a tour of the Residence?  What can you tell us about their time together? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You know, I haven&#8217;t had a chance to download yet with the President.  I did see the former President briefly, but his schedule is a little lighter than the current President’s these days. <br> <br>I do know that they had a great, expansive conversation.  I haven&#8217;t downloaded on the specifics of it yet.  I&#8217;m not sure I&#8217;ll be able to share those with all of you.  They did go take a look at the Oval Office and take a walk around.  And I know they enjoyed spending time together. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Just to put a finer point on some of the questions you, so far, have been asked: Why shouldn&#8217;t the images of the atrocities from Bucha compel a worldwide, unified coalition kinetic response? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  You mean a military war?  Tell me more about what you mean.<br> <br>Q    Sure.  A military response led by the United States and the international partners.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  As in bringing military troops on the ground from the United States and NATO? <br> <br>Q    Well, the President has described “outrageous” things.  You’ve called them atrocities.  You&#8217;ve said, perhaps “we should brace ourselves” for worse.  Why not?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I think what the President&#8217;s objective is and his responsibility is to make decisions that are in the interest of the United States and the national security of the United States and the American people, and that is not to go to war with Russia.  It is to do everything in our power to hold them accountable; to support efforts through international systems to do exactly that; and to provide military assistance, security assistance, and support to the Ukrainian people and the Ukrainian government.  That&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re doing.<br> <br>But it is not in our interest or in the interest of the American people for us to be in a war with Russia. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    To follow up on Phil&#8217;s question on the Russian sovereign debt: Does the White House have any sense of timing on when Russia might default?  <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I don&#8217;t have an assessment of that.  I will be looking forward to reading Bloomberg’s assessment of that.  But I don&#8217;t have an assessment of that from here. <br> <br>Q    And then also &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  It depends, in part, on what decisions they make.<br> <br>Q    On what decisions Russia make.  Okay. <br> <br>And then, on the Federal Reserve search &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; is the White House still searching for a nominee to replace Sarah Bloom Raskin?  And when are you expecting to make an announcement on that nomination?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  My understanding of the processes is it&#8217;s ongoing.  I don&#8217;t have an update on the timeline of when that would be concluded.  <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    A question on sanctions &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; the new ones that you&#8217;re going to announce this week.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    Can you &#8212; is there anything you can tell us about them?  And just to follow up: If China and Brazil and India and the Middle East are not participating, how effective can they be? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, tomorrow, what we&#8217;re going to announce &#8212; this is what I can tell you.  And it may not be fully satisfying, but let me do my best.<br> <br>In coordination with the G7 and the EU, an additional sweeping package of sanctions measures that will impose costs on Russia to send it further down the road of economic, financial, and technological isolation.  This will include a ban on all new investment in Russia, increased sanctions on financial institutions and state-owned enterprises in Russia, and sanctions on Russian government officials and their family members. <br> <br>These measures will degrade key instruments of Russian state power, impose acute and immediate economic harm on Russia, and hold accountable the Russian kleptocracy that funds and supports Putin&#8217;s war. <br> <br>So this is going to be done in coordination with others.  And those &#8212; the steps will be targeting, as I just noted, obviously, family members, Russian government officials, and other state-owned enterprises and financial institutions.<br> <br>Q    There&#8217;s some pretty big economies that are not participating. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Again, I think what we&#8217;re doing is we&#8217;re working to rally the world in taking steps to hold Russia accountable.  It does not mean they&#8217;re identical.  It doesn&#8217;t mean they all happen on the exact same timeline.  But that is what we&#8217;re continuing to work to do from here. <br> <br>Q    No, I&#8217;m asking about the countries that are absolutely not participating in your sanctions, like China and Brazil and India.  Is that &#8212;  <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I understand what you&#8217;re asking.  I understand what you&#8217;re asking.  What I&#8217;m conveying is that we are also coordinating with the G7 and the EU, which is about 50 percent of the global economy, which is still a significant unified entity, in holding Russia accountable. <br> <br>And in our conversations, obviously, we had our Deputy National Security Advisor travel to India recently to convey the implementation of our own sanctions.  And our expectation is not only that other countries will abide by, but that they will also<br>be a constructive part of holding Russia accountable. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you so much.  Just a question to see if you have any reaction to Viktor Orbán’s victory and whether &#8212; what kind of message that might send to allies in Europe. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Let me check with our national security team.  I&#8217;m sure we can get you a direct reaction to it.  <br> <br>Q    And then, I just wanted to ask, on COVID, if the President is seeing any sort of &#8212; having any new restrictions or if there are new procedures that are in place, just given &#8212; there have been a number of staff at the White House who have COVID, there have been a number of reporters who have COVID; many of them were mixing this weekend at a dinner.  Is that &#8212; <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Which he did not attend.  But &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Which he did not attend.  Which he did not attend.  But is there any sort of additional heightened concern, just given this moment and the fact that a lot of people in this town seem to be getting it?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, we know that BA.2, which is the dominant variant, is a very transmissible variant.  And so, we&#8217;ve obviously been watching that and &#8212; watching that closely.  And certainly, we knew that &#8212; as it has been the case in the broader population, including among the media, but also among staff &#8212; that means that there will be people who get COVID who are fully vaccinated and have been boosted, especially in the White House and I think with most members of the media as well. So, fortunately, what we&#8217;re seeing is largely mild symptoms. <br> <br>But what we do &#8212; the policies we do here &#8212; which we have not changed, but they are more stringent than the CDC.  So just to reiterate for all of you, the &#8212; our policy is that all Executive Office of the President employees surrounding the President are on a regular testing schedule to screen for COVID on campus.  That is a step beyond CDC guidance.  If you&#8217;re going to see the President, you will be tested that day, even if you&#8217;re not traveling with him &#8212; just if you&#8217;re going to see him for a meeting. <br> <br>The President&#8217;s doctor will continue to determine if additional testing is needed on any given week, in light of various considerations.  For example, because of the travel from a couple of weeks ago, he was tested, in addition to his regular cadence, after he came back.<br> <br>And importantly, as I noted, everyone going to a meeting with one of any of the four principals is obviously tested.  <br> <br>In addition, for those employees who test positive &#8212; and I can confirm this two times over &#8212; they&#8217;re required to isolate in alignment with CDC guidance, must test negative before returning to work.  That&#8217;s a step beyond what CDC recommends.  And if they test negative under 10 &#8212; under 10 days, they&#8217;re required to wear a mask for that period of time as well.  <br> <br>And meetings with the President are often socially distanced in many circumstances as an additional precaution, even as people are tested.  <br> <br>So, there are a range of steps, my point is.  I&#8217;m sorry, that was a lot of &#8212; a lot of list.  But is that we take a range of steps.  We have been taking a range of steps that are meant to put an extra layer on in protecting the four principals and given it is the White House.<br> <br>Q    Is there any thought to having the President take any medication prophylactically in case that he is in contact with somebody with COVID?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Not that I&#8217;m aware of.  I don&#8217;t even know what that would be.  But not that &#8212; not that I&#8217;m aware of.  He &#8212;<br> <br>Q    There are (inaudible) medications &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  He take &#8212; he &#8212; obviously, he relies on the advice of his doctor, but not that I&#8217;m aware of.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Yeah, thanks, Jen.  Senators Romney and Murkowski yesterday announced their support to &#8212; or plans to vote to confirm Judge Jackson later this week or perhaps next week.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Hopefully this week &#8212;<br> <br>Q    Yeah, this week &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  &#8212; because they&#8217;re going on recess. <br> <br>Q    Yeah, yeah.  Good point. <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Don’t tell senators you said that. <br> <br>Q    No.  That was a &#8212; that was a mix-up right there.  But what is your reaction to what you heard from Senators Romney and Murkowski there?  <br> <br>And it looks likely that she will get three Republican votes in support.  Does the White House believe that that&#8217;s a strong showing of bipartisan support for that &#8212; for her?  Or, you know, the fact that 47 Republicans appear likely to vote against her &#8212; you know, are you displeased with the lack of support of Republicans? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would note first that even for a number of senators who decided not to support her &#8212; and there&#8217;s quite a good little video “The Daily Show” may or may not have done on this &#8212; all of them talked about her impeccable credentials, her qualifications, what an incredibly inspiring story she has, and how qualified she is for the job.<br> <br>I would say: We believe &#8212; we&#8217;ve believed from the beginning that her record, her impeccable credentials warranted bipartisan support.  And that is exactly what she is going to get in her confirmation, thanks to those individuals and one more that had previously announced their support. <br> <br>So, we&#8217;re certainly encouraged by that.  We&#8217;re looking forward to seeing her confirmed and, of course, celebrating her confirmation to the Supreme Court.  <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  The CDC Director announced that she&#8217;s going to be doing a review of the agency &#8212; <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; and a revamp after they see what has worked and what hasn&#8217;t worked.  Is there something specific that the CDC has been doing wrong or some area where it’s been falling short that&#8217;s prompted this need to have such an intense review right now?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  Well, let me first say this is a CDC-driven decision, and they&#8217;d have more specifics.  But what I would say is that if you look back to the last year plus, never in its 75-year history has the CDC had to make decisions so quickly based on limited real-time and evolving science. <br> <br>And yesterday, what the CDC Director did is rightfully announce plans to initiate a review of the agency to &#8212; with the objective of strengthening, transforming, and modernizing CDC systems and processes around developing and deploying its science. <br> <br>I mean, look at what they&#8217;ve done over the last year.  Does it mean everything has been perfect?  They would say no.  You have to look at how it&#8217;s done, assess that, and take a look at how you&#8217;re going to improve things &#8212; anything you need to &#8212; moving forward. <br> <br>It&#8217;s not uncommon for a CDC Director to ca- &#8212; a take a careful look at the agency and assess if it&#8217;s positioned to meet current public health needs and recommend improvements to systems, processes, and structures. <br> <br>And while this is something that is being done independent of the White House, we certainly support all government working to improve systems and make things better.<br> <br>Q    It’s independent, and you said it was a CDC-driven decision.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah. <br> <br>Q    So this call for the review did not come from the White House? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  No.  It was a &#8212; it was CDC driven, and one &#8212; and certainly one we support.  But the process will be led by the CDC.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Jen, Senate Republicans are calling for an amendment on Title 42 to be attached to the COVID relief funding bill.  I just wanted to get the White House reaction to that.  But then also, what kind of effects are you guys worried about if this funding measure gets delayed or doesn&#8217;t pass?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I think my colleague &#8212; I don&#8217;t know, he&#8217;s seems senior to me &#8212; Jeff Zients said this.  What he said in response that &#8212; to this question is that decisions on Title 42 should &#8220;remain independent of the urgently needed funding&#8221; for COVID aid.  I mean, this is a decision made by the CDC.  It&#8217;s a public health decision.  It&#8217;s not one that should be wrapped up, of course, in politics.  And the decision made by the CDC is where it should belo- &#8212; belong as it relates to Title 42.<br> <br>I would note on your earlier question, you know, the impact of not getting this aid would be &#8212; would be significant.  Right now, these additional resources are urgently needed for our domestic response, including &#8212; just to give you a sense of some examples of how it would be used: booster shots for the general population, monoclonal antibodies and Evusheld for the immunocompromised, maintaining our testing capacity.  These are all components that are vital to our continued fight against &#8212; against the pandemic.<br> <br>And, you know, these are efforts that shouldn&#8217;t be political.  They shouldn&#8217;t be controversial.  We&#8217;re all &#8212; certainly COVID-19 doesn&#8217;t look at your party affiliation before they decide to &#8212; before it decides to inflict you with the virus.<br> <br>And so, they&#8217;re vital.  We need this funding.  And we&#8217;ll have to stop, as I&#8217;ve noted in here before, a number of these important programs if we don&#8217;t get the funding.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  I&#8217;m trying to understand how you see this &#8212; this horrible &#8212; it&#8217;s horrible news coming out of Ukraine with these massacres.  I’d like to understand: Do you see it as something fundamentally, you know, like a game changer?  Or is it just another incremental, you know, awfulness and a thing that&#8217;s been going on for now well over a month? <br> <br>And if it is something fundamentally different &#8212; these people with their hands tied and thrown into pits and cellars and whatever &#8212; does that mean that we can expect to be hearing a fundamentally different response?  Because that&#8217;s also been &#8212; also incremental.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say, first, that there&#8217;s nothing normal, there&#8217;s nothing acceptable, there&#8217;s nothing that shouldn&#8217;t shake people to their core about the photos they&#8217;re seeing of what is happening on the ground &#8212; or what has happened, I should say, on the ground.<br> <br>And what the President has said and been unquestionable about is that these are war crimes &#8212; the violation of the law of war.  <br> <br>And his view &#8212; and I talked to him about this as recently as this morning &#8212; is that we need to put down a marker for history.  That&#8217;s why he has been so outspoken about this and made clear that accountability is critically important when you see the horror that we&#8217;re seeing on the ground &#8212; the targeting of hospitals; of civilians; of, as you noted, the binding and killing of innocent people in Bucha, where we’re seeing the photos.<br> <br>We have all, though &#8212; also already seen evidence of war crimes before these photos.  <br> <br>And a lot of the measures that we’re putting in place &#8212; whether it is supporting international efforts to work towards gathering data and information through a range of mechanisms, or it is continuing to provide additional security assistance or humanitarian assistance &#8212; are in response to the atrocities and the horrors we&#8217;re seeing on the ground. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Yeah, I wanted to ask you about El Salvador, about the &#8220;state of exception&#8221; that has been imposed in El Salvador.  This state suspends constitutional guarantees, such as the right to assemble, and also basic procedural rights for the Salvadoran people.  Is the U.S. concerned about the impact of this measure?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  So, I would say &#8212; sorry, can you ask your question one more time?  I wanted to make sure I had the right information.<br> <br>Q    Of course, yes.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yes, go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Yeah, it&#8217;s about the state of exception that was imposed in El Salvador which suspends constitutional guarantees, such as the right to assemble, and also basic procedural rights for the Salvadoran people.  I wanted to see if the U.S. is concerned about this.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Let me check with our national security team and get more details for you.  And we will get you a more comprehensive comment after the briefing. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  I have a few for you.  I’ll start with the Supreme Court &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    &#8212; vote that took place yesterday.  Is the President disappointed, in particular, that Senator Lindsey Graham, who had voted for Judge Jackson before, opted to vote against her yesterday?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  The President is looking forward to Judge Jackson getting confirmed.  And I would say, as I &#8212; I’d echo what I said yesterday, which is this is a question best posed to Senator Lindsey Graham. <br> <br>What exactly has changed since he voted to support her just recently &#8212; relatively recently?  She has the exact same credentials, exact same qualifications.  <br> <br>So, no, I wouldn&#8217;t say the President is spending a lot of time thinking about it, but I would say it&#8217;s a good question to pose to Senator Graham.<br> <br>Q    On a related topic, I won’t get into all of the President’s polling, but I did want to ask you if you see the expected confirmation of Judge Jackson as a turning point in his presidency.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say, without getting into the politics of it, the President committed to nominate a African American woman to serve on the Supreme Court if there was an opening.  We are on the verge of that woman getting confirmed to the Supreme Court.<br> <br>This is a moment &#8212; even with everything going on in the world &#8212; to celebrate history, to celebrate this incredible woman who has impeccable credentials, who is about to serve on the Supreme Court.  And so, certainly, we&#8217;re going to take a moment to appreciate that and value that.  And I think a lot of people in this country will too.<br> <br>I can&#8217;t make a prediction on what that will mean for polls, and it&#8217;s really not about that for us.<br> <br>Q    And lastly, Jen, President Obama &#8212; former President Obama did seem to get into the politics of it today when he was talking about his own reelection battle and seemed to be delivering somewhat of a pep talk for Democrats facing potentially tough reelection battles in the midterms this year.  Is that a message that the White House wanted him to come here and deliver today? <br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, having worked for the former President for some time and the new &#8212; the newer President for some time as well, here&#8217;s what I heard him talking about: the fact that, in Washington, when you&#8217;re pushing for getting the right thing done &#8212; and he was talking about the Affordable Care Act &#8212; it means sometimes overcoming skepticism, Republican obstruction, even division within your own party, political challenges, countless headlines saying your agenda is dead, and still fighting to get it done. <br> <br>Sounds pretty similar to what we&#8217;re working on today.  That&#8217;s not about the midterms; that&#8217;s about why you&#8217;re in government and making government work for people, and why it&#8217;s important to continue to do, even when everybody says it&#8217;s not possible.  And that was the message I think he was delivering today.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  I have two questions on Ukraine.  Prime Minister Justin Trudeau said last week that he does not want President Putin to attend the G20 meetings and he has reached out to Indonesian President Joko Widodo, who is the host of this year&#8217;s meetings. <br> <br>So, does President Biden have plans to also do the same, to reach out personally to the Indonesian President?  And can you just share anything on the diplomatic front in terms of trying to get Russia out of the G20 meetings or get Ukraine in as an observer?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure, I don&#8217;t have any update on that.  I&#8217;m happy to see if we have any update from our front.<br> <br>Q    Okay.  And then just a follow-up on a different note on Ukraine.  China today urged the U.N. Security Council to verify and not to resort to unfounded conclusions on Bucha.  And meanwhile, Chinese media is also repeating Russia&#8217;s narrative that what&#8217;s happened in Bucha is fake news.  Can we get a White House reaction on that?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I would just say if you&#8217;re repeating the propaganda of the Russian government and President Putin, you&#8217;re on the wrong side of history.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you, Jen.  Last week, a senior Treasury official briefed that the sanctions on Russia were originally intended to deter, but now the point of the sanctions is intended to debilitate and impair the war effort.  Can you elaborate on any change in messaging around the sanctions and their intended purpose and how that&#8217;s changed?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Sure.  Well, look, I think the way we always saw it from the beginning is that the threat of sanctions &#8212; you know, your hope is that there&#8217;s a deterrence effect.  That has been played out in history that there has been a deterrence effect at times.  That is not a sure thing or a 100 percent.  But if it reduces or if it makes a leader potentially think about what actions &#8212; what horrific actions they&#8217;re going to take, then they&#8217;re worth that threat of sanctions.<br> <br>Never has it been the case that the &#8212; putting sanctions in place is it an effective deterrent; the threat of them has been an effective deterrent.  Obviously, the war has commenced. Right?  And sanctions have always had the purpose of putting in place consequences.<br> <br>So, right now, those consequences also include making it very difficult for President Putin to fund the war &#8212; which, as you know, includes steps like the step taken by the Department of Treasury yesterday where they&#8217;re going to be forced, because they don&#8217;t have unlimited resources, to make choices about how they&#8217;re going to spend the resources they have.<br> <br>Q    So how would you describe these latest rounds of sanctions?  Because the administration was very clear in the beginning that if the invasion happened that it would bring forth everything but the kitchen sink.  So that sanctions that we’re seeing rolled out now, how would you describe them?  Are they simply incremental at this point?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, the Russian &#8212; they&#8217;ve all been building on each other.  The Russian economy is on the brink of collapse.  The inflation is skyrocketing at 15 percent.  The detraction &#8212; or the constriction of the economy there is also projecting to decrease by 15 percent.  Bus- &#8212; private-sector businesses are not investing in Russia. <br> <br>And the President is &#8212; President Putin is a pariah.<br> <br>This has all been the result of a coordinated global effort to put in place economic and financial consequences that are having an incredible effect. <br> <br>In addition, we have made it much more difficult, because of export controls and other limitations on the type of materials that President Putin and the Russians can purchase, to build the technological systems and capacities to fight wars, in addition to funding wars.<br> <br>And those are all components that had been the result of the efforts to date.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  I wanted to ask about your Long COVID announcement earlier today.  The criticism that&#8217;s come from lawmakers has been that it&#8217;s going to take a long time to collect data and studies on Long COVID.  Can you talk about how this memo helps people that are living with that now?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I think this is an effort to acknowledge that this is something that many people in this country are suffering from and dealing with.  And unfortunately, science moves at that at the pace of science.  And it is an acknowledgement of that and a commitment by the U.S. government to take steps to look at it more closely and see what more we can do to help address and help people who have been suffering.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    I also wanted to ask about refugees.  I had asked yesterday about the 100,000 number.  You were talking about how the administration&#8217;s response has been geared toward refugees staying in nearby countries.  Can you talk about, though, how you got to that 100,000 number?  Does that have anything to do with the capacity of the U.S. government to take in people that are &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  That’s not exactly what I said yesterday, but I &#8212; what I said was, there is an ongoing policy process that hopefully will be concluded soon, and we&#8217;ll have more to share with all of you soon about the prioritization and how the process will work for these refu- &#8212; Ukrainian refugees who will be eligible.<br> <br>In terms of the number, this is an effort by the President and the United States to welcome through &#8212; through an expedited process &#8212; and a different process that we&#8217;ll have more details on soon &#8212; Ukrainian refugees into the United States, even as we know, factually, that the vast majority of them will want to and have expressed an interest in staying in countries nearby. <br> <br>So, it is just an effort to make clear our willingness and openness to doing that. <br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thanks, Jen.  Can you give us a sense of how President Biden will mark Judge Jackson&#8217;s confirmation later this week?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I expect we&#8217;ll have more details in the coming 24 to 48 hours on that, but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point in time.<br> <br>Q    Jen, there&#8217;s momentum in the European Union to ban all natural gas coming from Europe.  They’re not taking that step, but there&#8217;s momentum.  The European Commission is changing regulations to accelerate approvals for their natural gas infrastructure.  In the announcement in Brussels, the U.S. said they&#8217;re going to keep the regulatory framework.  <br> <br>So how is the U.S. going to continually support enough natural gas should Europe cut off the Russian flow in order to, long term, handle &#8212; to help our European neighbors?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, there are steps we&#8217;ve already taken in preparation that we will build on.  And we will continue to explore ways to ensure that European countries are not as reliant as they have been on Russia for natural gas and for a range of energy resources. <br> <br>One of the steps we&#8217;ve taken successfully, which we will continue to build on, is to tap into countries in Asia who have LNG &#8212; excess LNG capacity to provide that to Europe.  That is something we&#8217;ve already done to date.  And we will continue to explore &#8212; but we&#8217;ve been working on this for months in anticipation of a potential shortage or potential needs in Europe.<br> <br>Q    How about infrastructure projects in the U.S. though to help expand them &#8212; facilitate that going forward?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I &#8212; tell me more about what you mean exactly. <br> <br>Q    Well, I mean Senator Capito &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  To increase capacity &#8212; LNG capacity?<br> <br>Q    To increase capacity &#8212; yes.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I can check with our team and see if there&#8217;s anything to preview on that &#8212; any more.  <br> <br>Go ahead, George.<br> <br>Q    Yeah, there was a recent poll that showed more people think jobs were lost in the last year than think jobs were gained.  Why is that?  And is there anything that you can do to change that perception?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I saw that poll &#8212; or saw that data.  What I can tell you: What we can do from here is share the facts.<br> <br>And I know all of you are working to share facts as well, even as you ask us tough questions and hold us accountable and to account as well.  <br> <br>We know the fact is that the President created more jobs last year than any year in American history.  That is a very simple fact that I probably cannot say enough from here and our allies and partners cannot say enough out there in the country.  And we will just continue &#8212; have to continue to work at it.<br> <br>Q    But why is the &#8212; why is the belief out there, though?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I can&#8217;t make a clear assessment of that, George.  You know, I know that, obviously, people across the country &#8212; we know and we see this in data and polling &#8212; are still feeling the impact of COVID.  Their lives are not entirely back to normal.  They&#8217;re seeing some, you know, restrictions to their daily living, which is frustrating.  <br> <br>Obviously, the impact of the cost of items, whether it&#8217;s the price of gas that has a range of factors that have led to it &#8212; specifically the invasion of Ukraine, most recently &#8212; those impact how people feel.  We see that in consumer confidence. <br> <br>So, I can&#8217;t assess what is in the brain of every American.  But I can tell you what the facts are and tell you that we also recognize that there are areas, including bringing down costs, we’ll continue to work at.<br> <br>Ebony, go ahead. <br> <br>Q    Thank you.  Two quick questions.  One, the President is talking about Congress passing more money for COVID relief.  But what&#8217;s the President&#8217;s reaction to more cities taking COVID relief money and putting it towards policing in excessive amounts &#8212; specifically even like in DeKalb County, where a half million was spent on aerial drones?  I mean, is the President thinking that&#8217;s a bit of an abuse of funds?  Is he okay with that kind of spending?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  I haven&#8217;t seen that report.  I&#8217;d have to look into that specifically more.  I mean, there&#8217;s state and local funding that has gone out through the American Rescue Plan where there is flexibility in there, including to support state and local governments.  I don&#8217;t know if that is what it is being used for, but I&#8217;m happy to check into the more specific reports.  <br>Q    Secondly &#8212;<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Yeah.<br> <br>Q    My last question.  I wanted to ask this a couple of weeks ago, but I want to go back to Haiti very quickly to get the President&#8217;s response.  Patrol agents that were seen whipping Haitian migrants were not charged and held accountable for actions.  Even the President early on talked about how it was outrageous.  How does he &#8212; what&#8217;s his reaction to that response?  And to those who saw this horr- &#8212; horrific video go viral, and then, at the end of the day, nothing happens; there&#8217;s no accountability.<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, there was an investigation by the Department of Homeland Security, so I&#8217;d have you &#8212; point you to them for any further comment on it.<br> <br>Go ahead.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.  Two weeks ago, the President warned the American people and owners and operators of critical infrastructure that Russian cyberattacks were, quote, “coming.”  And he urged those owners and operators to harden their cyber defenses.  Is there any update &#8212; intelligence update that you can give to the American people and critical infrastructure operators about this pretty urgent warning that &#8212; that came recently?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I don&#8217;t have any additional intelligence to update you on from here.  But the reason we did that at the time is because there are steps we can take from the federal government, but there is also steps that private-sector companies can and need to take in order to protect themselves.  Those don&#8217;t typically happen overnight, so we wanted to ensure they understood that these threats are real, that it was urgent that they take these steps.<br> <br>But I don&#8217;t have anything in addition to predict about next steps or intelligence.<br> <br>Q    Any work that officials have done with these owners and operators that you can talk about &#8212; work on the ground?<br> <br>MS. PSAKI:  There is ongoing work that our cyber team has been doing from the beginning of the administration, working closely with the private sector.  That&#8217;s been a huge priority for the President &#8212; the recognition that it needs to be a partnership. <br> <br>And one of the reasons we go out publicly as we do is because even as we’re &#8212; and that was actually on the heels of &#8212; when Anne Neuberger came here, it was on the heels of a briefing she had done with larger institutions to talk about this. <br> <br>We also recognize, though, that cyberattacks can impact smaller institutions, medium-sized institutions, and institutions that, you know, need to know that there are easy steps they can take &#8212; two- &#8212; two-factor authentication, passwords, not clicking on mysterious links &#8212; that can also help protect themselves.  So that&#8217;s why we went out publicly to spread the message broadly.  <br> <br>Thank you so much, everyone.<br> <br>4:46 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
