<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:02:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki and Director of the National Economic Council Brian Deese, July 2, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/02/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-director-of-the-national-economic-council-brian-deese-july-2-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:02:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:16 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Friday.&#160; All right.&#160; So, today, it’s Jobs Day.&#160; We have our special guest, NEC Director Brian Deese, joining us, who will give us an overview and then take some of your questions.&#160;With that, I’ll turn it over to Brian.&#160;MR. DEESE:&#160; Well, I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:16 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Friday.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; So, today, it’s Jobs Day.&nbsp; We have our special guest, NEC Director Brian Deese, joining us, who will give us an overview and then take some of your questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, I’ll turn it over to Brian.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Well, I was going to say it&#8217;s a sign of the progress that we&#8217;re making that the last time that I came here the briefing room was significantly less full than it is right now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we are making &#8212; making progress across the board in all ways, except I guess now you guys are significantly more squished.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; so, yeah, happy to spend a couple of minutes with you guys to just provide a little bit more context.&nbsp; You all heard the President discussing the employment report that we got today, so I just wanted to provide a little bit of additional context on how we are looking at that data in the context of what we&#8217;ve seen over the course of the last couple of weeks and the last week in particular.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, obviously a strong and encouraging jobs report today: 850,000 jobs created last month.&nbsp; That takes us to more than 3 million jobs created since the President took office.&nbsp; Under the hood on that, I just want to just raise a couple of issues.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>First is, in addition to a strong jobs story today, we saw a strong story about wages &#8212; wages for workers.&nbsp; Average hourly earnings were up 3.6 percent over the year.&nbsp; And if you take out the pandemic, some of the &#8212; some of the movements in the pandemic, that&#8217;s &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen the largest three-month increase in wages on record; records go back to 2006.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so I think what we&#8217;re seeing here is a labor market where, as employers are increasingly looking for employment and jobs are plentiful, they are paying higher wages and people are taking jobs at a faster clip.&nbsp; Good news on both fronts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The second is, as we look, there&#8217;s &#8212; obviously there&#8217;s the payroll survey and the household survey.&nbsp; The household survey is what feeds into the unemployment rate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>A couple of things under the hood in the household survey that may be of interest to you, the first is around labor force participation.&nbsp; We saw an increase in labor force participation among the prime-age working population.&nbsp; So for those workers aged 25 to 54, we saw an increase.&nbsp; And in the pandemic, certainly because of the &#8212; some particular &#8212; particularities around teenagers and also early retirements, that prime-age workforce is particularly relevant, and so we keep an eye on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The second is, if you look at the broader definitions of unemployment &#8212; which have been particularly something that we and others have followed over the course of this pandemic &#8212; one notable thing this month is a market decline in the number of people who are working part-time for economic reasons.&nbsp; So this is a category that the Bureau of Labor Statistics tracks where people would like to be working more &#8212; like to be working more hours but are only employed part-time.<br>&nbsp;<br>We saw a 644,000-person decline in that figure over the course of this past month.&nbsp; Again, a sign that those who are wanting to work more are having an opportunity to do so.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that there was a slight intick [sic] &#8212; uptick in the number of long-term unemployed.&nbsp; That number has come down since the President took office, but that&#8217;s an issue that is a reminder that we continue to have challenges in an economy that is coming back from a historic pandemic, and we are still down more than 6 million jobs from where we started.&nbsp; So we still have a lot of work left to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The third point is just to put this report in the context of a set of economic data and indices we&#8217;ve seen over the course of the last week.&nbsp; In particular, it&#8217;s been a heavy week for economic data, so just a couple things I wanted to flag.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We saw consumer confidence come out earlier this week, and not only did we see the index increase for the fourth straight month at very high levels now in terms of consumers’ current and future sentiments about the economy, but a record level of consumers are seeing the job market as improving.&nbsp; So the &#8212; in fact, the share of consumers that say that jobs are plentiful in the economy is now at a 21-year high.&nbsp; So, again, consistent with a strong recovering labor market here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We saw both the Congressional Budget Office and the IMF come up with &#8212; come out this week with updated growth projections.&nbsp; The CBO, in particular, doubled its projected growth for 2021 from 3.7 percent to now 7.4 percent.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the &#8212; if we &#8212; if we achieve that growth in that range, we would be the highest in nearly 40 years.<br>&nbsp;<br>But also, notably, the CBO not only increased its growth projections but projected downward, where unemployment will be next year, and also downwardly revised its projections for 10-year deficits.&nbsp; So, actually, as growth &#8212; as growth estimates increased, its projections for future deficits as a share of our economy came down from where it was projecting in February.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Likewise, on the IMF front, projections of growth at 7 percent for the U.S. economy and, in their words, the fastest pace in a generation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Also this week: Notably, we saw the OECD reach an agreement with 130 countries endorsing a global minimum tax of at least 15 percent.&nbsp; This has been a priority for President Biden in our economic strategy from the beginning of this administration to try to help to galvanize a global effort to actually end the race to the bottom on taxes, and to encourage multinational companies to invest and compete on quality and price, and not on the effectiveness of being able to strip profits into local tax jurisdictions &#8212; a historic announcement this week and an important milestone in our effort to get that done this year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Number four &#8212; and I know &#8212; and then I will take your questions &#8212; is: I just wanted to also let you know, in terms of actions that we&#8217;re focused on to try to help address issues that consumers are facing &#8212; increased competition and lower prices &#8212; I want to confirm that there was some reporting this morning that the President is indeed intending to direct the Department of Transportation to engage in a series of rulemakings to protect airline passengers and to promote fair and competition &#8212; fair competition in the airline industry.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This may sound esoteric, but I&#8217;ll make it very simple, particularly for any of you who have flown or are intending to fly, now that the &#8212; that that&#8217;s more available: These rulemakings will specifically ensure that if a passenger pays to check a bag, they should get that fee back if the bag doesn&#8217;t arrive on time. &nbsp;Also, if the passenger pays for a service like Wi-Fi, and it doesn&#8217;t actually work, that you will get that fee back quickly.<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good luck with that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Um &#8212; and also, the President will direct DOT to ensure rulemaking that will &#8212; that will establish clearer upfront disclosure of fees &#8212; one of the challenges in being able to clearly understand baggage fees, change fees, cancellation fees at the time of the purchase of an airline ticket so that consumers have more and better information and understanding of what they actually are paying for.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that this &#8212; this direction will be part of a broader effort that the President will release shortly around driving greater competition in the economy, in service of lower prices for American families and higher wages for American workers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, with that, I&#8217;m happy to take your questions with one caveat, which you&#8217;ll hear me say every time I come to talk about monthly employment data or anything else, which is: Every piece of data is uncertain.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t look &#8212; we don&#8217;t put too much stock in any one month&#8217;s data.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking at longer-term trends, and certainly as we assess the trend over the longer term, we feel like we are seeing a strong and accelerating recovery connected to and driven by the President&#8217;s economic strategy.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Josh.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, good news on hiring, but we saw an increase in Black unemployment.&nbsp; Unemployment for Black men is about 10 percent &#8212; almost double what it is for white men.&nbsp; Do you expect to close this gap?&nbsp; And which policies are going to be the most important for getting that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m glad you raise the issue and certainly the &#8212; it underscores why it&#8217;s so important to not let up on the strategy that we&#8217;ve been putting in place to drive a strong recovery as fast as we can to get to full employment.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One of the things that we know is that one of the most powerful ways of actually addressing disparities within the labor market, and particularly the persistent gap between unemployment rates for whites and people of color, is to have a strong economy that is operating at full employment where employers are seeking to have a wider scope, and people who want to enter the labor force want to find jobs, have more options, and have more leverage, and have more power in the labor market.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So you&#8217;ve heard the President talk about this; he went to Cleveland and laid this out in a speech that an explicit part of his strategy is to have policies in place to get us to full employment as quickly as possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note, to your question about the most important policies: The American Rescue Plan was the &#8212; was unique across the world in terms of fiscal responses to this &#8212; to this pandemic crisis.&nbsp; The United States stepping in and having a more aggressive fiscal response than almost any country in the world.&nbsp; And what you’ve seen as a result is that most independent projections pulled forward, by a year or more, their projection of when we will get to that full employment.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But as we assess what it means to get to a full employment economy, we believe it&#8217;s critical to look at that from an inclusive perspective and not just look at the headline unemployment rate and recognize that these persistent barriers that have driven those divergences in employment outcomes need to be at the center of what we&#8217;re trying to address and part of what we want this economic recovery to achieve.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Andrea.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Brian, I wanted to ask you about the OECD tax agreement.&nbsp; Are you concerned at all that that could get held up; that the U.S. could have trouble enacting its part of that?&nbsp; And also, there were several countries that are in the European Union that didn&#8217;t sign on.&nbsp; Is that going to be a stumbling block to actually make it happen?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; So, we see the announcement today, or this week, as both a historic milestone and really important momentum to actually achieving both of the elements that you said &#8212; momentum to enact a corporate tax reform in the United States that would not only help to improve U.S. competitiveness by making it more attractive to invest here in the United States rather than invest in shifting production and profits to low-tax jurisdictions, but also raise revenue that we could invest in productivity-enhancing measures like investing in universal preschool.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Along the lines the President has laid out &#8212; and, in fact, the &#8212; one of the principal arguments against the kind of tax reform that the President has laid out is, “Well, if the United States acts, what happens if the rest of the world doesn&#8217;t come along?”&nbsp; Well, with this OECD announcement, we&#8217;re actually demonstrating that the world is prepared to do that, and obviously, it connects to a set of constructive conversations we&#8217;re having with leadership and the relevant committees in Congress right now about moving forward the President&#8217;s corporate tax reform.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this is a process.&nbsp; We &#8212; to your question about the remaining countries, this is a process. &nbsp;We saw at the G7, there were questions: Would the G7 come along and endorse this framework?&nbsp; And, of course, they did.&nbsp; Now, we have 130 countries endorsing this framework.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to keep working at it; we&#8217;re not there.&nbsp; This is a milestone in the process, but a real strong signal of momentum toward the ultimate goal.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Alex.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Brian. &nbsp;Brian, I wonder if you could address that competition initiative that you mentioned &#8212; give us a little bit more flavor of what&#8217;s coming on that.&nbsp; And then, secondly, I wonder if you could address &#8212; the chip shortage is still hurting. &nbsp;Ford, for example, is down 27 percent in June.&nbsp; How much of a drag do you think that&#8217;s going to have on the otherwise rosy outlook you just presented?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, on the first, I would say &#8212; I mean, I won&#8217;t &#8212; I won&#8217;t get ahead of the President.&nbsp; You can anticipate the President is going to be having more to say about this shortly.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an issue that we&#8217;ve been working on across the whole of government, and the actions that I outlined with respect to the Department of Transportation is one element of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think at the core just is &#8212; this is really about trying to imp- &#8212; to recognize that actually having more competition and more competitive markets is actually key to driving strong, durable, shared economic growth.&nbsp; And, in particular, we&#8217;ve seen increasing evidence that the lack of competition in a variety of markets can actually reduce choices and increase prices for consumers, for small businesses, and actually also hurt wages and wage growth for workers in the labor market.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, we&#8217;re looking at an effort across the government, looking at the different antitrust statutes and the different measures that agencies can take to try to improve competition and actually improve the opportunities for businesses to compete fairly without being impeded as well.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll have more to say about that, but that&#8217;s the basic contours of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just chips &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Oh, chips.&nbsp; Yeah, yeah, yeah.&nbsp; So, look, this has been an issue that we&#8217;ve been, you know, focused on for some time.&nbsp; It was the focus of the President&#8217;s 100-day supply chain review.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been in constant and close contact with the auto manufacturers, consumer electronics producers, and also then the chip manufacturers themselves.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say, in the short term, I think we&#8217;re hearing signs of there’s some improvement in the challenges.&nbsp; I think the second quarter clearly was a point where you saw that impacting, both on the production side and the employment side.&nbsp; The &#8212; we &#8212; at least the indications we&#8217;re hearing from industry participants is that you should expect some improvement sequentially over the second half of this year.<br>&nbsp;<br>From our perspective on the policy side, it&#8217;s why we&#8217;re incredibly focused &#8212; you&#8217;ve seen the President laser focused on trying to move and enact his proposal for $50 billion to invest in semiconductor production, manufacturing resilience here in the United States.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the long-term answer to this issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve &#8212; that&#8217;s passed through the Senate.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; we&#8217;re now working with the House to try to advance that legislation as well, and we look forward to getting that to the President&#8217;s desk as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Courtney.&nbsp; Oh, sorry &#8212; Jen.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are &#8212; just to go back to full employment &#8212; what are the metrics that the administration will look to to determine when the U.S. has reached full employment?&nbsp; And then, on manufacturing: Why are manufacturing jobs lagging so much &#8212; up only 15,000 in June, and still 480,000 below pre-pandemic levels?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll take &#8212; I&#8217;ll take the second half of your &#8212; of your question first.&nbsp; And obviously you can have a glass and maybe it&#8217;s half full, maybe it&#8217;s half empty.&nbsp; But I would say, sequentially, what we&#8217;ve seen is progress in the manufacturing sector, both in terms of employment and production.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it&#8217;s important to remember, you know, where we&#8217;re coming from: We had a pandemic and a historic economic crisis that sent &#8212; that cratered production and has created huge supply chain challenges and bottlenecks over the course &#8212; over the course of the economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think what we&#8217;re seeing now is demand has come back faster than anticipated, in large part because of the success of the vaccination effort and the historic fiscal response that the United States has taken, and you&#8217;re seeing manufacturers respond.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly there&#8217;s going to be some short-term issues to work through.&nbsp; But I think, you know, part of the job growth that we saw in June is reflective of the sector&#8217;s ability to start coming back here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the first half of your &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Oh, on full employment.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; So, look, you know, our approach is to &#8212; is to look at this from an inclusive perspective.&nbsp; Our approach has been to say: What does it mean to actually have an economy that is working for everybody, and where workers who want an opportunity to be full participants in the labor market have that opportunity?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That means not only looking underneath the hood of the traditional unemployment rate at the significant discrepancies we&#8217;ve seen historically on racial and ethnic lines, but also parents and women and what are the barriers to full participation in this economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so you certainly see that from the perspective of the Biden economic strategy to try to invest in the drivers that are actually going to increase labor force participation, increase the productive capacity of the economy by having &#8212; driving inclusive growth, shared growth, the kind of growth that we think will be durable across time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Courtney.&nbsp; This is going to have to be the last one.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right back here.&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Hi.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about infrastructure and ongoing negotiations &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the Hill. &nbsp;The House passed its INVEST in America Act &#8212; I believe it was either last week or this week &#8212; and House Transportation Chairman Peter DeFazio has said that he wants the policy in that bill to be how they flesh out the framework that the President agreed on &#8212; the bipartisan framework.&nbsp; Is that something that you would agree with?&nbsp; Is the policy in there what you want it to look like at the end of the day?&nbsp; Are there certain policies you would want to keep in the final bill?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Yeah, so that was &#8212; that was a vote that happened earlier this week, and I congratulate Chairman DeFazio and the committee and the House for progressing that.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is the process.&nbsp; This is the &#8212; you&#8217;re seeing the legislative process work.&nbsp; You saw the Senate committee pass a Surface Transportation Reauthorization unanimously out of committee with Chairman Carper, Ranking Member Capito there.&nbsp; And now you&#8217;ve seen a Transportation Reauthorization pass out of the House as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as we&#8217;ve said for some time, the expectation is that the legislative process will now work the way that it &#8212; the way that it has, and as part of the bipartisan infrastructure framework, moving from a framework or agreement to piece of legislation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As the President has said, the committee chairmen are going to be part of that process.&nbsp; The process is going &#8212; is happening in the Senate right now.&nbsp; But, obviously, working between the Senate and the House is a key element of this, so I think it&#8217;s an important milestone.&nbsp; And Chairman DeFazio has shown extraordinary leadership on this issue, and we&#8217;re going to keep working on it.&nbsp; This is the legislative process in real time working its will.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Brian, so much for joining us.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll be back.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. DEESE:&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, sorry, go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All right.&nbsp; Just two quick items for all of you at the top.&nbsp; As we shared from the podium a few weeks ago, the White House recently established the Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force &#8212; co-chaired by the Secretaries of Commerce, Transportation, and Agriculture &#8212; to bring a whole-of-government approach to addressing the near-term supply chain bottlenecks and supply constraints.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The task force has been actively engaging with a broad set of stakeholders to diagnose problems and identify solutions.&nbsp; And we want to share a few examples of recent engagements, given this is of great interest.&nbsp; Alex asked about it just a few minutes ago &#8212; or a version of it.<br>&nbsp;<br>On homebuilding, Secretary Raimondo and sen- &#8212; senior commerce officials have been meeting with timber and logging companies, sawmill operators, retailers, appliance makers, and homebuilders from across the nation, and will meet in the coming days with affordable housing and labor leaders to ensure the challenges in the homebuilding supply chain are thoroughly understood from every angle to address bottlenecks in the sector.<br>&nbsp;<br>On semiconductors &#8212; which affects many industries, including everything from autos to everyday electronics around our homes &#8212; Secretary Raimondo has continued to bring together semiconductor producers and users to build trust, improve transparency, and facilitate data sharing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Since March, the Commerce Department has supported nearly $75 billion in direct investments from both U.S. and foreign businesses in domestic semiconductor manufacturing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as for the Department of Transportation, under Secretary Buttigieg’s leadership, the agency is helping address the country&#8217;s truck driver shortages by supporting state DMVs as they return or even exceed pre-pandemic commercial driver&#8217;s license issuance rates.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In 2021, an average of 50,000 commercial driver&#8217;s licenses have been issued each month, which is 14 percent higher than the 2019 monthly average and 60 percent higher than the 2020 monthly average.&nbsp; So, clearly, their work is ongoing, but wanted to provide you a bit of an update about their outreach.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, in vaccine sharing news: On Sunday, we &#8212; we will send &#8212; this Sunday, we will send 1.5 million doses of Moderna to El Salvador.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Sorry, I will do the week ahead.&nbsp; Now, as we look to the week ahead &#8212; which, of course, includes this weekend, because the President has a busy schedule &#8212; on Saturday, he will travel to Traverse City, Michigan, with Governor Gretchen Whitmer as part of the administration&#8217;s nationwide America is Back Together Tour to celebrate our country&#8217;s progress against the virus.<br>&nbsp;<br>While there, he will visit a cherry farm, where he will highlight the benefits of the bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and what they will do to deliver to communities acro- &#8212; what it will do to deliver to communities across the country.<br>After his visit to Traverse City, he will travel to Wilmington, Delaware, where he will remain overnight.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On Sunday, the President and the First Lady will return to the White House where they will host a Fourth of July barbecue with essential workers and military families on the South Lawn.&nbsp; At 7:30 p.m. on Sunday night, the President will deliver remarks to celebrate Independence Day and independence from COVID-19.&nbsp; And later that night, the National Mall will be open for the traditional Independence Day fireworks displays so friends and family can gather together to celebrate our independence from the virus.<br>&nbsp;<br>On Monday, the President will not have public events.&nbsp; It is a federal holiday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And next week &#8212; we will have more details, hopefully, in the coming days &#8212; but he will continue to amplify the benefits of the bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, the American Families Plan.&nbsp; And again, we&#8217;ll have more announcements about it in the coming days.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Last thing.&nbsp; Emily, who many of you know &#8212; she&#8217;s going to get embarrassed &#8212; is a part of our amazing press team.&nbsp; She is a spokesperson on economic issues &#8212; not an easy thing.&nbsp; So, she&#8217;s here &#8212; hasn&#8217;t been in the briefing room &#8212; today, so wanted to welcome her here and thank her for all of her work.&nbsp; And also, to Chairman Schiff, who let me steal her from him, which I&#8217;m very grateful for every day.&nbsp; So, just wanted you to all know Emily if you don&#8217;t already know Emily.<br>&nbsp;<br>Josh, go ahead.&nbsp; Josh definitely knows Emily.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Given last night&#8217;s announcement on halting federal executions, is the President satisfied with the moratorium as it stands, or does he want to go further?&nbsp; And does he believe that Justice Department lawyers should continue to seek the death penalty in cases or should they hold off?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I will first say, Josh, that the President made clear, even during his first conversations with then-Judge Garland about the job, that he wanted to see an end to executions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the announcement that was made today is &#8212; he&#8217;s pleased to see that the Attorney General is taking steps forward which will put a stop to executions at the federal level during this review.&nbsp; And that is what&#8217;s ongoing, and he feels that&#8217;s an important step forward in delivering on that discussion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, with regard to the President and sexual assault cases and, kind of, where they are in the military chain of command: The President stopped short of where Senator Gillibrand is on having independent prosecutors handle felonies that call for more than a year in prison.&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s thinking on, kind of, the decision relative to that proposal?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would note that we put out a statement from the President.&nbsp; And let me just highlight some &#8212; some components of that for all of you, because this was an important step forward in his view today:<br>&nbsp;<br>He strongly supports Secretary Austin&#8217;s announcement that he’s accepting the core recommendations put forward by the Independent Review Commission on Military Sexual Assault.&nbsp; He views sexual assault as an abuse of power, an affront to our shared humanity.&nbsp; And sexual athault [sic] &#8212; assault in the military is doubly damaging, in his view, as it also shreds the unity and cohesion that is essential to a functioning U.S. Military and to our national defense.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also noted &#8212; and just to answer your question &#8212; that he looks forward to working with Congress to implement these necessary reforms.&nbsp; He&#8217;s grateful for the leadership of Senator Gillibrand, the work of Senator Ernst, Representative Speier, and Representative Mullin who have worked in a strong bipartisan way to move this forward.&nbsp; And certainly he feels that this announcement and the decision by Secretary Austin is a step forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Same two subjects.&nbsp; First, to the death penalty: There had been a campaign pledge to introduce legislation to end the federal death penalty.&nbsp; Is that still coming?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I would say that the President felt it was so important that it was a part of his discussion with the Attorney General when he interviewed him and talked to him about the job.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He is now &#8212; the Attorney General today announced that there will be a halt on executions while there&#8217;s an important review, and the President feels that&#8217;s an important step forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some advocates have called on him to commute all federal death penalty sentences.&nbsp; That&#8217;s different than what the Attorney General did.&nbsp; Has there been any discussion of doing that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s a review that was just announced.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t expect that we would speak to that while it&#8217;s ongoing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the sexual assault report, it found, in part &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to quote here &#8212; “a wide chasm between what senior leaders believe is happening under their commands and what junior enlisted service members actually experience.&nbsp; As a result, trust has been broken between commanders and the service members.”&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s a scathing vote of no confidence on a predominantly male military leadership.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m just curious, in his discussions with the Secretary of Defense or with uniformed leaders, if he, the President, has talked to these guys at all about the fact that this persists and is now called out in this report?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s certainly spoken with Secretary Austin about it.&nbsp; He&#8217;s spoken about &#8212; publicly about his concern, about what he&#8217;s seen in the reports of sexual assault in the military that have &#8212; were happening, of course, long before he became President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he also called out, in a statement today &#8212; he wanted to recognize the experience of our service members who have survived sexual assault, and the bravery of those who&#8217;ve shared their stories with the world and advocated for reform, which is something he felt was important to note and call out today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that Secretary Austin, in coming out and accepting these core recommendations, is taking an action step to change, and hopefully change the course of, what we&#8217;ve seen over the last several &#8212; for several years &#8212; something the President certainly applauds and supports.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it’s going to take until at least 2023 to get much of this implemented.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve got a bill in the Senate that has 60 votes at least; it&#8217;s bipartisan.&nbsp; Is there going to be a push by him to say, “Yes, let&#8217;s do this.&nbsp; It&#8217;s another example of bipartisan cooperation.&nbsp; It addresses this issue.”?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he note- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, why not come out and endorse it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He noted in his statement that he looks forward to working with Congress to implement these necessary reforms and to mot- &#8212; promote a work environment that is free from sexual assault and harassment for every one of our brave service members.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, yes, it is also the military &#8212; the leadership in the military &#8212; Secretary Austin, someone the President nominated and works with on a daily basis &#8212; who accepted these recommendations, and they need to be implemented.&nbsp; That will take some time, but that&#8217;s a forward step that was taken by our own military.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, some housekeeping, if I can, quickly: We saw all the debris when we arrived here at the White House earlier today.&nbsp; The President and First Lady were back at the White House when the tornado warning was in effect yesterday.&nbsp; Where did the President and First Lady shelter during the tornado warning?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I know they were &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if they were back from their trip yet or if they were arriving shortly back from their trip &#8212; they were here at the White House.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more details on whether they were moved.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would you follow up for us, possibly, and let us know (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to.&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me ask you:&nbsp; As we head into July 4th, very quickly, obviously the White House has said repeatedly that shots are safe, they&#8217;re effective, they&#8217;re available, but obviously, many states with the lowest vaccination rates are governed by Republicans right now.&nbsp; What risk does the White House believe those pockets of noncompliance might pose to other Americans, to the rest of the country right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the guidance from medical experts is very clear: If you&#8217;re vaccinated, you&#8217;re safe.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re not vaccinated, you&#8217;re at risk of getting the virus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the Delta variant &#8212; the transmissibility of it, which we&#8217;ve seen from medical experts who have made clear that it is far more transmissible, it can be deadly, it can make people incredibly sick &#8212; is just a reminder of what risk people are putting on themselves if they don&#8217;t get vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then &#8212; so for clarity, though, what risks &#8212; to my question &#8212; what risk do you think those pockets of noncompliance pose not just to themselves, but to the rest of the country?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t look at it as pockets, Peter.&nbsp; I would look at it as: Individuals in those pockets who are not vaccinated are certainly at a significant risk, given the transmissibility of the Delta variant.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you don&#8217;t think that risk is larger than those individuals (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; If those individuals are vaccinated in those areas, then they are protected.&nbsp; We have seen &#8212; also had some news this morning about the effectiveness of J&amp;J.&nbsp; But also, we know that Moderna and Pfizer are effective in fighting and protecting individuals from the Delta variant.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that we announced just yesterday our plans for a surge team, largely in response to the Delta variant across the country.&nbsp; That will include the physical deployment of personnel, virtual assistance, direct sharing of resources.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already deployed this &#8212; a team to Colorado to collaborate with the local Department of Health in Mesa County.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something we will continue to work with communities across the country to implement to address the rising threat of the Delta variant.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And given the White House is going to fall shy of its 70 percent goal for at least one shot in the arms of adults right now, is the White House done setting goals?&nbsp; Will you continue to do that?&nbsp; Or do you think that they&#8217;re no longer effective?<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, that&#8217;s one way of describing it.&nbsp; Another way of describing it is that we are on track, once the data comes in, to ensure &#8212; to report that 70 percent of adults 27 and older have received at least one dose of the vaccine.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a significant step forward &#8212; something we&#8217;re incredibly proud of.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a reflection of the leadership of the President, of the organizational expertise of the team he&#8217;s hired, and that&#8217;s an enormous step forward.&nbsp; That&#8217;s also why deaths and hospitalizations have fallen by more than 90 percent since January.<br>&nbsp;<br>We feel it&#8217;s important to set bold and ambitious goals.&nbsp; Even though we are on track to reach that goal for individuals 27 and up, our job is not done.&nbsp; The work continues even on July 5th.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On COVID, will we set a new goal?&nbsp; Is there a new goal that you&#8217;re targeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have no new goal to set today, but again, we feel that it&#8217;s important to set bold and ambitious markers and hold ourselves to account.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Is the White House concerned that some vice-presidential staffers reportedly feel like they work in a, quote, &#8220;abusive environment&#8221;?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, I would first note that I try not to speak to or engage on anonymous reports or anonymous sources.&nbsp; I will say that the Vice President is an incredibly important partner to the President of the United States.&nbsp; She has a challenging job, a hard job, and she has a great, supportive team of people around her.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But other than that, I&#8217;m not going to have any more comments on those reports.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;m hoping to clarify the administration&#8217;s position here on defunding the police.&nbsp; You say the President does not want to defund the police, but is the President concerned then that, last year, the now-Associate Attorney General, Vanita Gupta, said it was, quote, &#8220;critical for state and local leaders to heed calls from Black Lives Matter and Movement for Black Lives activists to decrease police budgets&#8221;?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that, as a Fox News report that came about in February quoted, quote, &#8221; Current and former police chiefs in more than 53 cities across the country, as well as the National Fraternal Order of Police, are issuing their support of the nomination of Vanita Gupta &#8212; President Biden’s nominee for Associate Attorney General &#8212; praising her leadership and record, and urging the Senate Judiciary Committee to &#8216;quickly confirm her&#8217; to the post.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t know that that was your report or not &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good quote.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; but it was certainly one from your network.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But she said &#8212; okay, so that&#8217;s the Fox report.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In Senate testimony, she said she wanted to decrease police budgets.&nbsp; So will she &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; She also made explicitly clear in her confirmation process that she opposes defunding the police.&nbsp; And the President ran on, most importantly &#8212; did not run on defunding the police.&nbsp; He&#8217;s always opposed defunding the police.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll also note, because you&#8217;ve asked this question before &#8212; or a few times over the last several days &#8212; that when we talk about individuals in Congress and their support for funding or opposition to funding for the police, I think what the American people are most focused on is how people vote, what their record is, which is a public record.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I will note that while the President ran on and won the most votes of any candidate in history on a platform of boosting funding for law enforcement after Republicans spent decades trying to cut the COPS program &#8212; which, again, is public record; we don&#8217;t need to under- &#8212; undervalue the intelligence of the American people &#8212; the President ran on increasing that funding.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in his budget.<br>&nbsp;<br>In President Trump&#8217;s budget, he significantly cut that.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a change.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the American Rescue Plan had a great deal of funding for local and state authorities, something that can support funding for local police in communities across the country, and something many have used.<br>&nbsp;<br>It doesn&#8217;t require me telling you names of individuals who oppose the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Every Republican opposed the American Rescue Plan, and I don&#8217;t have time to read out all their names today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On another subject &#8212; the official White House account tweeted yesterday: “The cost of a Fourth of July cookout is down 16 cents from last year.”&nbsp; Sixteen cents?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There has been a reduction in some of the costs of key components of the Fourth of July &#8212; a Fourth of July barbecue.&nbsp; That was what the tweet was noting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So does the White House think that 16 cents off a barbecue has more of an impact on people&#8217;s lives than gas being a dollar more this time &#8212; this Fourth of July versus last year?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say: If you don&#8217;t like hot dogs, you may not care of the reduction of costs.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can&#8217;t &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You don&#8217;t have to like hot dogs.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You can&#8217;t buy a hot dog for 16 cents.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A reduction of &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s like a bite of a hot dog.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will say that what we are most focused on is the fact that we&#8217;ve created now more than 3 million jobs since the President took office. &nbsp;That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re focused on, and continuing to implement additional components of his economic Build Back Better agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Andrea.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to switch gears completely &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; from hot dogs.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; So, the President of Belarus has shut the border to Ukraine.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve expressed concern about this halt to travel.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on what&#8217;s happening there and what your reaction is to that?&nbsp; I mean, is it time to take more serious action?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As you know, we have put in place a number of sanctions over the past several weeks in coordination with our European partners.&nbsp; I had not seen that report before I came out here.&nbsp; I will talk with our national security team and see if there&#8217;s any additional actions or calls that are happening today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, on the international front, these OECD talks are now going to be heading into the G10 &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, G20 meeting that&#8217;s coming up.&nbsp; The Treasury Secretary will be going.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Can you just, from where do you sit, sort of, say what your primary goal is for this upcoming G20 meeting and the finance officials, and what you’re &#8212; you know, what the President is saying to the Treasury Secretary about what he&#8217;d like to see get done?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, obviously, the Treasury team and the Treasury Secretary will preview what the focus of their trip is.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know and as you asked my colleague Brian Deese about, certainly a component of that will be about the global minimum tax and moving that across the finish line.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will note &#8212; and he touched on this a bit, but we are quite encouraged &#8212; and it is a positive sign, in our view &#8212; that there are 130 countries, representing more than 90 percent of global GDP, who have come together to support the Biden administration plan for a strong global minimum tax.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, of course, there&#8217;s more work to be done, but that is &#8212; will be certainly a focus.&nbsp; But otherwise, I would defer to the Treasury Department on previewing the Secretary&#8217;s trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, the President is going to be speaking, later on today, to the National Education Association.&nbsp; What is his primary concern?&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;ve talked a lot in here about critical race theory.&nbsp; Is this something that he&#8217;s going to bring up in terms of the teaching of American history?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, he&#8217;s married to a teacher and a longtime teacher &#8212; still a teacher.&nbsp; And so, certainly, educators and making sure he is communicating and conveying his commitment to the education system and the role of educators in the country is always going to be close to his heart.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will certainly expect that he will talk a bit about his plans and initiatives, whether it&#8217;s the American Jobs Plan or the components of the American Families Plan, which will be critical to communities &#8212; to school communities across the country.&nbsp; But I think that would be the focus of his remarks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Afghanistan, the President said, earlier, he does not think the drawdown will be done in a few days.&nbsp; The Pentagon has said it&#8217;s ahead of schedule &#8212; the September 11th date.&nbsp; So what is the latest date that the White House is looking at right now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we currently expect it to be completed by the end of August.&nbsp; So, as you know, the President decided to withdraw remaining U.S. troops from Afghanistan and finally end the U.S. war there after 20 years.&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s been some reporting about Bagram, which I expect &#8212; it may already be out &#8212; there&#8217;ll be a statement from the Secretary of Defense on that sometime today.<br>&nbsp;<br>But in terms of the timeline, we currently expect it to be completed by the end of August.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And when it comes to the translators that have applied &#8212; not just translators &#8212; drivers, engineers, people who have really put their lives on the line for the U.S. that are waiting on these applications &#8212; is it true that the administration is considering housing them in Central Asia &#8212; several countries in Central Asia &#8212; while they wait for those applications to either be accepted or denied?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There have been some reports about conversations.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not here to confirm any conversations.&nbsp; What I can tell you is we&#8217;ve identified a group of SIV applicants who have served as interpreters, translators, as well as other at-risk categories.&nbsp; They will be relocated to a location outside of Afghanistan.&nbsp; There are a range of options, but that will happen before we complete our military drawdown by the end of August, in order to complete their visa application process from there.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of locations or numbers, I&#8217;m just not going to be able to get into those specifics for security reasons.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you will eventually.<br>&nbsp;<br>And can you explain why the President was citing the July 4th weekend when he was being asked questions about Afghanistan as to why he did not want to answer further questions on that matter?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think what he was trying to convey to all of you is that he is heading into July 4th weekend &#8212; a weekend for family, a weekend to celebrate America &#8212; and that he was ready to be done answering questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>It wasn&#8217;t &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t related to Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up there &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; one of the things that you sort of punted on was that the fighting is getting closer and closer to Kabul.&nbsp; If the Afghan government falls, if there is a bloodbath in Kabul, is there any circumstance where the U.S. is reconsidering, is thinking about sending troops back?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s really important to remember what the President conveyed when he made his announcement &#8212; or how we kind of got to this point.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>First, when he announced our drawdown, he made clear that the Taliban would have been shooting at U.S. troops again after May 1st.&nbsp; And the withdwal [sic] &#8212; the withdrawal deadline negotiated by the previous administration kind of set that timeline.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, when he came into office, we had the lowest number of U.S. and partner forces in Afghanistan since the early days of the war; an agreement, as I note &#8212; just noted, was already in place; and the military stalemate between the Taliban and Afghan Forces was at a height.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also asked for a review of genuine, realistic options to advance and protect U.S. interests.&nbsp; The review did not sugarcoat what the likely outcomes would be or rely on best-case scenarios.&nbsp; And we emerged from that with a clear-eyed assessment of the best path forward to advance American interests, which is his focus and his role as the Commander-in-Chief and the President of the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And ending the war in Afghanistan after 20 years so that we can address the global threat picture, so that we can protect our men and women serving was his priority.&nbsp; So that continues to be and he continues to &#8212; we&#8217;re continuing to move forward toward our withdrawal plan by the end of August.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could I ask you a follow-up on something you said yesterday.&nbsp; You were asked about the end of the Supreme Court term.&nbsp; You reiterated the President&#8217;s commitment, should there be an opening, to nominate an African American woman.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He said, a year ago, that he was creating a list, that he would release that list for further vetting.&nbsp; Can you tell us what the status is?&nbsp; Is there going to be a list of potential nominees that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s released for us to see?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well there is not an opening on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s not a current hypothetical we&#8217;re even dealing with right now.&nbsp; He made clear at the time &#8212; or maybe around that time &#8212; that he would nominate an African American woman to serve on the Supreme Court should there be an opening while he&#8217;s President.&nbsp; And he remains committed to that &#8212; to that, should there be an opening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, David.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, about a little more than a week ago, the agreement with the Iranians to allow inspections to continue at the main sites expired, and a couple of administration officials &#8212; including, I think, the Secretary of State &#8212; had said that it would be a big problem if we lose inspection continuity.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, now we&#8217;re a week out.&nbsp; Is it your understanding that we have no inspection continuity?&nbsp; And tell us how this affects the way the President is hoping that all of this will unwind.&nbsp; How do you actually get to an agreement if you&#8217;re not sure that things have been diverted along the way?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think we certainly expect there could be challenges on the road to getting an agreement.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve lived through a version of this before, as have you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say that, consistent with what the Secretary of State said, we believe Iran must comply with the IAEA&#8217;s inspectors and it must comply with its obligations under its Safeguards Agreements with the IAEA.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working with allies and partners to reinforce broad support for the IAEA and the director general as he and his team carry out their important work.<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly, our message has continued to &#8212; has been from the beginning, but I will reiterate, that one of the reasons to move forward and to continue to pursue a diplomatic agreement to re-engage with our partners &#8212; P5+1 partners and the Iranians, even indirectly, is because we want to have that reliable access and understand and have visibility into what the Iranians are up to and how close they are to acquiring a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, we&#8217;ve just concluded the sixth round of talks.&nbsp; Everyone is back at their capitals.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you in terms of a next round, but that certainly is our hope in terms of the next step.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just following on the question you got before Afghanistan.&nbsp; When I asked President, during that previous event on the economy, about Kabul, he said, &#8220;We&#8217;ve worked out an over-the-horizon capacity that we can be value added, but the Afghans are going to have to be able to do it themselves with the air force they have.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, if we just understand what he said and then your answer before to Kaitlan, is he essentially saying, &#8220;If Kabul falls, it is not our primary responsibility at this point.&nbsp; We&#8217;re happy to go help, but it&#8217;s completely up to you&#8221;?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s saying that, as we said in the beginning, he asked for a review and an assessment of what the impact could be of our decision to withdraw troops.&nbsp; We asked them not to sugarcoat that; they didn&#8217;t.&nbsp; There have been intel assessments that have been out there from our own government.&nbsp; We&#8217;re certainly aware of those.&nbsp; We have never taken a step back from those &#8212; from the podium or from the President of the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, what I think he was conveying during his answer to you, David, is that we will also continue to work collaboratively, as we always have, with a range of countries that share our interest in countering the reemergence of a serious external-plotting capability emanating from Afghanistan, should that emerge.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will maintain over-the-horizon capacity, and we &#8212; that is something that will continue, as well as our security assistance to the Afghan National Security Forces, but they will be in the lead, as has always been the plan when we withdraw our troops.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Sha&#8217;Carri Richardson, the U.S. track star, has been suspended following a positive test for marijuana use.&nbsp; Does the President support that penalty or does he want to see her be able to represent the United States fully at the Olympic Games this summer?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, that this was an independent decision made by the U.S. Anti-Doping Agency, and not a &#8212; not a decision that would be made by the U.S. government, as is appropriate.&nbsp; And we will certainly leave them the space and room to make their decisions about anti-doping policies that need to be implemented.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will also note that Sha&#8217;Carri Richardson is an inspiring young woman who went &#8212; has gone through a lot, personally.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; and she also happens to be one of the fastest women in the world, and that&#8217;s an important part of the story as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So this is an independent &#8212; an independent decision by the U.S. Anti-Doping Agency, but I also felt it was important to note who she is and her history.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask a follow-up on Afghanistan?&nbsp; When it comes to the vulnerable Afghan employees that we were talking about that could be moved to other countries, what assurances does the administration have to them that they can be moved safely &#8212; that these visa applicants can be moved safely?&nbsp; I mean, isn&#8217;t there a target now on their backs now that the Taliban knows that they&#8217;re, you know, potentially going to be moved?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Sean, I think one of the reasons that I&#8217;m not going to get into security details about what third country they might go to and how many is exactly for that reason.&nbsp; But certainly, our timeline is to relocate these individuals to a location outside of Afghanistan before we complete our military drawdown.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that we will continue, even after we have our military with- &#8212; drawdown with a presence in Kabul, a diplomatic presence as well on the ground there.&nbsp; But certainly that&#8217;s the goal of our timeline and the reason I&#8217;m not getting into more specific details.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Asma.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, hi.&nbsp; Two quick questions on voting rights.&nbsp; One is actually a logistical question.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He said yesterday that he intends to, kind of, tour around and go and speak on this issue.&nbsp; Will he give remarks next week?&nbsp; Can we get any guidance on where he might go?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;&nbsp; He is eager to do that, as is evident by his mentioning it to you all yesterday and over the last couple of weeks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think, as you would note, hopefully, in his statement yesterday he is profoundly disappointed by the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just a reminder of how important it is to move forward on federal legislation.&nbsp; It &#8212; how important it is to &#8212; and urgent it is that Congress restore the Voting Rights Act.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a reminder of what the stakes are here, which is that our democracy is on the line.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We &#8212; as I noted in the beginning, we are still working out and finalizing details for next week.&nbsp; So I just don&#8217;t have anything to preview in terms of travel or the focus of his travel at this point in time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another related question, which was actually on the remarks he gave yesterday about the Arizona voting decision.&nbsp; I just wanted to clarify some things, so I&#8217;m going to quote &#8212; he said, &#8220;It is mildly positive in the sense that there&#8217;s a remedy available based on the particular voting decision.&#8221;&nbsp; And kind of &#8212; I was just confused what he was talking about was &#8220;mildly positive&#8221;?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;d have to look more closely at the specific statement.&nbsp; You know, I think that the President views this issue, broadly, as one where we need to continue to use every lever at our disposal, whether that is actions taken by the Department of Justice that the Attorney General has already announced some of in the last few weeks; or it is efforts that we have underway, led by our Vice President, to engage with civil rights groups, state legislators, and the American people to push back on anti-voter laws at the state level.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But that&#8217;s, broadly, what his view is, and I think what he was trying to project in the statement.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; OPEC Plus has been stuck in talks around raising oil production to ease prices.&nbsp; Is the White House concerned about high oil prices?&nbsp; And has the President or anybody in the administration been in touch with allies in &#8212; who are involved in OPEC to talk about this?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, somewhat related, on gas prices being high in the U.S. at, you know, peak travel time &#8212; probably even more so because of, kind of, the pandemic getting better: You know, are you concerned about that for Americans, at a time when it does seem like there are a lot of economic data points working in your favor, that this one that Americans really do feel day in, day out is not, you know, in a great position?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure, well, Jen, let me first say that there are, of course &#8212; we have seen an increase in the price of oil, as anyone has seen &#8212; as they&#8217;ve seen &#8212; who watches data.&nbsp; It will be, of course, a topic of discussion, as you noted, when OPEC meets over the coming days.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not in a position to speak to those conversations from here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I do &#8212; I can say that, currently, we expect there is enough spare oil production capacity globally.&nbsp; And as you know, because of the restart of global economy and the resumption of normal consumer activity, there is some impact on oil market conditions.<br>&nbsp;<br>On your second part of your question on the impact of individuals and consumers: Absolutely.&nbsp; I mean that&#8217;s one of the core reasons why the President was opposed to a gas tax and was opposed to a &#8212; any tax on travel or vehicles &#8212; vehicle mileage, because he felt that would fall on the backs of Americans who are returning to their workplaces, who are driving their kids to school.&nbsp; And that was a bottom line or a red line for him in the negotiations.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know well, the price of gas is often linked, of course, to oil prices.&nbsp; That will again be a topic of discussion over the coming days, but I don&#8217;t have anything to preview on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On the subject of infrastructure, there are a number of Republicans on the Hill who have raised concerns about the idea of giving the IRS $40 billion to basically crack down on tax cheats.&nbsp; They cite a lot of concerns, one of which is that they think that this &#8212; it raises the possibility of abuse by the IRS.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering what the administration&#8217;s response to that is.&nbsp; And also, how pivotal is this IRS component to paying for the President&#8217;s infrastructure plan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think it&#8217;s a key payfor, and one that was agreed to by a bipartisan group who negotiated the deal.&nbsp; And for clarity, what the &#8212; what it actually would do is ensure that the IRS has the support, the staffing, and the resources needed to ensure the wealthiest Americans are paying what they owe.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what it would do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have some estimates of what that would raise in terms of payfors.&nbsp; Those are actually quite conservative when you look at what economists &#8212; many economists suggest across the board.&nbsp; But it is a payfor that was agreed to and one that does not violate what was a red line for many Republicans, which was, in these bipartisan negotiations, doing anything to change the 2017 tax law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will, of course, go to that when we go to reconciliation, but that was a red line as it related to these negotiations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, we saw that the President was exasperated this morning when he was asked several questions about Afghanistan and Bagram.&nbsp; Bear with me for a second, but 20 years ago, we were a nation full of people &#8212; most Americans were gung-ho, full of patriotism to go get those people who had attacked our country in 2001.&nbsp; Twenty years on now, we&#8217;re &#8212; we seem to be &#8212; average Americans are just shrugging their shoulders at the fate of Afghanistan.&nbsp; They may have “Afghanistan fatigue.”&nbsp; Does the President feel that way?&nbsp; Does he have “Afghanistan fatigue”?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does he sense that in the American people?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First, I would say that the President has long felt, as many Americans have and many leaders have, that the war in Afghanistan was not one that could be won militarily.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have supported diplomatic negotiations and discussions, and we will continue to be engaged in those moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, we&#8217;ll continue to have a diplomatic presence on the ground, even after we bring our men and women home.&nbsp; As Commander-in-Chief, you have to make decisions about how to protect the men and women serving.&nbsp; When the May 1st deadline was set, that gave &#8212; provided us a timeline in which the President had to make a decision about bringing our men and women home, or beginning that process, so that they did not risk greater threats on the ground.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He went through an entire review, an assessment by his national security team to jump to that conclusion.&nbsp; And I will also reiterate that we will continue to provide security assistance, humanitarian assistance, and be partners to the government of Afghanistan in the months ahead, as is evident by the fact that he hosted leaders here just last Friday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the sense of fatigue, does he &#8212; do you &#8212; does he feel that way, do you think?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, I think people are a little overreading into his response to a series of &#8212; a Q&amp;A leading into a holiday weekend when he had already answered three questions on Afghanistan.&nbsp; And he just said, &#8220;This is the fourth question…&#8221; and he then went on and answered a couple additional questions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President could not be more proud of the men and women serving who have served over the last 20 years, and he is going to use every opportunity he can to thank them for their service, thank the families of those fallen service members who served proudly and bravely in Afghanistan.&nbsp; But this was a decision he made because he felt it was in the best interest of our national security in the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; I think you guys have to gather.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, go ahead.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the last one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; You mentioned that a COVID-19 surge team was heading to Colorado.&nbsp; Do you have an update on when one could be arriving in the state of Missouri?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And could you speak to the broader concern that the administration might have about the Midwest as a region?&nbsp; And then I do have one other question after that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Let me see if I have &#8212; I think I have &#8212; oh, we are also working with &#8212; closely with the Missouri Health Department in identifying needs there, and we&#8217;re prepared to mobilize a team to Missouri where the focus is on vaccine confidence efforts, epidemiology surveillance and sequencing support related to the Delta variant.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say our concern is where there are communities where there are lower vaccination rates because it means more people are at risk.&nbsp; And we are going to continue to do everything in the power of the federal government &#8212; whether that&#8217;s providing supply, whether that is sending surge response teams, whether that is ensuring people understand where they can get access, or whether it&#8217;s communicating directly to young people, people under 27 who have a lower vaccination rate.&nbsp; That will continue in communities in the Midwest or in any parts of the country where there are lower vaccination rates.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.&nbsp; Have a gre- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And following &#8212; following up on the President&#8217;s visit yesterday &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to Surfside: Once that investigation is complete and we know more about what caused the collapse, is there legislation potentially &#8212; would the White House be supportive of federal legislation that would address issues like building standards and condo association oversight and building recertification?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see what the investigation concludes, and then we can have a discussion about the next steps.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks so much, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks a lot, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Have a great weekend.<br>&nbsp;<br>2:12 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at the 2021 National Education Association Annual Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/02/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-2021-national-education-association-annual-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 23:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Walter E. Washington Convention CenterWashington, D.C. 5:19 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, everyone.  They tell me there are a few people out there watching.  (Laughter.)  MS. PRINGLE:  A couple thousand. THE PRESIDENT:&#160; A couple thousand. But, look, before I begin my formal comments, as Jill and your president spoke, it reminded me of two things.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Walter E. Washington Convention Center<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>5:19 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, everyone.  They tell me there are a few people out there watching.  (Laughter.) <br><br>MS. PRINGLE:  A couple thousand.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; A couple thousand.<br><br>But, look, before I begin my formal comments, as Jill and your president spoke, it reminded me of two things.&nbsp; One is that because of your help, because we were able to pass the American Rescue Plan, we&#8217;re able to get millions of shots in people&#8217;s arms and provide vaccines around the world and change the circumstances.&nbsp;<br><br>This week &#8212; this Friday &#8212; they announced the new employment figures.&nbsp; Another 800-and-some-thousand jobs created this week.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve now created more jobs since you got me sworn in than any president in American history in the same timeframe.&nbsp;<br><br>We are in a situation where we are doing things that I think are going to fundamentally change the trajectory of this country.&nbsp; I told you a long time ago: It&#8217;s not just the NEA and unions; it’s about building America from the middle up and the middle out, not trickling down.&nbsp; There’s a lot &#8212; a lot we can do.&nbsp; A lot more we can do.<br><br>And, folks, you know, the projected growth rate, before we started &#8212; I just was doing this earlier this morning &#8212; was to be half of what it is now.&nbsp; It&#8217;s expected to be over 7.2 percent the economy is going to grow this year.&nbsp; That means thousands and thousands and thousands and millions of jobs.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re just getting started.<br><br>So I want to thank you, Madam President, and congratulate you on your first representative assembly of the NEA.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And Jill and I wanted to congratulate you all on the 100th anniversary of this convening.&nbsp; And notwithstanding rumors, I was not at the first convening.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>The NEA is one of America&#8217;s indispensable organizations.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not just saying that because the First Lady is a member.&nbsp; And, by the way, I noticed &#8212; I noticed that what you all &#8212; I knew what you all were going through.&nbsp; Jill taught full-time this semester.&nbsp; Full-time.&nbsp; I watched Jill getting ready to teach her classes.&nbsp;<br><br>And going back to school herself, learning how to work online &#8212; and rapidly work online &#8212; and to teach online, it gave me an appreciation firsthand that I thought I had, but I wouldn&#8217;t have had had I not seen it.&nbsp; And then going out and teaching &#8212; she was working four or five hours a day, getting ready to teach, putting her lesson plans together a different &#8212; a different way.<br><br>And you all went through that.&nbsp; All of you went through that.<br><br>And again, I&#8217;m not saying this because of something Jill &#8212; you know, I would &#8212; the truth: If I didn’t support the NEA, I’d be sleeping in the Lincoln Bedroom alone.&nbsp; But &#8212; and that&#8217;s not where we sleep.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t sleep in the Lincoln Bedroom.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I&#8217;d be sent down to it.<br><br>But, you know, look, as Jill always says: Teaching is not what she does, it’s who she is.&nbsp; It&#8217;s who all of you are.&nbsp; Our children are the kite strings upon which our national ambitions are lifted aloft.&nbsp; And your profession &#8212; your profession helps them believe they can do anything.<br><br>For that, and so much more, we just wanted to thank you. Thank you all for what you do and what you continue to do.<br><br>And, President Pringle, you and I have something in common:&nbsp; We both took our current roles at a time of incredible challenge and incredible opportunity.<br><br>Over the last year, the entire country has witnessed the extraordinary dedication and resolve of the NEA members &#8212; teachers, professionals, who had to be not just educators, but tech support, social workers, often while trying to take care of their own children.&nbsp;<br><br>Other public employees who kept vital services up and running.&nbsp; I saw the bus drivers dropping off meals instead of picking up kids.&nbsp; Support staff had to become sanitation experts, making sure school buildings were safe.&nbsp; And tech experts making sure everyone could connect to the Internet from home.<br><br>You know, there&#8217;s been so much heroic work to help children stay connected to school and to each other.&nbsp; The American people saw it.&nbsp; They get it.&nbsp; And they understand what you&#8217;ve been saying for years: that you are professionals, all of you.&nbsp; All of you.&nbsp; All of us have a responsibility to make sure that you have what you need to educate our children safely, equitably, and well.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s why I made it a priority to get educators vaccinated and reopen schools as quickly as possible.&nbsp; Nationwide, 84 percent of K-through-12 educators and school staff are fully vaccinated, and they were by the end of May.&nbsp; Even more have gotten the vaccination since &#8212; the vaccine since.<br><br>But as I’ve said many times, it’s not enough just to get back to normal.&nbsp; We have to build back better than ever, especially our education system.<br><br>That’s why the American Rescue Plan made such historic investments.&nbsp; It was $1.9 trillion, and people said we could never get it passed.&nbsp; With your help, we did, and we transformed the country &#8212; began to transform the country &#8212; providing funding for state and local governors and school districts to make sure schools are safe and to keep you on the job and in the classrooms.&nbsp; Funding for summer learning and tutoring programs and hiring nurses and counselors.<br><br>Now we have an opportunity to make the game-changing investments for educators, students, and families, and make it even better.<br><br>We’re in a competition in the 21st century &#8212; a worldwide competition.&nbsp; And as Jill says often, “Any country that out-educates us is going to out-compete us.”&nbsp; We have to build for the 21st century because the rest of the world is not sitting around and waiting.<br><br>The bipartisan infrastructure agreement we just reached is going to deliver reliable high-speed Internet to every American.&nbsp; Every single American.&nbsp; And they’re going to be affordable, in rural and in urban areas.<br><br>Of the many things &#8212; of the many tough images this past year were children sitting in cars in fast-food parking lots because it was the only place they could get a Wi-Fi connection for remote schooling.<br><br>If we didn’t know &#8212; if we didn’t know it before, we do now: High-speed Internet is essential like electric and clean air &#8212; like electricity and clean water.<br><br>And speaking of clean water, this agreement that we put together will put Americans to work in good-paying union jobs, replacing 100 percent of lead water pipes in this country.&nbsp; One hundred percent.<br><br>Right now, there are 400,000 schools &#8212; and some of you teach in them &#8212; 400,000 schools and childcare centers with lead pipes.&nbsp; We know even that low levels of lead can cause behavior and learning problems in children, impairing their growth.<br><br>This deal contains the largest investment in clean drinking water in American history.&nbsp; It would end the threat of lead-contamination &#8212; contaminated water once and for all.<br><br>My American Families Plan &#8212; which we’re now trying to get done as well &#8212; calls for an historic investment in human infrastructure; guaranteeing four additional years of public education for everyone, starting as early as we can; universal high-quality preschool for three- and four-year-olds.&nbsp; And all the data shows how that increases their prospect, no matter what environment they come from, to do better and make it through school.&nbsp; Two years of free community college.&nbsp; And high-quality, affordable childcare for working families.<br><br>It would no longer cost &#8212; excuse me, it would lower the cost of lower-income &#8212; for lower-income students going to school &#8212; the Pell grants.&nbsp; We’d provide an additional mil- &#8212; 1.5 &#8212; $1,500 in Pell grants.<br><br>It will also make a $9 billion investment in educators so we can address teacher shortages, diversify our pipeline of teachers, and improve teacher training and teacher mentoring.&nbsp; And, critically, it would extend and expanded the Child Tax Credit, which will significantly benefit working families.<br><br>What that means: Instead of deducting $2,000 per child off the bottom line of your taxes, &#8211;which doesn’t do too much for families who don’t have a big tax bill to begin with &#8212; pretty soon, before this month is out, families are going to get a significant check.&nbsp; For every child under the age of six, you’ll get $3,600 per child.&nbsp; For every child 6 to 17, you’ll get $3,000 &#8212; not as a credit against your taxes that a lot of educators and school staff aren’t really going to feel.&nbsp; You’ll get cash.&nbsp; Cash.<br><br>Starting the middle of this month, you’ll start to get monthly payments between now and the end of the year.&nbsp; For example, if you have one child, and you’re going to get &#8212; you’re going to get $3,600.&nbsp; Between now and January, you’ll get $1,800 of that on a monthly basis between now and January.&nbsp; And between January and December, you’ll get the other $1,800.<br><br>Folks, this is a major tax break for working families, and my family plan will extend it for five years.&nbsp; The very &#8212; this year’s plan is estimated to cut child poverty in half.&nbsp; In half.&nbsp; The Child Tax&nbsp;<s>Care</s>&nbsp;[Credit].<br><br>So, look, folks &#8212; (applause)&nbsp;&#8212; I’m&nbsp;also working with Congress to support $100 billion in school infrastructure investments, making sure that our schools are safe, that you have the technology you need to prepare for students of the future &#8212; something that I&#8217;ve always cared deeply about.<br><br>My budget invests $20 billion more in Title I schools.&nbsp; No student &#8212; no student’s education should depend on their ZIP code.&nbsp; It would represent a historic effort to close the funding gap between rich and poor districts.<br><br>And one of the first things that funding will be used for is to help educators in those schools get the raises they deserve and the resources they need.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, by the way, if I’d note, this isn&#8217;t just &#8212; it’s not that I&#8217;m trying to be nice.&nbsp; This is absolutely necessary &#8212; necessary if we&#8217;re going to compete in the 21st century.&nbsp; Think about it: The idea that we have a large portion of our student population living in ZIP codes where they cannot afford the kind of education and can&#8217;t pay the teachers enough in those schools to educate them, it makes no sense.&nbsp; The people that are going to benefit the most from this is corporate America and businesses because they&#8217;re going to have a better-educated public, better-educated students.&nbsp;<br><br>Your union and teachers’ protests across the country made it clear that you deserve more than praise.&nbsp; You deserve a raise, not just praise.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, folks, every parent in this country who spent the last year helping educate their children at home understand you deserve a raise.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; They figured it out.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; Think about it.<br>It was the ultimate education of the public going through this pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>My budget would also allow us to invest more in counselors, social workers, community schools, nutrition support, and a whole lot more.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I have a lot more to say, but I&#8217;m going to get the hook from Jill if I keep talking.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>No, but let&#8217;s &#8212; so let me close with this: On Sunday, we&#8217;ll celebrate our independence as a nation, as well as our progress against the virus.&nbsp; In the days ahead, we have a chance to make another beginning &#8212; the beginning of a stronger, fairer education system.&nbsp; But it can&#8217;t be done &#8212; it can&#8217;t be done with you.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t do it alone.&nbsp; We need to keep getting the word out about the opportunities that lies ahead for us.&nbsp;<br><br>So, let&#8217;s make this happen together.&nbsp; I really mean this.&nbsp; This is a &#8212; this is a campaign in and of itself.&nbsp; Jill and I are proud of you.&nbsp; We&#8217;re grateful to you.&nbsp; And I really mean that.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I think about it: Why would a kid like me, from Scranton and Claymont, Delaware, be standing here as your President of the United States of America, were it not for the people who educated me, the teachers I had?&nbsp; It made a difference.&nbsp; They took a stuttering kid who couldn&#8217;t &#8212; couldn&#8217;t &#8212; couldn&#8217;t &#8212; couldn&#8217;t speak very well in school, was scared to death to be called on to read out loud.&nbsp;<br><br>And they nurtured me: “Joey &#8212; you&#8217;re a very smart boy, Joey.&nbsp; Just take your time.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t let that get in your way, Joey.”&nbsp; I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; I think what you all underestimate, beyond the teaching of reading and writing, adding and subtracting: You give so many kids confidence.&nbsp;<br><br>You let them believe in themselves.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; Think about yourself, your own &#8212; you can name the teachers who helped change your life.&nbsp; You can name them.&nbsp; I can still name them.&nbsp; I know who the &#8212; the people who made a difference in my life, made me believe I could do anything.&nbsp; When, if you looked at the background, there&#8217;s no reason why, coming from my circumstance.&nbsp; We weren&#8217;t &#8212; it wasn’t poverty, just &#8212; just making it.&nbsp; But you did it, and don&#8217;t forget it.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t forget how much difference you make.&nbsp;<br><br>Those of you who’ve been teaching a while, you have experiences like Jill has.&nbsp; People will come up to Jill and say, “Mrs. Biden, you had &#8212; I had your English class.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t thank you…”&nbsp; “What are you doing now?”&nbsp; “Well, I have my doctorate, and I&#8217;m teaching at such and such.”&nbsp; Or a fireman putting out a fire in our home: “Mrs. Biden…” &#8212; as his gear coming out of a house that almost burned down &#8212; &#8220;Mrs. Biden, you had me.&nbsp; You had me as a teacher, and you taught me English.&#8221;&nbsp; Think of the people’s lives you change.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I&#8217;m supposed to stop but I&#8217;m going to say a couple more things &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; because I &#8212; I really don&#8217;t think you understand or you appreciate just how important you are.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I genuinely mean it from the bottom of my heart.<br><br>I was overseas at what they call the G7 &#8212; the biggest economies in the world &#8212; and then with the NATO people, and then I met with Putin.&nbsp; And in the process of doing all of this, I was asked at one point, &#8220;Can you define America for me?&#8221;&nbsp; And I give you my word to this.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;Yes…&#8221; &#8212; and I believe this, and I repeated it again today as I swore in new citizens, young people in the White House.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;I can define America&#8221; &#8212; and I mean it from the bottom of my heart &#8212; &#8220;in one word: possibilities.&#8221;&nbsp; It&#8217;s the only nation in the world where we think we can do anything.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, why do we think that?&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Why do we think that?&nbsp; Why do we think anything is possible?&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just the system.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the people who look out for us.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve said a hundred times, you control &#8212; you, the teachers, determine what this country is going to look like.&nbsp; You are the people who take our children and nurture them.&nbsp; As I said many times, they&#8217;re the kite string &#8212; you&#8217;re the kite strings upon which we lift our national ambitions aloft.&nbsp; So, have &#8212; understand how important you are.<br><br>And, by the way, understand how important that cafeteria worker is who looks at that kid who&#8217;s a little bit ashamed that they have no food at home and says, &#8220;Honey, here.&nbsp; Here is a little more.&nbsp; Take some more.&#8221;&nbsp; Or packs a little bag without telling them after they have lunch and slips it to them.&nbsp; You provide their dignity.&nbsp; You give them dignity.<br><br>So, I really mean it: I think you&#8217;re the single most important component of America&#8217;s future.&nbsp; So don&#8217;t give up on yourselves, and I know you won&#8217;t.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t give up on these kids.&nbsp; Give them hope.&nbsp; Make them believe in themselves.&nbsp; And make sure when they&#8217;re much older, and they say, &#8220;How&#8217;d you get here?&#8221;&nbsp; &#8220;Because Mrs. Jones or Mr. Williams,” or whomever.&nbsp; Because it will be done.&nbsp; It will be done.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for all you do, all you give, and all that you are to your students and to the nation.&nbsp; You know you affect your students, but it&#8217;s to the nation.<br><br>God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>5:38 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Six Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/president-biden-announces-six-key-nominations-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 20:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following Six individuals to serve in key roles: Alexander Hoehn-Saric, Nominee for Chair of the Consumer Product Safety Commission Mary Boyle, Nominee for Commissioner of the Consumer Product Safety Commission Gerald Fauth, Nominee for Member of the National Mediation Board Linda Puchala, Nominee&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following Six individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Alexander Hoehn-Saric, Nominee for Chair of the Consumer Product Safety Commission</li><li>Mary Boyle, Nominee for Commissioner of the Consumer Product Safety Commission</li><li>Gerald Fauth, Nominee for Member of the National Mediation Board</li><li>Linda Puchala, Nominee for Member of the National Mediation Board</li><li>Betty Jang, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</li><li>Audrey Schuster, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Alexander Hoehn-Saric, Nominee for Chair of the Consumer Product Safety Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Alexander Hoehn-Saric is Chief Counsel for Communications and Consumer Protection for the U.S. House of Representatives Committee on Energy &amp; Commerce.&nbsp; In this position, he works on legislation and oversight related to product safety, consumer protection, and communications.&nbsp;&nbsp; Hoehn-Saric also served at the Department of Commerce as the Deputy General Counsel for Strategic Initiatives.&nbsp;&nbsp; Prior to that, he was senior counsel for the U.S. Senate Committee on Commerce, Science and Transportation Committee where he was responsible for product safety and consumer protection matters.</p>



<p>The son of first-generation immigrants from China and Austria, Hoehn-Saric grew up in Baltimore, Maryland.&nbsp; He received a bachelor’s degree in political science from the University of Chicago and a J.D. from UCLA Law School.&nbsp; Hoehn-Saric and his wife Loren, currently reside in Maryland with their son and daughter.</p>



<p><strong><u>Mary Boyle, Nominee for Commissioner of the Consumer Product Safety Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Mary T. Boyle, the current Executive Director of the U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), has spent more than a decade at CPSC in senior positions across the agency and is a member of the Senior Executive Service. Her work has covered a broad range of issues, including policy, administration, legal questions, budgets, product recalls, negotiations, rules and regulations, and agency morale.</p>



<p>Before joining the Commission staff, Ms. Boyle developed affordable housing programs for the city of Gaithersburg, Md., worked in private practice at a major international law firm, and served on Capitol Hill as a staff member for the late Congressman Steve Solarz and for the Asia and Pacific Subcommittee of the House Foreign Affairs Committee. Ms. Boyle received her B.A. in English from Georgetown University in 1985 and her law degree from the University of Virginia in 1991. She is a member of the District of Columbia and Maryland Bars. She was born and raised in Brooklyn, New York. She now lives with her husband in Bethesda, Maryland. They have three adult children, James, Julia, and Margot.</p>



<p><strong><u>Gerald W. Fauth III, Nominee for Member of the National Mediation Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Gerald W. Fauth III currently serves as Chairman of the National Mediation Board (NMB), where he has served as a Board Member since November 2017.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. Fauth has 40 years of experience in the private sector and Federal government working in the transportation industry.&nbsp; He has been directly involved in negotiating, mediating, arbitrating, facilitating, supporting and/or deciding the resolution of hundreds of complex transportation problems and disputes during his long career.&nbsp; In addition to his NMB experience, from 1999 to 2003, Mr. Fauth served at the U.S. Surface Transportation Board (STB), where he served as Chief of Staff and Senior Advisor to a Board Member and was directly involved in the decision-making process in hundreds of formal written decisions involving all matters of STB jurisdiction. In 1998, Mr. Fauth was named by the STB an original member of the Conrail Transaction Council, which was established in order to provide a forum for constructive dialogue and timely and efficient communication of information in order to resolve implementation problems and railroad service concerns associated with the Conrail railroad transaction, which was the largest railroad transaction in history.</p>



<p>Mr. Fauth holds a Bachelor’s degree from Hampden-Sydney College in Virginia.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Linda Puchala, Nominee for Member of the National Mediation Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Linda Puchala was first confirmed as Member of the National Mediation Board by the United States Senate on May 21, 2009. Ms. Puchala previously served as Chairman from July 1, 2011 through June 30, 2012, July 1, 2013 through June 30, 2014, from July 1, 2016 through June 30, 2017, and from July 1, 2019 through June 30, 2020. Her most recent Senate confirmation came on November 2, 2017.</p>



<p>Prior to becoming a Member, Ms. Puchala served 10 years at the National Mediation Board as a Mediator, Sr. Mediator (ADR) and the Associate Director of Alternative Dispute Resolution Services. Ms. Puchala’s prior labor relations experience includes work as International President of the Association of Flight Attendants-CWA, AFL-CIO and Staff Director, Michigan State Employees Association, AFSCME, AFL-CIO.</p>



<p>A Michigan native, Ms. Puchala resides in Glen Burnie, Maryland, and holds a Bachelor’s degree in Business Administration from Cleary University in Howell, Michigan.</p>



<p><strong><u>Betty Y. Jang, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>Ms. Jang is an executive with over 25 years of legal, compliance, and leadership experience.&nbsp; She most recently was an executive at publicly-traded companies. She has previously provided legal counsel at several Fortune 250 corporations, practiced law at a national law firm, and taught as an adjunct professor at the University of Illinois College of Law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ms. Jang began her career as an assistant public defender with the Office of the Cook County Public Defender.&nbsp; She has served as a scholarship evaluator for the APIA Scholars program, is an alumnus of the United State of Women Galvanize Chicago Program, and has held numerous board positions in local, state, and national bar associations.&nbsp;&nbsp;She received her B.A. from the University of Illinois and her J.D. from Chicago-Kent College of Law.</p>



<p><strong><u>Audrey K. Schuster, Nominee for Member of the Board of Trustees of the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>Audrey K. Schuster has been an active leader volunteer in the education and family service community for over 30 years. &nbsp;Schuster has dedicated her time and resources to families throughout the Boston community with a particular focus on mentoring youth and young mothers. &nbsp;For the last 16 years, Schuster has served as a trained volunteer for the Visiting Moms Program for Boston’s Jewish Family &amp; Children’s Services, a 100-year-old organization that helps seniors families and children who are experiencing hunger, poverty or domestic abuse. &nbsp;Schuster’s responsibilities include weekly in-home visits to serve families in need of support as they adjust to parenthood, isolation and food insecurity.</p>



<p>Schuster has been an active fundraiser and philanthropist, chairing record-breaking development activities for numerous organizations, including the Brain Tumor Society, the Dana Farber Institute, Tufts Medical School and Brandeis University Women’s Studies Research Center. She has served as a Committee Member of the Rivers School, the Meadowbrook School and Wheaton College to help address strategic issues and challenges facing their student and academic communities. &nbsp;Schuster is a graduate of Simmons University. She the loving wife to real estate developer Mark Schuster and the proud mother of their three children &#8211; Elizabeth, Nikki and John and their granddaughter Flynn. &nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Seven Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/president-biden-announces-seven-key-nominations-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 20:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles: Rachel Jacobson, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of the Army for Installations and Environment, Department of Defense Jose Javier Rodriguez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Employment and Training, Department of Labor Mallory Stewart, Nominee for Assistant&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Rachel Jacobson, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of the Army for Installations and Environment, Department of Defense</li><li>Jose Javier Rodriguez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Employment and Training, Department of Labor</li><li>Mallory Stewart, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Verification and Compliance, Department of State</li><li>Chantale Wong, Nominee for United States Director of the Asian Development Bank, with the rank of Ambassador</li><li>Amy Gutmann, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Federal Republic of Germany</li><li>Jeffrey M. Hovenier, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Kosovo</li><li>Virginia E. Palmer, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Ghana</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Rachel Jacobson, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of the Army for Installations and Environment, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Rachel Jacobson is an attorney who served at the Department of Defense during the Obama-Biden Administration as the Deputy General Counsel for Environment, Energy and Installations.&nbsp; Prior to joining DoD, Jacobson served for five years as an appointee at the Department of the Interior, as Principal Deputy Solicitor and acting Assistant Secretary for Fish and Wildlife and Parks.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jacobson, who ran a conservation program at the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation before joining the Obama-Biden Administration, is currently in private practice in the Energy, Environment and Natural Resources group of the law firm WilmerHale in Washington, D.C.&nbsp; Jacobson spent the majority of her career at the U.S. Department of Justice in the Environment and Natural Resources Division.&nbsp;A member of the American College of Environmental Lawyers, Jacobson received an undergraduate degree in economics from Washington University in St. Louis, and a law degree from Boston University School of Law.&nbsp; A native of Chicago, Jacobson resides in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jose Javier Rodriguez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Employment and Training, Department of Labor</u></strong></p>



<p>Jose Javier Rodriguez is a litigator and partner at Sugarman &amp; Susskind, PA in Miami, Florida, representing employees and labor unions as well as pension and benefit funds in a diverse litigation practice. Rodríguez has served on the faculty of South Florida law schools as adjunct professor and adjunct clinical professor.</p>



<p>Rodriguez served for eight years in the Florida Legislature after being elected in 2012 to represent District 112 in the Florida House of Representatives and in 2016 to represent District 37 in the Florida Senate. He has received numerous awards and recognitions for his work as a community leader and as policymaker, particularly in the areas of employment and the environment. Rodriguez served as vice-chair of the Senate’s Judiciary Committee while in the Florida Senate.</p>



<p>Raised in Miami, Rodriguez’s father left Cuba at the age of 15 through Operation Pedro Pan. Rodriguez served as a Peace Corps Volunteer in Senegal after earning a B.A. from Brown University and prior to earning a J.D. from Harvard Law School and returning to Florida to begin his legal career at Florida Legal Services. Along with his wife Sonia and two young sons,&nbsp; Rodriguez lives in Miami.</p>



<p><strong><u>Mallory Stewart, Nominee for Assistant Secretary of State (Verification and Compliance)</u></strong></p>



<p>Mallory Stewart currently serves as a Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Arms Control, Disarmament, and Nonproliferation on the National Security Council. Previously, Ms. Stewart was Senior Manager for Global Nuclear Security and Nonproliferation as Sandia National Laboratories.&nbsp; She also has served as a Nonresident Fellow in the WMD, Nonproliferation and Security Program at the Stimson Center, as an Adjunct Professor at Georgetown University’s Center for Security Studies and as a Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Emerging Security Challenges and Defense Policy in the Bureau of Arms Control, Verification, and Compliance. She worked in the State Department Legal Advisor’s Office on arms control issues and, among other roles, served as the lead lawyer and one of the primary architects of the U.S.-Russia Framework to eliminate Syria’s declared chemical weapons stockpile.</p>



<p>Ms. Stewart earned an A.B degree from Harvard College and her J.D. degree from Stanford Law School.&nbsp; She has written extensively on issues related to arms control and verification and was the recipient of the Secretary of State’s Award for Excellence in International Security Affairs among other honors.</p>



<p><strong><u>Chantale Wong, Nominee for United States Director of the Asian Development Bank, with the rank of Ambassador</u></strong></p>



<p>Chantale Yokmin Wong is a leading authority in international development policy with over 30 years of experience in the multi-disciplinary field that includes finance, technology, and the environment.&nbsp; She has been recognized throughout her career for transforming critical processes affecting the whole of government.&nbsp; Chantale was appointed by President Obama to serve as Vice President for Administration and Finance and Chief Financial Officer at the Millennium Challenge Corporation where she led change in financial, human capital, and information technology management.&nbsp; She was appointed by President Bill Clinton to the Board of Directors at the Asian Development Bank, representing the United States as the Alternate Executive Director, and overseeing policies and operations.&nbsp; She has held senior career appointments in the Office of Management and Budget, Treasury, NASA, and the Environmental Protection Agency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Among her personal passions are photography and videography, with which she has chronicled the annual Congressional Civil Rights pilgrimages in Alabama with the late Congressman John Lewis.&nbsp; In Asian American and Pacific Islander community, Chantale is known for establishing the Conference on APA Leadership, where she has guided young AAPIs for 32 years to seek careers in public service.&nbsp; She holds a Master’s in Public Administration from Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Government, and a Master’s in Environmental Engineering from the University of California, Berkeley.&nbsp; Her undergraduate degree is in Civil and Structural Engineering from the University of Hawaii.</p>



<p><strong><u>Amy Gutmann, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Federal Republic of Germany</u></strong><strong></strong></p>



<p>Amy Gutmann is the eighth President of the University of Pennsylvania, serving since 2004.&nbsp; She is also the Christopher H. Browne Distinguished Professor of Political Science, and a Professor of Communication at the Annenberg School for Communication.&nbsp; Her focus on global engagement fueled the creation of Penn’s Perry World House on campus, Penn Wharton China Center in Beijing, and the Penn Biden Center for Diplomacy and Global Engagement in Washington, D.C.&nbsp; Previously, at Princeton University, Gutmann was Provost, Dean of the Faculty, Founding Director of The University Center for Human Values, Laurance S. Rockefeller University Professor of Politics, and Director of the Program in Ethics and Public Affairs.&nbsp; She also worked at Harvard’s Kennedy School of Government and at the University of Maryland.&nbsp; Gutmann is an award-winning author and editor of 17 books, many centered on understanding and defending constitutional democracy and human rights. The daughter of a German Jewish refugee, and first in her family to graduate college, she earned a B.A. at Harvard-Radcliffe College, an M.S. at the London School of Economics, and a Ph.D. at Harvard.&nbsp; She was named by Fortune in 2018 as one of the “World’s 50 Greatest Leaders.”</p>



<p><strong><u>Jeffrey M. Hovenier, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Kosovo</u></strong></p>



<p>Jeffrey M. Hovenier, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister Counselor, currently serves as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Ankara, Turkey, where he served as Chargé d’Affaires a.i. from August 2018 through July 2019.&nbsp; Prior to that, he was Acting Deputy Chief of Mission and Minister Counselor for Political Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in Berlin, Germany.&nbsp; He also served at U.S. missions in Croatia, Greece, Panama, Paraguay, and Peru; at the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE); and on the staff of the UN Special Envoy for Kosovo Status.&nbsp; His Washington assignments include service as Director for Central and Southeastern European Affairs at the National Security Council and in the State Department’s Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs with responsibility for NATO and Central European Affairs.&nbsp; He has a Master’s degree from Georgetown University and a Bachelor’s degree from Brigham Young University.&nbsp; He speaks German, Greek, Croatian, and Spanish.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Virginia E. Palmer, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Ghana</u></strong></p>



<p>Virginia E. Palmer, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister Counselor, is Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the State Department’s Bureau of Energy Resources.&nbsp; She has served as Acting Assistant Secretary since January 20, 2021, overseeing U.S. foreign policy engagement at the critical intersection of our energy, climate and national security goals.&nbsp; Before assuming her current position, Palmer was the Deputy Commandant and International Affairs Advisor at the Dwight D. Eisenhower School for National Security and Resource Strategy at the National Defense University.&nbsp; She served as U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Malawi from 2015 until 2019.&nbsp; Prior to that, she was Deputy Chief of Mission and Chargé d’Affaires a.i., at the U.S. Embassy in South Africa;&nbsp; Deputy Chief of Mission and Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at the U.S. Embassy in Vietnam; the State Department’s Deputy Coordinator for Counterterrorism; and Director of the Bureau of East A’s Office of Economic Policy and the alternate U.S. Senior Official for the Asia Pacific Economic Cooperation forum (APEC).&nbsp; Other postings include assignments in Canada, Zimbabwe, the People’s Republic of China, Hong Kong, and Kenya.&nbsp; Palmer obtained her M.A. from the University of Virginia and a BSFS from Georgetown University.&nbsp; She also attended Washington University in St. Louis.&nbsp; She speaks Chinese and French.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi of Indonesia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-foreign-minister-retno-marsudi-of-indonesia-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 20:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi of Indonesia. Mr. Sullivan underscored the United States’ support for the people of Indonesia as they fight a surge in COVID-19 cases. Mr. Sullivan noted that the United States will be donating four million Moderna vaccine doses to Indonesia, and that these doses&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi of Indonesia. Mr. Sullivan underscored the United States’ support for the people of Indonesia as they fight a surge in COVID-19 cases. Mr. Sullivan noted that the United States will be donating four million Moderna vaccine doses to Indonesia, and that these doses will be shipped via COVAX as soon as possible. Additionally, they discussed U.S. plans to increase assistance for Indonesia’s broader COVID-19 response efforts. Mr. Sullivan highlighted the importance the Biden-Harris administration places on Indonesia, Southeast Asia and ending the pandemic more broadly and pledged continued support and high-level engagement.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Honoring the 2020 World Series Champions, the Los Angeles Dodgers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/02/remarks-by-president-biden-honoring-the-2020-world-series-champions-the-los-angeles-dodgers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 19:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 12:04 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a great beginning of the Fourth of July weekend.  Madam Vice President.  Mr. Leader, how are you?  Good to see you.  We’re here today to congratulate a group of folks who did pretty well.  Welcome to the White House.  I have a feeling, Kamala, I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>12:04 P.M. EDT<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  It’s a great beginning of the Fourth of July weekend.  Madam Vice President.  Mr. Leader, how are you?  Good to see you. <br> <br>We’re here today to congratulate a group of folks who did pretty well.  Welcome to the White House.  I have a feeling, Kamala, I think we may be doing this again by the end of the year.  (Laughter.)  I don’t know, man.  I’m not sure I’ll be able to handle Garcetti if you win twice.  (Laughter.)  I mean, it&#8217;s going to be hard &#8212; really hard.  <br> <br>But the 2020 World Series Champions, the Los Angeles Dodgers, are here.  (Applause.)  We are honored and thrilled they’re here.<br> <br>And that goes for the Vice President, too.  She’s from California, you probably heard.  I’m not going to mention which end of the state she’s from right now &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and who she roots for, but &#8212; is Doug here?<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  He was with them last night.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I know he was.  I thought he may &#8212;<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Came home wearing his jersey.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I tell you what &#8212; well, you know, we have &#8212; you know, when you talk about mixed families, I got a mixed family and she’s got a mixed family, based on baseball &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and sports.  I’m not going to mention that team in northern California, in the San Francisco area.  And I’m not going to mention that team in Philadelphia.  (Laughter.)  My wife is a Philly girl from her belt buckle to her shoe soles.  And if &#8212; if I root for anybody but the Phillies, I’ll be sleeping in the Lincoln Bedroom alone.  (Laughter.)  But it’s, you know, sometimes &#8212; well, no, never.  But at any rate &#8212;<br> <br>But the Dodgers are a lot more than a baseball club.  They really are.  They’re a pillar of American culture and American progress.  And that’s for real.<br> <br>The team that brought us the voice of Vin Scully and Sandy &#8212; the arm of Sandy Koufax and Fernando Valenzuela &#8212; and I was talking with staff and they said, “I want to teach you how to pronounce that name.”  I said, “I watched him pitch.”  (Laughter.)  But I’m only 37.  (Laughter.)  But it’s &#8212; I wish &#8212; anyway, above all else, the heart of Jackie Robinson.<br> <br>Now, you’re building a new dynasty for a new generation.  And I’ve often said that it’s never a good idea to bet against the American people; I tell that to every world leader I encounter.<br> <br>Well, now we know it’s never a good idea to bet against Mookie.  And Mookie is a hell of a ballplayer, but &#8212; and a guy who used to love Mookie is my Chief Strategist, Mike Donilon.  But he doesn’t want to talk to Mookie anymore.  (Laughter.)  Mookie left Boston, and this is a Boston fan.  I mean, you know, there’s nothing like dividing staffs based on baseball.<br> <br>But, folks, it’s not a good idea to bet against Clayton either, you know, or Cody.<br> <br> You know, this is &#8212; this is a world championship organization because they’ve got a team full of guys who stepped up when they were called upon.  Just stepped up.<br> <br>And it takes a team to finish with the best record in baseball &#8212; to knock out the Brewers, the Padres, the Braves, the Rays &#8212; and win it all.  And the Dodgers just didn’t win.  You finished with the highest winning percentage of any team since 1954.  (Applause.)  Think about that: the winningest ball club since 1954.<br> <br>You know, it takes a team to persevere through one of the most challenging seasons and one of the most challenging years<br>in our nation’s history.<br> <br>In the pandemic, when it struck, it upended just about everything &#8212; every part of American life.  Families were grieving for loved ones lost.  The economy collapsed.   And the pain and fear in the nation were immeasurable.<br> <br>And when the season began, it was easy to feel like it was &#8212; they had bigger things to worry about than just sports.  And, of course, we did and we still do. But I think what we discovered is that we need sports more than we ever realized.  We s- &#8212; we see it now as fans return to ballparks and arenas all across the country, cheering on their favorite players and teams, sharing that sense of community and pride.  It&#8217;s a uniting feature, as I said to you guys in the other room.<br> <br>And when we go through a crisis, very often sports brings us together to heal, to help us feel like things are going to be okay, they&#8217;re going to get better.  For a few hours each day, feeling and sensing and experiencing something familiar, something normal, something that&#8217;s fun in the middle of the chaos, and believing that we&#8217;re going to get back to all that we&#8217;re missing and we&#8217;re going to get back to it someday soon.<br> <br>So today, we celebrate your incredible achievement.  We celebrate the great work you do on and off the field, in the community, and on childhood literacy, preventing bullying, and so much more. <br> <br>For the way this team is built and from the way it’s built, I suspect we have &#8212; we have many of you, as I said, maybe back visiting soon.  <br> <br>Above all, as we beat this pandemic and celebrate fans coming back to stadiums, we celebrate something else: a national achievement.  We came together, as fellow Americans &#8212; frontline workers, friends, families, neighbors &#8212; looking out for one another.  And Dodger Stadium was the heart of that effort &#8212; I want to thank the ownership for that &#8212; the heart of the effort, administering more than 1 million COVID tests at the stadium and getting nearly a half million vaccine doses in people&#8217;s arms. <br> <br>Dodgers also helped us come together by being the first team in baseball to make their stadium available to voting &#8212; as distanced, outdoor vote centers during the last election. <br> <br>So not only does Dodger Stadium hosts world champions, it helped save lives and strengthen our democracy as well. <br> <br>Together, as a nation, we have proved that it truly is never a good bet to bet against America.   America is back, and the Dodgers are back. <br> <br>So, congratulations to all of you and the best of luck the rest of the season.  May God bless you all.  And may God protect our troops.  Thank you. (Applause.)<br> <br>Now &#8212; now let&#8217;s bring up a three-time Cy Young Award winner, Clayton Kershaw, to say a few words and maybe throw a few curveballs.  (Laughter.)  Okay.  Come on up, man.  (Applause.)<br> <br>MR. KERSHAW:  Hi, everybody.  First time to speak at the White House, so sorry if I&#8217;m a little nervous.  (Laughter.)  But, Mr. President, thank you for having us.  It&#8217;s an honor to be here and get to celebrate our World Series victory here at the White House. <br> <br>Last season was a special one for us, but it was also a challenging one for our country.  And our hope was that we were able to provide just a little bit of joy and comfort and relief to our fans that were going through some tough times. <br> <br>This season, it&#8217;s been incredible to have fans back in the ballpark.  We missed their energy and their passion for the game.  And it means so much to us that people are coming back to the ballpark and things around the country are going back to normal.  Hopefully, like you said, we can come visit again next year.<br> <br>So, with that, we brought something for you and the Vice President.  And now our team owner, Mark Walter, is going to bring that down for you.<br> <br>(The President is presented with a Dodgers jersey.)  (Applause.)<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I have to show you I&#8217;m a man of courage.  (Laughter.) <br> <br>Well, thank you very much.  What a &#8212; what a lovely &#8212; what a great honor.  Thank you.<br> <br>MR. KERSHAW:  I think Doc is going to come up now and present to Madam Vice President.  (Applause.)<br>(The Vice President is presented with a Dodgers jersey.)  (Applause.) <br> <br>MR. ROBERTS:  Madam Vice President, this is your jersey. <br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  I needed it.  (Laughter.)  (Applause.) Thank you all.  Thank you.  Thanks, guys.<br> <br>MR. ROBERTS:  That blue looks very good on you.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hold it up.<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  There you go.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  All right.  Okay.<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you. <br> <br>MR. KERSHAW:  Thank you so much for having us.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, man.<br> <br>MR. KERSHAW:  Appreciate it.  Thank you.  (Laughter.) <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  All right.  You&#8217;re going to take this down, I know, in a minute, but hang on a second. <br> <br>Folks, you know, I think even the Americans who aren&#8217;t baseball fans, they &#8212; there&#8217;s an awful lot of baseball metaphors and an awful lot that we &#8212; we &#8212; it creeps into every part of our language and our culture.  And it has been one of the great equalizers. <br> <br>What &#8212; come on up here, Madam Vice President.  What the Vice President and I have spent a lot of time working on making sure we do is deal with the equity in the United States.<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Yeah.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Making sure that we change the dynamic in a fundamental way.  That, you know, we are the only nation in the world based &#8212; organized, based on an idea.  Ever na- &#8212; every other nation is based on a notion of culture or geography or religion.  We&#8217;re the only one based on an idea.  Not a joke. <br> <br>And the idea is, &#8220;We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men [and women] are created equal… endowed by their Creator.&#8221;  That&#8217;s who we are.  And we decided this is a time to push that forward. <br> <br>Look what baseball has done.  Look what baseball has done.  Look at &#8212; look &#8212; the makeup of this ballclub and the makeup of the ballclubs all across the league.  I really mean that.  It&#8217;s gigantic.  Look at who&#8217;s managing this club.  You know, I mean, it&#8217;s &#8212; so it matters.  And you send a message that is profound. <br> <br>Now I&#8217;m going to mention one ballplayer that the Vice President heard me mentioned before, that I &#8212; even I never &#8212; and I &#8212; even I&#8217;m not old enough to have watched him play &#8212; but Satchel Paige. <br> <br>And Satchel Paige, as any pitcher out here can tell you &#8212; the older you get, the harder to keep that arm going.  Right?  Well, he didn&#8217;t get to the majors until he was 45 years old.  On his 47th birthday &#8212; I know you all know this &#8212; he pitched a win against Chicago.  And all the press went into his room, and &#8212; in the locker room, and said, &#8220;Satch, Satch, it&#8217;s amazing: 47 years old and you pitched a win.  How do you feel about being 47, Satch?&#8221;  He said, &#8220;Boys, that&#8217;s not how I look at age.&#8221;  I had the staff look this up.  This is what he did say: &#8220;That&#8217;s not how I look at age.&#8221;  &#8220;Then how do you look at it, Satch?&#8221;  &#8220;I look at this way&#8221; &#8212; he said, &#8220;How old would you be if you didn&#8217;t know how old you were?&#8221;  (Laughter.)  I am 51 years old.  (Laughter.)  You guys are 19.  (Laughter.) <br> <br>Anyway, I think you real- &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t underestimate it anymore.  You saw what happened in other professional leagues and the way you and all the leagues responded to the crisis we faced.  So thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.<br> <br>And I &#8212; I just want you to know that there &#8212; we have a congressional baseball game every year.  In the very beginning, I used to be a centerfielder and my Walter Mitty dream &#8212; anyways, it&#8217;s a long story, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212;<br> <br>And my kids only remember two things that ever happened to me in my career &#8212; my boys.  And they&#8217;ve met kings and queens, they&#8217;ve gone to other countries.  But I played, when the first &#8212; the second congressional baseball game at the old stadium &#8212; the old Washington stadium.  And I hit one off the right-centerfield wall.  It bounced off the wall.  I think it&#8217;s 368 or &#8212; I don&#8217;t know what is exactly now &#8212; but off the wall.  And I&#8217;m rounding &#8212; anyway, to make a long story short, my kids remember that, all the rest.  And guess what?  The only thing I remember, too.  (Laughter.)  Here I thought: What could have been.  What could have been. <br> <br>But at any rate.  And I&#8217;m with Cedric Richmond, who is a congressman, a hell of an athlete, pitched in college.  And he &#8212; we&#8217;re both hoping that somehow &#8212; he would do it based on merit; I&#8217;m hoping that because I got elected President, I may do it on influence &#8212; to be invi- &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to be inducted into the &#8212; the Congressional Baseball Hall of Fame.  (Laughter.)  You all think I&#8217;m kidding, don&#8217;t you?  (Laughter.)  No.<br> <br>Anyway, so thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you.  And I just want you to know, it really means a lot to us that you&#8217;re here.  It means a lot that &#8212; and the kind of hope you give the American people.  Don&#8217;t underestimate it, guys.  Don&#8217;t underestimate it. <br> <br>12:18 P.M. EDT </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Amends Florida Emergency Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-amends-florida-emergency-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 18:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional assistance available to the State of Florida by authorizing an increase in the level of federal funding for debris removal and emergency protective measures undertaken in the State of Florida as a result of the Surfside Building Collapse beginning on June 24, 2021, and continuing. Under the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional assistance available to the State of Florida by authorizing an increase in the level of federal funding for debris removal and emergency protective measures undertaken in the State of Florida as a result of the Surfside Building Collapse beginning on June 24, 2021, and continuing.</p>



<p>Under the emergency declaration issued for the State of Florida on June 25, 2021, the federal share was made available for the Individuals and Households Program under Section 408 of the Stafford Act and assistance for debris removal and emergency protective measures, including direct federal assistance, at 75 percent of the total eligible costs.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under the President&#8217;s order today, the federal share for debris removal and emergency protective measures, including direct federal assistance, under the Public Assistance program has been increased to 100 percent of the total eligible costs for a continuous period of 30 days beginning June 24, 2021.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT:  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the June Jobs Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/02/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-june-jobs-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 17:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 10:50 A.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; It is a good morning.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; It’s a good morning.&#160; As we get prepared to celebrate Independence Day, today’s job news brought us something else to celebrate.&#160; This morning we learned that, in June, our economy created 850,000 jobs.&#160; Eight hundred and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>10:50 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; It is a good morning.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; It’s a good morning.&nbsp; As we get prepared to celebrate Independence Day, today’s job news brought us something else to celebrate.&nbsp; This morning we learned that, in June, our economy created 850,000 jobs.&nbsp; Eight hundred and fifty thousand jobs.&nbsp; Wages went up for American workers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Since I took office, our recovery [economy] has created an average of 600,000 dollar &#8212; six- &#8212; “dollars.” &nbsp;(Laughs.) &nbsp;I wish they &#8212; they probably wish there was 600,000 jobs that paid $600,000 a year. &nbsp;But 600,000 jobs per month. &nbsp;We have now created over 3 million jobs since I took office &#8212; more jobs than have ever been created in the first five months of any presidency in modern history, thanks to the incredible work of the entire team.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is historic progress pulling our economy out of the worst crisis in 100 years, driven in part by our dramatic progress in vaccinating our nation and beating back the pandemic, as well as other elements of the American Rescue Plan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, the U.S. is the only major advanced economy where the OECD projections of future output are higher today than they were in January 2020, before the pandemic hit.&nbsp; And America was ranked first in Bloomberg’s “COVID Resilience Ranking.”&nbsp; None of this happened by accident.&nbsp; Again, it’s a direct result of the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; And at the time, people questioned whether or not we should do that, even though we didn’t have bipartisan support.&nbsp; Well, it worked.<br>&nbsp;<br>In February, the Congressional Budget Office projected 2021 economic growth would be 3.7 percent.&nbsp; Yesterday, they doubled that number to 7.4 percent, in large part thanks to the American Rescue Plan and our work to defeat the virus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The last time the economy grew at this rate was in 1984, and Ronald Reagan was telling us it’s “morning in America.”&nbsp; Well, it’s getting close to afternoon here.&nbsp; The sun is coming out.&nbsp; At the time, the CBO revised their long-run deficit projections down as a share of GDP they &#8212; just as they have done.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the American Rescue Plan is strengthening our financial position, and it grows our economy.&nbsp; It’s continuing to grow our economy.&nbsp; And the strength of our recovery is helping us flip the script.<br>&nbsp;<br>Instead of workers competing with each other for jobs that are scarce, employers are competing with each other to attract workers.&nbsp; That kind of competition in the market doesn’t just give workers more ability to earn higher wages; it also gives them the power to demand to be treated with dignity and respect in the workplace.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>More jobs, better wages &#8212; that’s a good combination.&nbsp; Put simply: Our economy is on the move, and we have COVID-19 on the run.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Yes, we have more work to do to get America vaccinated and everyone back to work.&nbsp; We are aiming for full employment, and that means keeping our pace on job growth, including for Black, Hispanic, and Asian workers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this progress is testament to our commitment to grow this economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan provided resources to get shots in people’s arms and checks in people’s pockets.&nbsp; Schools &#8212; schools were struggling to reopen so we made vaccinating teachers a priority, getting schools much-needed support.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In March, we&#8217;ve added &#8212; just in the month of [since] March, we added 364,000 education jobs and roles. &nbsp;Small businesses and restaurants were getting crushed. &nbsp;Now we’re delivering the loans and support they need to reopen and to stay open.<br>&nbsp;<br>This morning, we’ve learned that jobs in some hard-hit sectors &#8212; such as restaurants, hotels, amusement parks &#8212; were up by 343,000 last month; over 1.5 million over the past five months.&nbsp; And more help is on the way to give families just a little bit more breathing room.<br>&nbsp;<br>Starting this month, families are going to receiving one of the largest-ever, single-year tax cuts that middle-class families have ever received, and it’s called the Child Care Tax Credit.<br>&nbsp;<br>And here’s how it works: In the past, if you paid taxes and had a good income, you could deduct $2,000 per child, and that would come off the total amount of taxes you owe.&nbsp; If you had two children, you owed $10,000; you take off $4,000.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In the American Rescue Plan, we expanded that.&nbsp; Now a parent would get $3,600 for each child under the age of six, and $3,000 for dependents they had between the ages of 6 and 17.&nbsp; So instead of just being a credit against your taxes you owe, it’s now a fully refundable credit, half of which will get paid out in monthly basis.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, what that means is: This year, middle-class families with two young children can expect to get &#8212; receive $7,200 in a rebate, in effect &#8212; a tax return &#8212; with the monthly payments of $600 a month starting this month, until it’s paid out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Eight out of every ten families who use direct deposit will get their refunds.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll be able to get a monthly payment on the 15th of every month from now until the end of the year, so they get that paid out.&nbsp; Help with families most need it &#8212; most need help to make ends meet.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ve said it for a long time: It’s time to give ordinary folks, ordinary Americans, middle-class and working-class Americans a tax break.&nbsp; This is the type of tax cut that can help our economy because it will go to families who are going to spend it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It will also help lead a historic reduction in child poverty &#8212; excuse me &#8212; (the President takes a drink of water) &#8212; historic reduction in child poverty, which would have long-term benefits for our economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re delivering $39 billion to help childcare providers serve more families, to help parents, particularly women, get back to work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Last month, our economy added nearly 25,000 childcare jobs.&nbsp; Again, none of this happened by accident.&nbsp; We’re providing &#8212; proving to the naysayers and the doubters that they were wrong.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>None of this is guaranteed to continue, though, unless we finish our work.&nbsp; Now is the time to accelerate the progress we’ve been making.&nbsp; Now is the time to build in a long-term foundation that we’ve laid, and build it in for a long term.&nbsp; Economists of all stripes agree that my plan will create good jobs and drastically strengthen our economy in the long run.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we have to continue to make the investments that will allow our economy to build back better and deal everyone in.&nbsp; We took a significant step in that direction last week when the bipartisan group of senators forged an agreement with me to move forward on key portions of my American Jobs Plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It was &#8212; I just in Wisconsin, where I highlighted how this agreement is going to pave the way for a generational investment to modernize our infrastructure; create millions of jobs, according to the experts; and what that will mean an ever- &#8212; and it won&#8217;t just be in the center cities.&nbsp; It will be every corner of the state and our nation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to create jobs repairing roads and bridges, replacing 100 percent of our nation’s lead water pipes, making our power grid more reliable, delivering high-speed Internet to every American home, rural and urban.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re going to put people to work building a nationwide electric vehicle charging network, transitioning from diesel school buses and transit buses to electric buses, and bringing in world-class rail service to more Americans by reducing &#8212; and, in the process, reduce our carbon footprint.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, when I was up in Wisconsin, I said &#8212; I pointed out &#8212; the governor was there.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;Gov, I know it takes…&#8221; &#8212; or I don&#8217;t know how many people &#8212; a couple hundred people, I guess, in the audience.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;It takes, they tell me, four and half hours to drive from here to Chicago.&nbsp; With the money we have in &#8212; for mass transit here, we &#8212; you&#8217;re going to be able to do that in two and half hours.&#8221;&nbsp; And all the data shows that when it&#8217;s easier to get someplace by rail than by automobile, it&#8217;s cheaper and it generates a whole lot less carbon footprint.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to create good-paying union jobs capping hundreds of thousands of abandoned oil and gas wells to stop methane leaks, which are devastating, and to protect the health of our communities.&nbsp; These are good jobs.<br>&nbsp;<br>Taken together, these investments are going to position America to compete with the world and win the 21st century.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, as we bring home key parts of my American Jobs Plan, I’m going to make the case for equally critical investments that we still need, including those in which I introduced at the same time: my American Families Plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>When I was running for President, I put together a bold, aggressive plan to deliver childcare, paid leave, universal pre-K for three- and four-year-olds, free community college.&nbsp; Maybe the most important among them was extending the expanded Child Care Tax Credit I just mentioned for another five years, which will significantly benefit middle-class and working-class families.<br>&nbsp;<br>That human infrastructure is as essential as our physical infrastructure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to help us create more good jobs, ease the burden on working families, and strengthen our economy &#8212; strengthen it in the long run.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These investments are critical.&nbsp; And as the plans I put forward tackle our climate crisis, which are broad and deep, I&#8217;m going to fight to see them enacted and signed into law.&nbsp; We have a chance to seize this economic momentum of the first months of my administration, not just to build back, but as I&#8217;ve been saying, &#8220;build back better.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is much already &#8212; this much is already clear: We’re on the right track and we&#8217;re on the right track.&nbsp; Our plan is working.&nbsp; And we’re not going to let up now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I want to thank everyone.&nbsp; I wish you all a happy Fourth of July.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be able to go to ballgames.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to be able to sit in the stadiums.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to be able to be with your families in backyard barbeques, as we hoped.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to make more progress.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, God bless America.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could you talk to us about Afghanistan?&nbsp; Is the drawdown going to be done in the next few days?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, we’re on &#8212; we’re on track exactly as to where we expected to be.&nbsp; But we just &#8212; I wanted to make sure there was enough, quote, “running room” that we could get &#8212; wouldn&#8217;t be able to do it all until September.&nbsp; There will still be some forces left.&nbsp; But it’s a rational drawdown with our allies, and it’s making &#8212; so there&#8217;s nothing unusual about it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you worried that the Afghan government might fall?&nbsp; I mean, we are hearing about how the Taliban is taking more and more districts.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, we were in that war for 20 years.&nbsp; Twenty years.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; I met with the Afghan government here in the White House, in the Oval.&nbsp; I think they have the capacity to be able to sustain the government.&nbsp; There are going to have to be, down the road, more negotiations, I suspect.&nbsp; But I am &#8212; I am concerned that they deal with the internal issues that they have to be able to generate the kind of support they need nationwide to maintain the government.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow on that thought on Afghanistan &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I want to talk about happy things, man.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If there is evidence that Kabul is threatened, which some of the intelligence reports have suggested it could be in six months or thereabout, do you think you&#8217;ve got the capability to help provide any kind of air support, military support to them to keep the capital safe, even if the U.S. troops are obviously fully out by that time?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have worked out an over-the-horizon capacity that we can be value added, but the Afghans are going to have to be able to do it themselves with the Air Force they have, which we’re helping them maintain.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, on Afghanistan &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m not going to answer any more quick question on Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, it’s Fourth of July.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the economy &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned about Fourth of July gatherings &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m concerned that you guys are asking me questions that I&#8217;ll answer next week.&nbsp; But I’m &#8212; this is a holiday weekend.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to celebrate it.&nbsp; There is great things happening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The economy is growing faster than any time in 40 years.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got a record number of new jobs.&nbsp; COVID deaths are down 90 percent.&nbsp; Wages are up faster than any time in 15 years.&nbsp; We&#8217;re bringing out &#8212; bringing our troops home.&nbsp; We have &#8212; all across America, people are going to ballgames and doing good things.&nbsp; This is good.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll be &#8212; I’ll answer all your negative questions &#8212; not negative &#8212; your legitimate question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But with the gatherings, are you concerned that there is a potential, this weekend, in places where vaccination levels are not particularly high, that there will be new COVID outbreaks in various regions of the country?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I am concerned that people who have not gotten vaccinated have the capacity to catch the variant and spread the variant to other people who have not been vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I am not concerned there is going to be a major outbreak &#8212; in other words, that we&#8217;re going to have another epidemic nationwide, but I am concerned lives will be lost.&nbsp; And I was even reading today there&#8217;s some speculation and some judgment that’s coming out that you may be able to even communicate the vaccine &#8212; the &#8212; the new variant to your pets.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I say, not &#8212; not totally facetiously, for those of you who haven&#8217;t been vaccinated because you don&#8217;t &#8212; you don&#8217;t &#8212; you don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s &#8212; you want to go through it: It doesn&#8217;t hurt, it&#8217;s accessible, it&#8217;s free, it&#8217;s available.&nbsp; And not only &#8212; don&#8217;t think about yourself; think about your family.&nbsp; Think about those around you.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we should be thinking about today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Fourth of July this year is different than the Fourth of July last year.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to be better next year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you all.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you think that Congress will enact your plans?&nbsp; Are you confident &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that you&#8217;re going to get it done?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Come on.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Come on, guys.&nbsp; Am I co- &#8212; are you &#8212; have you ever been confident about anything with guarantee?&nbsp; Who wants to put money on anything that Congress is going to do?&nbsp; Look, folks, this is a process.&nbsp; This is a process.<br>&nbsp;<br>I love you guys, but it&#8217;s a process.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t &#8212; you want me to say, “Yes, I’m absolutely certain.”&nbsp; Well, are you absolutely certain this new commission is going to work, investigating what happened on the 6th?&nbsp; Are you guys confident that Republicans are going to participate?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, all I know &#8212; only thing I know what to do &#8212; and I really mean this &#8212; is do my best to lay out what I think the country has to do, try to be as persuasive as I can, and hope.&nbsp; And thus far, you know, it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, it seems to be working a little bit.&nbsp; So, thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>11:06 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/02/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-independent-review-commission-on-sexual-assault/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[5:02 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you so much for joining us.&#160; Today&#8217;s call is going to be on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&#160; And the contents of this call are embargoed until 11:00 tomorrow morning, Friday, June [July] 2nd. With that, I&#8217;m happy to turn it over to our speakers,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>5:02 P.M. EDT<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you so much for joining us.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s call is going to be on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And the contents of this call are embargoed until 11:00 tomorrow morning, Friday, <s>June</s> [July] 2nd.<br><br>With that, I&#8217;m happy to turn it over to our speakers, [senior administration official], who is the [redacted], and [senior administration official], who is the [redacted].<br><br>[Senior administration official], over to you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].<br><br>Good afternoon, and thank you all for joining us to discuss the President&#8217;s announcement regarding the findings and recommendations of the Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault in the Military.<br><br>As most of you probably know, President Biden has a longstanding and deep-seated commitment to fighting to eliminate all forms of gender-based violence.&nbsp; This has really been a central part of his life&#8217;s work, including as an original author of the Violence Against Women Act in 1994 as a senator.&nbsp;<br><br>So at the very early days of his presidency, following up on a promise he made during the campaign, he asked Secretary of Defense Austin to create this Independent Review Commission to undertake an in-depth analysis over a period of 90 days, and to provide its findings and recommendations to address sexual assault and harassment in the military.<br><br>On March 24th, the Independent Review Commission, chaired by Lynn Rosenthal and comprised of 12 independent highly qualified experts, began their work.&nbsp; They were charged with making recommendations &#8212; and [senior administration official] will talk about this more &#8212; in four key areas related to accountability, prevention, climate and culture, and survivor care and support.<br><br>The Commission has met with the Secretary on several occasions to present their findings and recommendations to him.&nbsp; Defense Secretary Austin informs the President that he is endorsing the findings of the Commission and supports the recommendation to remove cases of sexual assault, sexual harassment, and related crimes from the military chain of command, as well as recommendations in the other key areas of prevention, climate and culture, and victim care and support.&nbsp; The President spoke with Secretary Austin about these issues and fully supports his approach.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden appreciates the leadership Secretary Austin has shown in taking these bold steps necessary to remedy this persistent problem.&nbsp; The President has sought to stamp out the scourge of sexual assault in the military and believes that in advancing the IRC’s recommendations, the Department of Defense will be introducing comprehensive changes to implement his administration&#8217;s unwavering commitment to improving both the response to and prevention of sexual assault and sexual harassment in the military.<br><br>And the President would particularly like to thank the IRC chair, Lynn Rosenthal, who he has known for a very long time, and the entire Independent Review Commission for their exemplary work and dedication.&nbsp;<br><br>Most of all, the President is grateful to the hundreds of individuals across the Services, the many external stakeholders whom the IRC consulted with, and to the survivors who shared their stories and made recommendations to the IRC.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s also grateful to countless other survivors of sexual assault and sexual harassment in the military, who for decades have shared their stories and their pain, as well as their courage and their resilience to continue to speak out and advocate for these much-needed reforms and to improve the pathways to healing and justice for survivors.<br><br>Finally, the President wants to acknowledge and thank Senator Gillibrand for many years of tireless efforts to shine a light on these deep-seated problems and for her efforts to build a bipartisan consensus to work for change, and is also grateful for the leadership of Senator Joni Ernst, and others, who have amplified the voices of survivors to advocate for necessary reforms to address assault and harassment in the military.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to turn it over to [senior administration official] now to provide more information about how the IRC approach their work, as well as the findings and recommendations of the Commission.<br><br>Over to you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And I want to begin by just really appreciating the leadership of President Biden and Secretary Austin in addressing this longstanding problem.&nbsp; And I want to acknowledge the support and cooperation of the Department of Defense and the Services as a part of this process.<br><br>The Independent Review Commission established that independence by creating a body of highly qualified experts, external to the Department, as the deliberative body on our recommendations.&nbsp; We were supported in that effort, however, by senior leaders from the services and subject-matter experts across the force.&nbsp;<br><br>As a part of our process, we met with over 600 external experts, including survivors, researchers, former service members, commanders, junior and senior enlisted members, and advocates.&nbsp; And while we have some tough findings in our report, we don&#8217;t at all believe that these represent a lack of concern for this problem.&nbsp; Everyone we talked to &#8212; senior officials within DOD, senior leaders in the services, and enlisted junior and senior members &#8212; want to see change.&nbsp; Everyone we talked to wants to see that change.&nbsp; There are people working very hard to make that happen, but they often are not equipped to do so.&nbsp;<br><br>We identified that there is a troubling gap between what senior leaders say about this problem and how junior enlisted members experience the problem.&nbsp; We have heard for many years that there is no tolerance for sexual harassment and sexual assault, but we learned that, in practice, there is quite a lot of tolerance.&nbsp;<br><br>We found that the military justice system is not well equipped to handle sensitive cases like sexual assault, sexual harassment, and domestic violence.&nbsp; We note that there is a strong continuum between sexual harassment and sexual assault, and the relationship of both these problems to poor unit climates.&nbsp; We note also that the cyber domain has to be prioritized as a part of unit climates.&nbsp;<br><br>We found that there are critical deficiencies in the workforce across the services, including lack of experience and lack of specialization, which are key elements to addressing sexual assault and sexual harassment.&nbsp;<br><br>Nowhere is this problem more apparent than in the near-total lack of a prevention workforce.&nbsp; So we often hear that prevention is the key to solving this problem.&nbsp; But we learned that there aren&#8217;t actually prevention specialists working across the services to make that happen.&nbsp; There is a lack of an evidence-informed public health approach to prevention.&nbsp;<br><br>And finally, we found that victims carry a very heavy burden.&nbsp; And they carry this burden whether they report or not.&nbsp; Many whom &#8212; who did report regretted doing so because of what they experienced afterwards.&nbsp; That includes being ostracized, bullied, and having trouble accessing quality services.<br><br>I must say, and the IRC strongly believes, that leadership is the key to correcting all of these deficiencies.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made 28 recommendations and 54 sub-recommendations in those lines of effort that [senior administration official] noted, including accountability, prevention, climate and culture, and victim care and support.&nbsp;<br><br>So I just want to highlight a few.&nbsp; As you know, we&#8217;ve recommended shifting prosecution decisions to special victims prosecutors outside of the chain of command.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also recommended improving the handling of sexual harassment cases and a series of other improvements to the UCMJ.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve recommended equipping leaders to understand prevention and the development of an actual prevention workforce to carry out these programs.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve made a series of recommendations to improve unit climate, including better methods to select, develop, and evaluate leaders; enhancements to the climate survey process; and greater transparency about disciplinary actions.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve made a series of recommendations to improve victim care and support, including shifting sexual assault response coordinators and victim advocates out of the command structure, largely eliminating part-time and collateral-duty victim advocates, and professionalizing the sexual assault response workforce across the board.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve also recommended lifting the barrier to victims of sexual harassment receiving services from sexual assault prevention and response programs, which is a problem in the services, except for the Army which handles both of these problems together.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve recommended identifying a structure within the Department of Defense to provide greater assistance to the Services in addressing sexual harassment.&nbsp;<br><br>Our report includes four separate reports from each line of effort.&nbsp; So, depending on what you&#8217;re most interested in, when the report is released tomorrow, you&#8217;ll be able to dive into all of these recommendations in great detail in accountability, prevention, climate and culture, and victim services.&nbsp; So everything you want to know about what I just highlighted is within those four reports.&nbsp;<br><br>Finally, I want to note that we found and we believe that commanders are essential to implementing every one of these recommendations.&nbsp; Most importantly, commanders are the key to improving unit climate, to changing the culture, and to protecting victims from negative consequences related to reporting sexual assault.&nbsp; Indeed, commanders are the key to making it safe for victims to come forward at all.&nbsp;<br><br>And I want to say very clearly that we reject the notion that shifting legal decisions about prosecution from command to prosecutors diminishes the role of those commanders.&nbsp; We believe, instead, that it enhances their role and places them in the lead of taking care of their people &#8212; the number one job of commanders &#8212; and creating climates of no tolerance for sexual assault, sexual harassment, and related crimes.&nbsp;<br><br>And with that, I will turn it back over to [senior administration official].&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll just say a few more words on the process going forward, which is that the President &#8212; the Secretary, excuse me, has made it clear that he generally accepts all of these recommendations from the IRC and that now he&#8217;s going to move into the implementation process.&nbsp;<br><br>So as you have just heard and as you all know, this is a profound change for the Department of Defense and, really, a monumental pivot in how the department does its business.&nbsp;<br><br>So the Secretary has asked for the grace to, I think in his own words, “measure twice and cut once” as he thinks through implementation.&nbsp; And the President really fully supports that approach.&nbsp;<br><br>So, over the next few months, the White House and the Pentagon will be in consultation to best understand how to make these recommendations to reality, and work with Congress to amend the Uniform Code of Military Justice, as is required to make whatever legislative changes are part of these recommendations.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you all so much.&nbsp; With that, we&#8217;re happy to open the line to some press questions.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, in the recommendations that you made in terms of leadership selection and how you can do that better to make sure that a command climate doesn&#8217;t support or doesn&#8217;t tolerate sexual harassment and sexual assault, what are some of the specific recommendations that you made for that sort of selection process?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Most importantly, we recommend using narrative and qualitative data to select and evaluate commanders so that there&#8217;s a more &#8212; a fuller picture of how they&#8217;re actually addressing these climate issues.&nbsp;<br><br>And then we&#8217;ve recommended a series of improvements to the climate survey process so that they can get more on-the-ground information about the climate specifically related to sexual harassment and specific to the ability to report sexual assault.&nbsp; So those are some improvements we&#8217;ve recommended to the climate survey process.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So, I have a question for both of you.&nbsp; Does the Biden administration support the Gillibrand legislation that takes all felony crimes out of the chain of command?&nbsp; And if you don&#8217;t, then don&#8217;t you end up with two legal systems &#8212; one that deals with just sex crimes and then another that deals with felony and murder and other serious crimes?&nbsp;<br><br>And then my other question for you is: You talked about taking victim advocates out of the chain of command.&nbsp; Who would they report to?&nbsp; How would that work?&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I can jump in on the first one.&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think it&#8217;s really clear that Senator Gillibrand deserved an enormous amount of credit for her tireless efforts over many, many years to address the problem of sexual assault in the military.&nbsp; And the President really shares her strong passion to take on this issue. &nbsp;That&#8217;s why he asked Secretary Austin to stand up this IRC on sexual assault and sexual harassment immediately upon taking office.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think, you know, the President &#8212; this review commission has been squarely focused and was asked just to focus only on addressing the problem of sexual assault and harassment in the military.&nbsp; And he is really pleased to see that there is a growing consensus that these crimes should be taken out of the chain of command.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to now look to Congress to work out the details for legislating that change.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And this is [senior administration official].&nbsp; I think that there are a few different models for who the victim advocates and the sexual assault response coordinators could report to.&nbsp; So &#8212; it’s better &#8212; rather than identifying one specific component, we should talk about some of those guiding principles.&nbsp;<br><br>And we do believe in flexibility for the services because they all operate a little bit differently, but we think this requirement should be uniform, and then, within that, the services can develop implementation plans.&nbsp;<br><br>But the key is that sexual assault response coordinators and victim advocates need to be free of any sort of command influence over what kind of services a victim receives.&nbsp;<br><br>So, certainly, the commander is responsible for making sure that victims are protected from retaliation, bullying &#8212; all of that that can happen after a report &#8212; but actually what kind of services they might want to need to be developed by a professional victim advocate who can put a package together.&nbsp;<br><br>And we actually recommend a commander&#8217;s package, which will include what the victim has identified as his or her needs, the kind of support they might need throughout the process, what remedies should be available for them.&nbsp; And these could be as simple as having some time off to go to medical or legal appointments.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s really very much in the details of what victims identify that they need.&nbsp;<br><br>So you can see, as I laid that out, that those sexual assault response coordinators and victim advocates should be within a unit where they can receive some professional supervision.&nbsp; So that could be within a chain where social services are happening on an installation or a chain in which they can receive that sort of support from colleagues.&nbsp;<br><br>They also have to be able to provide these independent recommendations, but, at the same time, they have to have key relationships with commanders.&nbsp; So in no way does this sort of separate those conversations.&nbsp; What we envision is that the victim advocates are able to work closely with commanders and serve as key advisors.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I have two questions, one being if we could get a timeline or an estimated timeline for about how long you think it will take for some of these recommendations to start being implemented and maybe, you know, until all of them are implemented.<br><br>But then, also, [senior administration official], you mentioned in your remarks that you found that there was a gap between what senior leaders say is happening and what the junior enlisted service members are experiencing.&nbsp; How are these recommendations going to ensure that that gap is closed and that that won&#8217;t continue happening for years to come &#8212; where senior leaders are pointing to these recommendations as they&#8217;re being rolled out, but the junior service members are continuing to not see that play out at their level?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s really the heart of the matter.&nbsp; On the timeline, I think DOD is going to have to identify that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve recommended some key priorities for immediate action.&nbsp; We believe that because we found such critical deficiencies in victim care and support &#8212; and I might add that, to me, those were surprising findings, as somebody who&#8217;s worked on this for some time.&nbsp; But because we found those critical deficiencies, we would like to see &#8212; we recommend that manpower study be conducted on the victim advocacy workforce within three months, with additional implementation within six months.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we think those are priority for near-term actions.&nbsp; The legislative changes to the UCMJ will take &#8212; should take some time.&nbsp; So we recommend, in our report, enactment dates of 2023.&nbsp; We think that it&#8217;s important to take due care to structure this system in a way that has the best chance of success.<br><br>So, we recommend that there &#8212; this is not an area for quick wins or quick fixes, but rather a plan that will result in sustained change over time.&nbsp; And we think that investment of time is what will lead to the results.&nbsp; We think that’s what will really move the needle.<br><br>And your second question &#8212; the gap between what senior leaders say about the problem and what junior leaders actually experience?&nbsp; I mean, the key finding from junior leaders &#8212; well, from junior enlisted members &#8212; I’m sorry &#8212; is that they experience daily acts of demeaning language and sexual harassment.&nbsp; That is ubiquitous.&nbsp; In many units, that is a part of the climate, and that women in particular are told this is just what they should expect.&nbsp; We spoke with many, many survivors and also junior enlisted members who witnessed their friends experiencing sexual harassment and assault, who said that, on one hand, the leaders say there’s no tolerance, but on the other hand, they’re experiencing that daily.<br><br>So, by focusing on selecting, developing, and evaluating the right leaders, we should end up with commanders and leaders at all levels who actually practice no tolerance, which means interrupting these behaviors, which means setting that standard.&nbsp; And those things, quite frankly, while some of our package requires investment in the workforce and resources, that does not.&nbsp; That can start on day one &#8212; and that is: Interrupt these behaviors, speak out, and show and practice a real no tolerance.&nbsp; That’s how you create a positive climate.<br><br>When you take as good care of your people as you do your vehicles, that’s when we’ll start to see real change.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to clarify &#8212; thanks for the call &#8212; just to clarify: So you&#8217;re not suggesting (inaudible) until 2023 to take this out of the chain of command?&nbsp; And then also, if you could just give &#8212; just to confirm that.&nbsp;<br><br>And then also, if you just give us a sense of whether or not you think, once these recommendations are implemented, whether the kind of situation we all saw play out at Fort Hood could still repeat itself.&nbsp; Is it &#8212; or is it clear to you that once these changes are implemented, that kind of thing won&#8217;t happen again?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So we recommend that the legislation be enacted this year, but that the provisions are enacted in 2023 &#8212; that that kind of time is taken to appropriately build a structure which involves special victims prosecutors reporting outside of the chain of command &#8212; of the military chain of command &#8212; and addressing sexual assault, sexual harassment, domestic violence, and related crimes.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s our special victims bucket &#8212; the issues that we think should be addressed.&nbsp; And we believe it takes some time to establish that system.&nbsp; It involves a number of steps forward to do so.&nbsp;<br><br>And many of our recommendations parallel the Fort Hood report, particularly removing the victim advocates from the chain of command.&nbsp; So I think that we&#8217;ve identified some of those same problems.&nbsp; I think that when you have lea- &#8212; it&#8217;s all about leadership.&nbsp; It&#8217;s all about commanders stepping forward and leading and having the skills to do so.<br><br>I think, today, we heard from commanders that they don&#8217;t always know what to do to address their &#8212; these poor climates &#8212; that they&#8217;re seeking out.&nbsp; And we recommend some steps the Department can take to provide that kind of help to commanders who step forward and say, &#8220;I want to improve my climate.&#8221;<br><br>So I think careful implementation of this plan will result in leaders who are better equipped to address sexual harassment and sexual assault, and particularly the continuum between the two.&nbsp; So if commanders are aggressive, proactive in addressing sexual harassment &#8212; that means stopping the demeaning language, that means addressing those who are committing the harassment, that means working appropriately through the steps that will lead to accountability.&nbsp; When those things happen, we hope that we can prevent situations like what tragically happened at Fort Hood.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, everyone.&nbsp; That concludes our call.&nbsp; A friendly reminder that we are on background, attributed to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and that the contents of this call are embargoed until 11:00 tomorrow morning.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks all for joining.<br><br>5:27 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe Biden on the Results of the Independent Review Commission on Military Sexual Assault</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-results-of-the-independent-review-commission-on-military-sexual-assault/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I strongly support Secretary Austin’s announcement that he is accepting the core recommendations put forward by the Independent Review Commission on Military Sexual Assault (IRC), including removing the investigation and prosecution of sexual assault from the chain of command and creating highly specialized units to handle these cases and related crimes. Ending violence against women&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I strongly support Secretary Austin’s announcement that he is accepting the core recommendations put forward by the Independent Review Commission on Military Sexual Assault (IRC), including removing the investigation and prosecution of sexual assault from the chain of command and creating highly specialized units to handle these cases and related crimes. Ending violence against women and eliminating sexual assault against any person in our country has been a priority for me throughout my career in public service. Sexual assault is an abuse of power and an affront to our shared humanity. And sexual assault in the military is doubly damaging because it also shreds the unity and cohesion that is essential to the functioning of the U.S. military and to our national defense.<br><br>Yet, for as long as we have abhorred this scourge, the statistics and the stories have grown worse. We need concrete actions that fundamentally change the way we handle military sexual assault and that make it clear that these crimes will not be minimized or dismissed. They will be prosecuted under the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ) to their fullest extent. We will also prioritize effective prevention strategies; promote safe, healthy, and respectful climates; and improve services to address the trauma that sexual assault victims experience and to facilitate their healing and recovery.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank Lynn Rosenthal for her leadership of the IRC and her decades of dedicated work to end sexual assault and gender-based violence. To everyone who served on the IRC, thank you for your tireless work to deliver thoughtful, effective, actionable recommendations for how we can drive sexual assault and harassment from the ranks of the United States military.<br><br>I also want to recognize the determined leadership within Congress over the years—in particular of Senator Gillibrand, Senator Ernst, Representative Speier, and Representative Mullin, who have worked in a strong bipartisan way to support needed change and to keep this issue at the forefront of our agenda. I look forward to working with Congress to implement these necessary reforms and promote a work environment that is free from sexual assault and harassment for every one of our brave service members.<br><br>Finally, I want to recognize the experience of our service members who have survived sexual assault and the bravery of those who have shared their stories with the world and advocated for reform. This kind of violation and trauma should never occur. You have a right to be heard. You have a right to justice. And for all those in the ranks who have suffered an assault and its after effects in silence, whether because you felt that you would not receive the support you deserve, or because you feared the repercussions for yourself and your career—I hope this announcement offers some reassurance that the Department of Defense leadership stands with you, starting with your Commander in Chief.<br><br>I also want to honor the pain of those families whose loved one did not survive an assault or the struggle with PTSD that so often follows in the wake of sexual assault. The hurt of that loss is unimaginable.<br><br>Today’s announcement is the beginning, not the end of our work. This will be among the most significant reforms to our military undertaken in recent history, and I’m committed to delivering results. Keeping our country safe has to start with prioritizing the safety of those who proudly sign up to serve our country. And today’s announcement represents an important and overdue step in the right direction.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
