<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 18:23:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The New Atlantic Charter</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/10/the-new-atlantic-charter/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:54:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the President of the United States and Prime Minister of the United Kingdom reaffirm their commitment to work together to realise our vision for a more peaceful and prosperous future. Our revitalised Atlantic Charter, building on the commitments and aspirations set out eighty years ago, affirms our ongoing commitment to sustaining our enduring values&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the President of the United States and Prime Minister of the United Kingdom reaffirm their commitment to work together to realise our vision for a more peaceful and prosperous future.<br><br>Our revitalised Atlantic Charter, building on the commitments and aspirations set out eighty years ago, affirms our ongoing commitment to sustaining our enduring values and defending them against new and old challenges.&nbsp;We commit to working closely with all partners who share our democratic values and to countering the efforts of those who seek to undermine our alliances and institutions.<br><br><strong>First</strong>, we resolve to defend the principles, values, and institutions of democracy and open societies, which drive our own national strength and our alliances.&nbsp;We must ensure that democracies – starting with our own –&nbsp;can deliver on solving the critical challenges of our time.&nbsp;We will champion transparency, uphold the rule of law, and support civil society and independent media.&nbsp;We will also confront injustice and inequality and defend the inherent dignity and human rights of all individuals.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Second</strong>, we intend to strengthen the institutions, laws, and norms that sustain international co-operation to adapt them to meet the new challenges of the 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century, and guard against those that would undermine them.&nbsp;We will work through the rules-based international order to tackle global challenges together;&nbsp;embrace the promise and manage the peril of emerging technologies; promote economic advancement and the dignity of work; and enable open and fair trade between nations.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Third</strong>, we remain united behind the principles of sovereignty, territorial integrity, and the peaceful resolution of disputes. We oppose interference through disinformation or other malign influences, including in elections, and reaffirm our commitment to debt transparency, sustainability and sound governance of debt relief.&nbsp;So too will we defend key principles such as freedom of navigation and overflight and other internationally lawful uses of the seas.<br><br><strong>Fourth,&nbsp;</strong>we resolve to harness and protect our innovative edge in science and technology to support our shared security and deliver jobs at home; to open new markets; to promote the development and deployment of new standards and technologies to support democratic values; to continue to invest in research into the biggest challenges facing the world; and to foster sustainable global development.<br><br><strong>Fifth,</strong>&nbsp;we affirm our shared responsibility for maintaining our collective security and international stability and resilience against the full spectrum of modern threats, including cyber threats.&nbsp;We have declared our nuclear deterrents to the defence of NATO and as long as there are nuclear weapons, NATO will remain a nuclear alliance. Our NATO Allies and partners will always be able to count on us, even as they continue to strengthen their own national forces. We pledge to promote the framework of responsible State behaviour in cyberspace, arms control, disarmament, and proliferation prevention measures to reduce the risks of international conflict.&nbsp;We remain committed to countering terrorists who threaten our citizens and interests.</p>



<p><strong>Sixth,</strong>&nbsp;we commit to continue building an inclusive, fair, climate-friendly, sustainable, rules-based global economy for the 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century. We will strengthen financial stability and transparency, fight corruption and illicit finance, and innovate and compete through high labour and environmental standards.</p>



<p><strong>Seventh</strong>, the world has reached a critical point where it must act urgently and ambitiously to tackle the climate crisis, protect biodiversity, and sustain nature.&nbsp;Our countries will prioritise these issues in all our international action.<br><br><strong>Eighth</strong>, we recognise the catastrophic impact of health crises, and the global good in strengthening our collective defences against health threats. We commit to continuing to collaborate to strengthen health systems and advance our health protections, and to assist others to do the same.<br><br><strong>Joseph R. Biden, Jr.</strong><br><strong>Boris Johnson, M.P.</strong><br>June 10, 2021</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Brian Deese on Unemployment Insurance Claims</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/10/statement-from-brian-deese-on-unemployment-insurance-claims/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As President Biden travels overseas to engage with global counterparts, recent economic data reinforce that U.S. fiscal policy and vaccination progress are positioning the economy for growth and job creation. Today we learned that, since January, the four-week moving average for state unemployment insurance claims have fallen by more than 50% &#8212; from more than&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As President Biden travels overseas to engage with global counterparts, recent economic data reinforce that U.S. fiscal policy and vaccination progress are positioning the economy for growth and job creation. Today we learned that, since January, the four-week moving average for state unemployment insurance claims have fallen by more than 50% &#8212; from more than 834,000 to 402,500. That’s the lowest level since the pandemic began. &nbsp;This news comes as independent analysts project that economic growth in the United States will outpace growth for our peer nations and reach the fastest pace in nearly four decades.&nbsp; Earlier this week, the World Bank increased their projection for U.S. economic growth this year by 3.3% to 6.8%. The 3.3% upward revision in the United States compares to a 2.1% revision in other advanced economies. &nbsp;Another analysis last week found that the United States is the only major industrialized nation to have its growth projection through 2025 revised upward. These data underscore the leading role the U.S. is playing in building towards a global recovery.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement on the Visit to the United Kingdom of the Honorable Joseph R. Biden, Jr., President of the United States of America at the Invitation of the Rt. Hon. Boris Johnson, M.P., the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/10/joint-statement-on-the-visit-to-the-united-kingdom-of-the-honorable-joseph-r-biden-jr-president-of-the-united-states-of-america-at-the-invitation-of-the-rt-hon-boris-johnson-m-p-the-prime-min/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 17:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20337</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden visited the U.K. at the invitation of the Prime Minister and in advance of the G7 Summit. The President and the Prime Minister set out a global vision in a new Atlantic Charter to deepen cooperation in democracy and human rights, defence and security, science and innovation, and economic prosperity, with renewed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden visited the U.K. at the invitation of the Prime Minister and in advance of the G7 Summit. The President and the Prime Minister set out a global vision in a new Atlantic Charter to deepen cooperation in democracy and human rights, defence and security, science and innovation, and economic prosperity, with renewed joint efforts to tackle the challenges posed by climate change, biodiversity loss, and emerging health threats.</p>



<p><strong>DEMOCRACY, HUMAN RIGHTS, &amp; MULTILATERALISM</strong></p>



<ol><li>Building on the U.K. G7 Presidency’s focus on open societies, and looking ahead to the U.S.-hosted Summit for Democracy, the U.S. and U.K. will continue to make practical efforts to support open societies and democracy across the globe.&nbsp;We will do this by defending media freedom, advancing a free and open internet, combatting corruption, tackling disinformation, protecting civic space, advancing women’s political empowerment, protecting freedom of religion or belief, and promoting human rights of all people.&nbsp; The United Nations remains the cornerstone of the international system, and its foundational principles reflect our shared values.&nbsp; In the 75 years since the UN’s creation, international security has been increasingly challenged by threats that do not recognise borders: climate change, pandemics, famine, migration, organised crime, and terrorism. The U.K. and U.S. will work with the UN and our international partners to continue to adapt and reform the international system to tackle these evolving threats and to build back better for the 21st century, while remaining true to the universal founding principles of the UN and the core values of its Charter. We commit to promoting peaceful and inclusive societies to reduce injustice, inequality, poverty, and hunger worldwide. We carry responsibility for creating sustainable and viable conditions to global economic challenges through our commitment to the G7 Agenda and 2030 Agenda on Sustainable Development, and we will work together to address pre-existing inequities and inequalities being exacerbated by COVID-19, ensuring they no longer go unaddressed.&nbsp;The U.S. and U.K. are committed to promoting the advancement of gender&nbsp;equity and&nbsp;equality as a key pillar of foreign policy and national security, including through educating girls, empowering women socially, economically, and politically, and ending violence against women and girls.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<p><strong>DEFENCE &amp; SECURITY</strong></p>



<ol start="2"><li>We commit&nbsp;to enhance further the world’s strongest bilateral defence, security, and intelligence partnership to overcome the evolving threats of the twenty-first century. This includes&nbsp;threats and challenges associated with: cyberspace, foreign interference, harmful influence campaigns, illicit finance, violent conflict and extremism, and terrorism in all its forms. To this end, we will continue our partnership on those challenges, including working together closely on cyber security, countering&nbsp;illicit finance, and tackling all forms of terrorism by working&nbsp;together&nbsp;to address it online&nbsp;and enhance international collaboration on thwarting violent extremism that is racially, ethnically or ideologically motivated, including a range of hateful and white supremacist ideologies.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Through strong and principled leadership we will work to shape and secure the international order of the future with NATO as the bedrock of our collective defence.&nbsp;We will work together to further strengthen and modernise NATO, and increase its common funding, so the Alliance can harness the full range of military and non-military capabilities to contest existing and new threats, including malicious cyber activity and attacks that test the resiliency of our societies.&nbsp;We intend to take operational measures to modernise and integrate our armed forces, and strengthen bilateral cooperation on next generation capabilities. Last month, the U.K.’s new aircraft carrier, HMS QUEEN ELIZABETH, sailed on her first operational mission with U.S. and U.K. F-35 aircraft on board – a demonstration of the unique interoperability of our Armed Forces.&nbsp;&nbsp;As we maintain close alignment on our nuclear deterrence and modernisation programs, we reaffirm our commitment to effective arms control and nuclear security, and to the goal of a world without nuclear weapons. We will draw on our extensive diplomatic, defence, security, civil and scientific cooperation to ensure Space is a safe and secure environment for all.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We look forward to bringing into force a robust bilateral data access agreement, to be based on a mutual recognition that both countries have an appropriately high level of data protection, that allows law enforcement investigations on both sides of the Atlantic to obtain the evidence needed to bring offenders to justice, whilst maintaining rigorous privacy standards. We will work together to maintain tightly-controlled lawful access to communications content that is vital to the investigation and prosecution of serious crimes including terrorism and child abuse.&nbsp;And we will work in partnership with technology companies to do this, protecting the safety of our citizens.</li></ol>



<p><strong>SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY</strong></p>



<ol start="5"><li>We will develop a new landmark bilateral technology partnership in 2021/22.&nbsp;It will enable a new era of strategic cooperation to guarantee: the safety and security of our citizens; that we continue to lead the world in R&amp;D; wealth creation and tackling inequality; the values of liberal democracies, open societies and open markets; and that all of these are codified in and threaded throughout the design and use of technology globally We will strengthen cooperation in areas such as: ensuring the diversity, resilience and security of our critical supply chains; enabling our industries and research institutions to develop and apply existing and emerging technologies such as AI, quantum, and battery technologies; and reducing barriers to the accessibility and flow of data to support economic growth, public safety and scientific &amp; technological progress.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We will continue to strengthen collaboration in science and technology.&nbsp;This will facilitate increased joint world-class research, as well as encourage the development of rules, norms and standards governing data sharing, technology, and the digital economy that reflect our values and principles.&nbsp;We will cooperate on the basis of openness, transparency, and reciprocity, and in hope of ensuring that our collaborative research benefits our people.&nbsp;We will combine our expertise to tackle global challenges, such as cancer, antimicrobial resistance, climate change, and pandemic preparedness. We will do this through closer coordination between the Prime Minister’s Council for Science and Technology and the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology, and through closer collaboration between U.S. and U.K. senior science and technology advisers.</li></ol>



<p><strong>TRADE &amp; PROSPERITY</strong></p>



<ol start="7"><li>We commit to deepening and strengthening our vital economic and trading partnership. We commit to the rapid settlement of the Large Civil Aircraft dispute.&nbsp; Both countries recognise that trade, when done right, can support our mutual interest in sustainable and green growth, good jobs for our workers, new opportunities for our innovators and businesses, and high labour and environmental standards.&nbsp; We will therefore work closely to identify and pursue opportunities to deepen our already extensive trade relationship.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We reaffirm our commitment to spur economic regeneration and build back better in a way that benefits all communities that have experienced the pain of economic change and advances equality for all &#8211; not just in cities, but also small towns and post-industrial areas.&nbsp; Mindful of the distributional consequences of economic policy and that current economic models do not serve all equally in society or adequately tackle issues such as the climate crisis, and recognising the need for equality of opportunity, we intend to launch a new joint initiative that brings together experts, practitioners and officials to advance a new “common sense” about how the economy works and the goals it should promote; the initiative will share best practice and review the evidence around public policies to tackle structural inequalities across the economy and deliver prosperity across society.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We are proud to welcome G7 leaders’ discussions around&nbsp;a values-driven, high-standard and&nbsp;transparent,&nbsp;infrastructure&nbsp;partnership that seeks to&nbsp;collectively mobilise private-sector capital through catalytic investments &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;in low- and middle-income countries from our development finance tools. We look forward to discussing the outline of this new partnership with our G7 partners in Carbis Bay.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We also welcome the efforts underway through the G20/OECD Inclusive Framework to address the tax challenges arising from globalisation and the digitalisation of the economy and to adopt a global minimum tax. We commit to reaching an equitable solution on the allocation of taxing rights, with market countries awarded taxing rights on at least 20% of profit exceeding a 10% margin for the largest and most profitable multinational enterprises. We will provide for appropriate coordination between the application of the new international tax rules and the removal of all Digital Services Taxes, and other relevant similar measures, on all companies. We also commit to a global minimum tax of at least 15% on a country by country basis. We agree on the importance of progressing agreement in parallel on both Pillars and look forward to reaching an agreement at the July meeting of G20 Finance Ministers and Central Bank Governors.</li></ol>



<p><strong>CLIMATE &amp; NATURE</strong></p>



<ol start="11"><li>Together we will work to: rally all countries to strengthen their climate ambitions; achieve the goals of the Paris Agreement; keep within reach the goal of limiting global average temperature rise to no more than 1.5 degrees above pre-industrial levels; and bend the curve of biodiversity loss by 2030.&nbsp; We will champion the best available science – particularly reports from the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change and the Intergovernmental Science-Policy Platform for Biodiversity and Ecosystem Services – and welcome global partnerships, including&nbsp; the COP26 Policy Dialogue on a Transition to Sustainable Agriculture and the Agriculture Innovation Mission for Climate to increase and accelerate research and development for innovation in agricultural food systems; and support a resilient transition to decarbonised economies with quality job opportunities; and make progress on climate action in a gender responsive manner.&nbsp; We underscore our commitment to achieving net zero emissions by 2050 at the latest, and call on all other countries to do likewise.&nbsp; We welcome the G7’s creation of an Industrial Decarbonisation Agenda (IDA), which will help drive innovation in, and lower costs of, the decarbonisation of heavy industrial sectors around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We are committed to achieving an ambitious outcome at COP26 and to the collective developed country goal of mobilising $100 billion annually through to 2025 from a wide variety of public and private sources in the context of meaningful mitigation actions and transparency on implementation.&nbsp; We are both increasing our climate finance from 2020, including for adaptation, and are continuing to pursue additional opportunities to increase climate finance mobilisation.&nbsp; We intend to provide support to countries to enable adaptation, and address the effects of climate impacts, including through finance for nature-based solutions, and by scaling up disaster risk-management, including through the Risk-Informed Early Action Partnership. We are committed to mainstreaming nature across all sectors and into economic decision-making.&nbsp;&nbsp; We also commit to working even more closely together on forests, including through the Forest Agriculture, and Commodity Trade (FACT) Dialogue, the ocean, and finance for nature to conserve, protect and restore natural ecosystems including by championing an ambitious post-2020 Global Biodiversity Framework.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Recognising the impact that energy has on our national security, economy, net-zero ambitions, and shared prosperity, we are launching a new ‘Strategic Energy Dialogue’, led by the U.K. Department for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy and the U.S. Department of Energy. This dialogue aims to deepen our cooperation in areas such as the development and deployment of innovative, clean energy technologies, industrial decarbonisation, nuclear energy, energy security and resilience, joint priorities in multilateral energy forums, and shared science, research, and innovation cooperation.</li></ol>



<p><strong>HEALTH</strong></p>



<ol start="14"><li>We are determined to work together to overcome the current pandemic, which has reversed progress on improving the human condition, and to be better prepared in the future.&nbsp; Reflecting our shared strength in science and technology, we commit to enhancing our cooperation on tackling variants of concern and emerging infectious disease threats with pandemic or epidemic potential. This will be underpinned by collaboration between the new U.K. Health Security Agency (U.K.HSA) Centre for Pandemic Preparedness and the new U.S. National Center for Epidemic Forecasting and Outbreak Analytics.&nbsp; Our collective strength in science will allow us to: scale up surveillance and genomic sequencing capacity, as well as variant assessment capabilities; adopt a One Health approach to account for animal health, and zoonotic and environmental risk; and support others without these capabilities.&nbsp; We welcome the plan to establish an integrated global surveillance system &#8211; the Global Pandemic Radar &#8211; and commit to working with the WHO and other partners to take this forward. Enhancing global surveillance is critical to achieving our collective ambition to deliver safe, effective and affordable vaccines, therapeutics and diagnostics within 100 days of a future pandemic threat being identified.&nbsp; We are committed to working together with fellow G7 chief scientists to drive progress toward the bold 100 day ambition and report back to G7 leaders on next steps later this year.&nbsp; We will strengthen collaboration on G7 action on clinical trials for vaccines and therapeutics, through more coordinated research agendas and better sharing of data and results.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We look forward to normalising two-way travel between our two countries.&nbsp; We will establish a joint U.K.-U.S. Experts’ Working Group, which will share expertise and provide recommendations to leaders on the return of safe and sustainable international travel, demonstrating the commitment of both countries to tackle COVID-19 together.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We will work together to help increase global vaccine supply through investments in manufacturing of safe and effective vaccines and the materials needed to produce them.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We will promote the timely availability of vaccines, key components and equipment by encouraging bilateral trade and investment and avoiding export restrictions or other supply chain disruption. We will work together to strengthen multilateral vaccine initiatives, in particular COVAX and its partner organisations CEPI, Gavi, UNICEF and WHO. We will support resource mobilisation for partner financing needs, and work with international financial institutions to build delivery capacity in-country and develop long term, sustainable financing models to increase pandemic preparedness and response and global health security. To this end, the U.K. and U.S. will work together with likeminded countries to explore options for a new sustainable, catalytic health security financing mechanism. We will bring together government and industry to encourage further investment to tackle COVID-19 and prepare for the next health security threat, including by strengthening preparedness and resilience, increasing R&amp;D spending, and tackling new variants. We will continue to help allies and partners accelerate implementation of, and compliance with, the International Health Regulations (IHR). To move towards this goal, we will both strive to promote and advance the Global Health Security Agenda and its bold 2024 target, including through capacity building to prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease threats.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The U.K. and U.S. recognise the central importance of the WHO in global health security. The U.K. and the U.S. will work together and with like-minded Member States to implement the WHO strengthening resolution adopted at the World Health Assembly in May 2021. We will also support a timely, transparent and evidence-based independent process for the next phase of the WHO-convened COVID-19 origins study, including in China, and for investigating outbreaks of unknown origin in the future. We will take account of the recommendations of the International Panel for Pandemic Preparedness and Response as we work together to learn the lessons from the pandemic and strengthen future preparedness.&nbsp; We commit to advancing critical areas in global health, including strengthening health systems and building regional and country capacity to better withstand future shocks; expanding the availability, accessibility, and quality of essential health services among the world’s most vulnerable, marginalized, and inadequately-served; and prioritizing maternal, neonatal and child health, nutrition, malaria, tuberculosis and HIV/AIDS.&nbsp; We will also establish an institution-to-institution partnership to strengthen our approach to reducing health inequalities.&nbsp;&nbsp; We will elevate our partnership on Sexual and Reproductive Health and Rights advancing our renewed commitment throughout the 76<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;United Nations General Assembly. .&nbsp; We call on regional, local and national actors to support these efforts.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>We will convene the first U.S.-U.K. Bilateral Cancer Summit and bring together researchers, patients, and other stakeholders to share ideas and identify opportunities for collaboration to accelerate advances in lifesaving approaches to cancer, which remains a leading cause of death worldwide.</li></ol>



<p><strong>COMMITMENT TO NORTHERN IRELAND</strong></p>



<ol start="19"><li>Northern Ireland has taken huge strides forward since its courageous leaders put reconciliation and progress before violence and division 23 years ago. We are proud of the achievements of the Belfast/Good Friday Agreement, and we remain fully committed to its three strand approach, that: established the democratic institutions in Northern Ireland; provided for consultation, co-operation and action across the island of Ireland; and created structures for British-Irish engagement.&nbsp;It took a deep partnership between the U.K., Ireland, and the U.S. to support the people of Northern Ireland in bringing the Troubles to an end, and it will take a continued and ongoing partnership to advance and safeguard Northern Ireland’s stability and prosperity into the future.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Today, the U.K. and U.S. reaffirm their commitment to working closely with all parties to the Agreement to protect its delicate balance and realise its vision for reconciliation, consent, equality, respect for rights, and parity of esteem. Unlocking Northern Ireland’s tremendous potential is a vital part of safeguarding the stability created by the Agreement, and the U.K. and the U.S. will continue working together towards that shared goal.</li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials Previewing the President&#8217;s Bilateral Meeting with the Right Honorable Boris Johnson, Prime Minister of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/10/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-previewing-the-presidents-bilateral-meeting-with-the-right-honorable-boris-johnson-prime-minister-of-the-united-kingdom-of-great-britain-and/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:32 P.M. BST MODERATOR: So, in the interest of time, we&#8217;re going to now move on to the next section of this call.  So I am going to pass it back to [senior administration official] to preview the President&#8217;s bilateral meeting with Prime Minister Boris Johnson and the review of the Atlantic Charter. SENIOR ADMINISTRATION&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:32 P.M. BST</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR: So, in the interest of time, we&#8217;re going to now move on to the next section of this call. <br><br>So I am going to pass it back to [senior administration official] to preview the President&#8217;s bilateral meeting with Prime Minister Boris Johnson and the review of the Atlantic Charter.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Can you hear me?<br><br>MODERATOR:  Yes, go ahead. <br><br>We can&#8217;t hear you if you&#8217;re saying anything.  Are you there?  Apologies, everybody, while we figure out these technical difficulties.  One moment, please. <br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sorry, guys.  Sorry, sorry.  I&#8217;m here.  I apologize.  I was &#8212; somehow my phone just cut out for a minute, and I was shouting into the void. <br><br>Anyway, on the UK bilateral today, as you all know, the President is meeting with Prime Minister Boris Johnson this afternoon.  And we think it makes all the sense in the world for the President&#8217;s first trip overseas to be to the United Kingdom and for his first foreign leader meeting abroad to be with Prime Minister Johnson because the U.S. and the UK share a Special Relationship that is the foundational aspect of U.S. foreign policy. <br><br>The historic alliance between our two countries is founded on shared values and common beliefs and has worked for decades to ensure that the security and prosperity that we seek to deliver not just for the U.S. and UK, but for the entire world.  And it has become a truly global relationship.<br><br>So, today, the Prime Minister and the President will talk about every aspect of that relationship.  There&#8217;s the security dimension, with an unparalleled defense and security alliance promoting stability worldwide.  There&#8217;s an economic dimension &#8212; the robust economic partnership between our countries sees the UK as our largest investment partner and the fourth-largest trading partner for the United States.<br><br>And, of course, the relationship is also about democratic values.  Together, we &#8212; (audio drop).<br><br>MODERATOR:  Apologies.  I think we lost [senior administration official] for a second.  Give us one moment.<br><br> Thanks for your patience, everyone, as we&#8217;re waiting to get reconnected with [senior administration official].  It should be momentarily.<br><br> I think we have [senior administration official] back on the line now.  If you want to hit &#8220;*6&#8221; and unmute yourself, you can dive right back in.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Can you guys hear me?<br><br>MODERATOR:  Yes, go ahead.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  I&#8217;m so sorry, guys.  The digital infrastructure here is not agreeing with me. <br><br>I was talking about democratic values.  So, let me just shift to the program.  In terms of the program &#8212; you know, start with a greeting and an official photo.  The two leaders will then review the original Atlantic Charter, which was signed between President Roosevelt and Prime Minister Churchill in 1941 &#8212; so, 80 years ago this year.<br><br>And then, after that, they will have the formal bilateral meeting.  The key priorities that they&#8217;ll focus on in that meeting are, you know, really, the pressing set of global challenges facing our two countries and the whole world: COVID-19, climate change, counterterrorism and the current drawdown in the Afghanistan, the evolving challenges in the Indo-Pacific and the Middle East, the common threats we face from Russia, and so on.<br><br>The two presidents &#8212; the two leaders will also sign a new Atlantic Charter.  The notion is that it&#8217;s been 80 years since the last one; it&#8217;s about time that it gets refreshed.  And the original really outlined what the post-World War world order could and should look like.<br><br>This new charter will make clear what the coming decades of the 21st century can and should look like from the perspective of common values and common aspirations for people everywhere.<br><br>We will also be putting out a joint statement today with some new initiatives that we&#8217;ll commit to work together on in the areas of science, technology, energy, and health.  And that will include the launch of the U.S.-UK Energy Dialogue, led by the Department of Energy; a commitment to a new U.S.-UK science and technology agreement; a launch of an expert working group on opening up travel between the U.S. and UK; and a commitment to hold a U.S.-UK Cancer Summit.<br><br>So, you know, we will be releasing this renewed Atlantic Charter and then releasing the joint statement that includes these core initiatives, in addition to the time the two leaders will spend on a truly robust agenda of current events and long-term trends on all the significant issues that our two countries face.<br><br>So, with apologies for the technical difficulties, I&#8217;m going to stop there.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Thank you so much.  If anybody has any questions about this preview of the bilateral meeting, please use the “raise hand” function on Zoom interface.<br><br>All right.  We will go to David Sanger first.  David, please unmute yourself.<br><br>Q    There we go.  Can you hear me now?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINSTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yes, go ahead.<br><br>Q    Great.  [Senior administration official], I wanted to ask you a little bit about the renewed Atlantic Charter.  So, the initial document, of course, was signed before the U.S. entered the war in 1941.  But over time, it sort of became a standard bearer of the Cold War.  Right?  It laid out the ideological differences between the West and Russia. <br><br>And since the President has been talking so much about democracy versus autocracy, both in a Russia context and a China context, is it your intent that this serves much the same purpose, or is it a different purpose, at a moment that, you know, many people are saying, rightly or wrongly, that we&#8217;re headed into a very different kind of, but equally ideological, struggle?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  It&#8217;s a great question, David.  I would say: The same purpose in one fundamental respect, and a different purpose in another fundamental respect.  It&#8217;s the same purpose insofar as it is a profound statement of purpose of democracy at a moment when, as the President has said, democracies are very much in competition for autocracies, in terms of showing the world who can deliver for people. <br><br>And this is a statement about why these two leaders, and democratic leaders everywhere, believe that the democratic model is the right and the just and the best model for governance in the world.  And in that sense, it echoes and reflects the fundamental animating purpose of the &#8217;41 document. <br><br>In terms of different purpose insofar as it is not meant to be Cold War &#8212; a new Cold War charter.  It is not meant to pre-stage a new Cold War.  It is meant to pre-stage a much more complex global landscape where the challenges are accelerating and multiplying in ways that involve both great power competitors and significant transnational threats, like climate change or COVID-19, that &#8212; and also, economic and technological challenges that exist at the heart of the interconnected global economy that we have &#8212; an interconnected global economy that didn&#8217;t exist in nearly the same way through the years of the Cold War, given that their economy was divided into these competing blocs. <br><br>So that&#8217;s part of the reason to do it (inaudible) is &#8212; a renewal aspect to the commitment to these democratic principles in the face of genuine challenges and authoritarian competition.  And there&#8217;s the need to refresh and update the statement of principles so they actually reflect the world we&#8217;re dealing with today and not simply harkening back to the world of the Cold War.  And that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s what this is all about.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Great.  Thank you so much.</p>



<p>12:54 P.M. BST</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I wanted to ask [senior administration official] about the Johnson meeting just because we only got one question on that.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about Northern Ireland specifically and what the President might tell the Prime Minister on that subject?&nbsp; And I would love for you to respond to this report in the Times of the UK, as well, if you could.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; All right, sure.&nbsp; On Northern Ireland, the President is going to say to the Prime Minister what he has said publicly for a long time now, including as recently as St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, which is that he believes that the Good Friday Agreement is the foundation for peace and reconciliation in Northern Ireland; that a lot of progress has been made over the 20-plus years since the Good Friday Agreement came into force and that that progress must be protected; and that the outcome of the current discussions between the UK and the EU should ensure the continued vitality of the Good Friday Agreement.</p>



<p>You know, the United States is not in those negotiations and not seeking to be in those negotiations.&nbsp; And we are instead a strong and vigorous supporter of practical, creative, flexible, results-oriented negotiations that, at the end of the day, produce a result that protects all of the gains that the people of Northern Ireland &#8212; that all communities in Northern Ireland have made.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to say.</p>



<p>It will not be confrontational or adversarial or &#8212; you know, he didn&#8217;t come here to give a lecture.&nbsp; He came merely to communicate what he believes very, very deeply about peace in Northern Ireland, about the priority the United States places on that, about the priority Joe Biden places on that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the spirit with which he&#8217;ll approach the conversation.</p>



<p>12:55 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the President&#8217;s Historic COVID-19 Vaccine Announcement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/10/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-presidents-historic-covid-19-vaccine-announcement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:10 P.M. BST MODERATOR:  Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing.  In today&#8217;s background briefing, we will cover the United States&#8217; historic vaccine donation that President Biden will announce today.  We will cover a preview of the President&#8217;s bilateral meeting with Prime Minister Boris Johnson.  And last&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:10 P.M. BST<br><br>MODERATOR:  Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing.  In today&#8217;s background briefing, we will cover the United States&#8217; historic vaccine donation that President Biden will announce today.  We will cover a preview of the President&#8217;s bilateral meeting with Prime Minister Boris Johnson.  And last but not least, we&#8217;ll also cover a preview of the G7 Summit and economic deliverables coming out of the G7.<br><br>This call will be on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;  Additionally, (inaudible) invitation, various sections of these calls are under different embargo times, and we will make those sections very clear.<br><br>The portion of the call covering COVID-19 and the vaccine announcement, as well as the preview of the UK bilat, will be embargoed until this call concludes.<br><br>The G7 preview and the section on economic deliverables from the G7 will be embargoed until Friday, June 11th, 7:00 a.m. British Summer Time.<br><br>We&#8217;ll have time for a brief Q&amp;A at the conclusion of each section.<br><br>Not for reporting or attribution, but just for your knowledge, on today&#8217;s call, we have joining us [senior administration officials].<br><br>Before we get started, I wanted to share a quick update from the First Lady&#8217;s office for you all.  In addition to the G7 program of events and meetings, the First Lady will have an independent schedule. <br><br>Today, she will meet separately with Mrs. Carrie Johnson.  Friday, she will participate in the G7 Summit welcoming events; an additional scheduling update is expected for this day.  On Saturday, she will participate in a program for spouses of G7 leaders and will meet with members of Bude Surf Veterans, a local volunteer group that assists UK military veterans with physical or mental health injuries through surfing.  And on Sunday, before she departs, she will meet with UK veterans who participated in Walk of America.<br><br>The First Lady&#8217;s Communications Director, Elizabeth Alexander, and her Press Secretary, Michael LaRosa, are traveling throughout this trip.  Feel free to reach out to them with any questions.<br><br>With that, we’ll get started on the COVID-19 section, and I will pass it over to [senior administration official] to kick us off.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  All right, well, good morning, everyone, or good afternoon.  And also, thanks for joining us.<br><br>Today, I want to discuss the historic announcement the President will make in his remarks later today regarding our efforts to help vaccinate the world against COVID-19.<br><br>First, let’s talk about why the U.S. is so well-positioned to lead the global COVID-19 response efforts.  And that, of course, is the success of the President’s whole-of-government, wartime effort to respond to the pandemic at home.<br><br>In just over four months, we&#8217;ve vaccinated 64 percent of adult Americans with at least one shot, and, importantly, fully vaccinated 53 percent of adult Americans.  Already, 13 states have 70 percent of adults with at least one shot.<br><br>As a result, in communities and states across the United States, the pandemic is in retreat.  In fact, since President Biden took office, cases are down over 90 percent and deaths are down over 85 percent.<br><br>So, our successful vaccination program isn’t just saving tens of thousands of lives, it’s helping our economy rebound strongly and it’s letting tens of millions of Americans get back to living their lives.<br><br>As the days get brighter and brighter at home, we&#8217;re increasingly focused on driving progress to help end the pandemic around the globe.<br><br>First, it’s the right thing to do.  The U.S. has tragically lost more people to COVID-19 than any other country in the world: almost 600,000 deaths.  Americans have experienced the tragic human cost of this virus, and we want to do everything we can to prevent more tragic loss of life around the globe.<br><br>Second, it&#8217;s in our own national interest to end this pandemic everywhere.  COVID-19 knows no borders.  And as long as this virus has a hold somewhere in the world, Americans are at risk.<br><br>To be clear, as we have learned in the U.S., COVID-19 threatens more than our health; it also threatens economic opportunity and growth.  That’s why the President has committed that the U.S. will be the arsenal of vaccines in our global fight against COVID-19.<br><br>Over the past four and a half months or so, as we have mobilized a whole-of-government effort to vaccinate America, including getting at least one shot to over 170 million Americans and securing enough vaccine supply for all Americans, we have also been mobilizing an effort to help vaccinate the world.<br><br>Under President Biden’s leadership, the U.S. has already contributed more to COVAX than any other country.  We&#8217;ve worked with Japan, India, and Australia to support manufacturing efforts, and shared 4 million AstraZeneca doses with Canada and Mexico.<br><br>Recently, the President also committed to sharing 80 million doses with the world.  Eighty million doses represents 13 percent of the total vaccines produced in the U.S. by the end of this month.  We are working quickly and expeditiously to facilitate safe and secure delivery of these doses, and the initial doses started shipping last week.<br><br>Today, we are taking another major step forward &#8212; a step that will supercharge the global fight against this pandemic and save millions of lives around the world.<br><br>This evening, in the UK, the President will announce that the United States will purchase 500 million doses of Pfizer vaccine and donate them to 100 of the <s>lowest</s> [low]-income countries in the world.<br><br>To repeat, the U.S. is taking this historic step of purchasing half a billion doses of Pfizer vaccine and donating them to countries that need them the most, including the 92 Advance Market Commitment countries &#8212; these are the <s>lowest</s> [low]-income countries and economies in the world &#8212; and <s>all</s> members of the African Union member states.<br><br>This will be, clearly, the largest purchase and donation of COVID-19 vaccines by a single country by far, and it&#8217;s an unprecedented step to respond to an unprecedented pandemic.<br><br>Importantly, this is a vaccine that is proven to be extremely effective against COVID-19 and every known variant of this virus.  And these doses will jumpstart vaccination efforts in some of the most hard-hit and underserved populations in the world, bringing hope to every corner of the world and saving millions of lives.<br><br>[Senior administration official] will explain more about how we will share these doses, but I want to make a few points on timeline.  We expect to start shipping these Pfizer doses in August, with 200 million doses to be delivered this year, and the remaining 300 million to be delivered across the first half of 2022.<br><br>And as with all the vaccines we&#8217;ve committed to sharing, these vaccines will be delivered to countries as quickly and expeditiously as possible as soon as they become available.<br><br>Importantly, these Pfizer vaccines are the product of American ingenuity and innovation.  They will be produced through the power of American manufacturing in places like Michigan, Kansas, Missouri, Connecticut, and Massachusetts &#8212; employing thousands of workers.  American workers who produced vaccines to save American lives are going to produce those same vaccines to save the lives of hundreds of millions of people across the world.<br><br>This is a testament to the American people and American leadership.  We&#8217;re a nation full of people who step up and do their part.  That&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve been doing at home and will continue to do so, vaccinating more and more Americans in the weeks and months to come. <br><br>MODERATOR:  Thank you so much.  With that, I&#8217;m going to pass it over to [senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thanks, everybody.  Just following on [senior administration official]&#8217;s laydown, I want to make clear that not only is the United States taking this huge step to provide 500 million doses of the Pfizer vaccine to low-income countries around the world.  We&#8217;re also using this announcement today to leverage and mobilize larger commitments from the world&#8217;s democracies, from the G7 and partner countries. <br><br>And there will be a G7 COVID-related multilateral announcement coming later on vaccines, but on more than just vaccines &#8212; on a comprehensive roadmap to end the pandemic, with contributions from G7 members to every element of that roadmap. <br><br>So stay tuned for that, because over the course of this weekend at the G7 Summit, American leadership and what [senior administration official] described as &#8220;supercharging the effort&#8221; to provide vaccines around the world will also help catalyze, mobilize, and translate into a collective effort by the world&#8217;s democracies to beat COVID-19 once and for all.<br><br>In terms of this announcement that we&#8217;ve laid out today: It is a monumental commitment by the American people to help people around the world.  And we want to really underscore that this is fundamentally about the singular overarching objective of saving lives, improving livelihoods, and beating a pandemic that has ravaged the world and has spared no quarter from countries on every continent. <br><br>And in this regard, the United States is not seeking favors in exchange for these doses.  We&#8217;re not making demands in order for countries to get these doses.  We are not imposing conditions &#8212; political or economic, or otherwise &#8212; on countries receiving these doses.  We are going to be guided by the science and the public health experts in allocating them to the places where they can make the most difference, and in allocating them in a broad-based way so that countries in Latin America and the Caribbean, in Africa, in Asia, and in parts of Oceania can benefit from these Pfizer doses. <br><br>The other thing to say is that we know that low-income countries would not have an ability to compete with big economies on the vaccine marketplace and that these low-income countries have not had access to groundbreaking vaccines like this mRNA vaccine.  And so part of what we&#8217;re trying to do here is make sure that we are taking &#8212; on the basis of American generosity and American innovation and know-how &#8212; what we have available and getting to those countries who otherwise could not secure it. <br><br>And in addition to that, as [senior administration official] pointed out, I think it bears underscoring: Many of these low-income countries to whom we will be providing these doses &#8212; donating these doses &#8212; are subject to variants of the disease that have made other vaccines somewhat less effective. <br><br>And what has made us focus on the Pfizer vaccine for this significant announcement is that, as [senior administration official] said, it has proven highly effective against every known variant of COVID-19. <br><br>Just two other points before I turn it over for questions.  The first is that we have to connect the doses to shots in arms, just as we have done domestically.  And so the United States has, through the American Rescue Plan, allocated a significant amount of money for every step along the chain of vaccination and of building the resilience of public health systems.  And this monumental commitment of half a billion Pfizer doses will fit into that chain. <br><br>And then, secondly, I just want to reinforce what [senior administration official] said: What this really comes down to at the end of the day is, this is the right thing to do, it&#8217;s the smart thing to do, and it is tangible proof that it is going to be the world&#8217;s democracies who ultimately deliver when it comes to beating the COVID-19 pandemic. <br><br>So let me stop there and turn it back over to the moderator.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Thanks so much.  So, before we move on to some other sections, we have time for some brief Q&amp;A on the vaccines announcement.  So if you have a question, please use the &#8220;raise hand&#8221; function on the Zoom app, and we&#8217;ll call on you before we move on to other sections. <br><br>All right, first, we&#8217;ll go to Michael Shear from the New York Times.<br><br>Q    Hey, guys, thanks for calling on me.  I have two questions.  One is, is there an estimate of how much this is costing the United States to buy the 500 million doses, and the distribution costs, et cetera, that will go along with that?<br><br>And, second, to [senior administration official]&#8217;s point about the doses fitting into a broader process of actually getting them into the arms &#8212; I mean, the United States discovered that doses alone weren&#8217;t enough.  And so, I wonder, is there &#8212; as the United States chooses where to distribute &#8212; which countries to distribute them to, is there going to be some sort of conditionality on whether or not a country actually has a plan or actually has an infrastructure that can distribute them in a way that is effective?  Or is the United States &#8212; is part of the United States&#8217; effort going to be to try to help build that structure up so that the doses don&#8217;t, you know, languish without some sort of distribution ability to kind of get them into people&#8217;s arms?  So, thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Okay.  This is [senior administration official].  Can you hear me?<br><br>Q    Yes, I can. <br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sorry, I dropped off before.  I&#8217;ll (inaudible) your question and then I&#8217;ll hand it to [senior administration official]. <br><br>We are entering into the contracting process, so that will determine the final details of the agreement.  We&#8217;ve agreed on a not-for-profit price, and we&#8217;ll assure &#8212; ensure the contract &#8212; the contracting officers will ensure the contract reflects that. <br><br>The contract can be finalized over the coming weeks, and we&#8217;ll make the terms of the contract public.  You know, the U.S. plans to work with COVAX to utilize the second $2 billion in funding that we committed to the fight against the global pandemic.  And we expect, on top of that &#8212; this announcement of 500 million doses will cost about 1.5 billion dollars more, and that will be paid for by the already-appropriated funds from the American Rescue Plan. <br><br>So, back over to [senior administration official] for your question about shots in arms. <br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah, as I mentioned at the outset, what you will see coming out of the G7 is a comprehensive roadmap to end the pandemic that focuses not just on securing the necessary supply of vaccines &#8212; supply and production of vaccines, but also on getting those vaccines into arms. <br><br>And the U.S. has already allocated a substantial sum of money through the American Rescue Plan for this purpose.  We have CDC, USAID, and contributions through COVAX &#8212; some of our initial contributions through COVAX &#8212; are going towards this purpose. <br><br>And we will be working both through our own public health and international assistance agencies and through multilateral organizations like UNICEF, and regional organizations like the Pan American Health Organization, to ensure that as we&#8217;re allocating these doses to low-income countries, they also have the capacity to be able to deliver them and get them into arms. <br><br>I would not characterize this as a kind of conditionality where we go to a country and say, “You only get doses if you can do X, Y, and Z” and then, sort of, leave them to it.  I would describe it more as a partnership where, as we allocate these doses across the 500 &#8212; these 500 million doses across the 100 low-income countries, we will work out with each of them a game plan to ensure that those countries that don&#8217;t yet have the capacity to get them from the plane and into the arms of their citizens, that they get the necessary technical assistance, capacity, personnel, cold chain, et cetera, to be able to do this.<br><br>We feel that there is a lot of experience from previous vaccination campaigns that will allow us to surge capacity to hard-hit areas quite quickly, to build up the ability of health systems to do this, and to build on what is already preexisting in certain parts of the world is a fairly strong and robust health system infrastructure for vaccination. <br><br>So we are very mindful of the fact that this has to be part of a multifaceted effort to end the pandemic.  We have resources for that purpose, we have partners for that purpose, and we will be working with the other G7 countries as well to ensure that this is an integrated strategy.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Thanks.  Next, we’ll go to Josh Wingrove from Bloomberg.<br><br>Q    Thank you for doing this.   You cut out when you were talking about the cost of this, and so I just wanted to be clear: Did you say one and a half or five and a half billion (inaudible)?  Can you recap your answer, please, on the cost of these doses, and perhaps also say when you expect the contract will be finalized?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sure.  So, we are (inaudible) &#8212; (technical difficulties).<br><br>This is [senior administration official].  I heard Josh for the first part and not the second part.  Can you guys hear me okay?<br><br>MODERATOR:  Yes, we can hear you now.  You were cutting out a little bit, but now this is a lot crisper.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Okay.  So, let me answer the first part.  I don&#8217;t know &#8212; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; I didn&#8217;t hear the second.  But, you know, we&#8217;re entering into the contracting process, so the contracting officers will determine the final details of the agreement.  You know, the agreement is for a purchase at the not-for-profit price, and we&#8217;ll ensure the contract will reflect that. <br><br>The contract will be finalized over the coming weeks.  Delivery starts in August, of doses, and we’ll make the terms of the contract public at the right point.<br><br>The U.S. plans to work with COVAX to utilize the second $2 billion in funding of the $4 billion that we committed to the fight against the pandemic.  In addition to that, we expect the announcement to cost about $1.5 billion more, so a total of $3.5 [billion], Josh.  And that will be paid for by already-appropriated funds from the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>The one thing that I got cut off on that I know a lot of people have questions on &#8212; let me spend 30 seconds on &#8212; is that today&#8217;s announcement of the 500 million doses to the countries most in need, plus the 80 million doses the President announced in May &#8212; total 580.  So there are &#8212; those are separate announcements.  So the total is 580 million doses to donate to other countries. <br><br>And then, the U.S. will continue to share the additional doses across the summer months, in addition to that 580 million figure.  And we will continue to take additional actions to lead the world&#8217;s efforts to end this global pandemic. <br><br>So, a major milestone today, but I wanted to put it in the context of the work that&#8217;s been done already to share doses and that there&#8217;s more to come.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Thank you so much.</p>



<p>12:32 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom Before Bilateral Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/10/remarks-by-president-biden-and-prime-minister-boris-johnson-of-the-united-kingdom-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 16:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20251</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carbis Bay HotelCornwall, United Kingdom 3:23 P.M. BST PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&#160; Well, it is a &#8212; what a great, great pleasure, Mr. President, to welcome you to Cornwall. PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; It is a great pleasure to be here. PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&#160; Fantastic to see you.&#160; Fantastic to see you here on what &#8212; what I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Carbis Bay Hotel<br>Cornwall, United Kingdom</p>



<p>3:23 P.M. BST<br><br>PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&nbsp; Well, it is a &#8212; what a great, great pleasure, Mr. President, to welcome you to Cornwall.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; It is a great pleasure to be here.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&nbsp; Fantastic to see you.&nbsp; Fantastic to see you here on what &#8212; what I think is your &#8212; is your first big overseas trip since you&#8217;ve been &#8212;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; It is.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&nbsp; &#8212; since you&#8217;ve been President.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; It is.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve visited your great country many times, but this is the first time as President of the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&nbsp; Well, everybody is &#8212;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great honor.&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&nbsp; Everybody is absolutely thrilled to see you.&nbsp; And &#8212;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; And I&#8217;m thrilled to be here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m thrilled to meet your wife.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&nbsp; Yes, well &#8212; and they&#8217;ve gone off to do something else.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; They did.&nbsp; I told the Prime Minister we have something in common: We both married way above our station.&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&nbsp; And I’m &#8212; and I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to dissent from that one.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to disagree with the President on that or indeed on anything else, I think, either, likely.&nbsp;<br><br>Are we &#8212; are we going to &#8212; are we going to have like &#8212; we could just continue &#8212;<br><br>AIDE:&nbsp; Okay, thank you, press.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&nbsp; I was going to say, we generally agree, Joe.&nbsp; You could probably (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)<br><br>PRIME MINISTER JOHNSON:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp;<br><br>3:25 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President Biden Announces Historic Vaccine Donation: Half a Billion Pfizer Vaccines to the World’s Lowest-Income Nations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/10/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-historic-vaccine-donation-half-a-billion-pfizer-vaccines-to-the-worlds-lowest-income-nations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20159</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[500 million life-saving vaccines to be delivered by June of next year, including 200 million to be delivered by the end of 2021 Donation will serve as the foundation for a coordinated effort by the world’s democracies to vaccinate people around the world   Today, President Biden will announce that the United States will purchase&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>500 million life-saving vaccines to be delivered by June of next year, including 200 million to be delivered by the end of 2021<br><br>Donation will serve as the foundation for a coordinated effort by the world’s democracies to vaccinate people around the world  </em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Today, President Biden will announce that the United States will purchase and donate half a billion Pfizer vaccines to 92 low- and lower middle-income countries and the African Union, an historic action that will help supercharge the global fight against the pandemic. This is the largest-ever purchase and donation of vaccines by a single country and a commitment by the American people to help protect people around the world from COVID-19. President Biden will also call on the world’s democracies to do their parts in contributing to the global supply of safe and effective vaccines. The goal of today’s donation is to save lives and end the pandemic and will provide the foundation for additional actions to be announced in the coming days.</p>



<p>Thanks to the success of our vaccination program, the United States is beating COVID-19 here at home. 64% of adult Americans have received at least one shot in just four and a half months, daily death rates are lower than at any point in the pandemic, and our economy is rebounding. Now, the United States is using the power of our democracy, the ingenuity of American scientists, and the strength of American manufacturing to beat the pandemic globally by helping to vaccinate the world.</p>



<p>Today’s historic announcement comes on the heels of President Biden’s donation of at least 80 million vaccines from the United States’ supply by the end of June. Additionally, the United States has contributed two billion dollars to COVAX, more than any other nation—and is supporting local production capacity abroad for safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines, including through the Quad initiative.</p>



<p>President Biden has been clear that borders cannot keep this pandemic at bay and has vowed that our nation will be the arsenal of vaccines. The historic step the President will announce today therefore protects the health of the American people and the people throughout the world who will benefit from these life-saving vaccines.</p>



<p>Specifically, the actions the President will announce today will:</p>



<p><strong><u>PROVIDE A HALF BILLION PFIZER VACCINES TO LOW-INCOME NATIONS AROUND THE WORLD:</u></strong> Today, President Biden will announce that the U.S. government will purchase half a billion doses of Pfizer–BioNTech COVID-19 vaccines and donate to 92 low- and lower middle-income countries and economies as defined by <a href="https://www.gavi.org/news/media-room/92-low-middle-income-economies-eligible-access-covid-19-vaccines-gavi-covax-amc">Gavi’s COVAX Advance Market Commitment (AMC)</a> and the African Union. The vaccines will start shipping in August 2021.&nbsp; 200 million doses will be delivered by the end of this year and the remaining 300 million will be delivered in the first half of 2022. The U.S. will allocate these doses to low and lower-middle income nations around the world, working through COVAX to deliver them.</p>



<p><strong><u>GIVE LOWER INCOME NATIONS MORE ACCESS TO HIGHLY EFFECTIVE mRNA VACCINES:</u></strong> Today’s announcement will provide mRNA vaccines that have proven to be highly effective against COVID-19, including against all known variants. Tens of millions of Americans have benefited from these safe and effective vaccines and this historic donation will bring the life-saving benefits these vaccines provide to some of the most vulnerable populations around the world.</p>



<p><strong><u>HARNESS THE POWER OF AMERICAN MANUFACTURING TO HELP SAVE LIVES AROUND THE WORLD.</u></strong> Pfizer plans to produce these half a billion doses in the U.S. at their facilities in Kalamazoo, Michigan, which employs more than 3,000 American workers; McPherson, Kansas, which employs almost 2,000 workers; Chesterfield, Missouri, and Andover, Massachusetts, which employ 700 and 1,800 workers. The American workers who produced vaccines to save American lives will now produce those same vaccines to save the lives of hundreds of millions of people around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden to U.S. Air Force Personnel and Families Stationed at Royal Air Force Mildenhall</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/09/remarks-by-president-biden-to-u-s-air-force-personnel-and-families-stationed-at-royal-air-force-mildenhall/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 23:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Royal Air Force MildenhallMildenhall, United Kingdom 8:45 P.M. BST THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, Mildenhall! Colonel, thank you for that introduction and your service leading this team in such a difficult time.  Because we know that it’s the whole family who serves; I also want to Melissa.   I know &#8212; I know your next assignment at U.S.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Royal Air Force Mildenhall<br>Mildenhall, United Kingdom</p>



<p><br>8:45 P.M. BST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hello, Mildenhall!<br><br>Colonel, thank you for that introduction and your service leading this team in such a difficult time.  Because we know that it’s the whole family who serves; I also want to Melissa.   I know &#8212; I know your next assignment at U.S. Transportation Command starts soon.  So congratulations, and thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>And, Sydney, you&#8217;re 14 years old.  When I was 14 &#8212; please, at ease.  I keep forgetting I&#8217;m President.  (Laughter.)  When I was 14 years old, I would have been &#8212; I mean this sincerely &#8212; scared to death to stand up in front of a microphone, in a large crowd or small crowd.  See, when I was a child, I used to stutter badly &#8212; for real.  I had great difficulty speaking in front of other people.  And &#8212; so I expect that when you&#8217;re President, you’ll remember me.  (Laughter.)  You&#8217;ll remember me.   You’re, really, quite a polished young woman.  Thank you.<br><br>And, you know, it&#8217;s got to be hard to have your dad deployed to Afghanistan.  And I also know how proud you are of him and your mom, Chief Master Sergeant, for being part of the leadership team here.<br><br>Our son Beau served as a U.S. attorney for a while in &#8212; in Kosovo for a while.  Matter of fact, they erected a war monument to him.  And &#8212; and then he went on and he joined the National Guard.  Gave up his job as attorney general of the State of Delaware so he can go with his unit to Iraq for a year.  And when he got promoted to Major, I said, “Beau, you&#8217;re now a field-grade officer.”  I was in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan about 28 times.  And I said, “You&#8217;re now a field-grade officer.”  He said, “Dad, I have no illusions.  I know who runs the military: chief master sergeants.”  (Laughs.)  (Applause.)  So, I just want you to know we know.  Okay? <br><br>Thank you for your incredible dedication and service.  And, you know, I want to thank you all &#8212; all of you &#8212; all your families &#8212; for the sacrifices they&#8217;ve made.  And congratulations to having just a wonderful child.<br><br>There’s an awful lot of history at this base, a proud history for the British people &#8212; the bravery and heroism of the Royal Air Force pilots fighting to defend their nation.<br><br>I’m sure everyone here knows the history, but just six hours after Britain and France declared war on Germany in 1939, three Wellington bombers took off from Mildenhall and bombed Nazi battleships. <br><br>And over the course of World War Two, out of this base, RAF bombers dropped nearly 28,000 tons of bombs on Nazi Germany, flying more than 8,000 sorties.  This base has been a significant source of British air power &#8212; a proud, proud history of a proud nation. <br><br>But I also know there’s also an awful lot of American Air Force pride in this room tonight.  World War Two was when the U.S. Army Air Force formed the 100th Bombardment Group. <br><br>And, by the way, my &#8212; just so you know &#8212; although my uncle, who was killed in World War Two in New Guinea was Army &#8212; he was the Army Air Corps.  He got shot down in a reconnaissance flight.  And he would &#8212; he&#8217;s looking down and thinking, “All these years, my God, what this Air Force has become.”  It&#8217;s incredible. <br><br>The 100th also ran more than 8,000 sorties into hostile territory and supported operations from D-Day to the Battle of the Bulge, where another uncle of mine served.<br><br>And when they first arrived in the UK in ’43, the unit took such heavy losses, it earned the moniker that has been passed down to this day: “The Bloody Hundredth.”  The Bloody Hundredth.  <br><br>So let me hear it for the 100th Air Wing &#8212; Air Refueling Wing, AKA &#8212; known as the “The Bloody Hundredth.”  (Applause.)<br><br>And what about the 352nd Special Operations Wing?  (Applause.) <br><br>There&#8217;s Team &#8212; Team Reconnaissance.  Members of the Air Mobility Command.  (Applause.)<br><br>Do we have any folks from the 48th Fighter Wing, over from RAF &#8212; (Applause.)  By the way &#8212; I think maybe.<br><br>The 501st Combat Support Wing from RAF Alconbury.  (Applause.)<br><br>And this may be a historic first for an Air Force base, but I hear there just might be a few members of the United States Army here tonight with us.  (Applause.)  Come on, man.<br><br>To all of you airmen and soldiers, I want to just say thank you.  We owe you.  We’re so damn proud of you.  So proud.  And I only wish my Major was here to thank you as well.  Thank you &#8212; everything you do, for everything you are. <br><br>There’s nothing that Jill and I enjoy more than spending time with our troops and their families, wherever we go in the world.<br><br>I had the great honor of being in and out of Afghanistan and Iraq well over 27, 28 times.  I think Jill is the only Second Lady in American history who has gone into a warzone &#8212; into Baghdad with me as well. <br><br>You&#8217;re the best &#8212; you’re the best of our country.  That&#8217;s not hyperbole.  You&#8217;re the ones who sign up and run toward danger when duty calls.  Less than 1 percent of Americans make the choice that you make &#8212; that you made.  But the rest of us &#8212; the other 99 percent of us &#8212; we owe you.  We owe you big.<br><br>I’ve long said that, as a nation, we have many obligations,<br>but we only have one truly sacred obligation &#8212; only one &#8212; and that’s to properly prepare and equip the women and men we send into harm’s way, and to care for you and your families, both while you’re deployed and when you come home.<br><br>And now that I have the incredible honor of serving as your Commander-in-Chief, I believe that even more strongly.  You know &#8212; and I want to give an extra special thank you to all the families. <br><br>As you heard from Jill, we Bidens are a proud military family, and we know there&#8217;s not just the person who wears the uniform who serves; the whole family has to step up, the whole family makes sacrifices.  There&#8217;s a famous Irish poet who said, “They also serve who only stand and wait.”<br><br>I watched all those months Beau was in Kosovo.  And then I watched all those &#8212; that year he was in &#8212; in Iraq.  She would stand at that sink, leaving for school, drinking her coffee, and I could see her lips moving, saying that prayer, hoping that car never drove up in front of the house, hoping you never got that phone call. <br><br>And that&#8217;s even more true this past year during the lockdowns and safety precautions to curb the spread of COVID-19.  Everyone in this room knows that our military families are essential &#8212; essential to our strength.<br><br>It’s the key reason Jill relaunched Joining Forces: to make sure we’re doing everything we can to support our military spouses and children, and their mothers and fathers as well, just like they support all of you.<br><br>You know, you not only did an amazing job keeping COVID-19 under control on the base; you took care of each other and your mental health throughout the initiatives like your Spouse-to-Spouse Connection and your Wellness Advocacy Team.  (Cheers.)  Thank you.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  As you all know, this is a team sport. <br><br>And my mother would kill me if she were here.  She&#8217;d say, “Joey, you shouldn’t have…&#8221; &#8212; I should’ve turned around and apologized for by back to you.  I apologize.  (Laughter.)  I haven’t figured out how to turn in 360 yet.  (Laughter.)<br><br>But, folks, thousands of hours spent volunteering to make sure everyone got through this.  It was so important.<br><br>I know that these last 15 months added a lot of new pressure, but all of you rose to the task together as one team &#8212; Team Mildenhall.  And you never let up on your mission.<br><br>And I’m so proud to be here with all of you to kick off my first overseas trip as President.  I&#8217;ve been in and out of here many, many times.  I’ve visited well over 100 countries as President or as Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee &#8212; or I meant as Vice President or Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee.  This is my first overseas trip as President of the United States. <br><br>I&#8217;m heading to the G7, then to the NATO Ministerial, and then to meet with Mr. Putin to let him know what I want him to know.  (Laughter and applause.)<br><br>And at every point along the way, we’re going to make it clear that the United States is back and democracies of the world are standing together to tackle the toughest challenges and the issues that matter most to our future; that we’re committed to leading with strength, defending our values, and delivering for our people.<br><br>America is better positioned to advance our national security and our economic prosperity when we bring together like-minded nations to stand with us.  These nations that have shed blood alongside of us in defense of our shared values.  Our unrivaled network of alliances and partnerships that are the key to American advantage in the world and have been.  They&#8217;ve made the world safer for all of us, and they are how we are going to meet the challenges of today, which are changing rapidly.  We&#8217;re going to meet it, though, from a position of strength. <br><br>Our alliances weren&#8217;t built by coercion or maintained by threats.  They&#8217;re grounded on democratic ideals and a shared vision of the future and where every voice matters &#8212; (applause) &#8212; where the rights &#8212; where the rights of all people are protected. <br><br>It’s the same reason so many of you signed up to serve, to proudly defend and honor the democratic values that are the wellspring of our national strength. <br><br>If our British friends will excuse me quoting the Declaration of Independence &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; America is unique in all the world in that we are not formed based on geography, or ethnicity, or religion, but on an idea &#8212; an idea.  The only nation in the world founded on the notion of an idea. <br><br>“We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men and women are created equal, endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights,” including “life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.”  We mean it.  No nation can defeat us as long as we stick to our values. <br><br>It&#8217;s our American creed.  It’s what makes us who we are.  And it’s what draws friends and partners to our side.  And for hundreds of years, American patriots have fought, and sometimes died, defending those values.<br><br>Folks, look, I&#8217;m often quoted by the press as saying, “America leads not by the example of its power, but by the power of our example.”  All of you &#8212; our service members stationed around the world &#8212; you are the solid steel spine of America around which alliances are built and strengthened year after year. <br><br>These partnerships have hardened and have been hardened in the fire of war, and generations of Americans and service members who fought them, like the original Bloody Hundredth and those <s>RFA</s> [RAF] pilots, and their shared mission in World War Two &#8212; flying, fighting, winning.  It was done together. <br><br>These bonds of history and shared fi- &#8212; sacrifice run deep and are strong, based on values.  And they endure. <br><br>The connections and camaraderie between our troops, this community of American citizens stationed in the UK &#8212; U.S. visiting forces and families, 20,000 strong &#8212; are not only warriors, you’re diplomats and you’re bridge-builders.  You are the essential part of what makes up this Special Relationship between Great Britain and the United States. <br><br>Over the next few days, as I said, I&#8217;ll be participating in meetings with many of our closest partners at the G7 in Cornwall, and then on to Brussels and NATO Summit of the EU &#8212; and the EU Summit. <br><br>This diplomacy is essential, because no single nation acting alone can meet all the challenges we face today because the world is changing.  To quote another Irish poet, he said, “The world&#8217;s changed, changed utterly.  A terrible beauty has been born.” <br><br>We&#8217;re in a different place than we were 10 years ago &#8212; a better position but a different place.  We have to build the shared future we seek: a future where nations are free from coercion or dominance by more powerful states; where the global commons &#8212; the seas, the air, the space &#8212; and space &#8212; remain open and accessible for the benefit of all. <br><br>To tackle this century&#8217;s most pressing challenges, we have to do it together.  We have to end COVID-19, not just at home &#8212; which we&#8217;re doing &#8212; but everywhere.  There&#8217;s no wall high enough to keep us safe from this pandemic or the next biological threat we face &#8212; and there will be others.<br><br>It requires coordinated, multilateral action.  We must all commit to an ambitious climate action if we&#8217;re going to prevent the worst impacts of climate change, limiting global warning [sic] &#8212; warming to no more than 1.5 degrees Celsius, and lead the global &#8212; the global transition to clean energy technology. <br><br>You know, when I went over in the Tank in the Pentagon, when I first was elected Vice President, with President Obama, the military sat us down to let us know what the greatest threats facing America were &#8212; the greatest physical threats.  And this is not a joke: You know what the Joint Chiefs told us the greatest threat facing America was?  Global warming.  Because there&#8217;ll be significant population movements, fights over land, millions of people leaving places because they’re literally sinking below the sea in Indonesia; because of the fights over what is arable land anymore. <br><br>With the G7, we plan to launch an ambitious effort to support resilience and development around the world by investing in high-quality, high-standard physical, digital, and health infrastructures. <br><br>We have to make sure that new technologies and norms of conduct in cyberspace are established, including addressing the growing threat of ransomware attacks that are governed by our democratic values, not by the autocrats who are letting it happen. <br><br>These are all critical national security issues in 2021, and we&#8217;re going to be driving this agenda together with our G7 partners.<br><br>In Brussels, I will make it clear that the United States’ commitment to our NATO Alliance and Article 5 is rock solid.  It&#8217;s a sacred obligation that we have under Article 5.<br><br>The U.S. and the UK are both founding members of NATO &#8212; the strongest military and political alliance in the history of the world.  And that&#8217;s not hyperbole.<br><br>Our troops have stood shoulder-to-shoulder around the world, including serving bravely in the mountains of Afghanistan for the past 20 years.<br><br>Our NATO Allies have had our backs when it mattered, just like we&#8217;ve had theirs when it’s mattered.  And now we need to modernize our Alliance, investing on our critical infrastructure, our cyber capabilities, and to keep us secure against every threat that we’ve faced over the last decade, and the new challenges we&#8217;re about to face as well.<br><br>With the European Union leaders, I&#8217;ll discuss how the United States can work with Europe to address the full range of issues that require the full strength of our transatlantic partnership, including working together to shape the new rules for the 21st century economies. <br><br>And only after these meetings with our closest democratic partners to develop a common agenda and renewed purpose, I’ll travel to Geneva to sit down with a man I&#8217;ve spent time with before: President Vladimir Putin. <br><br>We&#8217;re not seeking conflict with Russia.  We want a stable, pretictable [sic] &#8212; predictable relationship.  Our two nations share incredible responsibilities, and among them ensuring strategic stability and upholding arms control agreements.  I take that responsibility seriously. <br><br>But I&#8217;ve been clear: The United States will respond in a robust and meaningful way when the Russian government engages in harmful activities.  We&#8217;ve already demonstrated that.  I&#8217;m going to communicate that there are consequences for violati- &#8212; for violating the sovereignty of democracies in the United States and Europe and elsewhere. <br><br>I&#8217;m going to be clear that the Transatlantic Alliance will remain vital &#8212; a vital source of strength for the UK, Europe, and the United States.  And I’m going to make sure there&#8217;s no doubt as to whether the United States will rise in defense of our most deeply held values and our fundamental interest. <br><br>Here&#8217;s why this all matters so much right now: I believe we&#8217;re at an inflection point in world history &#8212; the moment where it falls to us to prove that democracies will not just endure, but they will excel as we rise to seize the enormous opportunities of a new age. <br><br>We have to discredit those who believe that the age of democracy is over, as some of our fellow nations believe.  We have to expose as false the narrative that decrees of dictators can match the speed and scale of the 21st [century] challenges. <br><br>You know and I know they’re wrong.  But it doesn&#8217;t mean we don&#8217;t have to work harder than ever to prove that democracy can still deliver for our people.<br><br>For the many who think things are changing so rapidly, democracies cannot get together and form a consensus to respond like autocrats can, but you know better than anyone that democracy doesn&#8217;t happen by accident.  We have to defend it.  We have to strengthen it, renew it. <br><br>And I know that the American people are up to this job.  I know because I look around this hangar and what I see is I see America.  I see America &#8212; people of different backgrounds coming together in a share mission.  Our democracy has never been perfect.  Never been perfect.  But Americans of all races, religions, sexual orientation, immigrants, Native Americans all have spilled their blood to defend the values that we talk about.<br><br>Generation after generation of American heroes have signed up to be part of the fight because they understand the truth<br>that lives in every American heart: that liberation, opportunity, justice is far more likely to come to pass in a democracy than in the emerging autocracies in the world.<br><br>I promise you that’s what this is going to be all about for your generation and those of your children.  And here’s what else I know beyond a doubt: There is not a single thing &#8212; nothing &#8212; nothing beyond America’s competence to accomplish when we do it together, when we do it as one people.  You’re proof of that.  You’re proof of that every single day.  Your bravery, your decency, your honor, your commitment to duty. <br><br>You can send more fuel through a boom of a KC-135R in eight minutes than a civilian gas pump can pump in 24 hours, and you do it in midair, and it’s all a normal day for this team.  So don’t tell me we can’t win our race to the future across the board. <br><br>We’re the country that cracked the physicals and the physics of human flight, then crashed through the sound barrier, then put a man on the Moon and flew a helicopter on Mars.  I could go on and on and on.  There is nothing, nothing, nothing beyond our capacity.<br><br>So, I want to thank you again for welcoming Jill and me today.  It’s great to be here in the UK, but it’s greater being here and seeing you first.  Seeing all of you is the best possible way to start this trip. <br><br>Let me end where I began: by saying “thank you.”  I mean it from the bottom of my heart.  I give you my word.  Thank you all for what you do.  Thank you all for your understanding that we’re a nation based on values.  Thank you all for protecting us all. <br><br>May God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.  Thank you, and God bless.  (Applause.) <br><br>9:09 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Suffolk, England</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/09/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-suffolk-england/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Suffolk, England 6:56 P.M. BST&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Okay.&#160; Okay.&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; We are on our way, almost arriving on the President’s first foreign trip.&#160; We have a very special guest for our gaggle today.&#160; Our National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, will take some questions, and then once you’re done with that,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Suffolk, England</p>



<p>6:56 P.M. BST<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; We are on our way, almost arriving on the President’s first foreign trip.&nbsp; We have a very special guest for our gaggle today.&nbsp; Our National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan, will take some questions, and then once you’re done with that, I’m happy to take some as well.&nbsp; But you may have mostly for him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, do you want to talk a little bit about the President’s plan for boosting the global vaccine supply?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I do not want to get ahead of the President, who will be speaking to this issue tomorrow.&nbsp; And we’ll be able to talk about additional steps the United States is taking to help donate more doses to poor countries around the world and also to leverage what the United States is doing to help get the world’s democracies to increase their commitment to supplying vaccines to the developing world to help end this pandemic once and for all.&nbsp; But that announcement that he will make, he will &#8212; I will let him make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then the G7, we’ll make a combined announcement on this issue, and it won’t simply be about vaccines &#8212; though vaccines will be a part of it &#8212; but it will be a comprehensive plan to help end this pandemic as rapidly as possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the incentive for doing this?&nbsp; Is this about countering China and Russia?&nbsp; The President has talked about their vaccine diplomacy.&nbsp; Why is he trying to rally Western democracies, in particular, on this issue?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’d say three things about this:<br>&nbsp;<br>First, the President is focused on helping to vaccinate the world because believes it is the right thing to do; it’s what Americans do in times of need.&nbsp; When we have the capacity, then we have the will, and we step up and we deliver.&nbsp; And he said in his joint session that we were the arsenal of democracy in World War Two, and we’re going to be the arsenal of vaccines over the course of the next period to end this pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, it’s the smart thing to do, because if variants continue to proliferate and get worse, ultimately one could break through.&nbsp; And he wants to make sure we end the pandemic before that happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, third, he does want to show &#8212; rallying the rest of the world’s democracies &#8212; that democracies are the countries that can best deliver solutions for people everywhere.&nbsp; And that goes for COVID-19, it goes for climate change, it goes for economic recovery, and it goes for the basic human rights and human dignity of all people.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk about the working groups that are being launched to reopen travel within the G7?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We’ve established two working groups of experts &#8212; public health experts: one with the United Kingdom and one with the European Union.&nbsp; The point of these working groups is to share data and set out both milestones and criteria to enable a reopening of travel between our two countries as swiftly as possible, consistent with public health guidance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we expect any announcement on that front, during the trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think the working groups will have finished their work by the time the trip is through.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not currently anticipating any specific announcements because we&#8217;re being guided by science; we&#8217;re being guided by what the public health experts tell us is the right condition and the right timeframe for reopening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect that the EU&#8217;s refusal of the vaccine patent waiver to be a point of contention between the President and the other leaders?&nbsp; Is the President going to push them to waive &#8212; patent waivers?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t anticipate contention on the issue of vaccines.&nbsp; I anticipate convergence, because we&#8217;re all converging around the idea that we need to boost vaccine supply in a number of ways: sharing more of our own doses &#8212; and we&#8217;ll have more to say on that; helping get more manufacturing capacity around the world &#8212; we&#8217;ll have more to say on that; and, of course, doing what&#8217;s necessary across the chain of custody from when the vaccine is produced to when it gets in someone&#8217;s arms in the rural developing world, and we&#8217;ll have more to say on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I don&#8217;t foresee any clash or contest between the U.S. and our democratic partners on this issue.&nbsp; I see a unity of effort and a unity of commitment.&nbsp; And I think the results are going to end up speaking for themselves.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How prominent is the conversation with Putin going to be on Syria humanitarian aid passage and keeping that route to Idlib open?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, second, on that: With the decision to end the sanctions waiver for the American oil company that was operating there, that Russia very much against, was that sort of a fig leaf or playing out something for Putin to sort of smooth the talks on that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Syria will be on the agenda, and our position on the humanitarian access issue is well understood.&nbsp; We believe there has to be cross-border humanitarian access to save lives.&nbsp; And so that certainly will be something that the two presidents discuss.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to get into the details on it at this point because we want to give space for those conversations to play out in the run-up to Geneva and then between the two presidents.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve got nothing more for you today on the oil field issue in eastern Syria.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can you talk about strategic stability being a key part of the discussion?&nbsp; How are you defining that?&nbsp; Is it in the traditional nuclear arms control definition?&nbsp; Is it the mix of arms control/cyber vulnerabilities for the (inaudible)?&nbsp; Is it something broader involving the way the Russians are acting on their borders?&nbsp; What’s your concept?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We believe the starting point for strategic stability talks should be the very complex set of nuclear arms issues that face our two countries.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve extended New START for five years.&nbsp; But what comes after that, how do we deal with the fact that the INF Treaty is no more, how do we deal with our concerns about Russia&#8217;s new nuclear systems, and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) deployed you mean, but that Putin keeps showing.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; (Inaudible) development.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; And these are issues that we have raised publicly and we&#8217;ve raised privately with the Russians.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the starting point.&nbsp; Whether additional elements get added to strategic stability talks in the realm of space or cyber or other areas, that&#8217;s something to be determined as we go forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, there&#8217;s been an uptick in ransomware attacks recently.&nbsp; Is that going to be a point of discussion when the President meets with President Putin?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, 100 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What can you do about it?&nbsp; I mean, is retaliation on the table, off the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, our basic view on this is that all ransomware attacks are crimes.&nbsp; They should be prosecuted to the full extent of the law, and every responsible nation should take action against the criminals who are conducting them and should not harbor them in any way.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Ransomware attacks against critical infrastructure are of an even higher order of magnitude of concern for us, whether that&#8217;s about a pipeline or meat supply or a hospital system or other areas of critical infrastructure.&nbsp; The President will talk to President Putin about our concerns on this front.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We do not judge that the Russian government has been behind these recent ransomware attacks, but we do judge that actors in Russia have.&nbsp; And we believe that Russia can take and must take steps to deal with it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;m not going to be in the business of telegraphing our punches publicly or issuing threats publicly; I&#8217;m just going to say that we believe Russia has a responsibility.&nbsp; And, of course, any country that doesn&#8217;t act, then the United States will have to consider what its options are, following that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you think is causing the uptick?&nbsp; Why do you think now?&nbsp; Why do you think there&#8217;s been an uptick in attacks now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first of all, let&#8217;s be clear that this is not strictly a U.S.-Russia issue.&nbsp; Ireland has faced the &#8212; a catastrophic attack on its healthcare system.&nbsp; The JBS attack started in a computer system; it came from Russia, hit first a computer system in Mexico, affected Australia and Canada, as well as the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is a global problem and it&#8217;s being driven by a variety of factors, including increasing technical capability, and also, unfortunately, including the fact that many elements of the private sector globally have not brought their cybersecurity standards up to snuff.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And one of our messages has been &#8212; to the private sector in the United States and globally &#8212; that it is &#8212; it&#8217;s very important to lock your house, to make sure that it is more difficult for these criminals to get inside and hold them hostage or disrupt their operations.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the President will discuss the Nord Stream pipeline with the German chancellor and/or the Russian president?&nbsp; Will it come up?&nbsp; Do you expect them to raise it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I expect Nord Stream 2 will come up in conversations with the Germans.&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t want to negotiate publicly on this issue.&nbsp; They understand well our concerns.&nbsp; But we do want to talk to them about what the implications of this pipeline are for energy security in Europe and for Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, what is the message that President Biden will deliver to Prime Minister Boris Johnson on Brexit and the Northern Ireland &#8212; the Good Friday Agreement?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; President Biden has been crystal clear about his rock-solid belief in the Good Friday Agreement as the foundation for peaceful coexistence in Northern Ireland.&nbsp; That agreement must be protected, and any steps that imperil or undermine it will not be welcomed by the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Johnson taking steps to imperil it?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to characterize that at this point.&nbsp; I&#8217;m only going to say that President Biden is going to make statements in principle on this front.&nbsp; He&#8217;s not issuing threats or ultimatums; he&#8217;s going to simply convey his deep-seated belief that we need to stand behind and protect this protocol.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What else does he want to talk to Boris Johnson about?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;ll be talking to Boris Johnson about COVID-19; about climate change, as the UK is hosting COP26 in Glasgow later this year; about their joint commitment to developing an infrastructure financing mechanism for the developing world that is climate friendly, high standards, and transparent.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll talk to him about Afghanistan and our collective desire to maintain a strong embassy security &#8212; or embassy presence in Afghanistan after the troop drawdown.&nbsp; And, of course, there&#8217;s a whole global set of issues, from the Indo-Pacific to the Middle East, that the two leaders will cover.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, finally &#8212; you&#8217;ll see this when they meet tomorrow &#8212; there&#8217;ll be a refresher of the Atlantic Charter, which is now 80 years old.&nbsp; So there will be an updated statement of principles between the U.S. and the UK as free societies and free peoples speaking out about what we believe in in this 21st century.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, the President has talked about personal relationships in driving foreign policy.&nbsp; He had this meeting 10 years ago with Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; What did he learn from that meeting, and what is he bringing from that meeting?&nbsp; And has he been reflecting on it at all in the preparation for this upcoming meeting?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Bottom line: He believes you need to be clear, direct, and straightforward in every aspect of the engagement with Vladimir Putin, and that&#8217;s what he intends to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he ever consider having a joint press conference with him?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he &#8212; did the President ever consider having a joint press conference with Putin, or was it out of the question from the start?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I will defer to my press colleagues about the individual modalities of the press-related issues.&nbsp; But he does want to have an opportunity after that meeting to read it out and speak about his impressions and what he sees as the way forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you tell us what your views are on the 232 tariffs that remain in place?&nbsp; Do you expect them to come in and &#8212; like, do you think that those 232 tariffs are a national security issue?&nbsp; That was the guise or umbrella under which they were imposed in the first place.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, you know, in a real spirit of constructive engagement, the U.S. and the EU have agreed to a pause in the escalation of tariffs in response to the 232.&nbsp; That has given time and space for a negotiation to hopefully produce an outcome that meaningfully addresses the problem of Chinese overcapacity.&nbsp; And we regard that as a serious challenge that affects both Europe and the United States and must be dealt with effectively.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe there&#8217;s an outcome possible on this trip, or is that a longer-term discussion?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s going to take some time to work out, which is why that stand-down on the tariffs was so important &#8212; because it gives us the time and space for us to be able to (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;But you&#8217;re not rolling back tariffs? &nbsp;You’re not rolling back tariffs? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; (Shakes head no.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak a little bit about Iran and what the President will ask President Putin, in terms of supporting the JCPOA?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Russia is a member of the P5+1.&nbsp; The American negotiating team is working with the Russian negotiating team in Vienna.&nbsp; They have worked together in a productive and constructive way, to a large extent.&nbsp; And so this will be an opportunity for the two presidents to be able to consult on where we think we are in those talks and what needs to be done to get them across the line.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, on Iran &#8212; just continuing on that same line: The Secretary has frequently said we need something longer and stronger, and so forth.&nbsp; Do you have any reason to believe that after &#8212; if you get the agreement that is now basically in blue, that the Iranians have any interest in going to something that is longer and stronger?&nbsp; And what is that evidence?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t underestimate the difficulty of any nuclear negotiation with the Iranians, since we&#8217;ve been through them.&nbsp; But we do believe that there is scope for follow-on negotiations to deal with what &#8212; to build on the JCPOA once we are back in it.&nbsp; And we believe the Iranians will ultimately be prepared to engage in those negotiations.&nbsp; There are things for them to gain, because there are many aspects of our sanctions that are &#8212; are not necessarily part of the original JCPOA.&nbsp; And, of course, we retain all of the right and capacity to take additional steps if they&#8217;re not prepared to negotiate in good faith.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’ve talked before about the ransomware side.&nbsp; But, you know, a few months ago, if this meeting was happening, it would have been pretty much all about SolarWinds and state-sponsored actions.&nbsp; So is that now behind you, having done the sanctions and whatever unseen activities?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s the President&#8217;s message on that?&nbsp; What kind of guardrails might use that (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We have had the opportunity to engage with the Russians, through several channels, on the SolarWinds issue, both before and after we imposed costs in response to it.&nbsp; But that doesn&#8217;t mean that issue is behind us, of course. &nbsp;The issue of state-sponsored cyberattacks of that scope and scale remains a matter of grave concern to the United States.&nbsp; It will be a topic of conversation between the presidents.<br>&nbsp;<br>And us talking ransomware is not going to come to the exclusion of us talking about the cyber threat in multiple other domains.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) him to some understanding with Putin, to some understanding of what&#8217;s off limits.&nbsp; Can you tell us a little bit about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to leave that to the two presidents to discuss for now.&nbsp; You know, sort of, depending on how that conversation goes at the highest level and where we come out, we will be in a better position to be able to talk about our expectations, as well as our capacities at that point.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t want to front-run that today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has there been any developments on Airbus during this time at all?&nbsp; The Airbus dispute &#8212; the Boeing Airbus dispute.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;m not going to say one way or the other on that.&nbsp;&nbsp;All I will note is that the negotiations are ongoing, that we also there bought space with the mutual stand-down on tariffs as well that runs out much sooner than the 232.&nbsp;&nbsp;And so, I think there has been good progress in those negotiations, but I&#8217;m making no promises about what might happen over the course of the (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jumping ahead to the NATO meeting, does the President feel the need to restate U.S. support for Article 5?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, of course.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will he do that in Brussels?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He feels the need to restate support for Article 5 as often as he is able to do so, because for him, it&#8217;s an article of faith &#8212; for President Joe Biden and for the United States of America.&nbsp; And so he will proclaim that loudly and proudly, as he just did with the Secretary General when he was in town a couple of days ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, you know, he&#8217;s not just going to speak about principle; he&#8217;s going to speak about the practicalities of what&#8217;s required to make Article 5 real, including the work that needs to be done between now and 2030 on every aspect of transatlantic defense and security.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, in the last G7, there was not a communiqué because of disagreements between President Trump and the other leaders.&nbsp; Can we expect a communiqué at this G7?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to jinx it, but yes, I think you can expect a communiqué at this G7.&nbsp; And &#8212; you know.&nbsp; But you never know.&nbsp; I hope so.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right, I’m going to let Jake go back.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you can speak a little bit more about the format of<br>the bilaterals between President Biden and Putin, that would be great.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I mean, what I can tell you is we&#8217;re still discussing, so we don’t have a final conclusion yet.&nbsp; That what I can confirm for you is that you will have the opportunity to ask questions of President Biden.&nbsp; And we certainly hope that you&#8217;ll also have the opportunity to ask questions of President Putin.&nbsp; What that format looks like, we&#8217;ll know in the next couple days.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so it’s still being negotiated with the Russians?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Still being &#8212; still being discussed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And it’s still two bilats &#8212; a small and an extended one?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That’s right.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Talk about infrastructure a little bit.&nbsp; We saw the statement.&nbsp; Has the President now decided to go it only with Democrats to pass the bill?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So I talked to the President about this, this morning, and his view is that there are multiple paths forward.&nbsp; He feels it&#8217;s encouraging to see multiple proposals put out there, both from Republicans in the House and the Problem Solvers Caucus, as well as a bipartisan group that&#8217;s working on a proposal.&nbsp; Both will have increased numbers over what we&#8217;ve seen and been negotiating to date.&nbsp; Those are all positive steps.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the same time, Steve, we&#8217;re also &#8212; the Senate is also moving forward with a budget process.&nbsp; That, by the way, is how government should work.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an opportunity to move, through that vehicle, a bunch of his bold economic ideas, as well as corporate tax reform &#8212; something that, of course, will pay for a number of his proposals but also something that will make us more competitive and he thinks is long overdue.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President, with Senator Capito, pivoted to talking about a 15 percent minimum corporate tax as opposed to a 28 percent corporate tax rate.&nbsp; Of course, they’re not mutually exclusive, but is he resetting at all, now that he&#8217;s pivoting to the bipartisan group?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has always felt that corporate tax reform and raising the corporate rate to 28 percent &#8212; which he proposed and is in his budget, as you know &#8212; is something that is good for &#8212; good for our competition, good for our economy, good for workers in this country, and also will help pay for proposals.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you also know, the 15 percent minimum tax was an additional proposal that he put forward in the American Jobs Plan and also is in his budget.&nbsp; But it is a proposal that would not violate the red line the Republicans have put forward on the 2017 tax cuts.&nbsp; So, that, which would help pay for proposals, as well as the IRS going after individuals to ensure they&#8217;re paying for &#8212; they’re paying their fair share and they&#8217;re paying what they owe &#8212; are payfors that do not violate the 2017 taxes.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why he reelevated those.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think those corporate tax changes are more or less likely with this bipartisan group of senators than they were with Senator Capito’s group?&nbsp; Are they more on the table or less on the table?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll certainly see.&nbsp; But our view and the President&#8217;s view is that they should be on the table for all of them because they do not violate their red line; because &#8212; unless they feel that these corporations shouldn&#8217;t pay any taxes at all.&nbsp; We&#8217;re just suggesting they should pay 15 percent, which isn&#8217;t even what the tax rate he&#8217;s proposing for most corporations around the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did the President spend any time on the flight over, or even in the short time between when he woke up this morning, getting to talk to people and do some of this reach-out that he said he&#8217;s going to be doing on infrastructure, while (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m not sure even any of his close friends would like a call from him at 6:00 a.m.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But he will certainly be engaged on this trip with his domestic agenda, including having conversations with Democrats and Republicans back at home.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On this trip, he was primarily focused on having discussions with his national security team about the foreign trip &#8212; his first foreign trip overseas &#8212; but he will be having those conversations.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll keep you abreast of those.&nbsp; He&#8217;s also asked his Jobs Cabinet to run point and be closely engaged with all of these members of both parties who are interested in being part of the infrastructure negotiations moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know you guys &#8212; I know he can walk and chew gum, or whatever metaphor you want to use, but is there any disappoint, just not having that done before getting started with this also very important agenda item?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say that what we see are a number of signs of progress.&nbsp; One, the Senate just passed a China competition bill just yesterday.&nbsp; We&#8217;re eager for the House to move forward on that; that&#8217;s a positive step forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>While we&#8217;re on this plane &#8212; on this flight, Congressman DeFazio is helping oversee the markup of the Surface Transportation bill that has a great deal of overlap with the American Jobs Plan. &nbsp;And in addition to the Senate moving forward on a budget process that can be a vehicle for his economic ideas and corporate tax reform, we&#8217;ve also seen multiple options of proposals come forward in a bipartisan manner.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;s quite familiar with the fact that this process can take &#8212; it takes some patience at times; that there are going to be moments where we&#8217;re near death, and then it comes back.&nbsp; That&#8217;s always how policymaking, lawmaking, bill making happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212; but he&#8217;s been encouraged by the progress, encouraged by the interest by not just Republicans and Democrats in the country, but also in Congress, on working together to get an infrastructure bill passed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say what Jake meant by a “refresher” of the transatlantic charter?&nbsp; &nbsp;Can you tell us a little bit more about that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; It will be something that we will put out.&nbsp; it will update the charter that, as he noted, is several decades old &#8212; I believe is what he said.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll put that out publicly and it will &#8212; you know, it will confirm and be clear &#8212; and will be consistent with what our challenges are today and opportunities today.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll put that out publicly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk to us about what can we expect with the bilat with President Erdoğan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, this is a relationship, obviously a NATO partner, where there are areas where we feel it&#8217;s important to continue to constructively work together where there&#8217;s opportunity, and also areas where we have strong disagreement.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an opportunity to have that face-to-face diplomacy, which the President felt was important to do as a priority bilateral meeting during his first trip overseas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what are the specific issues?&nbsp; Like, Syria or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure they will discuss issues of regional security; issues, of course, that are impacting the global community, including the economy, including COVID-19.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more, I&#8217;m sure, as we get closer to the bilateral meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he going to have bilats with other leaders at the G7, or, like, pull-asides individually?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He will certainly have pull-asides.&nbsp; I will look back at the schedule and what we’ve confirmed publicly.&nbsp; As you all know, from covering these international summits, there are &#8212; the schedules are quite packed, but there is an opportunity often to have, kind of, pull-aside conversations, and he&#8217;ll look for the opportunity to do that on the ground as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s rumors that he&#8217;s going to be having a pull-aside with the Belarusian opposition leader. &nbsp;Is that correct?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have not seen &#8212; I am not aware of that plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On infrastructure &#8212; back to infrastructure: Leader Schumer suggested that the bill could possibly pass partially through reconciliation, partially through bipartisan.&nbsp; Is that something that the administration is open to?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I mean, the point is it&#8217;s moving on several paths.&nbsp; So even as we negotiate an infrastructure bill &#8212; right? &#8212; or portions of the American Jobs Plan, it’s already moving forward on several fronts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then there are components of the Amer- &#8212; of the President’s proposals, including the extension of the Child Tax Credit, making pre-K universal, making community college free, that are not a part of the negotiations now, so they would be natural components that would be added into a budget process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Jen, a couple of weeks ago, we heard the President agreeing to the statement that President Putin is a killer.&nbsp; Do you think that’s going to make things awkward coming into the summit?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has known President Putin for a long time.&nbsp; He has never held back in voicing his concerns or issues where their behavior is not aligned with democratic values, and he will certainly be straightforward in doing that in this meeting as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this is not about friendship.&nbsp; It’s not about trust.&nbsp; It’s about what’s in the interest of the United States.&nbsp; And, in our view, that is moving toward a more stable and predictable relationship.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the China bill, you now have to get to the House.&nbsp; What’s the strategy there?&nbsp; It looks like that may be a tougher climb than the Senate.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That &#8212; that may be the case.&nbsp; Look, the President was certainly encouraged by the fact that it passed the Senate.&nbsp; We’ve seen concerns expressed publicly by some members of the House, including some high up.&nbsp; And we’re going to take a look at what the legislation looks like, hear their concerns.&nbsp; We’ll be engaged, of course, in discussing how we can move this forward, you know, from a staff level.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a schedule for that, or not?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have a schedule or a timeline to predict.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the global minimum tax &#8212; some of the Republicans came out against it this week.&nbsp; Does that complicate the plan at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; On the world stage?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; No &#8212; yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, our view is that this is in the interest of America’s competition of our economy, of the global economy to have that global minimum tax, and felt it was a very positive sign that there was agreement among finance ministers at the G7.&nbsp; So we are encouraged by that, and, you know, it’s a positive sign.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) the EU and U.S. have a &#8212; their draft statement, as of now, includes a reference to the origins &#8212; the investigation into the origins of the coronavirus.&nbsp; Why is the U.S. seeking, sort of, support from European allies on this issue of getting to the bottom of where that virus came from?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that even as we pursue our own 90-day review, and &#8212; where we are going to tap into every resource we have available in the U.S. government, we also recognize that in order to send a clear message to China and to the WHO, of course, who’ve been a constructive partner, that it’s important that they are transparent, that they release all the available data, that we move forward on the second stage of this investigation.&nbsp; Doing that from a united front and doing that in partnership with our European partners is a vital part of this process.&nbsp; So, it’s an indication of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will there be a similar line in the G7 communiqué?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to predict for you on that quite yet.&nbsp; You’ll know soon enough.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you comment again on the vaccine patent waiver?&nbsp; The U.S. has just joined the G20 &#8212; I’m sorry, the APEC &#8212; to support the patent waivers.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the President be pushing this issue with European leaders who prefer to do compulsory licensing instead?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is an ongoing process that our ambassador &#8212; our USTR ambassador is running point on.&nbsp; It’s a long process, as you know &#8212; several months to negotiate what the best format will look like.&nbsp; Whether it’s coming up &#8212; going to come up in conversations, I’m sure we can &#8212; that will be reflected in readouts.&nbsp; But I would suspect we will leave it at the level of the U.S. ambassador.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the President doesn’t plan to put his diplomatic weight behind a patent waiver?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has certainly spoken about his support on the waiver.&nbsp; He believes it’s import- &#8212; an important component of addressing the global threat of COVID.&nbsp; And he will continue to play a constructive role.&nbsp; But I don’t have anything to preview for you or predict in terms of how it will come up in these conversations.<br>&nbsp;<br>All right, thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Have a good landing.<br>&nbsp;<br>7:25 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nomination Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/09/nomination-sent-to-the-senate-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20145</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATION&#160;SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Jayme Ray White, of Washington, to be a Deputy United States Trade Representative (Western Hemisphere, Europe, the Middle East, Labor, and Environment), with the rank of Ambassador, vice Michael N. Nemelka. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATION&nbsp;SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jayme Ray White, of Washington, to be a Deputy United States Trade Representative (Western Hemisphere, Europe, the Middle East, Labor, and Environment), with the rank of Ambassador, vice Michael N. Nemelka.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
