<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 19:49:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the 154th National Memorial Day&#160;Observance</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/30/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-154th-national-memorial-day-observance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 19:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Arlington National CemeteryArlington, Virginia 12:54 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; They lie here in glory and honor &#8212; in quiet rows in Arlington, in cemeteries in Europe that I visited and many of you have, in graves across our country, in towns large and small &#8212; America’s beloved daughters and sons who dared all,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Arlington National Cemetery<br>Arlington, Virginia</p>



<p>12:54 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They lie here in glory and honor &#8212; in quiet rows in Arlington, in cemeteries in Europe that I visited and many of you have, in graves across our country, in towns large and small &#8212; America’s beloved daughters and sons who dared all, risked all, and gave all to preserve and defend an idea unlike any other in human history: the idea of the United States of America.</p>



<p>And today, as a nation, we undertake a sacred ritual: to reflect and to remember.&nbsp; Because if we forget the lives that each of those silent markers represent &#8212; mothers, fathers, siblings, spouses, children &#8212; if we forget what they sacrificed, what they made so that our nation might endure strong, free, and united, then we forget who we are &#8212; who we are.</p>



<p>Ladies and gentlemen, our First Lady and the love of my life, Jill; Vice President Harris and the Second Gentleman; Secretary Austin; General Milley; the Joint Chiefs of Staff, Cabinet members; Gold Star families, most importantly; and survivors: Today we renew our sacred vow &#8212; it’s a simple vow: to remember.&nbsp; To remember.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Memorial Day is always a day where pain and pride are mixed together.&nbsp; We all know it, sitting here.&nbsp; Jill and I know it.&nbsp; Today is the day our son died.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, folks, for those who have lost a loved one in the service of our country, if your loved one is missing or unaccounted for, I know the ceremonies reopen that black hole in the center of your chest that just pulls you in, suffocates you.</p>



<p>As I said, seven years ago today, our son, Major Beau Biden, took his last breath at Walter Reed.&nbsp; A major in the Delaware Army National Guard, he insisted on deploying to Iraq</p>



<p>with his unit for a year when he was attorney general.&nbsp; He came home a decorated soldier, a Bronze Star, Legion of Merit, and Delaware’s Conspicuous Service Cross.</p>



<p>He didn’t die in the line of duty.&nbsp; He came home from Iraq with cancer.&nbsp; It was a horrific cancer that stole us from him, stole &#8212; and him from us.</p>



<p>But still, it always feels to me on Memorial Day &#8212; I see him, not as he was the last time I held his hand, but the day I pinned his bars on him as a second lieutenant.</p>



<p>I see him with me down at the Delaware Memorial Bridge hugging all the Gold Star families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Days like this bring back, before your eyes, their smile and their laugh.&nbsp; And the last conversation you had, each of you know it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The hurt can be overwhelming.  But for so many of you, as is with Jill and me, the hurt is wrapped around the knowledge that your loved one was part of something bigger &#8212; bigger than any of us.</p>



<p>They chose a life of purpose.&nbsp; It sounds corny, like a Memorial Day speech, but I mean it from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp; They chose a life of purpose.</p>



<p>They had a mission.&nbsp; And above all, they believed in duty; they believed in honor; they believed in their country.</p>



<p>And still today, we are free because they were brave.&nbsp; We live by the light of the flame of liberty that they kept burning.&nbsp; And so a part of them is still with us no matter how long ago we lost them.</p>



<p>And as hard as it is for many to believe, especially those whose loss is still raw, I promise you the day will come when the memory of your loved one, your patriot, will bring a smile to your lip before it brings a tear to your eye.&nbsp; That’s when you know you’re going to make it.</p>



<p>Today, America’s ser- &#8212; American service members stand watch around the world, and, as many of you know, often at great personal risk.</p>



<p>And this Memorial Day, we know the memory is still painful of all the fallen who lost their lives during the last two decades in combat.  Each of them leaving behind a family, a community.  Hearts broken by their absence, and lives that will never be the same.</p>



<p>We see in the hundreds of graves here in Section 60, at Arlington, a reminder that there’s nothing low-risk or low-cost about war for the women and men who fight it.</p>



<p>7,054 American military members gave their lives over 20 years of our Iraq and Afghan conflicts.&nbsp; Untold others died of injuries and illness connected to their service and these wars.</p>



<p>And the enduring grief borne by the survivors is a cost of war that we’ll carry as a nation forever.</p>



<p>And so, to every Gold Star family, to every survivor and family member and caregiver: This grateful nation owes you as well as that person you lost.</p>



<p>And we can never repay the sacrifice, but we will never stop trying.&nbsp; We’ll never fail in our duty to remember: With their lives, they bought our freedom.</p>



<p>And so, with our lives, we must always live up to their example &#8212; putting service before self; caring for our neighbors as ourselves; working fervently to bring our union just that much closer to fulfilling the founding creed, as the Secretary said, that all men and women are created equal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve often said that, as a nation, we have many obligations.&nbsp; But the only one that is truly sacred &#8212; the only truly sacred obligation we have &#8212; is to prepare and equip those women and men we send into harm’s way, and care for them and their families when they return home and when they don’t.</p>



<p>This is an obligation that unites Americans and brings us together &#8212; to make sure the women and men who are willing to lay down their lives for us get the very best from us in return.</p>



<p>I want to acknowledge that we’re making progress in key areas like the comprehensive, bipartisan legislation that is advancing in Congress that will deliver healthcare services and benefits to veterans and their survivors impacted by toxic exposures.</p>



<p>We don’t know how many Americans and service members may have died because of what they were exposed to on the battlefield.&nbsp; The toxic smoke from burn pits near where they were based &#8212; burn pits that incinerated the wastes of war, medical and hazardous material, jet fuel, and so much more.</p>



<p>But we have a duty to do right by them.&nbsp; And I am determined to make sure that our brave service families and members that served alongside them do not wait decades for the care and benefits that they deserve.&nbsp; And that’s why &#8212; that’s why we’re working so hard to find out what the facts are.&nbsp; Where we can still save lives, we have to act.</p>



<p>All of us also have a duty to renew our commitment to the foundational values of our nation, in their honor &#8212; for those are the values that have inspired generation after generation to service.</p>



<p>On Friday, I spoke at the graduation and commissioning of &#8212; ceremony of the U.S. Naval Academy.&nbsp; I had an opportunity to do that before as well.&nbsp; It was a remarkable experience again, an honor, looking out at those young men and women &#8212; newly commissioned officers &#8212; embarking on a life of service.</p>



<p>They hold before them the example of the heroes who have gone before them &#8212; many of you are family members &#8212; heroes who have answered duty’s call at Lexington and Concord, Antietam and Gettysburg, Belleau Woods and thee Battle of the Bulge, in Korea and Vietnam and Afghanistan, Iraq, and so many other places around the world &#8212; so many of whom never returned home, including the legacy of all those held prisoners of war or who are still missing in action.</p>



<p>To be here today, soon after that joyful celebration at the Academy, is a bracing reminder of all that we ask of our service members and their families &#8212; for it’s on the strong shoulders and noble spirits of our service members that our freedom is built, our democracy sustained.</p>



<p>And in this moment, when a war of aggression is once more being waged by Russia to snuff out the freedom, the democracy, the very culture and identity of neighboring Ukraine, we so &#8212; we see so clearly all that’s at stake.</p>



<p>Freedom has never been free.&nbsp; Democracy has always required champions.</p>



<p>And, today, in the perennial struggle for democracy and freedom, Ukraine and its people are on the frontlines fighting to save their nation.</p>



<p>But their fight is part of a larger fight that unites all people.&nbsp; It is a fight that so many of the patriots, whose eternal rest is here in these hallowed grounds, were part of.</p>



<p>A battle between democracy and autocracy, between liberty and repression, between appetites and ambition of a few who forever seek to dominate the lives and liberties of many.</p>



<p>A battle for essential democratic principles &#8212; the rule of law, free and fair elections, freedom to speak and write and to assemble, freedom to worship as one chooses, freedom of the press &#8212; principles that are essential for a free society.</p>



<p>You’ve heard this a lot.&nbsp; You’ve heard this a lot over the years, but we’re now realizing how real it is around the world in so many countries as I speak.&nbsp; These are the foundations of our great experiment, but they are never guaranteed, even here in America.</p>



<p>Every generation has to defeat democracy’s mortal foes.&nbsp; And into every generation, heroes are born, willing to shed their blood for that which they and we hold dear.</p>



<p>Ladies and gentlemen, today we remember and we reaffirm: Freedom is worth the sacrifice.&nbsp; Democracy is not perfect; it’s never been good &#8212; perfect.&nbsp; But it’s worth fighting for; if necessary, worth dying for.</p>



<p>It’s more than just our form of government, it is part of the very soul of America.&nbsp; The soul of America.</p>



<p>Our democracy is our greatest gift as a nation, made holy by those we’ve lost along the way.&nbsp; Our democracy is how we undertake the constant work of perfecting the union &#8212; and we have not perfected it, but we’ve never stopped trying; of opening the doors wider of opportunity and prosperity and justice for people everywhere.</p>



<p>Our democracy is how we endure through every challenge, overcome every obstacle we faced through the last 246 years of self-government, and how we’ve come back stronger than before.</p>



<p>We must never walk away from that.&nbsp; We must never betray the lives laid down to make our nation a beacon to the world &#8212; a  citadel of liberty and justice for everybody.</p>



<p>This is the mission of our time.&nbsp; Our memorial to them must not be just a day when we pause and pray, it must be a daily commitment to act, to come together, to be worthy of the price that was paid.</p>



<p>May God bring comfort to all those who mourn.&nbsp; May God bless our Gold Star families and survivors.&nbsp; And please, God, protect our troops.&nbsp;</p>



<p>God bless America and all of you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>1:09 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Marine One&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/30/remarks-by-president-biden-after-marine-one-arrival-10/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 18:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 9:15 A.M. EDT Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good morning, Mr. President.&#160; Do you feel more motivated to get action on guns now? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, I’ve been pretty motivated all along.&#160; You know, the folks &#8212; the folks who were victimized there, and their families, they spent 3 hours and 40 minutes with me.&#160; And they&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>9:15 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good morning, Mr. President.&nbsp; Do you feel more motivated to get action on guns now?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I’ve been pretty motivated all along.&nbsp; You know, the folks &#8212; the folks who were victimized there, and their families, they spent 3 hours and 40 minutes with me.&nbsp; And they waited all that time, and some came two hours early.</p>



<p>And &#8212; but the pain is palpable.&nbsp; And I think a lot of it is unnecessary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I’m going to continue to push, and we’ll see how this works.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to send long-range rocket systems to Ukraine?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We’re not going to send to Ukraine rocket systems that can strike into Russia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, do you think there is anything different in how Republicans will approach the gun reform question now, given the circumstances?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Since I haven’t spoken to them, I don’t know.&nbsp; But my guess is, if they have &#8212; if they &#8212; yes, I think they’re going to have to take a hard look.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there one element &#8212; is it aid, is it red flag, is it some component that you think could be most successful now?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, that’s hard to say because I have not been negotiating with any of the Republicans yet.&nbsp; And I deliberately did not engage in a debate about that with any Republican in &#8212; when we were down consoling the families in Texas.&nbsp; So I don’t &#8212; I don’t know what is the most &#8212; how far it goes.</p>



<p>I know that it makes no sense to be able to purchase something that can fire up to 300 rounds.&nbsp; I know it makes &#8212; and I know what happened when we had rational action before, back in &#8212; when the crime bill was &#8212; the law that got passed.&nbsp; It did significantly cut down mass murders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so there’s only one reason for something that can fire, you know, 100 shots.</p>



<p>I mean &#8212; and I’ll just conclude with this: Look, when I first started doing hearings on the issue of what rational gun laws should be, it was during a period when I was a senator and the death rate was going up.&nbsp; Not that many more people were being shot, but the death rate was up.&nbsp; And when I think of &#8212; I’m not sure, I think it was (inaudible) hospital in New York &#8212; whatever the largest trauma hospital is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I sat with a trauma doctor, and I asked him &#8212; I said, “What’s the difference?&nbsp; Why are so many people…” &#8212; and not that many more people were being shot.&nbsp; This is now 20 years ago, or 25 years.&nbsp; I said, “Why are they dying?”&nbsp; And they showed me x-rays.&nbsp; He said, “A .22-caliber bullet will lodge in the lung, and we can probably get it out, may be able to get it, and save the life.&nbsp; A 9mm bullet blows the lung out of the body.”</p>



<p>So the idea of these high-caliber weapons is of &#8212; there’s simply no rational basis for it in terms of thinking about self-protection, hunting.&nbsp; I mean, I just &#8212; and remember, the Constitution, the Second Amendment was never absolute.&nbsp; You couldn’t buy a cannon when the Second Amendment was passed.&nbsp; You couldn’t go out and purchase a lot of weapons.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And those who &#8212; not many are saying it anymore, but there was a while there where people were saying that, you know, the Tree of Liberty is watered with the blood of patriots, and what we have to do is you have to be able to take on the government when they’re wrong.&nbsp; Well, to do that, you need an F-15, you know?&nbsp; Or you need an Abrams tank.</p>



<p>I mean &#8212; so, it’s just &#8212; as I say, I think thing &#8212; I think things have gotten so bad that everybody is getting more rational about it.&nbsp; At least that’s my hope and prayer.</p>



<p>I’ve got Gold Star moms in there, so I got to go in.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, I know you want Congress to act, but do you believe that as President you have a particular responsibility now?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, I know I have it, but I &#8212; but there’s a Constitution.&nbsp; I can’t dictate this stuff.&nbsp; I can do the things that I’ve done.&nbsp; And any executive action I can take, I’ll continue to take.&nbsp; But I can’t outlaw a weapon.&nbsp; I can’t, you know, change the background checks.&nbsp; I can’t do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, my whole career, I’ve been doing it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And persuasion?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Persuasion, yeah.&nbsp; But, you know, there’s been a few things happening.&nbsp; I know you’ve noticed it.&nbsp; You’ve had to travel with me.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; McConnell has ordered a directive to Senator Cornyn to search for a compromise.&nbsp; Do you really think there’s something there?&nbsp; Or are they just making noise?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, I don’t know, but I think there’s a realization on the part of rational Republicans &#8212; and I think Senator McConnell is a rational Republican; I think Cornyn is as well.&nbsp; I think there’s a recognition in their part that they &#8212; we can’t continue like this.&nbsp; We can’t do this.</p>



<p>I’ve got to go in.&nbsp; I’ve got the Gold Star parents.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>9:20 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New&#160;Zealand</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/28/statement-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-jacinda-ardern-of-new-zealand/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 01:43:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, May 31, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand to the White House, for the first visit of a leader from New Zealand since 2014. The President and Prime Minister will continue to advance the U.S.-New Zealand partnership and their shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, May 31, President Biden will welcome Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand to the White House, for the first visit of a leader from New Zealand since 2014. The President and Prime Minister will continue to advance the U.S.-New Zealand partnership and their shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific. The two Leaders will discuss strengthening cooperation to support the Pacific Islands region, and our work together on a range of issues, including the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, addressing the climate crisis, and countering terrorism and radicalization to violence both off and online. Vice President Harris will also meet with Prime Minister Ardern at the White House.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden at the University of Delaware Commencement&#160;Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/28/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-university-of-delaware-commencement-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 20:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[University of DelawareNewark, Delaware 10:24 A.M. EDT AUDIENCE:&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe! THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; Thank you all.&#160; Is this working?&#160; There you go. Before you all sit down completely, the reason why you’re here is because of all of those people up in the stands.&#160; Stand up&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">University of Delaware<br>Newark, Delaware</p>



<p>10:24 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you all.&nbsp; Is this working?&nbsp; There you go.</p>



<p>Before you all sit down completely, the reason why you’re here is because of all of those people up in the stands.&nbsp; Stand up and give your parents and your grandparents, and those who got you, an applause.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You owe them!&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to all the parents up in the stands, this may be the best day of all.&nbsp; No more tuition!&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; But probably all of them are going to graduate school, so that probably won’t work.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Dr.&nbsp;Assanis, trustees, faculty, the staff; my good friend &#8212; and he is my really good friend for a long time &#8212; Tommy &#8212; I call him “Tommy” &#8212; but Tom Carper &#8212; Senator Carper.&nbsp; Lisa Blunt Rochester, our congresswoman who can preach &#8212; this woman can preach.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And is really good.&nbsp; She’s a great congresswoman.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the Class of 2022: Congratulations!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I know they’ve been recognized already, but I can’t &#8212; yesterday, I did the commencement at the Naval Academy, and it reminds me today: I want a special cons- &#8212; special congratulations to the veterans who are graduating today, all those who are being commissioned in the United States military.&nbsp; Would you please stand &#8212; of the graduating class?&nbsp; Stand up if you’re &#8212; (applause) &#8212;</p>



<p>And those of you have served as well in this class, stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And for all those of you who are joining the service or about to join the finest group of warriors the world has ever seen &#8212; and that’s not hyperbole; that’s literally true.&nbsp; So thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jill &#8212; better known as Dr. Biden &#8212; I happen to be her husband &#8212; not only earned her undergraduate degree here,</p>



<p>she also got her doctorate degree here.&nbsp; She got a master’s in between, somewhere else.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And the First Lady has continued to work full-time as a professor while being the First Lady.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, Gerret, you and I have something in common, pal: We both married way above our station.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Not only can she speak five different languages, whatever language she’s speaking, you better damn well listen, man.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, I’m telling you, thank you.</p>



<p>And I want to say this is a special day for my sister Valerie and I.&nbsp; She’s my best friend in the world.&nbsp; She graduated here with honors.&nbsp; I graduated.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Oh, that’s literally true.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And we took the same damn classes.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>We used to be three years apart, and now Val is 22 years&nbsp;</p>



<p>younger than I am.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But it feels like coming home because it is &#8212; this is home.&nbsp; This is home.</p>



<p>I once walked this campus as you did.&nbsp; Took the classes in the same classrooms you’ve taken classes.&nbsp; Walked the graduation ceremony just as you’re walking today.<a>&nbsp; Some of the best and most important years of my life were spent here.</a></p>



<p>And I had the opportunity to be taught by some great professors.&nbsp; I’ll bet every one of you already can name one or two professors that’s changed your life, that’s had an impact on you in a fundamental way.&nbsp; I was lucky &#8212; I graduated with a dual degree in history and political science.&nbsp; If you add up both my GPAs in each of those, I was probably a 4.0.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside,&nbsp;Dr. Dolan, from the political science department &#8212; I think he could picture me here in the endzone, maybe catching a pass over my left shoulder, but I doubt whether ever the hell he thought I’d be standing here as President of the United States.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Although,&nbsp;Dr. Ingersoll is the one &#8212; you know, professors make a difference.&nbsp; I was asked to seek the nomination by a group of people I won’t bore you with, and I thought it was a little off the wall that I was &#8212; I wasn’t even old enough.&nbsp; And I turned &#8212; it was after a Democratic off-year convention.&nbsp; And I turned to the Chief Justice, who was retired &#8212; from a family that has more senators than any family in American history: former Justice Tunnell.</p>



<p>And I said, “Mr. Justice, I’m not old enough.”&nbsp; He said, “You obviously didn’t do well in constitutional law, Joe.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, the Constitution says you need to be 30 to be sworn in, but you can be elected at any age they want to elect you.&nbsp; So why the hell I did it, I wasn’t sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I got in a car in Dover, and I drove straight to the campus.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; And I looked up Dr. Ingersoll, one of my professors that I admired most; taught political philosophy.</p>



<p>And I told him the dilemma, because I hadn’t thought about that at all at the time.&nbsp; I really hadn’t.&nbsp; And he looked at me and he said, “Joe, remember what Plato said.”&nbsp; I’m thinking, “What the hell did Plato say?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And he paraphrased it.&nbsp; And he said: The penalty good people pay for not being involved in politics is being governed by people worse than themselves.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, it’s what I want to talk to you all about today.&nbsp; Though I think even my professors would be surprised if there’s a Biden School of Public Policy and Administration at the University of Delaware.&nbsp; Thank you, Tatiana.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>But no one is more surprised than me.&nbsp; And while I had graduated before I &#8212; he started teaching, I wanted to acknowledge the respect and the &#8212; that I had for Dr. James Newton, a trailblazer in Black American studies and the civil rights across our nation.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>If there’s one message&nbsp;I hope you take from me today,</p>



<p>it’s: This is no time to be on the sidelines.&nbsp; It’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; I mean it from the bottom of my heart.</p>



<p>We need all of you to get engaged in public life and the life of this nation.</p>



<p>Because here’s the simple truth: You’re graduating and entering a world at a momentous and consequential and defining time.</p>



<p>The next 10 years of your life are going to determine what the next 50 years of this nation are going to look like.&nbsp; We’re at one of those inflection points in history where things are changing so fundamentally that we have to act.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like the Americans in the 1850s and ‘60s &#8212; we had to decide whether to preserve slavery or become a free nation &#8212; truly free.</p>



<p>Like Americans in the ‘30s and ‘40s &#8212; President Roosevelt had said they had a “rendezvous with destiny,” at home and abroad.</p>



<p>Like Americans in the ‘60s, in my generation &#8212; when I sat where you’re sitting in 1965&nbsp;&#8212;&nbsp;were bitterly divided over the war in Vietnam.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We watched our heroes &#8212; two Kennedys and a King &#8212; gunned down by assassins and, still, we chose to expand the possibilities of America by breaking down unjust barriers&nbsp;</p>



<p>of civil rights and voting rights.</p>



<p>Well, now, it’s your hour.&nbsp; The challenges are immense &#8212; foreign and domestic &#8212; but so are the possibilities.</p>



<p>I spent time &#8212; more time with Xi Jinping than any world leader has &#8212; over 76 hours.&nbsp; We traveled 17,000 miles in China and the United States together.&nbsp; We were on the Tibetan Plateau, and he turned to me and said, “Can you define America for me?”&nbsp; And I said, “Yes, I can, in one word: possibilities.”&nbsp; Everything is possible in America.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Everything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe that with every fiber of my being this is a decisive decade for America, at a time when we can choose the future we want, at a time when we must decide that darkness will not prevail over light.</p>



<p>In the last five years since many of you were in high school, America has faced some of its most difficult tests.</p>



<p>A global pandemic ended a million lives in America alone &#8212; a million &#8212; and upended, according to most studies, the lives of &#8212; personal lives of at least another 9 million children and family members, and many of your lives.</p>



<p>And a crisis of faith in the institutions that have &#8212; however flawed they may be &#8212; serve as the infrastructure for the American experiment in liberty and self-government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve defined to my foreign colleagues and heads of state America when I was at the G7.&nbsp; I said America is unique in the world.&nbsp; We’re the only nation in the world founded on an idea.&nbsp; Every other nation is founded on ethnicity, religion, geography.&nbsp; But only America is founded on an idea: We hold these truths to be self-evident that all women and men are created equal, endowed by their Creator with certain inalienable rights &#8212; life, liberty, the pursuit of happiness.</p>



<p>We say it so often.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never met the goal, but we&#8217;ve never walked away from it &#8212; ever.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And each generation has brought us closer to the goal.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what you&#8217;ve been through the last four years &#8212; and I&#8217;m not being solicitous with you &#8212; what you’ve been through the last four years, you could not have imagined when you were graduating from high school: campus shutdowns, classes on Zoom, the world turned upside down.</p>



<p>But you got through it.&nbsp; And it took an extraordinary commitment, determination, and resolve to do it.&nbsp; You should be proud you overcame it all to see this day.&nbsp; Your generation, and this class, can do anything.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I decided to seek the presidency.&nbsp; When I had concluded &#8212; I was a professor at Penn &#8212; I was never going to run again.&nbsp; And I meant that from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp; I had just lost my son Beau.&nbsp; And I had no interest whatsoever.&nbsp; And I was teaching at Penn.&nbsp; And then, Charlottesville.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the United States of America, in the 20th century &#8212; 21st century &#8212; people coming out of fields at night carrying torches.</p>



<p>Close your eyes.&nbsp; Remember what you saw.&nbsp; Their veins bulging, preaching the same hate &#8212; white supremacy; chanting the same Nazi phrases &#8212; not figuratively, literally &#8212; that were being chanted in the ‘30s in Europe.&nbsp; Torches lit again.</p>



<p>You know, when I was a young senator, I was proud to be the senator who actually got Strom Thurmond to vote for the Voting Rights Act.&nbsp; I got it extended 25 years, and I thought, “You can bury hate.&nbsp; You can wipe it out.”&nbsp; But I learned a lesson: You can&#8217;t eliminate hate.&nbsp; It only hides when it&#8217;s defeated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But when the prominent leaders are leader- &#8212; breathe oxygen under the rocks it&#8217;s hiding in, it takes on a new life.&nbsp; It comes roaring back out in ways, I must tell you, I never thought would happen.&nbsp; Because I got into politics sitting where you&#8217;re sitting because of civil rights in Delaware.</p>



<p>And then, nearly four years later, a mob of insurrectionists stormed the Capitol &#8212; the very citadel of democracy.</p>



<p>Imagine what you&#8217;d be thinking today if you had heard this morning, before you got here, that a group of a thousand people broke down the doors of the Parliament in Great Britain, killed two police officers, smashed and ransacked the office of members of the British Parliament, or any other.&nbsp; What would you think?&nbsp; What would you think?</p>



<p>And then, just this month, we thought that white supremacy</p>



<p>was finally being got hold of.</p>



<p>Buffalo, New York: A shopping center in a Black community.&nbsp; I went and met with every one of those parents, every one of those families.</p>



<p>And now, tomorrow, I&#8217;ll be heli- &#8212; I&#8217;ll be heading to Uvalde, Texas, to meet with each of those families.</p>



<p>And as I speak, those parents are literally preparing to bury their children in the United States of America &#8212; to bury their children.&nbsp; There’s too much violence, too much fear, too much grief.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s be clear: Evil came to that elementary school classroom in Texas, to that grocery store in New York, to far too many places where innocents have died.</p>



<p>In the face of such destructive forces, we have to stand stronger.&nbsp; We must stand stronger.&nbsp; We cannot outlaw tragedy, I know, but we can make America safer.</p>



<p>We can finally do what we have to do to protect the lives of the people and of our children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I call on all Americans this hour to join hands and make your voices heard and work together to make this nation what it can and should be.</p>



<p>I know we can do this.&nbsp; We have done it before.&nbsp; You and I acted as “We the People” seeking a more perfect union.</p>



<p>Always remember: Democracy is a human enterprise.&nbsp; We do many things well.&nbsp; Sometimes we fall short.&nbsp; That&#8217;s true in our own lives; it’s true in the life of the nation.&nbsp; And yet democracy makes progress possible.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And progress comes when we begin to see each other again, not as enemies but as neighbors.</p>



<p>When I spoke yesterday at Annapolis, I finished by talking about my friend &#8212; he was my close friend; on his deathbed, asked me to do his eulogy &#8212; who would scream at each other and holler like hell at one another: John McCain.&nbsp; Very different views.&nbsp; We still loved one another.</p>



<p>Not as mindless, competing factions, but as fellow citizens.&nbsp; Learned anew, in their own &#8212; on their own time that democracy is fragile, democracy is precious, but it&#8217;s also precarious.</p>



<p>Truth is truth.&nbsp; Lies are lies.&nbsp; And the truth is: We have a solemn duty to keep the flame of liberty burning.&nbsp; This is not about blue and red, rural and urban.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about America.&nbsp; The right to govern ourselves.&nbsp; The right to determine our own destinies, to overcome division and despair, and to meet the challenges of our time with grit and, maybe equally important, with some grace.&nbsp; To press ahead determined, resolved, and full of hope.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not easy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s never been.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s who we are &#8212; people united by a idea &#8212; by an idea, unbending in the face of adversity, and devoted to creating and sustaining the beloved nation of ours.</p>



<p>You don’t have to take my word for it.&nbsp; Frederick Douglass said it better.&nbsp; He said, “No soil is better adapted to growth of reform than [the] American soil.”</p>



<p>The women of Seneca Falls call for suffrage by writing, “We hold these truths to be self-evident that all&nbsp;<em>women</em>&nbsp;and men are created equal.”</p>



<p>Dr. King said his dream of liberty for all was deeply rooted in the American Dream &#8212; the right to life, liberty, the pursuit of happiness; the right to rise in the world as far as your talent can take you, unlimited by unfair barriers of privilege and power.</p>



<p>Such are the principles of democracy, and such are the principles of America.</p>



<p>And I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m exercising hyperbole.&nbsp; I’ve been around too long.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what is at stake today.</p>



<p>The question we face is nothing less than: “Who are we?”&nbsp; “What do we stand for?”&nbsp; “What do we believe?”&nbsp; And maybe more importantly, “Who are we going to be?”</p>



<p>And while this can feel like a very dark moment in America,</p>



<p>I&#8217;m optimistic.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve never been more optimistic in my entire life.&nbsp; And here&#8217;s why &#8212; and I mean this, my word as a Biden.</p>



<p>I mean it.&nbsp; Because of you &#8212; this generation, your generation &#8212; it makes me more optimistic.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve said it many times, as I look at my granddaughters who all graduated from universities and about to enter them &#8212; I&#8217;ll say it again today: Your generation is the most generous, the most tolerant, the least prejudiced, the best-educated generation this nation has ever known.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a simple fact.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And it’s your generation, more than anyone else, who will have to answer the question, “Who are we?”&nbsp; “What do we stand for?”&nbsp; “What do we believe?”&nbsp; “Who will we be?”</p>



<p>Progress in our country has always been met with ferocious pushback from the oldest and darkest forces in America.&nbsp; Always.</p>



<p>We should not be surprised that these same forces are fighting back again, preying on hopelessness and despair; demonizing people who don&#8217;t look like them; doing everything, no matter how desperate, to hold on to power.</p>



<p>This was never going to be an easy battle, and it never has been, because it&#8217;s occurred before in America.</p>



<p>The oldest and darkest forces in the past may believe they&#8217;ll determine America&#8217;s future.&nbsp; But I promise you &#8212; remember I said this, if you remember nothing that I said at this graduation: They are wrong.&nbsp; Wrong, wrong, wrong.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will, you will &#8212; in this moment, in this battle, we will not lose the right to vote, the right to self-determination, the right to choose, the right to be you, and marry the person you love.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We must and will stand together to save the planet and preserve democracy.</p>



<p>When America was literally facing war with itself when Lincoln was President &#8212; excuse me &#8212; when Lincoln was President, Lincoln reminded us.&nbsp; He said, “Let&#8217;s have faith that right makes might.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Right makes might.</p>



<p>This is an essential principle of the soul of America.&nbsp; I mean it sincerely &#8212; the soul of America.&nbsp; The principle must guide you and your lives regardless of your politics &#8211;conservative or liberal &#8212; but just human decency.&nbsp; The principle that guides me and my administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For we can and will and should disagree about the means of governance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what democracy is about as well.&nbsp; But we have to be unified in the purpose of America: to create possibility, prosperity; protect decency and dignity; to be free and fair.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just think about who we are.&nbsp; The bloodiest civil wars led the abolition of slavery.&nbsp; Generation after generation who stood against totalitarianism and terror.</p>



<p>And while we, the people, have undertaken great enterprises when building interstates, to finding vaccines, to going to the stars &#8212; in all these moments, we were driven, as we are today, by the most American of principles: that we the people have created the strongest, freest, most prosperous nation the world has ever known.&nbsp; And again, that is not hyperbole, it&#8217;s a fact.</p>



<p>Now, in this moment, we face our own test: to resolve &#8212; a test of resolve, a test of conscience, a test of history itself.</p>



<p>No generation gets to choose what world they graduate into.&nbsp; None.&nbsp; But a few &#8212; a few generations enter at a point in history where they have the power to change the trajectory of a nation.&nbsp; And you can.</p>



<p>When I sat where you are, in the mid-‘60s, I believed we could.&nbsp; And we did, through civil rights, change the trajectory of the nation.</p>



<p>And now I know that may feel like an added burden on top of all you&#8217;ve already been through.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not saying you have to shoulder the burden on your own.&nbsp; The task at hand and the task ahead is the work of all of us.&nbsp; What I am saying is you represent the best of us.&nbsp; You literally represent the best of us &#8212; a better America than we are today.</p>



<p>A generation &#8212; your generation will not be ignored, will not be shunned, and will not be silenced.&nbsp; You have an opportunity to not only reaffirm but to breathe new life into America&#8217;s most important values: equality, fairness, justice.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s what I felt like all those years ago when I sat where you are sitting today.&nbsp; And I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t think I was going to be President of the United States.&nbsp; It wasn’t like “I’m going to be President” &#8212; although I loved reading the biographies.&nbsp; Everybody knew I was going to be President when I was in high school.&nbsp; I had no idea of it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But for all the uncertainty in the world, this university gave me confidence in myself to engage, to get involved, because I believed I could make a difference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My sister Valerie and I come from very modest backgrounds.&nbsp; A three-bedroom, split-level home in a decent neighborhood; four kids and a grandpop living with us.&nbsp; We never felt we were poor, but we never had &#8212; we had trouble making the tuition, which was 300 bucks a year.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Or semester, I should say.</p>



<p>I hope you feel that way today, though, that you can change things.&nbsp; Because that&#8217;s what I see in all of you.&nbsp; You can make the difference.&nbsp; You can lift the country up.&nbsp; You can meet the challenges of our time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve always believed this nation can be defined by one word, as I said before: possibilities.&nbsp; It&#8217;s still true today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so to the University Class of 2022, there is no limit on what you can do.&nbsp; I promise you.</p>



<p>So get going, for God&#8217;s sake.&nbsp; Godspeed on your journey.&nbsp; Keep the faith.&nbsp; And take it back &#8212; please.&nbsp; This is yours.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Take it back!&nbsp; We need you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; I really mean it &#8212; I believe in you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>10:51 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By Vice President Harris At The Memorial Service For Mrs. Ruth&#160;Whitfield</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/28/remarks-by-vice-president-harrisat-the-memorial-service-for-mrs-ruth-e-whitfield/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mt. Olive Baptist ChurchBuffalo, New York THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; I’m not going to say anything about Reverend Sharpton right now.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160;&#160;Good afternoon, church.&#160;AUDIENCE:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; To the Whitfield family; the father of the Whitfield family, Mr. Whitfield.&#160; (Applause.)&#160;The pain that this family is feeling right now, and the nine other families here in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Mt. Olive Baptist Church<br><em>Buffalo, New York</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m not going to say anything about Reverend Sharpton right now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Good afternoon, church.<br>&nbsp;<br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; To the Whitfield family; the father of the Whitfield family, Mr. Whitfield.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>The pain that this family is feeling right now, and the nine other families here in Buffalo, I cannot even begin to express our collective pain as a nation for what you are feeling in such an extreme way &#8212; to not only lose someone that you love, but through an act of extreme violence and hate.&nbsp; And I do believe that our nation right now is experiencing an epidemic of hate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as we know and Scripture teaches us, when we talk about strength &#8212; the strength of personality, the strength of spirit, the strength of faith &#8212; I think we all know that a true measure of strength is not based on who you beat down, it&#8217;s based on who you lift up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Who you lift up.<br>&nbsp;<br>And it means then also, in that strength, understanding we will not allow small people to create fear in our communities; that we will not be afraid to stand up for what is right, to speak truth even when it may be difficult to hear and speak.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s a through-line &#8212; what happened here in Buffalo, in Texas, in Atlanta, in Orlando; what happened at the synagogues.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so this is a moment that requires all good people, all God-loving people to stand up and say we will not stand for this.&nbsp; Enough is enough.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We will come together based on what we all know we have in common, and we will not let those people who are motivated by hate separate us or make us feel fear.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I&#8217;m here to say that we are all in this together.&nbsp; No one should ever be made to fight alone.&nbsp; We are stronger than those who would try to hurt us think that we are.&nbsp; We are strong.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are strong in our faith.&nbsp; We are strong in our belief about what is right and our determination to act, to ensure that we protect all those who deserve to be protected; that we see all those who deserve to be seen; that we hear the voices of the people; and that we rise up in solidarity to speak out against this and to speak to our better angels.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END<br>&nbsp;<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Air Force Two&#160;Departure </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/28/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-air-force-two-departure-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 14:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Buffalo, New York Q    Madam Vice President, what was your message to the families? THE VICE PRESIDENT:  You know, I met with all the families.  And first of all, to lose a loved one unexpectedly and because of such an extreme act of violence and hate, the tragedy of it is beyond description.  And so, first, I expressed our condolences. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Buffalo, New York</em></p>



<p>Q    Madam Vice President, what was your message to the families?<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  You know, I met with all the families.  And first of all, to lose a loved one unexpectedly and because of such an extreme act of violence and hate, the tragedy of it is beyond description. <br> <br>And so, first, I expressed our condolences.  But also, when we think about what&#8217;s been happening &#8212; and you&#8217;ve heard me say it before &#8212; I really do think we need to look at the fact that this year alone, I&#8217;m told that we&#8217;ve had over 200 mass shootings &#8212; over 200 &#8212; and we’re barely halfway through the year.<br> <br>And when we&#8217;re looking at an epidemic of hate where people are being targeted just because of who they are, I think we all have to stand back and say, “Wait, enough.  Enough is enough.  A harm against any one of us is a harm against all of us.  No one should be left to fight alone.”  And we got to deal with this, and we have to deal with it in a number of ways.<br> <br>But I went through it even at the church.  You look at it &#8212; everything from Buffalo to what’s happened to those babies and the teachers being killed in Texas, the funerals &#8212; haven’t even really begun in terms of mourning that loss. <br> <br>We’re looking at &#8212; on the heels of Atlanta, just a year ago; Orlando; the Tree of Life.<br> <br>We have to agree that if we are to be strong as a nation, we must stand strong, identifying our diversity as our unity.  And that anyone who is trying to break that down, it’s hurting us as a country and as individuals who should identify as one, as a country, as Americans.<br> <br>So I think of it in a number of ways.  There is the tragedy of the personal loss that each of these families has made.  Mrs. Whitfield &#8212; the funeral today &#8212; what a beautiful woman who lived an extraordinary life. <br> <br>I met with the other families.  There were community leaders.  There were &#8212; a father of an infant.  And then, of course, the President is going to go tomorrow to Texas and be with the families who have lost their babies at a school.<br> <br>We have to &#8212; everybody has got to stand up and agree that this should not be happening in our country and that we should have the courage to do something about it. <br> <br>On the issue of gun violence, I will say as I said countless times: We are not sitting around waiting to figure out what the solution looks like.  You know, we&#8217;re not looking for a vaccine.  We know what works on this.  It includes: Let&#8217;s have an assault weapons ban.  You know what an assault weapon is?  You know how an assault weapon was designed?  It was designed for a specific purpose: to kill a lot of human beings quickly.  An assault weapon is a weapon of war with no place &#8212; no place in a civil society. <br> <br>Background checks.  Why should anyone be able to buy a weapon that can kill other human beings without at least knowing, hey, has that person committed a violent crime before?  Are they a threat against themselves or others?  That&#8217;s just reasonable.  It’s just reasonable.  We do that, saying you have to have a license to drive a car.  You have to be of a certain age to buy, you know, a six-pack.<br> <br>We are a society that is governed by rules, most of which were designed &#8212; those rules &#8212; to, at the very height of the purpose, prevent against harm, to promote safety, and to have a common order that we all agree a civilized society should agree to that ensures that there will be safety and that we can prevent chaos. <br> <br>When we&#8217;ve had over 200 mass shootings in our country already and we are barely in June, let’s all agree we got to do something, and it’s within our power to do it.  Congress needs to act.  And what I know is that we also have to come together as one nation, undivided, standing with each other.<br> <br>                          END<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation: Adjusting Imports of Steel Into the United&#160;States&#160;(Ukraine)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/27/a-proclamation-adjusting-imports-of-steel-into-the-united-states-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 21:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1.&#160; On January 11, 2018, the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) transmitted to the President a report on the Secretary&#8217;s investigation into the effect of imports of steel mill articles (steel articles) on the national security of the United States under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended (19 U.S.C. 1862). &#160;The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1.&nbsp; On January 11, 2018, the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) transmitted to the President a report on the Secretary&#8217;s investigation into the effect of imports of steel mill articles (steel articles) on the national security of the United States under section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended (19 U.S.C. 1862). &nbsp;The Secretary found and advised the President of his opinion that steel articles are being imported into the United States in such quantities and under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security of the United States.</p>



<p>2.&nbsp; In Proclamation 9705 of March 8, 2018 (Adjusting Imports of Steel Into the United States), the President concurred in the Secretary&#8217;s finding that steel articles, as defined in clause 1 of Proclamation 9705, as amended by clause 8 of Proclamation 9711 of March 22, 2018 (Adjusting Imports of Steel Into the United States), are being imported into the United States in such quantities and under such circumstances as to threaten to impair the national security of the United States, and decided to adjust the imports of those steel articles by imposing a 25 percent ad valorem tariff on such articles imported from all countries except Canada and Mexico. &nbsp;The proclamation further stated that any country with which we have a security relationship is welcome to discuss with the United States alternative ways to address the threatened impairment of the national security caused by imports from that country, and noted that, should the United States and any such country arrive at a satisfactory alternative means to address the threat to the national security such that the President determines that imports from that country no longer threaten to impair the national security, the President may remove or modify the restriction on steel articles imports from that country and, if necessary, adjust the tariff as it applies to other countries, as the national security interests of the United&nbsp;States require.</p>



<p>3.&nbsp; The United States and Ukraine have developed a close security relationship.&nbsp; Ukraine has expressed its willingness to work with the United States to address the global excess capacity for producing steel. &nbsp;Ukraine&#8217;s steel industry has been significantly disrupted by the Russian Federation&#8217;s unjustified, unprovoked, unyielding, and unconscionable war against Ukraine. &nbsp;The significant disruption in Ukraine&#8217;s steel production is expected to decrease the total amount of steel produced by Ukraine as well as the amount of steel imported into the United&nbsp;States from Ukraine, which in 2021 accounted for less than 1 percent of all steel imports into the United States.&nbsp; At the same time, the steel industry has been historically important to Ukraine, and both the United States and Ukraine have an interest in maintaining that industry as an economic lifeline while the country recovers.</p>



<p>4.&nbsp; The United States and Ukraine have recently engaged in broad security discussions.&nbsp; The current disruption of Ukrainian steel production has been part of those discussions, and the ongoing discussion is anticipated to include alternative measures to prevent imports of steel from Ukraine from threatening the national security of the United States as Ukraine&#8217;s steel production recovers from the significant disruption caused by the war.</p>



<p>5.&nbsp; In light of the ongoing security discussions and significant disruption of Ukraine&#8217;s ability to produce steel, I conclude that Ukraine&#8217;s present situation presents a special case.&nbsp; I have determined to suspend the tariffs set forth in Proclamation 9705 for the import of steel articles and derivative steel articles from Ukraine for 1 year.&nbsp; The Secretary shall monitor the situation in the domestic steel industry and developments in Ukraine&#8217;s steel industry and inform me of any need to terminate or extend this suspension.</p>



<p><a>6.&nbsp; </a>In light of my determination to adjust the tariff proclaimed in Proclamation 9705 as applied to eligible steel articles and derivative steel articles that are the product of Ukraine, I have considered whether it is necessary and appropriate in light of our national security interests to make any corresponding adjustments to such tariff as it applies to products of other countries.&nbsp; I have determined that it is necessary and appropriate, at this time, to maintain the current tariff level as it applies to products of other countries.</p>



<p>7.&nbsp; Section 232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended, authorizes the President to take action to adjust the imports of an article and its derivatives that are being imported into the United States in such quantities or under such circumstances as&nbsp;to threaten to impair the national security.</p>



<p>8.&nbsp; Section 604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (19&nbsp;U.S.C. 2483), authorizes the President to embody in the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTSUS) the substance of statutes affecting import treatment, and actions thereunder, including the removal, modification, continuance, or imposition of any rate of duty or other import restriction.</p>



<p>Now, Therefore, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United&nbsp;States of America, by the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;232 of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, as amended, section 301 of title 3, United States Code, and section&nbsp;604 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended, do hereby proclaim as follows:</p>



<p>(1)&nbsp; Clause 2 of Proclamation 9705, as amended, is revised to read as follows:&nbsp;</p>



<p>&#8220;(2)(a) &nbsp;In order to establish certain modifications to the duty rate on imports of steel articles, subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS is modified as provided in the Annex to this proclamation and any subsequent proclamations regarding such steel articles.</p>



<p>(b) &nbsp;Except as otherwise provided in this proclamation, or in notices published pursuant to clause 3 of this proclamation, all steel articles imports covered by heading 9903.80.01, in subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS, shall be subject to an additional 25 percent ad valorem rate of duty with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, as follows: &nbsp;(i) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on March 23, 2018, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, South Korea, and the member countries of the European Union; (ii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2018, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, and South Korea; (iii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 13, 2018, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, South Korea, and Turkey; (iv) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on May 20, 2019, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, South Korea, and Turkey; (v) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on May 21, 2019, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea; (vi) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern standard time on January 1, 2022, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea, and except the member countries of the European Union through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.80.65 through 9903.81.19, inclusive; (vii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April 1, 2022, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea, and except the member countries of the European Union through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.80.65 through 9903.81.19, inclusive, and from Japan, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.81.25 through 9903.81.80, inclusive; and (viii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, South Korea, and except from Ukraine through 11:59 p.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2023, and except the member countries of the European Union through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.80.65 through 9903.81.19, inclusive, and from Japan through 11:59 p.m. eastern standard time on December 31, 2023, for steel articles covered by headings 9903.81.25 through 9903.81.80, inclusive. &nbsp;Further, except as otherwise provided in notices published pursuant to clause 3 of this proclamation, all steel articles imports from Turkey covered by heading 9903.80.02, in subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS, shall be subject to a 50 percent ad&nbsp;valorem rate of duty with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on August 13, 2018, and prior to 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on May 21, 2019. &nbsp;All steel articles imports covered by heading 9903.80.61, in subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS, shall be subject to the additional 25 percent ad valorem rate of duty established herein with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern time on the date specified in a determination by the Secretary granting relief. &nbsp;These rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported steel articles, shall apply to imports of steel articles from each country as specified in the preceding three sentences.&#8221;</p>



<p>(2)  The first two sentences of clause 1 of Proclamation 9980 of January 24, 2020 (Adjusting Imports of Derivative Aluminum Articles and Derivative Steel Articles Into the United States), are revised to read as follows:</p>



<p>&#8220;In order to establish increases in the duty rate on imports of certain derivative articles, subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTSUS is modified as provided in Annex I and Annex II to this proclamation. &nbsp;Except as otherwise provided in this proclamation, all imports of derivative aluminum articles specified in Annex I to this proclamation shall be subject to an additional 10 percent ad valorem rate of duty, and all imports of derivative steel articles specified in Annex II to this proclamation shall be subject to an additional 25 percent ad&nbsp;valorem rate of duty, with respect to goods entered for consumption, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, as follows: &nbsp;(i) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern standard time on February 8, 2020, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, <a>the Commonwealth of Australia (Australia)</a>, Canada, and the United Mexican States (Mexico) and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Mexico, and South Korea; (ii) on or after 12:01&nbsp;a.m. eastern standard time on January 1, 2022, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, and Mexico and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex&nbsp;II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Mexico, and South Korea; (iii) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on April 1, 2022, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, and Mexico and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex&nbsp;II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Japan, Mexico, and South Korea; and (iv) on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, these rates of duty, which are in addition to any other duties, fees, exactions, and charges applicable to such imported derivative aluminum articles or steel articles, shall apply to imports of derivative aluminum articles described in Annex I to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, and Mexico, and to imports of derivative steel articles described in Annex&nbsp;II to this proclamation from all countries except Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, the member countries of the European Union, Japan, Mexico, and South Korea, and except from Ukraine through 11:59 p.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2023.&#8221; &nbsp;</p>



<p>(3) &nbsp;Any imports of steel articles from Ukraine that were admitted into a U.S. foreign trade zone under &#8220;privileged foreign status&#8221; as defined in 19 CFR 146.41, prior to 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, shall be subject upon entry for consumption made on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern daylight time on June 1, 2022, to the 25 percent rate of duty imposed by Proclamation 9705, as amended.</p>



<p>(4)&nbsp; Any provision of previous proclamations and Executive&nbsp;Orders that is inconsistent with the actions taken in&nbsp;this proclamation is superseded to the extent of such inconsistency.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this</p>



<p>twenty-seventh day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Call with President Castro of&#160;Honduras</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/27/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-call-with-president-castro-of-honduras/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 21:22:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54281</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris today spoke with President Xiomara Castro of Honduras.  President Castro updated the Vice President on actions she has taken to advance Honduras’ democracy and economy since the Vice President attended her historic inauguration in January 2022.  The Vice President and President Castro discussed deepening cooperation between the United States and Honduras&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">Vice President Kamala Harris today spoke with President Xiomara Castro of Honduras.  President Castro updated the Vice President on actions she has taken to advance Honduras’ democracy and economy since the Vice President attended her historic inauguration in January 2022.  The Vice President and President Castro discussed deepening cooperation between the United States and Honduras across a broad range of issues, including expanding economic opportunity and addressing the root causes of migration.  The Vice President underscored the United States’ commitment to advancing our shared interests together and reiterated her strong support for the partnership between the United States and Honduras. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting to Commemorate National Foster Care&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/27/readout-of-white-house-meeting-to-commemorate-national-foster-care-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 20:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, the White House commemorated National Foster Care Month with a roundtable highlighting seven young people with lived experience in the child welfare system. The meeting was convened by Assistant Secretary of the Administration for Children and Families January Contreras, White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling, White House Office of Management and Budget&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, the White House commemorated National Foster Care Month with a roundtable highlighting seven young people with lived experience in the child welfare system. The meeting was convened by Assistant Secretary of the Administration for Children and Families January Contreras, White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling, White House Office of Management and Budget Associate Director for Education, Income Maintenance and Labor Sherry Lachman, Deputy Assistant to the President for Racial Justice and Equity Chiraag Bains, Deputy Assistant to the President for Economic Mobility Carmel Martin, and Domestic Policy Advisor to Vice President Harris Rohini Kosoglu. The participants came to the White House from Florida, Kentucky, Maine, New Jersey, New York, Virginia, and Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>Participants discussed the importance of increased mental health services and trauma support for children in the child welfare system, the importance of kinship care, sibling connections, peer mentorship, and culturally competent placement, the need for continued resources for foster youth as they transition out of care, and the link between the child welfare system and the criminal justice system. Participants noted the disproportionate impact of the child welfare system on children of color, especially Black and Native youth, and on LGBTQI+ youth.</p>



<p>Administration officials highlighted the President and Vice President’s commitment to child welfare reforms, including the $10 billion increase in funding proposed in the President’s fiscal year 2023 Budget, which includes investments to support prevention and kinship care, expand support for youth aging out of foster care, and reduce reliance on congregate care. Administration officials also highlighted the President’s whole-of-government commitment to equity, strategy to address the national mental health crisis, and resources available to foster youth and transition-aged youth through the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the United&#160;States Naval Academy&#8217;s Class of 2022 Graduation and Commissioning&#160;Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/27/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-united-states-naval-academys-class-of-2022-graduation-and-commissioning-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 17:32:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[10:37 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT: &#160;Hello, Naval Academy!&#160; Whoa.&#160; Before I begin my speech, a thought crossed my mind as I was told the Class of ‘72 is here.&#160; I was appointed to the Academy in 1965 by a senator who I was running against in 1972.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Never planned it that way.&#160; I wasn&#8217;t&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>10:37 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;Hello, Naval Academy!&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before I begin my speech, a thought crossed my mind as I was told the Class of ‘72 is here.&nbsp; I was appointed to the Academy in 1965 by a senator who I was running against in 1972.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Never planned it that way.&nbsp; I wasn&#8217;t old enough to be sworn in.&nbsp; I was only 29 years old when I was running. &nbsp;He was a fine man, and his name was J. Caleb Boggs.</p>



<p>I didn&#8217;t come to the Academy because I wanted to be a football star.&nbsp; And you had a guy named Staubach and Bellino here.&nbsp; So I went to Delaware.</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, the best line of the debate was &#8212; after it was all over, the announcer &#8212; the questioner who was a good guy but supported my opponent &#8212; who was a good man as well, I might add &#8212; and he said, “Senator Boggs, you have anything else you want to say?”&nbsp; And he said, “Yes, just one thing.”&nbsp; And he took the microphone.&nbsp; He said, “You know, Joe, if you had accepted my commission to the Aca- &#8212; my appointment to the Academy,” he said, “you&#8217;d still have one year and three months active duty, and I&#8217;d have no problems right now.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>So, the Class of ’72 &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; welcome.&nbsp; You guys must be very proud of all you&#8217;ve seen and done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, midshipmen, you made it!&nbsp; You made it!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I’ll bet there were times you wondered if you’d ever see this day &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; especially in those early days when you had to chop everywhere, memorize every Reef Point to make it through the Sea Trials, so &#8212; and even &#8212; even passing chemistry, for God’s sake.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Well, this education has at times pushed the edge of what you thought would be possible in order to develop you morally, mentally, and physically.</p>



<p>And it was worth it.&nbsp; It was worth it all because today you stand ready to assume the title you’ve been working toward for so long: Ensign, the United States Navy.&nbsp; Second lieutenant, the United States Marine Corps.</p>



<p>Members of the greatest fighting force in the history of the world.&nbsp; And that’s no exaggeration.&nbsp; You have earned it.&nbsp; Congratulations.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I mean it &#8212; you really are.&nbsp; I’ve been in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan over 40 &#8212; I think 38 times.&nbsp; My son spent a year in Iraq, won the Bronze Star, Conspicuous Service Medal.&nbsp; I lost him.</p>



<p>But any rate, I’ve seen you in action.&nbsp; This is the finest military &#8212; not a joke.&nbsp; We have the finest military in the history of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And thank you, Admiral &#8212; Admiral Buck, for the work you and your team have done to put these young men and women in shape, when they arrived here four <s>days</s> [years] ago on I-Day, into officers of the Armed Services of the United States of America.</p>



<p>And, Secretary Del Toro, Admiral Gilday, General Berger, you know better than anyone how important this &#8212; these missions are that we’re going to ask these young officers to carry out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And looking out at this field, it’s clear to me we’re going to be sending our finest.</p>



<p>Congressman Ruppersberger, it’s great to see you here.&nbsp; I’m told you’re here.</p>



<p>I also want to recognize Congressman DesJarlais and &#8212; who &#8212; and Congressman Crowley, both here today as proud parents of commissioning midshipmen.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, by the way &#8212; and I know &#8212; you know that all midshipmen here are holding in their hearts the memory of two classmates who tragically did not live to see this day.&nbsp; I hope I’m pronouncing Duke’s last correctly &#8212; Carillo.&nbsp; And Michael &#8212; and Michael Myles James.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks &#8212; midshipmen, this is your day.&nbsp; But I want to start by recognizing the people who got you here: your parents, your family &#8212; everyone here that shows their support to get you here, it’s their day as well.</p>



<p>So, midshipmen, stand up and clap for them.&nbsp; For them!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, moms and dads and grandparents, thanks for instilling such honor and integrity in these young women and men.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Class of 2022, you’ve made incredible memories &#8212; please, have a seat &#8212; during your time in the Yard.</p>



<p>After all this &#8212; after all this, the class holds one of the fastest Herndon Climbs in history &#8212; (applause) &#8212; upholding a tradition set by the “link in the chain” &#8212; class chain &#8212; 50 years ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a class that earned a record number of wins against the Army in the “N-Star” Competition.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I hope my son up in heaven doesn’t hear me saying that part.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; He’s Army.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So many wins, you ran out of room on that flagpole, man.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, this is a class of Midshipman Diego Fagot, who wasn’t expecting that snap in this year’s Army-Navy Game.&nbsp; But once he got the ball, he knew what the hell to do with it, didn’t he?&nbsp; You won the game.&nbsp; You won the game.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The class of Midshipman Sarah Skinner, the 54th Rhodes Scholar from the United States Naval Academy &#8212; (applause) &#8212; 54th &#8212; and led the Women’s Rugby team to a national title.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Stand up.&nbsp; I want you standing up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And now Sarah is on the Olympic Development team.&nbsp; I can’t wait to see you, kid.&nbsp; I can’t wait to see you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I couldn’t play football anymore, I played rugby in law school.&nbsp; I should’ve spent more time in law school.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But at any rate, class of Midshipman, First Class, Andre Rascoe, Delta Company &#8212; your class president.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I don’t know, but somebody told me you may have questions for me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>I think only the class understands that one.</p>



<p>You’ve all got so much to be proud of.&nbsp; You really do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, once you’re commissioned, remember: I’m your Commander-in-Chief.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So don’t ask me too tough a question, okay?</p>



<p>Look &#8212; and I know, unlike me, when I graduated from the University of Delaware &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Wooo!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; I had a few &#8212; thank you &#8212; I had a few minor infractions, like hosing down an RA in a &#8212; anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Unfortunately, this &#8212; we didn’t have the same tradition you have here.&nbsp; So, before I take care of you, let’s not forget: This is also the class that also got rowdy during the Air Force week in plebe year, and they’re still trying to clean the chocolate syrup off the ceiling in King Hall.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>You lived through “Red Beach Massacre.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And that helped &#8212; and that helped the printers “earn their jump wings.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; If anyone wants to fess up to getting a printer onto the Chapel Dome, now’s your moment.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No one is going to admit it, huh?&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Because as your Commander-in-Chief, in keeping with longstanding tradition, I hereby absolve all those serving restrictions for minor infractions.&nbsp; You are absolved.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; as I said, I wished all my graduation speakers would’ve been able to do that.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; You all think I’m kidding; I’m not.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Midshipmen, above all, the Academy has trained you to be leaders.&nbsp; Easy word to throw around, but hard to accomplish.&nbsp; You didn’t take the easier route when you chose the Academy and, again, when you signed your Two for Sevens.</p>



<p>You chose a life of service and purpose.&nbsp; You chose trial and sacrifice.&nbsp; You chose to be part of a mission that is greater than any individual.</p>



<p>While every class of midshipmen is tested, you faced added challenges to maintain a sense of mission and community and purpose when the global pandemic forced everything &#8212; literally everything &#8212; to change.</p>



<p>When you were told not to return after spring break as “youngsters.”</p>



<p>When in your second year you weren’t allowed to see any other &#8212; anybody other than your roommate.&nbsp; Hope to hell you picked right.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when you had to take your classes over Joom [sic] &#8212; Zoom, I should say, sitting in your uniforms and mesh shorts.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Oh, I figured that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then coming back to the Yard as Firsties not only to reform, but to remember what this place and what this time is supposed to be like; to return to the brigade to what it was pre-COVID and rebuild morale.</p>



<p>You had the responsibility to right the ship.&nbsp; And all of you stepped up, I’m told.&nbsp; You came together.&nbsp; You learned the first and most important lesson of leadership: to always, always care for your people, to respect everyone’s talents, to be inclusive, and to make sure that the United States Navy and the United States Marine Corps draw from the full strength and diversity of this nation.&nbsp; Everybody.</p>



<p>Midshipmen, for the rest of your careers, you’re going to face challenges unforeseen.</p>



<p>You’re going to have to adapt and be ready to lead your people through whatever lies ahead.&nbsp; To state the obvious: No generation of graduates gets to pick what world they’re going live &#8212; they’re going to graduate into.&nbsp; It’s already been formed for you.&nbsp; But you must change it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>No officer knows the range of challenges they’ll face when they commission.</p>



<p>And, Class of 2022, you are graduating at an inflection point not only in American history but in world history.&nbsp; And I mean it.&nbsp; The challenge we face and the choices we make are more consequential than ever.</p>



<p>Things are changing so rapidly that the next 10 years will be the decisive decade of this century, because they’re going to shape what our world looks like and the values that will guide it not just for the immediate future, but for generations to come.&nbsp; And that is not hyperbole.</p>



<p>Over the past few years, we’ve seen how interconnected the world is.&nbsp; The deadly pandemic has impacted not just our own schooling, but almost every aspect of our lives &#8212; impacts of disruptions to the global supply chain causing significant inflation; accelerating the climate crisis that’s leading to rising seas and more severe weather patterns arou- &#8212; around the globe.</p>



<p>And Putin’s brutal, brutal war in Ukraine: Not only is he trying to take over Ukraine, he’s literally trying to wipe out the culture and identity of the Ukrainian people, attacking schools, nurseries, hospitals, museums with no other purpose than to eliminate a culture.&nbsp; A direct assault on the fundamental tenets of rule-based international order.</p>



<p>That’s what you’re graduating into.&nbsp; That’s the world in which ensigns and second lieutenants &#8212; a world that more than ever requires strong, principled, engaged American leadership; where America leads not only by the example of its power, but the power of its example.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Think of why most nations agreed to support us.&nbsp; It’s the example &#8212; it’s the example we set.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you’ll learn to crew the most advanced ships in the world, train the most elite combat units, conduct undetected submarine missions, fly the most advanced fighter planes.</p>



<p>But the most powerful tool that you’ll wield is our unmatched network of global alliances and the strength of our partnerships &#8212; which, since I got elected, I’ve been trying to re-establish in detail.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Earlier this week, I returned from my first trip as President &#8212; been there before &#8212; as President though &#8212; to the Indo-Pacific, a region that will be vital to the future of our world.</p>



<p>I met with the leaders of Japan &#8212; the heads of state of Japan, the Republic of Korea.&nbsp; I participated in a meeting of the Quad, which I restarted over China’s objection &#8212; including Australia, Japan, India, and the United States &#8212; four leading democracies in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I launched, together with 13 other countries across the region, the new Indo-Pacific Economic Framework to help write the rules of the road for the 21st century.</p>



<p>Before I departed Asia &#8212; before I left for Asia, I should say, I got a phone call from the Prime Minister of Sweden and the President of Finland &#8212; could they come and see me in the Oval.&nbsp; They came to ask me whether I would support them joining NATO.&nbsp; The actions taken by Putin were an attempt to &#8212; to use my phrase &#8212; to “Findalize” all of Europe &#8212; make it all neutral.&nbsp; Instead, he “NATOized” all of Europe.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all of this is illustrative of a foreign policy that is built around the power of working together with Allies and partners to amplify our strength, to solve problems, to project our power beyond what we can do alone, and to preserve stability in an uncertain world.</p>



<p>This is the work that will be asked of you.&nbsp; This is not hyperbole.&nbsp; I’m being deadly earnest with you, because it will be.</p>



<p>As sailors and Marines, submariners and SEALs, Navy aviators and surface warfare officers, we’re going to look to you to ensure the security of the American people, to build connections and strengthen interoperability of &#8212; with our allies and partners around the world.</p>



<p>You’ve already started that work here at the Academy, where today we are graduating 12 international midshipmen, representing 10 countries, who will commission as officers in the militaries of their nations.</p>



<p>Graduates, you will be the symbol and the strength of your commitment to lead the world.</p>



<p>You’re going to stand sentinel, often shoulder-to-shoulder, with our allies and partners in critical regions of the world &#8212; like the service women and men I just visited in the Republic of Korea or the troops I spent time with in Poland in March who are making real our commitment to the security of our NATO Allies.</p>



<p>In the Indo-Pacific, a maritime theater, [you] will be the leading edge of our response to natural or humanitarian disasters, showing people throughout the region the unmatched ability of the United States to be a force for good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’ll defend the international rules of the road and underwrite the future for the Indo-Pacific that is free and open, ensure freedom of navigation of the South China Sea and beyond, and make sure the sea lanes remain open and secure.</p>



<p>These longstanding, basic maritime principles are the bedrock of a global economy and global stability.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re going to help knit together our allies in Europe with our allies in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For the first time &#8212; if I can hesitate for a second here &#8212; did anybody think, when I called for sanctions against Russia, that in addition to NATO, that Australia, Japan, <s>North</s> [South] Korea, some of the ASEAN countries, would stand up and support those sanctions?&nbsp; The world is moving so rapidly.&nbsp; I need not tell you aviators.&nbsp; Within the next decade, you&#8217;re going to be able to circumvent the world in &#8212; within the atmosphere in a little less than &#8212; a little more than an hour.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Things are changing.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Putin’s brutal assault on Ukraine has spurred a truly global response not just from Europe, but from Japan, Korea, Singapore, New Zealand, and more &#8212; standing with us to impose sanctions on Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Australia, sending military aid.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Germany, for the first time, significantly upping their budget.&nbsp; Germany.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fiji, assisting the FBI in seizing the yacht of an oligarch.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re seeing the world align not in terms of geography &#8212; East and West, Pacific and Atlantic &#8212; but in terms of values.</p>



<p>We’re living through a global struggle between autocracies and democracies.&nbsp; And I will note &#8212; and my co- &#8212; I&#8217;ve met more with Xi Jinping than any other world leader has.&nbsp; When he called me to congratulate me on election night, he said to me what he said many times before.&nbsp; He said, “Democracies cannot be sustained in the 21st century.&nbsp; Autocracies will run the world.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Things are changing so rapidly.&nbsp; Democracies require a consensus, and it takes time, and you don’t have the time.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;s wrong.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each of you, as you go out into the world, will not only be a proud member of the Armed Forces of the United States of America, you’ll be representatives and defenders of our democracy.&nbsp; It sounds corny but, literally, our democracy.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why you swear an oath not to me as your Commander-in-Chief or to any political leader, but to the Constitution.</p>



<p>Our nation is placing in you great trust and great faith.&nbsp; A young we- &#8212; man with me today, carrying in town the football.&nbsp; All the responsibility given to so many of you, so consequential.&nbsp; Because you’ve chose &#8212; you’ve chosen the honorable path that few before you have done.</p>



<p>And you&#8217;re going to look to uphold the honor of this institution and the generation of proud patriots who’ve passed this way before you.&nbsp; Patriots like a dear friend of mine, John McCain.</p>



<p>John and I went after each other hammer and tong on the Senate floor.&nbsp; We disagreed politically on things.&nbsp; But being here, I can’t help think of John and how the Naval Academy meant so much to him.&nbsp; He chose these grounds for his final resting place.</p>



<p>John was an American hero who withstood torture, years of being held as a prisoner of war.&nbsp; And when he came home, he decided to continue &#8212; he wanted to continue to serve.&nbsp; We traveled tens of thousands of miles together as he &#8212; staffing me as a senator.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m one of the reasons &#8212; and I used to always get kidded by my Democratic friends &#8212; I talked him into running.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He was a man of great principle and capacity.&nbsp; He always lived by a code &#8212; the same code that you all have been taught.&nbsp; It’s not just words, it’s real: duty, honor, loyalty.</p>



<p>He kept that code throughout his years as a prisoner of war, all the time he served in the United States Congress.&nbsp; As I said, we often disagreed, but we were close friends.&nbsp; John and I, we knew one another.</p>



<p>In March of 2018, I was honored that John asked me &#8212; because he wasn’t physically able &#8212; to come to the Naval Academy and receive on his behalf the Alumni Association&#8217;s Distinguished Graduate Award and speak for him.</p>



<p>Shortly after that, when John was on his deathbed in his home in Arizona, I went to see him.</p>



<p>I was leaving, after the visit, and in a voice barely above a whisper, he called me over to his bedside.&nbsp; He said, “Joe, will you do my eulogy?”&nbsp; I said, “Yes, John.”&nbsp; And literally at the same time, two guys who think they&#8217;re hardass guys looked to one another and said, “I love you.”</p>



<p><br>Class of 2022, John McCain’s memorial was one of the first</p>



<p>experiences you had at the Academy back in 2018.</p>



<p>Your class motto, “Not all of me shall die,” I can’t help but think must be a reflection &#8212; some reflection of that moment in your lives, a reminder of the responsibilities you have taken on and the legacy you will leave behind.</p>



<p>It’s a promise &#8212; a promise you made to each other and to this institution, because what lives on will be the service you will give to others and the timeless principles that you’re willing to sacrifice everything to defend.</p>



<p>In this moment, we must steer our nation and our world through this decisive decade.&nbsp; I hope you’ll keep the memory of the example of Academy graduates, like my friend John McCain, close in your hearts as you embark on your commissions.</p>



<p>I cannot promise you the way will be straight or the sailing will be easy, but I can promise you that you all have the tools needed to navigate any waters you encounter.</p>



<p>This great academy has prepared you to face every challenge and overcome any obstacle.&nbsp; You are ready.</p>



<p>For my wish to you is fair winds and following seas, because I know you will remain always faithful.</p>



<p>May God protect you all and may He set you on your journey.&nbsp; And may God protect all those who wear the uniform of the United States of America.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for your service.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>11:01 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
