<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 18:01:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on House Passage of the America COMPETES&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/04/statement-from-president-biden-on-house-passage-of-the-america-competes-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 18:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House took a critical vote today for stronger supply chains and lower prices, for more manufacturing – and good manufacturing jobs – right here in America, and for outcompeting China and the rest of the world in the 21st century. I applaud Speaker Pelosi, Majority Leader Hoyer, Whip Clyburn, and Chairwoman Eddie Bernice Johnson&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The House took a critical vote today for stronger supply chains and lower prices, for more manufacturing – and good manufacturing jobs – right here in America, and for outcompeting China and the rest of the world in the 21st century. I applaud Speaker Pelosi, Majority Leader Hoyer, Whip Clyburn, and Chairwoman Eddie Bernice Johnson for their leadership in getting this done.</p>



<p>Business and labor alike have praised this legislation as vital for continuing the economic momentum we’ve seen over the last year, and national security leaders from both parties have said that the investments in this bill are needed if we want to maintain our competitive edge globally. This bill was built on numerous bipartisan elements and on shared bipartisan agreement on the need to act. If House Republicans are serious about lowering prices, making our economy stronger, and competing with China from a position of strength, then they should come to the table and support this legislation, which does just that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I look forward to the House and Senate quickly coming together to find a path forward and putting a bill on my desk as soon as possible for my signature. America can’t afford to wait.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation to Continue Facilitating Positive Adjustment to Competition From Imports of Certain Crystalline Silicon Photovoltaic Cells (Whether or Not Partially or Fully Assembled Into Other&#160;Products)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/04/a-proclamation-to-continue-facilitating-positive-adjustment-to-competition-from-imports-of-certain-crystalline-silicon-photovoltaic-cells-whether-or-not-partially-or-fully-assembled-into-other-produc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; 1.&#160; On January 23, 2018, pursuant to section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (the &#8220;Trade Act&#8221;) (19 U.S.C. 2253), the President issued Proclamation 9693, imposing a safeguard measure for a period of 4 years that included both a tariff-rate quota (TRQ) on imports of certain crystalline silicon photovoltaic (CSPV) cells,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 1.&nbsp; On January 23, 2018, pursuant to section 203 of the Trade Act of 1974, as amended (the &#8220;Trade Act&#8221;) (19 U.S.C. 2253), the President issued Proclamation 9693, imposing a safeguard measure for a period of 4 years that included both a tariff-rate quota (TRQ) on imports of certain crystalline silicon photovoltaic (CSPV) cells, not partially or fully assembled into other products, provided for in subheading 8541.40.6025 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States (HTS), and an increase in duties (safeguard tariff) on imports of CSPV cells exceeding the TRQ and all imports of other CSPV products, including modules provided for in subheading 8541.40.6015 of the HTS.&nbsp; Proclamation 9693 exempted imports from certain designated beneficiary countries under the Generalized System of Preferences from the application of the safeguard measure.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2.&nbsp; Clause (4) and Annex I of Proclamation 9693 directed the United States Trade Representative (USTR) to establish procedures for interested persons to request the exclusion of particular products from the safeguard measure.&nbsp; These provisions also authorized the USTR, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, to determine whether a particular product should be excluded, and, upon publication of a determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>, to modify the HTS to implement such determination.&nbsp; Furthermore, they authorized the USTR to modify or to terminate such determinations.&nbsp; Effective June 13, 2019, the USTR excluded bifacial solar panels that absorb light and generate electricity on each side of the panel and that consist of only bifacial solar cells that absorb light and generate electricity on both sides of the cells (bifacial modules).&nbsp; Exclusion of Particular Products From the Solar Products Safeguard Measure, 84 FR 27684 (June 13, 2019).<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3.&nbsp; On February 7, 2020, the United States International Trade Commission (USITC) issued its report, pursuant to section&nbsp;204(a)(2) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(a)(2)), on the results of its monitoring of developments with respect to the domestic solar industry (USITC, Crystalline Silicon Photovoltaic Cells, Whether or Not Partially or Fully Assembled Into Other Products: &nbsp;Monitoring Developments in the Domestic Industry, No.&nbsp;TA-201-075 (Monitoring)).&nbsp; In its report, the USITC found that, following imposition of the safeguard measure, prices for CSPV&nbsp;cells and modules declined in a manner consistent with historical trends, but that prices were higher than they would have been without the safeguard measure.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 4.&nbsp; On March 6, 2020, the USITC issued an additional report&nbsp;pursuant to a request from the USTR under section&nbsp;204(a)(4) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(a)(4)), regarding the probable economic effect on the domestic CSPV cell and module manufacturing industry of modifying the safeguard measure to increase the level of the TRQ on CSPV cells from the current 2.5 gigawatts (GW) to 4.0, 5.0, or 6.0 GW (USITC, Crystalline Silicon Photovoltaic Cells, Whether or Not Partially or Fully Assembled Into Other Products: &nbsp;Advice on the Probable Economic Effect of Certain Modifications to the Safeguard Measure, No.&nbsp;TA-201-075 (Modification)). &nbsp;In its report, the USITC advised that increasing the TRQ would help to continue growth in solar module production, but that expanded access to imported cells not subject to safeguard duties would put downward pressure on prices for cells made in the United States.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 5.&nbsp; After taking into account the information provided in&nbsp;the USITC&#8217;s reports, and after receiving a petition from a&nbsp;majority of the representatives of the domestic industry with&nbsp;respect to each of the following modifications, and under section 204(b)(1)(B) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(b)(1)(B)), the President issued Proclamation 10101 on October 10, 2020, in which he determined that the domestic industry has begun to make a positive adjustment to import competition, as shown by the increases in domestic module production capacity, production, and market share.&nbsp; Proclamation 10101 also:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; revoked the exclusion of bifacial modules from application of the safeguard measure on the basis that it had impaired and was likely&nbsp;to continue to impair the effectiveness of the safeguard action; and<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; adjusted the safeguard tariff for the fourth year of the safeguard measure from 15 percent to 18 percent on the basis that the exclusion of bifacial modules from application of the safeguard tariffs had impaired the remedial effectiveness of the 4-year action proclaimed in Proclamation 9693, and to&nbsp;achieve the full remedial effect envisaged in that action.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 6.&nbsp; On November 16, 2021, the United States Court of International Trade held in Solar Energy Industries Association et al. v. United States (SEIA) that the President acted outside of his statutory authority in issuing Proclamation 10101, and enjoined the Government from enforcing that proclamation.&nbsp; This injunction had the effect of reinstating the exclusion of bifacial modules from the safeguard tariffs and lowering the fourth year safeguard tariff to 15 percent.&nbsp; On January 14, 2022, the Government filed a notice of appeal of SEIA to the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7.&nbsp; On December 8, 2021, in response to petitions by representatives of the domestic industry, the USITC issued its determination and report pursuant to section 204(c) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(c)), finding that safeguard action continues to be necessary to prevent or remedy the serious injury to the domestic industry, and that there is evidence that the domestic industry is making a positive adjustment to import competition (USITC, Crystalline Silicon Photovoltaic Cells, Whether or Not Partially or Fully Assembled Into Other Products, Investigation No. TA-201-75 (Extension)).<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 8.&nbsp; Section 203(e)(1)(B) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2253(e)(1)(B)) authorizes the President, after receiving an affirmative determination from the USITC pursuant to section&nbsp;204(c) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(c)), to extend the effective period of any action taken under section 203 of the Trade Act if the President determines that the action continues to be necessary to prevent or remedy the serious injury, and there is evidence that the domestic industry is making a positive adjustment to import competition.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 9.&nbsp; After taking into account the information provided in&nbsp;the USITC&#8217;s report and the information received from the public through the process published in the <em>Federal Register&nbsp;</em>on&nbsp;September 30, 2021 (86 FR 54279), pursuant to section 203(e)(1)(B) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2253(e)(1)(B)), I have determined that the safeguard action on imports of CSPV cells, whether or not partially or fully assembled into other products, continues to be necessary to prevent or remedy the serious injury to the domestic industry, and that there is evidence that the domestic industry is making a positive adjustment to import competition.&nbsp; I have further determined to extend the safeguard measure proclaimed in Proclamation 9693, as modified by Proclamation 10101 (to the extent permitted by law), as follows:<br>(a)&nbsp; continuation of the TRQ on imports of solar cells not partially or fully assembled into other products described in paragraph 1 of this proclamation for an additional period of 4&nbsp;years, with unchanging within-quota quantities of 5.0 GW for each year and annual reductions in the rates of duty applicable to goods entered in excess of those quantities of cells in the fifth, sixth, seventh, and eighth years, as described in Annex I to this proclamation;<br>(b)&nbsp; continuation of the increase in duties on imports of modules described in paragraph 1 of this proclamation for an additional period of 4 years, with annual reductions in the fifth, sixth, seventh, and eighth years, as described in Annex I to this proclamation; and<br>(c)&nbsp; exclusion of bifacial panels from the extension of duties proclaimed in this paragraph.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 10.&nbsp; I have determined that an extension of this safeguard measure will provide greater economic and social benefits than costs.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 11.&nbsp; As provided in Proclamation 9693, this safeguard measure shall continue to apply to imports from all countries, except as provided in clause (4) of this proclamation and paragraph 10 of Proclamation 9693.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 12.&nbsp; Section 204(a)(2) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(a)(2)) requires the USITC to issue a report on its monitoring of developments with respect to the domestic industry, including the progress and specific efforts made by workers and firms in the domestic industry to make a positive adjustment to import competition, no later than the midpoint of the period of the extension.&nbsp; After I receive that report, I will evaluate whether to reduce, modify, or terminate the safeguard measure pursuant to section 204(b)(1) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2254(b)(1)).<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 13.&nbsp; As proclaimed in Proclamation 9693, the in-quota quantity in each year of the TRQ described in paragraph 9 of this proclamation shall be allocated among all countries except those countries the products of which are excluded from such TRQ pursuant to clause (4) of this proclamation or paragraph 10 of Proclamation 9693.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 14.&nbsp; In order to address certain technical errors in the HTS, the HTS is modified as set forth in Annex II to this proclamation.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 15.&nbsp; Section 604 of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2483) authorizes the President to embody in the HTS the substance of the relevant provisions of that Act, and of other acts affecting import treatment, and actions thereunder, including the removal, modification, continuance, or imposition of any rate of duty or other import restriction.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, including sections 203, 204, and 604 of the&nbsp;Trade Act, do proclaim that:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (1)&nbsp; In order to extend the measure applicable to imports of CSPV cells, not partially or fully assembled into other products, described in paragraph 1 of this proclamation, subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTS is modified as set forth in Annex I to this proclamation, subject to clauses (3) and (4) below.&nbsp; Any merchandise subject to the safeguard measure that is admitted into United States foreign trade zones on or after 12:01 a.m. eastern standard time on February 7, 2022, must be admitted as &#8220;privileged foreign status&#8221; as defined in 19 CFR 146.41, and will be subject upon entry for consumption to any tariffs or quantitative restrictions related to the classification under the applicable HTS subheading.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (2)&nbsp; Except as provided in clause (3) below, imports of CSPV products of World Trade Organization Member countries, as listed in subdivision (b) of Note 18 to subchapter III of chapter 99 of the HTS (Note 18), shall continue to be excluded from the safeguard measure extended by this proclamation, and such imports shall not be counted toward the TRQ limits that trigger the over-quota rates of duties.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (3)&nbsp; If, after the extension proclaimed herein is in effect, the USTR determines that:<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; the share of total imports of a country listed in subdivision (b) of Note 18 exceeds 3 percent;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; imports of the product from all listed countries with less than 3 percent import share collectively account for more than 9 percent of total imports of the product; or<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (c)&nbsp; a country listed in subdivision (b) of Note 18 is no longer a developing country for purposes of this proclamation;<br>the USTR is authorized, upon publication of a notice in the <em>Federal Register</em>, to revise subdivision (b) of Note 18 to remove the relevant country from the list or suspend operation of that subdivision, as appropriate.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (4)&nbsp; I instruct the USTR to enter into negotiations pursuant to section 203(f) of the Trade Act (19 U.S.C. 2253(f)) with Canada and Mexico.&nbsp; In the event that the USTR concludes an agreement that the USTR, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, determines will ensure that imports of Canada or Mexico do not undermine the effectiveness of the action extended through clause (1) of this proclamation, the USTR is authorized, upon publication of a notice in the <em>Federal Register</em>, to revise Note 18 to suspend application of that subdivision, in whole or in part, as appropriate, with respect to imports of Canada or Mexico.&nbsp; If the USTR subsequently determines, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Energy, that such an agreement is not effective, the USTR is authorized, pursuant to section 203(f) of the Trade Act, by publication of a notice in the <em>Federal Register</em>, to revise Note 18 to terminate any previous suspension of the action with respect to imports of Canada or Mexico.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (5)&nbsp; One year after the termination of the safeguard measure established in this proclamation, the U.S. note and tariff provisions established in Annex I to this proclamation shall be deleted from the HTS.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (6)&nbsp; Any provision of previous proclamations and Executive Orders that is inconsistent with the actions taken in this proclamation is superseded to the extent of such inconsistency.<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this<br>fourth day of February, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Signs Executive Order to Boost Quality of Federal Construction&#160;Projects</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/03/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-to-boost-quality-of-federal-construction-projects/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration will make federal procurement more economical and efficient by improving coordination and minimizing disruptions on large federal construction projects Tomorrow, the President will sign an Executive Order to improve timeliness, lower costs and increase quality in federal construction projects. Federal construction projects span the country – from the maintenance of nuclear sites to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration will make federal procurement more economical and efficient by improving coordination and minimizing disruptions on large federal construction projects</em></p>



<p>Tomorrow, the President will sign an Executive Order to improve timeliness, lower costs and increase quality in federal construction projects. Federal construction projects span the country – from the maintenance of nuclear sites to base construction to waterways and flood projects. By requiring the use of project labor agreements (PLAs) on federal construction projects above $35 million, the Order will help alleviate the management and coordination challenges that can stymie progress on major construction projects. This helps projects get completed on time and helps the government get the best value for taxpayers’ dollars.</p>



<p>Based on FY2021 figures, this Order could affect $262 billion in federal government construction contracting and improve job quality for the <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2021-11-24/pdf/2021-25317.pdf">nearly 200,000 workers</a> on federal construction contracts. Additionally, the President’s Executive Order directs the departments of Defense and Labor, along with the Office of Management Budget, to lead a training strategy for the nearly 40,000-person strong contracting workforce on the implementation of this Order’s policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This Executive Order is just one of many steps the Biden-Harris Administration is taking that will improve the efficiency of federal procurement. Since taking office, the President fulfilled his commitments to strengthen Buy American rules, and secured a reliable supply of experienced, quality workers for federal service contracts. As of January 30<sup>th</sup>, federal contractors in new or extended contracts must pay a $15/hour minimum wage, as the President directed in Executive Order 14026.</p>



<p>This new Executive Order, while only applicable to federal procurement, advances the Administration’s commitment to rebuild the nation’s infrastructure, on-time and at reasonable cost. The Order will only apply to provisions in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that are direct federal procurement, which excludes construction projects financed through grant dollars to non-federal entities. The Executive Order will benefit taxpayers, contractors, and workers by:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Alleviating the coordination challenges on large, complex projects. </strong>Multi-million-dollar projects can present real management challenges to the primary contractor on the project, which has to work with multiple businesses and multiple types of skilled labor to complete a project. PLAs can help coordinate diverse contractors and sub-contractors and their employees working on a project and prevent disputes between subcontractors. Additionally, workers will have more confidence in the management of the project and a greater commitment to completing the project if they have a voice at the table. This helps projects get completed on time by minimizing work disruptions. On-time projects save the government, and taxpayers, money.<br></li><li><strong>Raising quality standards for contractors bidding on federal projects. </strong>PLAs help raise the standards of all bidders on federal contracts. Contractors who offer lower wages or do not train their workers will need to raise their standards to compete with other high-wage, high-quality companies. Businesses with well-trained workers will be more likely to bid for and win federal contracts. Well-trained, high quality workers are more productive, completing projects well and on time.<br></li><li><strong>Reducing uncertainty in the contracting process. </strong>PLAs standardize the work rules, compensation costs, and dispute settlement processes on construction projects. This standardization helps create more certainty for the government and, therefore, taxpayers, about the costs and completion rate for projects.<br></li><li><strong>Increasing training for the federal contracting workforce. </strong>The Executive Order directs the Departments of Defense and Labor, along with the Office of Management and Budget, to lead a training strategy for the contracting workforce on Project Labor Agreements and the implementation of this Order. This training will create a more uniform and accessible experience for contractors interacting with departments and agencies across the federal government.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Gun Violence Prevention Task Force&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/03/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-gun-violence-prevention-task-force-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 21:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46587</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One Police PlazaNew York, New York 1:32 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Okay.&#160; Well, General Garland; Governor; Mr. Mayor; Representative Jeffers [sic] &#8212; Jeffries, excuse me; Representative Velázquez &#8212; they rode up on the flight with me &#8212; and other members of Congress that are here: Thank you.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; And I just want to thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">One Police Plaza<br>New York, New York</p>



<p>1:32 P.M. EST<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, General Garland; Governor; Mr. Mayor; Representative Jeffers [sic] &#8212; Jeffries, excuse me; Representative Velázquez &#8212; they rode up on the flight with me &#8212; and other members of Congress that are here: Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just want to thank Mayor Adams and Commissioner Sewell and the law &#8212; all the law enforcements here today for &#8212; not having me, for what you do every single day.<br><br>It’s &#8212; and let me start by saying Detective Wilbert Mora and Jason Rivera are the “who” and “what” law enforcement ought to be.&nbsp; And the &#8212; Senator Gillibrand and I have talked about that on the way up as well.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spoken to their families, and &#8212; and their loss for the city is also a loss for the nation.&nbsp; You know, the future is cut short by a man with a stolen Glock with 40 rounds &#8212; a magazine with 40 rounds.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s really a weapon of war.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things I was proudest of years ago, when I was in the Senate &#8212; I was able to get these weapons and the size of magazines outlawed.&nbsp; That got changed.&nbsp; It got overruled.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t see any rationale to why there should be such a weapon able to be purchased.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t violate anybody&#8217;s Second Amendment rights to deny that.&nbsp;<br><br>But anyway, their futures were cut short by a man with a stolen Glock and that 40-round magazine.&nbsp;<br><br>And I tell you, I want to thank the man back to my left &#8212; I think he&#8217;s sitting right there &#8212; for taking on.&nbsp; Stand up. (Applause.)<br><br>Now, if you’ll excuse a &#8212; as we used to say in the Senate, “a point of personal privilege,” I &#8212; when everything &#8212; when the economy died in Scranton, Pennsylvania, and I moved down to Delaware with my dad and my mom and the family, I moved to a little town called Claymont, Delaware.&nbsp; And it was a steel town just across the border from Pennsylvania, right up in that arc.&nbsp;<br><br>And I went to &#8212; I spent 12 years going to school there.&nbsp; Or actually, not 12; I started in third grade.&nbsp; At any rate, I went to a school &#8212; a little Catholic school called Holy Rosary, across from a small police department and a fire hall.&nbsp; And everybody that I grew up with either became a cop, a firefighter, or a priest.&nbsp; I wasn’t qualified for any of them, so here I am.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>But I admire the hell out of all of you.&nbsp; I really do.&nbsp; It’s not &#8212; I&#8217;m not being solicitous.&nbsp; I mean it sincerely.<br><br>And to the many parents, spouses, brothers, sisters who have to bury a piece of their soul in the deep earth, it&#8217;s really tough stuff.&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard as hell &#8212; you all know it &#8212; to lose a colleague, to lose a son, a daughter, a husband, wife.<br><br>And I want to thank &#8212; if &#8212; there are not many here, but I want to thank all the spouses of every one of you or your significant other, because every time you pin that shield on and walk out the door, they&#8217;re worried whether they&#8217;re going to get that phone call &#8212; get that phone call.&nbsp; And too many have gotten the phone call lately.&nbsp;<br><br>And every day in this country, 316 people are shot, 106 are killed.&nbsp; And six NYPD officers have been victims of gun violence so far, just this year &#8212; the same in the town north of me, Philadelphia; and my much smaller town of Wilmington, Delaware; and Washington, D.C.&nbsp;<br><br>Sixty-four children injured by gun violence so far this year, twenty-six killed.&nbsp; It&#8217;s enough.&nbsp; Enough is enough.&nbsp;<br><br>Because we know we can do things about this but for the resistance we&#8217;re getting from some sectors of the government and the Congress and the state legislatures and the organizational structures out there.<br><br>You know, Mayor Adams, you and I agree: The answer is not to abandon our streets.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not the answer.&nbsp; The answer is to come together, the police and communities, building trust and making us all safer.&nbsp;<br><br>The answer is not to defund the police, it’s to give you the tools, the training, the funding to be partners, to be protectors.&nbsp; And the community needs you &#8212; and know the community.&nbsp; You know &#8212; (applause) &#8212; police &#8212; policing that treats everyone with respect and dignity.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s why I called on the Congress to pass a budget later this year that provides cities, like New York and others, with an additional $300 million for community policing, you know, where the police interact with the community, get to know the community, build trust in the community.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;ve noticed, in my experience &#8212; when I wrote the first crime bill, I noticed that, you know, I don&#8217;t hear many communities &#8212; no matter what their color or their background &#8212; saying, “I don&#8217;t want more protection in my community.”&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know, I haven&#8217;t found one of those yet.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I&#8217;ve asked the Congress to provide $200 million to invest in community violence intervention programs as well &#8212; they work; they work &#8212; where community members with credibility work directly with people that are most likely to commit crimes or be victims of gun crimes.&nbsp; And they work.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, in 2017, the program I&#8217;m going to see this afternoon, which sends people to the community &#8212; in the community to interrupt violence, to mediate conflicts, to de-escalate &#8212; succeed in preventing single &#8212; a single shooting from occurring in this largest public housing development last year.&nbsp; No shooting for a full year because they engaged directly with the community.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I know this is a priority for Senator Schumer, what you all are doing here.&nbsp; If I hear one more call from him that we need more money for housing and more money for cops &#8212; I don&#8217;t know, I&#8217;m going to send him back to you all.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But all kidding aside, this is a &#8212; this is a half a billion dollars of proven strategies, and we know it will reduce crime.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Congress needs to do its job to pass the budget.&nbsp; Every one of these folks here from Congress are all supportive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, you know, it&#8217;s time to fund communities, community police, and the people who are going to protect them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, as I said, we&#8217;re not about defunding; we&#8217;re about funding and providing the additional services you need beyond someone with a gun strapped to their shoulder or to their hip.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We need more social workers.&nbsp; We need mental health workers.&nbsp; We need more people who when you&#8217;re called on these scenes and someone is about to jump off a roof, there’s not just someone standing there with a &#8212; with a weapon; it&#8217;s someone who also knows how to talk to people &#8212; talk them down.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t expect you to do every single, solitary thing that needs to be done to keep a community safe.&nbsp; It&#8217;s time to fund community policing to protect and serve the community.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I&#8217;m also calling for increased funding for the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms, and the U.S. Marshals offices.&nbsp; I&#8217;m confident that if we fund these programs, we’ll see a reduction in violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the next year&#8217;s budget, I&#8217;m also going to try to double down on this investment.&nbsp; I think I got a lot of partners here in New York that are going to help.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mayor Adams, you say that gun violence is a sea fed by many rivers.&nbsp; Well, you know, I put forward a plan to dam up some of those streams.<br><br>You know, you can count on me to be a partner in that effort.&nbsp; And I have the U.S. Attorney &#8212; United States Attorney General here with me today.&nbsp; And we put together a comprehensive strategy to combat gun crime in cities like New York, Philadelphia, Atlanta, and many other cities &#8212; San Francisco.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, we want to crack down on the flow of firearms used to commit violence.&nbsp; That includes taking on and shutting down rogue gun dealers at &#8212; and it’s about doing background checks, as well as outright selling of that &#8212; making sure the people who are not allowed to have a gun, don&#8217;t get the gun in the first place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And again, for any of the press in here, the press listening: This doesn&#8217;t violate anybody&#8217;s Second Amendment right.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no violation of a Second Amendment right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We talk like there&#8217;s no amendment that&#8217;s absolute.&nbsp; When the amendment was passed, it didn&#8217;t say anybody can own a gun and any kind of gun and any kind of weapon.&nbsp; You couldn&#8217;t buy a cannon in &#8212; when the &#8212; this &#8212; this amendment was passed.&nbsp; And so, no reason why you should be able to buy certain assault weapons.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s another issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And look, one of the things that we focused on, the Attorney General and I &#8212; and we&#8217;re getting to the point where I think we&#8217;re going to be able to have a real impact on it &#8212; includes going after ghost guns.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Ghost guns are the guns everyone in this room knows that can be purchased in parts, assembled at home, no serial number, and can&#8217;t be traced.&nbsp; And they’re as deadly as any other weapon out there.&nbsp; But the fact is: They are out there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, you know, this spring, the Justice Department &#8212; this spring, the Justice Department will issue a final rule to regulate these so-called “ghost guns.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But there&#8217;s more we can do.&nbsp; Across the country, police departments reported sharp increases in the number of ghost guns found at crime scenes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why, today, the department is launching an intes- &#8212; an intensified National Ghost Gun Enforcement Initiative to determine and deter criminals from using those weapons to cover their tracks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you commit a crime to the ghost gun, not only are state and local prosecutors going to come after you, but expect federal charges and federal prosecution as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also created a strike force to crack down on illegal gun trafficking across state lines.&nbsp; As the mayor said, as he pointed out, guns that are used to kill people in New York City, they aren&#8217;t made in New York City, they aren&#8217;t sold in New York City.&nbsp; They are sold in other places.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, the Attorney General directed all U.S. attorneys in the United States to prioritize combating gun trafficking across state lines and city boundaries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Justice Department is sending additional prosecutorial resources to help shut down what&#8217;s referred to, as you all know, as the “Iron Pipeline” that funnels guns from shops in states like Georgia to crime scenes in Baltimore and Philadelphia and New York and so many other places.<br><br>Governor, you worked with the mayor and the NYPD and nine other states to create an Interstate Task Force on Illegal Guns.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the kind of leadership that&#8217;s going to solve the problem.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m eager to hear more about that progress.<br><br>And, folks, the second thing I want to point out is I want to help every major city follow New York&#8217;s lead to put together partnerships like this one you put together that meet on a daily basis.<br><br>Every day, here in New York City, like this meeting today, federal, state, and local enforcement meet to share intelligence about arrests, shootings from the day before, and work to take those shooters off the streets as quickly as possible.<br><br>Just look around: This is what a partnership looks like, and this is what you put together.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an important partnership.&nbsp; And we need more cities adopting the same model.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s why, today, the Attorney General is also directing U.S. attorneys to work with state and local law enforcement to strength &#8212; to strengthen partnerships like this one and to get repeat gun violence offenders off the street and behind bars.<br><br>You know, I want more cities and states to use some of the $350 billion we sent to them on the American Rescue Plan to fight crime, to keep our communities safe by hiring more police officers for community policing and paying police overtime, and purchasing gun-fighting technologies, like technologies that hears, locates gunshots so there can be immediate response because you know exactly where it came from.<br><br>The third thing our plan calls for: investing in critical services that reduce crime and violence; community violence intervention programs, like the one I&#8217;m going to see after this meeting; summer school; afterschool programs for teens.&nbsp;<br><br>As the saying goes and the teachers have taught me, “An idle mind is a devil’s workshop.”&nbsp; We got to have things for these kids to do, jobs for young adults, more school counselors and nurses, more mental health required in school, and mental health/substance abuse treatment as well.<br><br>Fourthly, with someone &#8212; when someone finishes their time in prison, all our experience tells us you just can&#8217;t continue to give them 25 bucks and a bus ticket.&nbsp; They’ll end up under the same bridge you arrested them in the first place from.&nbsp;<br><br>And so I don&#8217;t want &#8212; I don&#8217;t want them ending up back in prison or being there because they&#8217;ve committed another crime.&nbsp; We need to be able to train for and get a job, find stable housing, reenter society, and have a second chance at a better life.<br><br>My Department of Labor is funding programs that help formerly incarcerated individuals, including young adults, receive the education and training they need and then connect them to quality jobs.<br><br>I&#8217;ll keep doing everything in my power to make sure that communities are safer.&nbsp; But Congress needs to do its part too: pass universal background checks, ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, close loopholes, and keep out of the hands of domestic abusers &#8212; weapons, repeal the liability shield for gun manufacturers.&nbsp;<br><br>Imagine had we had a liability &#8212; they&#8217;re the only industry in America that is exempted from being able to be sued by the public.&nbsp; The only one.&nbsp; Imagine had that been the way with cigarette manufacturers.&nbsp; Where the hell would we &#8212; where the heck would we be?&nbsp; We&#8217;d be in tough shape.&nbsp;<br><br>Why gun manufacturers?&nbsp; Because of the power of their lobbying ability.&nbsp; It&#8217;s got to end.&nbsp; End.&nbsp; They’ve got to be held responsible for the things that they do that are irresponsible.&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, you know, it&#8217;s the only industry in America, as I said, that’s exempt from being sued.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; I find it to be outrageous.<br><br>And, folks, these laws, if we&#8217;re able to pass them, are going to save lives, and more &#8212; and equally importantly, help you protect one another and protect yourself, put law enforcement in a more &#8212; a safer circumstance.<br><br>We have an opportunity to come together and fulfill the first responsibility of government and our democracy: to keep each other safe.<br><br>So, I want to thank you all.&nbsp; There&#8217;s much more to say, but I probably already said too much, because a lot of people are going to speak.&nbsp; But let&#8217;s get this done.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get this done.<br><br>And God bless the men and women who put their lives on the line every single day to keep our communities safe.&nbsp;<br><br>Now I&#8217;m going to turn it over, with your permission, to the Attorney General &#8212; Attorney General Garland.&nbsp; General?<br><br>1:47 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/03/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 19:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route New York, New York 11:36 A.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MS. PSAKI:&#160; I know this is a short flight, so I thought I would just start.&#160; And I know we&#8217;ve done a number of briefings, but just giving you all just a couple of key points on the President&#8217;s engagement in the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route New York, New York</p>



<p>11:36 A.M. EST<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know this is a short flight, so I thought I would just start.&nbsp; And I know we&#8217;ve done a number of briefings, but just giving you all just a couple of key points on the President&#8217;s engagement in the operation that happened overnight last night.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The operation has been months in &#8212; was months in planning.&nbsp; The President was first briefed on this operation in depth over a month ago by the actual operational commanders.&nbsp; He was regularly updated by the national security team on the planning details of this operation, to include a briefing in the Oval Office on Monday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last night, the President monitored key aspects of the operation in real time in the White House Situation Room.&nbsp; I think you all saw the photo that we released on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also want to stress that the President directed the Department of Defense to take every precaution to minimize noncombatant casualties in the operation, hence how they proceeded with their &#8212; the operation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Unfortunately, as we know and we saw, ISIS once again revealed its barbarity in a final act of cowardice, and displaying a never-ending &#8212; ended &#8212; disregard for innocent lives.&nbsp; Hajji Abdullah detonated an explosive device shortly after U.S. forces arrived on site, killing himself, a woman, and three children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Of course, there will be more assessments.&nbsp; I mean, the Department of Defense will do an assessment, as they always do.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just wanted to outline that at the top.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know we also did a briefing on the trip today to New York, but why don&#8217;t we get to your questions?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Two subjects.&nbsp; First, obviously, news of the day.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Big picture: Strategically, what does this mean for U.S.?&nbsp; What does this mean for the Islamic State?&nbsp; And what does this mean for Syria?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And did you coordinate or communicate with Russia at all, given the airspace issues in Syria?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me start with the first question.&nbsp; Hajji Abdullah’s death delivers a catastrophic blow to ISIS and shows that the United States will take out terrorist threats no matter where they stand to hide in the world &#8212; try to hide in the world.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last night&#8217;s effective action took a major terrorist leader off the battlefield and makes it clear that we will hold anyone accountable who seeks to harm Americans at home or around the world.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I would also note that while this planning was taking place, of course, we were also leading a coordinated effort, as you all know &#8212; more than 200 engagements with leaders around the world &#8212; to stand up for the sovereign &#8212; the territorial integrity of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, it shows the competence of U.S. leadership, the effectiveness of U.S. leadership, and our ability to keep the American people safe while also standing up for our values at the same time.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of international coordination, it&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I will have to check with the State Department on the specifics of it.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was there a video component to the scene unfolding in the Situation Room?&nbsp; And who else was in there with him?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure I can get you a complete list.&nbsp; I know some individuals were shown in the photo we released.&nbsp; Members of his national security team were there, including Jake Sullivan and Liz Sherwood-Randall.&nbsp; I think you could see John Finer in the photo.&nbsp; Obviously, the Vice President.&nbsp; We will venture to get you a full list of attendees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you &#8212; on the trip today, there was some reporting by the New York Times that the White House is trying to move more to the center when it comes to crime, and there’s concern about reaching out to police organizations.&nbsp; And obviously, there’s a policing executive order that’s supposed to be in the works.&nbsp; Can you talk a bit about: Is there a conflict between civil rights groups who want more accountability for police, want less use of force unnecessarily, and what the White House is doing right now, like on this trip?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, we would direct the &#8212; reject the notion that we were moving into any political direction.&nbsp; The President has a decades-long record of fighting &#8212; of being an advocate for fighting crime and supporting local COPS programs with necessary and appropriate resources and funding.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>He has never been an advocate for defunding the police, as you know, but his record on these issues long precedes his time as President.<br><br>I would say that he is also committed and he believes that both need to come hand in hand &#8212; that pursuing police reform is a step that will help rebuild trust in communities and is something that is welcomed by many communities and police forces across the country, and he believes that goes in hand with public safety.&nbsp; Having effective, accountable community policing to help us &#8212; helps us fight crime, and it also makes us safer.&nbsp;<br><br>So, while we are here in New York, what you will hear him talk about today, as we&#8217;ve previewed a little bit, is his, you know, decades-long commitment to supporting law enforcement, to ensuring that communities have the resources they need too.&nbsp;<br><br>And you&#8217;ll hear him talk about his sweeping and comprehensive plan to adjust gun frime [sic] &#8212; gun crime and our focus on implementing that, but also, again, ensuring that communities have the funding that they need, including his proposal to double federal support for community policing with $300 million more for cities, plus another $200 [million] more for community violence intervention program.&nbsp;<br><br>But you will also hear him &#8212; and he also remains very committed to taking steps we can to put in place police reform measures that he thinks are long overdue.&nbsp; Obviously, his preference was to have had that through legislative processes, but we are looking at what can be done through executive actions.&nbsp;<br><br>I think you may have seen Susan Rice convey we’re not close on that front, but we are working on it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, we’ve had six law enforcement officers killed by criminals this year.&nbsp; The President has not spoken out forcefully against any of these attacks.&nbsp; Even some of his supporters say the lack of forceful condemnation is demoralizing to police.&nbsp; Why hasn&#8217;t he spoken out more forcefully against these attacks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; More forcefully against attacks against police officers?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He went and gave an entire speech to the &#8212; to the police forces just a few months ago.&nbsp; He &#8212; we have put out statements, and he has condemned the violence and the attacks on these police officers.&nbsp; He&#8217;s reached out to family members.&nbsp; He is somebody &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But why not (inaudible) &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me finish my answer, because I think that&#8217;s an inaccurate characterization.&nbsp; And you haven&#8217;t even given me names of who you&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, Charles Wilson is &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But the President’s &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; (inaudible) of the National Association &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; the President&#8217;s record &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; of Black Law Enforcement Officers.&nbsp; He’s one of the people who said it&#8217;s demoralizing.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President&#8217;s record is very clear here.&nbsp; He has a long record of advocating for, supporting through funding, through speaking out, the role of local police, of national police and the important role they place &#8212; they play in addressing crime and keeping communities safe.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not go to one of the officer’s funerals, if you&#8217;re going to come to New York, and show support for the law enforcement?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President &#8212; we have been planning this trip in coordination with the mayor&#8217;s office.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve invited a number of officials to attend the trip.&nbsp; He also is, as you know, going to the police headquarters to make clear his strong support for them.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, I know you gave a little bit of the lead-up to the raid.&nbsp; I mean, can you give more on the President&#8217;s thinking ahead of the ISIS raid?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can, but tell me more about what you mean.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just mean like &#8212; well, you know, a little bit more from either inside the room &#8212; I know it’s the Situation Room, but like &#8212; or what the President was thinking as this &#8212; as this raid was taking place.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think the President, again, has been &#8212; received a number of briefings, as I noted, from his national security team over the course of the last several weeks, including one from the operational commanders just a few days ago.&nbsp; And the President was thinking: We got to go after terrorists wherever they are and get them, and protect the American people.&nbsp; He also was &#8212; made clear and reiterated this at every point in the process, to do everything we can to avoid civilian casualties.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think you saw the photo of him in the room.&nbsp; You&#8217;re always watc- &#8212; in those moments, you&#8217;re always watching, you&#8217;re thinking about the bravery and the courage of the &#8212; of the service members who are on the ground, you know, implementing an operation.&nbsp; And that is, of course, front and center from him &#8212; for him always.&nbsp;<br><br>But, you know, he was also thinking about, you know, the role he plays as Commander-in-Chief in keeping the country safe.&nbsp; And, certainly, taking out the current head of ISIS is a big step forward in that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you guys have a number on how many civilian casualties there were?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There &#8212; again, that is an assessment being done by DOD.&nbsp; I would note that &#8212; as was confirmed and I just confirmed again &#8212; that, given that the intended target self-detonated and deployed a tactic used by his predecessor, that that shows, again, the brutality of ISIS &#8212; and killed his own family.<br><br>We certainly know the facts of that, but I will leave it to DOD to give any additional assessments.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if I could, just on USICA.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are a number of House Democrats and Senate Democrats that really want to see this done by the President’s State of the Union Address.&nbsp; Are you &#8212; do you guys just want to see the House pass the Senate version of the bill, given that this &#8212; the House version is taking a lot longer with all of these amendments?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not going to make a calculation or direction of that from here.&nbsp; As you know, the process &#8212; how it works &#8212; is: Once it passes the House, it would &#8212; we would expect it would go to conference and there would be a discussion about any disagreements or any final details that are not aligned between the two pieces of legislation.<br><br>That&#8217;s a normal part of legislating.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we certainly support that.&nbsp;&nbsp;Obviously, the President has said he wants to sign it as quickly as possible.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;A few things.&nbsp;&nbsp;Were you in the room last night &#8212; the Situation Room?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp;No.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Okay.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s start with this one &#8212; today&#8217;s event.&nbsp; The governor is there as well.&nbsp; This is an official event, but is this an endorsement of her reelection &#8212; of her election campaign?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think this is an event and an opportunity.&nbsp; The President is a big fan of the governor, but this is not a political event.&nbsp; This is an event for the President to stand with leaders in New York as they&#8217;ve seen, you know, the tragic deaths of a number of police officers recently &#8212; people who have been serving on behalf of communities across New York &#8212; and also for the President to make clear he stands with them in their efforts to address crime in their communities.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two others from last night.&nbsp; Was he able to watch the whole thing live?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a detail of how &#8212; of that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And were any of &#8212; any members of the special forces team who conducted last night&#8217;s raid involved in the Baghdadi operation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would point you to the Department of Defense on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s a meeting today &#8212; remind me &#8212; today with Presidents Putin and Xi &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; in China.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do we feel about that meeting and not being invited to it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are diplomatic meetings that happen all the time. &nbsp;Our National Security Advisor, I believe, just recently spoke with his counterpart.&nbsp; Let me just get all the specific details on this so I can make sure it&#8217;s accurate for you.<br><br>And, you know, our view and assessment is that &#8212; oh, I should say &#8212; sorry &#8212; Secretary Blinken recently spoke to China&#8217;s Foreign Minister Wang, his counterpart, and underscored the global security and economic risk posed by further Russian aggression against Ukraine and conveyed that de-escalation and diplomacy are the responsible way forward.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, that is the message we continue to convey, including the fact that a destabilizing conflict in Europe would impact China&#8217;s interests all over the world.&nbsp; China certainly know that.&nbsp;<br><br>But we have our own means of communicating through counterparts.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue to do that and continue to stand up for what we feel should be global values.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the Supreme Court, any update on when he might begin interviewing potential nominees?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to provide an update on the process from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; Hey, Jen, two things on Congress.&nbsp; It seems like, on the Russia sanctions negotiations, that Congress is intent to at least include some preemptive sanctions into that bill.&nbsp; Is that a red line for you?&nbsp; Or could you ultimately support something that has preemptive &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have done some sanctions in advance already.&nbsp; Our approach &#8212; and we are in very close touch with members of Congress about this legislation, which I don&#8217;t think has been formally even proposed yet.&nbsp; So, we are in close contact, in conversations with them.&nbsp;<br><br>Our approach from the beginning has been based on our belief that, you know, the crippling economic sanctions package that we have been discussing and has been underway in our interagency process, which we briefed Congress on, is a &#8212; has a deterrent &#8212; could have a deterrent impact as we&#8217;re already seeing in the Russian markets.&nbsp;<br><br>But we&#8217;ve never set a red line.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not setting a red line.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve done sanctions in advance, and we&#8217;re in discussion with Congress about the legislation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the approps talks ongoing right now, can you detail a little bit about the White House&#8217;s engagement in them?&nbsp; And do you support larger increases to the defense budgets to get Republicans on board?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Those talks are being &#8212; we&#8217;re closely engaged with them from the White House, from our OMB team.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m not going to detail specifics of those behind-the-scenes talks at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If Russia &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And any &#8212; sorry, one more, Steve.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, go right ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any fear that the ongoing talks now will further delay your budget for next year, which I think Shalanda Young said is coming past the State of the Union?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any assessment of that.&nbsp; I know she confirmed that just a couple of days ago, so &#8212; but I don&#8217;t have a new timeline beyond that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s my understanding of where it stands at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, if Russia and Belarus are having some military exercises, is this any cause for concern?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve raised &#8212; our U.N. Ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, raised some concerns about this when she spoke at the United Nations, where she talked about her concern about &#8212; our concern about 5,000 troops in Belarus, the potential for 30- &#8212; up to 30,000 more.&nbsp; Clearly, this is an escalatory, not a de-escalatory action.&nbsp;<br><br>And certainly, we look at &#8212; look at, you know, these developments as we make assessments about how to support and work with our other NATO partners in the region.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With regard to the civilian casualties in Syria, are &#8212; is the administration saying that they were caused entirely by the bomb detonating or by crossfire from the one lieutenant engaging with U.S. forces?&nbsp; Like, what &#8212; give us some clarity on that.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Obviously, these events just happened overnight.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;m going to let the Department of Defense do a final assessment, which I&#8217;m certain they will provide additional detail on once it&#8217;s finalized.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, will there be any, like, evidence or, like, release to support the idea &#8212; I mean, I know the U.S. has put out its statement that, you know, they detonated the bomb themselves.&nbsp; But will the U.S. provide any evidence?&nbsp; Because there may be people that are skeptical of the events that took place and what happened to the civilians.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Skeptical of the U.S. military&#8217;s assessment when they went and took out an ISIS terror- &#8212; the leader of ISIS?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That they are not providing accurate information &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; and ISIS is providing accurate information?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, not ISIS, but, I mean, the U.S. has not always been straightforward about what happens with civilians.&nbsp; And, I mean, that is a fact.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, there&#8217;s an extensive process that the Department of Defense undergoes.&nbsp; The President made clear from the beginning, at every point in this process, that doing everything possible to avoid civilian casualties was his priority and his preference.<br><br>I just reconfirmed, and I think our national security colleague who did a briefing this morning also reiterated, that the individual who was the target detonated himself, killing his entire family.<br><br>Given these events just happened less than 24 hours ago, we&#8217;re going to give them time to make a final assessment.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ll provide every detail they can.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Civil rights advocates have asked the President to visit Rikers Island.&nbsp; I know that&#8217;s not on this trip.&nbsp; Can you speak to why this isn&#8217;t on the trip?&nbsp; And is there a plan for the President to visit Rikers Island anytime soon?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any trips to preview at this point in time.&nbsp; Obviously, this trip today, which is a full trip, including the President&#8217;s visit to thank law enforcement officials, to convey clearly to them that he has their back, that he is going to continue to support adequate funding and resources that they need to keep their community safe, and also to meet, of course, with leaders in the state who have shared concerns about rising crime.<br><br>But, you know, I expect he&#8217;ll be back to New York, you know, during his time as President, but I don&#8217;t have any preview of a trip to Rikers.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One thing, Jen.&nbsp; Do you have any updates on the German Chancellor visit &#8212; if you&#8217;re planning a press conference or anything to share on the details?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I believe we are, but let me see if I can get the final details for all of you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re about to land, just so you know.<br><br>11:52 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the National Prayer&#160;Breakfast</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/03/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-national-prayer-breakfast/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 19:11:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Capitol Visitor CenterWashington, D.C. 9:06 A.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Well, thank you.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t know who she&#8217;s talking about &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but thank you. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Folks, look, let me say &#8212; I hadn’t planned on &#8212; I didn’t know I was going&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The U.S. Capitol Visitor Center<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>9:06 A.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t know who she&#8217;s talking about &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Folks, look, let me say &#8212; I hadn’t planned on &#8212; I didn’t know I was going to get that kind of introduction.&nbsp; But let me say at the outset that, you know, we&#8217;ve all gone through really difficult times &#8212; every one of you out there &#8212; one way or another.&nbsp; And I had an overwhelming advantage, and I mean it sincerely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I had a family that was there for me every single, solitary moment.&nbsp; And so, I don’t deserve this credit for enduring that so many people I meet &#8212; think of all the people you know, whether they&#8217;re constituents or friends or relatives, who get up every morning, don’t have anybody &#8212; don’t have anybody, and they put one foot in front of the other, and they do it.&nbsp; They lost a child, they lost a mother, a father, a husband, someone close to them &#8212; just plucked away &#8212; and they get up every single day and put one foot in front of the other.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re the people who deserve our recognition and our credit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; I think I&#8217;ve talked to Bill and Grace Nelson about this: The only thing &#8212; today is my son Beau’s birthday.&nbsp; But the only thing that Beau said to me when he was &#8212; we were told he was &#8212; he was going to die within minutes or &#8212; if an hour &#8212; that he looked at me, and he said, “Dad, promise me &#8212; promise me, Dad, you&#8217;re going to stay involved.”&nbsp; I said, “I&#8217;ll be involved.&nbsp; I’ll be &#8212; I’ll be good, Beau.”&nbsp; He said, “No, dad, promise me.&nbsp; Give me your word as a Biden that you&#8217;re going to stay engaged.”</p>



<p>Because he knew, like a lot of you &#8212; what you’ve been through &#8212; the first instinct is you just want to curl up in a ball and just leave, no longer do what you’ve done your whole life that you’ve &#8212;</p>



<p>He said, “Dad &#8212; Dad, promise me.”&nbsp; “I give my word.”</p>



<p>And that &#8212; that was the last conversation in Walter Reed Hospital &#8212; laying there in the bed.&nbsp; And &#8212; and then he looked at me and he said, “And, Dad…” &#8212; and his brother Hunter was his closest friend.&nbsp; We were all three on the bed.&nbsp; And he turned to me and he said, “Dad, I want you to know I&#8217;m not afraid.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, I had so much help &#8212; so much help, starting from the time that I lost my wife and daughter in an accident.&nbsp; But look, everybody has got horrible things they’ve had to deal with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve watched them &#8212; I sat in the Senate for 36 years.&nbsp; We watched people literally die in our midst.&nbsp; I remember that scene where Teddy walked out.&nbsp; Or &#8212; I mean, there &#8212; so, you know, I&#8217;m flattered that you think as highly of me as you stated, Kirsten, but I had &#8212; I had a lot of help.&nbsp; I had a lot of help.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank you for the intr- &#8212; the introduction.&nbsp; It’s very gracious.&nbsp; But like I said, there&#8217;s a lot more people who’ve done a lot more.</p>



<p>And to my good friend Chris Coons &#8212; two things I tell everybody about Chris Coons you got to know: One, he’s smarter than you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And, two, the boy can preach.&nbsp; He’s the only guy that went to law school and got a divinity degree at the same time.&nbsp; I worry about “divine” lawyers.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But &#8212; anyway.</p>



<p>Chris, thank you.&nbsp; You’ve been a great friend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as &#8212; Bryan, as you were speaking, Chuck sort of leaned over; he didn’t say anything, but he just like, “Was that Delaware?”&nbsp; But it was Delaware.&nbsp; It’s why I got involved in politics in the first place.</p>



<p>I remember sitting on &#8212; going to a little Catholic grade school in Claymont, Delaware, which was a steel town that was dying.&nbsp; And the bus would go &#8212; my mother would drive me to the school parking lot &#8212; it was called Holy Rosary School &#8212; from a little &#8212; and it was called Brookview Apartments.&nbsp; Used to be Section 8 housing later.</p>



<p>And I get out of the bus &#8212; I get out of the car.&nbsp; And this is where I-95 runs parallel to these days.&nbsp; And I said, “Mom, why are all those kids” &#8212; it was then “colored.”&nbsp; “Why are all those colored kids in that bus?”&nbsp; Because in Scranton there weren&#8217;t any &#8212; there were very few Blacks.&nbsp; She said, “They’re not allowed to go to school with us here, in Delaware.” &nbsp;So, you know &#8212; and Milton wasn’t what you might call the epicenter of desegregation.</p>



<p>And so, you’ve been through a lot, but you’ve done a lot as well.&nbsp; And I thank you.</p>



<p>And, Kari &#8212; Kari Jobe, you have the voice of an angel, kid.&nbsp; I tell you what: You really do.&nbsp; And that guy sitting next to you, he’s a lucky guy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; He’s a lucky guy.&nbsp; And besides, he’s got all his hair.&nbsp; (Laughter.) &nbsp;</p>



<p>And Vice President Harris, Majority Leader Schumer, Mitch McConnell &#8212; and, Mitch, I don’t want to hurt your reputation, but we really are friends.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And that is not an epiphany we’re having here at the moment.&nbsp; We’ve always &#8212; you’ve always done exactly what you’ve said.&nbsp; You’re a man of word &#8212; of your word, and you’re a man of honor.&nbsp; Thank you for being my friend.</p>



<p>And, folks, members of Congress and spouses: I’m honored to join you all today.</p>



<p>You know, we’re keeping our prayers for Senator Luján, and keep him in your prayers today.&nbsp; I think, from what I understand, he’s going to be okay and be back with us in the not-too-distant future.&nbsp; But we pray for a safe recovery.</p>



<p><a>And a special thank you to the bipartisan chairs of this breakfast: Representative Lamb and Walberg, [Senators] Gillibrand and Rounds.</a></p>



<p>Mike, I know it’s been three months to this day that you lost Jean to cancer.&nbsp; So, you know &#8212; you know of which I speak.&nbsp; And it’s like losing a piece of your soul.&nbsp; And I &#8212; you know, I &#8212; I remember.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, as I said, is a day that a lot of us can remember the times when we lost &#8212; each of us.&nbsp; And just like I miss my son every single day, I &#8212; there’s &#8212; I know he’s always with me, for real.&nbsp; He’s always with me.</p>



<p>Congresswoman McBath, just like your precious son Jordan &#8212; he’s always going to be with you, for real.&nbsp; It becomes a piece of you.&nbsp; You know, how many times did you all been through this, about to make a decision and say, “What would Beau want?”&nbsp; Or “What would Jill want?”&nbsp; Or “What would…” &#8212; you know, whatever it is.&nbsp; So, it’s &#8212; you know.</p>



<p>And for everyone out there who has lost a piece of their soul, they’re always with you.&nbsp; And all through the pain, I think you &#8212; if you can find purpose, find purpose.&nbsp; Purpose of a life that makes you worthy in their eyes and what they expect of you.</p>



<p>This breakfast usually is held in a big Washington hotel with a big crowd.</p>



<p>Today, we’re here in the Visitor Center of the United States Capitol with a much smaller crowd, a more intimate setting to see each other here and listen to each other &#8212; standing in this, which is, in governmental terms, a “sacred place.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>I thank our &#8212; I think about our former colleagues and close friends we lost this year: Bob Dole; Harry Reid; Johnny Isakson, who was a hell of guy; Max Cleland; Carl Levin; Mike Enzi; John Warner; and Walter Mondale.</p>



<p>And, you know, I learned a long time ago: Never make one good eulogy.&nbsp; Because if you make one good eulogy, you got to do a lot of eulogies.&nbsp; But I’ve had the pleasure of knowing their families. &nbsp;And &#8212; and there’s a lot of good friends, both sides of the aisle, who disagreed on many, many things, who still talked and listened to one another.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think I’ve said to Mitch and some of you earlier, in the last couple of years, that, you know, one of the things I don’t know for sure but I think is missing in the Congress is we don’t spend as much time with one another as we used to.&nbsp; We used to eat lunch together.&nbsp; I mean, literally sit down &#8212; not in the Senate Dining Room of the Senate or that small dining room off to the &#8212; right across the hall from the visitors dining room, and there were those two big round tables &#8212; big &#8212; big dining room tables and a buffet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I remember when I first got here, after my wife and daughter were killed in an accident, my boys were still in the hospital &#8212; and I remember Teddy would always come and say, “Come to lunch.”&nbsp; I didn’t want any part of going to lunch.&nbsp; And one day, he just dragged me over to lunch.&nbsp; He said, “You’ll learn more there than at any place else.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would go to lunch there, literally every day, and listen to the senior members.&nbsp; And you learn about their losses, their happiness.&nbsp; You learn about them.&nbsp; You learn about their &#8212;</p>



<p>You know, I remember one day I walked in and there was a little corner in the table &#8212; or a corner table, when the big table was filled.&nbsp; And I sat down.&nbsp; And Jimmy said, “Come over here, Joe.&nbsp; Sit down here.”&nbsp; And I wasn’t about to sit in John Stennis’s seat, because he sat at the head of the table.&nbsp; And he said, “No, come on.&nbsp; He’s gone.”&nbsp; So, I ordered my hamburger or whatever (inaudible) and took a couple of bites.&nbsp; And in walks John Stennis.&nbsp; And I immediately put a napkin on all my stuff and I said, “I’m finished Mr. Chairman.&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; Right here.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>I later got a handwritten letter from him, about three o’clock in the afternoon: “I appreciate the honor of you recognizing my seat, but you didn’t finish your meal.&nbsp; I promise this favor will be returned.”</p>



<p>He not only returned, he actually endorsed me when I ran for President from Mississippi.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I think &#8212; that was an expensive hamburger for him.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I guess what I’m trying to say is: You know, when you know one another, when you know &#8212; and no matter how badly you disagree &#8212; and people think, Rev, that in the days as divided here, we had &#8212; we had a lot of flat-out, old segregationists still in our caucus.&nbsp; But Teddy Kennedy would argue like hell with Jim Eastland, and then he’d go down to have lunch.&nbsp; Didn’t agree with one another, but they treated each other with respect even in that day.</p>



<p>And I &#8212; I just think that, when you learn that another man or woman &#8212; and you’re flying a codel, and someone has their husband or wife with them, and you learn that they have a kid with a problem with alcoholism, or you learn that they have a daughter who is &#8212; has breast cancer.&nbsp; You learn that they have &#8212; it’s hard to dislike the person.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, one of the things I pray for &#8212; and I mean it &#8212; is that we sort of get back to the place &#8212; and it’s so busy; I think things have changed so much &#8212; but that we get to really know each other.&nbsp; It’s hard to really dislike someone when you know what they’re going through is the same thing you’re going through.</p>



<p>You know, like President Eisenhower, the first president to attend this breakfast 70 years ago &#8212; at the time, President Eisenhower said &#8212; he said, “There&#8217;s a need we all have in these days and times for some help which comes from outside ourselves.”&nbsp; Outside ourselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve attended many of these prayer breakfasts over the years &#8212; with our nation at war, in struggle, in strife, peace, in times of prosperity, when everybody was getting on, but a nation in prayer.</p>



<p>Jill and I have been humbled by the prayers of so many of you, and it means everything to us.&nbsp; We pray for our nation as we face an inflection point in our history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So much is going to change no matter who&#8217;s sitting in my job.&nbsp; The world is changing.&nbsp; The world is changing.</p>



<p>I &#8212; there’s a &#8212; the moment &#8212; but there&#8217;s also a moment of great progress, of lives saved in this pandemic, not just the ones lost &#8212; new jobs created for people, new hope for rebuilding the nation, but also a moment of pain for the lost lives and the &#8212; and the lives lost in this pandemic.&nbsp; And the cruel twist of fates that occur.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, at a moment of great division of our democracy is at great &#8212; grave risk.&nbsp; I pray that we follow what Jesus taught us: to serve rather than be served.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t always do it.&nbsp; I hope try.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t always do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I pray to keep the faith.&nbsp; That very promise of America, believing that there&#8217;s nothing we can&#8217;t do, where every person is created equal in the image of God &#8212; no matter who or where we come from, who we are, or what our color, or how we choose to pray, or whether or not we choose to pray &#8212; they deserve to be treated equally throughout their lives.</p>



<p>Faith in the very idea of America that can be defined, in my view, by a single word.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been saying this for over 30 years.&nbsp; When I get asked to define America, one word: “Possibilities.”&nbsp; “Possibilities.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the reasons why other countries sometimes think we&#8217;re arrogant is we believe anything is possible.&nbsp; Anything is possible.&nbsp; And faith in the American people will prove each and every day we&#8217;re a great nation because we&#8217;re, at our heart, a good people.&nbsp; We do bad things when we get frightened.</p>



<p>Saint Augustine wrote that, “A people was a multitude defined by a common object of their love.”&nbsp; I believe the common objects of our love that define us as Americans are opportunity, liberty, dignity, respect, honor, service, truth &#8212; things everybody recognizes both here and around the world.</p>



<p>As I stand in this citadel of democracy that was attacked one year ago, the issue is &#8212; for us is unity.&nbsp; How do we unite us again?&nbsp; Unity is elusive, but it&#8217;s really actually necessary.&nbsp; Unity doesn&#8217;t mean we have to agree on everything.&nbsp; But unity is where enough of us &#8212; enough of us believe in a core of basic things: the common good, the general welfare, a faith in the United States of America &#8212; the United States of America.</p>



<p>Nearly three weeks ago, we were reminded of that truth.&nbsp; A gunman entered a synagogue in Colleyville, Texas.&nbsp; He took four worshippers hostage, including a rabbi, for 11 hours.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But violence and vengeance didn’t pierce the goodness and grace of that scene.&nbsp; Heroic law enforcement officers were joined by local faith leaders, including an imam, a Baptist minister who offered their help.&nbsp; A nearby Catholic church opened its doors for the hostages’ families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At sunset, a group of Muslim women &#8212; friends of the rabbi’s wife &#8212; walked in with one of the rabbi’s favorite foods.&nbsp; They hugged and they wept.</p>



<p>Because of the bravery of the hostages and the law enforcement officers, the hostages were &#8212; escaped safely, and the families were reunit- &#8212; reunited.</p>



<p>When asked later if he would change anything, the rabbi said, quote, “We will do what we always do, which is the best we can.” &nbsp;“Which is the best we can.”&nbsp; I had a long conversation with the rabbi.&nbsp; It was interesting to hear him describe the scene and how faith mattered: Whether you’re in a synagogue or a church or a mosque or a temple, whether you’re religious or not, we’re all imperfect human beings, trying our best &#8212; the best we can, because we can&#8217;t know the future.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t know what&#8217;s coming.&nbsp; But we also can&#8217;t live in fear every step of the way.</p>



<p>That’s America.&nbsp; From darkness, we found joy, hope, and light.</p>



<p>Rather than driving us apart, faith can move us together.&nbsp; Because all the great confessional faiths have the same fundamental basic beliefs: not just faith in a higher power, but faith to see each other as we should: not as enemies, but as neighbors; not as adversaries, but as fellow Americans.</p>



<p>And as leaders of this nation who work and pray together, there is an oath to God and country to uphold and a charge to keep: to stand in the breach and to protect our democracy, to work together to right wrongs. &nbsp;That’s why we all came here, to make the most of our time on Earth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For if a house divided cannot stand, surely a house united can do anything.&nbsp; And if we do that, I think we’ll have done our duty.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With history and God watching, we will have to prove that there is nothing beyond the capacity of the United States when we’re united &#8212; the United States.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, some of the senior senators who are here used to kid me because I was quoting Irish poets on the floor of the United States Senate. &nbsp;And there&#8217;s a poem, “The Cure at Troy,” written by an Irish poet who I got to know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It says: History teaches us not to hope “on this side of the grave.&nbsp; But then, once in a lifetime, [that]…tidal wave of justice [rises] up, and hope and history rhyme.”<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I honestly believe we&#8217;re at one of those moments.&nbsp; There&#8217;s so much at stake.&nbsp; The division has become so palpable, not just here, but around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have a chance.&nbsp; We have a chance &#8212; a chance to make hope and history rhyme, because the rest of the world is looking to us.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Every time I&#8217;d walk out of my Grandpa Finnegan’s house up in Scranton &#8212; some of you heard me say this before &#8212; he’d yell, “Joey, keep the faith.”&nbsp; My grandmother would yell, “No, Joey, spread it.”&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go spread the faith.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>9:26 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/03/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 19:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46569</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160; Michael J. Adler, of Maryland, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of South Sudan.&#160;&#160;&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Edward Gabriel, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the Board&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p> &nbsp;&nbsp;  Michael J. Adler, of Maryland, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of South Sudan.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Edward Gabriel, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice Ikram U. Khan, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; John T. Godfrey, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of the Sudan.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Dara Lindenbaum, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Federal Election Commission for a term expiring April 30, 2027, vice Steven T. Walther, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nathalie Rayes, of Massachusetts, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice Joseph Eldridge, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mary Green Swig, of California, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace for a term of four years, vice Stephen D. Krasner, term expired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on a Successful Counterterrorism&#160;Operation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/03/remarks-by-president-biden-on-a-successful-counterterrorism-operation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 18:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46557</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 10:21 A.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Last night, operating on my orders, United States military forces successfully removed a major terrorist threat to the world: the global leader of ISIS, known as Hajji Abdullah. He took over as the leader of ISIS in 2019 after the United States counterterrorism operation killed al-Baghdadi.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>10:21 A.M. EST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Last night, operating on my orders, United States military forces successfully removed a major terrorist threat to the world: the global leader of ISIS, known as Hajji Abdullah.</p>



<p>He took over as the leader of ISIS in 2019 after the United States counterterrorism operation killed al-Baghdadi.</p>



<p>Since then, ISIS has directed terrorist operations targeting Americans, our Allies and our partners, and countless civilians in the Middle East, Africa, and in South Asia.</p>



<p>Hajji Abdullah oversaw the spread of ISIS-affiliated terrorist groups around the world after savaging communities and murdering innocents.</p>



<p>He was responsible for the recent brutal attack on a prison in northeast Syria holding ISIS fighters, which was swiftly addressed by our brave partners in the Syrian Democratic Forces.</p>



<p>He was the driving force behind the genocide of the Yazidi people in northwestern Iraq in 2014.</p>



<p>&nbsp;We all remember the gut-wrenching stories: mass slaughters that wiped out entire villages, thousands of women and young girls sold into slavery, rape used as a weapon of war.</p>



<p>And thanks to the bravery of our troops, this horrible terrorist leader is no more.</p>



<p>Our forces carried out the operation with their signature preparation and precision, and I directed the Department of Defense to take every precaution possible to minimize civilian casualties.</p>



<p>Knowing that this terrorist had chosen to surround himself with families, including children, we made a choice to pursue a special forces raid, at a much greater risk than our &#8212; to our own people, rather than targeting him with an air strike.&nbsp; We made this choice to minimize civilian casualties.</p>



<p>Our team is still compiling their report, but we do know that as our troops approached to capture the terrorist, in a final act of desperate cowardice, he &#8212; with no regard to the lives of his own family or others in the building, he chose to blow himself up &#8212; not just with a vest, but to blow up that third floor rather than face justice for the crimes he has committed, taking several members of his family with him just as his predecessor did.</p>



<p>I’m grateful for the immense courage and skill and determination of our U.S. forces who skillfully executed this incredibly challenging mission.</p>



<p>The members of our military are the solid-steel backbone of this nation, ready to fly into danger at a moment’s notice to keep our country and the American people safe, as well as our Allies.</p>



<p>And I’m also grateful to the families of our service members.&nbsp; You serve right alongside your &#8212; these soldiers and sailors, Marines, special forces &#8212; the loved ones, giving them the strength and support they need to do what they do.</p>



<p>To our service members and their families: We are forever grateful for the &#8212; what you do for us, and we owe you a debt.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>We’re also aided by the essential partnership of the Syrian Democratic Forces.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to commend our dedicated intelligence community, the Department of Defense, and members of our national security team throughout the government whose meticulous and tireless work over the course of many months ensured that this mission succeeded.</p>



<p>This operation is testament to America’s reach and capability to take out terrorist threats no matter where they try to hide anywhere in the world.</p>



<p>I’m determined to protect the American people from terrorist threats, and I will take decisive action to protect this country.</p>



<p>&nbsp;And we’ll continue working with our close allies and partners &#8212; the Syrian Democratic Forces; the Iraqi Security Forces, including the Kurdish Peshmerga; and the more than 80 members of the global coalition &#8212; to keep pressure on ISIS, to protect our homeland.</p>



<p>We remain vigilant.&nbsp; We remain prepared.</p>



<p>Last night’s operation took a major terrorist leader off the battlefield.&nbsp; And it sent a strong message to terrorists around the world: We will come after you and find you.</p>



<p>Once again, today, we continue our unceasing effort to keep the American people safe and to strengthen the security of our Allies and partners around the world.</p>



<p>I want to thank you all.&nbsp; And may God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.</p>



<p>I’m heading off to New York right now; I’m late.&nbsp; And I thank you for your time.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>10:26 A.M. EST&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call By Senior Administration Officials On U.S. Counterterrorism Operations in&#160;Syria</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/03/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-u-s-counterterrorism-operations-in-syria/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 17:26:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Via Teleconference 8:49 A.M. EST MODERATOR:  Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us on short notice.  Today&#8217;s call is going to be on background, attributed to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and the contents will be embargoed until the President concludes his remarks later this morning, probably at about 9:45 a.m., but please watch the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"> Via Teleconference</p>



<p>8:49 A.M. EST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:  Good morning, everyone, and thank you for joining us on short notice.  Today&#8217;s call is going to be on background, attributed to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and the contents will be embargoed until the President concludes his remarks later this morning, probably at about 9:45 a.m., but please watch the feed and we will confirm when the embargo has lifted.<br><br>     Our speakers today are going to be [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].  We&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] and [senior administration official] for some opening comments, and then we&#8217;re happy to take your questions.<br><br>     SENIOR ADMINSTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thank you.  I will give about a 10-minute opening on what happened last night and then turn it over to [senior administration official].<br><br>     Operating on the President&#8217;s orders, U.S. military forces, last night, successfully targeted Abu Ibrahim al-Qurashi, also known as Hajji Abdullah, the leader of ISIS and the successor to Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi.<br><br>     Hajji Abdullah coordinated the group&#8217;s global terror operations to include directing operations that posed a direct threat to the American people and our partners around the world.<br><br>     He was a driving force behind the genocide of the Yazidi religious minority in northwestern Iraq in 2014 and the enslavement of thousands of young Yazidi girls, using rape as a weapon of war.<br><br>     He oversaw the network that included ISIS branches around the world, from Africa to Afghanistan.<br><br>     He was directly overseeing activities of ISIS across Iraq and Syria, which were seeking to reconstitute under his leadership.<br><br>     The world is a safer place with him gone.<br><br>     Let me provide some context on the President&#8217;s command and direction of yesterday&#8217;s operation, and then I&#8217;ll turn it over to my colleague at DOD to provide some updates and tactical aspects.<br><br>     This operation has been months in planning.  The President was first briefed on the operation in depth over a month ago by the operational commanders and after we learned that Hajji Abdullah was definitely in this site.<br><br>     The President was regularly updated by his national security team on the planning details of this operation, to include a brief in the Oval Office earlier this week.<br><br>     He gave the final go on this operation on Tuesday morning, with the Secretary of Defense and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs, General Milley, in the Oval Office.<br><br>     Last night, the President monitored key aspects of the operation in real-time in the White House Situation Room, receiving reports from the Secretary of Defense, the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and General McKenzie and their teams.<br><br>     This operation is consistent with the President&#8217;s commitment to take out threats to the American people wherever they are and in any manner that does not require large deployments of U.S. forces.<br><br>     We are especially grateful for our local partner, the Syrian Democratic Forces, whose support was essential to the mission&#8217;s success and with whom we will continue to relentlessly pursue remnants of ISIS and its leadership.<br><br>     Let me say a few words about the operation itself.  The President, of course, directed the Department of Defense to take every precaution to minimize noncombatant casualties in this operation.<br><br>     That was particularly challenging here because Hajji Abdullah seemed to purposefully live in a residential building, with families on the first floor that we believe had nothing to do with ISIS and did not know who was living on the third floor.<br><br>     Hajji Abdullah never left the house.  He commanded by couriers who came and went.  He used these innocent people as his shield.<br><br>     It was due to the risk of this unwitting family and other civilians in the area that President Biden ordered this air assault operation, placing our own troops at risk to minimize the risk to others.  And they succeeded in that mission.<br><br>     In the earliest stages of the operation, a family on the first floor &#8212; one woman, one man, and a number of children &#8212; were safely removed from the site.<br><br>     Unfortunately, ISIS once again revealed its barbarity.  In a final act of cowardice and disregard for human life, Hajji Abdullah detonated a blast &#8212; a significant blast &#8212; killing himself and several others, including his wife and children.<br><br>     This is the same terrorist tactic of his predecessor: taking his own life and his own family, rather than face justice or stand and fight on his own.  Both these terrorist leaders murdered their own families. <br><br>     In this case, the blast was so large, on the third floor, that it blew bodies outside of the house and into the surrounding areas.<br><br>     All casualties at the site were due to the acts of ISIS terrorists inside the residence, including Hajji Abdullah, who set off this charge destroying most of the third floor.<br><br>     An associate of Hajji Abdullah &#8212; another ISIS terrorist, an ISIS lieutenant &#8212; barricaded himself and members of his own family in the second floor.  He and his wife engaged the assault force.  They were killed in the course of the operation.<br><br>After the second ISIS terrorist was eliminated, an additional number of children came out of the second-floor dwelling area and were safely removed from the site.<br><br>ISIS has made clear over and over again its utter and complete disregard for human life.  And that was clearly on display throughout the operation last night.<br><br>Looking ahead, the terrorist threats we face today are more ideologically diverse and geographically diffuse than 20 years ago.  Groups such as ISIS and al Qaeda have expanded across Africa and Southeast Asia.  These global networks and affiliates still aspire to attack the United States.<br><br>Years of sustained counterterrorism operations, pressure has forced them to shift their operating models and constrain their capabilities, but the threat remains serious.<br><br>Our partnership at the international, national, and local levels are vital to our success.  And this is not solely a military effort.  Working in concert with a global coalition of over 80 partners who are working to share intelligence, repatriate foreign fighters, prosecute ISIS leaders, and perhaps most importantly, deescalate regional conflicts and stabilize former ISIS safe havens to ensure these groups can not &#8212; never again resurge and threaten the American people.<br><br>President Biden has redoubled our commitment to stabilizing areas liberated from ISIS in Iraq and Syria, and recommitted to our vital partnerships in the region to include the counter-ISIS coalition, NATO, and our local and regional partners, all of whom remain essential to this ongoing effort.<br><br>The bottom line is that President Biden remains steadfast in his commitment to protecting the American people from the threat posed by terrorist groups.  Last night’s successful action took a major terrorist leader and his lieutenant off the battlefield, makes it clear that we will hold anyone accountable who seeks to harm Americans at home or around the world.<br><br>And I think the key facts of this operation, again, just show the barbarity of these ISIS terrorists.  All the casualties at the site were due specifically to their actions, including the significant detonation of Hajji Abdullah and the decision of his lieutenant to barricade himself on a second-floor room and engage U.S. assault forces.<br><br>And with that, I will turn it over to my colleague at the Department of Defense.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Thank you.  So, ladies and gentlemen, just to give you a little bit more background on the specific operational aspects to reinforce some of what was earlier said: So, this is an operation that has been long in planning and, from a tactical perspective, went precisely as expected. <br><br>The overall goal here was to remove Hajji Abdullah from the battlefield, and that was successful.  Much of what was built into this operation was explicitly and predictably based on protecting non-combatants.  We had good sense of who was in the building, as has already been briefed, and had taken numerous safeguards throughout the rehearsals and planning to protect those individuals. <br><br>What we can’t account for, of course, is actions taken by the targeted individuals themselves.  And in this case, it appears that they chose to detonate explosives or take other hostile action that resulted in the deaths of their relatives.<br><br>And with that, we can go through some of the details here of some of the operational mechanics for your benefit. <br><br>So, with the idea that noncombatants would be protected, it was an explicit decision to conduct a raid as opposed to a standoff strike of any sort.  With that, the raid force took a number of steps, including conducting call-outs &#8212; so, announcing their presence, asking people to leave the building, which resulted in some of the innocents coming out, as already has been briefed.  We were conscious of the fact that this is a residential area and there were also children in the building.<br><br>There were also multiple messages to local components around &#8212; this would be civilians and others &#8212; to ensure that they knew what was underway and didn&#8217;t in some way interfere, unintended or intended. <br><br>But intense care taken throughout the operation.  Much of this was built, again, on the idea that we knew that this was a complex target.<br><br>I will highlight a few other things just because we know it&#8217;s been out there already.  Once again, the target for this operation was the ISIS &#8212; overall ISIS Amir, Hajji Abdullah.  There were other reports of other targets &#8212; al Qaeda and others.  That&#8217;s not &#8212; that&#8217;s not truthful.<br><br>There was a situation in which one of our helicopters had a mechanical issue, and so it was properly disposed of some distance from the site; it had nothing to do with any kind of hostile action.  This was a mechanical issue, best we can tell at this early stage.<br><br>And then, further in the course of what was nearly two hours on the ground &#8212; which was the plan initially and continued to be the plan that was carried out &#8212; towards the end of that period, there was hostile action from local forces.  I think it&#8217;s important to keep in mind that this area is controlled by, in many cases, Hay&#8217;at Tahrir al-Sham, which is, by our estimate, a group that is a terrorist group; it certainly has al Qaeda affiliations.<br><br>At least some of those individuals engaged one of our helicopters, and we took action that resulted in, as we know it at this point, at least two enemy killed in action.  So some of the reports from the ground will highlight that as well.<br><br>That&#8217;s the operational laydown that augments what was already said.<br><br>I’ll turn it back over to [moderator].<br><br>MODERATOR:  Thanks very much.  Operator, we&#8217;re ready for questions.<br><br>     Q    Hi, thanks.  Real quick: Please give me a sense of how many civilians you estimate were killed.  And what was the mechanical issue with the helicopter?  And finally, was this ISIS leader in any way connected to the bombing at Abbey Gate?  Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Phil, let me just say: Some of the numbers that are reported out there do not align with our information.  We believe the number of children that came out of this site, according to the force that oversaw this and would monitor it in real-time, a number of eight children were removed from the site safely.<br><br>The casualties were all from the third-floor detonation of Hajji Abdullah&#8217;s &#8212; the third-floor dwelling area, and the barricaded &#8212; his lieutenant on the second floor.  Those were the only casualties on the site.<br><br>And some of the numbers out there don’t align with our information, but I can&#8217;t say specifically how many people Hajji Abdullah had with him when he decided to murder them.<br><br>On the second question, I&#8217;ll turn it over to DOD.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah, Phil, so the helicopter was a mechanical issue on the insertion; that, ultimately, that helicopter was able to extract itself from the immediate target area and, under control, able to land in another location where the decision was made to disable it and destroy it.<br><br>So, no casualties on the U.S. side throughout.  I think we highlighted that, but certainly not with the helicopter.<br><br>And then, on your last question on Abbey Gate: The Abbey Gate attack, of course, was ISIS Khorasan, which is an affiliate of ISIS and recognizes Hajji Abdullah as the overall Amir of ISIS.  So that&#8217;s the connection we would draw.<br><br>Over.<br><br>Q    Hi, yes.  Can you just describe again how it happened on the second floor with the lieutenant and who was killed and who was &#8212; how many survivors came out of that?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Eric, so the assault force on the second floor, we knew that Hajji Abdullah lived in this residence with another ISIS terrorist, lieutenant of his.  And he was involved in making sure that &#8212; even though Hajji Abdullah, again, never left his residence, because he used these &#8212; his own family and the residents &#8212; the family on the first floor, including a number of children &#8212; basically as his human shields.<br><br>The lieutenant kind of helped him run day-to-day operations.  Again, couriers came in and out.  So we knew this lieutenant was in the house.  And he barricaded himself in a room on the second floor and engaged U.S. forces, as did his wife.<br><br>After that, the threat from them was eliminated.  As I mentioned, four children came out of the second-floor dwelling areas.  The ISIS lieutenant and his wife were killed.  And they may have had their children &#8212; don&#8217;t know numbers &#8212; with them in that room.  So that&#8217;s something that still has to be confirmed. <br><br>But four &#8212; after that engagement, four children came out of the second floor and were safely &#8212; were brought to safety.<br><br>I have to say, I think you can get a sense of the complications of this and the care that went into it.  I&#8217;ve seen some reporting that the fact that the operation lasted two hours was unusual.<br><br>I think, as [senior administration official] said, everything here ran, really, according to clockwork.  And as the planning went, we were in the Situation Room for the two hours of the operation on the ground, as was planned.<br><br>And I think the complications was just because the leader of ISIS decided to run this global terror network in a house with an innocent family and others living on the first floor.<br><br>Over.<br><br>Q    Hey, good morning.  Thanks very much.  I&#8217;m wondering &#8212; I know you said that this mission was in planning stages for a long time.  Can you say whether the raid on a prison in Syria by ISIS and the recapturing of that, whether that played at all into the timeline of actually carrying out this operation?<br><br>And secondly, what is your assessment of the extent to which this killing will affect the future of ISIS in Syria and abroad?<br><br>And lastly, if you can just talk at all about any of the intelligence that led to that raid &#8212; what type of intelligence, and how the U.S. came to act on that intelligence.  Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  So this is [senior administration official].  Let me just &#8212; as the intelligence came in &#8212; that we believed we had a lead on Hajji Abdullah &#8212; of course, the President was briefed on this immediately and directed all of the whole interagency and national security team following these issues to make sure we did everything we possibly could to confirm his identity, and then, the President, obviously directing his military intelligence team to find the best mechanism to take this terrorist off the battlefield. <br><br>So, that whole process was really months &#8212; months in process.  The final fix of this certainty that this was Hajji Abdullah, I think it’s safe to say about early December or so. <br><br>And the President was briefed in December in detail, including, again, operational commanders came in to the Situation Room and briefed the President on a number of possible options for taking down this terrorist target, including the extraordinary complexity because of the number of children in the area, the families on the first floor, and the fact that Hajji Abdullah, with the exception of sometimes going to pray on his roof, never came out of the house.  He ran ISIS through couriers and by staying on the third floor of his residence. <br><br>So, an incredibly complex endeavor.  The President was directly involved throughout these deliberations, a constant give-and-take with his commanders and the national security team.  And, again, gave the final go for this operation on Tuesday morning in the Oval Office. <br><br>So, this was a process that was obviously months in work by our intelligence community to find a fixed location and our military team to develop options to present to the President. <br><br>So, that was basically the process here.<br><br>The prison &#8212; Hajji Abdullah directly was overseeing these operations in Syria, and including the prison, we believe.  But, no, the timing of the operation was not &#8212; was not tied to the prison operation at Hasakah.<br><br>[Senior administration official], anything else you want to add?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  I&#8217;ll just pick up on that theme, to answer the third question.  So, we think the impact of Hajji Abdullah being removed is going to be a blow to ISIS because he&#8217;s &#8212; even while Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi was the Amir, Hajji Abdullah was heavily involved in running many of the operations, including many of the external operations; as was already alluded to, was certainly influential in what was multiple threat streams against the Hasakah prison.<br><br>So, we anticipate that this is going to lead to disruption within ISIS.  He&#8217;s really one of the few remaining, shall we call them “legacy leaders.”  And so, this is a continued push that has been underway for quite some time to continue to remove the leadership elements of ISIS.<br><br>Over.<br><br>Q    Thanks, [senior administration official].  Let me ask you, kind of, broadly, in the aftermath.  The United States has killed Bin Laden and Baghdadi and now the latest ISIS leader.  What is the state of jihadism?  You mentioned how &#8212; its global spread.  How much harder is it for the United States to counter its efforts?  How much better off or worse off are we are than in the early days?<br><br>Secondly, can you describe the Situation Room and what, you know, some of the atmospherics of what Biden was doing.  Were there moments of tension?  Were there moments of &#8212; (inaudible) of work?<br><br>And finally, the SDF, how much of a role did it play in the initial intelligence &#8212; locating this guy, doing the legwork and the prep for this raid?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Let me hit some of that.  Just on the state of ISIS &#8212; of course, it wasn&#8217;t long ago, Robin, you were covering &#8212; they controlled a caliphate with 8 million people and were carrying out attacks all around the world in Paris, Brussels, elsewhere.<br><br>Obviously, it’s significantly degraded.  The leader of ISIS, Hajji Abdullah, hiding in a residential area, living on a third floor of a residential facility, but still in command of ISIS through a network of couriers and a global network, which obviously we have pretty good fidelity into.<br><br>So I think just the extraordinary work of our professionals who do this day-to-day, very difficult work are keeping the American people safe.  And I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official] for some more details on the state of the global jihad situation. <br><br>The SDF is essential.  We cannot do any of this without them.  So, just critical.  I don&#8217;t want to get into any details, but critical, vital enablers for operations like this. <br><br>In the Situation Room, we&#8217;ve monitored the operation in real-time, again, from shortly before the forces on the ground to when they landed.  The President came in with the Vice President and was receiving real-time reports from, as I mentioned, Lloyd Austin and General Milley and Frank McKenzie in real time.  So it was real-time monitoring.  We were able to monitor the situation with the helicopter mechanical failure.  The fact that &#8212; which we were all very focused on.  Obviously, tremendous tension, just given the number of children we knew were in the house, on the first floor. <br><br>It was a relief when one of the first reports was that when the team came on site and called everyone to come out, those on the first floor did come out and were led to safety.  Because, obviously, that was a key point of concern and why this operation was so complex. <br><br>There was then a report, before the assault force went into the house, of the significant explosion on the third floor, which later confirmed was Hajji Abdullah detonated basically the third floor &#8212; the third floor of the residence, killing himself and murdering his own family.  That happened fairly early in the operation. <br><br>And then, the second floor, a terrorist barricading himself and engaging our forces. <br><br>So this all kind of ran, you know, kind of in a linear fashion throughout the operation. <br><br>We also had the engagement, as [senior administration official] mentioned, with one of our helicopters, which we were able to &#8212; also able to monitor. <br><br>The President was obviously pleased with the reports from his commanders &#8212; tremendous praise for our team.  And when the team was wheels up, the President left the Situation Room.  He said, “God bless our troops.”  And I think Jake kept him informed throughout the night because they had to do another couple of stops to obviously get to safety.  And that was the operation.<br><br>So, a very &#8212; after months of planning, the President being very steeped in the operational details.  The commanders, as I mentioned, came into the Situation Room in December with a tabletop model of this site, which demonstrated where Hajji Abdullah was and the complexity of this operation.<br><br>This was not without significant, significant risk, both to our force, just given the forces who are in this area, as [senior administration official] mentioned, and also just the nature of this dwelling and the way Hajji Abdullah decided to conduct his affairs.  Incredibly complex, high risk. <br><br>And the President just &#8212; at the end just praised the professionalism &#8212; incredible professionalism of our forces.<br><br>Anything else to add, [senior administration official]?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Maybe just briefly on the overall global terrorist situation. <br><br>So I think, as already mentioned, ISIS has really been focused on &#8212; even though their caliphate has been degraded and many of their leaders have been killed or captured &#8212; continues to at least express the intent to conduct attacks against the United States and the West.<br><br>But the capability that has been pretty significantly degraded, starting with a series of leadership losses and then the rollback of the territory that [senior administration official] alluded to that they controlled until 2019 &#8212; we nonetheless see an expansion of ISIS branches and networks to over three dozen different countries.  But a lot of that is overseen from ISIS Khor &#8212; Hajji Abdullah and others.  <br><br>     We have, on balance, seen fewer attacks against the United States and Western interest in recent years.  And we assess that that’s a large function of the pressure that the coalition, some of the local allies, like the SDF and the United States, have placed on the network.<br><br>Over.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  If I can give one more &#8212; just one more anecdote.  We, of course, considered that Hajji Abdullah, on the third floor, might detonate himself in the operation, just given the record here &#8212; Baghdadi, for example.<br><br>And our engineers from our military team studying the structure, from the modeling they were able to do, did determine that if in the early phase of the operation Hajji Abdullah were to set off a detonation, that the structure would not collapse.  Because one of our main concerns was that he would kill himself and the structure would collapse, killing everyone else in the building.<br><br>So, we had high confidence that if this went according to how we thought it might go and did go &#8212; that he detonated himself and murdered his own family &#8212; it would not collapse the building and kill the other people in the building.<br><br>I doubt he knew that when he set off that detonation, so he obviously had every intent to take his own life and murder his own family, and at the very least, reckless disregard for everyone else in the building.<br><br>We had high confidence that if he did that, as he did, that the building would remain structurally sound as it did.  But I just want to emphasize, I doubt he knew that.  And it was probably his intent to kill everybody in that building.<br><br>But I think that just shows the level of detail that went into planning this operation.  And that fact was discussed a number of times with the President &#8212; if Hajji Abdullah were to detonate himself, would the building remain structurally sound, and it did.<br><br>Q    Hey, good morning.  Thanks for having this call.  Just a couple points of clarification.  One, with the helicopter mechanical issue, was there any kind of hard landing or crash?  And then, two, it sounds to me like U.S. forces were definitely outside the building when the explosion happened.  Do you have any estimate for how far away?  Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  So, the first issue on the helicopter: No, no hard landing.  This was the issue that resulted upon the immediate infil.  And the helicopter was able to depart the target location and move to another location, at which point it was determined that it was not going to be feasible for it to return to the next location for the return flight.<br><br>So, the decision was made to destroy it in place, well distant from the target location.  So, well beyond any kind of visual range.<br><br>On the question of the distance, as [senior administration official] already alluded to and as extensive experience over the years has shown, oftentimes the tactic used by these types of people barricaded, especially those known to wear suicide vests, is to explode themselves or the building they&#8217;re in.  So the assault force was well outside the range of what we assessed to be the likely explosive impact.  And as a result, none of the assaulters were injured in the initial blast, which, again, as [senior administration official] alluded to, occurred very quickly in the operation, shortly after the initial call-out and shortly after the family on the first floor departed.<br><br>So, we assessed that to have gone as we had &#8212; as part of our planning.  And certainly think that Hajji Abdullah  knew that his minutes were numbered, or he was at least going to be captured, and decided to take out not only the third floor but also the women and children with him.<br><br>Over.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Thanks, everyone.  That concludes our call today.  A reminder that we were on background, attributed to “senior administration officials” and that the contents of this call are embargoed until the President finishes speaking this morning.<br><br>We expect that he will go out shortly after 9:30 and give brief remarks.  So, hopefully, that will be before 10:00 a.m. when we&#8217;re able to lift the embargo.<br><br>Thanks all for joining, and have a good day.  Bye-bye.<br><br>9:19 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/03/statement-by-president-joe-biden-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 12:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=46515</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last night at my direction, U.S. military forces in the northwest Syria successfully undertook a counterterrorism operation to protect the American people and our Allies, and make the world a safer place. Thanks to the skill and bravery of our Armed Forces, we have taken off the battlefield Abu Ibrahim al-Hashimi al-Qurayshi—the leader of ISIS.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Last night at my direction, U.S. military forces in the northwest Syria successfully undertook a counterterrorism operation to protect the American people and our Allies, and make the world a safer place. Thanks to the skill and bravery of our Armed Forces, we have taken off the battlefield Abu Ibrahim al-Hashimi al-Qurayshi—the leader of ISIS. All Americans have returned safely from the operation. I will deliver remarks to the American people later this morning. May God protect our troops.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
