<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:58:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>United&#160;States to Host Ninth Summit of the Americas in&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/12/united-states-to-host-ninth-summit-of-the-americas-in-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is preparing to host the Ninth Summit of the Americas in early Summer 2022. &#160;The Summit has taken place approximately once every three years since 1994 and is the only meeting of all leaders from the countries of North, South, and Central America and the Caribbean.&#160; This will be the first time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States is preparing to host the Ninth Summit of the Americas in early Summer 2022. &nbsp;The Summit has taken place approximately once every three years since 1994 and is the only meeting of all leaders from the countries of North, South, and Central America and the Caribbean.&nbsp; This will be the first time the United States has hosted the Summit since the inaugural meeting in Miami, in 1994. Additional details to follow.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on How His Build Back Better Agenda Will Lower Prescription Drug&#160;Prices</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/12/remarks-by-president-biden-on-how-his-build-back-better-agenda-will-lower-prescription-drug-prices/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 20:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 1:27 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon. Before I begin, let me say a few words about the pandemic &#8212; the pandemic of the unvaccinated.&#160; I know there are lot of people out there trying to turn a public safety measure &#8212; that is, children wearing masks in school so they can be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>1:27 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br><br>Before I begin, let me say a few words about the pandemic &#8212; the pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; I know there are lot of people out there trying to turn a public safety measure &#8212; that is, children wearing masks in school so they can be safe –- into a political dispute.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>And this isn’t about politics.&nbsp; This is about keeping our children safe.<br><br>I saw a video and reports from Tennessee of protestors threatening doctors and nurses who were before a schoolboard making the case that, to keep kids safe, there should be mandatory masks.&nbsp; And as they walked out, these doctors were threatened, these nurses were threatened.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, our healthcare workers are heroes.&nbsp; They were the heroes when there was no vaccine.&nbsp; Many of them gave their lives trying to save others.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re heroes again with a vaccine.&nbsp; They&#8217;re doing their best to care for the people refusing to get vaccinated &#8212; unvaccinated folks who are being hospitalized and dying as a result of not being vaccinated.<br><br>To the mayors, school superintendents, educators, local leaders who are standing up to the governors politicizing mask protection for our kids &#8212; thank you, thank you as well.&nbsp; Thank God that we have heroes like you, and I stand with you all, and America should as well.<br><br>Now, let me turn to the focus of today’s remarks.&nbsp; There aren’t a lot of things that almost every American can agree on.&nbsp; But I think it’s safe to say that all of us &#8212; whatever our background, our age, or where we live -– can agree that prescription drug prices are outrageously expensive in America.<br><br>Today, I’d like to talk about how we&#8217;re going to help millions of Americans save money and ease their burdens by lowering the cost of prescription drugs.<br><br>Let me start by acknowledging the groundbreaking and lifesaving work that many pharmaceutical companies are doing.<br><br>Look no further than the vaccines they are manufacturing and delivering that are helping us beat this pandemic and save lives.<br><br>But we can make a distinction between developing these breakthroughs and jacking up prices on a range of medications for a range of everyday diseases and conditions.<br><br>Right now, right here in America, we pay the highest prescription drug costs of any developed nation in the world.&nbsp; Let me say that again: of any developed nation in the world.&nbsp; About two to three times what other countries pay.<br><br>Last week, in the Oval Office, I hosted a small-business owner named Gail from Denver.&nbsp; She’s 60 years old.&nbsp; When she was 11, she was diagnosed with Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; For nearly 50 years, she’s had to take insulin to stay alive.<br><br>But you know what she told me?&nbsp; She said she doesn’t worry about becoming blind or her blood sugar dropping dangerously low &#8212; the natural worries of anyone with Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; She worries about being able to pay for her prescription drugs.<br><br>During our conversation, she pulled out a vial of insulin from her bag.&nbsp; In 2001, she said, that single vial cost $32 a bottle.&nbsp; Today, that exact same bottle, with the same exact formula &#8212; no changes &#8212; costs $280 per bottle.<br><br>Gail and her husband work hard.&nbsp; They spend wisely.&nbsp; But because of the cost of her prescription drugs, her husband may not be able to retire.&nbsp; They drive the same car, she said, she&#8217;s had for 17 years, unable to afford repairs or a new one.&nbsp; And Gail is not alone.<br><br>It’s estimated that more than 34 million Americans &#8212; 10 percent of the population of the United States &#8212; have diabetes, including more than 1.5 million of those who have Type 1 diabetes.<br><br>And the outrageous cost, affecting everyone across the board, spanning every kind of condition and disease, is similar.<br><br>I remember what it was like for my mom as she got older and moved in with us.&nbsp; Her prescription drugs were so expensive<br>that it took me, my two brothers, and my sister &#8212; three siblings &#8212; chipping in to cover the thousands of dollars in monthly costs that she did &#8212; that she had to exhaust, rather than exhaust the little savings she had, for her prescription drugs.<br><br>It’s personal to so many of us and so many of you.&nbsp; You know, for more than 1 million Americans living with multiple sclerosis, one common drug for that disease costs $7,100 per month.&nbsp; The price has gone up 1,000 percent over the last 20 years without any change in the drug.&nbsp;<br><br>For more than 1 million people with rheumatoid arthritis, a common prescription drug used to cost about $1,350 per month; that was when it was introduced back in 2003.&nbsp; Today, the same drug costs $7,700 per month &#8212; over five times more expensive without any change.<br><br>For years, the price of many prescription drugs has dramatically outpaced inflation.&nbsp; These prices have put the squeeze on too many families and stripped them of their dignity.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been forced &#8212; we force people into terrible choices, between maintaining their health, paying the rent or the mortgage, putting food on the table.&nbsp; I mean, literally.&nbsp; And that’s the case for a lot of working families and seniors, even if you can get the care you need.&nbsp;<br><br>But, today, working families and too many seniors are struggling to make it work.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, one in four Americans who take prescription drugs struggle to afford them.&nbsp; Nearly 30 percent have skipped doses, cut pills in half, or &#8212; because they can’t afford the cost.<br><br>We have to change this, and we can.<br><br>My administration has already taken significant steps to lower the cost of prescription drugs.&nbsp; Last month, I signed an executive order that has the effect of improving competition in the economy, which will result in lower prescription drug fri- &#8212; drug costs.<br><br>Right now, when a drug company seeks permission from the FDA &#8212; the Food and Drug Administration &#8212; for a certain drug to get a patent, it’s allowed &#8212; the patent &#8212; it&#8217;s allowed to exclusively sell that drug without competition for up to 12 years.&nbsp; When that time period expires, other companies can come along, make the same exact drug, and sell it cheaper.&nbsp; It&#8217;s called a &#8220;generic drug.&#8221;<br><br>But unfortunately, it often takes a long time &#8212; years and years &#8212; for this to happen. &nbsp;That’s why I’ve instructed the federal Drug Administration to get these genetic [generic] drugs to consumers faster. &nbsp;This is going to increase competition, lower drug prices for everyone.<br><br>Research shows that prices could be cut by 25 to 33 percent and save $54 billion for consumers over the next 10 years.&nbsp; Makes a gigantic difference for an average family.<br><br>Secondly, I’ve ordered the FDA to work with states and Tribes to import prescription drugs safely from Canada.&nbsp; These are drugs that the FDA has determined are safe.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re going to make sure the drugs get to the states and Tribes safely.<br><br>Colorado estimates that their version of the Drug Importation Program is going to save $35 million to $60 million a year for people in Colorado, cutting the prices down by more than 60 percent for the cost of the same drug.&nbsp;<br><br>These things &#8212; and, by the way, you know, the company that&#8217;s making these drugs and causing &#8212; and charging exorbitant prices are selling the same drug in other countries at considerably lower prices.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like there&#8217;s another company always making this drug &#8212; same outfit.&nbsp;<br><br>These thing by themselves will be a great help.&nbsp; But to really solve the problem, we need Congress to act.&nbsp; That’s what my Build Back Better plan will do.<br><br>You know, there’s long been talk &#8212; I mean, a long time, since the days when I was back in the Senate &#8212; about giving Medicare the power to negotiate lower drug prices.<br><br>Now, Medicare takes care of millions of people.&nbsp; Medicare &#8212; my plan &#8212; going to &#8212; is going to allow that.&nbsp;<br><br>Every other type of healthcare service &#8212; from the cost of a doctor’s visit, how much a doctor can charge for a visit, hospital visits, crutches, wheelchairs &#8212; Medicare is allowed to negotiate and say, &#8220;We&#8217;ll pay no more, from the Medicare, than the following amount for those things.&#8221;<br><br>As I’ve said before, the only thing Medicare is not allowed to negotiate are prices for prescription drugs. My plan gets rid of that prohibition.<br><br>The proposal I made while I was running for President is that Medicare should negotiate drug prices across the board.<br><br>Congress is currently debating a more narrow vision letting Medicare negotiate some of the most expensive drugs, particularly from those companies that don’t face competition for that drug.&nbsp; We’re going to provide that competition through &#8212; we’re going to provide that competition through Medicare.&nbsp; Medicare is going to negotiate a fair price.<br><br>Right now, drug companies will set a price at whatever the market will bear.&nbsp;<br><br>Some of you may remember when I had the Moonshot going as &#8212; when I was Vice President.&nbsp; I met with 12 drug companies.&nbsp; And I agreed I would not name them at the time; it was just a private discussion.&nbsp; I said, “If any one of you came up with a drug that cured a particular type of cancer, what do you think you should be able to charge for it?”&nbsp; They said, “Whatever the market would bear.&nbsp; Whatever it will bear.”&nbsp;<br><br>But that often means a significant number of people can’t afford it under any circumstance and they’ll die without it.&nbsp; That’s unacceptable.&nbsp;<br><br>What we’re proposing is that we&#8217;ll negotiate a base &#8212; negotiate with the company based on a fair price, one that reflects the costs of the research and development and the need for providing for a significant prof- &#8212; a profit, but that&#8217;s still affordable for consumers.<br><br>And, by the way, if there was a significant amount that’s invested in it and a fair price is very expensive, we’re going to have to figure out society can provide for that drug that will save lives if people who can’t afford it.&nbsp; But that’s what we are trying to get done.&nbsp; And it has to get done.</p>



<p>But not only that my plan caps the amount that seniors<br>have to spend on prescription drugs each year at no more than about $3,000 a year, our plan says that drug companies<br>can only raise prices based on the rate of inflation after it’s determined how much they’ve invested and what a healthy profit constitutes.<br><br>Studies have shown that if we do this, we can save seniors thousands of dollars a year.<br><br>For example, an expensive drug for a cancer called &#8220;multiple myeloma&#8221; can cost $20,000 a month.&nbsp; Twenty thousand dollars a month.&nbsp; People who need that drug pay an average of $1,300 a month out of pocket even with Medicare.<br><br>What I’m proposing would reduce the total cost by thousands of dollars and seniors would not pay more than $250 a month on average.&nbsp; That’d be a game changer.<br><br>And by the way, it isn’t just seniors who will benefit.&nbsp; This would lower prescription drug prices for all Americans<em>.</em>&nbsp; And here’s how: If Medicare prices are available to private insurance companies, then it would reduce the cost of employer-based health insurance coverage.<br><br>What that means is: Once Medicare negotiates a lower drug price for its beneficiaries, an employer-based plan shouldn’t have to keep paying whatever the drug company demands.&nbsp; They should get access to the same drug for the same price as Medicare.<br><br>So, if you’re not on Medicare &#8212; you get your prescription drugs through your employer-based plan &#8212; your plan should pay the same price for that drug as someone on Medicare.<br><br>It means drug companies would have to sell their drugs to all distributors at the Medicare price or face up to a 95 percent excise tax. &nbsp;The savings for employers and employees would be billions of dollars a year.<br><br>We don’t have to stop there.&nbsp; My plan expands Medicare by adding dental, vision, and hearing, which would make a world of difference for millions of people.<br><br>And we can take some of that savings created when Medicare is no longer forced to overpay prescription drugs and use it to pay for these additional benefits and reduce premiums, improve access for people with coverage on Medicaid and the Affordable Care Act.<br><br>You know, at the same time, we can invest in medical breakthroughs that will also reduce the costs and save lives.<br><br>Right now, when Americans overpay for prescription drugs, too many pharmaceutical companies don’t use the profit nearly enough to innovate or research.<br><br>Too many companies use it on buying back their stock, inflate their worth, drive up CEO&#8217;s salaries and compensation, and find ways to box out the competition.<br><br>In fact, according to one study, from 2016 to 2020, pharmaceutical companies spent $577 billion in stock buybacks and dividends &#8212; $56 billion more than what they spent on<br>all research and development over that same period of time.<br><br>Look, folks, they should be able to make a significant prog- &#8212; prof- &#8212; profit, but why should we be paying two or three times what every other country in the world is paying for a similar drug?&nbsp; There&#8217;s so much we can do.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, at the Defense Department &#8212; for those of you who cover the Defense area &#8212; there’s something called the DARPA &#8212; the Defense Advanced Research Project Agency &#8212; set up exclusively within the Defense Department to seek out the cutting-edge research protects that enhance our national security.&nbsp; An outfit that came up with the Internet, GPS, and a lot of stealth technology &#8212; a lot of things.&nbsp;<br><br>I’m proposing we do a similar thing.&nbsp; I propose we spend $6.5 billion for a similar agency within the National Institute of Health &#8212; the NIH –- called &#8220;Advanced Research Project Agency&#8221; &#8212; ARPA-H &#8212; like DARPA &#8212; to help speed cutting-edge research on how to detect, treat, and cure diseases like Alzheimer’s, diabetes, and cancer.<br><br>It’s personal to so many people out there, and we can do this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not criticizing companies that aren&#8217;t prepared to spend billions of dollars on certain projects to research.&nbsp; I get it.&nbsp; But if they&#8217;re not, we should, to make sure the American &#8212; Americans are covered.&nbsp;<br><br>And here’s one other big thing that will help millions of Americans afford their prescription drugs: getting them affordable health insurance.<br><br>If anyone is worried about getting health insurance during the pandemic, there’s help today.&nbsp; For those who get their insurance through the Affordable Care Act, we’re covering more people, with better benefits, and with the premiums 40 percent lower.<br><br>That means the average premium has been cut by &#8212; from $104 a month to $62 a month.&nbsp; Sixty-two dollars a month for quality health insurance that covers doctors visits, hospital care, and prescription drugs.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, one third of the consumers are buying plans through the Affordable Care Act for less than $10 a month.<br><br>Earlier this week, I announced that more than 2.5 million Americans have signed up for coverage under the Affordable Care Act since I called for the Special Enrollment Period during this pandemic.<br><br>Folks, if you don’t have insurance, you can still sign up under the Affordable Care Act through Sunday, August the 15th.&nbsp; Just go to Healthcare.gov today, and get covered.<br><br>To all those folks expressing concern about rising costs for families, I urge you to support these basic reforms<br>that will allow drug companies to still make billions of dollars, as they have a right to do, but will address one of the largest out-of-pocket expenses that families face: prescription drugs.<br><br>We can do this.<br><br>Let me close with this: I’ve long said healthcare should be a right, not a privilege in this country.&nbsp; With my Build Back Better Plan, we have an opportunity to come together and get us even closer to that reality.&nbsp;<br><br>And the American people support it by overwhelming bipartisan margins.&nbsp; This isn’t a partisan issue.&nbsp; Alzheimer’s, diabetes, cancer &#8212; they don’t care if you&#8217;re a Democrat or Republican.&nbsp; This is about whether or not you and your loved ones can afford prescription drugs you need.<br><br>I look forward to Congress getting this done.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s another area &#8212; this is another area where you can come together and make a difference in people’s lives.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you.&nbsp; May God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>1:47 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/12/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-49/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 20:40:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  12:40 P.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning, and thank you for joining us.&#160; Dr. Walensky, Dr. Fauci, Dr. Nunez-Smith and I will keep our comments brief this morning so we can get to your questions. I’ll start with an update on our fight against the Delta variant.&#160; The Delta variant continues to drive&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference </p>



<p>12:40 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning, and thank you for joining us.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, Dr. Fauci, Dr. Nunez-Smith and I will keep our comments brief this morning so we can get to your questions.</p>



<p>I’ll start with an update on our fight against the Delta variant.&nbsp; The Delta variant continues to drive a rise in cases, with cases concentrated in communities with lower vaccination rates.</p>



<p>In the past week, Florida has had more COVID cases than all 30 states with the lowest case rates combined.&nbsp; And Florida and Texas alone have accounted for nearly 40 percent of new hospitalizations across the country.</p>



<p>We all know that vaccinations are the very best line of defense against COVID and how we end this pandemic.&nbsp; That is why we&#8217;ve been tireless in our efforts to get more and more Americans vaccinated.</p>



<p>For the first time since mid-June, we’re averaging about a half million people getting newly vaccinated each and every day. And overall in the last week, 3.3 million Americans rolled up their sleeve to get their first shot.</p>



<p>In the past month, we have doubled the average number of 12- to 17-year-olds getting newly vaccinated each day &#8212; critical progress as millions of adolescents start heading back to school.</p>



<p>Importantly, we’re seeing the most significant vaccinations progress in states with the highest case rates.</p>



<p>In fact, in the past month, we have nearly tripled the average number of shots each day in Arkansas and quadrupled in Louisiana, Alabama, and Mississippi.</p>



<p>So, we’re getting more shots in arms in the places that need them the most.&nbsp; That’s what it’s going to take to end this pandemic: more vaccinations, more Americans doing their part and rolling up their sleeve.</p>



<p>Over the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve seen strong actions from across the public and private sectors to help end the pandemic.</p>



<p>The President recently announced vaccination requirements for all 4 million federal workers, and we are working to apply similar standards to all federal contractors.</p>



<p>On Monday, the Department of Defense announced its plans to add COVID-19 vaccines to the list of vaccines required for more than 1.7 million active duty, reserve, and National Guard personnel.</p>



<p>And just this morning, the Department of Veteran Affairs and the Department of Health and Human Services announced new requirements: All 350,000 VA healthcare personnel and all 25,000 HHS healthcare personnel must now be fully vaccinated.</p>



<p>State and local governments; healthcare systems; businesses, small and large; universities; and other institutions are also stepping up.</p>



<p>Since last week, Washington State; Washington, D.C.; and Seattle have all adopted vaccination requirements, and more than 50 health systems across the country have announced that all staff need to be vaccinated, bringing the total to more than 200 health systems.</p>



<p>Just in the past 24 hours, Amtrak, McDonald’s, NBCUniversal, Discovery, and Capital One all announced new rules that workers must be vaccinated to return to the office.</p>



<p>California announced all schoolteachers and staff in the state, serving more than 6 million students, will be required to be vaccinated or tested weekly.</p>



<p>And the NEA and the AFT, two of the largest unions in the country &#8212; representing 5 million educators, childcare workers, and school staff &#8212; both came out in favor of school districts pursuing COVID-19 vaccination policies, including requirements for teachers and staff.</p>



<p>And across the country, nearly 700 colleges and universities have announced vaccination requirements, which will cover roughly 5 million students getting ready to head back to school.</p>



<p>So, clearly, vaccination requirements are gaining momentum across the country and are already covering tens of millions of workers, educators, college and university students, and healthcare providers.</p>



<p>They will help keep people and communities safe and help stop the spread of the virus.</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the bottom line: Through vaccination requirements, employers have the power to help end the pandemic.</p>



<p>As we drive progress on vaccinations, we are accelerating our efforts to help states respond to outbreaks caused by Delta.</p>



<p>Our COVID-19 Surge Response Teams have deployed more than 500 federal personnel, including hundreds of healthcare personnel in Louisiana, Mississippi, and Arizona to provide emergency medical care.</p>



<p>CDC is on the ground in Tennessee, Illinois, and Missouri to help local outbreak investigations and vaccination efforts.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve sent ambulances and paramedics to Missouri and Louisiana.&nbsp; And in Florida, we&#8217;ve stood up dozens of free testing sites and sent 200 ventilators to hospitals in the state.</p>



<p>And importantly, as Dr. Nunez-Smith will discuss, we sent five times as many lifesaving therapeutics to states in July compared to June.</p>



<p>I’ll close with this: We are doing everything we can to get people vaccinated and support state and local leaders on the ground.&nbsp; But as we have said from the start, ending this pandemic requires every American doing their part.</p>



<p>So, please, if you’re unvaccinated, get your shot.&nbsp; It’s free, it’s convenient, it works, and it’s never been more important.</p>



<p>With that, let me hand it over to Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp; Yesterday, CDC reported 132,384 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is about 113,000 cases per day, and this represents an increase of nearly 24 percent from the prior seven-day average.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is at about 9,700 per day, an increase of about 31 percent from the prior seven-day period.&nbsp; And the seven-day average of daily deaths has also increased to 452 per day, an increase of 22 percent from the prior seven-day period.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We continue to see cases, hospitalizations, and deaths increase across the country.&nbsp; And now, over 90 percent of counties in the United States are experiencing substantial or high transmission.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we have been saying: By far, those at highest risk remain people who have not yet been vaccinated.&nbsp; This week, we are taking two important steps in encouraging and improving vaccine protection for Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, for pregnant people who are at higher risk of severe illness from COVID-19, we are strengthening our guidance and recommending that all pregnant people or people thinking about becoming pregnant get vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We now have new data that reaffirm the safety of our vaccines for people who are pregnant, including those early in pregnancy and around the time of conception.&nbsp; These data build on previous evidence from three safety monitoring systems that did not find any safety concerns for pregnant people who are vaccinated late in pregnancy or for their babies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now these new data found no increase in the risk for miscarriage among people who received an mRNA COVID-19 vaccine before 20 weeks of pregnancy.</p>



<p>Clinicians have seen the number of pregnant people infected with COVID-19 rise in the past several weeks.&nbsp; The increased circulation of the highly contagious Delta variant, the general low vaccine uptake among pregnant people, and the increased risk of severe illness and pregnancy complications related to COVID-19 infection among pregnant people make vaccination for this population more urgent than ever.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, I want to take a moment to discuss what we are doing to help increase protection against COVID-19 for certain individuals who are moderately and severely immunocompromised.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we&#8217;ve been saying for weeks, emerging data show that certain people who are immunocompromised, such as people who have had organ transplant and some cancer patients, may not have had an adequate immune response to just two doses of the COVID vaccine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To be clear, this is a very small population.  We estimate it to be less than 3 percent of adults. </p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been working to identify how best to provide increased protection to these vulnerable people who are disproportionately impacted by severe outcomes due to COVID-19.&nbsp; FDA is working with Pfizer and Moderna to allow boosters for these vulnerable people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>An additional dose could help increase protections for these individuals, which is especially important as the Delta variant spreads.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Following the FDA&#8217;s decision, CDC will hold a meeting of its Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices tomorrow to discuss this issue and offer their expert insights and recommendations.&nbsp; We look forward to that discussion and to helping support this vulnerable population.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At this time, only certain immune compromised individuals may need an additional dose.&nbsp; Emerging data, including from a significant study published in the New England Journal of Medicine yesterday, show that there&#8217;s an enhanced antibody response after an additional dose of an mRNA COVID-19 vaccine in some immunocompromised people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This action is about ensuring our most vulnerable, who may need an additional dose to enhance their biological responses to the vaccines, are better protected against COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The science and resulting data in this pandemic are moving extremely rapidly.&nbsp; The U.S. government, in turn, is moving swiftly to analyze the science and make the recommendations most appropriate to protect Americans.&nbsp; We know our vaccines are safe and effective.&nbsp; And if you have not gotten a vaccine yet, please do so today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll turn things over to Dr. Fauci.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s becoming very clear now &#8212; if you go to the first slide &#8212; that we are dealing with a global outbreak of the Delta variant.&nbsp; I keep updating this slide; it now shows that at least 117 countries now have the Delta variant since it was first detected in June of 2020.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s just review some of the aspects of Delta to help put it into the context of what we&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp; We know the transmissibility &#8212; that it&#8217;s greater than the Alpha variant, at least two times as great.&nbsp; This makes a major difference in transmissibility.&nbsp; The viral load is up to 1,000 times greater in the nasalpharynx of people with Delta than Alpha, which is a mechanistic reason why you have such a tremendous increase in transmissibility.</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In previous reviews before this group, I have shown this slide, in checking the boxes as to the proof of protection against SARS-CoV-2 Delta variant. There was one glaring, missing check in previous iterations of this, and that was in the J&amp;J clinical effectiveness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I had showed you before this slide looking at data of immune responses in vitro.&nbsp; And this was the J&amp;J vaccine study, which showed that it elicited durable antibody and cellular responses against Delta with minimal decreases for at least eight months after immunization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We now have a slide that recently &#8212; a study that recently came out from South Africa and other southern African countries &#8212; it&#8217;s called the Sisonke study &#8212; involving about 478,000 healthcare workers.&nbsp; And this is real-world effectiveness against Delta, with a 91 to 96 percent protection against Delta, and then 71 percent protection against hospitalization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And remember, I showed you before that the durability of the immune response is out to eight months.&nbsp; And this is the first real-world data to show the effectiveness of J&amp;J from this challenging epidemiological setting of Delta, particularly in the context of people who might have HIV.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, if you look at breakthrough infections &#8212; which are inevitable with any vaccine, because no vaccine is 100 percent effective &#8212; as you can see, as we&#8217;ve seen in other studies, the breakthrough infections, namely infections that occur in the setting of full vaccination, were mild in 96 percent, moderate in 3 percent, severe in less than 0.05 percent, with death in less than 0.05 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;ll stop there and hand it over to Marcella Nunez-Smith.&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. NUNEZ-SMITH:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; And good afternoon to everyone.&nbsp; Today, I&#8217;ll just take a couple moments.&nbsp; I want to update you on vaccination equity, as well as on the importance of COVID-19 therapies.</p>



<p>So, first, when it comes to vaccinations and equity, important to note that the majority of people who are getting vaccinated through the direct federal programs are self-identifying as people of color &#8212; so that&#8217;s through community health centers, through dialysis centers, and at our Federal Retail Pharmacy partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a sense, President Biden made all adults in the U.S. eligible for vaccine on April 19th, and the majority of individuals receiving vaccines have identified as people of color.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that is notable progress, but it does not change the fact, as we&#8217;ve been discussing, that there is, of course, still more work to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the work in this phase of the vaccination campaign remains hyperlocal.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the Biden-Harris administration will continue to work just hand in hand with states and territories, Tribes, cities &#8212; always centering our partnerships with faith-based and community-based organizations, supporting that trusted outreach work that needs to be done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just want to provide a couple examples of the administration&#8217;s resource commitment to engage partnership.&nbsp; You know, in June and July, the federal administration awarded over $240 million to support community-based workers, community-based efforts &#8212; really expanding local, tailored opportunity to build both vaccine confidence and vaccine access.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This past week, the CDC officially launched the Partnering for Vaccine Equity program.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an investment of $120 million in grants that have been awarded.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And later this week, $20 million will be distributed specifically to Native Hawaiian communities.</p>



<p>In meeting people where they are, partnership is so powerful.&nbsp; And many of the incredible partners doing this work are health centers.&nbsp; This is National Health Center Week.&nbsp; And on behalf of the administration, I want to say thank you to health centers across the country: your commitment, your dedication reaching underserved groups &#8212; health centers on that frontline in vaccine administration, in testing, and in the administration of safe, effective therapies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Jeff mentioned earlier, these therapies do include monoclonal antibodies.&nbsp; And I want to talk a minute about those, but to people across the country, let me just reiterate: The best strategy to remain protected from the worst of COVID-19 is to get fully vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if you get COVID-19 and you&#8217;re at high risk, I want to assure you about these therapies.&nbsp; The monoclonal antibodies work.&nbsp; They are safe.&nbsp; They&#8217;re free.&nbsp; They keep people out of the hospital and help keep them alive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our surge teams have been working closely with states, increasing access, provider uptake, and patient confidence.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve conducted virtual trainings for physicians and health system officials.&nbsp; And this has been &#8212; you know, in Arizona, Nevada, Utah, Wyoming, with more to come in Alabama and elsewhere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in fact, in Arizona, we have a federal clinical team on the ground now, helping to set up and run two sites to provide these treatments.&nbsp; And those efforts are paying off.</p>



<p>Now, of the COVID-positive patients the Arizona team has treated so far, not one has required hospitalization after that treatment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we can also report that we&#8217;ve surged shipments to the states with the highest rates of community transmission.&nbsp; For example, Florida shipments increased over eightfold over the past month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in July, more than 108,000 treatments were shipped all over the country by the federal government.&nbsp; And as Jeff mentioned, this represents more than a fivefold increase nationally from June.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the course of the entire pandemic, more than 600,000 patients across the country have received monoclonal antibody treatments; that&#8217;s hospitalizations averted and lives saved.</p>



<p>So, the Biden-Harris administration continues to stand ready to assist states and territories and jurisdictions across the country to get more people connected to testing, to treatment, and, absolutely, to vaccination.</p>



<p>So, thank you so much.&nbsp; And with that, I&#8217;ll turn it back over to you, Jeff.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, well, thank you, doctors.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s open it up for questions.</p>



<p>First question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Sabrina Siddiqui at The Wall Street Journal.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much as always for doing the briefing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing a rising number of children being infected with COVID-19.&nbsp; So, I have a two-fold question: Is there data to suggest that the Delta variant is more virulent in children?&nbsp; And given that increase, are you still confident that schools can fully reopen for in-person instruction, or are you considering further changes to the guidelines?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s start with Dr. Fauci on the first part of the question, and then Dr. Walensky on school openings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Dr. Fauci.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; Well, in answer to the first part of your question: There&#8217;s no doubt that there are more children getting infected.&nbsp; As I mentioned in one of my slides, the Delta variant is much more highly transmissible than was Alpha.&nbsp; So, given that, you will see more children likely get infected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And since you have a certain percentage of children, even though the percentage is small, a certain percentage of children will require hospitalization.&nbsp; So, quantitatively, you will see more children in the hospital.</p>



<p>Regarding the severity of illness, there was a couple of studies, mostly international, which suggested that Delta was more severe in adults, namely causing more (inaudible) relative percentage of hospitalization and more severe disease.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With regard to children, this could possibly be the case, but we are not seeing this in a definitive way.&nbsp; The only thing we know for sure is that more infections mean more children will be in the hospital.</p>



<p>With regard to the school part &#8212; about that, I think we&#8217;ll go back to Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; And thank you, Sabrina, for that question.</p>



<p>What we know is that where we have higher rates of infection among children is where we have lower rates of vaccination, in general &#8212; higher rates of community transmission.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We do know how to keep our children safe.&nbsp; We know how to do so in schools.&nbsp; And we know that most of the infections that is coming in through &#8212; into schools is coming from high rates of disease in the community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the best way to keep our schools safe &#8212; and we know how to do it &#8212; is to vaccinate everyone who can be vaccinated, vaccinate family members of children who cannot yet be vaccinated, and then to follow the mitigation strategies in our school guidance, including masking in schools.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; The one thing I&#8217;d add there is, due to the passage of the American Rescue Plan several months ago, all schools have the resources to implement those mitigation strategies.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Josh Wingrove at Bloomberg.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on the plan to start shipping those 500 million Pfizer doses that was meant to commence this month?&nbsp; Has that started?&nbsp; And what kind of pace will we see in the coming weeks?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks, Josh.&nbsp; The 500 million Pfizer doses that were announced in June to be donated to the world &#8212; those shipments do begin this month, and we will ship a total of 200 million by the end of this year &#8212; this calendar year, with the remaining 300 million shipped no later than the first half of 2022.&nbsp; So, everything is on schedule there, Josh, and shipments are beginning in the next several days.</p>



<p>Next question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Weijia at CBS.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Kevin.&nbsp; And thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; My &#8212; a quick follow-up on Sabrina&#8217;s.&nbsp; What is the latest data about children and long-haul symptoms after they recover even from mild cases?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, Jeff, for you: Now that more entities are requiring vaccines, is the administration reconsidering something like a QR code or a passport to help verify people&#8217;s vaccination status?&nbsp; And if not, what are you doing to stop the proliferation of fake vaccine cards?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, on the children, long-COVID question.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Thank you for that question.</p>



<p>We are examining long COVID in children, and we are seeing long-COVID symptoms &#8212; mostly fatigue and headache.&nbsp; They appear to be happening at rates that are lower than they are in adults &#8212; in the 2 to 3 percent.&nbsp; But, of course, data with Delta and long COVID will need to be followed differently and longitudinally as we have been with Alpha.&nbsp; So more data to follow on that.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; You know, on to vaccination verification: There are a number of ways people can demonstrate their vaccination status.&nbsp; Companies and organizations and the federal government are taking different approaches.&nbsp; And, you know, we applaud this innovation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There will be no federal vaccination database.&nbsp; As with all other vaccines, the information gets held at the state and local level.&nbsp; But any system that is developed, in the private sector or elsewhere, must meet key standards, including affordability, being available both digitally and on paper, and, importantly, protecting people&#8217;s privacy and security.</p>



<p>The second part of your question &#8212; you know, we are aware of some cases of fraud or counterfeit COVID-19 cards being advertised on social media sites and eCommerce platforms.  While the practice is not widespread, you know, I will remind everyone that it&#8217;s a crime and the Office of the Inspector General, the Department of Health and Human Services is investigating these schemes.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Cheyenne Haslett at ABC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I want to follow up on a question from last week about the hospitalization rates for unvaccinated versus vaccinated people.&nbsp; The CDC has been saying it&#8217;s 97 percent of people winding up in the hospital who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; Has that number changed with Delta?&nbsp; And do you have better numbers on the efficacy, yet, Dr. Walensky?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; That 97 percent was data from January through May &#8212; January, sorry, through June.&nbsp; And, of course, with more and more people being vaccinated and with the Delta variant, those numbers are fluid, and we&#8217;re continuing to evaluate those.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Kelly Lienhard at Inside Health Policy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; There have been reports from CDC that over a million people have already gotten unauthorized third doses of mRNA vaccines.&nbsp; Do you know if private insurances and Medicare are still covering the administration fee for these shots even though they&#8217;re not recommended currently?</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, we are doing an evaluation on that just to make sure and understand &#8212; and we have the capacity to track this and to understand the practice.&nbsp; Many of these are occurring in the context of people who may believe they are &#8212; merit another shot, may be severely immunocompromised and are doing so in advance of our recommendations.</p>



<p>The one thing I want to highlight in the context of this is that it does undermine our ability to monitor safety in these contexts.&nbsp; So, we are asking people to follow our guidance, to follow what ACIP will say and the FDA will say in the coming day &#8212; several days, and to follow recommendations so we can we can follow safety signals here as well.</p>



<p>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Michael Erman at Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci said this morning on an interview that he believes boosters, in general, are an inevitability.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering how soon you expect that you might make a decision on that.&nbsp; And what sort of data are you looking for to make that decision?</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, when I made that statement &#8212; it&#8217;s a true statement that we believe, sooner or later, you will need a booster for durability of protection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Right now, you know, (inaudible), as we mentioned, we are evaluating this on a day-by-day, week-by-week, month-by-month basis, looking at any of a number of studies, both international and domestic studies.&nbsp; And as we&#8217;ve stated many times, right at this moment &#8212; apart from the immunocompromised, which was just discussed &#8212; we do not believe that others &#8212; elderly or nonelderly &#8212; who are not immunocompromised, need a vaccine right at this moment.&nbsp; But this is a dynamic process and the data will be evaluated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The one thing we are doing is we are preparing for the eventuality of doing that.&nbsp; So, if the data shows us that in fact we do need to do that, we&#8217;ll be very ready to do it and do it expeditiously.</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Yeah, I’ll just emphasize what Dr. Fauci ended with, which is if and when there is a decision, we are prepared.&nbsp; We have the supply, and people will be able to get a booster in a fast and efficient way &#8212; if and when the science dictates.</p>



<p>Thank you.  And I look forward to seeing everybody at the next briefing. </p>



<p>1:08 P.M. EDT      </p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/COVID-Press-Briefing_12August2021_for-transcript.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/COVID-Press-Briefing_12August2021_for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Build Back Better Investments in Care Will Boost Economic Growth and Help Businesses&#160;Thrive</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/12/fact-sheet-build-back-better-investments-in-care-will-boost-economic-growth-and-help-businesses-thrive/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 19:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday August 12th, Vice President Harris will meet with business leaders to discuss how the care provisions in the Build Back Better Agenda will help workers, businesses and the economy Leaders of Airbnb, Chobani, Etsy, Gap, Microsoft, Patagonia, Seventh Generation to join Vice President Harris at the White House Care Can’t Wait Coalition announces&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>On Thursday August 12<sup>th</sup>, Vice President Harris will meet with business leaders to discuss how the care provisions in the Build Back Better Agenda will help workers, businesses and the economy</em><br><br><em>Leaders of Airbnb, Chobani, Etsy, Gap, Microsoft, Patagonia, Seventh Generation to join Vice President Harris at the White House</em><br><br><em>Care Can’t Wait Coalition announces support from over 275 companies for care provisions in Build Back Better</em><br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, employers from across the country have stood together to make it clear that a strong care infrastructure is critical to their businesses and the U.S. economy.<br><br>They know that it is bad for business and the economy when working families do not have the support they need to work and find quality care for their children and older or disabled relatives. &nbsp;When workers don’t have adequate care for their families, they are more likely to experience care disruptions, which can translate to lower productivity, increased absenteeism, and higher turnover – all hurting the bottom line for businesses. For example, the <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=c26e82bdb6&amp;e=60572324a0">Work Institute’s 2020 Retention Report</a> estimates that replacing an employee costs as much as 30% of a worker’s annual salary.<br><br>And, with a large portion of the workforce facing care challenges, it is harder for businesses to recruit and retain a skilled, stable workforce so that they can compete globally. The United States has been falling behind its economic competitors in terms of the share of prime age men and women (ages 25 to 54) participating in the labor force, in part due to care challenges. One study estimates that&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=6fab819cef&amp;e=60572324a0">lack of access to “family-friendly” policies</a>, such as child care and paid parental leave, explains nearly a third of the decline in U.S. women’s labor force participation relative to other OECD countries. Stagnant or falling labor force participation not only hurts businesses directly, but it also represents a missed opportunity to increase U.S. GDP growth.<br><br>The President’s Build Back Better agenda has a robust plan to invest in care —making child care and long-term care accessible and affordable, and establishing national paid family and medical leave. These policies are a win-win for both employees and employers and will strengthen our economy as a whole. One economist finds the&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=a57e7cabfc&amp;e=60572324a0">President’s plan</a>, and especially its investments in the care economy, would <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=189bfdc01a&amp;e=60572324a0">increase labor force participation</a> by almost a full percentage point—with even greater gains for women—and <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=02abcb172b&amp;e=60572324a0">boost the economy’s real GDP growth</a> by 10 to 15 basis points in the long-term. &nbsp;<br><br><strong>Child Care</strong><br><br><a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=684d2638da&amp;e=60572324a0">About one-third</a> of the U.S. workforce live with children under the age of 14. The COVID-19 pandemic has highlighted how the strain of child care hurts businesses and the economy. <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=e6bfd8b9dd&amp;e=60572324a0">U.S. Chamber of Commerce Foundation</a> research found that two-thirds of working parents faced child care instability due to COVID-19, and that businesses have seen large numbers of workers leaving due to child care issues. But, families have long faced a caregiving crisis. Child care costs have been rising for decades, and even before COVID-19, <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=06b29853d0&amp;e=60572324a0">43 percent</a> of parents with children under age six reported struggling to find adequate child care for their children.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Child care increases worker productivity and business revenue.</strong> One <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=c8ebe145d8&amp;e=60572324a0">study</a> found a $57 billion annual cost to the economy due to child-care related lost earnings, productivity, and revenue, including nearly $13 billion that employers shoulder due to workers’ inability to access high-quality, affordable care.</li><li><strong>Access to affordable, high-quality child care would increase workforce participation, providing a more robust recruitment pipeline for businesses</strong>. Lack of childcare can make it logistically difficult for parents to work outside the home. Indeed, many parents <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=37dd9a1d59&amp;e=60572324a0">report</a>&nbsp;that they work fewer hours than they need to or would prefer in order to care for their young children, and <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=cf9dc48774&amp;e=60572324a0">86 percent</a> of primary caregivers say problems with child care hurt their efforts or time commitment at work. The lack of adequate child care especially puts a strain on working mothers. In a <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=6424177cd1&amp;e=60572324a0">study</a> of corporate America in 2020, one in four mothers considered slowing down their careers – including by reducing their hours, moving to part time, or taking a less demanding job – or leaving the workforce altogether. <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=8ccbb66ae1&amp;e=60572324a0">Studies</a> of child care subsidies find that increased access to child care can increase the likelihood parents are <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=f801bcc1fa&amp;e=60572324a0">employed and employed full-time</a>.</li><li><strong>Child care investments would boost family incomes, which can support business and economic growth.</strong> Child care has helped women enter the workforce, and over the past 40 years, as more women entered the labor force and brought home larger paychecks, they have driven&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=d1e9fa20b3&amp;e=60572324a0">91 percent</a>&nbsp;of the income gains experienced by middle-class families.&nbsp;When families have higher incomes, they can better save for retirement and purchase needed goods and services, driving consumer demand, and supporting business and economic growth.</li><li><strong>Investments in child care would make the U.S more competitive.</strong> The United States now lags behind other developed countries in&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=9c1d76c71b&amp;e=60572324a0">investments</a>&nbsp;in child care and early education, one major reason its labor force participation is declining while those of its competitors rise. Investments in child care can help reverse that trend, helping American businesses win the 21<sup>st</sup> century.</li></ul>



<p>&nbsp;<br><strong>Paid Family and Medical Leave</strong><br><br>The United States is one of the only countries in the world that does not guarantee paid leave of any kind —&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=246c57ee5f&amp;e=60572324a0">95 percent of the lowest wage workers</a>, who tend to be who <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=e34f2eb79f&amp;e=60572324a0">predominantly women&nbsp;</a>and&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=bc27ade0b6&amp;e=60572324a0">workers of color</a>, lack any access to paid&nbsp; leave. But, comprehensive paid family and medical leave is good for business.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Comprehensive paid family and medical leave policies are associated with higher profits for businesses. </strong>The adoption of a paid leave program is associated with a <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=3db3365ffb&amp;e=60572324a0">4.6 percent increase</a> in revenue per full-time employee and 6.8 percent increase in profit per full-time employee. State programs across the country have demonstrated that paid leave can increase recruitment, retention, productivity and morale. For example, in California, most employers surveyed found that adoption of the paid leave program was associated with either positive or neutral impacts on <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=902d7b2b28&amp;e=60572324a0">profitability and performance</a>, and some employers surveyed reported cost savings.</li><li><strong>National paid family and medical leave levels the playing field for small businesses.</strong> Less than one-third of small businesses with 100 or more employees offer paid &nbsp;leave, and that number drops to 14 percent for small businesses with fewer than 50 employees. Small businesses may lack the capital and the scale to provide paid leave, even when owners want to provide that benefit. While some small businesses may have the resources to offer paid leave to certain employees or on an ad hoc basis, the need for such leave is often unpredictable, and small businesses may not be able to offer leave consistently, equitably, or when it would be most beneficial to both the business and employees. <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=2b973a99c4&amp;e=60572324a0">Small businesses support</a> paid leave programs which help reduce business costs and level the playing field with larger employers, while also allowing small-business owners themselves the ability to take paid leave and care for their own families too.</li><li><strong>Businesses say paid family and medical leave would improve their resiliency.</strong> <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=0a4075cd38&amp;e=60572324a0">More than 75 percent of businesses agree</a> that a national paid leave policy would help them be better positioned to weather future public health emergencies and economic crises.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>&nbsp;<br><strong>Long-term Care</strong><br><br><a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=43dc082853&amp;e=60572324a0">Fifty-three million adults</a> are unpaid caregivers for an adult or child with disabilities. Over 60 percent of those caregivers work and, of those, 61 percent reported an impact on their work.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Investments in long-term care can increase workforce stability and boost workforce participation</strong>. According to a <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=b32f91e1d0&amp;e=60572324a0">2019 Bank of America survey</a>, working caregivers report missing an average of 12 hours per month of work because of their caregiving responsibilities. And, <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=5b5ce74eab&amp;e=60572324a0">10 percent</a> left work entirely.</li><li><strong>Long-term care investments will be especially critical in the coming years. </strong>The demand for home- and community-based long-term care will increase significantly with the aging of the population – <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=56a2e55103&amp;e=60572324a0">by 2060</a>, there will be nearly 95 million adults over the age of 65, almost twice the number of adults over the age of 65 in 2016. Despite the growing demand for long-term care, there aren’t enough paid caregivers to provide these critical services. An analysis conducted in <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=2c3d7e4a31&amp;e=60572324a0">2017</a> estimates that there will be a national shortage of 151,000 direct care workers by 2030 and 355,000 workers by 2040.</li><li><strong>Improving the quality of caregiving jobs is necessary to address the existing – and looming – workforce shortage issue</strong>. Paid caregivers – who are disproportionally women of color – have been <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=3398fc8917&amp;e=60572324a0">underpaid and undervalued</a> for far too long. Wages for essential home care workers are approximately <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=15d2947f55&amp;e=60572324a0">$13 per hour</a>, putting them among the lowest paid workers in our economy. In fact, <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=3550c293b1&amp;e=60572324a0">one in six</a> workers in this sector live in poverty. Improving caregiver wages is critical to bolstering our caregiving workforce, so they can enable more Americans to re-enter the workforce, pickup more hours, or face fewer care disruptions.</li></ul>



<p><br><strong>The President’s Plan Will Invest in Care so Businesses Can Compete</strong><br><br>President Biden’s plan:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Cuts costs of child care by more than half for most American families – and enables them to access more convenient, higher quality care where workers receive a better wage and benefits. </strong>The President’s plan fully covers the cost of high-quality child care for young children for the most hard-pressed working families, and ensures that families earning up to 1.5 times their state’s median income will pay no more than seven percent of their income for high-quality child care for all children under age five.</li><li><strong>Supports employers to build on-site child care facilities. </strong>The President is calling for an expanded tax credit to encourage businesses to build child care facilities at places of work. Employers will receive 50 percent of the first $1 million of construction costs per facility so that employees can enjoy the peace of mind and convenience that comes with on-site child care. </li><li><strong>Creates a national, comprehensive paid family and medical leave program</strong> that will provide a total of 12 weeks of leave per year for parental, family care, and personal illness/safe time by year 10 of the program, as well as three days of bereavement leave per year so that workers aren’t forced to choose between their jobs and their caregiving responsibilities.</li><li><strong>Expand access to quality, affordable home- or community-based care</strong>, while improving quality of care by boosting wages of caregivers<strong>.</strong></li><li><strong>Provides low- and middle-income families a tax cut based on care expenses. </strong>Families can receive a tax credit up to half of their expenses related to caring for a child or a loved one with disabilities. This would make permanent the dramatic expansion of the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit (CDCTC) enacted in the American Rescue Plan. With this expanded credit, families earning $125,000 can receive up to a total of $4,000 for one dependent or $8,000 for two or more. And, families earning up to $400,000 get at least as generous of a credit as they receive today.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden on the Fourth Anniversary of the Events at Charlottesville,&#160;Virginia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/12/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-fourth-anniversary-of-the-events-at-charlottesville-virginia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 17:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Four years ago today in Charlottesville, Virginia the battle for the soul of America was laid bare for all to see. The forces of hate and violence were summoned from the shadows as Neo-Nazis, Klansmen, and white supremacists descended on a historic American city. With torches in their hands and veins bulging from their necks, they&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Four years ago today in Charlottesville, Virginia the battle for the soul of America was laid bare for all to see.<br> <br>The forces of hate and violence were summoned from the shadows as Neo-Nazis, Klansmen, and white supremacists descended on a historic American city. With torches in their hands and veins bulging from their necks, they spewed the same antisemitic bile that was heard in Germany in the 1930s and with the same beatings and bigotry we saw in Jim Crow America for nearly a century.<br> <br>But what they didn’t account for was the extraordinary force of American goodness and decency. In that moment and as we’ve seen throughout our history, Americans of different races, religions, and backgrounds stood ground and stayed true to the promise of our nation: that we are all created equal and deserve to be treated equally throughout our lives.  <br> In that moment, the courage of the nation was summoned. One brave woman, Heather Heyer, a young civil rights activist, was murdered while representing the best of us. Her life and activism are reminders that while we have never fully lived up to the promise of America, we have never fully walked away from it either.<br> <br>What happened in Charlottesville – and securing the promise of America for every American – motivated me to run for president and now motivates my Administration’s work to ensure that hate has no safe harbor in America.<br> <br>In my first week in office, I signed an executive order establishing whole-of-government effort to advance racial equity and support underserved communities, and a presidential memorandum directing all federal agencies to combat the resurgence of xenophobia against Asian Americans that we’ve seen during this pandemic.<br> <br>And in May, I signed into law the COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act that empowers the U.S. Department of Justice and our entire Administration to address the critical problem of hate crimes being underreported. The law includes provisions in Heather Heyer’s name that will help state and local governments to ensure hate crimes information is more accessible to the public.<br> <br>Heather’s mother joined me at the bill signing. As I told her on that day, I know it’s hard. Even with the significance of the law being changed, it’s like getting the news of her death just seconds ago.  It takes enormous courage. It’s also especially hard on this day of commemoration. Jill and I are thinking about Heather and her family.<br> <br>And we know there is more work we must do as a nation – as we saw with the mob of insurrectionists at the United States Capitol on January 6<sup>th </sup>that joins the horror we saw in Charlottesville as shameful chapters in our history.<br> <br>We must acknowledge what America’s intelligence community has already confirmed, and what Charlottesville and so many other communities know all too well: the most lethal terrorist threat to our homeland in recent years has been domestic terrorism rooted in white supremacy.  We cannot ignore it.  We must confront the spread of hate-fueled violence in every form.<br> <br>To that end, in June, my Administration laid out America’s first-ever comprehensive effort to take on the threat of domestic terrorism.  We are doing so by countering and reducing online radicalization and recruitment to violence, disrupting the networks that inspire violence by domestic terrorists and hate groups, and providing new resources for communities to build up local resilience against the spread of hate.<br> <br>Charlottesville is an example of how this is the work of all of us.<br> <br>In the hours and days after what happened there, America’s moral conscience stirred. The nation’s military, business, and labor leaders took a firm stand. Political, community, and faith leaders raised their voices. Religious leaders held a prayer service at St. Paul’s Memorial Episcopal Church the night before the rally and marched in the streets the next day. When the Neo-Nazi marchers passed Charlottesville’s only synagogue, Beth Israel, the congregation continued worship services, stood up to the hate, and helped their neighbors. And we should never forget the courage of that small group of University of Virginia students who stared down the mob and did not flinch.<br> <br>While it may come with enormous pain and cost, the greatness of America is that at our best, we meet President Lincoln’s appeal to embrace the “better angels of our nature.”<br> <br>That’s what we must do – together – to win this battle for the soul of America.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Virtual Meeting with Elected Officials to Discuss the Importance of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/12/remarks-by-president-biden-at-virtual-meeting-with-elected-officials-to-discuss-the-importance-of-the-infrastructure-investment-and-jobs-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 17:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via TeleconferenceSouth Court Auditorium (August 11, 2021) 3:13 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, folks.&#160; Sorry I&#8217;m a few minutes late.&#160; It&#8217;s good to see you all.&#160; Gretchen, how are you?&#160; I understand we have another 95,000 people on this Zoom, but apparently there&#8217;s a large number of folks on. I&#8217;m going to begin by thanking&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>South Court Auditorium</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(August 11, 2021)</p>



<p>3:13 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, folks.&nbsp; Sorry I&#8217;m a few minutes late.&nbsp; It&#8217;s good to see you all.&nbsp; Gretchen, how are you?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I understand we have another 95,000 people on this Zoom, but apparently there&#8217;s a large number of folks on.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to begin by thanking you all &#8212; all those of you I can&#8217;t see as well &#8212; for signing on to help pass the infrastructure bill.&nbsp; It mattered a lot.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the first big bipartisan thing we&#8217;ve done in a long while, and I think it&#8217;s long overdue.&nbsp; And it is great to see you all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, the Senate passed the bipartisan infrastructure bill, in no small part because of all of you, in a significant milestone in the road toward making what we all know are long-overdue and much-needed investments.</p>



<p>As Gretchen, when she ran, said, &#8220;Just fix the roads, damn it.&#8221;&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re going to do more than that this time around.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank you for the work and for all of you &#8212; and my administration, with the members of Congress, with the media &#8212; to highlight the need to make these investments in our nation&#8217;s infrastructure.</p>



<p>As mayors, governors, Tribal and county leaders, state and local officials at every level, you know that there&#8217;s no such thing as a Democratic road or a Republican bridge.&nbsp; But you do know what&#8217;s not working, and you know what it means to be accountable to the people you serve and to focus on solving real problems people are facing in your communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you also know that often states and cities and counties can&#8217;t do it alone.&nbsp; They need the federal government to be a partner, solving problems.&nbsp; And being a partner is what we&#8217;re supposed to be doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s the approach we&#8217;ve been taking with this bipartisan infrastructure bill.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to create literally millions of jobs &#8212; good-paying jobs, putting America on a path to win the 21st century global economy.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re in a competition with many other nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it makes key investments to put people to work in cities, small towns, and rural communities.&nbsp; I believe it&#8217;s a historic investment in roads and rail, in transit and bridges, in clean energy and clean water.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to enable us not only to build back, but to build back better than ever before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Across America, more than 45,000 bridges are structurally deficient.&nbsp; Let me say that again: 45,000 bridges in America are structurally deficient.&nbsp; One out of every five miles of highway is in disrepair.&nbsp; And this bill makes the largest investment in bridges since the creation of the Interstate Highway System.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, 10 million households, and 400,000 schools, daycare centers &#8212; they lack safe drinking water.&nbsp; This bill is going to allow us to replace 100 percent of the nation&#8217;s lead pipes and service lines so every child in America can turn on a faucet in their school or at home and drink clean water.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s what this infrastructure is all about today.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to need to build the infrastructure for tomorrow, not just today.&nbsp; We got to build back not just &#8212; I know you&#8217;re tired of hearing me say it, but build back better that it was before we hit this God-awful circumstance we found ourselves in.</p>



<p>This bill is going to deliver high-speed Internet to every American.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll build a national network of 500,000 electric vehicle charging stations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And here is another important part of the bill: Nearly 90 percent of the jobs created by this bill don&#8217;t require a college degree.&nbsp; This is the ultimate blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re going to do it without raising taxes by one cent on anyone making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we wouldn&#8217;t even support a gas &#8212; increased gas tax.</p>



<p>As we did with the Transcontinental Railroad and the Interstate Highway System, we&#8217;re going to once again transform America and propel this nation into the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I believe that passing this bill will also do something else: It will help ease the years of gridlock in Washington and show the American people that their government can and will work for them again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to still have big disagreements, but it&#8217;s happening at a critical time, because now is the moment to build our &#8212; on our momentum.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, we&#8217;ve added more than 4 million new jobs since my first day in office six months ago.&nbsp; The unemployment rate is the lowest since the pandemic hit.&nbsp; We&#8217;re delivering a tax cut to families with children every single month.&nbsp; And those who get their health insurance through the Affordable Care Act, we&#8217;re covering more people, and we&#8217;re able to do it at lower premiums by up to 40 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it’s a battle with Delta virus.&nbsp; We have &#8212; we have the tools.&nbsp; We have the vaccinations.&nbsp; We have &#8212; we need to vaccinate more Americans and the tools to keep our economy growing and growing.&nbsp; But we got to get more people vaccinated.&nbsp; I know you all know that well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We just have to act.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what I want to talk about today.&nbsp; I want to hear from you about these investments: what they&#8217;re going to mean for your states and communities; what we could have done better, if there&#8217;s things we could have done; and why it is so urgent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so let me start with Governor Whitmer.&nbsp; We all remember your campaign slogan, Gov &#8212;</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; that &#8212; you’ve been focused on trying to fix the roads in your state since you took office.&nbsp; And what &#8212; what &#8212; what will this federal investments in Michigan roads and bridges do and mean to your state&#8217;s economy and job creation?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; and then I want to hear from the rest of you.&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll go one at a time, if that&#8217;s okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; Sounds perfect.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Gretchen, fire away.&nbsp;</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, Mr. President.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so glad to be here with you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s my honor to be here as the governor of the great state of Michigan as we come together to make the largest infrastructure investment in American history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Mr. President, you mentioned it, but I ran on fixing the damn roads.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I remember.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And you know, and it&#8217;s fixing the dams and roads.&nbsp; You know, don&#8217;t think I haven&#8217;t noticed that so many other governors and Cabinet Secretaries have been stealing that tagline.&nbsp; But, of course, it&#8217;s because it is true across the nation, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anyone can use that phrase, but just make sure that the mom in Flint who first said that to me back in 2018 gets a little bit of credit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, today, I&#8217;m especially proud to have so many partners in Washington who share our mission to fix the damn roads.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank you, Mr. President, and Vice President Harris for making infrastructure a real priority.&nbsp; And because of your leadership and dedication, countless families, communities, and small businesses in Michigan and across the country are going to benefit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to thank all the senators who worked across the aisle to get this done &#8212; including Michigan&#8217;s own Senator Debbie Stabenow and Senator Gary Peters, who&#8217;ve been tireless champions for Michiganders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m so glad to be here speaking alongside Mayor Dyer and Mayor Lumumba, Commissioner Hausmann, and Chief Hoskin.&nbsp; This diverse group shows just how wide-ranging an impact that this bill is going to have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act takes a big step toward helping Michigan modernize and develop the infrastructure we need to effectively connect our communities and continue our economic jumpstart.</p>



<p>The bold package is going to create millions of good-paying jobs; fix our crumbling roads and bridges; help us build a clean, resilient energy grid; bolster public transportation; deliver clean drinking water to millions of families; and ensure every home has access to high-speed Internet, which we know &#8212; after the last year and a half &#8212; is just truly a foundational and fundamental need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This landmark bill is going to be a game changer for us here in Michigan.&nbsp; We&#8217;re estimated to receive $7.26 billion for roads and bridges here.&nbsp; That $7.26 billion we can use to restore and rebuild our crumbling roads and bridges, saving drivers and small businesses money and time.&nbsp; That&#8217;s $7.26 billion to make commutes or the drive to school, road trips up north, safer and smoother.</p>



<p>The bill will also build out a national network of electric vehicle charging stations, helping Michigan&#8217;s iconic auto industry turbocharge its transition to electric and continue leading the future of mobility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that F150 that you drove in Dearborn, Mr. President, or I know that the GM truck you drove the other day, that&#8217;s how &#8212; we need to have this infrastructure so that we can lead the world in advanced mobility.</p>



<p>So, this is a much-needed investment in moving us towards an electric future, and it may be the momentum we need for bigger investments in the future.</p>



<p>Our Senators Stabenow and Peters spearheaded a record&nbsp; $1 billion investment in the Great Lakes Restoration Initiative.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR WHITMER:&nbsp; It&#8217;ll help us clean up and restore the beautiful freshwater lakes and preserve our picturesque peninsulas.</p>



<p>And finally, the package includes $10 billion to help us continue cleaning up toxic chemicals and contaminants from our water supply.&nbsp; It includes $4 billion to help water utilities remove chemicals from their supply or to connect well owners to local systems, and another $5 billion to help small or disadvantaged communities tackle PFAS in drinking water.</p>



<p>So, I think this is the &#8212; setting the stage for future collaboration as well &#8212; as well as this bill heads to the House and awaits final passage.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to keep working at the state level to make bold infrastructure investments as well.&nbsp; I got a $3.5 billion build &#8212; Rebuilding Michigan road bonding plan done the year before last.&nbsp; Twenty-one state highway construction projects are underway this summer, supporting 22,800 good-paying jobs.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re investing resources to make sure every Michigander can go about their day and get things done without worrying if they&#8217;re going to blow a tire or crack an axle.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing it while creating all these jobs in the process.</p>



<p>So, the economic and job-creating potential of this Infrastructure and Jobs Act is huge.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a big deal, as you would say.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>With this once-in-a-generation investment, we can usher in a new era of prosperity and build back better from this pandemic stronger than ever.</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m grateful for your leadership, Mr. President.&nbsp; I&#8217;m excited about the prospect of this and what it&#8217;s going to mean for every American &#8212; and not some, not a few, but every one of us will benefit when we get this done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m so glad to be with you today.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; And, by the way, you know, I think, sort of breaking through this first big barrier in a bipartisan way, I really believe &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t make everything easy, but it does have a way &#8212; it has an effect on other things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I noticed that you mentioned having &#8212; I had the three presidents of the three major American automobile companies, the UAW, and all of the &#8212; all the auto workers in my backyard here at the White House with their electric vehicles.&nbsp; The commitment is to get 40 &#8212; I believe, 50 percent of all our vehicles in America be electric vehicles, with 550,000 charging stations along the highways that are being repaired and &#8212; you know, or built.</p>



<p>And, you know, that means, for Michigan, if I&#8217;m looking at my notes here, you&#8217;re going to receive $110 million dollars for the expansion of EV &#8212; of EV charging networks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I just think, hopefully, this makes people realize if the autoworkers and the automobile executives can get together and form this kind of alliance, I think we&#8217;re making some real progress.</p>



<p>But, thank you, Jennifer [Gretchen], for what you&#8217;ve done and continue to do.</p>



<p>And, Mr. Mayor &#8212; Jerry, I don&#8217;t want to get you in trouble out in Fresno, California, for letting you know I actually like a Republican.&nbsp; But you&#8217;ve done a hell of a job.&nbsp; I&#8217;m anxious to hear about your electric buses later.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, anyway, the floor is yours, Jerry.</p>



<p>MAYOR DYER:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President, for your leadership on this critical infrastructure package.&nbsp; You know, there &#8212; there are really many things to like about this infrastructure bill, beginning with bipartisan support.&nbsp; That always makes it easier on us at the local level, as you mentioned.</p>



<p>And the last time I checked, both Republican and Democrats alike travel on our roadways and cross our bridges, use mass transit, and breathe the same air.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, unfortunately, Fresno, along with Los Angeles, our neighbors to the south, had some of the worst air quality in the nation &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>MAYOR DYER:&nbsp; &#8212; which is why we&#8217;re focused on transitioning to clean air buses in Fresno, as you mentioned.&nbsp; In fact, we rolled out our first two electric buses last week &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know.</p>



<p>MAYOR DYER:&nbsp; &#8212; thanks to a Federal Transportation Administration grant.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President, to your administration.&nbsp; And this bi- &#8212; this bill, I believe, will accelerate those efforts here in Fresno.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, as you know, Fresno is ground zero to &#8212; for California&#8217;s high-speed rail efforts.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>MAYOR DYER:&nbsp; And I&#8217;m proud to say that Fresno will be host to the &#8212; the nation&#8217;s first high-speed rail station right here in downtown Fresno.&nbsp; And so federal assistance is vital in order to complete this project.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m hopeful that this infrastructure bill will provide that financial support to us here in Fresno.</p>



<p>And Fresno, like many cities, is in the midst of airport expansion with the addition of a new terminal at our Fresno Yosemite International Airport this coming year.&nbsp; And certainly, this bill has the potential to expedite our airport expansion as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with the changing climate and drought conditions in California, we are facing, on a weekly basis, life-threatening wildfires that not only put our power grid in danger locally, but our firefighters as well.&nbsp; And this bill will strengthen our power grid by investing in it, which is vital in our region.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s very important that we do so in order to avoid some of the rolling blackouts that we experience here in Fresno as a matter of routine.</p>



<p>And lastly, unfortunately &#8212; and I&#8217;m not proud of this &#8212; but Fresno is number two in poverty in the state of California.&nbsp; We have a very poor valley, a very poor region.&nbsp; Most of our jobs historically have been agricultural-centric, although that is changing.&nbsp; And this infrastructure bill will create good-paying, meaningful jobs, which are desperately needed in Fresno and throughout our region, and allow us to build upon those agricultural jobs that we&#8217;ve been relying upon.</p>



<p>So I just want to say, on &#8212; as the mayor of Fresno and as a Republican, I am very grateful for your leadership, Mr. President on this infrastructure package &#8212; making it a priority with your administration; considering &#8212; or taking into consideration input from state and local jurisdictions; as well as working diligently to pursue that bipartisan support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you again, and we are here to assist and take advantage of that funding.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, Jerry &#8212; thank you, Mr. Mayor.&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not being solicitous, but we kind of had Fresno in mind &#8212; I&#8217;m not joking &#8212; because the air quality, the &#8212; where you sit, how tough it is for you there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, all the things you mentioned have an impact &#8212; are going to allow you to have an impact on air quality.</p>



<p>You know me, because you&#8217;re aware of it, I&#8217;m a big rail guy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MAYOR DYER:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have more money in this &#8212; in this area for high-speed rail than all the money we spend on set &#8212; setting up Amtrak.&nbsp; This is a gigantic investment.&nbsp; And you know as well as I do, when people can take a train from point A to point B &#8212; conveniently and faster than you can drive your vehicle &#8212; they take the train.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re talking about electric.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about electric.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not talking diesels.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about electric.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re talking about being able to transform and impact on the air quality in your area, because of geographic location and the spot you&#8217;re in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Also, with regard to the power grid: You know, you have seen more than most people &#8212; in California, you&#8217;ve seen the impact that weather has on not being able to sustain the security of the power grid &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MAYOR DYER:&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; whether it was bad weather or fires or whatever it is.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a lot of money in here &#8212; a lot of money in here for making sure we can take care of the lines that carry the electricity, the lines that move it along.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And one of the other pieces in here that I know you know about because you&#8217;re already doing it, is that &#8212; you know, your airport &#8212; your airport, as well as the high-speed rail terminal.&nbsp; That also &#8212; there&#8217;s money in here for airports.&nbsp; Republicans strongly supported it, as well as Democrats, because there&#8217;s a lot that has to be done to modernize the airports.&nbsp; And that also has the impact of cutting down on air quality problems and the like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, there&#8217;s so much.&nbsp; And I understand you have seven more electric buses on order or you&#8217;re thinking about getting another seven.&nbsp; We got some money for you.</p>



<p>MAYOR DYER:&nbsp; Yeah, we have &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We got some money for you.</p>



<p>MAYOR DYER:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Well, thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; We actually have seven more that are going to be coming on line in 2022.&nbsp; So &#8212; and if you want to send us more, we&#8217;ll take them.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, by the way, it is really a big, big deal.&nbsp; And one of the things we&#8217;re doing is we have provisions that we&#8217;re trying to encourage the American manufacturers to actually generate and build the platforms for these electric buses.</p>



<p>I was in Carolina looking at a factory where they&#8217;re making not only school buses, but also, you know, the regular transit systems that are electric-based.&nbsp; It&#8217;s phenomenal what&#8217;s going on, but we have to make sure we have all the par- &#8212; you know, access to &#8212; to the various pieces of materials and minerals we need to produce them.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s a big deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m going to be coming back to you, and all of you, to get help on making sure we continue to make these investments because I view this as just starting, not the end.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this is going to &#8212; this is going to play out over the next eight years &#8212; these investments.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a lot of money.&nbsp; It&#8217;s over $500 million &#8212; billion in new money over those eight years.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s paid for.&nbsp; It&#8217;s paid for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thanks for what you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, I always joke with my friends: You know, being a mayor maybe is the toughest job in American politics; they know where you live &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; and you affect their everyday lives more than anybody.&nbsp; So, I wish you the best of luck.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MAYOR DYER:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Mayor Lumumba, from Jackson, Mississippi.&nbsp; How you doing, pal?&nbsp; Good to see you again.&nbsp; Thanks for being so nice to my wife.</p>



<p>MAYOR LUMUMBA:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a pleasure to join you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a pleasure to join all of the amazing people on this call today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to express my gratitude not only to your administration, but towards the bipartisan effort that has led to this bill passing the Senate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to thank Roger &#8212; Senator Roger Wicker &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>MAYOR LUMUMBA:&nbsp; &#8212; from Mississippi &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He stepped up.</p>



<p>MAYOR LUMUMBA:&nbsp; &#8212; who stepped up and supported this effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, as you are well aware, the residents of Jackson, who I have the honor to serve, are greater than the sum of their challenges.&nbsp; And the city of Jackson is greater than the sum of its challenges, with amazing people and with a city which is pregnant with possibilities.&nbsp; But we do have real challenges, which were reflected in our February storms &#8212; the consecutive storms that we faced that completely debilitated our water distribution system.&nbsp; These are challenges we have seen frequently and were reflected in a different fashion most recently in February.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because we have experienced hotter &#8212; hotter summers, colder winters, and more rain in the rainy season, it has had a detrimental impact on our aging and crumbling infrastructure.&nbsp; What it resulted in, in February, was literally raw water screens that froze, making it difficult for water to get into our water treatment facility, consequently making it difficult for treated water to get out.&nbsp; This led to thousands &#8212; tens of thousands of residents across the city of Jackson being without potable and non-potable water.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is more than just a matter of convenience.&nbsp; It is a matter of life and what people rely on.&nbsp; It&#8217;s how people take their medication.&nbsp; It&#8217;s how people, in the midst of a pandemic &#8212; pandemic, take care of their sanitary needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, this has been an extreme challenge.&nbsp; And I can&#8217;t express enough my gratitude for your efforts and the bipartisan effort to see to this bill passing the Senate.&nbsp; And we look forward to its passage through the House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe that one of our <a>principal functions</a>, as leaders who are responsible for the needs of our residents, is understanding that budgets are moral documents which should reflect the values we have as a nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need our budgets and we need our economy to more than just reflect our aspirations of GDP and stock market metrics.&nbsp; They must meet <a>sustainable development goals, a</a>nd we must create a dignity economy &#8212; an economy which reflects the inherent dignity of every person.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To be able to provide safe drinking water, a sustainable infrastructure, a resilient infrastructure, and. might I add, an equitable infrastructure has to be a part of our plan to build back better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I want to, once again, express my gratitude for your hard work, your focus on this issue.&nbsp; When I met you during your campaign in Atlanta, Georgia, you stated that this would be a focus of yours, and I&#8217;m thankful for you holding true to that promise.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, Mr. Mayor, thank you.&nbsp; You know, I think it&#8217;s important that the other sixteen- or seventeen hundred people who are on this call understand what you and others have gone through.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You &#8212; you found yourself in a position, in terms of water, where &#8212; it&#8217;s estimated by our team that over the next 20 years, Mississippi drinking water infrastructure &#8212; Mississippi drinking water infrastructure is going to require $4.8 billion in additional funding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act includes $55 billion in investment to ensure clean, safe drinking water.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a right of all communities, as you point out.</p>



<p>And the bill would eliminate the nation&#8217;s lead-based service lines, which I know you and I talked about.&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s a lot of good that&#8217;s going on in here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I say to Mayor Dryer [Dyer] as well that &#8212; we talk about, you know, the poverty rate of these towns &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re going to be able to fab [sic] &#8212; all of you have full-blown Internet that&#8217;s affordable and available in rural and cities across the way that&#8217;s going to change the circumstance for people in those communities that &#8212; particularly, those folks &#8212; so people don&#8217;t have to &#8212; when they&#8217;re &#8212; if, God forbid, we&#8217;re back to having, you know, distanced learning, where they don&#8217;t have to sit in the McDonald&#8217;s parking lot to get access &#8212; with their mom or dad &#8212; to get access to the Internet to do their work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I just can&#8217;t thank you enough.&nbsp; You’ve &#8212; you’ve really gone out of the way to deal with the issues that we&#8217;re talking about here.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; I hope you&#8217;re going to see a lot of benefit flow from this.&nbsp; Because the idea, you know, no more Flints, no more Jacksons, in terms of water, because we’re going to get this done with &#8212; as my grandfather used to say, “with the grace of God and the goodwill of the neighbors.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we got, also, the entire United States Senate supporting it by 69 votes.&nbsp; And we’re looking forward to it happening in the House as well.&nbsp; So, thanks a lot, pal. &nbsp;And let us know what you need in this if you’re &#8212; if &#8212; any of you, if you, you know &#8212; if any of it comes across as confusing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, I know Liz Hausmann of Fulton County &#8212; County Commissioner &#8212; isn’t going to be confused about anything.&nbsp; But, I &#8212; you know, I &#8212; Liz, I made a mistake saying that being a mayor is the toughest; maybe being a county commissioner is.&nbsp; You know why?&nbsp; Because you knock on a door and say, “My name is Joe Biden, candidate for the county council.”&nbsp; And they’ll look at you and smile and say, “Yeah.”&nbsp; And you know what they’re thinking &#8212; “What do you do?&nbsp; What does a commissioner do?”&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anyway, you have a hell of a job, Liz, and so why don’t you tell me what you &#8212; what’s on your mind.&nbsp; And I know you take &#8212; do you take in a lot of Atlanta in your district?</p>



<p>COMMISSIONER HAUSMANN:&nbsp; Atlanta is in our county.&nbsp; Yes, sir.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>COMMISSIONER HAUSMANN:&nbsp; We have 15 cities, including Atlanta.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, fire away.&nbsp; The floor is yours.</p>



<p>COMMISSIONER HAUSMANN:&nbsp; Well, Mr. President, first of all, it&#8217;s an honor to serve the citizens of Fulton County, but it&#8217;s a true honor to be here with you today as we have this important conversation about the future and improving our nation&#8217;s infrastructure.&nbsp; So, thank you for having me.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>COMMISSIONER HAUSMANN:&nbsp; I’m coming from the state of Georgia, which provides &#8212; which prides itself in being the number-one state in the nation to do business.&nbsp; Along with that, of course, comes heavy traffic and congestion.</p>



<p>For counties across the country, generally, this is an important conversation, as we are tasked with directly supporting 78 percent of the public transit systems across the United States.&nbsp; So, this $39 billion in new investments is greatly appreciated and will be very impactful to the services that we provide in the public transit arena.</p>



<p>Counties invest over $23 billion each year in the operation, maintenance, and construction of transit utilities and mass transit systems, including subways, surface rails, and buses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s all to say that counties play a critical role in the nation&#8217;s transportation and infrastructure network, and we appreciate all the work that has gone into the creation of the bipartisan infrastructure investment and Jobs Act.</p>



<p>Here in Fulton County and the 13-county metro Atlanta region, we have done extensive planning for expanding our transit system, including site visits with our county and city leaders to transit assets of other major metropolitan areas.&nbsp; And our state has legislatively created a regional authority to coordinate efforts with existing transit agencies across our region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unfortunately, we do not have the resources necessary to implement those plans.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re especially pleased to see the increase in the Small Starts program project eligibility from $300- to $400 million, along with the increase of $50 million in the federal match.</p>



<p>For Fulton County and Metro Atlanta, this means that many of our transit expansion projects will now be eligible to receive this expanded federal funding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The bottom line is that this bipartisan infrastructure package provides mobility options for our community, and the transit provisions provide connectivity, jobs, and sustainability for the growth that we know is coming.&nbsp; In Metro Atlanta alone, we expect to grow by 2 million people in the next 20 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;ve long suffered with local governments being the &#8212; required to fund what really is a regional problem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>COMMISSIONER HAUSMANN:&nbsp; The reality is each county is limited to funding projects within our county borders.&nbsp; And our authority may stop at the county border, but our transportation needs do not.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Absolutely.</p>



<p>COMMISSIONER HAUSMANN:&nbsp; So, we can&#8217;t do it without the support and partnership of our state and federal government.&nbsp; And this bipartisan infrastructure package will help us do just that.&nbsp; So, thank you very much.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; Look, what usually is &#8212; I know all of you understand this &#8212; and the other over a thousand&nbsp; people on this call understand &#8212; local officials &#8212; is that when you talk about the commute times and public transportation,&nbsp;you know, the &#8212; in Georgia, public transportation spends an extra &#8212; those on public transportation spend an extra 74.1 percent of their time commuting.&nbsp; And non-white hol- &#8212; [non-]white households are 3.9 times more likely to commute on public transportation.</p>



<p>Seven percent of the trains and other transit vehicles in the state are past their useful life.&nbsp; And based on the formula funding alone, Georgia would expect to get $1.4 billion over the next five years &#8212; a significant portion of which would be in your county &#8212; under the infrastructure investment and Jobs Act to improve public transportation across the state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When you spend that much time commuting &#8212; all of you know this &#8212; it costs taxpayers &#8212; it cost those commuters a lot of money.&nbsp; For example, the average &#8212; the average Georgia driver, on average, spends $375 a year in costs due to driving on roads that need to be repaired.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You have a circumstance in your state where 374 bridges and over two thousand six &#8212; 260 miles of highway are in poor condition.&nbsp; So, it all comes down to being able to move and move without creating additional pollution, and generating the ability to move safely and do it in a way that will significantly increase business opportunities and the like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I &#8212; having been a county official myself, I know that it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to convince people that, because you overlap cities and towns and the like, that, you know, it all affects you; you don&#8217;t have it all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you for your support.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s going to be very helpful, I hope.</p>



<p>COMMISSIONER HAUSMANN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I’m glad to hear you’ve got Georgia on your mind, Mr. President.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, I do, for more &#8212; for more than one reason.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Look, I finally want to turn to Principal Chief Chuck Hoskin, Cherokee Nation in Oklahoma.&nbsp; Principal Chief Hoskin, your administration has invested millions of dollars to bring high-speed Internet to Cherokee Nation, especially rural Cherokee communities.&nbsp; How will the additional Tribal broadband resources support your Tribal citizens?&nbsp; Or whatever else you want to talk about.&nbsp; But it seems to me that ought to be &#8212; that &#8212; that should be of significant help to you, I hope.</p>



<p>PRINCIPAL CHIEF HOSKIN:&nbsp; It is.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great honor to be with you and with all the leaders on this panel.</p>



<p>This bill is important for the country.&nbsp; But I want you to know that the bill is important to me because you didn&#8217;t forget Indian Country.&nbsp; This bill, overall, has more than $11 billion in investment in Indian Country.&nbsp; That is historic &#8212; potentially transformational investment for Tribes across this country.&nbsp; That’s very important.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Indian nations.&nbsp; Indian nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRINCIPAL CHIEF HOSKIN:&nbsp; Indian Nations across this country, working as sovereigns &#8212; as sovereigns with the United States.</p>



<p>For us, broadband is a high priority.&nbsp; You know, no Cherokee kid ought to be going to school without access to high-speed Internet.&nbsp; No elder ought to lack access to the kind of telemedicine that we&#8217;re making available to our people because they live in an area without connectivity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The entrepreneurs that we know are out there in some of our little communities and our bigger communities &#8212; they shouldn&#8217;t miss opportunities to develop because they live in an area where they can&#8217;t connect with the rest of the world.&nbsp; Cherokee families ought to be able to connect just like anyone else.</p>



<p>And connectivity and broadband is important for the country.&nbsp; In Indian Country, the problem is particularly difficult in the rural parts of Indian Country, in particular.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re dealing with that at Cherokee Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve already, as you indicated, have invested heavily into that cause for the reasons that I mentioned.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s another reason, which is that, if a lot of these small communities in these rural areas wither on the vine because they don&#8217;t have broadband and a chance to succeed in the new economy, that means Cherokee lifeways and culture and our language withers on the vine, and we can&#8217;t let that happen.&nbsp; So, this is an important moment for the Cherokee Nation.</p>



<p>During COVID, what we found is what we already were concerned about, which is that when you have a lack of high-speed Internet, when you have the worst public health crisis in living memory, and students are having to change the way they learn, and elders are having to be more isolated, families are having to socially distance from their fellow Cherokees &#8212; we know that it&#8217;s more important than ever to stay connected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we found &#8212; we used a Department of Interior grant, and we found that 35 of our communities lacked connectivity, but we went right to work to stand up high &#8212; hotspots in those communities.&nbsp; We issued 11,000 hotspots to students and other Cherokees who needed them, just to get us through.&nbsp; That was important.&nbsp; It was a significant investment, but it really is a drop in the bucket, Mr. President, of what we need as we went out and visited with these families.</p>



<p>So, we are applying for the Tribal Broadband Connectivity grant through the United States Department of Commerce, the National Telecommunications &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>PRINCIPAL CHIEF HOSKIN:&nbsp; &#8212; and Infrastrati- &#8212; Information Administration.&nbsp; What this bill does is it injects $2 billion &#8212; more dollars into that program.&nbsp; It extends the life of the program by four years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s going to let Tribes, like the Cherokee Nation, that are already working on this to grab those dollars and put them immediately to work to scale up what I&#8217;m talking about.&nbsp; So those communities where we put up hotspots will &#8212; will build out the infrastructure needed to make permanent conductivity in those communities.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll make sure that those kids and those elders stay connected.</p>



<p>And the other thing that your administration has done is its commitment to working and consulting in a meaningful manner with Tribal nations.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we have confidence when we work with your Department of Commerce that we can tailor these programs in a way that&#8217;s flexible, that reflects what we need in our rural communities, in our Cherokee communities.&nbsp; We have great confidence in that.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s as much about the respect as it is about the dollars.&nbsp; But the dollars, of course, are indispensable, and they are plentiful in this bill.</p>



<p>We recently visited, Mr. President, an elderly family &#8212; some Cherokee elders that are fluent Cherokee speakers.&nbsp; They live in a little community called Bellefonte.&nbsp; They had told us that they actually didn&#8217;t go to their telemedicine appointments during COVID when we had to keep our health facilities limited in terms of access because they didn&#8217;t have connectivity.&nbsp; And we didn&#8217;t know it, so we partnered with Starlink and we have high-speed Internet to their home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, our Deputy Chief, Bryan Warner, and I got on a virtual conference with them.&nbsp; They said they&#8217;d only seen something like that on TV.&nbsp; They never thought they would do it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s opening up an entire world to them.</p>



<p>And what it told me, Mr. President, and what I think it tells a lot of Tribal leaders, is that we have a chance to get a foothold in the economy for our people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this is very important: Those are fluent Cherokee speakers.&nbsp; If we don&#8217;t succeed right now in connecting elders to kids, connecting schools, connecting healthcare, we will lose something that&#8217;s irreplaceable.&nbsp; It&#8217;s more irreplaceable than the economic development that we know this bill will generate.&nbsp; It&#8217;s more important than anything, and that is Cherokee language and culture.</p>



<p>When we look back, Mr. President, generations from now, and know that we saved it, know that Cherokee language is thriving and that our economy is doing good and that our reservation is a place where there&#8217;s prosperity &#8212; we&#8217;re going to look back at this moment, and we&#8217;re going to see that we had this opportunity to make transformational change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We couldn&#8217;t have done it without our federal partners.&nbsp; We&#8217;re certainly proud of our leadership.&nbsp; We couldn&#8217;t do it without this bill, I&#8217;m confident.</p>



<p>And you have my great appreciation and admiration for that.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, you have my appreciation.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t owe me anything or nothing to appreciate.&nbsp; This is &#8212; this is what we used to do when I first got to the Senate.&nbsp; You know, we actually worked with one another.</p>



<p>And look, one of the things that affects Tribal lands, in my &#8212; in my experience &#8212; not just Cherokee, but across the board &#8212; is that they&#8217;re significantly at risk for the effects of climate change.&nbsp; And infrastructure investments that we&#8217;re talking about here is going to invest in &#8212; in everything from forest management, to helping communities build resilience, to wildfires and floods, and everything from elevating buildings to roads to bridges.&nbsp; Because we have to &#8212; we have to build back to where we know the minimum requirements are now, and we got to do it better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can&#8217;t build back to what it used to be.&nbsp; You used to be able to build back a road to what it was before it got flooded out, before &#8212; you can&#8217;t do that anymore because the climate has changed so significantly already, and so you have to elevate.&nbsp; You have to move.</p>



<p>You see what&#8217;s happening on &#8212; at least in the East Coast, from Florida up to where I live in Delaware, and beyond &#8212; along the coast.&nbsp; You see the effects of the rising seas and buildings literally sinking or tilting, and losing their ability to stand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, it&#8217;s &#8212; it’s a big deal, the things that are changing.&nbsp; And so &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s particularly, you know, important in &#8212; in Tribal lands &#8212; elevating buildings, roads, bridges, winterizing the power grid, and the like.&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s a lot to do that benefits everybody.</p>



<p>You know, one of the points I want to make &#8212; and I&#8217;ll get off my soapbox here &#8212; but, you know, my observation in my years in public life have been that when ordinary folks do well, everybody does well.&nbsp; Everybody does well.&nbsp; The wealthy do very well.&nbsp; The upper-middle class do very well.&nbsp; The middle cla- &#8212; I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; When it works from the middle out and the bottom up, everybody does well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s all kinds of studies from the great universities in your states demonstrating that that is the case.&nbsp; And so, this is what this is about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think we have a real chance to deliver everything from clean drinking water, to access to Internets, to roads that are not congested, to dealing with the &#8212;</p>



<p>I was up in &#8212; I think it was Wisconsin, and I was talking to a group of folks in a factory.&nbsp; And &#8212; and then I spoke afterwards, and they showed me around.&nbsp; And there were about a couple hundred people.&nbsp; And in front of me, in this factory floor, were the elected officials &#8212; the governor and other folks &#8212; and to my right were all the folks &#8212; both the hourly workers and the management.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I talked about this having safety provisions in it.&nbsp; And they all looked at me like, “What the hell does that mean?”&nbsp; And I said, “I bet every one of you can name for me the intersections in your town, in your city where the highest accident rate is, where the most pedestrians are hit, where bicyclists get killed, where there is (inaudible).</p>



<p>And in unison &#8212; not a joke &#8212; if there were 120 people there, 100 of them started shaking their heads, “Yeah, we know.”&nbsp; This does a lot of practical things &#8212; a lot of practical things to change the environment that people live in.</p>



<p>So I &#8212; and there&#8217;s a lot more to do.&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; And we still have to get it through the House and get things moving.</p>



<p>But I want to thank you all for your time, your insight, and your continued leadership.&nbsp; And I want to thank you for &#8212; we&#8217;re closer than we&#8217;ve ever been a long time to making a once-in-a-generation investment.</p>



<p>You know, this total investment in roads, in highways is bigger than we did in the &#8212; Eisenhower&#8217;s, you know, Interstate Highway System.&nbsp; You know, this is &#8212; the &#8212; the only analogies out there and the vote to get it are similar.</p>



<p>Our &#8212; you know, we started off with, you know, the Erie Canal.&nbsp; We started off with moving people west.&nbsp; We started off the Intercontinental Railroad in the late 1800s.&nbsp; All &#8212; all kidding aside, we linked the coast.&nbsp; Now we came along and we did &#8212; and we had the &#8212; all the way up to Eisenhower&#8217;s Interstate Highway System.&nbsp; It has literally changed the way Americans live, changed the way we live and the way we&#8217;ve developed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now we&#8217;re investing as much money or more money to do those kinds of things that can make us better connected and also give us more breathing room and clean the air a little bit.</p>



<p>So, I want to thank you all because almost all of you &#8212; I think all of you signed on to the bipartisan effort of mayors and &#8212; and &#8212; as well as other state and county officials to support this.</p>



<p>And I promise you, we&#8217;re going to stay on top of making sure, as long as I&#8217;m here, that it gets out, it gets out swiftly, and it gets out economically, and it gets out in a way that builds this country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know I got criticized when I was running.&nbsp; Said &#8212; I said I was running for three reasons.&nbsp; One, to restore the soul of the country.&nbsp; Two, to rebuild the backbone &#8212; the middle-class and working-class people &#8212; of this country, and not leave them behind.&nbsp; And thirdly, to unite the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know a lot of people were skeptical, but we can do this.&nbsp; We can do this.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to disagree in philosophy on some of the things, but we can do this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m convinced we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, I&#8217;m going to say something that has no direct bearing on &#8212; immediate bearing on what any of you are dealing with.&nbsp; But, you know, when I was over in the NATO conference; or I was over for the G7, with the largest industrial nations in the world; and when I was at a, you know, summit with Putin &#8212; and I&#8217;m about to go do the same thing, in terms of the G20 &#8212; you know what affects our &#8212; the attitude of the American &#8212; of the rest of the world about the United States?&nbsp; “Can we still do &#8212; get things done?”&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I went over, I said &#8212; with those seven leaders, I said, “We&#8217;re back.”&nbsp; And the response was, “For how long?&nbsp; For how long?&nbsp; You guys can&#8217;t get anything done.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll conclude by saying that, you know, when I won &#8212; just because of my Irish background &#8212; heritage &#8212; they were ringing bells in Ireland and painting my picture on the side of buildings and the like.&nbsp; But the Taoiseach of Ireland &#8212; the Prime Minister of Ireland &#8212; said something just before I got sworn in that made a lot of sense.&nbsp; He said, “I think I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m not sure what America can do anymore.&nbsp; They can&#8217;t even deal with COVID.&nbsp; They can&#8217;t lead anymore.”</p>



<p>That’s what the world is looking at us &#8212; they&#8217;re wondering.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you got guys like Xi Jinping and Putin who think the answer is autocracy, because democracies can&#8217;t get together.&nbsp; The world is changing so rapidly &#8212; so rapidly.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t get together and answer the big, tough questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I really mean it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; I promise you, this is what your children and grandchildren are going to be writing about in their senior thesis in graduate school.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we got to make sure we can demonstrate we can get things done.&nbsp; And it can&#8217;t be done by one party.</p>



<p>So, thank you all so very, very, very much.&nbsp; And as I said, as my Grandpop would say, &#8220;With the grace of God, the goodwill of the neighbors, and the creek not rising, we&#8217;re going to get all this done.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and I hope you all take a look at my Build Back Better plan that has to do with a lot of other pieces that are &#8212; that the Senate just agreed to move forward on.&nbsp; You may not agree, but take a look at it and see if any of it has a value to your communities.&nbsp; Okay?</p>



<p>Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I really do appreciate it.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you worried about the debt ceiling, Mr. President?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Nope.&nbsp; They’re not going to let us default.&nbsp; Eight billion –- eight trillion of that is on Republican conscience.</p>



<p>3:59 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Calls on Congress to Lower Prescription Drug&#160;Prices</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/12/fact-sheet-president-biden-calls-on-congress-to-lower-prescription-drug-prices/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27031</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden believes that health care is a right, not a privilege. No American should have to face difficult choices between paying for their prescription medications or other essential needs. And yet, too many Americans face this exact challenge. On average, Americans pay two to three times as much as people in other countries for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden believes that health care is a right, not a privilege. No American should have to face difficult choices between paying for their prescription medications or other essential needs. And yet, too many Americans face this exact challenge. On average, Americans pay two to three times as much as people in other countries for prescription drugs, and one in four Americans who take prescription drugs struggle to afford their medications. Pharmaceutical companies do ground-breaking, life-saving work, but there is a difference between developing clinical breakthroughs and driving up prices for the drugs Americans rely on. Change is sorely needed.<br><br>Today, President Biden is laying out his vision for reducing the high cost of prescription drugs. As part of his Build Back Better agenda, he’s calling on Congress to address this crisis and allow Medicare to negotiate drug prices, significantly reducing costs for millions of Americans.</p>



<p>Specifically, the President’s plan includes:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Allowing Medicare to Negotiate Drug Prices.</strong></li></ul>



<p>For every other type of health care service, Medicare works to get the best prices for American seniors. But for prescription drugs – and only prescription drugs – Medicare is prohibited by law from negotiating for the best deal.&nbsp; This needs to change.&nbsp; Medicare should be able to negotiate the price for a subset of expensive drugs that don’t face any competition in the market.&nbsp; Medicare negotiators would be provided a framework for what constitutes a fair price for each drug, and there should be powerful incentives to make sure drug companies agree to a reasonable price.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Making Other Needed Reforms to Lower Prices.</strong></li></ul>



<p>We need to put an end to drug prices rising higher and higher with no end in sight. Drug companies that raise their prices faster than inflation should have to pay a penalty. Furthermore, today, seniors who take expensive drugs can face unlimited exposure to high drug prices. We have to fix this, and establish a firm cap on the amount that Medicare beneficiaries have to pay out-of-pocket for drugs each year.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Building on Existing Progress to Lower the Cost of Prescription Drugs.</strong></li></ul>



<p>These actions would build upon steps the President has taken to make prescription drugs more affordable for all Americans. Last month, President Biden <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/">signed an executive order</a> calling upon each Agency to improve competition, increase wages, and reduce prices—including for prescription drugs. Alongside other steps, the federal government will be working with states and Tribes to import safe, lower-cost prescription drugs from Canada and accelerating the development and uptake of generic and biosimilar drugs that give patients the same exact clinical benefit but at a fraction of the price.<br><br>These reforms would <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/healthcare/news/2021/07/20/501803/h-r-3-save-patients-thousands-dollars-prescription-drugs/">lower premiums and copays for millions</a> of Americans. &nbsp;Insulin prices could <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/healthcare/news/2021/07/20/501803/h-r-3-save-patients-thousands-dollars-prescription-drugs/">fall by hundreds of dollars</a> on average.&nbsp;&nbsp; The price for some arthritis medicines might fall by <a href="https://oversight.house.gov/sites/democrats.oversight.house.gov/files/Committee%20on%20Oversight%20and%20Reform%20-%20AbbVie%20Staff%20Report.pdf">more than $2,000 every month</a>.&nbsp; And for some of the most expensive drugs, prices would fall by tens of thousands of dollars per year.&nbsp; These price savings would put money back in seniors’ pockets: a person taking an expensive cancer drug could see their out of pocket costs fall by at least $9,000 a year, and even seniors who don’t take expensive drugs could see their premiums cut. &nbsp;<a href="https://www.cms.gov/Research-Statistics-Data-and-Systems/Research/ActuarialStudies/Downloads/HR3-Titles-I-II.pdf">On average, Medicare beneficiaries would save about $200</a>. And it’s not just Medicare beneficiaries that would benefit.&nbsp; If Medicare makes the prices it negotiates available to commercial payers, too, costs for employer health insurance would fall – reducing premiums by tens of billions of dollars or more.</p>



<p>Public opinion <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/poll-finding/kff-health-tracking-poll-may-2021/">polls</a> show that the majority of Americans—Republicans and Democrats—support this change. The Biden-Harris Administration continues to do everything we can to make high quality health care more affordable and accessible. By enabling Medicare to negotiate drug prices, Congress can do its part to bring down costs and secure the health and financial security of our nation’s seniors.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the Fifth National Climate Task Force&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/readout-of-the-fifth-national-climate-task-force-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 01:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the heels of the latest IPCC report, the National Climate Task Force met to discuss delivering on President Biden’s entire Build Back Better agenda in Congress and driving additional climate ambition. Today, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the fifth National Climate Task Force meeting where she was joined by Cabinet members and senior&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>On the heels of the latest IPCC report, the National Climate Task Force met to discuss delivering on President Biden’s entire Build Back Better agenda in Congress and driving additional climate ambition.</em></p>



<p>Today, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the fifth National Climate Task Force meeting where she was joined by Cabinet members and senior leadership from 17 federal agencies. The Task Force discussed the new Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) report, and its “code red” warning for the global community to take immediate action to avert the worst effects of climate change. This report underscores the need for action and achieving the President’s goal of taking bold action in this decisive decade on the path to economy-wide net zero emissions. Americans are already feeling the effects of climate change – from devastating wildfires to extreme heat to a historic drought – and the IPCC report reminds us that we must act swiftly and decisively to reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</p>



<p>During the meeting, Biden Administration officials discussed passage of the historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal through the Senate, and the Senate’s important step forward to passing the President’s full Build Back Better agenda, which includes creating an energy efficiency clean energy standard, expanding tax cuts for clean electricity, electric vehicles, and clean energy manufacturing, and creating a Civilian Climate Corps.</p>



<p>Additionally, agency leadership shared updates on the Administration’s whole-of-government approach to deliver the President’s vision to build back better:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Council on Environmental Quality Chair Brenda Mallory</strong> and <strong>Acting OMB Director Shalanda Young</strong> discussed the recently-released <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/omb/briefing-room/2021/07/20/the-path-to-achieving-justice40/">Justice40 interim guidance</a> that will ensure the federal government is delivering at least 40 percent of the overall benefits from federal investments in climate and clean energy to disadvantaged communities. The interim guidance identifies a pilot of 21 priority programs that will provide a blueprint for other agencies to help inform their work to implement the Justice40 Initiative across government.</li><li><strong>Secretary of Transportation Pete Buttigieg</strong> and <strong>EPA Administrator Michael Regan</strong> discussed the recent proposed rules issued by their agencies that would establish the most robust standards for fuel efficiency and emissions ever. They also discussed the President’s new goal that half of all vehicle sales be zero-emissions vehicles by 2030, and the accompanying standard-setting actions directed by the President, which will strengthen save consumers money, cut pollution, boost public health, advance environmental justice, and tackle the climate crisis.</li><li><strong>Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland</strong> and <strong>Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack </strong>provided an update on the devastation caused by the current wildfire season and the on-going severe drought that is afflicting communities across the West, including information on how each of their agencies are taking steps to invest in both immediate response efforts and long-term climate resilience to reduce the catastrophic effects of future wildfires and droughts.</li></ul>



<p>As outlined by President Biden’s January 27 <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/">Executive Order on Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad</a>, the Task Force is chaired by the National Climate Advisor and includes Cabinet-level leaders from 21 federal agencies and senior White House officials to mobilize the Biden-Harris Administration’s implementation of a whole-of-government approach.</p>



<p>Task Force membership is comprised of the following government officials:</p>



<ul><li>National Climate Advisor (Chair)</li><li>Secretary of the Treasury</li><li>Secretary of Defense</li><li>Attorney General</li><li>Secretary of the Interior</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture</li><li>Secretary of Commerce</li><li>Secretary of Education</li><li>Secretary of Labor</li><li>Secretary of Health and Human Services</li><li>Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Secretary of Transportation</li><li>Secretary of Energy</li><li>Secretary of Homeland Security</li><li>Administrator of General Services</li><li>Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality</li><li>Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration</li><li>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</li><li>Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs</li><li>Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism</li><li>Assistant to the President for Economic Policy</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Build Back Better&#160;Agenda</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/11/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-build-back-better-agenda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 21:10:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27009</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 1:43 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Last week, we had good news on job growth: 943,000 jobs created in July &#8212; the seventh-largest month of job creation in U.S. history &#8212; making the administration the first ever to add 4 million jobs in the first six months in office. And then, in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>1:43 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Last week, we had good news on job growth: 943,000 jobs created in July &#8212; the seventh-largest month of job creation in U.S. history &#8212; making the administration the first ever to add 4 million jobs in the first six months in office.<br><br>And then, in the past 24 hours, we’ve seen the Senate advance two key pieces of my economic agenda: the bipartisan infrastructure bill and the budget resolution that is the framework for my Build Back Better plan.<br><br>Today, I’m pleased to share more good news with the American people: The latest report on consumer price shows &#8212; prices show that we&#8217;ve expanded some easing &#8212; excuse me, the expected easing we thought was going to come has increased &#8212; that we are &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen a good monthly report.<br><br>The monthly core consumer price index is down by nearly two thirds from its pace over the past three months.<br><br>And when you take out the goods directly impacted by the pandemic, like cars and airplane tickets and month &#8212; the monthly core consumer price index has &#8212; is less than two tenths of 1 percent.  <br><br>So, here’s where we stand: Jobs are up, and monthly price increases have come down.  Economic growth is up to the fastest in 40 years, and unemployment is coming down. <br><br>So, I was &#8212; argued our &#8212; the Biden economic plan is working.  And historic investments are on the way as well.<br><br>This isn’t accidental.  It is the result of our strategy to get shots in arms, grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out.  And it’s the rest of the &#8212; the result of the American Rescue Plan and everything else that we&#8217;ve done.  And it’s a result of the grit and determination and really hard work of the American people.<br><br>But even with all this progress, a lot of families are still feeling the pinch.  Family budgets remain tight, and paychecks don’t go as far as they need to.  That has been a reality in the millions of households all across America for too long.<br><br>That’s why I want to talk today about what we’re going to do to try to ease the burden on families right now and what we need to do to help them succeed over the longer term.<br><br>First, for millions of families, help is on the way right now, thanks to the American Rescue Plan.  On Friday, about 40 million families will receive their second monthly payment<br>as part of our tax cut for families with children: three hundred and &#8212; $300 for each child under the age of 6, and $250 for every child 6 through the age of 17.  That’s money for diapers, food, rent, school supplies, fees and equipment for a child to join sports teams and dance class.  Most of all, as my dad used to say, it just gives a parent a little bit of breathing room.<br><br>The money is a game changer.  And so, I would argue, for &#8212; for some, it’s literally a lifesaver.<br><br>Economists also tell us that those kinds of tax cuts boost test scores, college attendance, and lifetime earnings for children &#8212; a win-win.<br><br>And that’s why I’m glad that, early this morning, Congress took an important step to make sure that this tax cut for families with children does not expire next year. <br><br>So let’s keep this tax cut going and not raise taxes on middle-class families. <br><br>The second point I&#8217;d like to make is: We’re talking about taking action that alleviates global supply chain challenges that keep prices higher than they should be.<br><br>For example, we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re tracking congestion at the ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach &#8212; the largest ports in United States &#8212; where increased shipping traffic, and the challenges of operating safely in a pandemic are creating disruptions.  Those disruptions impact everything from how much our food costs to when deliveries arrive.<br><br>So, my administration is bringing together the port operators, shipping lines, the labor unions, trucking companies, railroads, and others to speed up the port&#8217;s operations. <br><br>Right now, our experts believe &#8212; the major independent forecasters agree as well &#8212; that these bottlenecks and price spikes will reduce as our economy continues to heal. <br><br>And while today&#8217;s consumer price report points in that direction, we will keep a careful eye on inflation each month, and trust the Fed to take appropriate action if and when it&#8217;s needed. <br><br>Third, I&#8217;ve directed my administration to crack down on what some major players are doing in the economy that are keeping prices higher than they need be. <br><br>Take your groceries bill: When big agriculture operations consolidate, they put a squeeze on small and family farms, making them pay more for seed, paying them less for what they produce, and raising prices on what your groceries &#8212; what you pay for your groceries at the grocery store.  <br><br>My executive order opens up competition in the agricultural business, gives more farmers a chance to compete, which will give Americans more food choices at lower cost.<br><br>Fourthly, we are taking action to address gas prices as well.  Today, gas prices are lower than they were early in this decade.  But they’re still high enough to create a pinch on working families.<br><br>One key thing about the infrastructure bill that just passed the Senate is there are no gas tax increases.  No gas tax increases.  I made that absolutely clear that I would not raise gas taxes, and I’m glad everyone in the Senate seemed to agree with that.  But that’s not enough. <br><br>Recently, we’ve seen the price that oil companies pay for a barrel of oil begin to fall, but the cost of gasolines at the pump for more American people hasn’t fallen.  That’s not what you’d expect in a competitive market. <br><br>I want to make sure that nothing stands in the way of oil price declines, leading to lower prices for consumers.  So today, my Director of the Economic &#8212; the National Economic Council has asked the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission to use every available tool to monitor the U.S. gasoline market and address any illegal conduct that might be connect- &#8212; that might be contributing to price increases at the pump while the cost of barrel oil is going down.<br><br>We also made clear to OPEC &#8212; the major oil-exporting nations of the world &#8212; that the production cuts made during the pandemic should be reversed as the global economic &#8212; there as the global economy recovers, in order to lower the prices for consumers.  <br><br>The Child Tax Credit, stepping in to address supply chain challenges, my competition order, the FTC investigation into price gouging &#8212; these are some of the immediate steps we are taking to put more money in your pocket and make that money go further.<br><br>But we also need to do more to bring down the costs that are squeezing families month after month and year after year.  We need to make this economy work better for working families in the long run.<br><br>These challenges were with us long before the pandemic and before I took office.  But as we recover from this crisis, now is the moment to put in place a long-term plan to build back America better &#8212; a plan that will increase opportunities with better jobs and with higher wages; a plan that will lower the everyday costs that strain our budgets and our nation’s families today and long into the future.<br><br>It starts with making investments that we know will make the economy more productive and lead to more growth over the long run.<br><br>Bringing down the costs &#8212; everyday costs that have been taking a bigger and bigger bite out of middle-class families’ incomes &#8212; the expenses that parents &#8212; that keep parents up at night and rob seniors of their dignity: healthcare, prescription drug costs, childcare, education, housing, or caring for an elderly relative or loved one.<br><br>For those who get their health insurance through the Affordable Care Act, the American Rescue Plan allowed us to cover more people at lower premiums &#8212; and lower premiums by an average of 40 percent.  In my Build Back Better plan, we want &#8212; we want to build on that progress. <br><br>Or prescription drugs.  Right now, we pay the highest prescription drug cost prices of any developed nation in the world &#8212; the highest.<br><br>My Build Back Better plan is going to lower predi- &#8212; prescription drug costs by finally giving Medicare the power to negotiate the prices of drug they purchase for the American people, saving Americans hundreds of billions of dollars.<br><br>On top of that, my plan would add hearing, dental, and vision benefits to Medicare.<br><br>Right now, there are hundreds of thousands of Americans who need home- and community-based care services.  My plan expands homecare for older Americans and people with disabilities while improving jobs and the pay for the workers who care for them.<br><br>My plan will also provide access to quality, affordable childcare, with new and upgraded childcare facilities all across the country.  Middle-class families will pay no more than 7 percent of their income for highly qualified care for children up to the age of five.  The most hard-pressed working families will not pay a dime.<br><br>Today, my Council of Economic Advisers and the Office of Management and Budget released a report showing clearly how my Build Back Better plan will lower out-of-pocket expenses for families.<br><br>For example, a family with two parents who together earn $85,000 per year.  They have an adult daughter who lives with them and attends a community college.  They care for an elderly parent who needs arthritis medicine, which costs $5,500 out-of-pocket each year, and an eye exam to get a new pair of glasses. <br><br>Under our Build Back Better plan, their daughter would be eligible for two years of community college free.  That will save them $2,400 a year.  That’s like a $2,400 tax credit.  In addition &#8212; and I should say &#8220;tax cut,&#8221; not just &#8220;credit.&#8221;<br><br>In addition, my plan would cap out-of-pocket expenses and costs for their mom&#8217;s and dad’s prescription drugs, saving that family another $2,400 a year.<br><br>And this new vision &#8212; and the new vision benefit under Medicare would pay for that eye exam and new glasses and lenses, saving $450 a year.<br><br>All told, my plan would save that family making $85,000 a year $5,250.<br><br>And the Build Back Better plan is going to save your family a lot, as well.<br><br>Now, there are a number of &#8212; there&#8217;s been a lot of misleading talk &#8212; which is no surprise, I guess &#8212; about what I’m proposing in my Build Back Better agenda.  It’s not a short-term stimulus; it’s a long-term investment in American families.<br><br>My Republican colleagues have argued that long-term investments in physical infrastructure will grow the economy and reduce inflationary press- &#8212; pressures.  And I thank them for that.  They&#8217;re exactly right.  We agree on that.<br><br>And the same time, it&#8217;s true that long-term investments<br>that bring down the biggest costs that families face &#8212; housing, childcare, education, and healthcare &#8212; these investments will lower out-of-pocket expenses, not raise them.  They will spur more people to work by helping ease the burdens of childcare and senior care that parents, especially mothers, bear &#8212; keeping them out of the job market. <br><br>And they&#8217;ll spread out over the decade.  They’ll make a huge difference for families, but they’ll only make up around 1 percent of our economy&#8217;s &#8212; of our economy each year over the next decade.  And they’re going to be fully paid for.<br><br>This isn’t going to be anything like my predecessor, whose unpaid tax cuts and other spending added nearly $8 trillion in his four years to the national debt.  Eight trillion dollars.  They didn’t even purport to try to pay for their tax cuts, which went straight to the largest corporations and the wealthiest Americans.<br><br>The investments I am proposing will be fully paid for over the long term by having the largest corporations, including the 55 corporations that paid zero federal tax last year, and the super wealthy begin to pay their fair share.  They&#8217;ll still make a lot of money, but pay their fair share.  That means it will actually reduce the national debt, improve our fiscal position over the long run. <br><br>My Build Back Better agenda is fiscally responsible &#8212; the fiscally responsible way to reduce costs for families.<br><br>In fact, we’re hearing economists across the board confirm this.  Moody’s has said that, quote, “worries that the plan will ignite&#8221; &#8212; and this is Moody&#8217;s now &#8212; &#8221; will ignite undesirably high inflation and an overheating economy [is] overdone.”<br><br>Nobel Prize winning economist Joseph Stiglitz said of my plan, and I quote, “There is no conceivable way that they [will] have any significant effect on inflation.”<br><br>Jason Furman of Harvard University has said, quote, “I don’t think the infrastructure bill or reconciliation plan would materially impact inflation over the next decade.”<br><br>So, if your primary concern right now is the cost of living, you should support this plan, not oppose it.  Because a vote against this plan is a vote against lowering the cost of healthcare, housing, childcare, eldercare, and prescription drugs for American families.<br><br>So, let me close with this: We’ve brought this economy back from a cold start.  And there is going to be &#8212; there are going to be some ups and downs.  But I am committed to making sure that our historic economic recovery reaches everyone &#8212; this time, it reaches everyone &#8212; and eases the burden on working families not just this year, but for the years to come.<br><br>So, thank you.  God bless you.  And may God protect our troops.  Thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;1:59 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the First Listening Session of the White&#160;House Legal Aid Interagency&#160;Roundtable</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/11/readout-of-the-first-listening-session-of-the-white-house-legal-aid-interagency-roundtable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 20:47:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Second Gentleman Douglas Emhoff, White House Counsel Dana Remus, and Associate Attorney General Vanita Gupta convened&#160;the first listening session of the White House Legal Aid Interagency Roundtable&#160;(WH-LAIR).&#160;They were joined by five panelists and 33 administration officials to discuss access to justice challenges during the COVID-19 pandemic. During the meeting, Mr. Emhoff, Ms. Remus, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Second Gentleman Douglas Emhoff, White House Counsel Dana Remus, and Associate Attorney General Vanita Gupta convened&nbsp;the first listening session of the White House Legal Aid Interagency Roundtable&nbsp;(WH-LAIR).&nbsp;They were joined by five panelists and 33 administration officials to discuss access to justice challenges during the COVID-19 pandemic. During the meeting, Mr. Emhoff, Ms. Remus, and Ms. Gupta discussed the Biden-Harris Administration’s ongoing work to address some of the most pressing challenges posed by the pandemic, including the Administration’s recent actions to prevent evictions. They also re-affirmed the Administration’s commitment to working with direct legal service providers to expand access to legal representation and the courts, and to ensure that federal resources make their way to the people who need them most.</p>



<p>The WH-LAIR will continue to convene and discuss how the federal government can incorporate legal services among the range of supportive services provided, and increase the availability of meaningful access to justice for individuals and families, regardless of wealth or status.</p>



<p>Panelists included:</p>



<ul><li>BB Beltran, Executive Director, Sexual Assault Support Services</li><li>Brian Frosh, Maryland Attorney General</li><li>Tiffany Graves, Co-President, Association of Pro Bono Counsel</li><li>Archie Roundtree, 2020 Equal Justice Foundation Legal Fellow, Bet Tzedek Legal Services</li><li>Monica Vigues-Pitan, Executive Director, Legal Services of Greater Miami</li></ul>



<p>Members of the WH-LAIR include:</p>



<ul><li>Department of State</li><li>Department of the Treasury</li><li>Department of Defense</li><li>Department of Justice</li><li>Department of the Interior</li><li>Department of Agriculture</li><li>Department of Labor</li><li>Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Department of Transportation</li><li>Department of Education</li><li>Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Department of Homeland Security</li><li>Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</li><li>Corporation for National and Community Service</li><li>Office of Management and Budget</li><li>United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Administrative Conference of the United States</li><li>National Science Foundation</li><li>United States Digital Service</li><li>Domestic Policy Council</li><li>Office of the Vice President</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
