<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 16:21:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on Trade in Goods and&#160;Services</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/statement-from-president-biden-on-trade-in-goods-and-services/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 16:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54994</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we received additional news underscoring the strength of our economic recovery. U.S. goods exports hit a record in April, even after adjusting for inflation, which in turn narrowed the trade deficit. While monthly trade data can be volatile, this suggests American businesses and farmers are selling record numbers of their goods abroad, as we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we received additional news underscoring the strength of our economic recovery. U.S. goods exports hit a record in April, even after adjusting for inflation, which in turn narrowed the trade deficit. While monthly trade data can be volatile, this suggests American businesses and farmers are selling record numbers of their goods abroad, as we continue to make more in America.</p>



<p>In addition, one of the nation’s largest retailers announced that it will take swift action to lower prices for certain goods, as American families’ spending returns to more normal patterns. This is an additional indicator that our economy is beginning to transition from an historic recovery to steady, stable economic growth.</p>



<p>The economic progress we have made didn’t happen by accident—it is a direct result of my economic plan to grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out and to unsnarl supply chains so retailers can rebuild inventories and American goods can more smoothly move through our ports. There’s more work to do to build on our historic recovery and bring down costs for families, without giving up on the significant gains we’ve made in the last year. I’ll work with anyone serious about helping transition our economy to steady, stable economic growth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on the Vice President&#8217;s Engagements Regarding Root Causes of&#160;Migration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/07/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-the-vice-presidents-engagements-regarding-root-causes-of-migration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference&#160;(June 6, 2022) 5:19 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thanks, everyone, for joining us.&#160; This briefing is to preview the Vice President&#8217;s engagements tomorrow &#8212; Tuesday, June 7th &#8212; in Los Angeles related to her work addressing the root causes of migration.&#160; I would just note, as many of you are aware, there is another background&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>&nbsp;<br>(June 6, 2022)</p>



<p>5:19 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining us.&nbsp; This briefing is to preview the Vice President&#8217;s engagements tomorrow &#8212; Tuesday, June 7th &#8212; in Los Angeles related to her work addressing the root causes of migration.&nbsp;<br><br>I would just note, as many of you are aware, there is another background briefing at 6:00 p.m. Eastern Time, which will cover other issues related to the Summit of the Americas, which I know many are interested in.&nbsp; But again, this briefing is about the Vice President&#8217;s engagements regarding root causes.&nbsp;<br><br>This briefing is on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The contents will be embargoed until Tuesday, June 7th, 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time, 2:00 <s>p.m.</s> [a.m.] Pacific Time.&nbsp; And by joining this call, you&#8217;re agreeing to these ground rules.&nbsp;<br><br>Following the call, we&#8217;ll also be sending you some factsheets to support the announcements that the Vice President will be making.&nbsp; They are also embargoed until Tuesday, June 7th at 5:00 a.m. Eastern, 2:00 a.m. Pacific Time.&nbsp;<br><br>And for your awareness today, our speaker is [senior administration official], who will hereinafter be referred to as “senior administration official.”&nbsp;<br><br>And before I hand it over to him, I would just like to preview what we already put out publicly, but to recap the Vice President’s schedule for tomorrow, Tuesday, in Los Angeles.&nbsp;<br><br>First, she&#8217;ll deliver remarks at a women&#8217;s economic empowerment event hosted by the Chamber of Commerce and the Partnership for Central America.&nbsp;<br><br>She will host a roundtable with women leaders, including women business executives, entrepreneurs, and civil society.&nbsp;<br><br>And third, she will host a roundtable with business executives as part of her call to action in partnership with the private sector.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, I will turn it over to senior administration official number one.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [moderator].&nbsp; And thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp;<br><br>Before I dive into some of the specific announcements of this week, let me just take a step back and give you some context for the Vice President&#8217;s approach to this set of issues.&nbsp;<br><br>As you all know, the Vice President leads our administration&#8217;s implementation of the strategy to address root causes of migration from Central America &#8212; a strategy that we launched last summer.&nbsp; And this week is a real opportunity for her to continue to drive this process under her leadership.&nbsp;<br><br>The focus of that strategy is addressing endemic issues in the countries of El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras &#8212; issues such as poverty and corruption and gender-based violence, which are the causes of migration.&nbsp;<br><br>The Vice President&#8217;s theory of the case in approaching this and at the center of this strategy is that people don&#8217;t want to leave their homes.&nbsp;And&nbsp;if you can help provide them hope and opportunity, particularly economic opportunity, there&#8217;s a greater chance that they will remain there.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve acknowledged all along that the drivers of migration from Central America and elsewhere are long-term issues that can&#8217;t be resolved quickly.&nbsp; But we think that we have been tackling them and are seeing real progress in our efforts.&nbsp;<br><br>When the Vice President began her work on this issue, she recognized that governments were important, but we also had to engage the private sector and civil society.&nbsp; And she believes that governments can&#8217;t solve these problems alone.&nbsp;<br><br>So as part of that process, she launched the call to action in May 2021, in which she challenged and encouraged companies to invest in the region and help provide those economic opportunities and support the sort of long-term development in the region that would provide opportunity and hope for people to stay home.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s the context in which the call-to-action work she&#8217;s doing in Los Angeles this week takes place.&nbsp; And let me roll out some of what she is able to announce this week.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;ll remember last December, when the Vice President held a roundtable with some business executives, she announced that we had galvanized $1.2 billion of commitments for the region.&nbsp;<br><br>Tomorrow, we will announce &#8212; and you&#8217;ll get this factsheet &#8212; that the Vice President has galvanized a total of more than $3.2 billion of investments for the region from 40 different companies and organizations.&nbsp;<br><br>So, this total includes more than $1.9 billion in new investments that we&#8217;re going to announce tomorrow from 10 new companies.&nbsp; And I just underscore: These, we think, are pretty sizable direct investments in economies the size of the three countries in question, and they will be responsible for creating tens of thousands of jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, we&#8217;ll get you a factsheet and all of the details, but just to give you a sense of what I&#8217;m talking about, it includes $150 million from the Gap to increase its sourcing from Central America.&nbsp; Another apparel company, SanMar, will invest $500 million in the region, generating 4,000 additional jobs.&nbsp; There&#8217;s $700 million from Millicom, a telecommunications company that&#8217;s going to expand its mobile and broadband networks in the region, and $270 million from Visa to expand financial inclusion and digital infrastructure.&nbsp;<br><br>And I particularly stress in the context of these announcements &#8212; you know, the last two, which expand broadband and financial inclusion and banking opportunities for people, really help make this project part of creating an ecosystem of opportunity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just the direct jobs that are created by these investments, but jobs in areas that help people thrive and succeed economically.&nbsp;<br><br>The Vice President believes that we need to not just offer an individual a job but address the full spectrum of needs and support individuals in the different facets of their lives.&nbsp; And that’s what this project is all about: trying to help individuals move up the economic ladder and not just have a job but also have access to information technology, banking system, and infrastructure that creates that positive ecosystem.<br><br>So we feel like, in the call to action, we’ve created an innovative public partner &#8212; public-private partnership model where companies and organizations and governments can work together and build off of each other’s work.&nbsp; And that’s what the Vice President will be discussing in a number of roundtables with business executives and others throughout the week.<br><br>She’s also going to be discussing other elements of our strategy, which we think make the investment climate even more attractive to these companies.&nbsp; I’m talking about combating corruption, promoting rule of law, reducing violence, and, in particular, empowering women, about which I can say a little bit more now.<br><br>But I just want to underscore that we believe, and the strategy last summer articulates this comprehensively, that you need all of these pillars &#8212; better governance, anti-corruption, rule of law, reducing violence, empowering women &#8212; going hand-in-hand with the job creation to have the long-term effect that we’re looking for.<br><br>So, I mentioned some specific initiatives in the space of empowering women, which the Vice President feels strongly about.&nbsp; And tomorrow, she&#8217;ll announce further initiatives in this area.&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;ll send you a factsheet.<br><br>But she&#8217;ll be announcing new commitments from the United States government and the private sector to support women&#8217;s economic empowerment and reduce gender-based violence in the region.<br><br>Some of the companies involved in the call to action, who have all stressed the importance of women&#8217;s empowerment for economic reasons, among others, are coming together for a new initiative called “In Her Hands,” where companies and organizations are making commitments to empower, train, and protect women.<br><br>Taken together, these private sector commitments will connect more than 1.4 million women and their communities to the financial system and digital economy, accelerate women&#8217;s participation in the agro industry, train more than 500,000 women and girls in core job skills, promote gender parity, and elevate women within the companies across the region.<br><br>Additionally, she&#8217;ll be announcing some U.S. government initiatives and funding, including efforts to address gender-based violence, which goes hand-in-hand with their economic empowerment.<br><br>So, tomorrow, the Vice President will speak to these initiatives and their importance.&nbsp; She will make clear the case that when a woman has access to economic opportunities and is safe and secure, it&#8217;s not just good for the individual, it&#8217;s good for her children, her family, her community, and our entire hemisphere.<br><br>Her central message in all this is that when women succeed, all of society benefits.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what she has told the companies that we &#8212; and organizations we&#8217;ve been working with, and that&#8217;s what she&#8217;s heard from them as well.<br><br>She’s prioritized this work as part of the Root Causes Strategy, and we are really pleased to see so many organizations and companies join us in lifting up women in Central America.<br><br>Lastly, let me just mention that the Vice President will also launch an initiative called the Central American Service Corps.<br>This is a $50 million initiative that will be administered by USAID.&nbsp; We will provide young people in northern Central America with paid community service opportunities.&nbsp; They will engage on local priorities, such as education and tutoring, climate action, food security, health services, and violence prevention.&nbsp; This will help them with life and job skills and, we believe, further help address the root causes of migration.<br><br>This initiative began as a pilot project in response to the call to action by our private sector and philanthropic &#8212; philanthropic partners.&nbsp; And we are pleased that we are now able to dedicate U.S. government resources to scale it up.<br><br>It really is &#8212; and I&#8217;ll end with this &#8212; a good example of how the public and private sectors can go hand-in-hand and work together and create the sort of synergies we think we need to be successful in this area.<br><br>So thanks for listening to that, sort of, summary.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;ll be happy to take a couple of questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yeah, if our operator could re-up the instructions to get in the queue that would be great.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Given that the Vice President is focused on the Northern Triangle, I wanted to see if any Northern Triangle leaders are going to be going to the summit, and if not, what that says about her efforts to engage with them.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; What we can confirm is that the countries of what you&#8217;re calling the Northern Triangle, northern Central America &#8212; Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador &#8212; will be represented at the summit and will fully participate in the summit.&nbsp; They are sending delegations.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;ve heard from the leaders of those countries.&nbsp; And we’ll leave them to speak for themselves about whether their leaders themselves are going to come.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a call for them to make.&nbsp; Some of them have said that they aren&#8217;t going to come, but they also have confirmed that they will be sending delegations.&nbsp;<br><br>So we consider them the participants in the summit.&nbsp; Each of them had a different reason for the leader &#8212; him or herself &#8212; potentially not coming.&nbsp; But it doesn&#8217;t undermine any of what I wrote out in terms of our approach to the region.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, we do work with and need to work with governments, and we do so where we can.&nbsp; But at the same time, we&#8217;re consistent with our principles.&nbsp;<br><br>I mentioned earlier how central anti-corruption and good governance was to making this effort work, and we&#8217;re not going to shy away from standing firm on those principles.&nbsp; And indeed, you know, he was standing firm on principles, such as inviting just democratic countries to participate in the summit and pursuing anti-corruption efforts, that may be the reason that particular leaders choose not to come.&nbsp; And we have nothing to apologize for in standing for those principles.&nbsp;<br><br>But going back to what I laid out in terms of our efforts to create economic opportunity (inaudible) hope, you&#8217;ll see that (inaudible) we&#8217;ve been, I think, remarkably successful in generating public-private partnership and private sector interest in these countries, and it&#8217;s having real results.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; I want to piggyback off of that last question for a second, because &#8212; so I know the President of Honduras, Castro &#8212; they announced on Saturday that they would be sending the Foreign Minister, but whether or not she&#8217;s attending, it&#8217;s still (inaudible).&nbsp;<br><br>I wonder if the Vice President is at all disappointed that you guys don&#8217;t know whether the President, Castro &#8212; who, you know, she obviously talked to in late May &#8212; is coming; whether you guys expect a phone call to happen in the next few days with either her or the Guatemalan President, since those are the two countries, out of the three, that Harris has talked to the most.&nbsp;<br><br>And as the President of Mexico is not coming, but we know that he&#8217;s going to be headed to the White House next month, can we expect any type of travel either on the Vice President’s side or on either of those two leaders’ sides to the U.S. in, kind of, the same fashion if they don&#8217;t make it?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Thanks for all of that.&nbsp; Just on the last thing: I don’t have any travel to announce, but I&#8217;m happy to address the three countries that you mentioned.<br><br>And I&#8217;m glad you started with Honduras.&nbsp; And I think the President of Honduras herself has said that she didn&#8217;t plan to come, and the reason that she &#8212; it was that she believes all countries in the region should be invited.&nbsp; And, you know, mainly that&#8217;s a reference to Cuba, which was not included.&nbsp;<br><br>The Vice President has a good relationship with the new President &#8212; I say “new”; it&#8217;s been over 100 days now &#8212; of Honduras.&nbsp; She went to her inauguration.&nbsp; She supports her efforts to support democracy and, indeed, fight anti-corruption &#8212; the issue I mentioned a minute ago. &nbsp;<br><br>But like I said, President Biden took a decision not to invite Cuban participation.&nbsp; This is a longstanding principle, in fact, of the Summit of the Americas which &#8212; and I think the third summit in 2001, in Canada, all of the countries participating made clear that democracy should be a core principle for this summit.&nbsp;<br><br>So we&#8217;re consistent with that collective decision, not just the U.S. one.&nbsp; And if that was the reason that &#8212; you know, as the President of Honduras, we respect her decision.&nbsp; If she wants to make a stand on that issue and feels differently, that&#8217;s obviously her sovereign right.&nbsp;<br><br>But my point on that is that it doesn&#8217;t interfere with our relationship with Honduras, with the Vice President&#8217;s personal relationship with President Castro, with Honduras&#8217;s participation in the summit &#8212; which you mentioned; they do plan to participate.&nbsp; The Foreign Minister will be here, and we look forward to fulsome engagement and follow-up.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to do all the private sector work that I described.&nbsp;<br><br>Guatemala is a different question.&nbsp; Again, I &#8212; you know, you can refer you to &#8212; I’ll refer you to the government of Guatemala for the reasons President Giammattei may not come.&nbsp;<br><br>I can only say on that: We&#8217;ve been consistent on the issue of principle as well.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve said that corruption is a core part of the Root Causes Strategy that President Biden put out an executive order on fighting corruption around the world, and we&#8217;ve been following up on that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been following up in terms of Guatemala.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m sure you saw last month we sanctioned and designated the newly re-appointed attorney general over issues of corruption.&nbsp; We set up an anti-corruption task force.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we&#8217;re just going to continue to be consistent and principled on the issues we think are important.<br><br>So, once again, it hasn’t prevented our work with the government of Guatemala or even the President of the Guatemala, for that matter, with whom we have engaged extensively.&nbsp; And it hasn’t stood in the way of the economic development that we&#8217;re trying to &#8212; and succeeding in delivering, or uplifting women and providing opportunity and empowering women in Guatemala and elsewhere.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s how I see the situation there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, how are you?&nbsp; I wanted to ask you regarding this last question: How confident are you that these issues about root causes of migration can be addressed without talking to the government delegations?&nbsp; Because, you know, like &#8212; there is, like, civil society and other representatives, as you’ve said, that it will be interesting to talk about the bilaterals &#8212; if there are going to be any in which the Vice President is going to take part.<br><br>And another question is: Is the Vice President going to meet with the Spanish delegation with &#8212; regarding an announcement that was circulated last week about possibly both Spain and Canada &#8212; this was published by Axios &#8212; taking Central American refugees from the United States, from the border?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, first of all, on the first part, let me be clear: We are talking to and the Vice President is talking to the countries in question.&nbsp; I mentioned their representation will be here.&nbsp; Our government-to-government work goes on.&nbsp; We have diplomats in the field.&nbsp; There are lots of phone calls.<br><br>So, when you say, you know, &#8220;Can the root causes be addressed without dealing directly with the governments?” &#8212; no, we don&#8217;t think so.&nbsp; It&#8217;s very helpful to deal with the governments as we do and we will continue to do, even as we also engage civil society and the private sector.<br><br>And again, I want to be clear: All of the governments we&#8217;ve talked about will be represented here in Los Angeles and will have interactions with their American counterparts.<br><br>On the issue of Spain and Canada, let me just say: We&#8217;ll have further announcements in the course of the week about migration.&nbsp; It is one of the issues that this summit is tackling, and there&#8217;s been an in-depth conversation going on with all of the countries of the hemisphere but then also some external partners like Spain, which has been really helpful including, frankly, on the root causes in Central America issue, but also potentially on migration.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ll have more to say on that in the course of the week.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s definitely in-depth conversations going on about a regional approach to those issues.&nbsp; And the two countries you mentioned are a core part of that.<br><br>Maybe we&#8217;ll take one last question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for having this.&nbsp; Since my colleagues beat me to the attendance questions, I&#8217;ll ask about the investment.&nbsp; In terms of keeping the governments of the region up to date with your actions and your announcements, are these governments &#8212; are the governments of Giammattei and Castro, and I suppose Bukele not so much, part of these announcements?&nbsp; Are they informed ahead of time of these announcements like the Gap, Visa, and so on that you mentioned?&nbsp; Or are they just going to find out tomorrow when the embargo breaks?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The initiative that I&#8217;ve described is based in the Partnership for Central America, which is a non-governmental entity that was set up in the context of the Vice President&#8217;s call to action.&nbsp; And most of this private sector work and these discussions have been in that &#8212; in that context.<br><br>I think it goes without saying that major investments of the scale that I&#8217;ve been talking to also entail and involve contact with the government by the companies in question.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s not part of our process necessarily to engage the government as we discuss and encourage and work on these investments, but it&#8217;s also not in any way going on behind their backs.&nbsp;<br><br>They &#8212; in fact, they welcome it.&nbsp; I know President Giammattei has underscored his personal interest in making foreign direct investment a priority for his country.&nbsp; President Castro, the same thing.<br><br>So, in terms of driving this process, I think it&#8217;s fair to say, you know, we&#8217;re doing it transparently, we&#8217;re on the same page, and we have a common interest in increasing jobs and foreign direct investment.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you very much to our speaker and thank you, everyone, for joining us.<br><br>As a reminder, that was on background to a &#8220;senior administration official&#8221; and the contents are embargoed until Tuesday, June 7, 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time and 2:00 a.m. Pacific Time.<br><br>We will follow up with all of you on some supporting materials, and we look forward to tomorrow&#8217;s announcements.&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 5:42 P.M. EDT</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Harris Announces More Than $1.9 Billion in New Private Sector Commitments as Part of Call to Action for Northern Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-more-than-1-9-billion-in-new-private-sector-commitments-as-part-of-call-to-action-for-northern-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Vice President, U.S.&#160;Department of State, and&#160;the&#160;Partnership for Central America (PCA),&#160;come together to announce private sector commitments now total more than $3.2 billion Vice President Kamala Harris today announced more than $1.9 billion in new private sector commitments to create economic opportunity in northern Central America, more than doubling the value of initial private sector&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The Vice President, U.S.&nbsp;Department of State, and&nbsp;the&nbsp;Partnership for Central America (PCA),&nbsp;come together to announce private sector commitments now total more than $3.2 billion</em><br><br></p>



<p>Vice President Kamala Harris today announced more than $1.9 billion in new private sector commitments to create economic opportunity in northern Central America, more than doubling the value of initial private sector investments in response to her Call to Action.&nbsp; As part of her role addressing the root causes of migration from Central America, in May 2021, the Vice President <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/27/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-launches-a-call-to-action-to-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-the-northern-triangle/">launched</a> the Call to Action for businesses and social enterprises to make significant commitments to promote economic opportunity for people in the region. This is in support for the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/Root-Causes-Strategy.pdf">U.S. Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration</a> which the Vice President launched in July 2021. A summary of progress in implementation of the Root Causes Strategy can be found <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/fact-sheet-update-on-the-u-s-strategy-for-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/">here</a>.<br>&nbsp;<br>The announcement today builds on the announcement the Vice President made in <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/vice-president-kamala-harris-announces-new-commitments-as-part-of-the-call-to-action-for-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-central-america-now-totaling-over-1-2-billion/">December 2021</a> of $1.2 billion in private sector commitments. &nbsp;Aggregate commitments under this initiative now total more than $3.2 billion.&nbsp; Taken together, these investments are creating an ecosystem of opportunity and helping to provide hope for people in the region to build safe and prosperous lives at home. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Biden-Harris Administration recognizes that long-term development in northern Central America requires more than just the resources of the U.S. Government. For this reason, Vice President Harris called upon the private sector to draw upon its resources and expertise to support inclusive economic growth in northern Central America. Over the course of the past year, the Vice President has convened CEOs and philanthropic leaders to advance this effort, and will do so again on the margins of the Summit of the Americas in Los Angeles at events hosted by the Partnership for Central America and Chamber of Commerce.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>New Commitments</u></strong><br><br>The following 10 companies and organizations announced major new commitments today, joining 30 companies that have already invested since the launch of the Call to Action in May 2021:<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Agroamerica</u></strong>:&nbsp; Agroamerica, a family-owned sustainable food and ingredients corporation, will invest more than $100 million in six new projects that will generate 1,000 permanent, living-wage jobs in northern Central America over the next 5 years.&nbsp; Future projects include a food ingredients refinery, a 600-hectares banana plantation,&nbsp;a large avocado plantation and processing plant,&nbsp;and the expansion of a Natural Ingredients Processing Plant. &nbsp;Agroamerica expects to drastically reduce food waste in the region while presenting an innovative business line for small and independent producers of raw ingredients and tropical fruits produced in Central America.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>COATL</u></strong>: COATL, a digital service firm, will invest $35 million in El Salvador to expand rural access to high-speed internet over the next 5 years by expanding and operating a highly reliable rural broadband network over existing high-power electricity lines. This work will allow equal access to a digital ecosystem in rural areas, enabling online education, financial inclusion, and e-services.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Fundación Terra</u></strong>:&nbsp; Fundación Terra, an independent foundation funded by contributions from Terra Inversiones, which works in the energy, petroleum, retail, and real-estate sectors, will invest $24.5 million in new programs over 5 years.&nbsp; These programs will support secondary education, digital access, entrepreneurship, and environmental conservation, including scholarships to tutor 40,000 students in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras in Math and Spanish, which will promote financial inclusion.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Gap Inc.</u></strong>: Gap Inc. is committed to sourcing in Central America, and their current production in Central America supports an estimated 8,200 manufacturing jobs in the region held primarily by women.&nbsp;Gap Inc. plans to increase its sourcing in Central America by approximately $50 million per year, for a total growth commitment of $150 million by 2025, as part of its strategy to increase supply chain resilience by nearshoring more production to the Western Hemisphere.&nbsp;These increased purchases from the region will support an estimated 5,000 additional jobs in Central America.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Millicom</u></strong><strong>:&nbsp; </strong>Millicom, a telecommunications company, will invest $700 million to expand and maintain its mobile and broadband networks in Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador over the next two years.&nbsp; This investment will advance Millicom’s efforts to accelerate economic growth in the region via increased connectivity as penetration rates for broadband in these markets are well below regional averages. &nbsp;In addition, Millicom’s investments will be made in line with the Race to Zero, the UN-backed campaign aimed at promoting a healthy, resilient, zero-carbon recovery.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Pantaleon</u></strong>:&nbsp; Pantaleon, a conglomerate including investments in agroindustry and real-estate, will invest $9.4 million to fund the initial phase of a 1,200-acre industrial park on Guatemala´s Southern Coast.&nbsp; Once completed, the park is expected to house a mix of manufacturing, logistics, and distribution businesses, among others.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>SanMar</u></strong>:&nbsp; SanMar, a U.S.-based apparel wholesaler, will increase its purchases of products manufactured in northern Central America by $500 million by 2025.&nbsp; These purchases will support the supply of products to SanMar’s over 60,000 customers, the overwhelming majority of which are American small businesses engaged in domestic light manufacturing.&nbsp; The increased capacity required for this growth will lead to the creation of 4,000 additional full-time jobs at Elcatex, a Honduras-based apparel manufacturer owned in part by SanMar.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Unifi</u></strong>:&nbsp; Unifi, a company that produces recycled and synthetic yarns, established its manufacturing and sales operation in El Salvador (Unifi Central America) in 2010 and has been invested in El Salvador and the region since then.&nbsp; Unifi is making significant investments in the footprint capacity and innovation of its El Salvadoran operation and has committed to investing $15 million over the next five years to expand capacity, improve efficiency, and reduce energy use.&nbsp; The investment includes new innovative texturing technology that will increase the company’s polyester yarn production in El Salvador by 40% and support continuous training and job growth in the region.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Visa</u></strong>:&nbsp; Visa will invest more than $270 million over the next five years to expand financial inclusion and digital infrastructure, with the goal of adding 6.5 million people and 1 million small and medium enterprises (SMEs) into the formal financial system in Guatemala, El Salvador, and Honduras. Visa will focus on helping the local financial sector deploy innovative payment technology, improving citizens’ financial capabilities while driving efficiencies in key areas of the economy including: agriculture, digital disbursement of government subsidies, and remittances, while also expanding financial education for citizens and SMEs, thus increasing acceptance of digital payments and bringing more people into the formal economy.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Yazaki</u></strong><strong>:&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>Yazaki North America, an automotive components producer, will invest an additional $110 million to hire over 14,000 new employees in Guatemala and El Salvador by the end of 2026.&nbsp; This builds upon a recent announcement to invest $10 million in a new factory in Guatemala, which is scheduled to start production with its first 1,000 employees in January 2023.&nbsp; Yazaki NA provides electrical wire harnesses for General Motors, Ford, Stellantis, and other global automakers.<br><br><strong><u>Updates on Previously Announced Commitments</u></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>Starting with just 12 companies and organizations, the Call to Action now includes 40 companies and organizations that have made commitments to invest in the region, representing financial services, textiles and apparel, agriculture, technology and telecommunications, and nonprofits.&nbsp; In addition, the&nbsp;Call to Action has generated new collaboration across participating companies, further boosting the initiative’s impact.<br><br>Highlights of progress to date include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Microsoft </strong>announced in December that they have expanded broadband internet access to nearly 2 million people. The company anticipates reaching 3 million individuals across the region by July 2022. Additionally, Microsoft expanded on its initial commitment and will provide digital skills training for 1 million individuals by 2025.</li><li><strong>Nespresso </strong>committed in May 2021 to support regional economies with a minimum of $150 million in investment by 2025. To date, Nespresso has signed over $100 million in contracts for coffee procurement, including the first-ever Nespresso coffee shipments from Honduras and El Salvador, which will increase incomes for thousands of farmers.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Accion</strong> through its work with partners in northern Central America, has brought over 140,000 people living in Guatemala — including 90,000 women — into the formal financial sector.</li><li><strong>Davivienda</strong> has brought over 201,000 individuals into the formal financial sector through expansion of digital services, signed a new Loan Portfolio Guarantee Agreement with the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), and extended over $100 million in low-cost loans for housing and small businesses.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>How to Respond to the Call</u></strong><br><br>The Call to Action is facilitated through a public-private partnership between the State Department and the independent organization the Partnership for Central America, in close coordination with USAID. &nbsp;The&nbsp;Call to Action’s six focus areas are intended to support long-term development of the region, including: promoting a reform agenda; digital and financial inclusion; food security and climate-smart agriculture; climate adaptation and clean energy; education and workforce development; and public health access. It serves as one component of the Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration, which involves significant commitments of U.S. government resources to support the long-term development of the region—including by fostering economic opportunity, strengthening democratic governance, combatting corruption, and improving security. This approach will leverage commitments and resources from the governments in the region, as well as partnerships with multilateral development banks, international financial institutions, and other partner countries.<br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration looks forward to increased collaboration with private companies from around the world to build upon this&nbsp;Call to Action&nbsp;in the months and years to come. The Administration welcomes additional commitments to participate in this initiative and promote economic opportunity in northern Central America.&nbsp;Vice President Harris invites&nbsp;interested parties to visit the State Department’s website at&nbsp;<a href="http://www.state.gov/jointhecall">www.state.gov/jointhecall</a>, or contact the State Department at&nbsp;<a href="mailto:jointhecall@state.gov">jointhecall@state.gov</a>.<br><br>More information can also be found in the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/27/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-launches-a-call-to-action-to-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-the-northern-triangle/">initial Fact Sheet announcing the Call to Action on May 27</a>. More information about the Partnership for Central America can be found at www.centampartnership.org. The Partnership can be contacted at&nbsp;<a href="mailto:support@centampartnership.org">support@centampartnership.org</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Vice President Harris Announces the Central American Service Corps&#160;(CASC)</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-the-central-american-service-corps-casc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris announced the Central American Service Corps (CASC).&#160; The CASC initiative was developed by public, private, and philanthropic partners in response to the Vice President’s Call to Action for northern Central America. CASC—a $50 million initiative, which will be administered by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)—will provide young people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris announced the Central American Service Corps (CASC).&nbsp; The CASC initiative was developed by public, private, and philanthropic partners in response to the Vice President’s Call to Action for northern Central America. CASC—a $50 million initiative, which will be administered by the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)—will provide young people in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras with paid community service opportunities, mentorship, and a path to future employment. Young people are looking for meaningful opportunities to build their futures and CASC is aimed at addressing the range of challenges youth face in the region. By supporting life and job skills, offering hope, and building confidence and a sense of belonging for youth, the CASC initiative will generate leadership potential and help foster optimism among youth in Central America that a better future is possible for themselves and for their communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>This initiative is in support of the U.S. Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration in northern Central America, which the Vice President launched in July 2021.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Central American Service Corps</u><br>&nbsp;</strong><br>Through CASC, youth will be offered opportunities to work in their own communities on local priorities such as educational support and tutoring, climate action, food security, green jobs, health education and services, violence prevention, and other civic-engagement activities.<br>&nbsp;<br>CASC will help address the drivers of irregular migration among those most likely to migrate by engaging youth in local driven service opportunities, providing a modest stipend, offering work and life skills acquisition, and enhancing young people’s sense of rootedness and commitment to their communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Youth service programs harness the energy of young people to meet critical local development needs, while providing them a pathway to education, employment, and a sense of civic responsibility and belonging. &nbsp;Educated, healthy, employed, and civically engaged youth are critical for driving economic growth, democracy, and prosperity.<br>&nbsp;<br>CASC programs will be funded in part through FY 2022 appropriations, which included $50 million for the&nbsp; Central America Youth Empowerment Program.&nbsp; The&nbsp; initiative is a multi-sectoral effort that will benefit from technical and financial support provided by a wide range of stakeholders in the public, private, and philanthropic sectors.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Partnerships</u></strong><br>&nbsp;<br>USAID’s coordination of CASC will promote the development of a robust network of youth service corps programs in Central America. It builds on a collaboration between USAID, the Howard G. Buffett Foundation, and Salvadoran NGO Glasswing International on a youth service pilot program which launched in 2021 with $13.2 million provided exclusively by the Buffett Foundation.&nbsp; CASC also builds on a collaborative effort between the Partnership for Central America (PCA) and Glasswing International to implement a community service program for young adults in the region in response to the Vice President’s Call to Action.<br>&nbsp;<br>Further, Peace Corps will draw upon its experience in partnering with host countries Costa Rica, Paraguay, and Peru to help Glasswing and other partners establish this service initiative.&nbsp; The Inter-American Foundation will leverage its broad network of civil society grantees and partners in the region to support CASC.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, more than a dozen businesses affiliated with PCA that collectively employ tens of thousands of people across the region have committed to support CASC through such possible activities as matching participants to potential jobs, training and mentoring, facilitating financial inclusion efforts, and direct financial support.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Harris Announces New Commitments Supporting Women’s Economic Empowerment in Latin&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-announces-new-commitments-supporting-womens-economic-empowerment-in-latin-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 09:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State, U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), and the Partnership for Central America (PCA), come together to announce programs supporting women’s economic empowerment in northern Central America and the broader Western Hemisphere Vice President Kamala Harris today announced new commitments from the U.S. government, private sector companies and organizations to support women’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>U.S. Department of State, U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), and the Partnership for Central America (PCA), come together to announce programs supporting women’s economic empowerment in northern Central America and the broader Western Hemisphere</em></p>



<p>Vice President Kamala Harris today announced new commitments from the U.S. government, private sector companies and organizations to support women’s economic empowerment in northern Central America and the Western Hemisphere more broadly. Accion, CARE International, Cargill, Mastercard, Microsoft, and PepsiCo—companies and organizations who have responded to the Vice President’s Call to Action—made additional commitments to remove barriers to women’s full economic participation and strengthen women’s access to quality employment, tools, resources, and networks for business development and growth—thereby promoting equitable economic recovery across the hemisphere. These commitments will also address gender-based violence in northern Central America—to help create safer, stronger, and more prosperous communities across the region.</p>



<p>These initiatives are committed in support of the U.S. Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration in northern Central America, which the Vice President launched in July 2021.</p>



<p><strong><u>Private Sector and Civil Society Commitments</u></strong></p>



<p>Today, the Vice President and the Partnership for Central America launched <a href="https://www.centampartnership.org/inherhands"><strong><em>In Her Hands</em></strong></a> as a private sector initiative to empower, train, and protect women in northern Central America and across the Western Hemisphere. Founding members are a coalition of companies and organizations who responded to Vice President Harris’s Call to Action, including CARE, Cargill, Mastercard, Microsoft, Millicom, Nespresso, PepsiCo, PriceSmart, and Pro Mujer.</p>



<p><strong>The integrated <em>In Her Hands</em> commitments will connect more than 1.4 million women and their communities to the financial system and digital economy, accelerate women’s participation in the agroindustry, train more than 500,000 women and girls in core job skills, promote gender parity, and elevate women within companies across the region.</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Establishing a Gender Equity Center</strong>: As a follow up to its December 2021 commitment in response to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/vice-president-kamala-harris-announces-new-commitments-as-part-of-the-call-to-action-for-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-central-america-now-totaling-over-1-2-billion/">the Vice President&#8217;s Call to Action</a> humanitarian organization CARE officially established the Center for Gender Equity in Central America. The Center is designed to empower 500,000 individual women and their families&#8211;providing benefits to a total of two million people to advance efforts to address the root causes of migration. The Center will leverage CARE’s gender and development expertise and deep connections to local partners and women&#8217;s organizations to support financial inclusion, women’s economic empowerment (including in the protection of labor rights and in supporting entrepreneurship), improved agricultural outcomes, prevention and reductions in gender-based violence.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Integrating Women into the Financial</strong><strong> Sector:</strong> Accion, with support from the Mastercard Center for Inclusive Growth, will partner with local institutions to connect over 300,000 Guatemalan women to the financial sector by 2025. In addition, PriceSmart, INCAE Business School, Mastercard, and Cargill will work with the Central American Institute of Business Administration to support 120 women-led small-and-medium enterprises (SMEs) in Honduras and Guatemala in increasing their access to markets and capital to grow their businesses and support job growth in areas of high-out migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Supporting Female Agricultural Workers</strong><strong>:</strong> Cargill has committed to empowering women in northern Central America’s agriculture sector by allocating a portion of its $160 million commitment in commercial and charitable investments made in December 2021 to establish new programs that will support and accelerate women’s participation in the agroindustry.&nbsp; One of these programs, a partnership with the global development organization ACDI/VOCA and their Transforming Market Systems program will provide grants to women-owned small businesses in Honduras to create thousands of jobs. These programs will facilitate women’s access to financing, provide them with training, and connect them to new markets to grow their businesses. To help empower women and increase employment among female farmers, Nespresso will roll out programs in El Salvador and Honduras in 2022 that will train its agronomists on gender equity. Finally, PepsiCo Latin America will bring the Next Generation Agriculture Fund to Guatemala, in partnership with the Interamerican Development Bank and a local implementing partner.&nbsp; The program will accelerate women’s participation in the agroindustry and increase their incomes.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Digitizing Women-owned Businesses:</strong> &nbsp;Mastercard will digitize 300,000 women-owned and led businesses in Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador by 2025. This commitment will build on Mastercard’s May 2021 commitment to&nbsp;bring five million people in the region into the financial system and digitize&nbsp;one million micro and small businesses in the three countries by ensuring Mastercard’s efforts reach women across the region. &nbsp;Additionally, Accion will partner with key stakeholders in El Salvador and Honduras to expand digital services to over 700,000 people within the next five years. Microsoft will also work with local partners to launch high-tech digital community centers in 20 new communities across the region to provide women and girls with internet, digital skills, devices, educational experiences, and mentorship in rural and high-migration areas.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Training Women in Critical Job Skills</strong><strong>:</strong>&nbsp; Microsoft will partner with Trust for the Americas to expand on its commitment to provide cybersecurity, coding, and artificial intelligence skills training to reach an additional 400,000 women, bringing the total number of beneficiaries to more than 500,000 women in Central America. Through a partnership with Pro Mujer, Microsoft will assist 146 organizations in the region to provide financial literacy and education programs to nearly 25,000 low-income women. Additionally, Mastercard will support 5,000 girls to pursue a future career in Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics through its award-winning Girls4Tech program. Millicom will also provide digital skills training for more than 8,000 adolescent girls and adult women in 2022—with a commitment to year-over-year increases—in the three countries of northern Central America through its <em>Conectadas </em>program. &nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Achieving Gender Parity: <a>&nbsp;</a></strong>PepsiCo will launch a fellowship program designed to elevate more women in PepsiCo with a goal to achieve equal representation at management levels in the company by 2025. &nbsp;Millicom similarly committed to achieve gender parity across its 22,000-employee organization by 2030.&nbsp; To ensure long-term sustainability of their gender commitments, anchor members of the Partnership for Central America, Mastercard, Microsoft, Nespresso, and Cargill will integrate CARE’s gender equity framework into their programming.&nbsp; This will build off examples from Nepal, Australia, France, Canada, and the United States to improve gender integration, strengthen capacity, and set new performance targets.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Elevating Women Within Companies:</strong>&nbsp; The World Economic Forum committed to launching a Gender&nbsp;Parity&nbsp;Accelerator&nbsp;focusing on economic empowerment in Central America. Building off the models deployed elsewhere in Latin America, the Accelerator will reskill women to prepare them for high-growth sectors, work to enhance work quality and pay standards, enhance social safety nets, and advance more women into management and leadership positions, with targets for women in leadership across government and business.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>U.S. Government Announcements</u></strong></p>



<p>Building off her leadership of collaborative public-private partnerships to address key challenges in the region, the Vice President announced the following U.S. government initiatives to complement private sector commitments to empower women and girls in the Latin American region:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Gender-Based Violence (“GBV”) Prevention, Protection, and Accountability Initiative:&nbsp;</strong>The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) announced new programs in northern Central America to end the scourge of GBV.&nbsp; In Guatemala, a new $6.5 million program will provide access to violence prevention interventions and services while increasing the capacity of local institutions and service providers.&nbsp; In Honduras, USAID will dedicate $2.7 million to strengthen access to security and justice for GBV survivors, as part of a broader investment in the judicial sector. The initiative will work with each country’s justice system to address crimes, especially those that are drivers of migration, such as GBV, homicide, extortion, and corruption, as well as human trafficking. This builds off a recently-announced program in El Salvador, the $35 million GBV Prevention, Protection, and Accountability Initiative, which will support prevention, protection for survivors, and increasing accountability for perpetrators.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>GBV Analysis and Roadmap:&nbsp; </strong>USAID’s new initiative will advance efforts to prevent sexual, gender-based, and domestic violence; hold perpetrators accountable; and protect and provide services for victims in northern Central America.&nbsp; Migration patterns and GBV are deeply intertwined, and individuals on migration pathways, especially irregular ones, are often at heightened risk of experiencing GBV due to their vulnerable status as undocumented migrants.&nbsp; This initiative will analyze gaps, drivers, and opportunities in preventing, mitigating, and responding to GBV in the context of migration, and offer a roadmap to inform U.S. government policies in support of the U.S. Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration.<strong><em><u></u></em></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Women’s Entrepreneurship and Labor Rights:</strong> To promote economic security for all, the Department of State will provide $4.5 million through the Gender Equity and Equality Action (GEEA) Fund to support the economic participation of women and girls across the region.<ul><li><strong>Empower Innovation Challenge: &nbsp;</strong>The State Department’s $3.5 million program will build the capacity of local civil society organizations and women-owned small businesses in Belize, Colombia, Costa Rica, Dominican Republic, Guatemala, Ecuador, El Salvador, Haiti, Honduras, Panama, and Peru. &nbsp;The initiative aims to empower women-owned micro-, small-, and medium-sized enterprises to scale their businesses through small grants, training, access to capital, networking, and partnership opportunities with local and international businesses. &nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Domestic Workers Rights Program:</strong>&nbsp;The State Department will expand&nbsp; its “Promoting the Rights of Domestic Workers in Mexico” program to protect labor rights of domestic workers and support their transition to the formal workforce. &nbsp;This $1 million project will also support exchanges between domestic worker organizations in Mexico and Guatemala.&nbsp; Program activities include national and international-level advocacy for the rights of domestic workers; training and mentorship to build the knowledge and capacity of domestic worker organizations; legal assistance for domestic workers; training domestic workers on a variety of topics related to labor rights, leadership, and professionalization; and education for employers to formalize relationships with domestic workers.&nbsp; </li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Women’s Digital Inclusion Initiative:&nbsp; </strong>The U.S. Mission to the Organization of American States (OAS), in partnership with the OAS Secretariat for Integral Development, will launch the $1.5 million “Economically Empowered Women for Equitable and Resilient Societies”&nbsp;project to increase the knowledge and capacity of women to effectively function in the digital economy, build sustainable livelihoods, and increase their participation in policymaking and leadership in their societies.&nbsp; The OAS Secretariat for Integral Development will implement the 36-month project, in partnership with Meta, which aims to build the capacity of women-led small and medium-sized enterprises to digitize, build an online presence, and access financial services and international markets.&nbsp; The initiative will benefit 18,000 women in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, as well as a select group of six Eastern Caribbean countries.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Dinner with Business Executives and Leadership of the Call to Action for Northern Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-dinner-with-business-executives-and-leadership-of-the-call-to-action-for-northern-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 03:59:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris tonight hosted a dinner in Los Angeles with business executives and leadership of the Call to Action for northern Central America, her effort to bring together the private sector and social enterprises to invest in and support the long-term development of the region. This dinner is part of a series of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">Vice President Kamala Harris tonight hosted a dinner in Los Angeles with business executives and leadership of the Call to Action for northern Central America, her effort to bring together the private sector and social enterprises to invest in and support the long-term development of the region. This dinner is part of a series of engagements in which the Vice President will participate on the margins of the Summit of the Americas to further her work addressing the root causes of migration from northern Central America. The Vice President believes that governments cannot solve these problems alone, which is why she has focused on bringing the private sector and civil society to the table.  In advance of roundtable meetings tomorrow, the Vice President and the business executives discussed how to further strengthen our collaboration and strategize on next steps as we continue to create economic opportunities for those in northern Central America. They also reviewed progress made thus far, including progress on the investments from 40 companies and organizations that have participated thus far in the Call to Action.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Meeting with Faith Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-faith-leaders-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 01:29:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54959</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris held a roundtable in Los Angeles, California with faith leaders to discuss some of the most urgent challenges facing our communities, including protecting reproductive rights and addressing the epidemic of hate that is gripping our nation. Attendees discussed the importance of protecting access to reproductive health care, preserving the right to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris held a roundtable in Los Angeles, California with faith leaders to discuss some of the most urgent challenges facing our communities, including protecting reproductive rights and addressing the epidemic of hate that is gripping our nation.<br> <br>Attendees discussed the importance of protecting access to reproductive health care, preserving the right to self-determination for individuals and families, and working together to chart the path forward. The Vice President affirmed the key role faith leaders play in bringing people together to move our country in the direction of justice, and she highlighted the constitutional rights affirmed in <em>Roe</em>, including the right to privacy, which protects the right to use contraception and the freedom to marry the person you love.<br> <br>Participants underscored the importance of ensuring that health care decisions are made by women without government interference, and the need to work together as a coalition to safeguard this right. The Vice President raised that the Louisiana legislature passed a bill that would ban abortion even in cases of rape and incest, saying the bill illustrates that there is a clear and imminent threat to the shared principle of allowing women to make decisions about their own bodies.<br> <br>During the conversation, the Vice President also raised the issue of gun violence that has been plaguing our nation. The Vice President thanked the faith leaders for the important role they play in working toward healing, hope, and unity in their congregations and communities.<br> <br>The Vice President affirmed that faith leaders are essential partners to the Administration and that she looks forward to continuing to work with them to build coalitions across faiths.<br><span style="text-decoration: underline"><br>Participants included:</span></p>



<ul><li><strong>Pastor Demetries Edwards</strong>, Pastor, 23rd Avenue Church of God (Oakland, CA)</li><li><strong>Rabbi Dara Frimmer</strong>, Senior Rabbi, Temple Isaiah (Los Angeles, CA)</li><li><strong>Rev. Edgar Boyd</strong>, Senior Minister, First AME Church (Los Angeles, CA)</li><li><strong>Nitasha Kaur Sawhney</strong>, Sikh civil rights advocate and lawyer (La Cañada, CA)</li><li><strong>Edina Lekovic</strong>, UCLA Community Scholar in Residence, Islamic Studies Program (Los Angeles, CA)</li><li><strong>Claire Lipschultz, </strong>VP of Board of Directors, National Council of Jewish Women (Sacramento, CA)</li><li><strong>Rev. Dr. Amos Brown, </strong>Pastor, Third Baptist Church (San Francisco, CA)</li><li><strong>Jackie Dupont Walker, </strong>Director, Social Action Commission, AME Church (Los Angeles, CA)</li><li><strong>Reverend Dr. Young Lee Hertig</strong>, Executive Director, Innovative Space for Asian American Christianity (Los Angeles, CA).</li><li><strong>Rev. Najuma Smith-Pollard</strong>, Assistant Director of Community and Public Engagement, USC Center for Religion and Civic Culture (Los Angeles, CA).</li></ul>



<p><br><span style="text-decoration: underline">The Vice President was also joined by:</span></p>



<ul><li><strong>Senator Alex Padilla</strong> (D-CA)</li><li><strong>Representative Jimmy Gomez</strong> (D-CA-34)</li><li><strong>Lieutenant Governor Eleni Kounalakis</strong></li><li><strong>Mayor Eric Garcetti</strong></li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before Roundtable with Faith Leaders on Reproductive&#160;Healthcare</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/06/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-roundtable-with-faith-leaders-on-reproductive-healthcare/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:47:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles County Federation of LaborLos Angeles, California THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  I want to thank these extraordinary leaders for being here today for a very important conversation that we will have about the challenges facing our nation, but our collective commitment to address these challenges in a way that inspires hope&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles County Federation of Labor<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, good afternoon, everyone.  I want to thank these extraordinary leaders for being here today for a very important conversation that we will have about the challenges facing our nation, but our collective commitment to address these challenges in a way that inspires hope and optimism and grace and dignity and love.  And so, I&#8217;m looking forward to our conversation.<br> <br>I want to recognize and thank Senator Padilla for being here.  I watched your work in the halls of the United States Senate and you represent California in such an extraordinary way.<br> <br>Congressman Jimmy Gomez &#8212; just always fighting.  Fighting for your district and fighting for our state and for our country.  Thank you for that.<br> <br>Of course, Lieutenant Governor Eleni Kounalakis, thank you for your extraordinary leadership of our state and the work you do every day.<br> <br>And, of course, our mayor, Eric Garcetti.  Thank you.  Thank you.<br> <br>So, I think we all would agree that, in particular, these last few years have, in many ways, tested our faith &#8212; tested our ability to believe that everything will be okay, should be okay, can be okay.<br> <br>Over the last few years, we&#8217;ve experienced &#8212; as a community, as a society, as a country, as a world &#8212; so much loss, unpredictability. <br> <br>And, of course, one of the discussions that we will have today is about also what we&#8217;ve seen in terms of a rise in hate and misinformation.<br> <br>And so, I do believe &#8212; and I, my entire life, believed this &#8212; but I think we, collectively, know, in particular now: We need faith.  We need faith. <br> <br>I know that no matter the differences among us in a society, there&#8217;s so much more in common than what separates us.  And I think most people, regardless of who they are, would agree.<br> <br>We need faith in each other, in our nation, and in our future.  And so, that&#8217;s why we are coming together today with a goal of instilling in folks a belief that gives them a sense of hope and optimism in themselves, in their community and our future. <br> <br>So, the faith leaders who are gathered here today are representative of many different faiths, many different communities, but share a common purpose, which is to bring healing and hope and a sense of community to all people.<br> <br>So, our discussion today will focus on, I&#8217;m sure, a number of issues.  But in particular, there are two &#8212; which is, one, what I believe is something that requires all of the leaders at this table, which is what we have been experiencing in terms of what I call an &#8220;epidemic of hate,&#8221; where we have seen so many communities who are being targeted &#8212; individuals who are being targeted simply because of who they are. <br> <br>And we combine that then with what we have seen in terms of misinformation that now, because of this age that we are in and how quickly it can spread unchecked, how ubiquitous it is, what it does to fan the flames of hate, which, of course, has always and recently vividly manifested itself in violent acts targeting innocent people and their families and their community and our nation as a result of those acts.  So, we will talk about that. <br> <br>And also, I would like to talk with these faith leaders about the impending decision from the United States Supreme Court that we believe will undo the very principles and premise of the importance of the privacy, the right that Roe v. Wade stands for.  And so, we will talk a bit about that.<br> <br>And I will say that, on the first issue, a subset &#8212; but a very, very specific subset &#8212; that we must address is how hate manifests itself in violent acts, most of which are committed with the use of guns, and what, therefore, that requires in terms of sensible laws for any society that should be rules-based with a goal of being a civil society.  And so, we can talk a bit about that.<br> <br>And then, on the issue of Roe, it, of course &#8212; basically, the premise of Roe and the power of Roe is it is about saying that people should have the right to make decisions about their own bodies &#8212; that women should have that right and have unfettered access to reproductive healthcare.<br> <br>So, that conversation, of course, in my mind, is a conversation that requires us to also discuss whether we value the concept of self-determination &#8212; the ability of an individual to make decisions about their own life and the future of their life and the choices that will directly impact so many other choices.  The issue of self-determination.<br> <br>I do believe that when we look at the challenge that we will face when that decision comes down, a part of it will be that it will directly, if not indirectly, impact other privacy rights, including the right to have access to contraception and the right to marry the person you love. <br> <br>And how will we then &#8212; as those who are guided by our faith, who believe in the best of what we are and who we can be &#8212; how will we speak with and talk about the people who are going to be directly impacted by that decision and how we uplift them in a way that they do not feel alone and without options.<br> <br>And I think it is very important to say &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to close my comments in a moment &#8212; it&#8217;s very important, I think, for us to agree and it&#8217;s an important point to make that to support Roe v. Wade and all it stands for does not mean giving up core beliefs.  It is simply about agreeing that a woman should be able to make that decision with her faith leader, with her family, with her physician &#8212; and that the government should not be making that decision for her.<br> <br>And I can&#8217;t end my comments without mentioning that, today, Louisiana is on the path to pass a law &#8212; or passed a law that will take away this right with no exception for rape or incest.<br> <br>So, the threat to all of these principles and priorities is very clear and imminent. <br> <br>And with that, I will close by again saying that &#8212; that you all, as our faith leaders, have done extraordinary work, in particular of these last few years, to remind folks that they are not alone, that we are in this together, that there is a higher purpose, and that we should be guided by all that we know &#8212; that that gives us a chance of shining a light in the midst of dark moments and dark days.<br> <br>So, I look forward to our conversation and talking about how we&#8217;re going to build the coalition based on these shared principles and beliefs.<br> <br>And with that, I thank you all.  And I thank you.  We&#8217;re now going to thank the press for your attention, and we&#8217;re going to have a conversation.<br> <br>So, thank you, all.<br> <br>END<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Head of the Foreign Relations Department of the Presidential Administration of Azerbaijan Hikmat&#160;Hajiyev</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-head-of-the-foreign-relations-department-of-the-presidential-administration-of-azerbaija/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan met today with Hikmat Hajiyev, Head of the Foreign Relations Department of the Presidential Administration of Azerbaijan.  They welcomed the 30-year anniversary of relations between the United States and Azerbaijan and underscored their readiness to further deepen bilateral ties.  They discussed their shared commitment to helping the people of Ukraine&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Adviser Jake Sullivan met today with Hikmat Hajiyev, Head of the Foreign Relations Department of the Presidential Administration of Azerbaijan.  They welcomed the 30-year anniversary of relations between the United States and Azerbaijan and underscored their readiness to further deepen bilateral ties.  They discussed their shared commitment to helping the people of Ukraine in response to Russia’s unprovoked aggression.  Mr. Sullivan commended Azerbaijan for its long-standing commitment to European energy security and discussed efforts to further diversify regional energy supplies.  The two shared their perspectives on the implications of the conflict in Ukraine for the broader region.  Mr. Sullivan conveyed the commitment of the United States to peace, security, and prosperity in the South Caucasus region.  He praised the significant and historic diplomatic efforts between Azerbaijan and Armenia toward a lasting peace.  Mr. Sullivan expressed support for talks hosted by President of the European Council Charles Michel.  He conveyed the readiness of the U.S. to engage closely and support progress through a variety of means, including in our capacity as a Co-Chair of the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) Minsk Group.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, June 6,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/06/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-june-6-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 22:44:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54950</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:34 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hey!&#160; Okay.&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Okay, I have one thing at the top for everybody. So, I know a lot of people have been asking about the Summit of Americas.&#160; And you probably saw: Tonight, at six o&#8217;clock, there&#8217;ll be a background call with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:34 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hey!&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Okay, I have one thing at the top for everybody.</p>



<p>So, I know a lot of people have been asking about the Summit of Americas.&nbsp; And you probably saw: Tonight, at six o&#8217;clock, there&#8217;ll be a background call with some of our experts, who &#8212; later today, clearly, at six o&#8217;clock &#8212; who will discuss the summit in detail and give you all the information that you wished for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I wanted to give a quick preview each day of the summit so you all have it now.&nbsp; And it will be arranged around five key areas that President Biden will focus on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Wednesday, the focus will be on economic agenda for the region and promoting health systems and health security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thursday will be responding to the climate crisis and combating food insecurity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Friday will focus on migration in the Western Hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can expect to see deliverables in those areas announced by the President and other members of his Cabinet on all the &#8212; all three days, relating to those focus areas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And one final item of note: Later this afternoon &#8212; hoping before our background call at six &#8212; we will share the list of countries attending for &#8212; for the summit.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure &#8212; I know everyone is excited about that.&nbsp; Everyone has been looking forward to that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, we&#8217;re going to try and end this at 4:15.&nbsp; I want to make sure I get to people in the back, so I just want folks to be mindful.&nbsp; I want to make sure that we make our rounds and so that people can have their questions answered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, with that, Chris, you want to kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I just have two questions.&nbsp; So, given the people who are not going to the Summit &#8212; the President of Mexico; President of Honduras, who the Vice President recently spoke directly to &#8212; what does it say about the strength of the U.S. influence in the region if these people are deciding they don&#8217;t want to go?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let me just speak to the President of Mexico very quickly, because I have something in there for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have had candid engagement with President López Obrador, as well with other regional partners, for more than a month regarding the issue of invitations to the summit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is important to acknowledge that there are a range of views on this question in our hemisphere, as there are in the United States.&nbsp; The President&#8217;s principal position is that we do not believe that dictators should be invited, which is the reason that he has &#8212; the president has decided not to attend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We look forward to hosting Foreign Secretary Ebrard as the Mexican representative.&nbsp; And we welcome Mexico’s significant contribution to the summit &#8212; to the &#8212; to the major summit deliverables.</p>



<p>President Biden and First Lady &#8212; and the First Lady look forward to welcoming President Obrador and Fir- &#8212; and the First Lady of Mexico to Washington in July for a bilateral visit.&nbsp; At that meeting, President Biden and President Obrador will have the opportunity to carry the work forward for the summit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To your second &#8212; to your other &#8212; to your actual question &#8212; I just wanted to make sure I dealt with Mexico because we had a little announcement there: The U.S. remains the most powerful force in driving hemis- &#8212; hemispheric actions to address core challenges facing the people of the Americas &#8211;inequality, health, climate and food security.&nbsp; And so, the President continues to be a leader in the hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The other question is: Russian President Vladimir Putin said that if the West continues to deliver rocket systems, Moscow will “hit objects we haven&#8217;t yet struck,” possibly expand the attacks (inaudible).&nbsp; What is the administration&#8217;s thinking on that?&nbsp; How is the White House interpreting that comment?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so I would refer you to the President&#8217;s op-ed that he did just last week &#8212; the New York Times &#8212; in which he laid out our objectives, which is &#8212; in Ukraine &#8212; and explain why we are sending Ukraine more advanced rocket systems and munitions.&nbsp; We are providing them with capabilities to help them defend their territory from Russia’s advances.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, this is Russia&#8217;s advancement onto their sovereignty, onto their territorial integrity.&nbsp; This is Russia&#8217;s war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we&#8217;re trying to provide &#8212; what we&#8217;re trying to provide with historic assistance to Ukraine is to &#8212; so that Ukraine could fight for their freedom.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The compromise that is being worked on, on the Senate side, on Capitol Hill, sounds like it might include some incremental expansions to background checks, possibly maybe encouraging more states to adopt red-flag laws, but it wouldn&#8217;t be a major expansion of background checks or raise the purchasing age for semi-automatic weapons or ban magazines &#8212; large-capacity magazines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How is the President thinking about a compromise like that? How disappointed would he be if it didn&#8217;t include many of the things that he just laid out the other night?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So let me just say that the President is encouraged by the discussions that are happening currently in the Senate by the bipartisan group that&#8217;s being led by Senator Murphy and other members, and it shows the urgency of the moment.</p>



<p>Look, so we have to remember that while there have been measured victories on gun violence prevention in recent years, there hasn&#8217;t been a wide-ranging bill passed since 1994.&nbsp; That&#8217;s almost three decades ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the President has made it clear that it’s time for Congress to act.&nbsp; We’ve seen the House do &#8212; take some actions last week; they’re going to take some more actions this week.</p>



<p>And so, we can’t &#8212; he can’t do it &#8212; he can’t do it all alone, right?&nbsp; He has taken some actions &#8212; some executive actions, as we’ve talked about here.&nbsp; And he believes that Congress should continue to act.&nbsp; And we are going to see how the negotiations go.&nbsp; We’re going to give it the space that it needs.&nbsp; And we’re not going to speak to what exactly is being discussed &#8212; the pieces of legislation &#8212; but we are encouraged and we think these incremental steps, these steps that they’re taking, this conversation that they’re having is very important for the moment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So does he consider this compromise that is potentially taking shape to be wide-ranging?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, he &#8212; what he’s calling for, clearly &#8212; and we’ve heard him talk to this on Thursday when he talked about how it is “enough” and how, when he went to Texas, Uvalde, the parents that he met with for more than three hours asked &#8212; asked him to do something, asked for Congress to do something.&nbsp; And this is what we&#8217;re seeing now.</p>



<p>We believe Congress needs to act.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re seeing is that they&#8217;re taking those actions by having this conversation, by having these negotiations to act.</p>



<p>And again, we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; we haven&#8217;t seen these types of steps in a long time.&nbsp; And so, the President is encouraged by it.&nbsp; He welcomes it.&nbsp; We have to see what the exact &#8212; what will come out of the negotiations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, you said he&#8217;s giving them space.&nbsp; You mean he&#8217;s not in regular communication &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I’m &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; with either the Democrats or Republicans involved in that compromise?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I’ll say this: What I can say is that, you know, what I&#8217;m &#8212; I’m not going to &#8212; as we, you know, we like to say, we don&#8217;t read out any private conversations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But &#8212; and I mentioned this last week &#8212; our Office of Leg. Affairs &#8212; his Office of Leg. Affairs have been in constant communications.&nbsp; Since the Uvalde shootings, more than &#8212; dozens of conversations with leadership in Congress, with the negotiation &#8212; negotiators, and also with staff.&nbsp; So that has been continuing.&nbsp; So his &#8212; his staff is really &#8212; has been very involved in that.</p>



<p>One more thing I do want to add: Senator Chris Murphy was on one of the networks here, and he said that he has been in constant communication with us every day during these &#8212; this time of negotiation.&nbsp; And he also said that he believes it&#8217;s time for the Senate to make a move and it&#8217;s time for the Senate to take action.</p>



<p>Okay, let me just go around.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to go back a little bit, but go ahead, Mary.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just following up on that &#8212; I think trying to get a sense of how the President defines success when it comes to this issue.&nbsp; I mean, you note those pleas to do something.&nbsp; Is doing something &#8212; even if it is far short of, obviously, you know, sort of the sweeping legislation that the President is looking for &#8212; is that still a success in the President’s mind?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think the way that the President &#8212; and he has said this, right? &#8212; which is: Yes, he has laid down a sweeping list of actions.&nbsp; He did that very passionately and very effectively on Thursday.&nbsp; And what he is saying, because the parents &#8212; he heard directly from the parents in Uvalde, and families &#8212; is that they just want to see some action.&nbsp; They want to see that &#8212; that Congress actually can put their politics aside and come in a bipartisan way and deliver something.</p>



<p>And when you think about the red-flag law &#8212; I know Nancy was asking me about that &#8212; 72 percent of Americans want the red-flag law.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s encouraging.&nbsp; That is important.</p>



<p>And if &#8212; if you think about it, too &#8212; if you look at the shootings in the past: Parkland &#8212; if the red-flag law was in &#8212; was in place back in 2018, that would have prevented &#8212; if it was enacted, that would have potentially prevented that tragedy.&nbsp; So &#8212; and now Florida has that red-flag law, and it has prevented tragedy in the state.</p>



<p>So, there are things here that are very important, I think, that are going to have some impact.&nbsp; Does &#8212; of course, the President is always going to call for more, but we want to see action.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re hoping to see with the negotiation that&#8217;s currently happening in the Senate.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the timing of all this, Leader Schumer wants to give enough time for negotiators to try and find some common ground but also wants to be able to get especially Republicans on the record on where they stand here.&nbsp; How long does the President believe these talks should be able to continue if there isn&#8217;t a real formal agreement yet?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, the President wants action right away, as soon as possible.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t want to &#8212; clearly, the families don&#8217;t want to wait, who have lost their loved ones, sadly.&nbsp; But we leave the mechanism to how this process is going to work and move forward to Senator Schumer.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just go to take &#8212; I&#8217;m going to go take some in the back here.&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Go ahead, you with &#8212; you in the &#8212; I know you yelled a question at me when I was walking out the other day.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Real quick &#8212; yeah, so, on Chinese tariffs, I want to ask you about &#8212; the Commerce Secretary said the President has asked her to look into possibly removing tariffs on some imports coming in.&nbsp; If that happens, has there been conversations with the Chinese about them dropping their tariffs for U.S. products going into China?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I just don&#8217;t want to get ahead of that.&nbsp; I know the &#8212; when the Secretary was doing Sunday television yesterday, she spoke to this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As she said, the President has asked her and others in the administration to look at this &#8212; to look at the Chinese tariffs.&nbsp; I do not want to get ahead of it.&nbsp; She even said the President is going to have to make a decision once it&#8217;s presented to him.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any of that at this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And one more on the Defense Production Act that was announced today.&nbsp; The President &#8212; what &#8212; taking a step back from that, what emergency is the President using to invoke the Defense Production Act?&nbsp; Because, historically, it&#8217;s been &#8212; in the 1950s, for the Korean War, and during COVID it was enacted.&nbsp; What emergency is it &#8212; what’s the real emergency in the solar industry for the Defense Production Act?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me &#8212; I was going to say, first, the President &#8212; you know, when he takes the Defense Production Act, it’s to make sure that he&#8217;s delivering for the American people.&nbsp; It is an important tool that he has used a couple of times, and it has been incredibly effective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, for this particular clean energy Defense Production Act, he is invoking the Defense Production Act to rapidly expand domestic production of solar panel parts, building insulation, heat pumps, and more.&nbsp; He is putting the full force of the federal government&#8217;s purchasing power behind supporting American clean energy manufacturers.&nbsp; And he is providing U.S. solar deployers the short-term stability they need to build clean energy projects and deliver more affordability energy to American families and business.</p>



<p>Altogether, these historic actions will cut costs for American families, strengthen our power grid, and tackle the climate crisis.&nbsp; And with a stronger clean energy arsenal, the United States can be an even stronger partner to our allies, especially in the face of Putin&#8217;s war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what&#8217;s the emergency in the solar industry?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, this is just a step to get to &#8212; to a place where we do have a clean energy arsenal.&nbsp; And so, this is a very important part of the President&#8217;s &#8212; this is a very important part of the President&#8217;s agenda in getting to that clean energy system that he&#8217;s been talking about since he walked into the administration.&nbsp; So, this is that, and this a way that we felt that we can act to get moving in that way.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll come back up.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Summit of the Americas with the U.S. not inviting Cuba, Venezuela, and Nicaragua for “principled reasons,” as it&#8217;s been described &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; about democracy, does the President feel in any way embarrassed that a neighbor like Mexico is not coming?&nbsp; Does it rise to that level of awkwardness?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me just first say that the President was aware that &#8212; when speaking to Obrador &#8212; that he wasn&#8217;t going to attend.&nbsp; He was aware before the press conference was made, before he made his decision to make that announcement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there was communication there, and he was made aware. Look, we have had candid engagement with the President of Mexico, as well with other regional partners, for more than a month regarding the issue of invitations to the summit.</p>



<p>It is important to acknowledge that there are a range of views on the question &#8212; in our &#8212; on this question in our hemisphere, as I mentioned earlier.&nbsp; The President&#8217;s principal position is what &#8212; we do not believe that dictators should be invited.&nbsp; That said, we look forward to hosting Foreign Secretary Ebrada- &#8212; Ebrard as the Mexican representative, and we welcome Mexico&#8217;s contribution to the major summit deliverables.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I mean, at the end of the day, to your question, we just don&#8217;t believe dictators should be invited.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s &#8212; and so we don&#8217;t regret that, and we will stand &#8212; the President will stand by his principle.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There was understandable skepticism &#8212; and, to some degree, pessimism &#8212; about the ability to get something related to guns over the finish line in the immediate wake of Uvalde.&nbsp; Has that shift &#8212; shifted at all inside the White House?&nbsp; Are you moving more towards an optimism, “this could actually get done” type of moment?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, the President is going to continue to use the bully pulpit to call on action.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we saw him do Thursday, and he has been doing that for this past year and a half.&nbsp; It is an issue that is a priority to him.&nbsp; This is why he has done the most executive actions than any President at this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we are optimistic, we are encouraged, as I just mentioned, of what we&#8217;re seeing on the Hill.&nbsp; The House has taken some action; they&#8217;re going to continue to take some action.&nbsp; But as we know, in the Senate, it takes 10 Republicans to get things done, to get something like this &#8212; as big as this done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, again, we&#8217;re encouraged.&nbsp; Chris &#8212; Senator Murphy has been pretty positive.&nbsp; And so, we &#8212; you know, that is something that we listen to.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue having conversation from the staff level to members and staff on the &#8212; on the Hill.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one on a separate issue.&nbsp; On gas prices, I understand what the administration has done up to this point on the policy side of things.&nbsp; I also understand it&#8217;s a global marketplace.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Given the fact that they keep hitting new highs, are there new initiatives, new policy proposals that your team is working through right now that could possibly have an effect or that you could roll out in the weeks ahead if prices continue where they’ve been?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, everything is on the table, as you heard us &#8212; as you heard us say the last couple of weeks.&nbsp; But I do want to say: Look, you know, if you look at what happened when Putin started amassing troops on the border with Russia, the price of gas has increased by $1.51.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I also want to add &#8212; because this is really important so that people understand and flag that similar issues are happening around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the EU, gas is $8.15 per gallon.&nbsp; It has increased by $1.74.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Germany, gas is $8.88 per gallon.&nbsp; It has increased $2.16.</p>



<p>In Canada, gas is $6.23 per gallon.&nbsp; It has increased $1.93.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all of this has happened since December of 2021.&nbsp; This is &#8212; to your point, Phil &#8212; which is &#8212; this is a global challenge.&nbsp; This is something that everyone is feeling across the globe.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we understand that prices &#8212; these gas prices, including food prices in particular &#8212; those two things, as we look at inflation and trying to make sure that we&#8217;re fighting inflation in every way that we can, is hurting families &#8212; is hurting families, especially as they sit around their kitchen table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re going to continue to do everything that we can. &nbsp;I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you.&nbsp; But, you know, one thing also I want to say: The Rescue Plan has really been able to help us put &#8212; put us in a &#8212; in an economic &#8212; a place where we&#8217;re stronger.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we saw that with the jobs numbers on Saturday &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, on Friday &#8212; and that is an important thing to note as well.&nbsp; Because when the President walked in &#8212; and this is &#8212; you know, this is something that we have to really continue to remember &#8212; we were in an economic crisis.&nbsp; And the President met that moment by putting forth the American Rescue Plan, by Democrats on the Hill voting for that plan, and really putting us in a place where we look at today in a much stronger economic situation where we can actually deal with inflation head on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have a lot of work to do, and we understand what the American people is feeling, but we are in a stronger place to take that on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, to the back.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh &#8212; oh, my gosh.&nbsp; Okay, let me just go to the back.&nbsp; Let me just go to the back.&nbsp; I&#8217;m trying.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Yeah, I haven’t seen you in here in a while.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s been a while, yeah.</p>



<p>So, a Washington Post feature over the weekend showed that the U.S. still has 94 contracts with the Saudi military and that Americans have been helpful in the coalition&#8217;s offensive operations in Yemen.&nbsp; The admin has said the U.S. support is only defensive.&nbsp; Is the Post report wrong on (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Wait.&nbsp; Say that last part.&nbsp; I didn’t &#8212; you kind of went out a little bit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; The admin has said the U.S. support is on the defensive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say &#8212; wait, say that whole &#8212; can you just say the whole thing?&nbsp; You said &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure, sure.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; 94 percent.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure, sure, sure.&nbsp; So, a feature in the Washington Post this weekend &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; showed that the U.S. still has 94 contracts &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; with the Saudi military, and Americans have been helpful in the coalition&#8217;s offensive operations in Yemen.&nbsp; But the admin has said it&#8217;s only &#8212; support is only defensive.&nbsp; So, is the Post wrong on that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me speak to the Washington Post piece &#8212; is that U.S. diplomacy under our administration has established a ceasefire in Yemen and the most peaceful period there &#8212; there has &#8212; that we have seen in six years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think the results of our approach speak for themselves, but I can&#8217;t speak to what has happened earlier before the &#8212; prior to this administration, earlier years of the war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just to your point about aircrafts and what&#8217;s happening there &#8212; and even training pilots &#8212; I know that&#8217;s been part of the discussion as well: Look, we are committed to helping Saudi Arabia defend its territory.&nbsp; Since last year, Saudi Arabia was attacked by nearly 500 missiles and drones.&nbsp; Most of these threats were defeated by the anti-air systems and Saudi aircraft firing air &#8212; in-air munitions.&nbsp; Seventy thousand Americans lives and work &#8212; live and work in Saudi Arabia, including in the areas targeted by these missiles and drones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re going to continue that support because they &#8212; because of &#8212; because they need to defend themselves and what they&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on Saudi.&nbsp; What evidence can the White House point to that repairing relations with Saudi Arabia will lead to reduced gas prices here in the United States?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Well, when it comes to oil or gas prices, that&#8217;s something that OPEC-Plus deals.  We do not get involved in any of that.  That is not the conversations that we have with Saudi Arabia.  And I know they &#8212; OPEC-Plus made an announcement last week, on Friday, and we welcome that announcement.  But that is not a part of our agenda when we have a discussion with them.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>Hold on.  Hold on.  Oh, my goodness. <br><br>Go ahead.  Go ahead, Jenny.<br><br>Q    Thanks, Karine.  Back to the Summit of the Americas: With Mexico and Honduras not coming and El Salvador not being expected, how do you have a high-level or effective immigration discussion with the region, with the presidents of Mexico and two thirds of the Northern Triangle countries boycotting this event?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I think we&#8217;re able to still &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re able to still have an array of conversations and really focus on our agenda.<br><br>I do want to list out who are &#8212; who is going to be attending.  I know we&#8217;re going to have a list fairly shortly, I hope.  We&#8217;re going to have 68 delegations, including organizations and observers, are scheduled to attend.  We have at least 23 heads of state of government &#8212; heads of &#8212; I&#8217;m &#8212; I should be careful here &#8212; heads of government who will be attended &#8212; attending.  And more than 10 U.S. Cabinet members will attend, reflecting President Biden&#8217;s whole-of-government approach.<br><br>So I listed out each day what our agenda is going to be, what we&#8217;re going to discuss, which is also very important.  But we are going to have on par &#8212; our attendance is going to be on par of what we&#8217;ve seen in the past.  And so, that&#8217;s important to know.<br><br>Yes, you know, we have these &#8212; you know, these &#8212; these couple of countries who are not going to be attending, but we have to &#8212; the President has to stick by his principle.  He believes that he needs to stick by his principles and not invite dictators.  But we can still have a fulsome conversation.  There is a full agenda where he&#8217;s going to be very busy.<br><br>I was looking at his calendar; he&#8217;s going be very busy those three days.  And he&#8217;s looking to having conversations with other heads of states who will be there.<br><br>Q    And then, one more on the DPA action that you announced today.  Invoking the DPA and imposing this two-year freeze on any new tariffs is a pretty novel way of using these wartime powers to declare the lack of solar goods a national emergency.  Should we expect similar actions from this administration when it comes to other clean energy imports or goods that we import that are facing tariffs or could be facing tariffs?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Yeah, I don&#8217;t have anything to &#8212; to preview &#8212; anything more coming forward.  But I do want to talk about how this is going to work.<br><br>So, the first step is to invoke the Defense Production Act, which is what the President is going to do today &#8212; is doing today.  This kicks off a process that includes relevant federal agencies and stakeholders to quickly determine most immediate needs and identify the appropriate financial tools and resources to meet those needs.<br><br>As that process unfolds, we will, of course &#8212; we will use &#8212; we will continue to work with Congress to advance these important priorities, which are necessary to position the United States to win the 21st century.<br><br>So I just wanted to give &#8212; I know some folks had questions about how the DPA was going to act.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q    I just want to get back to what you said a minute ago with Saudi Arabia.  I mean, finding more oil and getting that to market is such a key part of the broader strategy with Russia right now.  When OPEC-Plus made that announcement, you put out a statement saying, “We recognize the role of Saudi Arabia…in achieving this consensus.”<br><br>You&#8217;re saying, when the President, when senior administration officials are talking to people in Saudi Arabia, the question of oil production never comes up?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I&#8217;m saying it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not the &#8212; it&#8217;s not the focus; it&#8217;s not the &#8212; on the agenda, right?  That&#8217;s something for OPEC-Plus to decide.  Clearly, Saudi Arabia chairs that.  And so, we just want to be very clear on that.<br><br>And I was asked the same question last week, and I pretty much said the same thing.  And so, that&#8217;s &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m just going to leave it there.<br><br>Q    Okay.  And then a quick question on the &#8212; on the solar announcement today.  I understand the policy reasons for the announcement, but given how many times the administration, the Commerce Department said, “We want to be really careful to not get in the way of this investigation” &#8212; I think the Secretary said, “My hands are tied when it comes to this” &#8212; can you just explain the administration’s thinking in how this two-year pause and guarantee doesn&#8217;t undermine an investigation into those tariffs?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  Yeah, so the President is invoking an authority under the Tariff Act that authorizes him to suspend certain important duties to address an emergency.  In this case, the emergency is the threat to the availability of sufficient electricity-generation capacity to meet expected customer demand.  So that&#8217;s the emergency there.<br><br>The President&#8217;s action will help ensure that we have the solar capacity additions necessary to meet our electricity and generate &#8212; and generation needs.<br><br>So, the President is invoking section three- &#8212; 318(a) of the Tariff Act, and that&#8217;s how we&#8217;re moving forward.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to move aro- &#8212; I&#8217;m going to move around.<br><br>Q    (Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I’m going to move around.<br><br>Q    (Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  I’m goi- &#8212; go ahead, Steven.</p>



<p>Q    Just to follow up on Saudi Arabia: It’s been reported as fact that the President has decided he is going to go this summer.  You said on Friday it was still a possibility.  Can you give us a sense of where that decision stands today?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:  So, we have no travel to &#8212; to announce today.  But I can assure you that what the President is focused on is &#8212; first and foremost is how his engagements with foreign leaders advance American interests.  That is &#8212; that as &#8212; as true with Saudi Arabia with &#8212; than anywhere else &#8212; than any &#8212; with anyone else.</p>



<p>Just as he has engaged recently with leaders of ASEAN in Asia &#8212; and this week, he&#8217;s going to do that at the Summit of Americas &#8212; the President will look for opportunities to engage with leaders from the Middle East region.&nbsp; And we just ha- &#8212; don&#8217;t have anything to announce today.<br><br>But I do want to be &#8212; make &#8212; you know, be clear here: People have been asking if it was postponed.&nbsp; You &#8212; look, he said &#8212; the President said himself on Friday &#8212; I believe, yes, Friday &#8212; that the &#8212; that there was a &#8212; a visit in the works.&nbsp; But it was &#8212; it was &#8212; it wasn&#8217;t moved or postponed.&nbsp; It was &#8212; that &#8212; that reporting is actually not accurate.&nbsp; We were still having discussions, it was being considered, but it was never locked in.&nbsp; So I just want to be very clear on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up: Congressman Schiff said, on “Face the Nation” yesterday, the President should not go to Saudi Arabia, and that he would not shake the Crown Prince&#8217;s hand.&nbsp; He said, “This is someone who butchered an American resident, cut him up into pieces and in the most terrible and premeditated way.”&nbsp; How does that weigh on the President&#8217;s thinking about a possible trip?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, Congressman Adam Schiff is someone that we &#8212; we respect very much, that the President respects very much.&nbsp; As the President said on Friday, he believes it&#8217;s his job to try to bring peace where he can.</p>



<p>This trip to Israel and Saudi Arabia, when it comes, would be in the context of significant deliverables for the American people and the Middle East region.<br><br>You know, we look forward to consulting closely with members of Congress.&nbsp; But again, I don&#8217;t have a trip right now to announce.&nbsp; So there&#8217;s really &#8212; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of something that we&#8217;re just &#8212; don&#8217;t have anything for &#8212; to share.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to guns and the Capitol &#8212; what&#8217;s going on there.&nbsp; Senator Toomey said on “Face The Nation” this weekend that the President has actually not been helpful, that the speech was too left leaning.&nbsp; And I’ve know I’ve had sources &#8212; and including some Democrats &#8212; who also feel like this White House has not really helped talks, whether it be on this or Build Back Better.<br><br>Can you can you respond to Senator Toomey’s idea that the President has not been helpful?&nbsp; And also, just what is the President doing to try and build this compromise?&nbsp; Or is staying away from the Capitol what he&#8217;s doing?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, so we would respectfully disagree with Senator Toomey.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been in close, regular contact, dozens of conversations that our Office of Leg Affairs has had with Senate &#8212; Senate negotiators, leaders of Congress, since Uval- &#8212; since, sadly, the shooting in Texas, in Uvalde.&nbsp; So they&#8217;ve been in constant communication while this has been happening.<br><br>And, you know, we&#8217;re calling for action that broadly shared by &#8212; by the vast majority of Americans.&nbsp; According to a CBS/YouGov poll out this weekend, 81 percent of Americans want universal background checks.&nbsp; As I mentioned, 72 percent want a national red-flag law; 62 percent want a nationwide ban on AR-15s; and, importantly, 72 percent agree that mass shootings are something we can prevent.&nbsp; And the President agrees, and this is why he&#8217;s calling for them to act.<br><br>But the President has been involved &#8212; or, in- &#8212; involved in this since day one.&nbsp; Since the day &#8212; since day one, when he walked in and talked about comprehensive gun reform and what he was going to do.&nbsp; Again, the State of the Union &#8212; you&#8217;ve heard me talk about &#8212; say that he made sure that that was a par- &#8212; a big part of his address to Congress and to the country.<br><br>When he &#8212; when we talk about the executive actions that he&#8217;s taken &#8212; more than any president at this time of their administration &#8212; those are real steps that this president has taken.&nbsp; And not just as president, during his Senate years, in 1994, the banning of assault weapons; that is something that he led on.<br><br>And if we even look at what happened those first 10 years of that &#8212; of that assault <s>ban weapon</s> [weapons ban] was in law &#8212; into law, it actually brought down mass shootings.&nbsp; And when it &#8212; when it expired in 2- &#8212; in 2004, 10 years later, we saw mass shootings triple.<br><br>And so these are the things that the President continues to call for.<br><br>But he&#8217;s encouraged.&nbsp; He&#8217;s encouraged by what he&#8217;s seeing in Congress.&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;ve been in constant communications; Senator Murphy said this yesterday during one of his Sunday show interviews.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we’re &#8212; but we&#8217;re going to continue to do our part.&nbsp; The President is going to continue to use the &#8212; his bully pulpit to call for action, which he did on Thursday.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, on Boris &#8212; on Boris Johnson?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, on Boris Johnson.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; It just came over the wire: Prime Minister Johnson has survived a no-confidence vote among Tory MPs, 211 to 148.&nbsp; Was the President concerned that he might be removed?&nbsp; And does he have any plans to speak with him?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And is the President concerned that perhaps his weakened standing &#8212; 148 conservative MPs wanting to remove him &#8212; might hurt the attempts to keep this coalition that the President has built, with respect to Ukraine, together if the possibility of a leadership change in the UK government remains?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m not going to comment &#8212; we are not going to comment on inter- &#8212; inter- &#8212; internal politics.&nbsp; I would refer you to the UK government.&nbsp; We just are not going to comment on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, my &#8212; go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; I haven’t seen you in here in a while.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, please go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to the summit.&nbsp; You spoke about a month or so of engagements between U.S. and Mexico.&nbsp;&nbsp; I wonder if you can talk about the tone and timbre of those conversations, particularly if the President or the Vice President talked to President López Obrador.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I have another question too about the summit.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, look, you know, I don&#8217;t have any conversations to read out to you.&nbsp; We try to keep our &#8212; as we say over and over again, we try to keep our conversations private.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any readout for you on the tone or tenor of a conversation.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have a &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t have any calls to read out that the President may have had with any &#8212; with the Mexican President in particular.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Senator Menendez accused, you know, López Obrador of siding with dictators, and said that, you know, his actions will, you know, have a negative impact on U.S.-Mexico relations.&nbsp; Does the United States or the White House share, you know, that assessment or have worries about that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; This is &#8212; say that one more time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Senator Menendez said &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; accused López Obrador of siding with dictators and it will have a negative impact on U.S.-Mexico relations.&nbsp; I wonder what the White House feels about that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we see our relationship with Mexico &#8212; they &#8212; we see them as a close ally, as a partner.&nbsp; They&#8217;re coming here in July with the &#8212; the President is coming with his first &#8212; with the First Lady.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to continue to talk about the opportunity to carry out the work of the summit forward.&nbsp; And so, we see them as a friend and a close ally.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, in your description of the three countries that were not invited, you said President has drawn a line at dictatorship, which is basically taking the moral position and putting that in a priority above, say, getting more oil from Venezuela and so forth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But when you got to Saudi Arabia, you said you were looking to work for the American people toward a better solution.&nbsp; Does this suggest that the President, who called Saudi Arabia a “pariah state,” does not believe it is a dictatorship or believes that, for whatever its governance’s shortcomings, obtaining the oil is more important?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you &#8212; as you started off saying, the President is focused on getting things done for the American people.&nbsp; You know, and if he determines that it&#8217;s in the interest of the United States to engage with a foreign leader and that such enga- &#8212; such an engagement can deliver results, then he&#8217;ll do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the case of Saudi Arabia &#8212; to your question &#8212; which has been a strategic partner of the United States for nearly 80 years, there&#8217;s no question that important interests are interwoven with Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; And the President views the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia as an important partner on a host of initiatives that we are working on, both in the region and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I said on Friday, the extension of the “Yemen Truce,” as we &#8212; as we talked about, is a clear example of where our engagement with a foreign leader can deliver results.&nbsp; Ending the Yemeni war is a priority of the President’s.&nbsp; And the King of Saudi Arabia and the Saudi Crown Prince played a critical role in securing an extension of the truce that has been in place since April.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This truce brought about one of the most peaceful periods since this terrible war began seven years ago and saved thousands of lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President has also repeatedly confirmed our commitment to supporting Saudi Arabia in the defense of its territory from Iran and other threats, as I just laid out a moment ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also no question that, as with many countries where we share interests, we have concerns about its human rights record &#8212; that is a very &#8212; a very important thing to the President &#8212; and past conduct, much of which predated our administration.&nbsp; And we raised those concerns with them, as we do with others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, of course, there are also strategic priorities that are important to address.&nbsp; And our contacts and diplomacy have intensified recently, and that will continue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to continue because I want to get around.&nbsp; We have about 10 minutes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Does the White House have a reaction to Russia imposing personal sanctions on Secretary Yellen, Secretary Granholm, and others in the U.S.?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I &#8212; I have not seen that, so I don’t have a comment from here on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the war effort and the attack over the weekend by Russia in Kyiv give the White House pause about the status of the battle between those two countries and influence additional U.S. support, perhaps, for Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, Russia continues to make incremental gains and limited progress in certain areas of Ukraine.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we are continuing to provide deliveries of weapons and equipment as quickly as possible.&nbsp; So, that has not changed; we&#8217;re going to continue to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s why Secretary Austin and the Department of Defense have organized meetings with more than 40 countries to facilitate weapons transfers from our Allies and partners to help Ukraine defend the democracy &#8212; their democracy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are committed to make sure that Ukraine is able to fight for their freedom.&nbsp; This is the &#8212; this is coming from the President&#8217;s New York Times article last week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, this is Russia&#8217;s aggression on Ukraine sovereignty, on their territorial integrity.&nbsp; This &#8212; they are fighting for their democracy.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to do everything that we can to put them in a position of strength so that they can defend themselves.&nbsp; And if there is an opportunity for them to negotiate, they would be able to do that at a &#8212; in a position of strength.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; On the solar panels, how is this not a gift to Chinese solar manufacturers who &#8212; many of whom operate with forced labor and are subsidized by the Chinese Communist Party?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, today&#8217;s announcement is about one country and one country alone, and it&#8217;s about the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is about the reliability of our power &#8212; of our power grid.&nbsp; It is about reducing costs for American families, and it’s about enabling domestic solar manufacturers to move forward with their projects.</p>



<p>The actions that we’re &#8212; we are currently doing is being applauded by members of Congress, by labor, by climate groups, by U.S. CEOs, and domestic solar manufacturers as well.</p>



<p>The &#8212; the actions do not apply to any materials imported from China.&nbsp; Import duties will remain in place on solar cells and panels from China or Taiwan.&nbsp; So it has nothing to do with either; it’s about making sure that we’re delivering for the American public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the summit: Cuba, Nicaragua, Venezuela aren&#8217;t getting invites because of their human rights records &#8212; I know you just got a question on this &#8212; but then how does it make sense to then have the President visiting with Mohammed bin Salman, who the CIA says ordered the killing of Jamal Khashoggi?&nbsp; How does it make sense to deny those countries and then have a visit with the Crown Prince?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, first of all, there&#8217;s no &#8212; there&#8217;s no trip for me to announce.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I&#8217;ve said.&nbsp; The President even said that, you know, let&#8217;s not get ahead of ourselves here when he was asked specifically about meeting with MBS.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he may &#8212; he may not do it?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying that I just don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; it&#8217;s a hypothetical, and I just don&#8217;t have anything to announce or to speak to about a meeting.&nbsp; You said, “He&#8217;s going to be meeting with…”&nbsp; I&#8217;m telling you I don&#8217;t have anything to announce at this &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there some in the administration who say he shouldn’t be meeting with him?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me just &#8212; you asked me about Khashoggi.&nbsp; Let me just say this: When the President came into office, we were determined to make sure that our decades-long relationship with Saudi Arabia was serving our own interests and our values as we move forward, but also preserving it, because it has also help us accomplish many important things, and that’s largely what we’ve done.</p>



<p>The murder of Jamal Khashoggi was something that we and so many others around the world took very, very seriously.&nbsp; One of the things that we did early on was to release our own report on this murder.&nbsp; At the same time, we initiated the so-called “Khashoggi ban” to make sure that any country that seeks to use tools of repression against people abroad who are criticizing, in one &#8212; one way or another, the government would pay a price for that.&nbsp; And we’ve used it multiple times since.</p>



<p>At the same time, we thought it was very important to engage Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; Yemen was one of the most important places that we wanted to do that, and we’ve seen, as a result of our work with Saudi Arabia, is a real progress in actually dealing with one of the worst conflicts in &#8212; the world has seen over the last decade.</p>



<p>I’m going to take one more question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk by reporters.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I’m trying to go to somebody I haven’t called in &#8212; on in a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I haven’t seen you in a while.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I want to go back to the solar energy announcement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing big increases in electricity rates in many places around the country for the summer.&nbsp; Regulators are warning about an elevated chance of blackouts this summer, particularly in the Western and Midwestern states.&nbsp; The DPA announcement today isn&#8217;t going to have any kind of immediate impact on those events.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m wondering if there are actions that the administration can take that would address those issues this summer and if that&#8217;s something that you&#8217;re working on.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I said earlier that, you know, we will cont- &#8212; we&#8217;re going to continue to work with Congress to advance important priorities.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s going to continue as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the steps we&#8217;re taking today are in response, you know, to an urgent need of &#8212; to grow the domestic clean energy economy and strengthen U.S. energy security.&nbsp; They are part of the President’s multi-pronged approach to accelerating the transition to a cleaner &#8212; a clean energy future made right here in America.</p>



<p>This is particularly urgent given the impact of Russia’s invasion in Ukraine on the global energy supply, as well as the intensifying &#8212; the impacts of climate change on the electricity grid.</p>



<p>So this is just one part.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to call &#8212; call on Congress to make sure that they are also acting.&nbsp; But this is an important first step in getting to our goal.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does it have an impact this summer on &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just say &#8212; I &#8212; what I would say is: This is an important first step.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have the specifics on when it will have an impact, but this is an important step to getting to where we need to make sure that we are actually heading to a place where we&#8217;re getting to a clean energy.</p>



<p>That’s it.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We’re going to go.&nbsp; We’re going to get going, guys.&nbsp; It&#8217;s time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:16 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
