<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 19:23:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/25/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47897</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Jay Shambaugh, Nominee for Under Secretary for International Affairs, Department of the Treasury William Duncan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of El Salvador Lesslie Viguerie, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Jay Shambaugh, Nominee for Under Secretary for International Affairs, Department of the Treasury</li><li>William Duncan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of El Salvador</li><li>Lesslie Viguerie, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kyrgyz Republic</li><li>Denis Udall, Nominee for Trustee of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation</li><li>Tess Udall, Nominee for Trustee of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Jay Shambaugh, Nominee for Under Secretary for International Affairs, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Jay Shambaugh is a Professor of Economics and International Affairs at the George Washington University. His area of research is macroeconomics and international economics. His work includes analysis of the interaction of exchange rate regimes with monetary policy, capital flows, and trade flows as well as studies of international reserves holdings, country balance sheet exchange rate exposure, the cross-country impact of fiscal policy, the crisis in the euro area, and regional growth disparities.</p>



<p>Shambaugh served as a Member of the White House Council of Economic Advisors (CEA) from 2015-2017. Earlier, he served on the staff of the CEA as a Senior Economist for International Economics and then as the Chief Economist. He also spent three years as the Director of the Hamilton Project at the Brookings Institution. He is a Research Associate at the National Bureau of Economic Research and Non-Resident Senior Fellow in Economic Studies at Brookings. Prior to joining the faculty at George Washington, Shambaugh taught at Georgetown and Dartmouth and was a visiting scholar at the International Monetary Fund. He has published a book on exchange rate regimes, edited a number of policy related books, and published in many leading economics journals. Shambaugh received his Ph.D. in economics from the University of California at Berkeley, an M.A. from the Fletcher School at Tufts, and a B.A. from Yale University.</p>



<p><strong><u>William Duncan, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of El Salvador</u></strong></p>



<p>William H. Duncan, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as a Senior Inspector in the Office of the Inspector General, U.S. Department of State. Previously, he served as Consul General in Monterrey, Mexico. Prior to that, he served as Deputy Chief of Mission at U.S. Embassy Mexico City, Mexico. A Foreign Service officer since 1992, he has also served at U.S. Diplomatic Missions in Asunción, Madrid, Baghdad, Mexico City, Bogotá, San Salvador, and Matamoros. His domestic assignments include the Offices of Andean Affairs, Mexican Affairs, East African Affairs, and Central American Affairs, as well as the State Department Operations Center. Duncan has received numerous performance awards, including a Presidential Meritorious Service award and four Senior Foreign Service Performance awards.</p>



<p>A native of Louisiana, Duncan has a Bachelor’s Degree and a Juris Doctor from the University of Arkansas. He speaks Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lesslie Viguerie, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kyrgyz Republic</u></strong></p>



<p>Lesslie Viguerie, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the U.S. Department of State’s Deputy Assistant Secretary for Central Asian and Pakistan Affairs within the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs. Previously, he was Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Tashkent, Uzbekistan, and Minister-Counselor for Political Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in New Delhi, India. In Washington, DC, he was Director for Europe and Asia in the Bureau of International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs, and Director for Central Asia in the Bureau of South and Central Asia Affairs. Previous overseas assignments include Deputy Political Counselor for the U.S. Embassy in New Delhi, Senior Director of the Interagency Rule of Law Section for the U.S. Embassy in Kabul, and External Political Relations Chief for the U.S. Embassy in Moscow.</p>



<p>A native of Virginia, Viguerie is the recipient of numerous State Department performance awards, including a Senior Foreign Service Performance award. Viguerie is a graduate of The George Washington University (B.A.) and Catholic University of America (J.D.) and is a member of the District of Columbia Bar Association. He speaks Russian, Hindi, and Portuguese.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Denis Udall, Nominee for Trustee of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>Denis Udall is the Director of Strategic Partnerships with the George Lucas Education Foundation where he manages the strategic direction of the Foundation’s priorities related to project based-learning. Previously, Udall was a program officer at the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation for eight years where he managed strategy and grantmaking related to a wide range of areas, including improving the quality of curriculum and instructional materials, California education policy, and classroom and school-level formative assessment. During his tenure at the Walter S. John Foundation, Udall focused on vulnerable, disconnected youth. Udall has also had a 10-year history with Outward Bound including helping to found Expeditionary Learning (now EL Education), a national school improvement network, and the New York City Outward Bound Center, Outward Bound’s first urban center. Udall is the founder of the North Oakland Community Charter School. He received an Ed.M. from the Harvard Graduate School of Education.</p>



<p><strong><u>Tess Udall, Nominee for Trustee of the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation</u></strong></p>



<p>Tess Udall is a sixth generation Coloradan, born and raised in the foothills of Boulder. Udall is currently a law student at the University of Colorado, where she is specializing in environmental law with an emphasis on native communities and civil rights. While at Colorado Law, she has interned with the Colorado Attorney General’s Office, served as a student clerk for Chief Justice Brian Boatright of the Colorado Supreme Court, and is currently a student attorney in the Getches-Green Natural Resources and Environmental Law Clinic.</p>



<p>Udall previously served as Chief of Staff to the COO of the Retail and Rental Division at Vail Resorts. Udall also worked on strategic partnerships and client relations at Guild Education, a Denver education startup redefining the future of work. Earlier in her career, Udall served in the Obama-Biden White House in various roles in the Chief of Staff’s Office, on the Scheduling and Advance team, and for First Lady Michelle Obama. Udall graduated from the University of Virginia with a degree in Foreign Affairs and Sociology.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Nominates Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson to Serve as Associate Justice of the U.S. Supreme&#160;Court</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/25/president-biden-nominates-judge-ketanji-brown-jackson-to-serve-as-associate-justice-of-the-u-s-supreme-court/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 15:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47858</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden will announce his intent to nominate Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson as Associate Justice of the U.S. Supreme Court. Currently a judge on U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit, Judge Jackson is one of the nation’s brightest legal minds.  If confirmed, she will be the first Black woman to serve on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden will announce his intent to nominate <a href="/kbj/">Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson</a> as Associate Justice of the U.S. Supreme Court. Currently a judge on U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit, Judge Jackson is one of the nation’s brightest legal minds.  If confirmed, she will be the first Black woman to serve on the Supreme Court.<br><br>Since Justice Stephen Breyer announced his retirement, President Biden has conducted a rigorous process to identify his replacement.  President Biden sought a candidate with exceptional credentials, unimpeachable character, and unwavering dedication to the rule of law.  He also sought a nominee—much like Justice Breyer—who is wise, pragmatic, and has a deep understanding of the Constitution as an enduring charter of liberty.  And the President sought an individual who is committed to equal justice under the law and who understands the profound impact that the Supreme Court’s decisions have on the lives of the American people.<br><br>As the longtime Chairman of the Senate Judiciary Committee, the President took seriously the Constitution’s requirement that he make this appointment “by and with the Advice and Consent of the Senate,” seeking the advice of Senators in both parties.  He studied the histories and case records of candidates, consulted legal experts, and met with candidates.<br><br>A former clerk for Justice Breyer, Judge Jackson has broad experience across the legal profession – as a federal appellate judge, a federal district court judge, a member of the U.S. Sentencing Commission, an attorney in private practice, and as a federal public defender. Judge Jackson has been confirmed by the Senate with votes from Republicans as well as Democrats three times.  </p>



<p>Judge Jackson is an exceptionally qualified nominee as well as an historic nominee, and the Senate should move forward with a fair and timely hearing and confirmation.<br><br><strong>Judge Ketanji Brown Jackson</strong><br>Judge Jackson has devoted the majority of her career to serving the public—as a U.S. Sentencing Commission lawyer and commissioner; as a federal public defender; and as a federal judge. Judge Jackson currently serves on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit. From 2013 to 2021, she served as a United States District Judge for the District of Columbia. She has been confirmed by the Senate on a bipartisan basis three times – twice as judge and once to serve on the U.S. Sentencing Commission.<br><br>Judge Jackson was born in Washington, D.C. and grew up in Miami, Florida.&nbsp; Her parents attended segregated primary schools in the South, then attended Historically Black Colleges and Universities.&nbsp; Both started their careers as public school teachers and became leaders and administrators in the Miami-Dade County Public Schools.&nbsp; When Judge Jackson told her high school guidance counselor she wanted to attended Harvard, the guidance counselor warned that Judge Jackson should not to set her sights “so high.” That didn’t stop Judge Jackson. She graduated <em>magna cum laude </em>from Harvard College, then attended Harvard Law School, where she graduated <em>cum laude</em> and was an editor of the <em>Harvard Law Review</em>.</p>



<p>After law school, Judge Jackson served in Justice Breyer’s chambers as a law clerk.&nbsp; Judge Jackson served as a federal public defender from 2005 to 2007, representing defendants on appeal who did not have the means to pay for a lawyer.&nbsp; If confirmed, she would be the <em>first</em> former federal public defender to serve on the Supreme Court.</p>



<p>Prior to serving as a judge, Judge Jackson followed in the footsteps of her mentor Justice Breyer by working on the U.S. Sentencing Commission—an important body, bipartisan by design, that President Biden fought to create as a member of the U.S. Senate.&nbsp; Her work there focused on reducing unwarranted sentencing disparities and ensuring that federal sentences were just and proportionate.</p>



<p>Judge Jackson lives with her husband, Patrick, who serves as Chief of the Division of General Surgery at Georgetown University Hospital, and two daughters, in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How to Watch President&#160;Biden&#8217;s First State of the Union&#160;Address</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2022/02/25/how-to-watch-president-bidens-first-state-of-the-union-address/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 13:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tuesday, March 1, 2022, 9 PM EST Where can I watch the State of the Union livestream? To watch the State of the Union speech live, visit WH.gov/sotu. Tune into the official social media streams of the White House for President Biden&#8217;s State of the Union address. YouTube:&#160;President Biden’s First State of the UnionTwitter: @WhiteHouse&#160;or @POTUSFacebook:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center is-style-large-text">Tuesday, March 1, 2022, 9 PM EST</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<h2>Where can I watch the State of the Union livestream?</h2>



<p>To watch the State of the Union speech live, visit <a href="/sotu">WH.gov/sotu</a>. Tune into the official social media streams of the White House for President Biden&#8217;s State of the Union address.</p>



<p>YouTube:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mVIXLQrC9rE" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">President Biden’s First State of the Union</a><br>Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/whitehouse">@WhiteHouse</a>&nbsp;or <a href="https://twitter.com/potus">@POTUS</a><br>Facebook: <a href="https://www.facebook.com/WhiteHouse/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">White House on Facebook</a></p>



<p>The White House feed will include ASL interpretation for accessibility.</p>



<h2>When does the State of the Union start?</h2>



<p>The President will address a Joint Session of Congress at the United States Capitol on Tuesday, March 1, 2022 at 9 PM EST.</p>



<h2>Is this President Biden&#8217;s first State of the Union?</h2>



<p>It will be President Biden&#8217;s first State of the Union speech, and his <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/04/29/remarks-by-president-biden-in-address-to-a-joint-session-of-congress/">second address to a joint session of Congress</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki and Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics and Deputy NEC Director Daleep Singh, February 24,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/24/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-international-economics-and-deputy-nec-director-daleep-singh-february-24-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 04:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 5:35 P.M. EST MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, back by popular demand.&#160; If he decides he&#8217;s not going to be an economic expert anymore, he might have a future in our business or in our &#8212; in the press office. So back &#8212; Daleep is back.&#160; He&#8217;s going to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>5:35 P.M. EST</p>



<p><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, back by popular demand.&nbsp; If he decides he&#8217;s not going to be an economic expert anymore, he might have a future in our business or in our &#8212; in the press office.</p>



<p>So back &#8212; Daleep is back.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to give some brief comments at the top, take a few questions.&nbsp; Then we’ll do some briefing after then.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll just say at the top: For anyone who needs to leave for TV, feel free to go.&nbsp; It’s all fine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will turn it over to Daleep now.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Good to see all of you again, but this a briefing I never wanted to give.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to start by saying: The prayers of the entire world are with the people of Ukraine today as they suffer an unjustified, unprovoked, and premeditated attack by the Russian military forces.</p>



<p>President Biden has said from the start of this crisis: If Putin chooses to invade, the cost to Russia will be immediate and profound &#8212; to its financial system, to its economy, to its technology base, and to its strategic position in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the world has now witnessed, Putin has made his choice. He rejected diplomacy and chose war.&nbsp; And today, the President has announced our response.</p>



<p>Because of Putin’s choices, his flagrant violation of international law, and his utter disregard for the principles that underpin peace and security across the world, we will now ensure his decision is remembered as a strategic failure.</p>



<p>Today, we imposed an unprecedented package of financial sanctions and export restrictions in lockstep with our Allies and partners that will isolate Russia from the global financial system, shut down its access to cutting-edge technology, and undercut Putin’s strategic ambitions to diversify and modernize his economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me walk you through a few specifics, then I&#8217;ll be happy to take questions.</p>



<p>On financial sanctions: I stood at this podium on Tuesday and said we would impose the most severe sanctions ever levied on Russia if Putin proceeded with the invasion.&nbsp; Today, we&#8217;re following through.&nbsp; We will impose sanctions on Russia&#8217;s two largest financial institutions &#8212; Sberbank and VTB &#8212; which together hold more than half of the Russian banking system’s assets &#8212; over $750 billion in total.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For VTB, we will freeze all of its assets touching the U.S. financial system and prohibit U.S. persons from doing any business with the bank.&nbsp; For Sberbank, we will sever its access to the U.S. financial system.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll also freeze the assets of and prohibit any business dealings with three additional Russian banks with combined assets of over $70 billion.</p>



<p>We’ll also restrict U.S. investors from providing debt or equity financing for 13 of the most critical Russian state-owned enterprises, which combined have estimated assets nearing $1.5 trillion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, we&#8217;ll also impose sanctions on the executives at these state-owned institutions, as well as additional Russian elites who are complicit in Putin&#8217;s kleptocracy and their family members.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Those who’ve shared in the Kremlin&#8217;s corrupt gains and stored their wealth in yachts and luxury condos and fancy cars will now share in the pain of these measures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of the financial impact, as I said, these are the most impactful and significant sanctions the U.S. has ever taken.&nbsp; But financial sanctions are just one part of our response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also unveiling today an expansive and unprecedented set of export restrictions developed in historically close coordination with the European Union, Australia, Japan, Canada, New Zealand, the United Kingdom, and Taiwan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These new measures include sweeping restrictions on Russian military end users to impair Putin&#8217;s military capabilities and will also deny exports across Russia to sensitive, cutting-edge technology, primarily targeting Russia&#8217;s defense, aerospace, and maritime sectors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In total, the United States and our partners will effectively be cutting off more than half of all high-tech imports going into Russia.&nbsp; This includes curbing Russia&#8217;s access to advance semiconductors and other foundational technologies that Russia needs to diversify and modernize its economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Working in tandem, these financial sanctions and the export controls will undercut Putin’s aspirations to project power on the world stage.&nbsp; And those impacts intensified dramatically just today.</p>



<p>The Russian stock market plunged over 30 percent at one point before being halted by local regulators.&nbsp; Russia&#8217;s currency, the Ruble, weakened to its weakest value on record against the Dollar before the Central Bank intervened.&nbsp; And the price the market is charging the Russian government to borrow is now above 15 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These impacts over time will translate into higher inflation, higher interest rates, lower purchasing power, lower investment, lower productive capacity, lower growth, and lower living standards in Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To be clear: This is not the outcome we wanted.&nbsp; It&#8217;s both a tragedy for the people of Ukraine and a very raw deal for the Russian people.&nbsp; But Putin’s war of choice has required that we do what we said and to ensure this will be a strategic failure.</p>



<p>Finally, let me just say a few words about the impact of Russia’s choices on the U.S.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve intentionally scoped our sanctions to deliver severe impact on the Russian economy while minimizing the cost to the U.S., as well as our Allies and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To be clear: Our sanctions are not designed to cause any disruption to the current flow of energy from Russia to the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve carved out energy payments on a time-bound basis to allow for an orderly transition of these flows away from sanctioned institutions, and we&#8217;ve provided other licenses to provide for an orderly winddown of business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me just stop there and take your questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Real quick, I guess that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just had a real quick question.&nbsp; You said it would take some time before it affects the economy and inflation.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the timetable?&nbsp; How long do you think it will take until you have demonstrable results?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, look, these are &#8212; these are costs that build over time.&nbsp; And as I mentioned, I think, last Friday, any leader, whether you&#8217;re an autocrat or a small-“d” democrat, has to pay attention to the living standards of your country.&nbsp; And already, we&#8217;re seeing the effects of these measures in the signaling that we provided over the last three months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before these sanctions were implemented, inflation in Russia was 8.7 percent, the government&#8217;s borrowing costs had spiked above 10 percent, the Ruble had lost almost 15 percent of its value.&nbsp; And today, those costs escalated dramatically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, it&#8217;s going to be up to President Putin to decide, ultimately, how much cost he&#8217;s willing to bear.&nbsp; What we control is to make sure this will be a strategic failure &#8212; not just because of the sanctions but also because of the export controls; because of Europe&#8217;s accelerated diversification away from Russia, in terms of its energy supply; due to our fortification of NATO&#8217;s eastern flank; and due to the renewed energy and unity and determination by the West to stand up for our values and advance our principles.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But to confirm: You&#8217;re in it for the long haul, right?&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; I mean, your &#8212; until you see the results that you want?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; We understand that these costs will accumulate over time.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Memoli.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve just laid out all of the actions that the U.S. and our Allies have taken at this point.&nbsp; As you understand, the questions, though, at this point, are about the actions you have not yet chosen to take at this point, specifically the SWIFT system and sanctioning President Putin specifically himself.&nbsp;<br><br>What are the triggers at this point?&nbsp; Are there actions that President Putin might still take that you&#8217;re expecting that would trigger those sanctions?&nbsp; Or what are the potential complications, especially about sanctioning Putin personally?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; So, I m- &#8212; I understand there are a lot of questions about SWIFT and about sanctioning President Putin and lots of other measures that could be mentioned.&nbsp; But let me &#8212; let me say this: I think today was a demonstration that we mean what we say.&nbsp; We delivered on what we said we would do, in terms of imposing costs.&nbsp; So when we say all options are on the table and that we&#8217;re prepared to continue to ratchet costs higher, it would be a mistake to doubt that resolve.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me &#8212; let me also step back and say that when we consider which sanctions to apply, we&#8217;re not cowboys and cowgirls pressing a button to impose costs; we follow a set of principles.&nbsp; We want the sanctions to be impactful enough to demonstrate our resolve and to show that we have the capacity to deliver overwhelming costs to Russia.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, we want them to be responsible, to avoid even the perception of targeting the average Russian civilian and, of course, unwanted spillovers back to the U.S. or the global economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number three, we want to stay coordinated.&nbsp; And so, we calibrate our sanctions to maximize the chance that we move in lockstep with our Allies and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number four, they should be flexible so that we can escalate or de-escalate depending on facts on the ground.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And lastly, as I mentioned before, they have to be sustainable.&nbsp; These sanctions work over the long term.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what will guide our design.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; MJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In light of the sanctions that were announced against individuals and entities in Belarus, can you tell us whether there are sanctions against any other countries that are being seriously considered at the moment?&nbsp; And what is the line that a nation would need to cross in this conflict for them to recei-&nbsp; &#8212; be on the receiving end of sanctions from the U.S.?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp;Well, the Belarus measures were about delivering costs to a country that aided and abetted what we saw yesterday and overnight.&nbsp; But I have nothing else for you in terms of other countries being targeted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; JJ.</p>



<p>Oh, did you have a question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, definitely.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I didn’t (inaudible) &#8212; I was confusing the arms here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Daleep.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll come back to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about the &#8212; some of the carve-outs.&nbsp; There are general licenses for more than a dozen areas &#8212; agriculture, energy &#8212; and you just said that the importance is to limit the impact on Americans.&nbsp; But I was hoping that you could say &#8212; is there a percentage that you could share of the number of exemptions that make up the overall transactions?&nbsp; So, the general licenses, how many &#8212; how many tran- &#8212; what percentage of the transactions are under those licenses?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; I would refer you to Treasury and OFAC for the &#8212; for the details on what exactly is being exempted and the percentage of business that would be included.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I mean, could you say &#8212; is it a third?&nbsp; Is it a half?&nbsp; I mean, is it a small percentage?&nbsp; Is it a high percentage?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; I would go back to the principles of our design.&nbsp; The measures themselves and the exemptions are balanced so that we can deliver overwhelming costs while not having unintended consequences.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s the &#8212; that&#8217;s the principle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as to the specifics, I&#8217;d refer you to Treasury.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But wouldn&#8217;t the &#8212; wouldn&#8217;t the oil be a large percentage, I mean, considering how important it is to &#8212; to Russia&#8217;s bottom line?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, look, where we have an asymmetric advantage is in foreign capital and cutting-edge technology.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s where we&#8217;re &#8212; that&#8217;s where we&#8217;re delivering the most concentrated impact.</p>



<p>When it comes to energy: This is the one area &#8212; this is the one area where Russia has systemic importance in the global economy.&nbsp; We know it&#8217;s the second-largest natural gas producer in the world.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also the second-largest crude oil producer in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s not to say that we have a dependence on Russia; Russia depends on those revenues just as much as the world needs its energy.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not going to &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to do anything which causes an unintended disruption to the flow of energy, as the global economic recovery is still underway.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Two quick questions, Daleep.&nbsp; One, if Putin takes Kyiv, does that trigger additional sanctions &#8212; specifically that scenario?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; I’m not going to speculate on particular hypotheticals.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And you mentioned the timeline &#8212; you’ve been asked about the timeline.&nbsp; The President said, in one of the answers to his questions today, said, “Let’s have a conversation in [a] month” to see if these sanctions are working.&nbsp; But my question is: What happens in the meantime?&nbsp; Russia is taking over parts of Ukraine &#8212; major parts of Ukraine as we speak.&nbsp; So the world just sits back and watches that happen until these sanctions take effect?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, we can&#8217;t dictate Putin&#8217;s actions.&nbsp; What we can do is what&#8217;s within our control and to make sure this is going to be a strategic failure for Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, over the course of the next month, what you can expect is that we&#8217;ll see an intensifying negative feedback loop in Russian markets &#8212; and I&#8217;ve described the elements of that.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see record capital outflight &#8212; capital &#8212; record capital outflows.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see a weaker currency.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see higher inflation.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see lower purchasing power.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll see lower investment.</p>



<p>And that negative feedback loop &#8212; the velocity of it &#8212; is going to be determined by Putin&#8217;s own actions.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s what you should expect on the financial sanctions front.</p>



<p>On export controls, what you can see is that, over time, this is going to atrophy Russia&#8217;s capacity to diversify outside of just oil and gas, and to modernize the strategic sectors that Putin himself has said he wants to develop: aerospace, defense, IT, lasers, sensors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These sectors all depend on foundational technologies designed and produced by the West.&nbsp; You will begin to see a chilling effect take hold in Russia as those inputs are denied.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Weijia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; For weeks now, administration officials have repeatedly said &#8212; yourself included &#8212; that these sanctions are meant to deter and prevent Putin from moving forward, from acting.&nbsp; Can you help us understand why the President said today that no one expected the sanctions to prevent anything from happening?</p>



<p>And then secondly, a quick one on Putin sanctions: Without talking about when you might trigger them, can you help us understand what harm they would do to him personally if you were to sanction Putin?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, on your first question, we don&#8217;t usually engage in hypotheticals up here at this podium, but let&#8217;s play this out.&nbsp; Had we &#8212; had we unleashed our entire package of financial sanctions preemptively, I think a couple things might have happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number one, President Putin might have said, &#8220;Look, these people are not serious about diplomacy.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not engaging in a good-faith effort to promote peace.&nbsp; Instead, they&#8217;re escalating.&#8221;&nbsp; And that could provide a justification for him to escalate and invade.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secondly, he could look at it as a sunk cost.&nbsp; In other words, President Putin could think, &#8220;I&#8217;ve already paid the price.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t I actually take what I paid for, which is Ukraine&#8217;s freedom?&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s what we wanted to avoid.</p>



<p>Look, ultimately &#8212; ultimately, the goal of our sanctions is to make this a strategic failure for Russia.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s define a little bit of what that means.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Strategic success in the 21st century is not about a physical land grab of territory.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what Putin has done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this century, power &#8212; strategic power is increasingly measured and exercised by economic strength, by technological sophistication, and your story &#8212; who you are, what your values are, can you attract ideas and talent and goodwill.&nbsp; On each of those measures, this would be a failure for Russia.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; but &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Singh, I keep asking &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you these same questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I didn’t &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Simon, she&#8217;s not done yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Excuse me.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let Weijia finish.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; On President Putin.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But did you &#8212; but is it fair to say no one expected the sanctions to prevent anything?&nbsp; You certainly expected that, right?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, we &#8212; we signaled as clearly as we could what was coming if Russia proceeded with an invasion.&nbsp; You know, as I mentioned before, economic costs of this severity generally matter to any leader because of the effect it has on &#8212; on his people&#8217;s living standards.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this case, Putin made the wrong choice.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; JJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Singh, (inaudible).&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; JJ.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I keep asking you the same question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get &#8212; JJ is asking a question, Simon.</p>



<p>Go ahead, JJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more on SWIFT, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do we assure that these sanctions don’t really affect ordinary &#8212; ordinary people in Russia?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The UK has been pressuring Allies to still reject Russia from the SWIFT system.&nbsp; Can you say if the U.S. is still intensely working to pressure Allies to do the same?&nbsp; How intensely are you guys pursuing that?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t comment on what the UK&#8217;s position is.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to speak to that.&nbsp; But what I&#8217;ll say is the sanctions measures we imposed today, I think, without question, were the most consequential ever levied on Russia and arguably the most consequential ever levied in history, if you look at the aggregate financial impact on Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s why we took the measures that we did.&nbsp; And we did so because we could move in lockstep with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; And because we think the spillover effects will be manageable.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What I&#8217;m still &#8212; I&#8217;m trying to figure out &#8212; if this is still a realistic live round, is the U.S. really still making an intense effort for this?&nbsp; Or is it essentially &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; &#8220;This&#8221; being SWIFT?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SWIFT, right.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, look, again, I&#8217;m just going to repeat: All options are on the table, and we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re prepared to ratchet costs higher at a time and place of our choosing.&nbsp; And, you know, President Putin should take that seriously after what he saw today.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Michael.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. Singh, how do you ensure that these sanctions don’t really affect ordinary people in Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Simon &#8212; Simon &#8212; Michael &#8212; let Michael ask his question.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Michael.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I keep asking the same question, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just two questions.&nbsp; First, if you were to sanction Vladimir Putin, do you know where his money is?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Not going to comment on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, secondly, if &#8212; what is the message to Russia at this point on what it would take to roll back &#8212; relieve some of the sanctions that you&#8217;ve put in place today?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, the road to diplomacy is always open.&nbsp; Diplomacy is never dead.&nbsp; But in the current circumstance, in the immediate aftermath of an invasion, that &#8212; that option is not available.&nbsp; Right now, we&#8217;re imposing severe consequences on Russia for its decisions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If there were to be a shift in Russia&#8217;s strategic choices that upheld core principles of respecting your neighbors&#8217; borders, respecting your neighbors&#8217; sovereignty, allowing countries to have the freedom to set their own course and their own destiny, that would be a different situation, but that&#8217;s not where we are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tyler.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You suggested that there are things that still remain on the table, but as you walked through the hypothetical scenarios of trying to keep diplomacy open, you said that they have now crossed the line.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if you&#8217;re saying there is still more on the table, do expect things to get worse in the coming days, that Russia will continue to move forward?&nbsp; Is that the intelligence?&nbsp; I know you guys have been quite transparent about the intelligence you have.&nbsp; Are you keeping things back because you think the situation is going to get worse?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Well, I think we&#8217;ve &#8212; we&#8217;ve been transparent in &#8212; to a remarkable degree.&nbsp; And one aspect of that transparency is by saying we can&#8217;t get into President Putin&#8217;s head.&nbsp; And so, your question requires me to speculate on &#8212; on how he&#8217;s thinking about next steps.&nbsp; And I simply can&#8217;t do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just in terms of U.S. intelligence and the way that you are planning out the different sanctions you have and keeping things on the table, is that a sense that it will get worse, because you want to hold things back?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Look, our job is to be prepared and manage risks &#8212; all manner of risks.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve been doing over the past three months as this crisis intensified.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue doing that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Last one, from Steve.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up &#8212; follow up from Franco, the &#8212; targeting the Russian energy industry is totally off the table.&nbsp; Is that what you&#8217;re saying, Daleep?</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is that our measures were not designed to disrupt in any way the current flow of energy from Russia to the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, we have also said we are going to cut off Russia&#8217;s access to cutting-edge technology.&nbsp; That technology can be used across many sectors.&nbsp; And so, as it relates to Russia&#8217;s long-term productive capacity, we are seeking to degrade that capacity, but nothing &#8212; nothing in the short term, as it relates to energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Daleep.</p>



<p>MR. SINGH:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you for joining us.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>Okay, I know it&#8217;s late, but we will get to as many people as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just wanted to note a couple of things at the top for all of you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One, USAID put out an announcement that they&#8217;ve deployed a DART, or Disaster Assistance Response Team, to respond to humanitarian needs in Ukraine.&nbsp; This DART team, which is currently based in Poland, is working closely with European Allies and partners who will be on the frontlines of their response.&nbsp; The team will lead the U.S. government&#8217;s humanitarian response to help address critical needs caused by Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The DART comprises 17 disaster experts from USAID who are assessing the situation, identifying priority needs to scale up assistance inside Ukraine, and working with partners to provide rapidly needed assistance to communities affected by the conflict.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I know a number of you have also asked me and we&#8217;ve tried to provide as much detail as possible about how the President has spent his time over the last period since last evening.&nbsp; I think we put out a few details, but just to reiterate for all of you:</p>



<p>He closely monitored the events on the ground from both the Oval Office and then back in the Residence over the course of last evening.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We put out a few details last night, including the fact that he spoke repeatedly with his National Security Advisor, Jake Sullivan.  He also spoke with his U.S. U.N. Ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, before she gave that powerful speech at the U.N. last night.  He received a briefing from Secretary Austin, Chairman Milley, Secretary Blinken, and his National Security Advisor around 11:00 p.m., approximately, last evening, as well.  And as you know, he also spoke with President Zelenskyy.  He continued to monitor closely into the wee hours last night. </p>



<p>This morning, as you all know, he engaged &#8212; or he met for just about an hour with his national security team, which included both a full table in the room and full members from the Cabinet, from the national security team on the screen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During that meeting, as is standard, he received an update from, of course, Defense, intel, his diplomatic team about the status on the ground.&nbsp; And he has, of course, remained closely engaged with them through the course of the day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, he also had a G7 meeting that lasted a couple of hours this morning.&nbsp; And he also spent an hour this afternoon on the phone with the leaders &#8212; leaders in Congress &#8212; Democratic and Republican leaders in Congress, briefing them on the situation on a secure call, briefing them on the situation on the ground, answering questions they had as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that has been his day to date.&nbsp; And he is continuing, of course, to focus on other priorities as President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But why don&#8217;t we go to you, Zeke?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just picking up on that, has the President made any additional foreign leader calls today?&nbsp; Has he spoken to President Zelenskyy since their call late last evening?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There has not been another call to President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; I expect, as you have seen over the past several days, he will continue to have calls with leaders.&nbsp; We will keep you abreast as those happen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with the U.S. government saying that it believes that the Russian objective right now is to, quote, &#8220;decapitate&#8221; the Ukrainian government, does &#8212; does the U.S. believe that President Zelenskyy, at this moment, is safe?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to get into security &#8212; security questions, but we are in touch with President Zelenskyy, and we are working to provide him a range of support.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And President Zelenskyy, in addition to calling for the West to impo- &#8212; to cut Russia off from SWIFT, also proposed or called for &#8212; demanded, I think, is the word he used in a tweet that the U.S. and its Allies impose a no-fly zone over Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know the President has said that he won&#8217;t put U.S. boots on the ground in Ukraine to fight Russia.&nbsp; Is &#8212; is Ukrainian airspa- &#8212; is Ukrainian airspace in play?&nbsp; Is that something that has &#8212; the subject of any discussions?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve certainly seen &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen &#8212; we&#8217;ve certainly seen his &#8212; his tweet &#8212; or his request via tweet.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have an update on that request.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is that &#8212; that’s not off the table?&nbsp; A no-fly zone is not off the table?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I don&#8217;t have any update on it at this point in time or status of the discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Just a follow-up on troops, fast, and a few cyber questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you expect NATO to call up a major response force? And how many U.S. troops could be called to help in that effort?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s really up to NATO.&nbsp; As you know, we have a number of troops &#8212; thousands of troops that are on call.&nbsp; But that is a decision to be made by the NATO Alliance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said if Putin pursues cyberattacks against our companies, our critical infrastructure, we are prepared to respond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So just clarifying: Does that, first, mean that there has not been any evidence of any cyberattack from Russia against any American companies at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not that we have identified or attributed at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you explain &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I mean, aside from past ones that you are (inaudible) tracking.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I guess I mean in the last &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; 24 hours.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you explain more of the White House&#8217;s thinking on, kind of, this debate in Washington about whether a cyberattack against a NATO Ally would trigger an Article 5 response &#8212; a response from the Alliance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that, again, is up to the NATO Alliance to determine, but, obviously, a cyberattack does constitute an attack, so that would certainly be a point of discussion among the NATO members.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, one more really fast.&nbsp; On the US- &#8212; USAID disaster response that you just mentioned, a 17-person team &#8212; is that enough?&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;re talking about &#8212; we&#8217;ve heard you guys talk about the potential of hundreds of thousands of refugees &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re absolutely right.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s an important point.&nbsp; But what I &#8212; what we&#8217;re trying to do here is provide any incremental update on the status of what our work is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll just note, and you may be fully aware of this &#8212; but in terms of humanitarian assistance, we have been the biggest provider of humanitarian assistance to Ukraine; we&#8217;ve provided over $52 million in humanitarian assistance to Ukraine in the past year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the past few weeks, we&#8217;ve committed additional funding and supplies to humanitarian organizations.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a specific need and therefore a focus on support services, food, clean water, hygiene, shelter, trauma, primary healthcare.&nbsp; Our prepare &#8212; and we are prepared to certainly provide a significant amount more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this is just one step &#8212; obviously, less than 24 hours after the events of last night, and we will continue to plus up from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, there are a number of protests within Russia itself.&nbsp; Are you monitoring this?&nbsp; What&#8217;s your message to them?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there certainly are.&nbsp; And I know, with everything going on, this may not have caught everybody&#8217;s attention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me just note that, you know, today we&#8217;re seeing Russian people in the streets, open letters from leading Russian journalists, cul- &#8212; and cultural figures denouncing President Putin&#8217;s war of choice, and reports of Russian mothers concerned about the reckless deployment of their sons to this fratricidal war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s important to remember back in 2014 when they didn&#8217;t even acknowledge that they were sending Russian soldiers, they didn&#8217;t even acknowledge when there were body bags coming back from Ukraine into Russia.&nbsp; And there is an outcry in the streets by Russian people, by &#8212; by more Russian people than I think many would expect.&nbsp; So, despite Putin&#8217;s crackdown at home, dissenting views remain, and I think that&#8217;s important to note.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To publicly protest against President Putin and his war is a deeply courageous act.&nbsp; Their actions show the world that, despite the Kremlin&#8217;s propaganda, there are Russian people who profoundly disagree with what he is doing in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one more.&nbsp; Speaker Pelosi is talking about sending $600 million in lethal aid to Ukraine.&nbsp; Is this something you support?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are in conversations with Congress.&nbsp; And I mentioned the President spoke with leaders just earlier this afternoon.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an exact number, but those are ongoing conversations about what needs the Ukrainians have on the ground in a variety of categories: security, humanitarian, other economic assistance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the U.S. have any analysis to indicate that there is dissent or division within Putin&#8217;s government?&nbsp; Or is it your understanding that Putin&#8217;s government is united in this war?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s an interesting question, MJ.&nbsp; And without getting into intelligence, which obviously we look at &#8212; I mentioned, obviously, Russians protesting in the streets.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not exactly what you asked about.&nbsp; But if you watched the meeting the Pres- &#8212; President Putin had with members of his national security team the other day, it was quite striking the back-and-forth he had with his intel chief in that meeting.&nbsp; And the analysis of that is &#8212; certainly can be done in an open-source manner, given it was quite public.&nbsp; But I will leave outside analysis to give further assessment of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as you know, we are seeing Ukrainians start to flee the country.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the U.S. prepared to accept Ukrainian refugees?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are, but we &#8212; we certainly expect that most, if not the majority, will want to go to Europe, in neighboring countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are also working with European countries on what the needs are, where there is capacity &#8212; Poland, for example, where we are seeing a &#8212; an increasing flow of refugees over the last 24 hours &#8212; or through its flow of individuals, I should say &#8212; out of Ukraine, what their needs are.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been talking and engaging with Europeans about that for some time now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So part of what you&#8217;re doing is to prepare for the United States to accept refugees?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President is certainly prepared for that.&nbsp; But I would just note that because there are a number of European countries neighboring Ukraine who have expressed an openness to it, we would anticipate many of them would want &#8212; would want to go to European countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; quick question.&nbsp; The President, of course, has repeatedly said that American troops will not enter Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there any scenario that has been discussed where that decision might be reconsidered?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President has no intention of sending U.S. troops to fight in Ukraine.&nbsp; That has not changed.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This was asked to the President earlier, but I don’t think we got a full answer.&nbsp; Yesterday, Vladimir Putin said that &#8212; he warned if others got involved, they&#8217;ll suffer&nbsp; &#8220;consequences that you have never encountered in your history.&#8221;&nbsp; Does the U.S. understand that as a threat of using nuclear weapons?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we can&#8217;t, obviously, get into the mind of President Putin as much as he said that, nor do we know all the specific details about his strategic posture, but we don&#8217;t see any increased threat in that regard at this point in time.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on some of the cyber questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know that you and others have talked about how the government is on alert for the potential of a cyberattack.&nbsp; But can you share &#8212; like are there any specific steps that are being taken that you can share that the U.S. is doing to protect the infrastructure, power grid, U.S. banks?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say: One, we&#8217;ve been &#8212; there&#8217;s been efforts that have been ongoing for some time since the beginning of the administration to harden the private sector and work with the private sector in partnership to harden their cybersecurity protections.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve actually seen a great deal of progress made in the financial sector.&nbsp; It&#8217;s one of the stronger sectors in terms of protections, from a cyber front, that we see out there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s been ongoing for several months.&nbsp; Obviously, when there are moments like this where we continue to watch and look for what the potential is, we will &#8212; we continue to re- &#8212; to engage closely with a range of industries about what they need to do about the potential threats.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that happens, obviously, privately and through a range of agencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I can see if there&#8217;s anything more specific that we can read out to all of you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And just real &#8212; just, real quick, one follow-up.&nbsp; President Biden said they are &#8212; that the U.S. is prepared if an attack comes (inaudible).&nbsp; Would &#8212; pardon me &#8212; he said “prepared to respond.”&nbsp; Would that response be a &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A cyberattack you&#8217;re talking about?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A cyberattack, yes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would that be an equivalent cyberattack against Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:  Well, I would say that the President reserves the option to respond in any manner of his choosing: overt or covert &#8212; &#8220;seen or unseen,&#8221; as we like to say in more available English.  But I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics of what that looks like.  He has a range of options.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; On oil prices and the SPR.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the administration have an oil price in mind that would trigger another release from the SPR?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think &#8212; not that we&#8217;re going to get into detail or &#8212; from here, JJ.&nbsp; I understand, certainly, the question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What you heard the President talk about today, and I can just reiterate a little bit, is that what has been ongoing &#8212; both from the President, who has been very engaged in this, having conversations with leaders in the Middle East and other parts of the world, as well as many members of his national security team &#8212; taking whatever steps we can to mitigate the impact on the global oil markets.&nbsp; And, obviously, that means increasing supply.&nbsp; Obviously, a coordinated released from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve would be part of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of what that looks like or the specifics, I&#8217;m just not in a position to get into more details at this point.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; If the worst happens and Russia either reduces the flow of natural gas or cuts off energy altogether to Europe, does the administration have a good idea for how long households in Europe could last under that kind of circumstance?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an assessment of that from here.&nbsp; I can certainly check with our economic team.</p>



<p>One thing I will say &#8212; that one of the steps we&#8217;ve been taking &#8212; obviously, natural gas shortages and supply is a &#8212; it is an enormous regional issue, one that would hugely impact Europe more than here, of course.&nbsp; One of the steps we&#8217;ve been focused on and been taking is engaging with partners who have &#8212; who may have ex- &#8212; excess LNG supply, like countries in Europe &#8212; Japan, for example, where they had &#8212; where we would &#8212; were planning to give them some, and now they&#8217;re going to divert it to Europe.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ve been working to help mitigate any impact of a further invasion and a shortage in Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Some of the activity that we&#8217;ve seen today in Ukraine &#8212; some of the clashes have been in and around Chernobyl.&nbsp; Does the United States have an assessment of the risk of a radioactive release?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, I do have one actual update on that as well.&nbsp; There&#8217;s also been &#8212; there was also a report out &#8212; so let me speak to this first, just so I don&#8217;t forget &#8212; about hos- &#8212; hostages around there as well, so let me speak to that first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are outraged by credible reports that Russian soldiers are currently holding the staff of the Chernobyl facilities hostage.&nbsp; This unlawful and dangerous hostage-taking, which could upend the routine civil service efforts required to maintain and protect the nuclear waste facilities, is obviously incredibly alarming and greatly conserming [sic] &#8212; concerning.&nbsp; We condemn it, and we request their release.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of a further assessment, I don&#8217;t have anything more on that from here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you gave a readout of how the President spent the past 24 hours or so.&nbsp; First, I wanted to ask about his call with President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; Did he indicate if he was still in Kyiv?&nbsp; Did he identify his location at this point?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are aware of where he is located.&nbsp; And we are in touch with him.</p>



<p>I would say on that call, what &#8212; what they discussed is President Zelenskyy&#8217;s request for the President to be &#8212; to condemn the actions of President Putin and the Russians and to engage with other global leaders about it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what he&#8217;s done.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen a number of statements today from former presidents &#8212; President Obama, President Bush &#8212; and also saw former President Trump on television talking about this.&nbsp; Has the President &#8212; you mentioned, during the Afghanistan drawdown, he had been in contact with his predecessors.&nbsp; Has he been in touch with any of his predecessors during this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has not been today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in terms of another domestic priority that was potentially included in his meetings today, given the situation &#8212; his time and focus and attention on Supreme Court &#8212; excuse me, on Ukraine &#8212; will this affect the timing of his Supreme Court announcement?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We &#8212; we are still on track to make an announcement before the end of the month.&nbsp; We have to do a lot of things around here at the same time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on the cyberattacks and Article 5 question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you said that it&#8217;s up to NATO to decide, but from a U.S. perspective, would any cyberattack against a NATO Ally trigger Article 5 or would there be a measure for what counts?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, this is the conversation we would have with our NATO Allies and partners.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have more ad- &#8212; anything in addition to add to it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just to follow up on the Supreme Court: I know you said you&#8217;re on track, but has he made a final decision, given they are basically two days left before the end of the month?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not a &#8212; not a final final.&nbsp; No offer has been &#8212; no job offer has been made.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Just a couple.&nbsp; Are there any concerns or indications at this point that Russia had prepared for the sanctions that you&#8217;re putting in place and developed, preemptively, ways to block that impact?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s an interesting question.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; and some of it is hard because it&#8217;s hard to get into the minds of President Putin and the oligarchs around him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the steps we tried to take is to &#8212; you know, as we were &#8212; as we were contemplating the individuals we were going to sanction, we &#8212; we sanctioned family members as well, because what we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; the tactics they&#8217;ve used in the past is they&#8217;ve moved money around and resources around to family members.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve tried to address that on the front end.</p>



<p>In terms of the banking and the financial sector, I mean, it accounts for such a large percentage of how they do business, that that is &#8212; it would be a difficult thing for them to plan and plot against.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you look to just even the anticipation of the potential sanctions, as Daleep was mentioning, you know, the Ruble is the worst-performing currency in the world right now.&nbsp; Their inflation is &#8212; has skyrocketed.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re even seeing in their markets the anticipated impact even before today, and that&#8217;s even before the actual squeeze on the financial sector in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it feels to me it would be a little hard to plan around and plot around, given the significance of what was done today and the fact that when we &#8212; sanctioning 10 &#8212; 10 of Russia&#8217;s financial institutions and these export control measures, which essentially cuts President Putin off from semiconductors and access to a range of technology he wants for the future, those are difficult things to plan ahead for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And then, I guess, secondly, does the administration have any assessment for how China is reacting to this at this point &#8212; whether they are willing to provide support to Russia and how much?&nbsp; And has there been any kind of contact there to kind of attempt to move them off of any support?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, in terms of what impact they can have, I mean, China only accounts for about 15 percent of &#8212; China and Russia &#8212; I&#8217;m not sure; you can double check me on this &#8212; about 15 percent of the global economy.&nbsp; If you look at G7 partners, in the U.S. and Europe, it&#8217;s about 50 percent.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So they cannot cover what the impact of the sanctions that have been announced in coordination with Europe would &#8212; how they would impact Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I think from our perspective, as it relates to China, while I can&#8217;t get into the heads of what their thinking is, you know, this is a really &#8212; a moment for China, for any country to think about what side of history they want to stand on here.&nbsp; And, you know, that is certainly the &#8212; the case that we would make publicly and privately.</p>



<p>I think you saw that Secretary Blinken spoke with his counterpart just a couple of days ago.&nbsp; You know, the President is certainly open to speaking with his counterpart.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have any prediction of that at this point in time or a timeline.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Over the past couple of weeks as you&#8217;ve been sending the alarm on this, you&#8217;ve put the sanctions package together, done &#8212; conducted diplomacy with the Russians and the rest of the world.&nbsp; How did the Ukrainian government use that time since they&#8217;ve been initially warned that this was a likelihood?&nbsp; Did they use that time wisely to prepare?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tell me more about what you mean, exactly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you&#8217;re seeing reports from the streets in Russia of &#8212; sorry, in Ukraine of people being surprised.&nbsp; You had, obviously, local and national leadership in Ukraine telling people to stay calm, to remain &#8212; to go to work even a day before the invasion began.&nbsp; So, were they properly prepared?&nbsp; And was there more that they could have done in the leadup?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think it&#8217;s not particularly constructive for us to give an assessment of that.&nbsp; What &#8212; what I can tell you is that our focus has been on providing up-to-date &#8212; what has turned out to be quite accurate and transparent information about what the &#8212; President Putin has &#8212; was preparing to do, which is invade Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have been very clear with American citizens who were there.&nbsp; We have been clear with our European partners for months now, including Ukrainian leadership.&nbsp; So that has been what our focus has been.&nbsp; And, you know, we will remain a strong support &#8212; supporter and partner of President Zelenskyy and Ukraine moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Following up on the sanction question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have heard for weeks that these sanctions were, at least in part, a part of a strategy that was based on deterrence &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; as well as prevention.&nbsp; Today, with the President&#8217;s comment that &#8220;no one expected the sanctions to prevent anything from happening,&#8221; moving forward, do you expect this slate of sanctions to prevent any further advancement or aggression from Russia?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that later in the &#8212; later in the back-and-forth or the press avail, he also said, when asked, &#8221; If sanctions cannot stop President Putin, what penalty can?&#8221; And he said, &#8221; I didn&#8217;t say sanctions couldn&#8217;t stop him.&#8221;&nbsp; Which leads me to believe that&#8217;s not exactly what he meant.&nbsp; He also went on to say &#8221; The threat of the sanctions and imposing the sanctions and seeing the effect of the sanctions are two different things.&#8221;</p>



<p>And the way we look at this, broadly speaking &#8212; and Daleep touched on this a little bit &#8212; is that we do see them as having a deterrent impact, right?&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean they&#8217;re 100 percent foolproof.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if you &#8212; if there&#8217;s a 95 percent chance of Russia invading without the threat of sanctions, and there&#8217;s a 60 &#8212; I&#8217;m making up these percentages just to make a point &#8212; but &#8212; and a 65 percent chance that they will with them, you&#8217;re obviously going to go with the threat of sanctions because you want to reduce the threat of an invasion.&nbsp; So, there is a deterrent.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen the deterrent impact work at times.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d also note, though, that we are very clear-eyed about the fact that President Putin not just a few days ago &#8212; I mean, he gave the speech a few days ago where he questioned the legitimacy of Ukraine as a sovereign country.  He&#8217;s also talked about how the breakup of the Soviet Union was the worst thing that&#8217;s happened &#8212; that&#8217;s a paraphrase &#8212; in recent &#8212; you know, in decades of history.  So, we are clear-eyed about his ambition. </p>



<p>But what the other part of it that we are quite focused on is the consequences.&nbsp; And the way we see it is &#8212; you know, as we&#8217;ve touched on a little bit &#8212; inflation is skyrocketing, the Ruble is the worst-performing currency in the world.&nbsp; It was his decision to go to war.&nbsp; It&#8217;s our choice to make him pay a price &#8212; same with the global community &#8212; and we believe these consequences are also going to have an impact.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that &#8212; just at the risk of repeating your question as well: I mean, the President did also say, you know, let&#8217;s check in in a month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q    And there has been some questions about time here.  It seems like this is a strategy to use these sanctions to put pressure on Russia to eventually discourage them to pull out &#8212; or to force them to pull out this &#8212; this advance.  So, what is the timetable here, you think, for when the Russian government will start actually feeling the impact of these sanctions and possibly pull out?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, in many senses, they&#8217;re already feeling the impact.&nbsp; I mean, look at where the Ruble is. Look at where inflation is.&nbsp; Look at where the markets are in Russia.</p>



<p>In terms of how Putin will feel the impact, we just sanctioned a range of oligarchs around him.&nbsp; We sanctioned 10 financial institutions.&nbsp; These are all &#8212; these are all significant, enormous steps that are going to have an impact on him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in terms of the moment by moment, I can&#8217;t give you an assessment of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp; Just off topic.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just &#8212; there&#8217;s been a lot of questions about refugees in the region.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For Ukrainians that are in the country, is the U.S., especially after yesterday, considering TPS or any sort of protections?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; As you know, that&#8217;s a decision that would be made through an interagency process led by the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have any prediction of that.&nbsp; I mean, I don&#8217;t have any kind of prediction of that at this point in time.&nbsp; Obviously, these &#8212; these events are just unfolding as we speak.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that process hasn&#8217;t started?&nbsp; That conversation hasn&#8217;t &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to give you any specifics on an internal process.&nbsp; But I would just say, again, it&#8217;s an interagency process.&nbsp; And, right now, we&#8217;re, of course, in the middle of an invasion and a &#8212; and a &#8212; you know, a war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Earlier you had you have to do a lot of things at the same time.&nbsp; One of those things, of course, is the State of the Union next week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you tell us how the President this week has been preparing for that, how much time he spent on the speech, and how he&#8217;s juggling that with this very busy schedule that you laid out earlier tonight?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, absolutely.&nbsp; So, in addition to obviously being very closely engaged and leading the effort on the U.S. response to the Russia &#8212; to Russia &#8212; the Russian military invasion of Ukraine, the President has been working with speechwriters, working with pol- &#8212; members of his policy team to finalize details of his State of the Union, doing &#8212; starting to do some readthroughs &#8212; not too many, yet.&nbsp; I expect those will increase in the days ahead.&nbsp; I expect we won&#8217;t have too much of a preview for you.&nbsp; Maybe tomorrow, but maybe &#8212; more likely this weekend.</p>



<p>He&#8217;s also been engaging with his COVID team, talking about where we are in the state of the pandemic, what&#8217;s next in the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He has been working closely with his economic team on &#8212; and receiving updates on the supply chain, the implementation of the Infrastructure Bill.</p>



<p>So, even as we have all been understandably focused on the conflict in Ukraine, the President has been very hard at work on a range of issues that are vital to the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you touched on my follow-up.&nbsp; ABC is reporting that the White House is revamping the COVID strategy now that hospitalizations are on the decline.&nbsp; Should we expect the President to roll that out in the speech next Tuesday?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any preview for you on timeline or format.&nbsp; But the President has been working and engaged with his COVID team for some time now, and we&#8217;re making strong &#8212; strong progress on moving toward a time when COVID is no longer a crisis.</p>



<p>The COVID team has been spending a lot of time and energy, including with the President, working with experts inside and outside government, local public health officials, and governors. &nbsp;And this work is broader than one piece of guidance.</p>



<p>How we look at it is we&#8217;re preparing to stay ahead of the virus, protecting our most vulnerable, keeping our country open.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; and that is going to look at everything from &#8212; the CDC is obviously reviewing mask guidance, but also how we&#8217;re going to ensure that vaccines, boosters, tests, treatments, and other &#8212; and other important components of our medicine cabinet are available to the American people.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I had a couple of questions.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, sure.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll go to you next.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I had a couple of questions.&nbsp; First a follow-up about some of the humanitarian needs you&#8217;ve been talking about.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;ve talked about how much money and supplies are going to be going, but how are you going to ensure that those supplies get to the Ukraine?&nbsp; Is there going to be some sort of airdrop?&nbsp; And would the President consider putting U.S. boots on the ground for humanitarian needs to make sure they get to the people that need it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we do have, fortunately or unfortunately, a fair amount of experience on providing humanitarian assistance in conflict zones, and we typically work &#8212; and USAID, specifically, has a great deal of experience with that &#8212; working with trusted third-party entities; obviously, the government, which remains in power.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s a range of ways that we would provide assistance.</p>



<p>In terms of other mechanisms, I don&#8217;t have anything to predict for you at this point in time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then another question for you, and this has been happening while you&#8217;ve been up at the podium, so &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m not trying to ambush you &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but I wanted to give you a chance to respond.&nbsp; Senator Ted Cruz is speaking at CPAC, and you came up.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He called you, quote, unquote, &#8220;Peppermint Patty,&#8221; and has encouraged people to boo you.&nbsp; So, I wanted to &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Don&#8217;t tell him I like Peppermint Patty.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I &#8212; so I&#8217;m not going to take it too offensively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You just did.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Senator Cruz, I like Peppermint Patty.&nbsp; I&#8217;m a little tougher than that, but there you go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Yeah, so back to the President&#8217;s comments earlier today.&nbsp; So, he did say to give it a month to see if these sanctions work.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; However, you know, under Russia&#8217;s current assault, Ukraine clearly might not have a month or even weeks.&nbsp; So, is it fair to say that he is conceding Ukraine to Putin?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing about the President&#8217;s strategy or approach or leadership in the world &#8212; building a coalition of the majority of countries, you know, in the Western world, to stand against the actions of President Putin &#8212; that suggests that he is ceding anything.</p>



<p>You saw him lay out a set of historic sanctions today that will maximize pain on Russia.&nbsp; Yes, as we&#8217;ve &#8212; as we&#8217;ve conveyed, they&#8217;re meant to have a squeeze over the course of time, but we&#8217;re already seeing an impact on the financial markets, on the currency, on inflation in Russia.&nbsp; And there is a &#8212; there are &#8212; unfortunately, the Russian people are going to feel the pain of that.</p>



<p>So, I would say the President is going to continue, as he has for weeks now, to work in close lockstep with European partners to continue to press &#8212; to press from the global community for de-escalation as a relates to the events in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; If President Zelenskyy is in danger of being killed or captured and put on some sort of a show trial, would President Biden send U.S. troops in on a rescue mission to get him out?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, we are in touch with President Zelenskyy, who is an important partner.&nbsp; We support him.&nbsp; He is the leader of Ukraine, of gov- &#8212; the President of Ukraine, but I&#8217;m not going to get into security steps.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; There&#8217;s this talk about a possible forecast for financial pain, particularly at the gas pump &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for Americans.&nbsp; The President said today, &#8220;The notion that this is going to last for a long time is highly unlikely.&#8221;&nbsp; Would he try to ensure that by lifting some of the restrictions that he&#8217;s put in place on the energy industry or rethinking some projects like the Keystone Pipeline?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, the Keystone Pipeline is not flowing, so I&#8217;m not sure how that would solve anything.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s also plenty of oil leases that are not being tapped into by oil companies, so you should talk to them about that and why.</p>



<p>But what the President is talking about is &#8212; we certainly understand &#8212; and he said this today, right? &#8212; it may have been in response to your question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t remember.&nbsp; But if there&#8217;s an invasion of another country by a big country, there&#8217;s going to be impacts on the markets.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And we certainly anticipated that, and we anticipate that as it relates to the global oil market as well.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s why the President, for weeks now, has been engaging with a range of big global suppliers &#8212; some in the Middle East, others &#8212; to see what we can do to ensure there is supply out there in the market to reduce the impact on the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the U.S. is one of the Russian oil industry&#8217;s best customers &#8212; hundreds of thousands of barrels per day.&nbsp; Would the President ever consider ordering U.S. companies to stop importing Russian oil?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any prediction of that at this point, Peter.&nbsp; We announced some significant sanctions today.&nbsp; Our objective is to ensure there is the greatest pain &#8212; economic pain on Russia and not on the Russian people, but on President Putin, and to minimize the impact on the American people, including companies here in the United States.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the President said that he thinks that Putin is go and try to expand back the Soviet Union.&nbsp; So, is this &#8212; do you all think this is act one in a multiple-country invasion?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to make a prediction of that, but we certainly think he has grander ambitions than Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And to clarify that same point: Does he believe that President Putin is going to absorb Ukraine into Russia when he says that President Putin wants to &#8220;reestablish the…Soviet Union&#8221;?&nbsp; Is that what he&#8217;s saying?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think he believes that &#8212; as we all do &#8212; that President Putin has more &#8212; has grander ambitions in Ukraine.&nbsp; Hence, the military campaign is continuing.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll do this more tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>6:23 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Administration Announces New Actions to Address the Needs of People with Disabilities and Older Adults in Response to and Recovery from&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/fact-sheet-administration-announces-new-actions-to-address-the-needs-of-people-with-disabilities-and-older-adults-in-response-to-and-recovery-from-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Administration recognizes that the COVID-19 pandemic has had tremendous impacts on disabled individuals and has resulted in new members of the disability community. Over the past year, the Administration has collaborated and consulted with the disability community andtaken several key actions to address the unique needs of individuals with disabilities. Among other actions, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Administration recognizes that the COVID-19 pandemic has had tremendous impacts on disabled individuals and has resulted in new members of the disability community.</p>



<p>Over the past year, the Administration has collaborated and consulted with the disability community andtaken several key actions to address the unique needs of individuals with disabilities. Among other actions, the U.S. government released key civil rights guidance to protect disabled individuals during the COVID-19 pandemic or any public health emergency; prioritized Long COVID services, supports, and research in the context of disability; established a call line dedicated to ensuring individuals with disabilities can equitably utilize the Administration’s at-home test distribution program; ensured disabled individuals and other high-risk individuals have access to at-home testing; and invested American Rescue Plan (ARP) resources to build COVID-19 vaccine confidence and access among people with disabilities.</p>



<p>Moving forward, the Administration will take several key steps to further our work to ensure that disabled individuals, regardless of where they live or the level of community transmission of the virus, have equitable access to COVID-19 testing, masks, and other critical mitigation strategies. The Administration remains committed to implementing these policies and developing additional policies in close collaboration with the disability community – keeping equity and accessibility at the center of our COVID-19 response and beyond. The Administration will:</p>



<ul><li><strong><strong>Equip schools with guidance and support to keep vulnerable students safe and learning in-person.</strong></strong> The Department of Education (ED) will work with school administrators and educators on strategies they can use to continue providing safe, in-person instruction for all students in their classes. ED will engage the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to ensure that its guidance is fully aligned with the latest public health guidance and that schools have clear recommendations and strategies to help protect the safety of and access to rigorous learning that all children deserve. ED will also provide resources for parents who would like additional support in understanding how to navigate their child’s in-person learning experience through local regional parent training and information centers. Parents may find their local center <a href="https://www.parentcenterhub.org/find-your-center/">here</a> and reach out for direct assistance and referrals to other organizations, as well as to gain skills to effectively participate in the education and development of their children. States and school districts should use the unprecedented resources provided through the ARP to implement these recommendations and ensure access to a high-quality education for all students, including students with disabilities. Children learn best in-person, and are better able to engage with rigorous instruction and access services and supports tailored to their needs when they are learning alongside their peers. The President has been clear since Day One that we need students back to school for full-time, in-person learning, and thanks to the unprecedented resources provided through the ARP, schools have what they need to safely remain open, keep students and staff safe, and address the impact of the pandemic on student learning and mental health. Some students may need additional protections to ensure they can remain safe in the classroom – including students who are immunocompromised, with complex medical conditions, or with other disabilities that may put them at higher risk of severe outcomes from COVID-19. For nearly two years, educators across the country have provided services and supports to children with disabilities in ways never anticipated prior to the COVID-19 pandemic, and the Administration is committed to ensuring that children with disabilities continue to receive the services and supports they need so they can reach their highest potential.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expand the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Administration for Community Living’s Disability Information and Access Line to support people with disabilities who face difficulty using or cannot use a self-test.</strong> The <a href="https://acl.gov/DIAL">Disability Information and Access Line</a> (DIAL), available at 1-888-677-1199, is launching a new initiative to support disabled individuals who need assistance using at-home tests distributed by the Administration or support in finding alternatives to at-home testing. For individuals who can use an at-home test, DIAL operators are available to assist with ordering free tests; understanding instructions for test administration and test results; or providing alternative instructions for those unable to access, read, or understand the manufacturer’s version. For those who cannot use an at-home test, DIAL operators can assist individuals with ordering tests to collect a specimen that can be mailed back for results. For individuals who cannot use either an at-home test or an alternative “swab and send” test, DIAL operators can assist callers with locating their state or local health department and/or aging and disability resources for additional assistance with other testing options that may be available in their community, including identifying potential in-home testing options or assistance with transportation or companion support to visit a community-based testing site.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Launch new COVID-19 testing guidance in American Sign Language and review all existing COVID-19 guidance to confirm accessibility for all disabled individuals.</u></strong> CDC recently released “How to Interpret Positive Self-Test Results” <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eN9abSiscac">guidance</a> in American Sign Language (ASL), a first step towards ensuring that deaf or hard of hearing individuals can access key information about how to protect themselves and their communities. CDC is also collaborating with the CDC Foundation, Georgia Tech’s Center for Inclusive Design and Innovation, and their partners across HHS to pursue key improvements for all COVID-19 guidance available on CDC’s website that cannot be accessed elsewhere: information in Braille, ASL translation, simplified text, and other alternative formats.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Execute a new effort to develop at-home COVID-19 tests that are accessible to all.</u></strong> The National Institutes of Health (NIH)’s RADx program has launched a new effort to seek both short- and long-term solutions to improve at-home test accessibility. RADx will consult and work with national organizations who represent communities in need of accessible tests, and test manufacturers to inform the modification or development of more accessible at-home tests, including device design, packaging, and modes of instruction, and challenges. Though at-home COVID-19 tests were only invented last year, the Administration’s investment in this technology has rapidly scaled up manufacturing to the millions per day. This effort strives to ensure that all individuals have an option for at-home testing that can be used and interpreted without assistance, and will set the course towards accessible testing in the weeks and months to come.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Incentivize all at-home test manufacturers to prioritize accessibility of at-home tests.</u></strong><strong> </strong>The Administration has published a formal Request for Information (RFI) to ensure the preservation and expansion of current domestic manufacturing capacities for at-home rapid tests and point-of-care tests. The RFI specifically asks manufacturers to prioritize the accessibility of at-home tests for people who are blind or visually-impaired; individuals with physical, cognitive, or other disabilities; and individuals who need non-English language or literacy support. The Administration will use the information gathered in March 2022 to inform near-term investments – towards ensuring that accessible at-home tests are available for federal purchase.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Request accessible instructions from manufacturers who have received a Food and Drug Administration (FDA) Emergency Use Authorization (EUA).</u></strong><strong> </strong>The FDA has reached out to all test developers that have received an EUA to request that they provide instructions that are accessible and compliant with the Americans with Disabilities Act, including alternative text for all images as well as html versions. FDA will use all authority available to receive these accessible instructions as quickly as possible, while working with RADx to identify other wraparound services that can be provided immediately to make existing at-home tests more accessible.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Distribute masks to disabled individuals through community-based organizations and jurisdictions.</u></strong><strong> </strong>HHS will support health centers and aging and disability networks as they collaborate on efforts to distribute N95 masks to individuals with disabilities who cannot leave their homes. As the President announced in January 2022, the Administration is making 400 million N95 masks from the Strategic National Stockpile available to all individuals in the United States for free. HHS is sending tens of millions of free, high-quality masks to community health centers and rural health clinics – organizations that play a critical role in serving communities across the country, including individuals with disabilities. &nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Call on states to directly distribute high-quality masks through community-based organizations serving individuals with disabilities</u></strong><strong>.</strong> Over the past year, the Administration has also sent millions of high-quality masks to states and territories across the country. We encourage all jurisdictions to work in partnership with community-based organizations to expand access for the hardest-hit and highest-risk individuals – including people with disabilities who may be unable to leave their homes.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Russia&#8217;s Unprovoked and Unjustified Attack on&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/24/remarks-by-president-biden-on-russias-unprovoked-and-unjustified-attack-on-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 21:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47820</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 1:43 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Sorry to keep you waiting.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; The Russian military has begun a brutal assault on the people of Ukraine without provocation, without justification, without necessity. This is a premeditated attack.&#160; Vladimir Putin has been planning this for months, as I&#8217;ve been &#8212; as we&#8217;ve been saying all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>East Room</em></p>



<p>1:43 P.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sorry to keep you waiting.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; The Russian military has begun a brutal assault on the people of Ukraine without provocation, without justification, without necessity.</p>



<p>This is a premeditated attack.&nbsp; Vladimir Putin has been planning this for months, as I&#8217;ve been &#8212; as we&#8217;ve been saying all along.&nbsp; He moved more than 175,000 troops, military equipment into positions along the Ukrainian border.</p>



<p>He moved blood supplies into position and built a field hospital, which tells you all you need to know about his intentions all along.</p>



<p>He rejected every good-faith effort the United States and our Allies and partners made to address our mutual security concerns through dialogue to avoid needless conflict and avert human suffering.</p>



<p>For weeks &#8212; for weeks, we have been warning that this would happen.&nbsp; And now it&#8217;s unfolding largely as we predicted.</p>



<p>In the past week, we’ve seen shelling increase in the Donbas, the region in eastern Ukraine controlled by Russian-backed separatists.</p>



<p>Rus- &#8212; the Russian government has perpetrated cyberattacks against Ukraine.</p>



<p>We saw a staged political theater in Moscow &#8212; outlandish and baseless claims that Ukraine was &#8212; Ukraine was about to invade and launch a war against Russia, that Ukraine was prepared to use chemical weapons, that Ukraine committed a genocide &#8212; without any evidence.</p>



<p>We saw a flagrant violation of international law in attempting to unilaterally create two new so-called republics on sovereign Ukrainian territory.</p>



<p>And at the very moment that the United Nations Security Council was meeting to stand up for Ukraine’s sovereignty to stave off invasion, Putin declared his war.</p>



<p>Within moments &#8212; moments, missile strikes began to fall on historic cities across Ukraine.</p>



<p>Then came in the air raids, followed by tanks and troops rolling in.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been transparent with the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve shared declassified evidence about Russia’s plans and cyberattacks and false pretexts so that there can be no confusion or cover-up about what Putin was doing.</p>



<p>Putin is the aggressor.&nbsp; Putin chose this war.&nbsp; And now he and his country will bear the consequences.</p>



<p>Today, I&#8217;m authorizing additional strong sanctions and new limitations on what can be exported to Russia.</p>



<p>This is going to impose severe costs on the Russian economy, both immediately and over time.</p>



<p>We have purposefully designed these sanctions to maximize the long-term impact on Russia and to minimize the impact on the United States and our Allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to be clear: The United States is not doing this alone.&nbsp; For months, we’ve been building a coalition of partners representing well more than half of the global economy.</p>



<p>Twenty-seven members of the European Union, including France, Germany, Italy &#8212; as well as the United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, Australia, New Zealand, and many others &#8212; to amplify the joint impact of our response.</p>



<p>I just spoke with the G7 leaders this morning, and we are in full and total agreement.&nbsp; We will limit Russia’s ability to do business in Dollars, Euros, Pounds, and Yen to be part of the global economy.&nbsp; We will limit their ability to do that.&nbsp; We are going to stunt the ability to finance and grow Rus- &#8212; the Russian military.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to impose major &#8212; and we&#8217;re going to impair their ability to compete in a high-tech 21st century economy.</p>



<p>We’ve already seen the impact of our actions on Russia&#8217;s currency, the Ruble, which early today hit its weakest level ever &#8212; ever in history.&nbsp; And the Russian stock market plunged today.&nbsp; The Russian government’s borrowing rate spiked by over 15 percent.</p>



<p>In today’s actions, we have now sanctioned Russian banks that together hold around $1 trillion in assets.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve cut off Russia’s largest bank &#8212; a bank that holds more than one third of Russia’s banking assets by itself &#8212; cut it off from the U.S. financial system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, we&#8217;re also blocking four more major banks.&nbsp; That means every asset they have in America will be frozen.&nbsp; This includes V.T.B., the second-largest bank in Russia, which has $250 billion in assets.</p>



<p>As promised, we’re also adding names to the list of Russian elites and their family members that are sanctioning &#8212; that we’re sanctioning as well.</p>



<p>As I said on Tuesday, these are people who personally gain from the Kremlin’s policies and they should share in the pain.&nbsp; We will keep up this drumbeat of those designations against corrupt billionaires in the days ahead.</p>



<p>On Tuesday, we stopped the Russian government from raising money from U.S. or European investors.</p>



<p>Now, we’re going to apply the same restrictions to Russia’s largest state-owned enterprises &#8212; companies with assets that exceed $1.4 trillion.</p>



<p>Some of the most powerful impacts of our actions will come over time as we squeeze Russia&#8217;s access to finance and technology for strategic sectors of its economy and degrade its industrial capacity for years to come.</p>



<p>Between our actions and those of our Allies and partners, we estimate that we’ll cut off more than half of Russia’s high-tech imports.</p>



<p>It will strike a blow to their ability to continue to modernize their military.&nbsp; It’ll degrade their aerospace industry, including their space program.&nbsp; It will hurt their ability to build ships, reducing their ability to compete economically.&nbsp; And it will be a major hit to Putin’s long-term strategic ambitions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’re preparing to do more.&nbsp; In addition to the economic penalties we’re imposing, we’re also taking steps to defend our NATO Allies, particularly in the east.</p>



<p>Tomorrow, NATO will convene a summit &#8212; we’ll be there &#8212; to bring together the leaders of 30 Allied nations and close partners to affirm our solidarity and to map out the next steps we will take to further strengthen all aspects of our NATO Alliance.</p>



<p>Although we provided over $650 million in defensive assistance to Ukraine just this year &#8212; this last year, let me say it again: Our forces are not and will not be engaged in the conflict with Russia in Ukraine.&nbsp; Our forces are not going to Europe to fight in Ukraine but to defend our NATO Allies and reassure those Allies in the east.</p>



<p>As I made crystal clear, the United States will defend every inch of NATO territory with the full force of American power.&nbsp; And the good news is: NATO is more united and more determined than ever.</p>



<p>There is no doubt &#8212; no doubt that the United States and every NATO Ally will meet our Article 5 commitments, which says that an attack on one is an attack on all.</p>



<p>Over the past few weeks, I ordered thousands of additional forces to Germany and Poland as part of our commitment to NATO.</p>



<p>On Tuesday, in response to Russia’s aggressive action, including its troop presence in Belarus and the Black Sea, I&#8217;ve authorized the deployment of ground and air forces already stationed in Europe to NATO’s eastern flank Allies: Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, and Romania.</p>



<p>Our Allies have also been stepping up, adding &#8212; the other Allies, the rest of NATO &#8212; adding their own forces and capabilities to ensure our collective defense.</p>



<p>And today, within hours of Russia’s unleashing its assault, NATO came together and authorized and activated &#8212; an activation of response plans.</p>



<p>This will enable NATO’s high-readiness forces to deploy and &#8212; when and where they&#8217;re needed to protect our NATO Allies on the eastern boundaries of Europe.</p>



<p>And now I&#8217;m authorizing additional U.S. forces and capabilities to deploy to Germany as part of NATO’s response, including some of U.S.-based forces that the Department of Defense placed on standby weeks ago.</p>



<p>I’ve also spoken with Defense Secretary Austin and Chairman of the Joint Chiefs, General Milley, about preparations for additional moves should they become necessary to protect our NATO Allies and support the greatest military Alliance in the history of the world &#8212; NATO.</p>



<p>As we respond, my administration is using the tools &#8212; every tool at our disposal to protect American families and businesses from rising prices at the gas pump.</p>



<p>You know, we&#8217;re taking active steps to bring down the costs.&nbsp; And American oil and gas companies should not &#8212; should not exploit this moment to hike their prices to raise profits.</p>



<p>You know, in our sanctions package, we specifically designed to allow energy payments to continue.</p>



<p>We are closely monitoring energy supplies for any disruption.&nbsp; We have been coordinating with major oil producing and consuming countries toward our common interest to secure global energy supplies.</p>



<p>We are actively working with countries around the world to elevate [evaluate] a collective release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserves of major energy-consuming countries.&nbsp; And the United States will release additional barrels of oil as conditions warrant.</p>



<p>I know this is hard and that Americans are already hurting.&nbsp; I will do everything in my power to limit the pain the American people are feeling at the gas pump.&nbsp; This is critical to me.</p>



<p>But this aggression cannot go unanswered.&nbsp; If it did, the consequences for America would be much worse.&nbsp; America stands up to bullies.&nbsp; We stand up for freedom.&nbsp; This is who we are.</p>



<p>Let me also repeat the warning I made last week: If Russia pursues cyberattacks against our companies, our critical infrastructure, we are prepared to respond.</p>



<p>For months, we have been working closely with our private &#8212; with the private sector to harden their cyber defenses, sharpen our ability to respond to Russian cyberattacks as well.</p>



<p>I spoke late last night to President Zelenskyy of Ukraine and I assured him that the United States, together with our Allies and partners in Europe, will support the Ukrainian people as they defend their country.&nbsp; We’ll provide humanitarian relief to ease their suffering.</p>



<p>And in the early days of this conflict, Russian propaganda outlets will keep trying to hide the truth and claim success for its military operation against a made-up threat.</p>



<p>But history has shown time and again how swift gains in territory eventually give way to grinding occupations, acts of mass civil &#8212; mass civil disobedience, and strategic dead-ends.</p>



<p>The next few weeks and months will be hard on the people of Ukraine.&nbsp; Putin has unleashed a great pain on them.&nbsp; But the Ukrainian people have known 30 years of independence, and they have repeatedly shown that they will not tolerate anyone who tries to take their country backwards.</p>



<p>This is a dangerous moment for all of Europe, for the freedom around the world.&nbsp; Putin has a &#8212; has committed an assault on the very principles that uphold global peace.</p>



<p>But now the entire world sees clearly what Putin and his Kremlin &#8212; and his Kremlin allies are really all about.&nbsp; This was never about genuine security concerns on their part.&nbsp; It was always about naked aggression, about Putin’s desire for empire by any means necessary &#8212; by bullying Russia’s neighbors through coercion and corruption, by changing borders by force, and, ultimately, by choosing a war without a cause.</p>



<p>Putin’s actions betray his sinister vision for the future of our world &#8212; one where nations take what they want by force.</p>



<p>But it is a vision that the United States and freedom-loving nations everywhere will oppose with every tool of our considerable power.</p>



<p>The United States and our Allies and partners will emerge from this stronger, more united, more determined, and more purposeful.</p>



<p>And Putin’s aggression against Ukraine will end up costing Russia dearly &#8212; economically and strategically.&nbsp; We will make sure of that.&nbsp; Putin will be a pariah on the international stage.&nbsp; Any nation that countenances Russia’s naked aggression against Ukraine will be stained by association.</p>



<p>When the history of this era is written, Putin’s choice to make a totally unjustifiable war on Ukraine will have left Russia weaker and the rest of the world stronger.</p>



<p>Liberty, democracy, human dignity &#8212; these are the forces far more powerful than fear and oppression.&nbsp; They cannot be extinguished by tyrants like Putin and his armies.&nbsp; They cannot be erased by people &#8212; from people’s hearts and hopes by any amount of violence and intimidation.&nbsp; They endure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in the contest between democracy and autocracy, between sovereignty and subjugation, make no mistake: Freedom will prevail.</p>



<p>God bless the people of a free and democratic Ukraine.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Associated Press, Zeke.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Chris Megerian.&nbsp; So, do you have any plans to speak with President Putin at this point?&nbsp; And what interactions have you had with the Russian government?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I heard the first part: Do I have any plans to speak with Putin at this point.&nbsp; And what?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What communications have you had with the Kremlin as far as military (inaudible) in Ukraine and making sure this does not spiral into a larger conflict?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s a large conflict already.&nbsp; The way we&#8217;re going to assure it&#8217;s not going to spiral to a larger conflict is by providing all the forces needed in the Eastern European nations that are members of NATO.&nbsp; NATO is more united than it&#8217;s ever been.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I have no plans to talk with Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Wall Street Journal, Tarina [Tarini].</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, you didn&#8217;t mention SWIFT in your sanctions that you announced.&nbsp; Is there a reason why the U.S. isn&#8217;t doing that?&nbsp; Is there disagreement among Allies regarding SWIFT and whether Russia should be allowed to be a part of it?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; The sanctions that we have proposed on all their banks is of equal consequence &#8212; maybe more consequence than SWIFT &#8212; number one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, it is always an option.&nbsp; But right now, that&#8217;s not the position that the rest of Europe wishes to take.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Cecilia Ve- &#8212; Vega, ABC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; Sir, sanctions clearly have not been enough to deter Vladimir Putin to this point.&nbsp; What is going to stop him?&nbsp; How and when does this end? &nbsp;And do you see him trying to go beyond Ukraine?</p>



<p>And a second question I&#8217;ll just give to you now: This statement that he gave last night will &#8212; that the We- &#8212; the threat that he gave &#8212; the West &#8220;will face consequences greater than any you have faced in history.&#8221;&nbsp; Is he threatening a nuclear strike?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I have no idea what he&#8217;s threatening.&nbsp; I know what he has done, number one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And number two, no one expected the sanctions to prevent anything from happening.&nbsp; That has to sh- &#8212; this is going to take time.&nbsp; And we have to show resolve so he knows what&#8217;s coming and so the people of Russia know what he&#8217;s brought on them.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what this is all about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is going to take time.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not going to occur &#8212; he&#8217;s going to say, &#8220;Oh my God, these sanctions are coming.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to stand down.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;s going to test the resolve of the West to see if we stay together.&nbsp; And we will.&nbsp; We will and it will impose significant costs on him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will he go beyond Ukraine, sir?&nbsp; Do you see him going beyond Ukraine?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212; Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Points to reporter.)&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Two topics, just really quick. &nbsp;First, markets are down and gas prices are up.&nbsp; I know you always stress the difference between Wall Street and Main Street, but everybody seems to be in for some economic pain.&nbsp; How economically painful is it going to get for people in this country?</p>



<p>And I do have one more question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; First of all, there&#8217;s no doubt that when a major nuclear power attacks and invades another country that the world is going to respond and markets are going to respond all over the world.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s no doubt about that, number one.</p>



<p>Number two, the notion that this is going to last for a long time is highly unlikely, as long as we continue to stay resolved in imposing the sanctions we&#8217;re going to impose on Russia, period.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What&#8217;s your next question?&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The next question is: Did you underestimate Putin?&nbsp; And would you still describe him the way that you did in the summer, as a &#8220;worthy adversary&#8221;?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; At the time, he was &#8212; I made it clear he was an adversary, and I said he was “worthy.”&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t underestimate him.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ve read most of everything he&#8217;s written.&nbsp; Did you read the &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t sa- &#8212; I&#8217;m not being a wise guy.&nbsp; The &#8212; you heard the speech he made &#8212; almost an hour&#8217;s worth of speeches &#8212; why he was going into Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He has much larger ambitions in Ukraine.&nbsp; He wants to, in fact, reestablish the former Soviet Union.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what this is about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think that his &#8212; his ambitions are &#8212; are completely contrary to the place where the rest of the world has arrived.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden &#8212; President Biden &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And &#8212; and with that &#8212; with his ambitions, you&#8217;re confident that these devastating sanctions are going to be as devastating as Russian missiles and bullets and tanks?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Russian bullets, missiles, and tanks in Ukraine.&nbsp; Yes, I am.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, President Biden.&nbsp; If sanctions cannot stop President Putin, what penalty can?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t say sanctions couldn&#8217;t stop him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you&#8217;ve been talking about the threat of these sanctions for several weeks now &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, but the threat of the sanctions and imposing the sanctions and seeing the effect of the sanctions are two different things.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, but &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They’re two different things.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re now going to &#8212; he&#8217;s going to begin to see the effect of the sanctions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what will that do &#8212; how will that change his mindset here, given he&#8217;s attacking Ukraine as we speak?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Because it will so weaken his country that he&#8217;ll have to make a very, very difficult choices of whether to continue to move toward being a second-rate power or, in fact, respond.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said, in recent weeks, that big nations cannot bluff when it comes to something like this.&nbsp; You recently said that the idea of personally sanctioning President Putin was on the table.&nbsp; Is that a step that you&#8217;re prepared to take?&nbsp; And if not &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s not a bluff; it’s on the table.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sanctioning President Putin?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not sanction him today, sir?&nbsp; Why not sanction him today, sir?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, if I can, you detailed some severe and swift new sanctions today and said the impact it will have over time, but given the full-scale invasion, given that you&#8217;re not pursuing disconnecting Russia from what&#8217;s called “SWIFT” &#8212; the international banking system &#8212; or other sanctions at your disposal, respectfully, sir, what more are you waiting for?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Specifically, the sanctions we&#8217;ve imposed exceed SWIFT.&nbsp; The sanctions we imposed exceed anything that&#8217;s ever been done. &nbsp;The sanctions we imposed have generated two thirds of the world joining us.&nbsp; They are profound sanctions.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s have a conversation in another month or so to see if they&#8217;re working.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me ask you about &#8212; can I ask you about Zelenskyy?&nbsp; Sir, you spoke to Volodymyr Zelenskyy yesterday, sir, if I could follow up &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the risk that we are watching the beginning of another Cold War?&nbsp; And is there now a complete rupture in U.S. and Russian relations?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; There is a complete rupture right now in U.S.-Russian relations if they continue on this path that they&#8217;re on.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And in terms of a Cold War, that depends.&nbsp; You have the vast majority of the rest of the world in total opposition to what he&#8217;s doing &#8212; from Asia to South America to Europe to acr- &#8212; around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, it&#8217;s going to be a cold day for Russia.&nbsp; The idea &#8212; you don&#8217;t see a whole lot of people coming to his defense.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And are you &#8212; are you &#8212; if I could follow-up, sir. Are you urging China to help isolate Russia?&nbsp; Are you urging China to help isolate Russia?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not prepared to comment on that at the moment.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Wait.&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; (Points to reporter.)&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, no, no.&nbsp; He&#8217;s had his hand up a long time.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; How concerned are you that Putin wants to go beyond Ukraine into other countries and the U.S. will have to get involved if he moves into NATO countries?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, if he did move into NATO countries, he will be involved &#8212; we will be involved.&nbsp; The only thing that I&#8217;m convinced of is: If we don&#8217;t stop now, he&#8217;ll be emboldened.&nbsp; If we don&#8217;t move against him now with these significant sanctions, he will be emboldened.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, you know, every &#8212; well, anyway.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can you talk anything more about your conversation &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m sorry, I can’t hear you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, India, which is a major defense partner of the United States &#8212; is India with &#8212; fully with you on the issue of Ukraine and Russia?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Does the Defense Department of the United States &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, India is one of your major defense partners.&nbsp; Is India fully in sync with United States on Russia?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be &#8212; we&#8217;re in consultation with &#8212; with India today.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t resolved that completely.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more question &#8212;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay, thank you all very much.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>    2:05 P.M. EST   </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After Swearing In Scott A. Nathan as Chief Executive Officer of the United&#160;States International Development Finance&#160;Corporation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/24/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-swearing-in-scott-a-nathan-as-chief-executive-officer-of-the-united-states-international-development-finance-corporation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 21:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47816</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President’s Ceremonial OfficeEisenhower Executive Office THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So, I know you all &#8212; well, all eyes around our country and the world are on Ukraine, and Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.  And I want to be clear that we know and believe that this is a war of choice.  It is unprovoked, it is unwarranted,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President’s Ceremonial Office<br>Eisenhower Executive Office</em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So, I know you all &#8212; well, all eyes around our country and the world are on Ukraine, and Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine. <br> <br>And I want to be clear that we know and believe that this is a war of choice.  It is unprovoked, it is unwarranted, and it is unjustified.<br> <br>As the President made clear from the beginning: If Russia were to take aggressive action against Ukraine, our response would be swift and certain.  And that is, in fact, what has occurred.<br> <br>Today, the President outlined the sanctions, which are going to have a direct impact on Russia&#8217;s economy, both in terms of sanctions and in terms of export controls.  Those &#8212; the effect will be immediate on Russia.<br> <br>And we will continue, as we have from the very beginning, to work with our Allies and our partners around the world.  We are unified in our position on this and in our reaction to this unjustified, unprovoked attack on a sovereign nation.<br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>END </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Regional Appointments for USDA, EPA, and&#160;FEMA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/president-biden-announces-key-regional-appointments-for-usda-epa-and-fema/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) at the Department of Homeland Security: Amy Knapp Pettit, UDSA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Alaska Janice&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) at the Department of Homeland Security:</p>



<ul><li>Amy Knapp Pettit, UDSA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Alaska</li><li>Janice Kolvet, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Nevada</li><li>Marcy Svenningsen, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, North Dakota</li><li>Julia Hnilicka, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Alaska</li><li>Chris Kanazawa, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Hawaii</li><li>Terry Goodin, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Indiana</li><li>Scott Soares, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, and Connecticut</li><li>Colleen Landkamer, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Minnesota</li><li>Trina George, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Mississippi</li><li>Jane Asselta, USDA State Director, Rural Development, New Jersey</li><li>Kenneth Corn, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Oklahoma</li><li>David Cash, EPA Regional Administrator, Region 1</li><li>Willie Nunn, FEMA Regional Administrator, Region 10</li></ul>



<p>These regional appointees will be critical to the President’s efforts to rebuild communities most impacted by the pandemic, the economic recovery, and climate change. They bring deep expertise in their issue areas as well as critical relationships with federal, state, tribal, and local leaders. And, consistent with the President’s commitment to building an administration that looks like America, these regional appointees represent the diversity of America and the communities they serve.<br><br><strong>UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE (USDA)</strong><br>The USDA’s Farm Service Agency implements agricultural policy, administers credit and loan programs, and manages conservation, commodity, disaster, and farm marketing programs in each U.S. State. Its mission is to equitably serve all farmers, ranchers, and agricultural partners through the delivery of effective, efficient agricultural programs for all Americans. State Executive Directors oversee this work, ensuring the needs of local constituents are met and that USDA resources are distributed equitably and fairly.<br><br>USDA’s Rural Development mission area is committed to helping improve the economy and quality of life in rural America. State Directors lead offices that offer grants, loans, and loan guarantees to help create jobs and support economic development and essential services.<br><br><strong>Amy Knapp Pettit, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Alaska</strong><br>Amy Knapp Pettit was raised on a cow-calf operation on the Southern Oregon Coast where generations of her family have raised premier beef cattle for over 100 years. Pettit graduated from Oregon State University with a Bachelor of Science in Agricultural Business Management in 2003.<br><br>She arrived in Alaska in 2005 and began her career with the State Division of Agriculture. During her tenure, she led the Marketing &amp; Development team, was a founding board member of the Alaska Food Policy Council, and sat on the North American Agricultural Marketing Officials Executive Board. Pettit became the Executive Director of the Alaska Farmland Trust in 2015 where her role includes permanently protecting valuable agricultural lands, promoting the industry across multiple platforms, and educating fellow Alaskans on the importance of their food system. When she’s not working to inspire others about Alaska’s agriculture industry, Pettit enjoys chasing her teenaged daughters from the soccer pitch to the basketball court and seeks to balance it all through teaching and practicing yoga.<br><br><strong>Janice Kolvet, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Nevada</strong><br>Janice Kolvet was born and raised in Reno, Nevada. Kolvet began her federal career 25 years ago and served in many positions with the Farm Service Agency in Nevada, California, and Washington, D.C. She managed farm program delivery at the county office level as a district director, and as an agricultural program specialist in both the Nevada and California state FSA offices. In Washington, D.C., she served as a supervisory agricultural program specialist in the Production, Emergencies and Compliance Division, Disaster Assistance Section, at FSA headquarters where she directed a staff charged with national farm policy. She also worked on a 2014 Farm Bill task force, with the responsibility for developing new policy for federal disaster assistance. Kolvet also has previous experience as a cattle rancher in Elko, Nevada. As a career federal employee with both field and national office experience with federal farm programs, and as a rancher, Kolvet knows the importance of federal farm policy for all agricultural producers.<br><br><strong>Marcy Svenningsen, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, North Dakota</strong><br>Marcy Svenningsen has spent most of her adult life advocating for family farm agriculture. She grew up on a family farm and received a degree in Accounting from Valley City State University. Svenningsen and her husband, Greg, live and work on a farm and ranch about 10 miles west of Valley City where they grow wheat, corn, soybeans, and feed for their cattle. Svenningsen spent 12 years as a District Director on the North Dakota Farmers Union state board. She also served as the Chair of the USDA ND Farm Service Agency State Committee for eight years. Most recently, Svenningsen has been serving as the chair of the Cass County Electric Cooperative board of directors and as a director on the Minnkota Power Cooperative board.<br><br>Svenningsen and Greg have two married children and five grandchildren. They are working with their son and his family in their farming operation, and Svenningsen has also worked off the farm for over 30 years as a Finance Director for Open Door Center in Valley City, a non-profit corporation that provides services to individuals with disabilities. She is the Secretary/Treasurer for Zion Free Lutheran Church and is an active participant in the church and her community.<br><br><strong>Julia Hnilicka, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Alaska</strong><br>Born and raised in rural Alaska, Julia Hnilicka has resided for the majority of her life in her home village of Nenana. The daughter of a tugboat captain and an educator, her background instills a deep, lived understanding of the complexities of the issues facing rural residents. Her professional experience includes remote logistics, economic development, academic and environmental research, Indigenous studies, politics, education, and business management. Hnilicka’s recent run for Alaska State House, in the rural Interior district, activated her passion and drive for addressing the many persistent problems facing Alaska’s most valuable asset, our people. She obtained her Master’s in Rural Development from the University of Alaska Fairbanks, Department of Alaska Native Studies and Rural Development. While seeking her degree, she traveled throughout Alaska, interfacing with a vast diversity of population and resources. Her decade-long workplace experience in managing a successful freight logistics business on the Yukon River gives her a unique awareness of the challenges that face rural Alaska. Her primary mission is to be a positive force in Alaska’s future, which drives her dedication to address the housing crisis, broadband for all, support for small businesses, and workforce development.</p>



<p><strong>Chris Kanazawa, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Hawaii</strong><br>Chris J. Kanazawa has over 25 years of experience in the real estate industry. Having served in several leadership roles, Kanazawa has extensive knowledge of planning, land use entitlement, and development of residential, commercial, industrial, resort, and golf course real estate projects. He previously held positions as President of the Land Division for Amfac/JMB Hawaii, and upon leaving the real estate industry, Kanazawa was named President and CEO of Parker Ranch, Inc. in Waimea, Hawaii, the fifth largest cattle ranch in the United States with landholdings of over 133,000 acres.<br><br>In 2010, Kanazawa was appointed by President Obama as the USDA Rural Development State Director for Hawaii. Under his leadership, the Hawaii State Office provided over $2.5 billion in loans and grants to assist residential, commercial, public infrastructure, renewable energy, utility, and agriculture projects. His region of responsibility covered over 4.3 million square miles across the Pacific and included Hawaii, Guam, The Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, The Republic of the Marshall Islands, The Federated States of Micronesia, and The Republic of Palau. Kanazawa is a resident of Honolulu and holds a Bachelor of Arts degree in Economics from the University of Hawaii at Manoa as well as a Master of Business Administration degree in Accounting and Finance from the University of Southern California Marshall School of Business.<br><br><strong>Terry Goodin, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Indiana</strong><br>A lifelong Hoosier, Dr. Terry Goodin grew up raising beef cattle on the family farm and has committed his professional life to public service. Most recently, Goodin served for 24 years as a public-school superintendent at Crothersville Community Schools. As superintendent, he developed one of the first Early College Initiatives in the state, allowing students the opportunity to graduate from high school with a college degree. He also initiated vocational classes that allowed students to earn national and international certifications, giving them the skills and confidence to start a profession immediately after high school graduation.<br><br>Elected in 2000, Goodin served for 20 years in the Indiana House of Representatives and was chosen by his colleagues as the House Minority Leader in 2017. As a member of the Indiana General Assembly, Goodin committed his time to creating better opportunities for rural Indiana through educational, agricultural, and rural development initiatives and was a staunch advocate for the expansion of broadband connectivity. He also served on the State Budget Committee, was Vice-Chairman of the House Ways and Means Committee, and was a member of the following committees: Agriculture and Rural Development, Natural Resources, Roads and Transportation, International Trade, Banking and Finance, Elections and Apportionment. Goodin is a graduate of Eastern Kentucky University, where he received his Bachelors of Arts in 1989 and Master of Arts in History and Secondary Education in 1990. In 1995 he received his Doctorate from Indiana University Bloomington. Goodin is a native of Austin, Indiana where he resides with his wife and three children and continues to raise beef cattle on the family farm.<br><br><strong>Scott Soares, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, and Connecticut</strong><br>Scott J. Soares is the owner of Boston Bay Consulting. Drawing on over 25 years of experience, he offers a broad range of government relations services, business and project development assistance, and organizational management support to those working in aquaculture, agriculture, fisheries, and food systems. Soares was appointed by President Obama to serve as USDA Rural Development State Director for Connecticut, Massachusetts, and Rhode Island where he oversaw staff and program delivery for a suite of over 50 programs that were aimed at improving economic prosperity for Southern New England&#8217;s rural communities. Through his work as Executive Director of the U.S. Cranberry Marketing Committee (CMC), Soares worked with the cranberry industry across the United States, led a redesign and implementation of new processes and data collection services for CMC, and propelled marketing initiatives in Europe, Asia, and South and Central America. Soares began his career at the Massachusetts Department of Agricultural Resources where he held a variety of leadership positions including the Commonwealth’s first Aquaculture Program Director and culminating with a gubernatorial appointment as Commissioner of the Department in 2009.<br><br>Soares received a double major in Biology and Marine Biology from The University of Massachusetts Dartmouth and completed course work in aquaculture and fisheries at University of Rhode Island. Soares is also a proud veteran of the United States Army where he served as an Airborne Field Artillery Surveyor and the Massachusetts Army National Guard.<br><br><strong>Colleen Landkamer, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Minnesota</strong><br>Colleen Landkamer was first elected to the Blue Earth County Board of Commissioners in 1988. After 21 years of service, she was appointed by President Obama to serve as USDA Rural Development State Director for Minnesota in 2009. Following her eight-year appointment and almost 10 years away from serving on the Blue Earth County Board, Landkamer was re-elected to the board in 2019. In southern Minnesota, Landkamer represents a district located within the county seat of Mankato.<br><br>Landkamer has an enormous passion and energy for county government. She has brought the concerns of counties to the national stage since her involvement in forming the National Association of Counties Rural Action Caucus (RAC) in 1998. Landkamer&#8217;s enthusiasm for RAC helped take it from an organization of 20 members to several hundred. In 2006 and 2007, Landkamer served as President of the National Association of Counties (NACo) and has also served on NACo’s executive board since 2002. Landkamer is a past president of the Association of Minnesota Counties (AMC). In 2000, Landkamer was recognized by <em>American City and County Magazine</em> as 2000 County Leader of the Year. She has attended the Army War College, has been a Humphrey Institute Policy Fellow, a Columbia University rural policy fellow, graduate of the Senior Executive Program in State and Local Government at Harvard University, and a graduate of the 2005 New York University leadership program.<br><br><strong>Trina George, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Mississippi</strong><br>Filled with a passion to serve her fellow Mississippians, Dr. Trina George’s service includes decades of experience working to develop rural communities and economic development in Mississippi. Previously, she was employed as the Special Projects/Community Outreach and Development Coordinator in the Office of Congressman Bennie G. Thompson (MS-02). This experience allowed her to directly engage and support the surrounding communities of western Mississippi, assisting constituents with rural housing, water, wastewater, and infrastructure requirements. Her hands-on experience collaborating with federal, state, and local governments to develop rural communities prepared her for her appointment as the USDA Rural Development State Director for Mississippi in 2009. As a part of the Obama Administration, this opportunity enabled George to continue her service to the people of Mississippi, facilitating programs that resulted in the distribution of over $5 billion in federal loan and grant funds to rural communities. In addition to her professional dedication to public service, George has served as a President of the Parent Teacher Association, AmeriCorps volunteer, lifetime member of the Girl Scouts of America, and an active member in the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated. <br><br>She is the proud parent of three children, all of whom are serving their country in the Armed Forces. George earned her Ph.D. from Walden University in Public Policy and Administration. She holds a master’s degree from Mississippi State University and a bachelor’s degree from Mississippi Valley State University. She also has a Specialized Certification in Creating Collaborative Solutions: Innovations in Governance from Harvard University’s Kennedy School of Executive Education and a Professional Certificate in Management and Leadership from the NeighborWorks Training Institute of America in Washington, D.C. <br><br><strong>Jane Asselta, USDA State Director, Rural Development, New Jersey</strong><br>Jane Asselta serves as Vice President of the Southern New Jersey Development Council (SNJDC), a 501(c)(6) non-profit business association comprised of key leaders and decision-makers representing businesses and organizations in the public and private sectors who care about the issues concerning the current and future development in New Jersey’s eight southern counties.<br><br>Prior to joining the SNJDC, Asselta operated a boutique fundraising consulting firm in Chicago, which relocated to South Jersey in 2005, providing candidates for public office services including developing a fundraising strategy and plan; structuring, staffing, and supervising a finance department and team; and organizing major fundraising events with high-profile special guests. Asselta is a native of Vineland, growing up a few miles from the family’s produce farm when “farm to table” was a way of life. Asselta is a graduate of Douglass College, Rutgers University, and Vineland High School.<br><br><strong>Kenneth Corn, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Oklahoma</strong><br>Kenneth Corn has spent his entire adult life serving the people of Oklahoma, including serving in the Oklahoma House of Representatives after being elected at age 22 and later in the Oklahoma State Senate. During his tenure, Corn was honored to serve as the Democratic Caucus Chair as well as the chair of the Senate Appropriations Sub-committee for Public Safety and Judiciary where he was considered a strong advocate for law enforcement and good steward of taxpayers&#8217; dollars. During his service in the Oklahoma Legislature, Corn was a driving force behind increasing teacher pay, working hard to pass the Larry Dickerson Flexible Benefit Act providing 100 percent health insurance to school personnel throughout Oklahoma. Additionally, he tackled prison overcrowding and staffing shortages, additional academies to put more troopers on the street, and increased the pay of state law enforcement officials.<br><br>In 2010, Corn returned home to Poteau where he worked in the oil and gas transportation industry and in 2015, Corn was appointed the City Manager of Anadarko, OK where he manages the day-to-day functions of the city government and the public works authority.<br><br><strong>ENVIRONMENTAL PROTECTION AGENCY (EPA)</strong><br>Regional Administrators lead the EPA’s 10 regional offices around the country, each of which is responsible for the execution of EPA programs within a set of several states and territories. EPA regional offices also ensure the views and needs of each region are incorporated into the formulation of agency and national policy.<br><br><strong>David Cash, EPA Regional Administrator, Region 1</strong><br>David W. Cash has spent his career in public service harnessing science, innovative policy, and participatory decision-making to solve challenges and seize opportunities at the intersection of environment, economy, and equity. In his most recent position, Cash was the Dean of the John W. McCormack Graduate School of Policy and Global Studies at the University of Massachusetts Boston. Cash spent a decade in Massachusetts state government, where he held a range of senior positions. As Assistant Secretary of Policy in the Executive Office of Energy and Environmental Affairs in Governor Deval Patrick&#8217;s Administration, he was an architect of nation-leading climate, clean energy, and environmental justice policies. All of these initiatives were grounded in the notion that wise environmental policy, economic policy, and policies for equity can and should go hand-in-hand. He then served as a Commissioner in the Department of Public Utilities, followed by serving as the Commissioner of the Department of Environmental Protection.<br><br>With this rare experience of being both an environment and an energy commissioner, Cash had the unique perspective of understanding the importance of breaking down silos and focusing on complex issues in much more comprehensive and integrative ways. In these roles, he collaborated in government and with communities and the private sector to craft and implement innovative science-based policies around climate, environmental justice, energy, job creation, water, land use, waste management, and grid modernization. Cash holds a Ph.D. in public policy from the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University. He and his wife Annie Weiss, a psychotherapist, live in the Boston area and have two young adult daughters.</p>



<p>Region 1 serves Connecticut, Maine, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, and Vermont.</p>



<p><strong>FEDERAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY (FEMA)</strong><br>Regional Administrators lead FEMA’s 10 Regional offices and&nbsp;coordinate directly with the FEMA Administrator to support state, local, tribal, and territorial (SLTT) communities in their geographic area of operations delivering frontline services across the spectrum of preparedness, mitigation, response, recovery, and continuity programs.&nbsp;The Regional Administrators play a critical role in delivering timely, efficient, effective, and accessible federal assistance.<br><br><strong>Willie Nunn, FEMA Regional Administrator, Region 10</strong><br>Willie G. Nunn is a Type 1 Federal Coordinating Officer (FCO1) and a member of the Field Leadership Cadre in the Department of Homeland Security, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA). As an FCO, Nunn serves as the representative of the President of the United States, Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security, and FEMA Administrator during major disaster and emergency declarations; and as an FCO1 serves as FCO1 Field Leader Supervisor for FEMA Regions II, VIII, IX, &amp; X.<br><br>Prior to joining FEMA, Colonel Nunn completed a United States Air Force career with over 26 years on active duty. His assignments included two command tours and two combat tours in in Operations ENDURING FREEDOM 2002 in Afghanistan and IRAQI FREEDOM 2003 in Iraq. As a Master Air Battle Manager, he has over 2,900 flight hours on board AWACS and JSTARS with 201 flight hours in combat. Nunn graduated from the University of Alabama-Birmingham with a Bachelor of Arts in History and from the University of Oklahoma with a Master of Public Administration. He and his wife Sylvia have three children, Sacha, Adam, and Alene.<br><br>Region 10 serves Alaska, Idaho, Oregon, and Washington.&nbsp;<br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Economic Council Director Brian Deese on One Year of Action and Progress on America’s Supply&#160;Chains</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/statement-by-national-economic-council-director-brian-deese-on-one-year-of-action-and-progress-on-americas-supply-chains/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 19:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Even as we engage and respond forcefully to the crisis unfolding in Ukraine, we are focused on the crucial work of advancing economic progress at home. Today, we received news confirming the strength and resilience of the American economy: GDP increased 7 percent in the fourth quarter of 2021 and the four-week average of weekly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Even as we engage and respond forcefully to the crisis unfolding in Ukraine, we are focused on the crucial work of advancing economic progress at home. Today, we received news confirming the strength and resilience of the American economy: GDP increased 7 percent in the fourth quarter of 2021 and the four-week average of weekly unemployment claims fell. &nbsp;A year ago, President Biden signed &nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/24/executive-order-on-americas-supply-chains/">Executive Order 14017</a> on <em>America’s Supply Chains, </em>launching <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Capstone-Report-Biden.pdf">a historic year of action and progress</a> to strengthen the resilience, security, and sustainability of America’s supply chains. These actions are contributing to a historic recovery in American manufacturing and industrial strength, helping to rebuild our supply chains here at home and make more here in America.</p>



<p>As the President has said: we have more work to do, to bring back manufacturing to the United States, to make things more affordable for consumers, and to strengthen the resilience of our supply chains. But we are making critical progress. The six industrial base reports released today are an important milestone, laying a strong foundation <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/the-biden-harris-plan-to-revitalize-american-manufacturing-and-secure-critical-supply-chains-in-2022/">upon which we can rebuild</a> America’s global leadership in technological development and manufacturing, and create new jobs and new businesses in communities across America.</p>



<p>To secure America’s supply chains and ensure the United States remains the most productive and innovative nation in the world, President Biden is urging Congress to pass a final version of comprehensive competitiveness legislation, building on USICA and the COMPETES Act.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Joined by Allies and Partners, the United&#160;States Imposes Devastating Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/fact-sheet-joined-by-allies-and-partners-the-united-states-imposes-devastating-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 19:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47800</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;Russia to Face Massive Costs from its Isolation from the Global Financial and Trade System and Cutting-Edge Technology Today, the United States, along with Allies and partners, is imposing severe and immediate economic costs on Russia in response to Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine. Today’s actions include sweeping financial sanctions and stringent export controls&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>&nbsp;Russia to Face Massive Costs from its Isolation from the Global Financial and Trade System and Cutting-Edge Technology</em></p>



<p>Today, the United States, along with Allies and partners, is imposing severe and immediate economic costs on Russia in response to Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine. Today’s actions include sweeping financial sanctions and stringent export controls that will have profound impact on Russia’s economy, financial system, and access to cutting-edge technology. The sanctions measures impose severe costs on Russia’s largest financial institutions and will further isolate Russia from the global financial system. With today’s financial sanctions, we have now targeted all ten of Russia’s largest financial institutions, including the imposition of full blocking and correspondent and payable-through account sanctions, and debt and equity restrictions, on institutions holding nearly 80% of Russian banking sector assets. The unprecedented export control measures will cut off more than half of Russia’s high-tech imports, restricting Russia’s access to vital technological inputs, atrophying its industrial base, and undercutting Russia’s strategic ambitions to exert influence on the world stage. The impact of these measures will be significantly magnified due to historical multilateral cooperation with a wide range of Allies and partners who are mirroring our actions, inhibiting Putin’s ambition to diversify Russia’s brittle, one-dimensional economy. The scale of Putin’s aggression and the threat it poses to the international order require a resolute response, and we will continue imposing severe costs if he does not change course.</p>



<p>Putin’s threatening actions and now his unprovoked aggression toward Ukraine are being met with an unprecedented level of multilateral cooperation. The United States welcomes the commitments by Australia, Canada, the European Union, Japan, and the United Kingdom that they will also take similarly forceful actions to hold Russia accountable – demonstrating the strength of our partnerships and deepening the impact on Russia more than any action we could have taken alone. This follows our joint action earlier this week to impose a first tranche of severe sanctions on Russia.</p>



<p>As a result of Putin’s war of choice, Russia will face immediate and intense pressure on its economy, and massive costs from its isolation from the global financial system, global trade, and cutting-edge technology. This includes cutting off Russia’s largest bank from the U.S. financial system – a significant blow to its ability to function and process global trade. It also includes full blocking sanctions on Russia’s second largest bank – freezing any of its assets touching the U.S. financial system. &nbsp;Russia’s ability to access global markets, attract investment, and utilize the U.S. dollar will be devastated.</p>



<p>Russia’s economy has already faced intensified pressure in recent weeks; just today its stock market sunk to its lowest level in four and a half years, and the ruble weakened beyond its weakest daily settlement price on record – before additional sanctions were even imposed. With these new stringent measures, these pressures will further accumulate and suppress Russia’s economic growth, increase its borrowing costs, raise inflation, intensify capital outflows, and erode its industrial base. The United States and our Allies and partners are unified and will continue to impose costs, forcing Putin to look to other countries that cannot replicate the financial and technology strengths of Western markets.<br>Today, the United States carried out the following actions:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Severing the connection to the U.S. financial system for Russia’s largest financial institution, Sberbank</strong>, including 25 subsidiaries, by imposing correspondent and payable-through account sanctions. This action will restrict Sberbank’s access to transactions made in the dollar. Sberbank is the largest bank in Russia, holds nearly one-third of the overall Russian banking sector’s assets, is heavily connected to the global financial system, and is systemically critical to the Russian financial system.<br> </li><li><strong>Full blocking sanctions on Russia’s second largest financial institution, VTB Bank (VTB)</strong>, including 20 subsidiaries. This action will freeze any of VTB’s assets touching the U.S financial system and prohibit U.S. persons from dealing with them. VTB holds nearly one-fifth of the overall Russian banking sector’s assets, is heavily exposed to the U.S. and western financial systems, and is systemically critical to the Russian financial system.<br> </li><li><strong>Full blocking sanctions on three other major Russian financial institutions</strong>: Bank Otkritie, Sovcombank OJSC, and Novikombank- and 34 subsidiaries. These sanctions freeze any of these institutions’ assets touching the U.S financial system and prohibit U.S. persons from dealing with them. These financial institutions play a significant a role in the Russian economy.<br> </li><li><strong>New debt and equity restrictions on thirteen of the most critical major Russian enterprises and entities. </strong>This includes restrictions on all transactions in, provision of financing for, and other dealings in new debt of greater than 14 days maturity and new equity issued by thirteen Russian state-owned enterprises and entities:  Sberbank, AlfaBank, Credit Bank of Moscow, Gazprombank, Russian Agricultural Bank, Gazprom, Gazprom Neft, Transneft, Rostelecom, RusHydro, Alrosa, Sovcomflot, and Russian Railways. These entities, including companies critical to the Russian economy with estimated assets of nearly $1.4 trillion, will not be able to raise money through the U.S. market — a key source of capital and revenue generation, which limits the Kremlin’s ability to raise money for its activity.<br> </li><li><strong>Additional full blocking sanctions on Russian elites and their family members: Sergei Ivanov (and his son, Sergei), Nikolai Patrushev (and his son <strong>Andrey</strong>), Igor Sechin (and his son Ivan), Andrey Puchkov, Yuriy Solviev (and two real estate companies he owns), Galina Ulyutina, and Alexander Vedyakhin.</strong> This action includes individuals who have enriched themselves at the expense of the Russian state, and have elevated their family members into some of the highest position of powers in the country. It also includes financial figures who sit atop Russia’s largest financial institutions and are responsible for providing the resources necessary to support Putin’s invasion of Ukraine. This action follows up on yesterday’s action targeting Russian elites and their family members and cuts them off from the U.S. financial system, freezes any assets they hold in the United States and blocks their travel to the United States.<br> </li><li><strong>Costs on Belarus for supporting a further invasion of Ukraine</strong> by sanctioning 24 Belarusian individuals and entities, including targeting Belarus’ military and financial capabilities by sanctioning two significant Belarusian state-owned banks, nine defense firms, and seven regime-connected official and elites. We call on Belarus to withdraw its support for Russian aggression in Ukraine.<br> </li><li><strong>Sweeping restrictions on Russia’s military to strike a blow to Putin’s military and strategic ambitions.  </strong>This includes measures against military end users, including the Russian Ministry of Defense<strong>.</strong> Exports of nearly all U.S. items and items produced in foreign countries using certain U.S.-origin software, technology, or equipment will be restricted to targeted military end users. These comprehensive restrictions apply to the Russian Ministry of Defense, including the Armed Forces of Russia, wherever located.<br> </li><li><strong>Russia-wide restrictions to choke off Russia’s import of technological goods critical to a diversified economy and Putin’s ability to project power. </strong>This includes Russia-wide denial of exports of sensitive technology, primarily targeting the Russian defense, aviation, and maritime sectors to cut off Russia’s access to cutting-edge technology<strong>.</strong> In addition to sweeping restrictions on the Russian-defense sector, the United States government will impose Russia-wide restrictions on sensitive U.S. technologies produced in foreign countries using U.S.-origin software, technology, or equipment. This includes Russia-wide restrictions on semiconductors, telecommunication, encryption security, lasers, sensors, navigation, avionics and maritime technologies. These severe and sustained controls will cut off Russia’s access to cutting edge technology.<br> </li><li><strong>Historical multilateral cooperation that serves as a force multiplier in restricting more than $50 billion in key inputs to Russia- impacting far more than that in Russia’s production. </strong>As a result of this multilateral coordination, we will provide an exemption for other countries that adopt equally stringent measures. Countries that adopt substantially similar export restrictions are exempted from new U.S. licensing requirements for items produced in their countries. The European Union, Australia, Japan, Canada, New Zealand and the United Kingdom, have already communicated their plans for parallel actions. This unprecedented coordination significantly expands the scope of restrictions on Russia. Further engagement with Allies and partners will continue to maximize the impact on Russia’s military capabilities.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
