<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 17:37:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Chair’s Summary of the Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate Held by President Joe&#160;Biden </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/18/chairs-summary-of-the-major-economies-forum-on-energy-and-climate-held-by-president-joe-biden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 17:37:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55889</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 17, 2022,&#160;President Biden convened&#160;his third&#160;Major Economies Forum&#160;on Energy and Climate&#160;(MEF) to build on the progress achieved at COP 26 by further strengthening climate action while also addressing urgent energy and food security concerns arising from Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.&#160; Participants shared steps they are taking to strengthen their national climate efforts, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On June 17, 2022,&nbsp;President Biden convened&nbsp;his third&nbsp;Major Economies Forum&nbsp;on Energy and Climate&nbsp;(MEF) to build on the progress achieved at COP 26 by further strengthening climate action while also addressing urgent energy and food security concerns arising from Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; Participants shared steps they are taking to strengthen their national climate efforts, and many joined the United States in initiatives to reduce methane emissions, speed the commercialization of critical technologies, put more zero-emission vehicles on the road, decarbonize ocean-based shipping, and increase fertilizer efficiency and alternatives.&nbsp; The initiatives will bolster energy security and food security, speed the clean energy transition, and accelerate efforts to tackle the climate crisis.</p>



<p>Argentina, Australia, Canada, Chile, China, Egypt, the European Commission, France, Germany, India, Indonesia, Italy, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Mexico, Nigeria, Norway, Saudi Arabia, Turkey, United Arab Emirates, United Kingdom, Vietnam, and the U.N. Secretary-General participated in the virtual meeting.</p>



<p>Special Presidential Envoy for Climate John Kerry opened the meeting by noting the valuable role the Major Economies Forum played in 2021 in contributing to the progress achieved at the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Glasgow (COP 26) and emphasizing the urgency of building on that progress at COP 27 in November in Sharm el-Sheikh.</p>



<p>President Biden emphasized that, while COP 26 brought the world much closer to a 1.5-degree Celsius limit on temperature rise, the world’s leading scientists have since underscored once more, with increased alarm, the rapidly narrowing window for decisive action to stem the climate crisis. &nbsp;In line with the United States’ “Implementation-Plus” approach, the President called on countries to dedicate themselves to implementing existing goals while undertaking additional efforts to strengthen climate ambition.&nbsp; Noting that the Glasgow Climate Pact calls on countries to revisit and strengthen their 2030 Nationally Determined Contribution (NDC) emissions targets as necessary to align with the Paris Agreement temperature goal, he urged participants to share any steps they are taking to update their targets.&nbsp; The President also outlined new initiatives in the energy, transportation, and agriculture sectors and invited participants to join the United States in undertaking them.</p>



<p>President Biden and President Abdel Fattah El-Sisi of Egypt announced that the United States and Egypt will partner on Adaptation in Africa, including at COP 27, with a focus on tangible actions to improve people’s lives and build resilience to a changing climate.</p>



<p>Leaders spoke to the imperative and urgency of further strengthening action in this critical decade, including references to the importance of countries updating NDC targets this year that are not yet in line with the Paris Agreement temperature goal and to the need for submitting or updating long-term strategies.&nbsp; Many emphasized the link between climate security and energy security, noting that Russia’s war in Ukraine only highlights the need to accelerate the clean energy transition and that renewable energy supports energy security. &nbsp;Many highlighted the importance of scaling up finance and investment and underscored the economic and social benefits of a just energy transition.&nbsp; Leaders commended Egypt for its efforts to ensure the success of COP 27.</p>



<p>With respect to 2030 NDC targets:</p>



<ul><li>Australia noted that it submitted this week an enhanced NDC to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 43% below 2005 levels by 2030.</li><li>Chile announced that it will strengthen its NDC, aiming to bring it in line with the vital goal of keeping within reach a 1.5 degree C limit on global temperature rise.</li><li>Egypt announced that it is putting the finishing touches on an updated NDC, which will include specific ambitious quantitative targets in multiple sectors.</li><li>Indonesia indicated that it is in the process of updating its NDC.</li><li>Mexico intends to submit an enhanced 2030 NDC target in line with the Paris temperature goal ahead of COP 27.</li><li>Turkey said it will submit an updated NDC by the end of this year.</li><li>The United Arab Emirates announced that it intends to submit an enhanced 2030 NDC target this year.</li><li>Vietnam will enhance its NDC.</li></ul>



<p>Participants also announced other steps to strengthen national and regional climate efforts, including closing coal-fired power plants; instituting and expanding carbon pricing; setting ambitious national zero-emissions vehicle targets; setting ambitious national methane targets and developing methane abatement plans; increasing renewables, including through specific targets, incorporating climate assessments into the development of national budgets; modernizing hydroelectric plants; making large-scale investments in solar energy; pursuing efforts in the agricultural sector to promote emission reductions and food security; pursuing sustainable forestry initiatives; investing in hydrogen and ammonia; promoting reliable supplies of clean energy minerals and materials; strengthening national adaptation efforts; and pursuing regional mitigation and resilience efforts.</p>



<p>With respect to new joint initiatives:</p>



<ul><li>The United State and the European Union, building on the Global Methane Pledge (GMP) they launched last year, announced a new <strong>Global Methane Pledge Energy Pathway</strong> , with Argentina, Canada, Egypt, Germany, Italy, Japan, Mexico, Nigeria, and Norway as inaugural members.  The Energy Pathway aims to encourage all nations to capture the maximum potential of cost-effective methane mitigation in the oil and gas sector and to eliminate routine flaring as soon as possible, and no later than 2030.  The participants cover two-fifths of global gas production and three-fifths of global gas import volumes.  Countries and supporting organizations have announced $59 million in dedicated funding and in-kind assistance in support of the Pathway. With Egypt joining the Global Methane Pledge with respect to the oil and gas sector, 120 countries have now joined the Pledge.</li><li>Canada, the European Commission, France, Germany, Indonesia, Italy, the United Kingdom, and the United Arab Emirates expressed support for the <strong>Clean Energy Technologies Demonstration Challenge</strong> to raise $90 billion of public funding by 2026 to build commercial-scale demonstration projects that the IEA reports are needed this decade to achieve net-zero emissions by 2050.  In support of this goal, the United States and the European Commission highlighted planned investments totaling more than $50 billion. Countries are to announce their specific investment levels and action plans at the Global Clean Energy Action Forum this September in Pittsburgh.</li><li>Canada, Chile, the European Commission, France, Germany, Italy, Mexico, Norway, and the United Kingdom joined the United States in <strong>a collective 2030 zero-emission vehicle (ZEV) deployment goal</strong> of ZEVs comprising 50 percent of new light-duty vehicle sales by 2030, to include battery electric, fuel cell electric, and plug-in hybrid vehicles. </li><li>Canada, Chile, the European Commission, France, Germany, Indonesia, Republic of Korea, Mexico, Norway, and the United Kingdom expressed support for the <strong>Green Shipping Challenge</strong>, which encourages governments, ports, maritime carriers, cargo owners, and others to come forward at COP 27 with concrete steps, such as producing zero-emission fuels or creating green shipping corridors, that will help put the international shipping sector on a credible pathway this decade toward full decarbonization no later than 2050.</li><li>The European Commission, Germany, and Norway expressed support for the <strong>Global Fertilizer Challenge</strong>, which aims to raise $100 million by COP 27 to strengthen food security and reduce agricultural emissions by advancing fertilizer efficiency and alternatives.  The initiative will seek to ease pressure on fertilizer and natural gas supplies, lower nitrous oxide emissions, increase fertilizer availability and agricultural productivity, and reduce food insecurity globally by helping countries with high fertilizer usage and loss adopt efficient nutrient management and alternative fertilizers and cropping systems.</li></ul>



<p>In closing remarks, Special Presidential Envoy Kerry said the announcements made, including with respect to NDC enhancement and the various new initiatives, will bring the world closer to keeping a 1.5 degree C limit on temperature rise within reach.&nbsp; He noted that each initiative addresses a different aspect of the climate challenge and an area where countries can work together.&nbsp; He stressed the need to move away from business as usual and “break the mold.”&nbsp; He urged leaders to further strengthen the spirit of cooperation on the road to COP 27 and beyond.</p>



<p>Participants included:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>His Excellency Alberto Fernández, President of the Argentine Republic</li><li>The Honorable Anthony Albanese MP, Prime Minister of Australia</li><li>The Right Honorable Justin Trudeau, P.C., M.P., Prime Minister of Canada</li><li>His Excellency Gabriel Boric, President of the Republic of Chile</li><li>His Excellency Abdel Fattah El-Sisi, President of the Arab Republic of Egypt</li><li>Her Excellency Ursula von der Leyen, President of the European Commission</li><li>His Excellency Olaf Scholz, Chancellor of the Federal Republic of Germany</li><li>His Excellency Joko Widodo, President of the Republic of Indonesia</li><li>His Excellency Kishida Fumio, Prime Minister of Japan</li><li>His Excellency Han Duck-Soo, Prime Minister of the Republic of Korea</li><li>His Excellency Andrés Manuel López Obrador, President of the United Mexican States</li><li>His Excellency Muhammadu Buhari, President of the Federal Republic of Nigeria</li><li>His Excellency Jonas Gahr Støre, Prime Minister of Norway</li><li>His Excellency Recep Tayyip Erdoğan, President of the Republic of Turkey</li><li>His Highness Sheikh Mohamed Bin Zayed Al Nahyan, President of the United Arab Emirates</li><li>The Honorable Joseph R. Biden, Jr., President of the United States of America</li><li>His Excellency António Guterres, Secretary-General of the United Nations</li><li>His Excellency Xie Zhenhua, Special Envoy of President Xi Jinping, People’s Republic of China</li><li>Her Excellency Agnès Pannier-Runacher, Minister for Energy Transition of the French Republic</li><li>His Excellency Bhupender Yadav, Minister for Environment, Forest and Climate Change of the Republic of India</li><li>His Excellency Roberto Cingolani, Minister of Ecological Transition of the Italian Republic</li><li>His Excellency Adel Al-Jubeir, Minister of State for Foreign Affairs, Member of the Council of Ministers, and Envoy for Climate, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia</li><li>The Right Honorable Alok Sharma MP, President for COP26, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</li><li>His Excellency Tran Hong Ha, Minister of Natural Resources and Environment of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<p><a id="_msocom_1"></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Aïssata Tall Sall of&#160;Senegal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/18/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-foreign-minister-aissata-tall-sall-of-senegal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 15:50:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55887</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Foreign Minister Aïssata Tall Sall of Senegal at the White House.  Mr. Sullivan affirmed the Administration’s commitment to partnering with Senegal and the African Union to tackle shared global challenges.  The National Security Advisor and Foreign Minister discussed the devastating impact of Russia’s war on Ukraine on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Foreign Minister Aïssata Tall Sall of Senegal at the White House.  Mr. Sullivan affirmed the Administration’s commitment to partnering with Senegal and the African Union to tackle shared global challenges.  The National Security Advisor and Foreign Minister discussed the devastating impact of Russia’s war on Ukraine on food security in Africa, and the need to keep global food and fertilizer markets open and functioning.  The National Security Advisor and Foreign Minister agreed to deepen cooperation, including on maritime issues, and Mr. Sullivan commended Senegal’s leadership to address insecurity in West Africa. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After Air Force Two&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-air-force-two-arrival-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 22:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55881</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dulles International AirportDulles, Virginia THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; So, about the hearings, I &#8212; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; I wanted to ask you about January 6th &#8212; THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Yeah.&#160; So, here’s what I’ll say, that &#8212; when we look at what happened that day, and then we’ve seen &#8212; I’ve seen bits and pieces of the hearings&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Dulles International Airport<br><em>Dulles, Virginia</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So, about the hearings, I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about January 6th &#8212;</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, here’s what I’ll say, that &#8212; when we look at what happened that day, and then we’ve seen &#8212; I’ve seen bits and pieces of the hearings in the last few days &#8212; there &#8212; without question, there was a clear erosion of some of the foundational aspects of our government and, therefore, our democracy.</p>



<p>You know, regardless of what party you register to vote with, regardless of who you voted for, I think we should all agree that there are certain rules and norms and standards that we, as Americans, should hold ourselves and leaders to &#8212; and they were broken, at least for that moment, in that moment in time in the history of our con- &#8212; of our country.</p>



<p>I think it should require all of us to be concerned about the fragility of our democracy, but also it should hopefully reinvigorate us to understand that the democracy of our country and our government is going to be as strong as we, the people, will be in demanding that we maintain its integrity.</p>



<p>That’s how I feel about it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was there anything about the hearings that just &#8212; that surprised you?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; I mean, I haven’t been watching them closely.&nbsp; I will say that it seems that &#8212; that most of what the hearings have covered, we have known but perhaps not at the degree or with the level of detail that the hearings have disclosed.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>Q    Can I ask you about abortion?  Do you have &#8212;<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Okay.  One more, and then I’m going to &#8212;<br></p>



<p>Q    I know you&#8217;ve been doing a lot of work with activists &#8212;<br></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Yes.<br><br>Q    What should American people expect from the administration, in terms of executive action, if Roe is overturned?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, let&#8217;s first wait and see exactly what the Court does, because that&#8217;ll give us a good idea of, frankly, what harm is going to result and &#8212; but I have been convening folks around many sectors of just who we are as a society. <br><br>Most recently, I brought together some constitutional scholars around privacy issues, because we are very concerned that the privacy right that &#8212; from which Roe v. Wade flows can also put at risk the right to contraception, the right to same-sex marriage.<br><br>We&#8217;re &#8212; we’re very concerned about what a degradation of the right to privacy will mean, beyond the right to have access to an abortion.<br><br>So we&#8217;re going to see.  I&#8217;ve been convening &#8212; I&#8217;ve convened faith leaders.  And, you know, for those of us of faith, I think that we &#8212; we agree, many of us, that there&#8217;s nothing about this issue that will require anyone to abandon their faith or change their faith.<br><br>It&#8217;s simply saying that the government should not have the ability to decide what an individual does with her own body.  Let her make that decision with her pastor or her rabbi or whoever she consults.  But it should not be the government making that decision.<br><br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Talent Pipeline Challenge Launch Event with Senior Administration Officials, Employers, Union Leaders, Training Providers, and Local&#160;Officials  </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/readout-of-talent-pipeline-challenge-launch-event-with-senior-administration-officials-employers-union-leaders-training-providers-and-local-officials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 22:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55878</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden-Harris Administration held an event to launch the Talent Pipeline Challenge, a program to help employers build education and training partnerships to connect American workers to good jobs rebuilding our infrastructure, supply chains, and manufacturing. The Vice President, First Lady, Cabinet Members, and senior administration officials are working to bring major employers, trade&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration held an event to launch the Talent Pipeline Challenge, a program to help employers build education and training partnerships to connect American workers to good jobs rebuilding our infrastructure, supply chains, and manufacturing. The Vice President, First Lady, Cabinet Members, and senior administration officials are working to bring major employers, trade associations, training providers, union leaders, and state and local governments together to create good-paying jobs for a diverse group of workers. The Talent Pipeline Challenge’s goal is to create and support programs that provide skills training and match workers with in-demand jobs that will be critical to completing infrastructure projects, including those funded by the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</p>



<p>National Economic Council Director Brian Deese, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, Senior Advisor and Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator Mayor Mitch Landrieu, Senior Advisor and American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling, and Secretary of Labor Marty Walsh hosted the Talent Pipeline Challenge event at the White House. They were joined by leading employers, unions, training providers, and industry associations. Today’s event showcased how the summer-long challenge will bring together government, labor, and workforce leaders and highlight effective strategies and partnerships that deliver good jobs for all and equitable workforce development.</p>



<p>The administration officials thanked the participants for being among the first to sign up for the Talent Pipeline Challenge and serving as ambassadors who will work to bring other employers to the table. There was broad agreement that ensuring a reliable and continuing supply of skilled workers for infrastructure projects is critical and that because of the additional demand created by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, employers will need to expand their search to communities that historically have been excluded from hiring and training opportunities, including rural, Tribal, and historically under-served communities. Administration officials closed the meeting by emphasizing that partnerships between employers and training providers will ensure that America has a well-trained, highly skilled and diverse workforce ready to strengthen the economic security of communities across the country.</p>



<p>Employers participating in the event voiced their commitment to training investments and partnerships. AT&amp;T CEO John Stankey discussed how the company’s relationship with the Communication Workers of America (CWA) supports their highly-skilled workforce and how the launch of their innovative training program with Corning, a fiber manufacturer, has prepared workers for the broadband sector. Brian Stewart, CEO of The Superior Group, an electrical contractor in Ohio, emphasized their efforts working closely with the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW) to train and secure credentials for their employees to install electric vehicle chargers through the Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP). Deryl McKissack, one of the owners of the Black-woman owned construction firm McKissack and McKissack, discussed the importance of creating a pipeline for equitable training and hiring and how she works to recruit more people from underrepresented communities, with a strong focus on Black women, into the construction field.</p>



<p>The organizations in attendance that help facilitate training, in particular community colleges and unions, emphasized the importance of their partnerships with employers. Union leaders from the AFL-CIO, IBEW, CWA, and LiUNA highlighted the importance of ensuring jobs are good-quality union jobs, the value of skills training programs that include wrap-around supports to help underserved workers secure jobs in these sectors, and to the importance of expanding pre-apprenticeships that are connected to registered apprenticeships as a pathway to middle-class jobs for workers from disadvantaged communities. Robert Holsten of Wilson Community College talked about the college’s new and unique partnership with Greenlight utility to train broadband workers. Mayor Purzycki of Wilmington, Delaware praised the flexibility and timing of the Rescue Plan funds to make key investments in training in-demand workers for key sectors, including infrastructure.</p>



<p>Participants in today’s launch event included:</p>



<p><strong><em>White House</em></strong></p>



<p>Brian Deese, Director of National Economic Council</p>



<p>Mitch Landrieu, Senior Advisor and Infrastructure Coordinator</p>



<p>Carmel Martin, Deputy Assistant to the President for Economic Mobility</p>



<p>Susan Rice, Domestic Policy Advisor</p>



<p>Gene Sperling, Senior Advisor to the President and American Rescue Plan Coordinator</p>



<p><strong><em>Department of Labor</em></strong></p>



<p>Marty Walsh, Secretary of Labor</p>



<p><strong><em>Employers</em></strong></p>



<p>Brendan Bechtel, CEO, Bechtel</p>



<p>Barbara Humpton, CEO, Siemens USA</p>



<p>Deryl McKissack, President and CEO, McKissack &amp; McKissack</p>



<p>Qiana Spain, Executive VP and Chief HR Officer, Amtrak</p>



<p>John Stankey, CEO, AT&amp;T</p>



<p>Bryan Stewart, CEO, The Superior Group</p>



<p>Wendell Weeks, CEO, Corning</p>



<p><strong><em>Employer Associations:</em></strong></p>



<p>Shirley Bloomfield, CEO, NTCA &#8211; The Rural Broadband Association</p>



<p>Gary Bolton, CEO, Fiber Broadband Association</p>



<p>Martin Durbin, Senior Vice President, Policy, U.S. Chamber of Commerce</p>



<p>Jonathan Spalter, President &amp; CEO, USTelecom</p>



<p><strong><em>Unions</em></strong></p>



<p>Kenny Cooper, Secretary Treasurer, International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (IBEW)</p>



<p>Terry O’Sullivan, President, Laborers’ International Union of North America (LiUNA)</p>



<p>Fred Redmond, Secretary Treasurer, American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO)</p>



<p>Chris Shelton, President, Communications Workers of America (CWA)</p>



<p><strong><em>Training Providers &amp; Intermediaries</em></strong></p>



<p>Chaton Green, Building Pathways</p>



<p>Rusty Greiff, Chief Strategy Officer, Jobs for the Future</p>



<p>Robert Holsten, VP of Academic Affairs at Wilson Community College (NC)</p>



<p>Jennifer Mefford, National Co-Chair, Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP)</p>



<p>Steve Preston, CEO, Goodwill Industries</p>



<p>Jon Schnur, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer, America Achieves</p>



<p>Andy Van Kleunen, Chief Executive Officer, National Skills Coalition</p>



<p>Jennifer Worth, Senior VP, Academic &amp; Workforce Development, American Association of Community Colleges (AACC)</p>



<p><strong><em>Local Officials</em></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Unique Morris Hughes, Washington, D.C. Dept. of Employment Services <strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Mayor Mike Purzycki, Wilmington, DE</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Passage of Delaware Assault Weapons Ban and Other Gun Safety&#160;Legislation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-passage-of-delaware-assault-weapons-ban-and-other-gun-safety-legislation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 21:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55875</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the wake of the horrific massacres in Buffalo, New York, and Uvalde, Texas, the families of the fallen had one message for all of us: Do something. Do something to prevent this carnage and make our communities safer. I again called for a ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, stronger background checks, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In the wake of the horrific massacres in Buffalo, New York, and Uvalde, Texas, the families of the fallen had one message for all of us: Do something. Do something to prevent this carnage and make our communities safer. I again called for a ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazines, stronger background checks, and a host of other commonsense measures to protect our fellow Americans.<br><br>I’m proud that my home state of Delaware—“the First State”—has become one of the very first states in recent weeks to answer that call and take decisive action to reduce gun violence. Yesterday, the Delaware state legislature passed a historic assault weapons ban, strict limits on high-capacity magazines, and legislation to significantly improve background checks. The legislature has also taken up several other critical gun safety bills, including a bill to make it easier to hold gun manufacturers accountable for how they market and sell weapons of war<br><br>These are reasonable measures, supported by the vast majority of Americans. And they work. In the decade after Congress passed the 1994 ban on assault weapons and high-capacity magazines—with bipartisan support in Congress and the backing of law enforcement—mass shootings went down. But after Republicans let the law expire in 2004 and those weapons were allowed to be sold again, mass shootings tripled. Those are the facts, and they should inspire us to action.<br><br>I have already taken more executive action to curb gun crime than any other President during their first year in office. States like Delaware, thanks to the leadership of Governor John Carney and the State Legislature, continue to lead the way in protecting their people. But a national crisis demands a national response, and it’s past time for Congress to do the right thing. As a step in the right direction, I urge the United States Senate to pass a meaningful bipartisan gun safety bill without delay. This is an issue of conscience and common sense. We must meet this moment. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the National Parent Teacher Association&#8217;s 125th Anniversary&#160;Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-national-parent-teacher-associations-125th-anniversary-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 19:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gaylord National Resort &#38; Convention CenterFort Washington, Maryland 10:14 A.M. EDT THE FIRST LADY: &#160;Thank you. &#160;Thank you so much. &#160;Thank you. &#160;Where are you, Delaware? &#160; AUDIENCE MEMBER: &#160;Right here! THE FIRST LADY: &#160;(Laughs.) &#160;Please, thank you. &#160;Thank you so much.&#160; I don&#8217;t know why she was so nervous. &#160;She should just think of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Gaylord National Resort &amp; Convention Center<br>Fort Washington, Maryland</p>



<p>10:14 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY: &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;Thank you so much. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;Where are you, Delaware? &nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER: &nbsp;Right here!</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY: &nbsp;(Laughs.) &nbsp;Please, thank you. &nbsp;Thank you so much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t know why she was so nervous. &nbsp;She should just think of me like her English teacher. &nbsp;(Laughter.) &nbsp;</p>



<p>And thank you, President King. &nbsp;Anna, you know, I’m so grateful for your leadership. &nbsp;And President-elect Johnson, as a &#8212; (applause) &#8212; as a fellow Delawarean, I’m proud that you are representing our state.</p>



<p>So, good morning.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE: &nbsp;Good morning!</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY: &nbsp;Wow. &nbsp;I love that. &nbsp;I love that energy this early in the morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m honored to be with all of you today. &nbsp;For 125 years, the PTA has been an incredibly effective champion for our nation’s students.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;You’ve worked to create child labor laws and kindergarten classes, and better public health services. &nbsp;And I have been grateful for the chance to partner with you to better support military kids through Joining Forces. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe that your success can be traced back to your roots &#8212; the values of your three founding mothers: Alice, Phoebe, and Selena. &nbsp;See, I read your website. &nbsp;You didn’t know that, did you? &nbsp;(Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>They believed that children deserve better than the status quo. &nbsp;And they understood that the best way to win that change was by harnessing the love, passion, and persistence of the people who care most about our kids &#8212; their parents and educators. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like your founders and many of you here, I am both a mother and a teacher. &nbsp;So, I know how personal your fight is, and I know how powerful this partnership can be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that’s why I’ve been frustrated by those who have tried to divide us in these last few years. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;From reopening schools to class curriculum, we’ve been told that parents and teachers are at odds. &nbsp;</p>



<p>But as I visit schools and meet with families, that’s not what I’ve seen.</p>



<p>I’ve seen parents and educators working more closely than ever, finding new ways to support students through the challenges of virtual learning.</p>



<p>I’ve seen teachers and counselors who check in on struggling parents, and families calling for better pay for our educators. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as my husband worked to get the American Rescue Plan passed and as we got millions of Americans vaccinated and made sure that schools could reopen safely, parents and educators were our best advocates and closest partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is no divide between those who love our students and those who teach them, because we all do! &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Parents, we know that we are our children’s first teachers. &nbsp;And, educators, we choose this path because we love what we do and who we teach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, we can lead the change that our children need. &nbsp;In fact, right now, we must.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Because even as our schools are reopened, we know that recovery isn’t always the same as healing. &nbsp;Our students are still wrestling with the aftershocks of this pandemic &#8212; the isolation, anxiety, and sorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I hear it so much: Parents who are worried that their kids are having a hard time, you know, catching up after learning virtually. &nbsp;Educators who tell me that they’re burned out. &nbsp;Students who are dealing with the trauma of loss and grief.</p>



<p>Joe and his team are working hard to ensure that students have the mental health and academic support they need and to keep them safe. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;Because safety is always on our minds and especially right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Three weeks ago, Joe and I stood before the 21 crosses at Uvalde. &nbsp;I touched the pictures of the bright, beautiful faces that would never again laugh or open birthday presents or tell their parents that they loved them. &nbsp;And I laid down white roses on a sea of colorful flowers, the offerings of a town broken by grief, just as I had done in Buffalo, New York, one week before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a teacher, I’ve imagined that scene in my own classroom again and again. &nbsp;You know, at the start of each semester &#8212; I&#8217;m sure all of you in here who are teachers do this &#8212; you explain to your students of the first day a path &#8212; a pathway to get out if a shooter comes into the school so that they&#8217;re prepared.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I explain it to my students because, you know, they need to know what they should do if the worst happens. &nbsp;And though I now go to work with the Secret Service, I have often wondered over the years &#8212; and it’s true; you know, this is my thirty- &#8212; I think I&#8217;m going into my 38th year of teaching. &nbsp;(Laughs.) &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I wondered over the years if my students would be the next heartbreaking headline. &nbsp;All of you in here who are in the classroom know this. &nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Congress did not act after Columbine, after Sandy Hook, after Parkland. &nbsp;Nothing changed. &nbsp;And nothing will change unless we change it. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; Joe has called on Congress to pass commonsense gun safety reform &#8212; (applause) &#8212; things that the majority of Americans want. &nbsp;And a bipartisan group of senators have come up with a plan to address gun violence. &nbsp;And it would be the most significant gun safety legislation to pass Congress in decades, and with bipartisan support.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;There are no excuses. &nbsp;It’s up to Congress to act. &nbsp;(Applause.) &nbsp;And they represent the will of the people. &nbsp;And that’s why we need the people to speak up &#8212; parents and teachers, all of us. &nbsp;We need to fight now for the lives of our children and for the safety of our schools.</p>



<p>So let me say again: This partnership of parents and educators is powerful. &nbsp;You, together, are powerful. &nbsp;Because you have to be. &nbsp;Because when it comes to mental health or learning resources or safe schools, you see what’s at stake every day in the eyes of the people you love.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Your children need you to act, and I know you would do anything for your kids. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So thank you, all of you, for being here. &nbsp;Thank you for showing up for your children and for students across this country. &nbsp;Thank you for using your voice.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, we can change our future. &nbsp;We can. &nbsp;And we have to protect our children and make our schools work for everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, PTA, I am honored to stand with you. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;END &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;10:24 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration’s Progress Addressing the Infant Formula&#160;Shortage</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administrations-progress-addressing-the-infant-formula-shortage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 19:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, June 17th, Vice President Harris will travel to Dulles International Airport to announce the arrival of over 14,000 pounds of Kendamil infant formula—the equivalent of more than 200,000 8-ounce bottles of formula—that will be used to add more supply to shelves. This shipment is the latest through the Biden-Harris Administration’s Operation Fly Formula,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, June 17<sup>th</sup>, Vice President Harris will travel to Dulles International Airport to announce the arrival of over 14,000 pounds of Kendamil infant formula—the equivalent of more than 200,000 8-ounce bottles of formula—that will be used to add more supply to shelves. This shipment is the latest through the Biden-Harris Administration’s <strong><u>Operation Fly Formula</u></strong>, a multi-agency partnership through which the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) ship infant formula so it can get to store shelves faster.&nbsp;<br><br>By this week’s end, Operation Fly Formula will have delivered the equivalent of 13 million 8-oz bottles since its inception—4 million of which were delivered this week alone. The shipment that the Vice President announces on Friday was donated by United Airlines and constitutes just one of ten international shipments of baby formula facilitated through Operation Fly Formula for the week of June 13<sup>th</sup>, which also include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>June 13:</strong> A United Airlines flight arrived at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li><li><strong>June 14:</strong> Two United Airlines flights arrived at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li><li><strong>June 15:</strong> A United Airlines flight arrived at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li><li><strong>June 16:</strong> A flight arrived in Columbus, OH, from Melbourne, Australia, carrying Bub’s Australia infant formula. And, a flight arrived in Louisville, Kentucky from Switzerland carrying medical specialty infant formula from Nestlé.</li><li><strong>June 18:</strong> A United Airlines flight will arrive at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li><li><strong>June 19:</strong> Two United Airlines flights will arrive at Dulles International Airport from London Heathrow carrying Kendamil infant formula.</li></ul>



<p>Operation Fly Formula represents just one component of the Biden-Harris Administration’s multi-pronged approach to ensuring families are able to access safe baby formula. While there is more work to do, these successes have meant more product on shelves and fewer families in need.<br><br><u><em><strong>Additional Actions Taken to Get Formula Back on Shelves and Increase the Supply of Infant Formula Quickly and Safely</strong></em></u><em><br></em><br>The Administration is executing an all-of-government approach to produce more infant formula and get it on the shelf. The federal government—including the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), Department of Agriculture (USDA), Department of Justice (DOJ), Department of Transportation (DOT), U.S. Trade Representative (USTR), Department of Homeland Security (DHS), Department of Commerce (DOC), Department of Defense (DoD), and the White House—has worked around the clock to address the shortfall in infant formula production while the Sturgis plant remains offline. The recent actions described below build upon the prior actions taken by FDA and USDA to address this shortage at its earliest stages.</p>



<ul><li><strong><u>Invoking the Defense Production Act:</u></strong> To ensure that manufacturers have the necessary ingredients to make safe, healthy infant formula here at home, President Biden has invoked authorities under the Defense Production Act (DPA). The DPA empowers the government to require suppliers to direct needed resources to infant formula manufacturers before any other customer who may have ordered that good. The Administration has already invoked this authority to direct firms to prioritize and allocate the production of key infant formula inputs like raw materials, formula ingredients and bottling and packaging materials. This will continue to help manufacturers increase production and speed up supply chains. To date, the President’s invocation of the DPA has resulted in three priority orders:<ul><li>Abbott Nutrition receiving priority orders of raw materials like sugar and corn syrup for infant formula, enabling a planned 25% increase production so they can manufacture at 100% capacity.</li><li>Reckitt receiving priority orders for consumables like single-use products such as filters, which Reckitt expects will allow the company to expand production by 40%.&nbsp;</li><li>Cargill Inc. receiving priority on materials such as corn products, sweeteners, and oils to maximize production of formula.&nbsp;</li></ul></li><li><strong><u>Cutting Red Tape to Increase Imports:</u></strong> The FDA is cutting red tape to increase the supply of safe, high-quality formula through increased imports. The FDA, with import inspection support from USDA and Customs and Border Protection (CBP), is encouraging infant formula manufacturers worldwide to take advantage of these flexibilities, and will continue to actively work with USDA, the UK, Australia, New Zealand, Singapore, and European authorities to expedite entry for products made abroad, and FDA. The Administration has thus far approved nine applications, representing over 210 million 8-ounce equivalent bottles eligible and committed for import, including:<ul><li>Bubs Australia will provide at least 1.25 million cans of several varieties of its infant formula from Melbourne, Australia, which will make at least 27.5 million 8-ounce bottles.</li><li>Kendal Nutricare will provide at least 58 million bottle-equivalents of its routine infant formula from the UK.</li><li>Nestle will provide approximately 33 million bottle-equivalents of Gerber Good Start Gentle formula from Mexico.</li><li>Nutricia (Danone) will provide 5 million bottle-equivalents of its Neocate Infant DHA/ARA specialty formula from the UK.</li></ul></li><li><strong><u>Facilitating WIC Waivers for Families in Need:</u></strong> Earlier this month, the President called on WIC state agencies that were not yet taking full advantage of the of flexibilities available in WIC to act immediately to adopt any waivers that could help those they serve. Since then, all 50 states have acted, allowing greater flexibility for WIC families to get the formula they need. &nbsp;Additionally, thanks to Congress’ quick action, USDA will also have added flexibility to waive rules and allow WIC participants to purchase multiple brands of formula during supply chain disruptions or other crises. This new legislation will also require formula companies to demonstrate they have a plan in place to respond to an infant formula recall, including how they would prevent shortages.</li><li><strong><u>Getting the Abbott Facility Reopened Safely:</u></strong> This past February, the largest infant formula manufacturer in the country—Abbott Nutrition—initiated a voluntary recall of several lines of powdered formula. This came after concerns about bacterial contamination at Abbott’s Sturgis, Michigan, facility after four infants fell ill and two died. The Sturgis plant closed as a result of the contamination. Since then FDA has entered into a consent decree with Abbott to ensure its facility can reopen safely. FDA is working with Abbott to ensure that the product manufactured at the Sturgis plant is safe for families.&nbsp;</li><li><strong><u>Cracking Down on Price Gouging:</u></strong><strong> </strong>The DOJ is engaging with state attorneys general to encourage them to use their powers to monitor and address price gouging in the infant formula market, and urging them to devote more resources to monitoring predatory behavior in the market for infant formula, which states like New Jersey have recently announced. In addition, following President Biden’s call for the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to use all its available tools to monitor and investigate reports of illegal and predatory conduct, the FTC launched an inquiry into the ongoing shortage for infant formula including examining deceptive, fraudulent, or otherwise unfair business practices that take advantage of families.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris Before a Conversation on Historic Investments to Remove and Replace Lead&#160;Pipes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-before-a-conversation-on-historic-investments-to-remove-and-replace-lead-pipes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 19:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Community Empowerment AssociationPittsburgh, Pennsylvania THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, let me just start by saying thank you all for the &#8212; for this meeting and for this conversation.  Secretary Fudge and I have been &#8212; together with Administrator Regan from the EPA &#8212; have been working on this issue for quite some time, thinking about it deeply&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Community Empowerment Association<br><em>Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Well, let me just start by saying thank you all for the &#8212; for this meeting and for this conversation. <br> <br>Secretary Fudge and I have been &#8212; together with Administrator Regan from the EPA &#8212; have been working on this issue for quite some time, thinking about it deeply in terms of the significance and the seriousness of it and the impact in terms of what we&#8217;re doing to fix it. <br> <br>In fact, the Administrator and I have been on what we call a roadshow &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; going around the country, talking about lead pipes. <br> <br>And so, it&#8217;s good to be back in Pittsburgh.  And it&#8217;s good to be back with you, as leaders, to think about how we can continue to get the word out about the rights that people in the community have to expect this is going to be handled with a sense of urgency, with a sense of speed, and also to talk about why it is important in terms of &#8212;<br> <br>You know, there are, I think, three principles at play, really.  You know, there&#8217;s the piece that is about equity &#8212; right? &#8212; which is literally different communities are &#8212; are dealing with this differently based on what resources they have.  And that shouldn&#8217;t be the case. <br> <br>It&#8217;s an issue that is obviously about public health, in terms of the harm. <br> <br>And then there&#8217;s the issue, because of the harm that is &#8212; that makes it an issue, that’s also about education, meaning: Can our babies learn if they&#8217;re drinking toxic water?  Right?<br> <br>So that&#8217;s why they&#8217;re here: to have this conversation with you and &#8212; and to highlight the work that that the Secretary and the Administrator are doing through the agencies and on behalf of our administration to finally deal with this issue in a substantial way and see it through in terms of what we know can be done when we prioritize it.<br> <br>So, with that, I thank you all.  And we&#8217;ll begin our discussion now. <br> <br> END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration’s Historic Investments to Remove and Replace Lead&#160;Pipes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-biden-harris-administrations-historic-investments-to-remove-and-replace-lead-pipes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 19:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55837</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Community Empowerment AssociationPittsburgh, Pennsylvania 1:51 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  Good afternoon.  Kim, I want to thank you for that.  We had a wonderful conversation with Hanna, who I think is out here &#8212; there&#8217;s Hanna &#8212; and Gwendolyn.  And I just want to thank the leaders here in Pittsburgh, in Pennsylvania, for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Community Empowerment Association<br><em>Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania</em></em></p>



<p>1:51 P.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon, everyone.  Good afternoon.  Kim, I want to thank you for that.  We had a wonderful conversation with Hanna, who I think is out here &#8212; there&#8217;s Hanna &#8212; and Gwendolyn.  And I just want to thank the leaders here in Pittsburgh, in Pennsylvania, for the work that you’ve been doing on this issue. <br><br>I’m honored to be traveling with Secretary Marcia Fudge, with Administrator Michael Regan to highlight the work that is happening in local communities like Pittsburgh, which are models of what can and will happen around the country.<br><br>In large part, the work that we are doing is in response to the advocacy that has been coming out of leaders, like the leaders here in Pittsburgh, for years, who have been demanding that we prioritize this as an issue, have been demanding that we put the resources in that are reflective of a priority, and that we do the work in a way that is collaborative with local leaders, local elected officials, with community leaders, knowing that the work that we do together will have profound impact when we are coordinated.<br><br>So I want to thank everyone who was here for the work that you have been doing for years.  We came to Pittsburgh to talk about you here in your backyard, but then to talk about you around the country as a model of what can be done around the country.<br><br>So, Secretary Fudge, Administrator Regan, I want to thank you for traveling with me.  Congressman Lamb, thank you for your leadership.  I&#8217;ve seen you and Congressman Doyle, the work that you do in Washington, D.C., representing the people of this district so, so well and so strongly.  And again, Kim, thank you for that.<br><br>So, basically, we come at this issue from probably an obvious perspective, which is that we believe, the President &#8212; President Joe Biden and I, our administration &#8212; we all believe that all people have a right to be able to drink clean water, that all people have a right to breathe clean air.<br><br>So we approach this from that perspective, which is that we as a society and certainly as a government must ensure that that right is real and that it is protected.<br><br>On the issue, then, of lead pipes, we know that up to 10 million homes in our country have lead pipes that are feeding the water that flows in their home.  We know that when it comes to lead paint, we&#8217;re looking at at least 24 million homes that have lead paint.  And those are the numbers that have been reported.<br>One of the things that, Kim, that we talked about was there are plenty of folks who live in homes, whether they&#8217;re renters or owners, that may be unaware that there is lead in their paint or in the pipe.<br> <br>And so, again, that highlights the importance of what&#8217;s happening here in Pittsburgh, which it is not only about addressing the issue in terms of amelioration and mitigation, but addressing the issue in terms of doing the first step, which is public education about the seriousness of the issue and the need, then, to address the harm that the issue creates.  And to do that, what we must do as government and together, collectively, to allow homeowners to become aware if their paint contains lead or their pipes are flowing with lead, in terms of the water that then goes into their home.<br> <br>So the work we are doing together includes public education; it includes speaking loudly about what we must do to let people know about their rights and about the harm.<br> <br>So, the harm &#8212; let&#8217;s talk about that.  We talked with, for example, Gwendolyn, who runs a childcare center, about the realities of lead poisoning that includes creating developmental issues for our children; learning disabilities can result from drinking toxic water.  And it&#8217;s basically poison, when we talk about lead in water or in paint.<br> <br>We have talked about what it means in terms of the harm to adults.  It can increase blood pressure.  It can decrease kidney function.  These are real harms that are created because of the lead in paint or in pipes.<br> <br>So then there is the issue that is about public education.  And part of that is, again, about what we will do with the $50 billion that the President, that our administration, together with our Congress members &#8212; and these two Congress members, in particular &#8212; what we have done to put $50 billion into the amelioration of lead in paint and in pipes.<br> <br>That money will go to a number of things: public education; it will go toward what the local governments can do to facilitate testing, at-home tests, things of that nature; and it will go to the removal, then, of lead pipes.<br> <br>Let&#8217;s think about why this is important and why government has a responsibility here.  Lead pipes existed in many communities.  But the disparities exist when a particular community and the members of that community don&#8217;t have the personal resources, the private resources to remove the lead pipes.<br> <br>So there are communities that have the resources, individuals that have the resources to do it on their own.  But if you&#8217;re working three jobs, if you&#8217;re working minimum wage, if you&#8217;re barely getting by month to month, then you probably cannot afford the work that needs to get done to remove the lead.  That&#8217;s where government has a responsibility to kick in and help put the resources in so that we can remove the lead, understanding there are three issues that are at play here.<br> <br>One issue is the issue that is about equity.  All people have a right to drink clean water.  And so this should not be a function of how much money you have to pay to remove the lead from the pipes. <br> <br>It is an issue of public health.  We have talked about the damage to children, to adults, from drinking water that has lead. <br> <br>And then, three, this is an education issue.  This is literally an issue about the education of our children, because we know there&#8217;s a direct correlation between lead pipes and learning ability or disabilities based on the toxins that are present in that water.<br> <br>So I am proud to be joined with these leaders.  And I&#8217;m proud to be with you today to uplift the work that you are doing here in this community.  I thank you for that work.<br> <br>And again, this is a model of what we will be continuing to do around the country.  And again, this is an example of where community leadership influences what happens at the highest levels of our government.  And I do believe that, in that way, this is a success story in terms of the dedication and the commitment that we all have to getting this job done and seeing it through.<br> <br>And here in Pittsburgh, you, I think, are ahead of your timelines in terms of what you expect to get done to meet your timeline goals. <br> <br>And for the President and I, it is our full intention with our Lead Pipe and Paint Action Plan to remove all lead pipes within 10 years.<br> <br>So with that, I thank you all, and let us continue to do the good work that we know will result in generational impact for the better.<br> <br>Thank you.  Thank you.  (Applause.)<br> <br>END                 1:59 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/17/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 17:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 10:59 A.M. EDT Q    Mr. President, have you made a decision about how you will handle the Khashoggi killing when you go to Saudi Arabia? THE PRESIDENT:  The same way I’ve been handling it.  I’m not going to meet with &#8212; I’m not going to meet with MBS; I’m going to an international&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>10:59 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q    Mr. President, have you made a decision about how you will handle the Khashoggi killing when you go to Saudi Arabia?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The same way I’ve been handling it.  I’m not going to meet with &#8212; I’m not going to meet with MBS; I’m going to an international meeting.  And he’s going to be a part of it, just like there were people part of the discussion today.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, how concerned are you about the three Americans who are reportedly missing in Ukraine?  Have you been briefed?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I have been briefed.  We don’t know where they are.</p>



<p>But I want to reiterate: Americans should not be going to Ukraine now.&nbsp; I’ll say it again: Americans should not be going to Ukraine now.&nbsp; They should not be going to Ukraine.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What will the consequences be for oil companies if they don’t boost supplies?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, one of the things that has happened is that the price of gasoline exceeds the price based on the barrel of oil costs right now.&nbsp;&nbsp;So if you get &#8212; based on what a barrel of oil costs on average, it should not be this high.&nbsp; They’re making exorbitant profits &#8212; number one.</p>



<p>Number two, I’ve contacted them &#8212; my team has &#8212; to ask what their plans are and to give any suggestions they have.&nbsp; They have over 9,000 leases &#8212; 9,000.&nbsp; They can drill until they’re &#8212; until (inaudible) won’t have it.&nbsp; But they’re not doing it &#8212; number two.</p>



<p>Number three, I think we’re going to be in a position where we’re going to &#8211;</p>



<p>Oh.&nbsp; (The First Lady approaches the President.)</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; We got to go!</p>



<p>(Cross-talk by reporters.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) two billion people in India are waiting for you to visit India.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ve been to India twice, and I’ll be back to India.&nbsp; And my relations are very good.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>11:01 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
