<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:08:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications John&#160;Kirby</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/20/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-nsc-coordinator-for-strategic-communications-john-kirby-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 13:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57901</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:31 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello.&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Okay, so today we are joined by John Kirby, NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications.&#160; Kirby is here to share an update on Russia’s activities in Ukraine and answer a few questions.&#160; So, Kirby, the floor is yours. MR. KIRBY:&#160; Thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:31 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Okay, so today we are joined by John Kirby, NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications.&nbsp; Kirby is here to share an update on Russia’s activities in Ukraine and answer a few questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Kirby, the floor is yours.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; So I wanted to let you know that we have information today, including from downgraded intelligence that we’re able to share with you, about how Russia is laying the groundwork to annex Ukrainian territory that it controls, in direct violation of Ukraine’s sovereignty.</p>



<p>We’re seeing ample evidence in the intelligence and in the public domain that Russia intends to try to annex additional Ukrainian territory.&nbsp; Russia is beginning to roll out a version of what you could call an “annexation playbook,” very similar to the one we saw in 2014.</p>



<p>Already, Russia is installing illegitimate proxy officials in areas of Ukraine that are under its control.&nbsp; And we know their next moves.&nbsp; First, these proxy officials will arrange sham referenda on joining Russia.&nbsp; Then, Russia will use those sham referenda as a basis to try to claim annexation of sovereign Ukrainian territory.</p>



<p>The Russian government is reviewing detailed plans to purportedly annex a number of regions in Ukraine, including Kherson,<strong> </strong>Zaporizhzhia, all of Donetsk and Luhansk Oblasts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russia is attempting to set the conditions on the ground by seeking to establish branches of Russian banks, to establish the ruble as the default currency in these areas, and to sabotage civilian Internet access.</p>



<p>Russia’s security services continue to target Ukrainians that they believe to be associated with resistance activities.&nbsp; In Kherson, for example, Russia is taking control of broadcasting towers, establishing loyalist security forces, replacing telecommunications infrastructure, forcing residents to apply for Russian citizenship, and issuing Russian passports.</p>



<p>Russia is also installing loyalists in areas of Ukraine that it controls, including a man named Sergei Yeliseyev, a former Russian intelligence officer who has been put in charge of Kherson.&nbsp; Figures like Yeliseyev are Russian bureaucrats with absolutely no connection to Ukraine.&nbsp; No connection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Kremlin has not disclosed the timeline for the referenda, but Russian proxies in these territories claim they will take place later this year, possibly in conjunction with Russia’s September regional elections.</p>



<p>So what are the implications?&nbsp; At the start of the year, Russia told the world that it was not planning to invade Ukraine, and now we’re expected to believe that they&#8217;re not going to plan to annex Ukrainian territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Annexation by force would be a gross violation of the U.N. Charter, and we will not allow it to go unchallenged or unpunished.</p>



<p>We will continue to provide Ukraine with historic levels of security assistance.</p>



<p>Later this week, the administration will announce the next Presidential Drawdown package of weapons and equipment for Ukraine.  It’ll be the 16th such drawdown to support Ukraine since the President took office.</p>



<p>That package will include more HIMARS &#8212; that’s Highly Mobile <s>Advanced</s> [Artillery] Rocket Systems &#8212; which the Ukrainians have been using very effectively to make a difference on the battlefield.&nbsp; And it’ll also include some additional rounds of Multiple Launch Rocket Systems and artillery ammunition.</p>



<p>We’re also going to continue to expose Russian plans so the world knows that any purported annexation is premeditated, illegal, and illegitimate.&nbsp; And we are sanctioning the Russia-installed puppets and proxies in areas of Ukraine that are under Russian control.&nbsp; For example, just last month, we sanctioned the illegitimate Russian-installed mayor of Melitopol, as well as the chairperson and deputy chairpersons of the so-called government of the DNR.</p>



<p>So what next?&nbsp; If Russia nevertheless proceeds with their annexation plans, we are going to respond swiftly and severely and in lockstep with our allies and partners.</p>



<p>Russia will face additional sanctions and become even more of a global pariah than it is now.&nbsp; We will never recognize any purportedly annexed territory as belonging to Russia.&nbsp; We will support accountability efforts for forced deportations, prosecutions of oppositionists, and other gross human rights abuses carried out by Russia.</p>



<p>And we would remind Mr. Putin that, over time, it may prove unable to hold this territory.&nbsp; It’s not a given.&nbsp; The Ukrainian territo- &#8212; the Ukrainian military will work to retake that territory, and the Ukrainian people will resist Russian control and seek to drive Russia out as they have been doing the last five months.</p>



<p>Russia already made a grave mistake with this invasion.&nbsp; It’s achieved none of their strategic objectives.&nbsp; When they invaded Ukraine, only 4 of the 192 other members of the U.N. took Moscow’s side.&nbsp; So the international community, we’re convinced, will continue to stand up for state sovereignty.&nbsp; Any sham efforts to legitimize an illegal land grab will only make things worse for Russia.&nbsp; And we’re going to help make sure of that.</p>



<p>And one other item before I start taking some questions: Today we announced a series of actions the Biden-Harris administration has taken to expand the toolkit that the U.S. government uses to deter and disrupt hostage takings and wrongful detentions &#8212; I think you may have seen this out there &#8212; that&#8217;ll help bring Americans home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This morning, the President signed an executive order that provides expanded tools to help bring our citizens home.&nbsp; Specifically, it authorizes agencies to impose costs and consequences, including financial sanctions and visa bans on governments and non-state actors and those that provide them with the material support who are involved in hostage takings or wrongful detentions.</p>



<p>The State Department is also introducing a new risk indicator to their travel advisories to inform U.S. citizens about the risk of wrongful detention by a foreign government in six countries that have regularly engaged in this practice.&nbsp; This new indicator joins the existing “K” indicator.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s a “D” indicator, the new one.&nbsp; The “K” indicator, that in- &#8212; that covers the risk of kidnapping and hostage taking by non-state actors, as well as a range of other existing risk indicators for a country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These actions demonstrate President Biden&#8217;s unwavering commitment to bringing home U.S. nationals held hostage and wrongfully detained, and to try to help prevent more Americans and their families from having to go through this kind of terrible ordeal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So with that, I’ll take questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Nancy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, John.&nbsp; Given what you&#8217;ve said about Russians anne- &#8212; Russia&#8217;s annexation plans, what is the U.S. assessment of President Putin&#8217;s visit to Iran and why he was willing to take such an unusual and risky trip at this time to meet with the Supreme Leader?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll let Mr. Putin speak for why he decided to go at this particular time.&nbsp; But I would say three things about this trip:</p>



<p>One, it shows the degree to which Mr. Putin and Russia are increasingly isolated.&nbsp; Now they have to turn to Iran for help.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Two, it shows the degree to which his own defense industrial base is having a hard time keeping up with his unprovoked war in Ukraine.&nbsp; We already know that in respect to precision-guided munitions and advanced systems, tanks, even aircraft, he&#8217;s having trouble &#8212; particularly with the micro-electronics &#8212; because of the sanctions and the export controls.&nbsp; And we already know that even without that, his defense industrial base is challenged because of the rate of operation, the pace of operations in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then the third thing I think this indicates is the degree to which he has absolutely no intention of stopping the war and sitting down in good faith and negotiate a settlement with Mr. Zelenskyy.&nbsp; He has every intention quite the contrary, because now he wants to go buy several hundred UAVs to continue to prosecute this illegal war and to continue to kill Ukrainians.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, and what does the U.S. know about the meeting that President Putin had in Iran with Turkish leader Erdoğan and what it could mean for reinstating Ukrainian grain exports?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let them speak to their meetings.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know what was on the agenda for that.&nbsp; We are mindful of the talks that have been ongoing between Turkey, Russia, and Ukraine about grain exports, and we hope for progress in those talks. But we&#8217;re clear-eyed about it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re clear-eyed about Russia&#8217;s ambitions here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re clear-eyed about the fact that there&#8217;s basically a blockade in the Black Sea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So while we certainly welcome Mr. Erdoğan’s leadership in here &#8212; and the President has thanked him for that leadership &#8212; we&#8217;ve trying to come up with a negotiated solution here to get the grain out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s unfortunate that he even has to have those talks, because there&#8217;s a blockade that Russia could stop today. They can take their ships out of the Black Sea.&nbsp; They could let that grain go and alleviate a lot of food security problems not just in Europe, but in the Middle East, in Africa, or elsewhere around the world.</p>



<p>So, again, we&#8217;re hopeful that there can be some sort of arrangement to get that grain out of there, but &#8212; but we&#8217;re not looking at it through rose-colored glasses in terms of the success that they&#8217;ll ultimately be able to achieve.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The only thing I&#8217;d add to that is: It&#8217;s good to see Ukraine at the table in these discussions, and that &#8212; that&#8217;s as it should be.&nbsp; Ukraine absolutely has to be part of whatever solution is solved, and their economy can&#8217;t suffer any more than it already has as a result of Russian blockade activity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s got to the back.&nbsp; Janne, Phil.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; And let me get my pen.&nbsp; I dropped it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Because often, when you ask me questions &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; &#8212; I have to write them down.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s okay.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t be nervous, okay?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Oh, no. &nbsp;I am always nervous when you&#8217;re called on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Next time I know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, John.&nbsp; I have two questions on &#8212; one Ukraine and one Russia.&nbsp; The Ukraine recently announced that diplomatic severance with North Korea.&nbsp; And meanwhile, Russia announced that it will be sending North Korean workers to rebuild Donbas in Ukraine.&nbsp; What is your comment?&nbsp; Or is it a violation of U.N. Security Council sanctions?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not an expert enough on sanctions to know whether these actions are violations of resolutions.&nbsp; But again, it just shows the degree to which Mr. Putin remains isolated.&nbsp; Now he&#8217;s got to turn to North Korea, you know, and he&#8217;s got to turn to Iran here, rather than just doing the right thing to begin with and ending the war.</p>



<p>And eventually, there&#8217;s going to be reconstruction of Ukraine.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s going to be for the Ukrainians to decide, Janne &#8212; not the Russians, not the North Koreans, not anybody else but President Zelenskyy and the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to get to decide how they reconstruct their country after this war.&nbsp; And obviously, and you’ve heard the President talk about this, we&#8217;re going to be there to support them through that process.</p>



<p>The goal right now &#8212; and we can&#8217;t forget what it is right now, as I &#8212; well, I mentioned it in my opening statement &#8212; is to continue to help Ukraine defend itself against this aggression inside their country, making sure that Mr. Zelenskyy and the Ukrainian Armed Forces have what they need to continue to fight back and to reclaim their sovereignty.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what matters right now.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Phil.&nbsp; And then we’ll come back (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to ask you, sir, a question about some of the comments that the President made when he was in Spain last month.&nbsp; But before that, rewinding to some of your statements moments ago, you said that Russia, over time, may prove unable to hold the territory that they&#8217;re annexing.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: What does that mean in terms of the U.S. commitment to Ukraine?&nbsp; Are we talking about, you know, backing some sort of military operation for the Ukrainians to take back territory that was taken from them?&nbsp; Or is that a more general statement about diplomatic pressure?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; There&#8217;s no change to our policy with respect to helping Ukraine defend itself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, we help provide them the training that they need with some of these advanced systems and the systems themselves.&nbsp; And I would remind you that it&#8217;s not just the United States; some 50 other countries.&nbsp; In fact, Secretary Austin is going to be holding yet another iteration of the Ukraine Contact Group this week, and I suspect you&#8217;ll see additional international contributions to Ukrainian security assistance.</p>



<p>And we give that material to them; we give them the training if they need it.&nbsp; Mr. Zelenskyy and his chain of command, they determine how they&#8217;re going to use it.&nbsp; And we have seen over the last, it&#8217;s hard to believe, five months &#8212; but five months &#8212; where the Ukrainians, sometimes all in the same day, will be on the defensive in some areas and on the offensive in others.&nbsp; And we have seen, just in the last week or two, both of that, depending on where you&#8217;re at.</p>



<p>The Ukrainians are certainly &#8212; they have a right not only to defend themselves, but they absolutely have a right to go on the counter-offensive inside their own country against Russian forces.</p>



<p>Now, where and when they do that, how they do that, and what systems they use, that&#8217;s for them to decide.&nbsp; Our job, again, is to make sure they&#8217;ve got the tools and the training to be able to defend themselves.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then my second question: President Biden announced last month that he was going to be sending two more destroyers to Rota, Spain.&nbsp; I think the number is going from four to six.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I guess I&#8217;m wondering: You know, why is the President sending these warships to the Mediterranean to defend the Spanish coast there &#8212; I mean, this is a country that spends about 1 percent of its GDP on total defense &#8212; when there seems to be an increasingly serious threat in the Indo-Pacific from China?&nbsp; I mean, shouldn&#8217;t Spain step up?&nbsp; Shouldn&#8217;t the Italians or French, you know, patrol their own waters so that we can have a free hand on the other side of the world?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; This is one of the very few questions I&#8217;ll probably ever get that are right down my lane.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I knew you were coming today.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I &#8212; and I served as a young officer in the Med on a couple of different deployments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, so &#8212; so a home port is just where the ship stays.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean that the ship is just there to sail in the waters off of Spain. &nbsp;And so the four destroyers that we have in the Mediterranean right now, they patrol the Mediterranean, and frankly, there are times when they&#8217;ll patrol into the North Atlantic.&nbsp; It’s just &#8212; just having them in Spain is what we call forward deployed.&nbsp; It&#8217;s like we have &#8212; you know, we have an aircraft carrier and warships in Japan forward deployed.&nbsp; We have ships forward deployed into the Middle East, in &#8212; based in Bahrain.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just a place to &#8212; it shortens the time and distance to get them on station where they might need to be.</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s &#8212; this decision by the President to add two destroyers to the four that are there I think is indicative of what the President has said many times: The security environment in Europe is different now; it has changed.&nbsp; Not is changing, not will change.&nbsp; Has changed.&nbsp; And we need to meet that.</p>



<p>This is just one of many moves, and that the President spoke to in Madrid and at the G7, that were taken to improve our military posture on NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.&nbsp; And some of those moves will be permanent, in addition to the two ships, and it&#8217;s going to take a little while for them to get there, to be permanently homebased there.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s not going to happen tomorrow.</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re going to put a headquarters forward command element in Poland &#8212; first time ever.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to make more regular the &#8212; more routine, I should say, the rotational deployments of Army land forces throughout the eastern flank as well.</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s all part and parcel of a larger effort by the United States to make sure that we are able to meet our Article 5 commitment to our NATO Allies, particularly on the eastern flank.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we’re not emphasizing one theater at the expense of another?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Oh, look, you have to do both.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m glad you followed up on that.&nbsp; I mean, we already have 60 percent of the United States Navy either in or based in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; There&#8217;s already a robust military capability in that part of the world.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s &#8212; we have no intention whatsoever of decreasing that focus and that energy there.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve heard Secretary Austin talk about China being the pacing challenge for the United States military, and that&#8217;s exactly how they&#8217;re treating it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Take a look at the budget that we just submitted for ’23, and you&#8217;ll see chapter and verse how the United States military is really trying to make sure they&#8217;re investing in the kinds of capabilities that we&#8217;re going to need in the Indo-Pacific to face that pacing challenge.</p>



<p>Look, the United States military is a global &#8212; a global power.&nbsp; And you have to be focused on all kinds of different regions and face all kinds of different threats.&nbsp; The President was just in the Middle East because that too is an important area for our national security interests.&nbsp; We can do &#8212; we can do more than one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Nandita.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Quick question, just to sort of follow up on what you said about the U.S. responding to any sort of annexation attempts.&nbsp; What kind of options are available to the U.S. if you were to respond?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yeah, I talked about that a little bit in the &#8212; in the open.&nbsp; We certainly have additional sanctions we could &#8212; we could employ.&nbsp; We could strengthen the ones that are already in place.&nbsp; We can further try to make it harder, squeeze Mr. Putin&#8217;s ability to wage war.&nbsp; Waging war is an expensive business.&nbsp; He now &#8212; his &#8212; he&#8217;s facing inflation of up to &#8212; thanks to all the international pressure, he&#8217;s already facing inflation of up to 20 percent.&nbsp; His &#8212; his imports have fallen by 40 percent.&nbsp; The Russian stock market fell by about 30 percent recently.</p>



<p>I mean, this has not been without costs, and we can &#8212; we can raise those costs on him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you expecting to do any of that in the next few days, weeks?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce today.&nbsp; We wanted to make it clear today what we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve already, as I said in my opening statement, started to exe- &#8212; to sanction some of these so-called officials.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I don&#8217;t have any new announcements to make today, but we just wanted to make very plain for the American people what we&#8217;re seeing and make it very plain to Mr. Putin that nobody is fooled by it.&nbsp; We know he&#8217;s just dusting off the old playbook from 2014.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be watching this closely.</p>



<p>Last point &#8212; and it&#8217;s important, and I know I say it all the time, but it&#8217;s not just the United States.&nbsp; The international community is wise to this as well.&nbsp; And we fully expect that our allies and partners will participate in any additional pressure put on Mr. Putin.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, John.&nbsp; I wonder if we could change topics a bit here.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve long talked about how climate change is a national security issue for the country.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you view this as a national emergency and if you believe that executive actions that will be announced are enough of a message to send to the world that the U.S. is indeed serious about climate change.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of any announcements on specific actions with respect to climate.</p>



<p>But let me take a step back.&nbsp; I mean, the Pentagon has noted not just in this administration, but even the previous one, that climate change is a national security issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Geez, Jeff, I mean, not only does it affect our infrastructure &#8212; and you&#8217;re already starting to see military bases like Norfolk Naval Base having to invest millions of dollars to try to improve their infrastructure because of rising sea levels.&nbsp; So it has an impact on our infrastructure.&nbsp; It has an impact on our readiness, because you &#8212; and you&#8217;re seeing it now, even in the wildfires, where so many National Guardsmen are being called out.&nbsp; And &#8212; and God love them for that, but they&#8217;re &#8212; those are important tasks and missions, but it takes away from other tasks and missions when it comes to defending the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s an impact on our own readiness just because our &#8212; our troops, our sailors, our Marines, our airmen, our Coast Guardsmen are being called out for &#8212; to respond to natural disasters, which are getting worse because of climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then lastly, it&#8217;s a driver of actual missions, because climate change creates instability, which creates insecurity in some places.&nbsp; And you can end up &#8212; the fighting in Syria started, really, as a result of a drought.&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s a &#8212; it can actually drive military missions and force the military to become involved in places and at times where they wouldn&#8217;t have had to otherwise.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, again, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President or any &#8212; any decisions he may or may not make.&nbsp; But the President believes that this is a very important issue for our own national security.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to treat it that way.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to Iran and Russia and then, if I may, one quick one on the executive order from today.&nbsp; Jake Sullivan had said last week that Iran was preparing to train Russian forces to use armed drones in Ukraine starting this month.&nbsp; Does the U.S. have an indication that those training sessions have started or that Iran has actually given those drones to Russia?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any indications that the &#8212; that the sale has actually occurred.&nbsp; And so, therefore, we wouldn&#8217;t have any indications that there&#8217;s been training done on them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I don&#8217;t want us to get lost in the details here.&nbsp; I mean, I know it&#8217;s important.&nbsp; Obviously, we wouldn&#8217;t have talked about it if it wasn&#8217;t.&nbsp; But it is an indication of how much more desperate Mr. Putin is becoming in terms of his own defense industrial base and the degree to which he wants to continue to prosecute this war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, a lot of it&#8217;s going to depend on how many does he buy, what kind of capabilities they have.&nbsp; But the Iranians have a domestic production capability of drones, and those drones have lethal capabilities.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen that for ourselves in the attacks that they have &#8212; they have perpetrated in Iraq and in Syria against our own troops and against our own facilities there.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re watching this closely, and we&#8217;re taking it seriously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the executive order from today: How quickly might we see sanctions on people or countries that the U.S. considers responsible for detaining Americans wrongfully right now?&nbsp; And how might this impact or play into the cases of Brittney Griner or Paul Whelan?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any decision space here.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not my role today.&nbsp; These are additional tools that this EO gives us, including the ability to levy additional sanctions.&nbsp; So, again, I&#8217;m not going to preview anything or get ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last thing I&#8217;d say on this is that the President remains laser-focused on these cases and in constant touch with his national security team and with our Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs on all these cases, including, of course, Mr. Whelan and Mrs. Griner.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jacqui and then Franco.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; On the Iran nuclear deal talks, John, I just wanted to get your view on this.&nbsp; Wendy Sherman said last week it&#8217;s in Iran’s deal &#8212; best interest to make a deal.&nbsp; “They would get sanctions relief.&nbsp; They would improve their economy and sell their oil again, and the world needs their oil so they could get a good price for it.”&nbsp; So I&#8217;m asking: Is the White House viewing sanctions relief for Iran as a way to bring down gas prices?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; The administration is looking at a return to the JCPOA &#8212; the Iran deal &#8212; to prevent Iran from obtaining a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the goal.&nbsp; And you heard the President talk about this on the trip.&nbsp; No problem in the Middle East &#8212; none &#8212; gets easier to solve if Iran has a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the goal of the Iran deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, look, there&#8217;s a deal on the table.&nbsp; And the onus is on Iran now to decide whether they&#8217;re going to take that deal.&nbsp; If they take that deal, yes, sanctions relief will be a part of it, as it was before, before the previous administration pulled out of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the goal, the objective, the purpose is to prevent Iran from getting a nuclear weapon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So how should we understand her statement then?&nbsp; Because the President&#8217;s whole strategy when he was on his Middle East tour was to counter Iran, but her language makes it seem like maybe, you know, they&#8217;re not so bad if they bring down gas prices, which has been hurting the President in polls, obviously.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, look, I mean, there&#8217;s obviously a tangential &#8212; potentially tangential benefit, should they sign into the deal and actually stop spinning their centrifuges and come into compliance and allow themselves to be back inside the most rigid inspection regime ever in an arms control agreement, which would include potentially sanctions relief, which would include obviously some economic breathing space for them to do things potentially on the oil market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, again, Jacqui, that&#8217;s not the purpose here.&nbsp; The purpose is to try to prevent them from having a nuclear weapons capability.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the goal.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s all about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One last question. &nbsp;On this statement from Iran that they can produce a nuclear bomb if they want to but they haven’t made that decision, it comes after Biden and the Israeli Prime Minister publicly disagreed on the best way to counter Iran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, how concerning is it that Putin is meeting with Iran right after Iran said that they can build a bomb if they want to?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;ll let those leaders speak for the timing of this visit.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re focused on is making sure Ukraine can continue to defend itself.&nbsp; And, obviously, it looks like, potentially, they&#8217;re going to have to learn to defend themselves from these Iranian drones.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as you saw on the trip in Middle East, the President is focused on an integrated, more stable, more secure Middle East. &nbsp;And you can&#8217;t get there, you can&#8217;t have that as an outcome if Iran builds a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re closer to it today than they were five years ago.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President understands that sense of urgency, which is why he wanted his team to negotiate this deal.&nbsp; And now the negotiations are complete.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re close.&nbsp; Iran just has to agree to accept that deal, come back into compliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That won&#8217;t solve all the problems.&nbsp; Not at all.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll solve &#8212; if they come back into compliance and submit to the inspections and a reduction in their stockpiles, it&#8217;ll certainly help solve the more urgent problem now of their burgeoning nuclear capability, but it won&#8217;t necessarily solve their developing ballistic missile capability, which continues to improve.&nbsp; It won&#8217;t necessarily solve their support for terrorist networks in the region.&nbsp; It won&#8217;t solve the threats to maritime security in the Gulf that we continue to see out of Iran.&nbsp; And it potentially could &#8212; you know, might make &#8212; you know, won&#8217;t solve all problems in Yemen, although we&#8217;re glad for this ceasefire.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re still going to have to stay focused on all those other issues, which is, again, why the President&#8217;s trip was so important.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Franco.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; John, first on the Russian annex, and then if I could ask a China question.&nbsp; On the Russia annexation comments that you&#8217;re making: Can you talk a little bit more about what specifically is new in the downgraded intelligence that you brought up?&nbsp; I mean, the administration has been warning about sham elections, about referendums since the spring.&nbsp; Kherson has been named in the past as possibly a place this could happen.&nbsp; So what has actually &#8212; what are you seeing that is new in the last few weeks that you did not know, before?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I have to be somewhat careful in answering the question because we&#8217;re talking about some declassified intelligence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would &#8212; I would point you to some of the specificity in my opening comments about some of the individuals, some of the locations, and then just the modalities, I think, of how the Russians plan to pursue this in time and space.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s really about as far as I&#8217;m able to go.</p>



<p>But we know this is going to be a concerted effort here.&nbsp; And some of it is in con- &#8212; is in parallel to the incremental territorial gains that they&#8217;re making.&nbsp; And some of the designs here are a representation of the frustration that they haven&#8217;t had as much success in territorial gains as they&#8217;ve had in the past.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is this more of an incremental advancement in that &#8212; in that theory of Russia trying to annex?&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;ve just been hearing about it for a while.&nbsp; So, I mean, I&#8217;m just trying to gauge how much &#8212; how different is this than what&#8217;s been going on for a while now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; They &#8212; this is out of the playbook, and we&#8217;ve seen him do it in the past.&nbsp; I think what we&#8217;re seeing now is a more concerted, more strategic effort.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s really about as far as I can go.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On China, China tariffs &#8212; you know, I asked Karine about this yesterday and talked about the efforts of the administration to kind of address that and resolve concerns that they have about what Trump did.&nbsp; Can you talk about &#8212; a little bit about where efforts to ease those tariffs is and when we might be able to &#8212; when we might see some of the things that Biden has said is expected to come out of that?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new for you today, and I certainly can&#8217;t add to what Karine said yesterday.&nbsp; The President is looking at this.&nbsp; He wants to make sure that he makes the best decisions for the American people and for the American economy.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m certainly not going to get ahead of that.&nbsp; He&#8217;s taking this very seriously, as he should.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, I’m going to take two from the back.</p>



<p>Yeah, Ed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And then (inaudible).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp; So I want to ask you about oil and Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>So should we expect an announcement then from &#8212; on August 3rd &#8212; from OPEC or Saudi Arabia about increasing oil production because of the President’s visit?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I’m &#8212; I’m certainly not going to speak for OPEC.&nbsp; They get to make their decisions and speak to them.&nbsp; I would point you to what the President said when we were in Jeddah: that the discussions on energy security were quite constructive and that he expects that it’s possible that we could see some movement here in the next two to three weeks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; so we’re just going to watch that and see how it goes.<br><br>Important to remember, and I think he also reminded, that OPEC+3 has already increased by 50 percent &#8212; planned increases in July and August; that’s been helpful &#8212; in addition to the 1 million barrels per day that the President has released from the Strategic Reserve.<br><br>All that oil has helped stabilize the market, and the price still hovers around $100.&nbsp; That’s because the market likes stability.&nbsp; And so those additions have created that kind of breathing space for the prices on &#8212; at the pump to start &#8212; just to start to come down.</p>



<p>So we’ll see where it goes.&nbsp; The discussions both at the GCC and bilaterally with the Saudis, again, were very constructive when it comes to energy.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be watching.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on the &#8212; so I noticed, on the President&#8217;s schedule the last two days, there have been no public events.&nbsp; Is he resting after the large international trips (inaudible)?<br><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Well, the President has been busy.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let Karine speak to the President&#8217;s schedule.&nbsp; But the President has been quite busy.&nbsp; Just because you don&#8217;t see something necessarily on the public schedule doesn&#8217;t mean that there&#8217;s not a lot of work going on.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; The gentleman in the back there.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; The Senate Foreign Relations Committee just reported out the resolution regarding the admission of Finland and Sweden to NATO, and they&#8217;re likely to do that before August recess.&nbsp; Can you speak to the importance of getting that done before the August recess?<br><br>And also, is there any sort of message regarding the, I think it was 18, House Republicans who last night voted against a non-binding resolution on the admission of the countries to NATO?</p>



<p><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I would just tell you that we obviously want to see Finland and Sweden brought into the Alliance as soon as possible.&nbsp; And so we look forward to congressional action that will allow that to be the case, at least from the United States perspective.&nbsp; As you know, every Ally has to ratify; we&#8217;re not the only ones.&nbsp; But certainly, we believe it&#8217;s in our interest and it&#8217;s in the Alliance&#8217;s interest for accession of those two countries to happen as soon as possible.<br><br>These are modern militaries, militaries that we know well.&nbsp; We exercise with them, operate with them; I myself did a long, long time ago.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve got incredible modern capabilities that will absolutely help bolster NATO&#8217;s defensive capabilities and contribute significantly to the Article 5 commitment that we all sign into when we come into the Alliance.<br><br>So we&#8217;re looking forward to it. &nbsp;We urge Congress to act as quickly as possible.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Steven, last question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; John, I wanted to give you a chance to respond to the families’ reaction to the hostage and wrongful detention executive order.</p>



<p><br>The group Bring Our Families Home issued a statement saying that the order is simply the White House “taking executive action to direct itself to follow existing law.”&nbsp; The group says the President should agree to take a meeting with the families.&nbsp; Will he do that?<br><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything on the President&#8217;s schedule specifically to speak to you today.&nbsp; I would remind that the whole national security team remains committed to staying in touch with these families, and we have routine discussions with them &#8212; with all of them.&nbsp; Our Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs is in regular contact with them.<br><br>We know that they&#8217;re suffering.&nbsp; We know they&#8217;re scared.&nbsp; And we know they&#8217;re anxious.&nbsp; And we know that they want their loved ones back home, and the President wants that too.&nbsp; And this executive order will give us some additional tools in the toolbox.<br><br>Is it going to solve every problem?&nbsp; Nope.&nbsp; Every case is specific, and you got to look at each one individually and figure out what the best way is forward.&nbsp; Sometimes turning up the heat publicly is the answer.&nbsp; Sometimes turning it down is the answer.&nbsp; Sometimes, you know, sanctions could be useful. Sometimes not.<br><br>Each one is in- &#8212; each one is individual and each one is different.&nbsp; Because, you know what? &nbsp;To those families, it’s individual as well.&nbsp; They just want their loved ones home, and the President wants that too.<br><br>This EO is a useful extra set of tools that we&#8217;ll have in our toolbox to help bring that about.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, John.<br><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Appreciate it, everybody.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, John.<br><br>MR. KIRBY:&nbsp; Yes, ma’am.&nbsp; Bye, bye.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;All right.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I have a few things at the top.&nbsp; Speaking of climate change: So we are closely monitoring extreme heat conditions impacting much of Europe as well as the extreme heat impacting the more than 100 million Americans who are struggling with extreme heat conditions here at home just this week alone.<br><br>The impacts of extreme weather are intensifying across the globe, including here in the United States.&nbsp; No one is immune from climate change.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why the President has been rallying the world to take the decisive action needed in this decade to tackle the climate change &#8212; the climate crisis.<br><br>It&#8217;s also why the President is committed to taking aggressive action to tackle climate change and made clear if the Senate won&#8217;t act, he will.&nbsp; In fact, as many you &#8212; as many of you have seen already today, the President will travel to Somerset, Massachusetts, tomorrow.&nbsp; While there, he will visit the future site of a manufacturing plant located at a former coal-fired power plant that will produce transmission cables for Massachusetts’s booming offshore wind industry.<br><br>The President will underscore the historic clean energy investments his Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will make in Massachusetts and announce additional actions he will take to tackle the climate crisis and secure a clean energy future.<br><br>The President ran on fighting the unprecedented economic and national security threat of climate change.&nbsp; And he has take- &#8212; he has been taking decisive action to do so since taking office.&nbsp; Tomorrow&#8217;s action will be a continuation of that work.<br><br>And I have two things, because I know folks in the room asked this question &#8212; two different questions yesterday, and I said I would get back to them.<br><br>I think, Eugene, you had a question about ACLU.&nbsp; The Department of Homeland Security is committed to complying with the law and respects the privacy and civil liberties of individuals.&nbsp; DHS employs various forms of technology to undertake the &#8212; its mission.&nbsp; This includes using tools to better investigate threats to infrastructure; traffickers of deadly opioids on the dark web; and to identify those involved in cross-border, transnational criminal organizations and terrorist activities.<br><br>And again, as I said to you yesterday, for further information, I would point you to DHS.<br><br>And I just have one more for the Marburg virus disease in Ghana.&nbsp; I have an answer &#8212; came back with an answer for you &#8212; I think this is from Simon.<br><br>Ghana reported two fatal cases of suspected hemor- &#8212; hemorrhagic fever in the Ashanti region of Ghana in early July, which tested positive for Marburg virus disease almost two weeks after presentation.&nbsp; These were the first cases ever reported from the country.&nbsp; U.S. agencies, our embassy in Accra have been in close collaboration with Ghana Health Services, World Health Organization.&nbsp; And other partners have engaged with public health working group in the country to share information.<br><br>The government of Ghana has not made any request of us, but we stand ready to assist however we can.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s that answer there for you all.<br><br>Will, you want to kick us off?</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got two things.&nbsp; It doesn’t look like we&#8217;ll be getting a climate emergency announcement this week.&nbsp; I want to make sure that’s still on the table.&nbsp; And I wanted to ask if the White House has any concerns that the President might be relying on executive action too much.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the fi- &#8212; to answer your first question &#8212; look, one thing that I just want to step back and just lay out for all of you: When &#8212; the President was one of the first in Congress, when he was a senator, to ring the bell &#8212; the alarm bell on climate crisis.<br><br>So this is an issue that has been front of mind for him.&nbsp; This is an issue that has been &#8212; when it comes to the climate crisis &#8212; a priority.&nbsp; And taking action is something that he said he will do if Congress won&#8217;t.&nbsp; And he has been taking action, as we have &#8212; as I had just stated in my opening remarks, since he&#8217;s taken &#8212; since he taken office.<br><br>So he&#8217;s going to take, as I said, additional climate actions in that vein tomorrow, and he&#8217;s going to continue.&nbsp; He’s&nbsp; not going to just stop with the actions of tomorrow.&nbsp; But I would not plan a announcement this week on national climate emergency.<br><br>Again, everything is on the table.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just not going to be this week on that decision.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On another matter, Senator Manchin is rejecting the global tax deal that Secretary Yellen negotiated with, like, 100-plus countries.&nbsp; What will happen if those countries move ahead with the deal and the U.S. doesn’t?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I have a couple of things on &#8212; a couple of points on that that I wanted to share with all of you.<br><br>So we remain committed to finalizing a global minimum tax.&nbsp; It will level the playing field, as you all know, for U.S. businesses, decrease incentives to move jobs offshore, and close loopholes that <s>cooperations</s> [corporations] have used to shift profits overseas, which will benefit American workers, businesses, taxpayers, and middle-class families.<br><br>So that is critical and that is important and why we need to do this.&nbsp; But this significant incentive for America to come into &#8212; it is &#8212; it&#8217;s significant for America to come into compliance.<br><br>Right now, other countries are pursuing legislation that would put them in compliance.&nbsp; If they act and America doesn&#8217;t, we&#8217;ll lose out on tax revenues that we could use to invest in the strength of our economy and the middle class.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s too important for our economic strength and competitiveness to finalize this agreement.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll continue to work always to get it done.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s going to be our focus, as well.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Ashley.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Two related questions on climate.&nbsp; First, why did the White House decide that tomorrow is not the day to declare a climate emergency?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, what I can say is the President is going to do everything that he can to take action.&nbsp; Again, climate &#8212; climate crisis &#8212; taking climate action is critical, it&#8217;s important.&nbsp; You heard Kirby talk about our national security &#8212; how it threatens our national security, how it threatens the economy.&nbsp; And what the President wants to continue to do is make sure that we&#8217;re lowering energy costs for the American family.&nbsp; Again, everything is on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to go into private discussions that &#8212; policy discussions or get ahead of the President at this time.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to make some announcements. &nbsp;Today, what I can say: This climate emergency is not going to happen tomorrow.&nbsp; But we have &#8212; we have &#8212; we still have it on the table.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll &#8212; I don&#8217;t have a circle &#8212; a date circled on the calendar.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If and when it does happen, can you talk a little bit about what specific tools it would then give the administration and what specifically you would use it for and do?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, one thing that I just wanted to make clear, because some folks were asking about &#8212; about the abortion piece &#8212; the emergency abortion piece.&nbsp; So I just wanted to just lay out: So, look, we haven&#8217;t ruled out a public health emergency, as I just laid out.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re just &#8212; we&#8217;re just still moving forward with &#8212; with the options that we potentially have in front of us; everything is on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But declaring a public health emergency is very different from declaring a climate emergency.&nbsp; Each unlocks a different set of authorities and a different pot of funding.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s one way to think about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, one of the reasons I wanted to bring this up, because we&#8217;ve heard this &#8212; and so comparing one against the other as a reflection of priority would not be &#8212; would not be accurate.&nbsp; But again, it&#8217;s on the table.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t made &#8212; we haven&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything to announce at this time.&nbsp; And, you know, the President will speak more on what it is &#8212; how he wants to move forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But on those differences, is it a bigger pot of money it unlocks?&nbsp; I know that was one of the concerns the administration had about the public health emergency.&nbsp; And are there any other specifics you can share about how you could use a climate declaration?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have any specifics or anything to move further on what I just stated.&nbsp; But you&#8217;re right: When Jen Klein was here, just almost two weeks ago, she talked about how in the pot of money for the &#8212; for the abortion pieces, there was just tens of thousands of dollars there.&nbsp; So we &#8212; there was some feeling that we didn&#8217;t know exactly how that would work.&nbsp; But she did state that it would be still on the table and that we were still thinking through it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as far as the &#8212; what&#8217;s on the &#8212; in the climate &#8212; the climate side, I just don&#8217;t have more information to share.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there any downsides to declaring a climate national emergency?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right now, like I said, it&#8217;s not on the table for this week.&nbsp; We&#8217;re still considering it.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have the upside or the downsides of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you can imagine, and I have said, this is an important priority when it comes to getting to clean energy, when it comes to dealing with climate crisis, when it comes to taking action.&nbsp; So the President is going to continue to make sure he&#8217;s doing everything that he can to deal &#8212; of the threats of climate change.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have specifics on the pros and the cons, but it is still on the table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When you talk about actions for tomorrow, should we assume that he’ll be signing executive actions to announce tomorrow?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Jeff, I just don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; Again, he&#8217;s going to make some announcement &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will there be a briefing call on this later to explain what he’s doing? &nbsp;Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; There &#8212; there might be.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have one to announce.&nbsp; We normally do.&nbsp; To your point, we usually have background calls when we&#8217;re ready, and we usually invite all of you.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have one to announce.&nbsp; There might be in the next couple of hours.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have anything to share at this point.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he been involved in these meetings today?&nbsp; Or what exactly has he been doing yesterday and today?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So he&#8217;s been in meetings.&nbsp; I was &#8212; I was called &#8212; I was scheduled to meet with him today in the Oval Office.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s been meeting with his senior staff.&nbsp; He&#8217;s been meeting with staff.&nbsp; I think some of you may have seen him when &#8212; when the First Lady of Ukraine was vidi- &#8212; visiting with our First Lady.&nbsp; I believe you saw &#8212; you saw him very briefly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So he&#8217;s just been very busy dealing with the issues of the American people and meeting with his staff and senior staff the last two days.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick one on the climate emergency and public health emergency.&nbsp; How concerned is the White House it may end up, sort of, angering female voters if it does sort of go ahead and announce a climate emergency ahead of a public health emergency, considering we haven’t seen such an announcement after Roe?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that why maybe the timing &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; has been moved?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I wouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t look into &#8212; I wouldn&#8217;t make that into an issue.&nbsp; I &#8212; both of &#8212; both of those things are still on the table.&nbsp; We just haven&#8217;t announced them or made a decision yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I just laid out what the difference &#8212; the difference is between when you look at a public health emergency on the abortion side, when you look at public health emergency &#8212; more so on the abortion side, but the difference between the two.&nbsp; We just don&#8217;t &#8212; they&#8217;re both on the table.&nbsp; We just don&#8217;t &#8212; haven’t made an announcement on that yet.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the President did say that he&#8217;s asked his administration to see if he has the authority to declare a public health emergency.&nbsp; Is there, sort of, any update on &#8212; into that work to see if he has the authority, ultimately, to declare something like that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, we&#8217;re looking at all options.&nbsp; Everything is on the table.&nbsp; We just haven&#8217;t made a decision on this yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Karen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The mayors of New York City and D.C. are calling for more federal resources to assist with asylum seekers who are being bused to those cities from Texas and Arizona.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve had thousands of people arriving over the past couple of weeks.&nbsp; Mayor Bowser, here in D.C., said that these people are being “tricked.”&nbsp; What federal resources is the White House preparing, if any, to deliver to these cities and other cities that are now dealing with an increase of asylum seekers?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I can tell you, Karen, that we have been in touch with both of their &#8212; both of their administrations, both of their offices.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to look into their requests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just &#8212; I don&#8217;t have further than that to share.&nbsp; But we have been in touch with Mayor Bowser&#8217;s office and we have been in touch with Mayor Adams’s office.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there could be resources that can be given to &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right now, I can tell you that FEMA is the lead agency on this.&nbsp; And so I would &#8212; I would point you to them on &#8212; on any more information or details that they can provide.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the other end of it, some advocates say that the governors of these states are using these migrants as pawns.&nbsp; Has the White House reached out to those governors and said, “Don&#8217;t send these people to these cities on the East Coast”?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know, we&#8217;re in constant communication and contact with governors just across the country.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything specific to that &#8212; you know, the specific on migrants being shipped to other states.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a message from the White House about &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what they should be doing or not doing?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think we &#8212; we have &#8212; this has come up before, I believe, a couple of months ago.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; we believe it&#8217;s shameful that &#8212; that some governors are using migrants as a political tool, as a political play, when we should be making sure that we&#8217;re doing everything that we can to help &#8212; to help folks who are coming into this process in a legal way and making sure that, you know, we do this in a &#8212; in a safe &#8212; in a safe way and a respectful way.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s shameful that that is happening.</p>



<p><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The Secret Service now says that they are unable to retrieve any more emails from agents from January 5th and 6th of last year.&nbsp; Does the President believe that it&#8217;s acceptable for a law enforcement agency &#8212; a federal law enforcement agency to simply lose such critical communications that are important to an investigation?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I appreciate the question.&nbsp; This is not something that I can speak about from here.&nbsp; This is some- &#8212; this is a question that has to go to the &#8212; any information or details has to go to the U.S. Secret Service.&nbsp; I just can&#8217;t speak from that from here because it&#8217;s a &#8212; it is a active investigation.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand, but this is something the Secret Service is saying publicly that they just &#8212; you know, they didn&#8217;t back up their emails and texts properly, apparently.&nbsp; I’m just wondering: This is the agency that is tasked with protecting the President of the United States.&nbsp; Is he concerned about some gaps in the mission there?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I understand the question, and I hear the question, but we just can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t respond to it from here, from the podium.&nbsp; It’s an active investigation.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, has the President been &#8212; I know you mentioned Marburg’s disease at the top.&nbsp; Has the President been briefed on the situation with Marburg’s disease?&nbsp; And is the White House preparing any additional action?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re ready.&nbsp; We have not gotten, as I stated, any &#8212; any ask for assistance, and we are ready to assist when asked.<br><br>I would have to check in with the team to see if the President has been briefed about this particular issue.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Josh.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say what role the ongoing reconciliation talks played in the climate decision?&nbsp; For instance, is the climate emergency off the table because you&#8217;re worried it will upend the applecart in the Senate with Senator Manchin or Sen- &#8212; or others by going sort of too big, too fast?&nbsp; Can you talk about what role the (inaudible) are between what to do now on climate and what you&#8217;re still hoping to get out of Congress?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So when it comes to what&#8217;s happening on the Senate with reconciliation, I will not negotiate in public or speak to any private conversation.&nbsp; I can tell you that our teams are in regular contact with Senator Manchin and other members in the Sen- &#8212; in the Senate and in Congress, just as we do on a &#8212; on a constant &#8212; in a constant way and a constant basis.<br><br>I will say that, as I mentioned, I wouldn&#8217;t expect an announcement this week on the emergency &#8212; on the climate change emergency.&nbsp; But what I will say is that it is still on the table.&nbsp; We have not made a decision yet.<br><br>Again, this is &#8212; what we&#8217;re seeing &#8212; this action that we&#8217;re going to hear about from the President tomorrow, this is part of multiple actions that the President has already taken from the moment that he walked into office.&nbsp; This is urgent to him.&nbsp; He called the climate crisis one of the four major crisis that he had to &#8212; that he was dealing with once walking into the administration.<br><br>Again, we&#8217;re talking about national security, we&#8217;re talking about lowering energy costs, we&#8217;re talking about threats to our economy.&nbsp; All of these things are critical.&nbsp; All of these things are important.&nbsp; And he will be &#8212; continue to be steadfast in focusing on the climate crisis.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And did he not do these things &#8212; the executive actions &#8212; previously because he hoped that he would get it in the legislation?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, the President &#8212; and you&#8217;ve heard me say this, you&#8217;ve heard him say this: When it comes to the climate change provisions in reconciliation, of course he wants to see it in the rec- &#8212; in the bill.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I guess, “Why not both?” is my question.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Pardon me?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not both?&nbsp; Like, why did he hold off &#8212; he seems to have held off doing executive action waiting for the bill.&nbsp; Could he have not done &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; look, we &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; walk and chew gum?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think we could still walk and chew gum.&nbsp; No one says &#8212; again, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp; You know, the &#8212; the process in the Senate is &#8212; is happening.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to speak to that in public.<br><br>Look, this was an opportunity.&nbsp; The President has said that he was going to take action.&nbsp; He said &#8212; you know, he&#8217;s always said if they &#8212; the Senate won&#8217;t, he will take action.&nbsp; He is just taking another step.&nbsp; This is not the final step.&nbsp; This is part of a process that he &#8212; that you have seen him take, especially when it comes to the climate crisis.<br><br>And so, you know, I wouldn&#8217;t see this as an either/or. &nbsp;I would see this as part of what he has been trying to continue to do in playing our part in the &#8212; in the climate crisis and dealing with climate change.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, can you offer any update on the deliberations on student loan relief and what kind of timeline, if any, there is on that?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you.&nbsp; I know this is a question that comes up often in the briefing room.&nbsp; This is something that is clearly important to the President, and so as soon as we have anything to preview, we will make sure that happens.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two on China.&nbsp; China is warning that relations with the U.S. will be damaged if Speaker Pelosi visits Taiwan.&nbsp; Do you have any comment on the reports that she&#8217;s going?&nbsp; And has the White House had any communication with her office about &#8212; about this (inaudible)?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m just not going to comment on travel that the Speaker&#8217;s office itself has not announced, I believe.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the last that I&#8217;ve heard before I came to the podium.&nbsp; So we will refer you to the congressional delegation on their travel.</p>



<p>I will reiterate that the United States remain committed to our One China policy, which is set forth in the Taiwan Relations Act, as you know, the Three Joint Communiqués, and the Six Assurances.</p>



<p>This has been a consistent U.S. position for decades across multiple administrations.&nbsp; This is nothing new here.&nbsp; U.S. support for Taiwan remains rock solid, principled, and bipartisan, and is in line with our One China policy and longstanding U.S. commitments.&nbsp; But from what I understand, there has been no announcement, and I&#8217;m certainly not going to comment on her travels at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there any update on when President Biden may speak or have a phone call with President Xi?&nbsp; I know that&#8217;s been talked about.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; As you know, they spoke recently &#8212; not too long ago.&nbsp; We &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said this before &#8212; we are &#8212; we are keeping the lines of communication, of dialogue, open.&nbsp; There has been staff-to-staff communications over the last several months since the last time the President spoke to President Xi.</p>



<p>I just &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview on the next conversation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;re at your time, if you need be going. &nbsp;Do you want to do one more?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp; I&#8217;m at my time.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go around.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Mike.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, a question on the Respect for Marriage Act.&nbsp; The President, after Dobbs, said he believed the right to privacy is at risk.&nbsp; Obviously, you, yesterday, said that the administration supports this bill.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re seeing some Republican lawmakers in the House come out in favor of it, and McConnell says he won&#8217;t preview his vote on it until it reaches the Senate.&nbsp; So do you believe that Senate passage is actually in reach?&nbsp; And what is the President doing to get it closer to that?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, as you know, and I said this yesterday, this is an issue when it comes to the right to marry, loving who you want to love.&nbsp; The President has been supportive of that for many, many years, clearly before he was the President, and he has been very vocal.</p>



<p>And so, first, I want to say that he strongly supports the bill, as you heard me say yesterday.&nbsp; He&#8217;s grateful that this has bipartisan support in the House, as we&#8217;re seeing it.</p>



<p>Right now there is a SAP, a statement of administration policy, that we sent out to show &#8212; continue to show our support.</p>



<p>Look, the President is always going to continue to speak on equal rights, especially as it relates to this particular piece on LGBTQ rights, equ- &#8212; marriage equality.&nbsp; This is not something that he will not stop talking about.&nbsp; He will make sure he is very clear.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a priority for him, hence why we did the SAP.</p>



<p>But I do want to take a step back, because I know that this has bipartisan support.&nbsp; You know, the exact reason for why this bill is being voted on is because of Republicans&#8217; assault on the recognition of Americans&#8217; right to privacy, which has been recognized and upheld over decades by judges appointed by a wide range of presidents that puts us here.&nbsp; That is why the House, you know, vote &#8212; had to vote &#8212; vote for this bill, because &#8212; so that we can protect people&#8217;s rights because of what we have seen these past several weeks.</p>



<p>The judges they&#8217;ve endorsed, for example; the state legislators they work with &#8212; they have said the quiet part out loud, which is they are coming for the right to marriage.</p>



<p>Justice Thomas &#8212; as I&#8217;ve said many times before, right here in this briefing room; as the President has said &#8212; explicitly in his concurring opinion said this.&nbsp; He was very clear about this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we need this legislation and urge Congress to move as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something the vast majority of country supports &#8212; of the country supports, just like they support restoring Roe, which is a priority for the President; stopping a national ban that we&#8217;re seeing from the ultra-MAGA who wants to make sure &#8212; who wants to make a national ban when it comes to abortion.</p>



<p>So, we have to keep &#8212; continue to speak out.&nbsp; And the President is going to continue to urge for Congress to act.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just want to follow up on that question.&nbsp; Is the White House speaking to Republicans about this bill &#8212; Senate Republicans about the bill?&nbsp; Because we are starting to see even some of the Republicans in the Senate say they would be interested in passing the bill if came to them.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; And so we support that.&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is something that we are grateful to see.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you guys behind the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We are grateful to see.&nbsp; Look, we have multiple conversations with members in Congress, whether it&#8217;s a Republican or a Democrat.&nbsp; This is something our office does pretty regularly &#8212; the Office of Legislative Affairs.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything specific to share on the different conversations on this.&nbsp; But certainly we are in constant touch with members of Congress and their staff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what do you have to say to climate activists who feel like President Biden isn&#8217;t being urgent enough?&nbsp; So, you know, 20 percent of the U.S. population, about 60 million people, are going to see temperatures above 100 degrees Fahrenheit over the next few days.&nbsp; They&#8217;re constantly seeing how the Supreme Court is taking some of the power away from the agencies to do that work.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re &#8212; they want to see President Biden do more and do it quick &#8212; and do it quickly.&nbsp; We talked about him possibly doing this emergency declaration and that not being on the table. &nbsp;Why not just do it if it is so urgent, as you guys said?&nbsp; What is the hold-up?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, again, he is going to take an action tomorrow.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; That’s why we&#8217;re going to Massachusetts.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; Hopefully we&#8217;ll have a background call, like we normally do, to share specifically what that looks like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, I would disagree with the characterization of your question.&nbsp; The President has been one of the first &#8212; again, first folks and member &#8212; amongst the members on the Hill when he was senator to ring the bell &#8212; to ring the alarm bell on climate crisis.</p>



<p>He has been &#8212; he has taken action.&nbsp; He has been &#8212; you know, he has said, when he walked in, that the climate crisis was one of the crises &#8212; the four crises that he had to deal with.</p>



<p>He has taken action to meet the goals &#8212; very &#8212; very big goals, if you will &#8212; that he wants this country, our country to make in order to deal with the climate &#8212; climate crisis.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll continue to do that.</p>



<p>And so, again, this is one step.&nbsp; This is a continuing step of other steps that he has taken this past year, and we&#8217;ll see more actions from this President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You&#8217;re welcome.</p>



<p>4:31 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the U.S.-Africa Leaders&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/20/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-u-s-africa-leaders-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57881</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I look forward to hosting leaders from across the African continent in Washington, DC on December 13-15, 2022, for the U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit.&#160; The Summit will demonstrate the United States’ enduring commitment to Africa, and will underscore the importance of U.S.-Africa relations and increased cooperation on shared global priorities. The U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit will build&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I look forward to hosting leaders from across the African continent in Washington, DC on December 13-15, 2022, for the U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit.&nbsp; The Summit will demonstrate the United States’ enduring commitment to Africa, and will underscore the importance of U.S.-Africa relations and increased cooperation on shared global priorities.</p>



<p>The U.S.-Africa Leaders Summit will build on our shared values to better foster new economic engagement; reinforce the U.S.-Africa commitment to democracy and human rights; mitigate the impact of COVID-19 and of future pandemics; work collaboratively to strengthen regional and global health; promote food security; advance peace and security; respond to the climate crisis; and amplify diaspora ties.</p>



<p>I look forward to working with African governments, civil society, diaspora communities across the United States, and the private sector to continue strengthening our shared vision for the future of U.S.-Africa relations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on FDA and CDC Authorizing Novavax’s COVID-&#8288;19 Vaccine for&#160;Adults</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-fda-and-cdc-authorizing-novavaxs-covid-19-vaccine-for-adults/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 23:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57884</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today is another step forward in our nation’s fight against the virus. Following an independent scientific review by the Food and Drug Administration last week and today by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Novavax’s protein-based COVID-19 vaccine for adults has been authorized. We now have four safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines available to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today is another step forward in our nation’s fight against the virus. Following an independent scientific review by the Food and Drug Administration last week and today by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Novavax’s protein-based COVID-19 vaccine for adults has been authorized. We now have four safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines available to protect Americans against serious illness, hospitalizations, and death.<br> <br>When I took office, my Administration took decisive action to fix a broken COVID-19 response and stand up a historic vaccination program that has gotten over 260 million Americans at least their first shot, and nearly 110 million people a booster shot. This unprecedented effort has already saved over 2 million American lives, but more people need to roll up their sleeves, particularly as we confront BA.5.<br> <br>The science and data are clear: vaccines continue to protect people from serious illness, hospitalizations, and death—and with BA.5 increasing infections, it is essential that people get themselves and their kids vaccinated and stay up to date on their COVID-19 vaccinations. I encourage everyone to get their booster if they are eligible. If you’re age 50 or older, or a moderately or severely immunocompromised individual, and haven’t gotten a vaccine shot this year—you should get one right away. It is free, easy, and could save your life.<br> <br>Over the past 18 months, my Administration has left no stone unturned to ensure Americans have easy and convenient access to lifesaving tools, including vaccines, treatments, tests and more. These tools work even in the face of BA.5—they protect people, keep people out of the hospital, and save lives. While we know COVID-19 isn’t over, we can manage this moment and continue to minimize COVID-19’s impact on our daily lives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s New Executive Order to Bolster Efforts to Bring Home American Hostages and Wrongful&#160;Detainees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/background-press-call-on-president-bidens-new-executive-order-to-bolster-efforts-to-bring-home-american-hostages-and-wrongful-detainees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57840</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference(July 18, 2022) MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thank you all for joining this evening’s NSC background call on President Biden’s new executive order to bolster efforts to bring home American hostages and wrongful detainees. As a reminder of the ground rules, this call is on background attributable to “senior administration officials” and embargoed until&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference<br>(July 18, 2022)</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thank you all for joining this evening’s NSC background call on President Biden’s new executive order to bolster efforts to bring home American hostages and wrongful detainees.</p>



<p>As a reminder of the ground rules, this call is on background attributable to “senior administration officials” and embargoed until tomorrow morning, Tuesday, July 19th at 9:00 a.m. Eastern Standard Time.</p>



<p>For your awareness but not for your reporting, today’s speakers are [senior administration official], [senior administration official], and [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I’ll turn it over to [senior administration official], our first speaker.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much, [moderator], and thanks to everyone for joining this call.&nbsp; We are eager to share how the Biden-Harris administration is expanding the toolkit that the U.S. government uses to help bring home American hostages and wrongful detainees.</p>



<p>Foreign states that engage in the practice of wrongful detention, whether it’s for political leverage or to seek concessions from the United States, threaten the integrity of the international political system and, moreover, the safety of US nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; And the same can be said of terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or other nefarious gains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. government maintains its unwavering commitment to bringing home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained.</p>



<p>And so that is why we are proud to announce that tomorrow, President Biden will be signing a new executive order that will provide new and expanded tools to help bring our citizens home and impose costs on the culprits as well as provide greater transparency regarding the risks.</p>



<p>The new executive order is entitled “Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained U.S. Nationals Home.”&nbsp; It reaffirms the fundamental commitment of the President, of the administration to bring home those Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>The executive order draws on the 2020 Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage Taking Accountability Act.&nbsp; And just as the name itself suggests, that law is a credit to the perseverance of the Levinson family and others who have turned their family’s extraordinary hardships into constructive and meaningful action.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Frankly, all of us who work on these issues are blown away by the courage and the leadership the families in these awful circumstances show in an effort to make our government and all of us better in resolving these cases.</p>



<p>The new EO builds on those efforts and the efforts of others who have worked diligently to bring the Levinson Act to fruition, and it expands and strengthens the government’s toolkit in key ways.</p>



<p>For example, this EO reinforces U.S. government efforts to support the families of Americans wrongfully detained or held hostage overseas by directing parts of the federal government to bolster their engagement with such families and their sharing of relevant information, including intelligence information, with families regarding their loved ones’ status and the government’s efforts to secure their release or their return.</p>



<p>The new executive order also authorizes departments and agencies to impose costs and consequences on those who are involved.&nbsp; That includes financial sanctions and it includes visa bans, and it can apply whether the individual subject to those costs and consequences has acted on behalf of a state or a terrorist network or some other non-state actor.</p>



<p>This EO reflects the administration’s commitment not just to the issues generally, but to the families in particular, and it has been informed by the government’s regular engagements with them and other stakeholders who have and continue to undertake important, constructive advocacy efforts on behalf of their loved ones.</p>



<p>President Biden and those across the administration will now draw on this EO to advance our efforts, and we hope to do so in active conversation with family members and outside stakeholders.</p>



<p>In addition to the EO, tomorrow, the Biden-Harris administration will introduce a new risk indicator, the “D” for wrongful detention indicator, to the State Department’s travel advisories, which exist for all countries around the world to warn Americans of risks they may face in traveling to particular destinations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This new “D” indicator will, in particular, inform American travelers of the risk of wrongful detention by a foreign government, will highlight the elevated risk that Americans face in particular countries, and provide Americans with comprehensive safety and security information to use in making informed travel decisions.</p>



<p>Its transparency will also show to governments that engage in this sort of reprehensible practice, and indeed to the world, our commitment to calling out this sort of behavior.</p>



<p>The “D” indicator joins the existing “K” for kidnapping indicator that covers the risk of kidnapping and hostage taking by non-state actors as well as a range of other existing risk indicators.</p>



<p>State Department travel advisories are continuously revised and updated based on a comprehensive review of all available safety information and ongoing developments.</p>



<p>I should emphasize here that this work to punish those responsible for this sort of behavior, to increase transparency, to share risks about hostage taking and wrongful detention, all of this is in addition to the very hard, very important work that we do with the NSC, with State Department, the FBI, and other colleagues across the government every day to resolve particular hostage and wrongful detainee matters.&nbsp; This isn’t a substitute; it’s in addition.&nbsp; And it is a way to increase transparency through the indicator, impose costs through the executive order, and overall, try to prevent the next set of families going through this horrible ordeal.</p>



<p>I’ll now turn things over to our next speaker, [senior administration official], for additional context on the new EO and its implementation.&nbsp; And then you’ll hear from our final speaker, [senior administration official], for additional information on the update to our travel advisories.</p>



<p>Over to you, [senior administration official.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official], thanks a lot for that introduction, and thanks for bringing up this topic and also for convening this call.&nbsp; I know you’ve been at this since 2015 trying to work this problem set.&nbsp; So, grateful that you’re able to bring us all together to talk about this.</p>



<p>Folks, the President is once again demonstrating his commitment to bring home U.S. nationals held hostage and wrongfully detained abroad.&nbsp; And we continue to work closely across the administration to realize this prioritized commitment.</p>



<p>The EO is critical and gives the U.S. government expanded tools to help get Americans home, including specific authority to impose sanctions on those responsible for or complicit in wrongful detentions or hostage taking of U.S. persons overseas, regardless of whether the perpetrator is a terrorist or a state actor.</p>



<p>On the new sanctions authority for which the State Department will have the lead for developing targets, our goal is to bring folks home.&nbsp; So we use the sanctions authority with a primary focus on helping to secure a loved one’s release.</p>



<p>Now, using sanctions may not always help secure someone’s release, so we will therefore be judicious and strategic in our use of this authority.&nbsp; But the families of those held know their loved one’s case best and we intend to hear from them, hear their good ideas, and listen to their recommendations.</p>



<p>At this point, I’d like to turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everybody, for dialing in today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to take this opportunity to tell you about the parallel efforts to demonstrate our focus on this issue that [senior administration official] mentioned.&nbsp; And that is that tomorrow we’re introducing a new risk indicator, the “D” indicator, to the State Department’s travel advisories to inform U.S. travelers of the risk of wrongful detention by a foreign government.&nbsp; We’re making this change to highlight the elevated risk of wrongful detention in particular countries whose governments have engaged in that practice.</p>



<p>We’re committed to providing U.S. citizens with comprehensive safety and security information about foreign countries so they can make informed travel decisions before they head overseas.</p>



<p>The United States opposes wrongful detention and the practice of using individuals as political bargaining chips everywhere.&nbsp; These practices we know represent a threat to the safety of all U.S. citizens traveling and living abroad.</p>



<p>I’m sure you’ve all heard us say many times that we as a department have no higher priority than the safety and the security of U.S. citizens overseas.&nbsp; We definitely take extremely seriously our commitment to inform U.S. citizens living and traveling abroad of potential risks.&nbsp; And our travel advice is apolitical, fact-based, and transparent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As [senior administration official] noted, we issue travel advisories for every country around the world offering standardized levels of advice based on established risk factors.&nbsp; Our advisories are based on the risk factors that include things like crime, for which we use a “C” indicator; health, for which we use an “H”; and [senior administration official] also mentioned the “K” indicator for kidnapping or hostage taking.</p>



<p>We’re also constantly reviewing our travel advisory system in an effort to provide the most accurate and transparent information for U.S. citizens traveling overseas.</p>



<p>We consider a lot of factors in determining which indicators to incorporate into the travel advisory for each country.&nbsp; The “D” indicator may be assigned to a given country following a department determination that the detention of a U.S. national is wrongful.&nbsp; The indicator will consider the number of cases of wrongful detentions of U.S. nationals in any given country to help determine the appropriate travel advisory level.</p>



<p>We routinely update our travel advisories for all countries based on that ongoing comprehensive review of all available safety information and ongoing developments.</p>



<p>So tomorrow, the following countries will receive the “D”-risk indicator: Burma, the People’s Republic of China, Iran, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, Russia, and Venezuela.</p>



<p>So on behalf of the State Department, I want to reiterate our commitment to bringing wrongfully held U.S. nationals home and to working closely with their families to do so.</p>



<p>My colleagues and I in Consular Affairs have a really strong partnership with our colleagues in SPEHA, with [senior administration official]’s team, and we remain in regular contact with the families of those held hostage or wrongfully detained.</p>



<p>We’re really proud of our partnership with SPEHA and with the White House, and we continue to work together to ensure we’re communicating and sharing information in a way that’s useful to the families and to the American public.</p>



<p>So I’ll stop there, and I look forward to answering your questions.&nbsp; Over.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; With that, I’ll turn it back over to the moderator for question-and-answer.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking the call.&nbsp; A couple questions.&nbsp; Can we expect any sanctions announcements tomorrow along with the rollout of the executive order?&nbsp; And if so, on whom?&nbsp; How long has this executive order been in process, given the Levinson Act has been passed for quite a bit of time now?</p>



<p>And then, tangentially, there’s a number of families of detainees and hostages who are coming to D.C. this week.&nbsp; Will the President meet with any or all of them?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I’m happy to take a first stab.&nbsp; My colleagues may have thoughts as well.&nbsp; But thank you, Jennifer, for the good questions.</p>



<p>So I’ll take them in order.&nbsp; There won’t be particular sanctions targets announced tomorrow with the EO, but this is a process that we want and need to be sustainable for weeks and months to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In other contexts &#8212; and I’m thinking of the human rights context in particular &#8212; the development of those sorts of packages has really generated constructive, productive collaboration, not just across the federal government &#8212; and, of course, this is, by definition, a new authority and we’ll work to build the backing to utilize it &#8212; but also between government and those outside it, with a robust dialogue on the potential targets of sanctions and the information that the government at least should consider in assessing those targets.</p>



<p>So we hope that this is a project that not only gets attention and focus within the government, as it will with the President’s direction coming tomorrow, but also with so many who work so hard on these issues outside government as well.</p>



<p>The executive order has been in development for a while now.&nbsp; Bringing something to the President’s desk obviously takes care and consideration by experts across the government.&nbsp; We also have had a number of steps that have been critical to implementing the Levinson Act, which was an important step forward through legislation.&nbsp; And that has included the use of the statutorily-defined elements for wrongful detention cases, which [senior administration official] may want to say a word about, but which have been used now in an important process that runs within the State Department.</p>



<p>Finally, I can’t speak to the President’s particular schedule, but I can speak to his commitment to these issues and to the priority he places on bringing home Americans held hostage abroad and wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>This executive order is, of course, one significant piece of that but it comes in the wake of efforts to &#8212; and successful efforts &#8212; to bring home Americans from countries really across the globe: Haiti, Afghanistan, Venezuela, Burma, and elsewhere, during the course of this administration.&nbsp; And he’ll continue to track these matters at the highest levels, including with the direct engagement of National Security Council staff leadership, State Department leadership, and others.</p>



<p>But let me see if my colleagues want to chime in on any of those three questions, as well, please.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp; And, Jen, I guess the only thing I would say is that, you know, [senior administration official] indicated that a lot of work goes into this to make sure that it’s pretty much perfect when it gets to the President’s desk.&nbsp; I can tell you that we’ve been working pretty hard on this.&nbsp; The meetings have been continuous since the Levinson Act was passed pretty much.</p>



<p>And the idea was that we had to get this right.&nbsp; This is not something we want to rewind in any way, shape, or form.&nbsp; So we wanted to have a tool that was useful.&nbsp; And that took a long time to try to make sure that all the stakeholders got a chance to weigh in so we could find something that was going to be useful, powerful, and going to achieve the end states that we were hoping to achieve.</p>



<p>So it took a while, but if you want to get it right, sometimes you have to invest the time, and I think that’s the case here.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Shall we go to the next question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Recently, a lot of families have criticized the administration over what they see as a lack of strategies broadly.&nbsp; I mean, looking at your executive order, it talks about bolstering engagement, information sharing.&nbsp; A lot of them have been also complaining about lack of communication at times.</p>



<p>But, I mean, can you talk a little bit &#8212; are you able to talk a little bit about broader strategy in terms of what exactly the U.S. government is doing to bring these people home?&nbsp; Do you have a blanket strategy?&nbsp; And by that, I mean, you guys have also been criticized by the families for refusing to make some swaps on certain occasions, and so has there been any change, for example, in that approach?&nbsp; I understand this has to do with DOJ as well.&nbsp; But basically, what is your response to all of those criticisms?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for the question, and I’m sure [senior administration official] will have some thoughts on this as well.&nbsp; But let me say a couple things.</p>



<p>One, anyone who’s worked on these issues for any period of time knows that strategies need to be case specific.&nbsp; They have to be informed by the intelligence and information about a particular case.&nbsp; They need to take into account country-specific facts, regional facts, and really anything we can bring to bear to leverage to get what we all ultimately want, which is an American home with his or her loved ones.</p>



<p>Families are in regular contact with [senior administration official] and his team at the State Department, as well as for hostage cases, the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell, which is an interagency body that sits at FBI, and are part of conversations not just in developing strategies but also in refining those strategies and considering when it’s time to pivot to a plan B &#8212; and there always needs to be a plan B.</p>



<p>I would just emphasize in particular that in this administration, the President has been willing to make what he himself has said publicly are tough but important calls when it means bringing home Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’ll call attention, in particular, to his willingness to do what was necessary to bring home Trevor Reed from wrongful detention in Russia.&nbsp; It is, of course, public that that involved the release of Mr. Yaroshenko, who had served a great deal of but not all of his sentence in the United States.</p>



<p>And the President, as he said in his public statement that day, was willing to take that very rare, very extraordinary, very hard step when it meant bringing home someone for whom there was a great urgency to see home and to see healthy as well.</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], do you have more you want to add?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Yeah, I wouldn’t mind adding just a little bit.</p>



<p>You know, this reminds me of that saying that “the other side always gets a vote.”&nbsp; And I’m always mindful in these cases that as we work on these different strategies &#8212; and as [senior administration official] said, they’re case specific &#8212; but as we’re executing them, at the end of the day, the other side, whether it’s Russia, China, Venezuela, et cetera, they get a vote.&nbsp; In a way, they have a very strong vote in that they hold the keys to the jail cell.&nbsp; And what we often find ourselves doing is trying to strategize and organize and, frankly, work with the families to find ways that might get those keys to open up and we can bring an American home.&nbsp; At times, it can be challenging.</p>



<p>I can tell you I probably spend one to four hours a day on the phone talking to family members.&nbsp; I’m currently away from Washington, D.C.&nbsp; I’m visiting a family tonight; will spend three hours in their home talking about their case.</p>



<p>But the bottom line is that we’re trying to partner with families to find these solutions.&nbsp; We definitely work strongly within the interagency on what we call the Hostage Recovery Enterprise.&nbsp; And frankly, we also work with members of Congress; the members and their staffers; NGOs; I would say, third-party intermediaries, but also even with the media, to come up with, I guess you would say, an overarching way of getting people back.&nbsp; And I think the media has been very powerful in really just calling awareness to this topic and, at times, even holding us accountable.</p>



<p>So, grateful for the chance to talk about this.&nbsp; But, really, to get to the meat of your question, we have ongoing strategies in all this.&nbsp; We review them pretty much on a daily basis, and we’ll partner with everyone we possibly can to see if we can bring this to a successful conclusion.</p>



<p>But I can tell you one thing: that the President of the United States, and my direct report, Secretary Blinken, they are committed to getting all these cases resolved and getting this done, and at the same time, start to bring up a deterrence strategy that can raise the cost of hostage taking and wrongful detention taking to the point that it’s no longer a feasible diplomatic strategy for those who would use it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Forgive me if I didn’t hear, but I didn’t hear a response to, especially, to Jennifer’s question about whether the President would be meeting with any of the families who were in town while they were here.</p>



<p>And if you could explain: If you are going to redefine when the administration can get involved, if they could get involved sooner with people wrongfully held &#8212; if you’re moving that bar. And if you can explain why Mark Fogel is not considered wrongfully detained, because his former colleagues and friends at the Embassy Moscow tell us that his conviction is for medical marijuana, and it seems very similar to the Griner case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you for the questions.&nbsp; I’ll take a first stab and, again, invite colleagues to comment.</p>



<p>On the third one, I won’t comment &#8212; I don’t think any of us will &#8212; on a particular case, but refer you to the State Department which handles by law, by the Levinson Act, designations of those unlawfully or wrongfully detained.</p>



<p>I’ll reiterate that I can’t speak for the President’s schedule but can speak for his commitment to these issues and his willingness to authorize and indeed direct, as this executive order does, the parts of his government that can do really the two things [senior administration official] has emphasized that we need to do at the same time.</p>



<p>One is resolve the current cases and bring people home and, at the same time, add to the costs for those who engage in this behavior through the executive order; add to the transparency for American travelers and for the world by the new indicator; and overall, reduce the next generation, so to speak, of cases from arising in the first place.</p>



<p>And then, in terms of the definition of a “wrongful detainee,” that is something that is set out in the Levinson Act by federal law with a number of factors that the State Department is to consider in any particular case in reaching a conclusion as to whether a given American held abroad and acknowledged as such by a foreign government should be deemed wrongfully detained.</p>



<p>So we wouldn’t be able to redefine that via executive order, but [senior administration official] and others across the State Department are day-to-day, week-to-week implementing that in some very effective and informative ways that I think take that law, and the powerful advocacy that helped to get it passed by the Levinson family and so many other families, and showing the value of having that designation and entrenched in the U.S. code, the factors that inform it.</p>



<p>But let me turn to others for anything they’d like to add as well.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, it’s [senior administration official].&nbsp; I’ll jump in.&nbsp; The wrongful termination process, I guess you can say we will pull up a case, and then it becomes ongoing research to determine whether it starts to, using the Levinson criteria, look like a wrongful detention.</p>



<p>We’ve had some cases go very fast in that we get information, and it seems like the information is self-evident, and that leads to a rather quick determination.&nbsp; We have other cases where we’re constantly bringing in information and it finally, to an extent, kind of crosses the bar and it becomes a wrongful detention but only after more information was gathered.</p>



<p>And I can tell you that we never take a case and put it away.&nbsp; Once we take a look at a case, we’re constantly trying to, like, as I say, vacuum in information, whether it’s from family members, newspaper reports, the intelligence community, to see if we can get that little extra piece of evidence that might raise it to the bar of being a wrongful detention.</p>



<p>Some cases never really rise to that level because, for some reason or not, they’re not wrongful.&nbsp; You know, we keep getting information that doesn’t quite reach the level of being recommended for determination.</p>



<p>On the Fogel case, I probably shouldn’t talk about any cases that are ongoing.&nbsp; We’ve been looking at that for a while now.&nbsp; I spent a few hours on the Fogel case just last week trying to get more information on it.&nbsp; So it’s ongoing and active; we’re looking at it.&nbsp; But I’d rather not go into any more details on specific cases.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much for addressing this call.&nbsp; And based on those comments, I’m hoping you can provide some kind of comment.&nbsp; But I mean, is there anything that you could say in regards to how these efforts would impact Brittney Griner’s case or cases like hers, or anything you can say on efforts to secure her release?&nbsp; Any positive progress, discussion of a prisoner swap, for example?&nbsp; I would appreciate anything that you can share, even in general.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Again, I’m happy to start, and then we’ll let colleagues jump in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First of all, with respect to the executive order, there are a number of ways in which it would affect cases like that, cases in the wrongful detainee category.&nbsp; The executive order directs those across the executive branch to share consistent and accurate information with the families of those who are deemed wrongfully detained to ensure that they receive support and assistance throughout the ordeal and to work with parts of our government to try to impose costs on those responsible.</p>



<p>And as I indicated, those responsible can be government officials, and it’s really quite expansive language: “foreign persons determined…to be responsible for or complicit in, to have directly or indirectly engaged in…to be responsible for ordering, controlling or otherwise directing the hostage taking of a U.S. national or the wrongful detention of a U.S. national abroad,” or to have “attempted” to do so or indeed to have been the “leader…of an entity that has engaged” in that sort of activity.</p>



<p>And so as this authority gets implemented, it will, we hope, have a couple of effects.&nbsp; One is to impose consequences on those who’ve been part of this just abominable, inhumane practice; and in so doing, to generate over time a deterrent from others becoming part of that practice, as well, whether that’s at a broad leadership level or whether that’s particular individuals who realize there can be very personalized repercussions for engaging in this sort of activity.</p>



<p>And then, with respect to the travel indicator, of course this will help increase the transparency to Americans as they think about destinations, so they can factor in the State Department’s indication that, at least as of tomorrow &#8212; and this will be reviewed, as you heard &#8212; there are six countries where the risk of being wrongfully detained, held by a foreign government in order to be exploited or used as a bargaining chip, is very real for Americans in particular.</p>



<p>Let me invite colleagues to add to that as well.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think you covered it perfectly.&nbsp; Nothing to add.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; I agree entirely.&nbsp; The one thing I would flag is that the “D” indicator is a way of increasing transparency for the U.S. public traveling.&nbsp; We have for a long time highlighted the risk of wrongful detention in certain countries, but by flagging it in this very clear way, we are hopeful that there will be fewer cases of U.S. travelers choosing to go to certain countries where this risk is greater than in others.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], my first question is for you.&nbsp; You mentioned that sanctions might not work or be applicable for every single case.&nbsp; So I’m wondering if there are particular cases or clusters of cases in which you think sanctions might be most appropriate or most relevant, or if there’s a particular impetus for this part of the EO.</p>



<p>And then, [senior administration official], this notion of sharing additional information, being transparent with families, was, of course, a signature element of Presidential Policy Directive 30, which you were obviously an instrumental player in seven years ago.&nbsp; So I’m wondering why this element is being introduced again.&nbsp; Is there a sense that that action from 2015 didn’t go far enough in sharing information?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m just kind of curious whether there’s particular aspects or element or fact that wound up leading to this new action. Thank you so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey, Eric.&nbsp; It’s [senior administration official].&nbsp; I’ll jump on and then they’ll turn over to [senior administration official], if that’s okay &#8212; although I may be asking &#8212; answering part of the question that you might have directed to him.</p>



<p>I mean, the Levinson Act, essentially, in public law, asks us to look into creating a sanctioning authority and sanctioning ability.&nbsp; And in wrestling with that over almost the last year and a half, this is the road that we’ve taken, and that seems to be a pretty good one.</p>



<p>So if there’s a reason why it’s coming out now, it’s really because it’s finally done.&nbsp; And it’s something that we’ve been working on based on what we were directed to by public law.</p>



<p>In terms of whether it can be used, I mean, obviously, I might have a country or two or three that I might be thinking about, but to be honest, I want to talk to the families.&nbsp; The families follow this case, as we do.&nbsp; We follow the cases, as you can imagine.&nbsp; But the families have a particular amount of depth to each one of their cases, for obvious reasons, and we would like to, in our engagements with them, kind of see who they think might be up for the targeting process.&nbsp; And we’d like to work with them a little bit.</p>



<p>So even though I might have a country or two where I think this might be a tool that could be put into action, I think I’m going to, kind of, withhold my fire for now until we can talk to the families and build up a strategy, because I don’t want to do that &#8212; what is it called? &#8212; like, “ready, fire, aim.”&nbsp; I want to do “ready, aim, fire.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>I want to make sure that this is integrated into our ongoing strategy and that it has impact.&nbsp; What I don’t want to do is do something where we use a pretty powerful tool but do not get the result that we want to achieve, and that’s bringing people home and then creating that deterrent effect.</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], can I turn it over to you to see if you can hit some of this and his other question?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great answers.&nbsp; And I’ll just flesh out a little bit on one of them, totally consistent with what [senior administration official] has said, which is: The focus of Presidential Policy Directive 30, in many ways, not in all ways, was in hostage cases rather than detainee cases. Now, it accounted for the latter.&nbsp; It specifically assigned the role of Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs to include working diplomatic engagements for cases in which a foreign government confirms, acknowledges that it’s detained a U.S. national but our government regards such detention as unlawful or wrongful.&nbsp; That is language that, as [senior administration official] said, was then picked up by Congress in the Levinson Act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And indeed, PPD 30 did take account of the fact there would need to be family engagement for those cases as well.&nbsp; It explicitly made available to the State Department the family engagement coordinator that was being built at the time at the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell.</p>



<p>But over time, the cases that are in the detainee category &#8212; the “foreign government held,” “foreign government acknowledge” category &#8212; have risen in both number and degree of difficulty.&nbsp; And that is something that Americans see every day with some of the cases that are in the headlines.</p>



<p>And so the Levinson Act took an important step forward in entrenching some of the reforms set out in PPD 30, not just for hostage cases, but also for detainee cases.&nbsp; This implements that; it takes it forward.</p>



<p>And indeed, in some ways, one key theme of both the executive order that will be announced tomorrow, as well as the “D” indicator, is that they continue to elevate the priority being placed on the “government held,” “government acknowledged” wrongful detainee cases and enhance the toolbox available to us across the government in addressing those cases, which ultimately means resolving the current ones and trying to warn about and deter future ones.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And that is all the questions that we have time for.&nbsp; [Moderator], we’ll turn it back over to you.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; And thank you, everyone, for joining this call this evening.&nbsp; As a reminder of the ground rules, the call was held on background with the speakers attributable to “senior administration officials,” and it is under embargo until tomorrow morning at 9:00 a.m. Eastern.</p>



<p>Thank you very much.&nbsp; I hope everyone has a wonderful evening.</p>



<p>&nbsp;END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Message to the Congress on Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United&#160;States Nationals&#160;Home</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/message-to-the-congress-on-bolstering-efforts-to-bring-hostages-and-wrongfully-detained-united-states-nationals-home/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57836</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order declaring a national emergency with respect to hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United&#160;States nationals. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order declaring a national emergency with respect to hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United&nbsp;States nationals.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals are heinous acts that undermine the rule of law.&nbsp; Terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or other gain &#8212; as well as foreign states that engage in the practice of wrongful detention, including for political leverage or to seek concessions from the United States &#8212; threaten the integrity of&nbsp;the international political system and the safety of United&nbsp;States nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; I have determined that hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals abroad constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 19, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United&#160;States Nationals&#160;Home</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/19/executive-order-on-bolstering-efforts-to-bring-hostages-and-wrongfully-detained-united-states-nationals-home/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-taking Accountability Act (22 U.S.C. 1741 et seq.) (Levinson Act), the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-taking Accountability Act (22 U.S.C. 1741 <em>et seq.</em>) (Levinson Act), the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq</em>.) (NEA), section 212(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952 (8 U.S.C. 1182(f)), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code,</p>



<p>I, Joseph R. Biden JR., President of the United States of America, find that hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals are heinous acts that undermine the rule of law. &nbsp;Terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or&nbsp;other gain &#8212; as well as foreign states that engage in the practice of wrongful detention, including for political leverage or to seek concessions from the United States &#8212; threaten the&nbsp;integrity of the international political system and the safety&nbsp;of United States nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; I&nbsp;therefore determine that hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals abroad constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; I hereby declare a national emergency to deal with this threat.</p>



<p>The United States Government must redouble its efforts at home and with partners abroad to deter these practices and to secure the release of those held as hostages or wrongfully detained.&nbsp; Processes established under Executive Order 13698 of June 24, 2015 (Hostage Recovery Activities) and Presidential Policy Directive 30 of June 24, 2015 (U.S. Nationals Taken Hostage Abroad and Personnel Recovery Efforts) (PPD-30) have facilitated close interagency coordination on efforts to secure the safe release of United States nationals taken hostage abroad, including engagement with the families of hostages and support of diplomatic engagement with partners abroad.&nbsp; This order reinforces the roles, responsibilities, and commitments contained in those directives and seeks to ensure that &#8212; as with hostage recovery activities &#8212; interagency coordination, family engagement, and diplomatic tools are enshrined in United&nbsp;States Government efforts to secure the safe release and return of United States nationals wrongfully detained by foreign state actors.&nbsp; This order also reinforces tools to deter and to impose tangible consequences on those responsible for, or complicit in, hostage-taking or the wrongful detention of a&nbsp;United States national abroad.</p>



<p>Accordingly, I hereby order:</p>



<p><a><u>Section</u></a> 1.&nbsp; <a></a>Executive Order 13698 and PPD-30 shall continue to apply to United States hostage recovery activities.&nbsp; Nothing in this order shall alter the responsibilities of the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell (HRFC), the Hostage Response Group (HRG), or the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs (SPEHA), established by Executive Order 13698, with respect to hostage recovery activities under Executive Order 13698 or PPD-30.&nbsp; Nor shall this order alter the scope of PPD-30, which applies to both suspected and confirmed hostage-takings in which a United&nbsp;States national is abducted or held outside of the United&nbsp;States, as well as to other hostage-takings occurring abroad in which the United States has a national interest, but does not apply if a foreign government confirms that it has detained a United States national.</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The HRG shall, in coordination with the National Security Council&#8217;s regional directorates as appropriate, convene on a regular basis and as needed at the request of the National Security Council to work to secure the safe release of United States nationals held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The HRG, in support of the Deputies Committee of the National Security Council and consistent with the process outlined in National Security Memorandum 2 of February 4, 2021 (Renewing the National Security Council System), or any successor memorandum, shall:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;identify and recommend options and strategies to the President through the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs to secure the recovery of hostages or the return of wrongfully detained United States nationals;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;coordinate the development and implementation of policies, strategies, and procedures for the recovery of hostages or the return of wrongfully detained United States nationals;</p>



<p>(iii) &nbsp;coordinate and deconflict policy guidance, strategies, and activities that potentially affect the recovery or welfare of United States nationals held hostage or the return or welfare of United States nationals wrongfully detained abroad, including reviewing proposed recovery or return options;</p>



<p>(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;receive regular updates from the HRFC, the Office of the SPEHA, and other executive departments and agencies (agencies), as the HRG deems appropriate, on the status of United States nationals being held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad and measures being taken to effect safe releases;</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;receive regular updates from the Department of State on all new wrongful detention determinations; and</p>



<p>(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;where higher-level guidance is required, make recommendations to the Deputies Committee of the National Security Council.</p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The SPEHA shall report to the Secretary of State on a regular basis and as needed to advance efforts to secure the safe release of United States nationals wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The SPEHA shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;coordinate diplomatic engagements and strategy regarding hostage and wrongful detention cases, in coordination with the HRFC and relevant agencies, as appropriate and consistent with policy guidance communicated through the HRG;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;share information, including information acquired during consular interactions and engagements, regarding wrongful detention cases with relevant agencies to facilitate close interagency coordination;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; draw on the experience and expertise of the HRFC to support efforts to return wrongfully detained United States nationals, including by providing support and assistance to the families of those wrongfully detained;</p>



<p>(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;develop and regularly update, in coordination with relevant agencies, strategies for wrongful detention cases for review by the HRG;</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;ensure, in coordination with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, that relevant agencies have access to necessary information, including intelligence information, on wrongful detention cases to inform strategies and options; and</p>



<p>(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;share, in coordination with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, relevant information, including intelligence information, on developments in wrongful detention cases with the families of wrongfully detained United States nationals, in a timely manner, as appropriate and consistent with the protection of sources and methods.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; To ensure that the United States Government provides a&nbsp;coordinated, effective, and supportive response to wrongful detentions, the Secretary of State shall identify adequate resources to enable the SPEHA to:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;ensure that all interactions by executive branch officials with the family of a wrongfully detained United States national occur in a coordinated fashion and that the family receives consistent and accurate information from the United States Government, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;provide support and assistance to wrongfully detained United States nationals and their families throughout their detention, including through coordination with the HRFC, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law; and</p>



<p>(iii) &nbsp;provide support and assistance to United States nationals upon their return to the United States from wrongful detention, including through coordination with the HRFC and the Department of Health and Human Services, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law.</p>



<p>Sec. 4.&nbsp; The SPEHA, in coordination with the HRG, the HRFC, and relevant agencies, as appropriate, shall identify and recommend options and strategies to the President through the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs to reduce the likelihood of United States nationals being held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad.&nbsp; The options shall seek to counter and deter hostage-takings and wrongful detentions by terrorist organizations, foreign governments, and other actors by imposing costs on those who participate in, support, or facilitate such conduct.&nbsp; The strategies shall seek to deter any effort to engage in hostage-taking or the wrongful detention of United States nationals abroad through cooperation with like-minded foreign governments and organizations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 5.&nbsp; The Secretary of State shall publicly or privately designate or identify officials of foreign governments who are involved, directly or indirectly, in wrongful detentions, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, including section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2022 (Division K of Public Law 117-103).</p>



<p>Sec. 6.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;All property and interests in property of the following persons that are in the United States, that hereafter come within the United States, or that are or hereafter come within the possession or control of any United States person, are blocked and may not be transferred, paid, exported, withdrawn, or otherwise dealt in:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;any foreign person determined by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Attorney General:</p>



<p>(A)&nbsp; to be responsible for or complicit in, to have directly or indirectly engaged in, or to be&nbsp;responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the hostage-taking of a United States national or the wrongful detention of a United States national abroad;</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; to have attempted to engage in any activity described in subsection (a)(i)(A) of this section; or</p>



<p>(C) &nbsp;to be or have been a leader or official of an entity that has engaged in, or whose members have engaged in, any of the activities described in subsections (a)(i)(A) or (a)(i)(B) of this section relating to the leader&#8217;s or official&#8217;s tenure;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; any foreign person determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General:</p>



<p>(A)&nbsp; to have materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of:</p>



<p>(1)&nbsp; any activity described in subsection (a)(i)(A) of this section; or</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp; any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order;</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; to be owned, controlled, or directed by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order; or</p>



<p>(C)&nbsp; to have attempted to engage in any activity described in subsection (a)(ii)(A) of this section.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or any license or permit granted prior to the date of this order.<a></a></p>



<p>Sec. 7.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The unrestricted immigrant and nonimmigrant entry into the United States of noncitizens determined to meet one or more of the criteria set forth in section 6(a) of this order would be detrimental to the interests of the United States, and the entry of such persons into the United States, as immigrants or nonimmigrants, is hereby suspended, except when the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, determines that the person&#8217;s entry would not be contrary to the interests of the United States, including when the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, so determines, based on a recommendation of the Attorney General, that the person&#8217;s entry would further important United States law enforcement objectives.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretary of State shall implement this authority as it applies to visas pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, may establish.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Secretary of Homeland Security shall implement this order as it applies to the entry of noncitizens pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may establish.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; Such persons shall be treated by this section in the same manner as persons covered by section 1 of Proclamation 8693 of July 24, 2011 (Suspension of Entry of Aliens Subject to United Nations Security Council Travel Bans and International Emergency Economic Powers Act Sanctions).</p>



<p>Sec. 8.&nbsp; <a></a><a></a>I hereby determine that the making of donations of the types of articles specified in section 203(b)(2) of IEEPA (50 U.S.C. 1702(b)(2)) by, to, or for the benefit of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order would seriously impair my ability to deal with the national emergency declared in this order, and I hereby prohibit such donations as provided by section 6 of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 9.&nbsp; <a></a>(a)&nbsp; Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p>Sec. 10.&nbsp; For those persons whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order who might have a constitutional presence in the United States, I find that because of the ability to transfer funds or other assets instantaneously, prior notice to such persons of measures to be&nbsp;taken pursuant to this order would render those measures ineffectual.&nbsp; I therefore determine that for these measures to be effective in addressing the national emergency declared in this order, there need be no prior notice of a listing or determination made pursuant to section 6 of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 11.  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.  The Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury.  All agencies of the United States Government shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to carry out the provisions of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 12.&nbsp; <a></a>Nothing in this order shall prohibit transactions for the conduct of the official business of the United States Government by employees, grantees, or contractors thereof.</p>



<p>Sec. 13.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to submit recurring and final reports to the Congress on the national emergency declared in this order, consistent with section 401(c) of the NEA (50 U.S.C. 1642(c)) and section 204(c) of IEEPA (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1703(c)).</p>



<p>Sec. 14.&nbsp; For purposes of this order:&nbsp;</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; the term &#8220;foreign person&#8221; means any citizen or national of a foreign state (including any such individual who is also a citizen or national of the United States, provided such individual does not reside in the United States) or any entity not organized solely under the laws of the United States or existing solely in the United States;</p>



<p>(c)  the term &#8220;hostage-taking&#8221; has the same meaning as provided in PPD-30, which is the unlawful abduction or holding of a person or persons against their will in order to compel a third person or governmental organization to do or to abstain from doing any act as a condition for the release of the person detained;</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; the term &#8220;noncitizen&#8221; means any person who is not a citizen or noncitizen national of the United States;</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity;</p>



<p>(f)&nbsp; the term &#8220;United States national&#8221; means:</p>



<p>(i)   a &#8220;national of the United States&#8221; as defined in 8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22) or 8 U.S.C. 1408; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; a lawful permanent resident with significant ties to the United States;</p>



<p>(g)&nbsp; the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States; and</p>



<p>(h)  the term &#8220;wrongful detention&#8221; means a detention that the Secretary of State has determined to be wrongful consistent with section 302(a) of the Levinson Act.</p>



<p>Sec. 15.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of&nbsp;Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 19, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden Welcoming Important Steps Towards EU Integration for Albania and North&#160;Macedonia </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/statement-by-president-biden-welcoming-important-steps-towards-eu-integration-for-albania-and-north-macedonia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 13:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States welcomes the important steps the European Union is taking to advance the integration of the Western Balkans into the Euro-Atlantic community by opening EU accession talks with Albania and North Macedonia. In a moment when Russia has shattered peace in Europe, it is more important than ever to support the aspiration for a Europe whole, free, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States welcomes the important steps the European Union is taking to advance the integration of the Western Balkans into the Euro-Atlantic community by opening EU accession talks with Albania and North Macedonia. In a moment when Russia has shattered peace in Europe, it is more important than ever to support the aspiration for a Europe whole, free, and at peace. A democratic, secure, and prosperous Western Balkans remains essential to this vision. The United States will continue to be a strong and reliable partner as those nations work to defend human rights, strengthen democratic reforms, and uphold the rule of law. The steps that the EU, Albania, and North Macedonia have taken in recent days should inspire all EU aspirants in the region to increase their commitment to strengthening their democracies.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Builds on Efforts to Bring Home American Hostages and Wrongful&#160;Detainees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-builds-on-efforts-to-bring-home-american-hostages-and-wrongful-detainees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden reaffirms his commitment to bring home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained abroad by issuing a new executive order (E.O.), Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United States Nationals Home. This E.O. expands the tools available to deter and disrupt hostage-taking and wrongful detentions. &#160;It creates new ways to impose&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden reaffirms his commitment to bring home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained abroad by issuing a new executive order (E.O.), <em>Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United States Nationals Home</em>. This E.O. expands the tools available to deter and disrupt hostage-taking and wrongful detentions. &nbsp;It creates new ways to impose costs on terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or other gains and thus threaten the integrity of the international political system and the safety of U.S. nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; This E.O. advances the unwavering commitment of the United States to bring home Americans who are held hostage or wrongfully detained.<br><br>In addition, the Biden-Harris Administration is introducing a new risk indicator—the “D” indicator—to the State Department’s Travel Advisories to inform American travelers of the risk of wrongful detention by a foreign government.&nbsp; This additional risk indicator will highlight the elevated risk that Americans face in particular countries and provide Americans with comprehensive safety and security information with which to make informed travel decisions.&nbsp; The “D” indicator joins the existing “K” indicator that covers risk of kidnapping and hostage-taking by non-state actors, as well as a range of other existing risk indicators.&nbsp; State Department Travel Advisories are continuously revised and updated based on a comprehensive review of all available safety information and ongoing developments.<br><br>The executive order will generate expanded and enhanced ways to address the hostage-taking and wrongful detention of Americans abroad.&nbsp; This E.O. reflects the Biden-Harris Administration’s continued commitment to bringing them home.&nbsp; In particular, this E.O. draws on the 2020 Robert&nbsp;<em>Levinson</em>&nbsp;Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability&nbsp;<em>Act and </em>reinforces the Administration’s tool kit in key ways.&nbsp; Specifically, this E.O.:</p>



<ul><li>Reinforces the U.S. Government’s efforts to support families of Americans wrongfully detained or held hostage overseas;</li><li>Authorizes agencies to impose costs and consequences, including financial sanctions, on those who are involved, directly or indirectly, in hostage-taking or wrongful detentions to support expanded and ongoing interagency efforts;&nbsp;</li><li>Directs relevant parts of the U.S. Government to bolster their engagement and sharing of relevant information, including intelligence information, consistent with the protection of sources and methods, with families regarding their loved ones’ status and U.S. Government efforts to secure their release or return, as appropriate; and</li><li>Charges experts across the interagency to develop options and strategies to deter future hostage-taking and wrongful detentions.</li></ul>



<p>This E.O. is informed by our regular communications with the families and other stakeholders who have undertaken incredible advocacy efforts on behalf of their loved ones.  The Biden-Harris Administration appreciates the continued diligence of such families and considers them essential partners in our efforts to bring Americans home.  President Biden and experts across the Administration will draw on this E.O. to advance our efforts and remain committed to reuniting Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained with their families. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and CEA Member Jared&#160;Bernstein</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/19/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-cea-member-jared-bernstein/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 12:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:16 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160;&#160; Hello.&#160; Good afternoon, everybody. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good afternoon. MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160;&#160; Okay.&#160; So today I’d like to welcome Jared Bernstein, member of the Council of Economic Advisers, back to the briefing room.&#160; Jared is here to talk about the strong economic progress we&#8217;re making and the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:16 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So today I’d like to welcome Jared Bernstein, member of the Council of Economic Advisers, back to the briefing room.&nbsp; Jared is here to talk about the strong economic progress we&#8217;re making and the enormous opportunities Congress has ahead to continue that progress.<br><br>We’re really glad to have him here again.&nbsp; And, Jared, I welcome you back to the podium.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, thank you so much.&nbsp; I have an opening statement, after which I&#8217;ll take questions.</p>



<p>President Biden, who grew up in a family where the price of gas was a kitchen table issue, has elevated easing price pressures as his top economic priority.&nbsp; We economists think of this in terms of inflation, inflationary expectations, interest rate changes &#8212; a vast array of complicated concepts and measurements.</p>



<p>But the fact is that it comes down to affordability and the need among American households for a bit of breathing room in making ends meet.&nbsp; Therefore, we&#8217;re very happy to report that the current drop in the price of gas, down 50 cents per gallon over the past 34 days, is one of the fastest decline in retail gas prices in a decade.</p>



<p>At current prices, the average American driver will spend about $25 per month less on gasoline than they would have if prices had stayed at their June peak.&nbsp; Economy wide, that means American drivers are saving around $190 million each day from lower gas prices.&nbsp; And since gasoline prices affect the prices of other goods and services through transportation costs &#8212; food is a good example &#8212; both households that drive and households that don&#8217;t yield some benefit from lower gasoline prices.</p>



<p>Now, the decline in retail gas price is not a daily blip.&nbsp; The chart behind me shows that gasoline prices have declined every single day for the past 34 days.&nbsp; Just yesterday, we witnessed the largest single-day decline in national gas prices since 2008.</p>



<p>As we all know, in contrast to the, quote, “law of one price” they teach in Econ 101, gas prices vary from place to place.&nbsp; But according to an industry analyst, around 20,000 gas stations across over 30 states are now charging less than $4 per gallon.</p>



<p>Now, we know this is a volatile market; that&#8217;s one reason we&#8217;re highlighting a trend here and not a blip.&nbsp; But if you look at the about $20 decline in the price of oil since early June, as well as the drop in &#8212; that&#8217;s on the next chart &#8212; as well as the drop in the wholesale gas price, we think it&#8217;s reasonable to expect more gas stations to lower their prices in response to lower input costs and thus, barring unforeseen market disruptions, to see average prices fall below $4 per gallon in more places in coming weeks.</p>



<p>While there&#8217;s a lot that goes into setting the global oil and gas price, the historic actions taken by President Biden to address the impact of Putin&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine have helped and continue to help to increase the global supply of oil and therefore are in the mix of factors driving down the price.</p>



<p>Because the President&#8217;s announcement on releasing 180 million barrels from our Strategic Petroleum Reserve and another 60 million from our global partners was back in March, I suspect there are people who forget about this critically important intervention in energy markets.&nbsp; But this action is very much in play in today&#8217;s market, currently releasing a record 1 million barrels of oil per day on average and 84 million barrels so far.</p>



<p>These releases have had an outsized effect at a time when the market is especially tight.&nbsp; In fact, as one leading oil market analyst put it, quote, “The U.S. has become the world&#8217;s oil barrel of last resort, single handedly keeping prices in the energy market from exploding even higher by selling a large chunk of its Strategic Petroleum Reserve.”&nbsp; End quote.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Two further points before I take &#8212; we take your questions.</p>



<p>As gas prices are coming down, our labor market, which is where working-age families get most of their income, remains historically very strong.&nbsp; Job gains continue to come in at historically high levels.&nbsp; Private sector employment has surpassed its prior peak.&nbsp; And the jobless rate has been at 3.6 percent &#8212; just about its pre-pandemic level &#8212; for four months in a row.</p>



<p>As someone who has carefully tracked labor market recoveries for decades, I assure you that this one is already in the record books for the speed of its recovery.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no question that the American Rescue Plan, with its shots in arms and checks in pockets, helped to achieve that goal.</p>



<p>Finally, while the lower gas price creates some much-needed breathing room, American households need a lot more.&nbsp; Congress has enormous opportunities to help by continuing progress on both prescription drug costs, the cost of health coverage, and long-term growth with CHIPS Act.</p>



<p>I cannot overemphasize the importance, at this moment in our economic expansion, for taking action on these crucial supports for family budgets and for long-term growth and economic security.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And Karine will call on folks.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Jared, is the administration preparing for a recession?&nbsp; And how do you react to companies, like Apple, and banks saying today that they intend to slow hiring because the economy is slowing?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So let me tell you a little bit about the way the National Bureau of Economic Research Business Cycle Dating Committee &#8212; that&#8217;s the group that decides recessions &#8212; makes their call.</p>



<p>They weigh a couple of variables pretty heavily, and one of them is payroll employment.&nbsp; Now, based on payroll employment &#8212; which, by the way, of course, relates to the unemployment rate, 3.6 percent &#8212; an historically very low unemployment rate for the past four months &#8212; those kinds of statistics are anything but recessionary.</p>



<p>Now, that&#8217;s very much a look at the job market today.</p>



<p>Slightly more forward-looking is: If you look at consumers &#8212; and, by the way, the bank reports, I thought, had this in their earnings reports &#8212; they talked about the strength of the American consumer.&nbsp; If you look at retail sales from just last week, you&#8217;ll see American consumers still helping to fuel an economy that&#8217;s delivering really remarkable job gains.</p>



<p>So I think &#8212; and, by the way, that in itself relates to something I kind of referenced in my opening comments: the fact that not only do people have the benefit of an historically strong job market behind them, a real tailwind in this economy, many also still have excess savings; this is one of the things that’s helping to fuel consumer spending, which, again, is 70 percent of our economy.</p>



<p>So I think if you look at the strength of the current economy, if you look at the strength of the labor market, if you look at the strength of consumer spending, you would conclude that where we are right now remains solidly within expansion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just one follow-up to that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we all remember, a year ago, other colleagues of yours stood here and said inflation was transitory and was not going to last, and it was certainly not going to go up to where we are now.&nbsp; Do you think it&#8217;s possible in a couple of months you might regret standing here and saying we&#8217;re not about to be in a recession?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, I want to be very clear what I&#8217;m saying.&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is that based on &#8212; based on consumer spending, based on payroll employment, based on where the unemployment rate is, I think we can confidently say that these numbers that we&#8217;re posting are very much inconsistent with a recessionary call, given where we are right now.</p>



<p>I think that is the most accurate way to assess the answer to that question.</p>



<p>When it comes to transitory, I think the answer there is that we were careful, when we were talking about that, to consistently reference the forecasts that were out there, the view on inflation’s trajectory by not only pretty much every forecaster we could find, but of course, the Federal Reserve as well.</p>



<p>And so this was a period where we, you know, hadn&#8217;t seen new variants of the &#8212; of the virus; where the war in Ukraine, of course, was not yet a reality.</p>



<p>So I think that if you look at the &#8212; look at the general trajectory of where the forecasts were pointing in there, that was generally the way in which we tried to talk about that.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s worth going back and seeing.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, MJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jared, Senator Manchin said that he is a no-go on the climate deal because he has concerns about inflation.&nbsp; Is there a scenario where you all try to wait for better inflation news and then try again on that front?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, let me just start by saying, you know, “better inflation news,” I mean, that&#8217;s a &#8212; again, getting into a level of forecasting that I&#8217;m not going to do in this period of uncertainty.</p>



<p>What I can very much assure you, though, is that the price of gas is considerably lower in July than it was in June, and this is something the President referenced when the June CPI report came out.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re talking about, as I mentioned in my opening comments, a situation where the price of gas is falling at about the fastest rate it has in a decade and where more than 20,000 gas stations now are selling gas for less than $4 a gallon.  That will show up as some easing of prices.   <br><br>I think when it comes to reconciliation, the President has a view that was very clearly laid out in a statement last Friday: He will always follow a legislative path to get the deal done for the American people to deliver the kind of relief, both near term and long term, that he came here to administer.  But if &#8212; if that &#8212; if part of that legislative path to reconciliation closes, we have other options.<br><br>We can certainly pursue reconciliation with two critically important policies &#8212; lowering the cost of prescription drugs and lowering the cost of health insurance premiums to folks who get that from the &#8212; from the exchanges.<br><br>Particularly on the &#8212; those are both really important.  Let me say a couple of words about them.<br><br>When you&#8217;re talking about the exchanges, you&#8217;re talking about 13 million people who are looking at a potential increase in their average premiums of $800 a year.<br><br>Now, the Center on Budget, where I used to work, did a calculation showing that for a couple 60 years old with $45,000 &#8212; so not rolling in dough, exactly &#8212; failing to extend these enhanced premiums would raise their premium costs by $1,900. <br><br>Now let&#8217;s talk about prescription drugs for a second.  Presidents from both parties have long tried to accomplish this critically important measure to stop prohibiting Medicare from competing in &#8212; in the market to lower drug prices for our seniors.<br><br>Now, I think you have to ask yourself why it is that in other countries people pay two to three times less than we do for the same drugs.  The same pill costs two to three times more here than it does there.<br><br>The relief that we could deliver to our seniors, from allowing &#8212; allowing prescription drugs to compete, as the President has stressed, is not just essential for their living standards and their wellbeing; it is a way to actually ease inflationary pressures.<br><br>So this is a very clear choice of whether you stand with Big Pharma or whether you stand with American seniors and the Medicare program &#8212; which, by the way, would be $100 billion better off over 10 years if we can achieve this in reconciliation.<br><br>Now, the Democrats appear to be aligned on that.  And that &#8212; that, along with the &#8212; with the premium coverage, would be an absolutely huge win for reconciliation.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Ashley.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Following up on Jeff&#8217;s question about transitory inflation, I&#8217;m curious what made the White House realize that the phrase was inaccurate and also politically problematic.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I think it has to do with the &#8212; I&#8217;m going to use an economics word &#8212; the periodicity, which is &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The what?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I’m &#8212; see, this is &#8212; this is why you do a better job than I do.<br><br>I think it has to do with the ambiguity about the length of that word is what it has to do with.&nbsp; I think it has to do with the ambiguity about the length of that word.<br><br>Some people hear “transitory,” and they&#8217;re going to think weeks and months.&nbsp; Others hear “transitory” &#8212; particularly, probably, economists who are used to the broader ups and downs of cycles &#8212; and think longer periods.<br><br>And I think the lack of specificity about the cadence that was implied by that word &#8212; the temporal cadence implied by that word &#8212; led to a level of ambiguity that wasn&#8217;t serving the debate very well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what about just the second part about “politically problematic”?&nbsp; Was that something you were hearing from voters, seeing show up in polls that that language was hurting the President (inaudible)?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I think that when it comes to, you know, politically problematic, you&#8217;ve heard the President say in recent days that this is &#8212; that the inflation is unacceptably high and that bringing it down is his absolute number one domestic priority.&nbsp; And I think that that is all you need to know in terms of what he is dispatching his economics team to do in that front.<br><br>Now, I also think &#8212; and let&#8217;s not lose this, because I think it&#8217;s really important, and this is why I tried to focus in on my comments at the top &#8212; is that his actions &#8212; this is &#8212; this is not just forward-looking; it is, but it&#8217;s not just forward-looking.&nbsp; Actions he has taken thus far are providing real relief to the American people, okay?<br><br>His release of oil from the Strategic Reserves, his increase in E15 ethanol &#8212; these are not the only reasons that the price is behaving as you saw in those charts, but they are in the mix.<br><br>The President&#8217;s actions taken thus far are helping to provide real relief, real breathing room for the American consumers at the pump.<br><br>So this is not just an aspirational goal of this President.&nbsp; This is something he and his team are actively working on.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; In the back.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; The first quick one is &#8212; I guess, does the council have an estimate for how much the administration&#8217;s regulatory changes have combatted or contributed to regulation &#8212; to inflation thus far?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I think, in many ways, we&#8217;ve been talking about a lot of that already.&nbsp; I mean, I just mentioned the E15 ethanol waiver, so that&#8217;s a waiver that helps increase the supply of gas &#8212; gasoline, particularly in the Midwest.<br><br>I think, certainly, if you broaden, sort of, the regulatory scope to consider executive actions and rule changes, you see a lot more.&nbsp; I mentioned the Strategic Reserve release.<br><br>We&#8217;ve talked &#8212; we haven&#8217;t talked about this yet, but the President has made real progress in helping to ameliorate food price pressures through issues that include double cropping, taking action on fertilizer prices, ocean shipping.<br><br>So all of these are actions that he&#8217;s taken.&nbsp; In some cases, they&#8217;ve involved legislation, but in many cases they haven&#8217;t.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then my second question: Tomorrow marks the one-year anniversary of President Biden insisting that high prices and inflation, in the President&#8217;s words, were “expected to be temporary.”&nbsp; A lot of my colleagues have asked similar questions, but I&#8217;m wondering how much faith can the American public put in future White House assessments about the economy, about inflation after they saw that inflation number increase month after month, and before the Russian invasion of Ukraine?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, let me say two things.&nbsp; First of all, I tried to answer as fulsomely as I could, some of that &#8212; part of that question earlier.&nbsp; But let me ask you to focus on what we&#8217;re trying to talk about today, which is something that is happening in the here and now.<br><br>The chart is not up, but that first chart, which we can certainly make available to you, that shows we&#8217;re not talking about looking around any corner here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about what has happened in the past 34 days to prices at the pump.&nbsp; They’ve fallen 50 cents, and you heard me go through some of the numbers in terms of the relief for American drivers.<br><br>At the same time, we are not stopping there.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; This is nothing close to a victory lap, because we have much more to do to achieve the President&#8217;s agenda of helping families get some breathing room in this tough environment, which is characterized by, of course, such highly elevated prices.<br><br>Now, if you can help people with prescription drugs, drugs that cost two or three times less in other countries for the same pill; if you can help a 60-year-old couple with a $45,000 income not have to pay another $1,900 to get their insurance coverage, you are accomplishing the President&#8217;s goals.<br><br>Now, to do that, we need Congress to align and work with us.&nbsp; And, you know, Democrats &#8212; many Democrats are there when it comes to prescription drugs.<br><br>This is something that President Trump said he wanted to achieve.&nbsp; And, you know, he didn&#8217;t get there.&nbsp; This President is pushing hard to achieve that goal.<br><br>One last point on this.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve talked about mostly near-term relief, because that&#8217;s so important for families who are seeking a little bit of breathing room right now.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s another piece of legislation on the docket.&nbsp; And that, of course, is CHIPS.&nbsp; And this is something that has had real bipartisan support.&nbsp; I believe it got &#8212; I believe an earlier version got 68 votes in the Senate.<br><br>I think it is absolutely and critically important for this nation to invest in domestic production of microprocessors.&nbsp; Again, not only would this be a criti- &#8212; not only would this be a highly favorable investment for growth and for jobs, it would be disinflationary, because one of the areas where we see inflationary pressures is, of course, in autos, which now very much depend on chips.<br><br>To be clear, that&#8217;s not a near-term intervention.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not going to show up, you know, in the next couple of months.&nbsp; But longer term, absolutely.&nbsp; Supply chain, same thing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Aren’t you having it both ways, Jared?&nbsp; Because when the gas prices go up, it&#8217;s got nothing to do with the President; when we see some decline, you want him to get the credit.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Look, I think that &#8212; that there&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s no both-way thinking here at all.&nbsp; I think that there has been a consistent, I think, pressure on this White House to try to do everything it could to ameliorate inflationary pressures.&nbsp; And the President has reacted from the beginning, talking about how this was such an important priority to alleviate these pressures on behalf of the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>So what did he do?&nbsp; He put his head down and got to work, and got us to work, to do everything we could to achieve that goal.<br><br>He then presided over the largest historical release of barrels of oil from the Strategic Reserve &#8212; 180 million barrels.&nbsp; Then he talked to global partners to get them to kick in another 60 million.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So when they rose, it was Putin’s fault.&nbsp; When they’re coming down, he gets the credit.&nbsp; Is that (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah, I very much disagree with that framing.&nbsp; I think what’s happening here is a President who is working tirelessly to address the largest constraint &#8212; probably the toughest constraint &#8212; facing American households right now: the budgetary impacts of these elevated prices.&nbsp; And we’re showing you here today some real results, partially &#8212; that partially derived from concrete efforts he’s taken.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Go ahead, Eugene.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the different economic data releases we’ve seen, they aren’t really consistent with each other.&nbsp; So, out of all of the choices of indicators, what does the administration see as the most important indicators for how the economy is doing?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; That’s a great question.&nbsp; So, there is no most important indicator at the CEA.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A group of indicators then.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah, a group of them. &nbsp;So, at the CEA, we &#8212; we just &#8212; we just look at all of them.</p>



<p>And I think where I would take your question is that &#8212; we don&#8217;t give all of them &#8212; it&#8217;s sort of like I was talking to this gentleman before about the different weights that economists put on these variables when we&#8217;re trying to assess the conditions of the business cycle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think this is particularly relevant in the area of GDP. So, in terms of real GDP, if you look at consumer spending and business investment, you actually see some very solid numbers. And these are some of the numbers &#8212; and particularly consumer spending &#8212; retail sales, consumer spending, personal income, taking out transfers &#8212; these are some of the measures that the Business Cycle Dating Committee look at, and so we&#8217;re looking at them too.</p>



<p>And if you get under the hood of the GDP report from the Q1 &#8212; and we&#8217;ll probably be &#8212; and we&#8217;ll certainly be getting under that same hood in Q2 &#8212; one of the things you see is consistently strong consumer spending.</p>



<p>Now consumer spending is 70 percent of our economy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s actually uniquely high.&nbsp; In Europe, it&#8217;s about 55.&nbsp; In China, it&#8217;s about 45.&nbsp; So, you know, I could tell you stories about my family and some of the orders that I&#8217;ve seen come in from our own consumer preferences.&nbsp; They’re &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; this is a very &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Please do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; This is a &#8212; I won’t.&nbsp; I’m &#8212; this is a very acquisitive nation &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; &#8212; when you compare our consumer spending shares to other countries.</p>



<p>So, when you&#8217;re looking at an economy with a 70 percent consumer spending share, and then you look at a labor market, which is, of course, as I said in my comments &#8212; which is, of course, where most working people get their income; it’s from the labor market &#8212; and you look at the level of elevated savings, which, again, has the fingerprints of the Rescue Plan on it, you get a sense of what we&#8217;re looking at in terms of economic indicators that continue to fuel pretty robust consumer spending.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s an important, I think, element of the current economy.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let’s take a few more.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, a quick one on student loan debt and cancellation.&nbsp; Does the White House believe &#8212; does the White House have any concern that canceling any amount of student loan debt will further aggravate inflation?&nbsp; And what kind of a status update can you give us on the President&#8217;s deliberations on that?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President and give you any kind of a status update.</p>



<p>What I will say are things that, you know, I myself have said and NEC Director Brian Deese has said &#8212; that if you think about the inflationary implications of student debt relief and you think about the &#8212; those of restart &#8212; restarting payments &#8212; they push in different directions.&nbsp; And we think that the &#8212; we think, broadly speaking, that the &#8212; those effects would essentially neutralize.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Nancy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jared.&nbsp; You said over the weekend that the President is going to look to enact his climate agenda with or without Congress.&nbsp; But realistically, how much of it can he enact without Congress, especially now that the Supreme Court has tied his hands to some degree when it comes to emissions regulations at the EPA?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I think, realistically, there is a lot he can do and there is a lot he will do.&nbsp; The President will aggressively fight to attack climate change because he knows it&#8217;s one of the reasons he&#8217;s here.&nbsp; And it is absolutely core to transitioning from where we are to where we need to be.</p>



<p>Now, I think I&#8217;ve given you a fulsome sense today of &#8212; that both of the sides of that transition are important: affordability at the pump, yes, but we also have to plot a path to clean energy.</p>



<p>I said over the weekend that it&#8217;s kind of unfathomable to me that &#8212; that one wouldn’t appreciate this urgency.&nbsp; If you look at the costs to our economy of floods, of droughts, of fires; if you look at the global economy and you see the kinds of heat waves that are occurring right now, scientists will tell you all day that this very much relates to global warming.&nbsp; You&#8217;re talking about something like 100, 120 billion dollars a year in costs to our economy.</p>



<p>If you think about the geopolitical costs occurring when a Russian plutocrat weaponizes energy and fossil fuels and funds this unjust aggression against Ukraine with it, you get another sense of just how important it is to intervene.&nbsp; And this all comes from conversations we&#8217;ve had with the President.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how urgent this is.</p>



<p>Now, you asked what can he do.&nbsp; Let me start by telling you a little bit about what he has done.&nbsp; He has taken unprecedented action already to tackle the climate crisis.&nbsp; He&#8217;s invoked the &#8212; and this is non-legislative &#8212; he&#8217;s invoked the Defense Production Act to make more clean energy in America.&nbsp; He&#8217;s jumped-started the offshore wind industry.&nbsp; He has set the strongest emissions standards ever.&nbsp; And it is our firm belief that he can and will continue to do so if the legislative path is closed to him.&nbsp; But he will also pursue that path as well.&nbsp; And this is how important and urgent it is to him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So then why do you think that &#8212; you know, you just laid out the costs of inaction.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Clearly, Senator Manchin believed that the cost of action was too high in the face of high inflation.&nbsp; Why do you think you weren&#8217;t able to convince him that the cost of doing nothing would be higher?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;m just &#8212; I just don&#8217;t have a great answer to that question.&nbsp; I mean, I think what we can do &#8212; and, you know, I hope I&#8217;ve been a little bit convincing here in my conversation, but, you know, I&#8217;ve worked for Joe Biden for a long time, and I’ve found him to be profoundly convincing in this area.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, he&#8217;s someone who&#8217;s been in the Senate for decades, so it&#8217;s not like he grew up in a world where climate change and global warming were, you know, the top of the agenda.&nbsp; But his understanding of that, his deep appreciation of the urgency of what I&#8217;ve just described of you is &#8212; is as high as I&#8217;ve been stressing in my comments today.</p>



<p>So, I find &#8212; you know, I, personally, and I think lots of other people &#8212; there were 81 million people who voted for him &#8212; find him extremely convincing on this.&nbsp; And when he says &#8212; you know, when “Fightin’ Joe Biden” says he&#8217;s going to keep fighting for this issue, you know, I think we should all believe him.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Two more.&nbsp; Go ahead, Franco.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; Thanks, Jared.&nbsp; You talked earlier about the importance of the prescription drugs efforts, but you also kind of took a sigh of deep breath when asking the inability to convince Manchin on climate change.&nbsp; I mean, how &#8212; or how is the reduced or the smaller reconciliation package &#8212; I mean, does the White House feel that&#8217;s a defeat?&nbsp; And if not, how not so?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Not even close.&nbsp; I mean, the &#8212; accomplishing the prescription drug agenda that the President has been talking about and underscoring since before the campaign &#8212; I was his chief economist when he was the Vice President lo these many years ago, and he was talking about the importance of it back then.</p>



<p>I remember briefing him on these points about how prescription drugs are two to three times more expensive here; how we could save Medicare $100 billion over 10 years by injecting competition into &#8212; into this &#8212; into this space.&nbsp; That just resonated with him, I think, probably ever since he&#8217;s been aware of the issue.&nbsp; And achieving that would be an absolutely landmark goal not just on behalf of American seniors and their living standards, but on behalf of this absolutely essential and much-loved program called Medicare.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But considering where the original proposal was, I mean &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So, let me &#8212; I see where you&#8217;re going.&nbsp; So, considering where the original proposal was, I want to refer you to the comments I just made.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sure, we will &#8212; this President will always try to pursue a legislative pla- &#8212; path to get the best deal for the people who sent him up here to do just that.</p>



<p>But if that path closes, he will find another path.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll keep working on the legislative path.</p>



<p>Joe Biden is someone who’s been pulling legislative rabbits out of hats for, you know, 30 &#8212; for three or four decades now, and he&#8217;s going to continue to do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, whatever paths are open to &#8212; whatever paths are open to us, we will take.&nbsp; When those paths are closed, we&#8217;re going to find other paths.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how important this agenda is.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jim.&nbsp; And then Kelly O, you’ll have the last one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to reconciliation.&nbsp; Obviously, one of the parts of the President&#8217;s agenda had been a global tax deal that this administration has led the world in sealing.&nbsp; But now, because of the dropped tax provisions in reconciliation, the United States will not be in compliance with the deal that it negotiated essentially.&nbsp; How can you possibly expect the rest of the world to follow along if the U.S. is not going to actually be in compliance with the deal?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:  So, let me say a few things about that, kind of warming up to the answer, because I want to just give a little bit of a runway.  First of all, I do want to give &#8212; I do want to give a real shout-out to Secretary Yellen, who&#8217;s worked very hard in this space and has accomplished a lot in terms of working with our global partners.</p>



<p>And I think one of the things you got when Joe Biden came to the White House is a President who was going to reengage with global partners in a way that delivered the progress we&#8217;ve made thus far.</p>



<p>I also want to say something about this idea that has come up in some recent discussions that somehow increasing taxes leads to higher inflation.&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard for me to even put the phrase together because I think it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s really &#8212; it&#8217;s really the other way.</p>



<p>When you &#8212; when you increase taxes, particularly on those the most &#8212; particularly on those at the highest incomes &#8212; so you&#8217;re not talking about people who are liquidity constrained for whom inflation is nearly the problem that it is for middle- or lower-income people.&nbsp; When you&#8217;re talking about tax increases for those at the top of the income scale, this is deficit reducing, and reducing the deficit is disinflationary, not inflationary.</p>



<p>By the way, just a side note here &#8212; I was just looking at some of these numbers in my preparation for the shows I did yesterday: The budget deficit has come down 77 percent in this fiscal year, in the nine months of this fiscal year, from October 21 through June 22.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the largest decline on record over that part of a fiscal year.&nbsp; And I know some people say, “Well, that&#8217;s all just spending coming off of the Rescue Plan.”&nbsp; In fact, spending is down &#8212; spending is down eigh- &#8212; I think I have these numbers right.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Spending is down 18 percent.&nbsp; Receipts &#8212; tax receipts are up 26 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll put these later out on my blog today, @EconJared46.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to put these out, so I have these I &#8212; I&#8217;m pretty sure I&#8217;m remembering them correctly.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About the global tax deal?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;ll get back to that in a second.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So, deficit reduction &#8212; deficit reduction is disinflationary, and tax increases, you know, fit into that.</p>



<p>Now, in terms of the global tax deal, there&#8217;s a lot of moving parts going on with that right now, Jim.&nbsp; The President remains fully committed to this; the Treasury Secretary fully committed to this.&nbsp; We have a staff that&#8217;s worked on this intensely for month after month after month.&nbsp; And it is &#8212; it is &#8212; any rumors of its demise are hugely premature.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, Kelly O, last question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have one quick follow-up and then one question.&nbsp; On the issue, right off the bat, that Jeff asked about &#8212; preparing for a recession: Understanding that you made it clear that you don&#8217;t see those factors, how important is it for you to give the President guidance on what could trigger a recession so that he can take action?</p>



<p>And then secondly, what have you learned from your national security colleagues about what came out of Saudi Arabia and how that might affect gas prices and your expectations on what OPEC and others might do in a few weeks?&nbsp; “In a few weeks” is what the President had said.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Let me start with the second part of your question.&nbsp; We saw Saudi Arabia say it would work to increase its capacity for oil production.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d refer you to them for more information on that.</p>



<p>Remember, they&#8217;re a key member, of course, of the OPEC cartel.&nbsp; And as the President said, we welcomed their decision &#8212; OPEC’s decision &#8212; to increase production by 50 percent above what was planned for July and August.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s already in the mix.</p>



<p>Now, in terms of keeping the President abreast of these issues, one of the things we do at CEA &#8212; I don&#8217;t know how &#8212; this is one of the ways we spend a lot of our time, and I suspect folks know about it, but just so you know &#8212; is that every economic report that we get, we write up and we put it in the President&#8217;s book: industrial production, GDP, jobs, inflation, every &#8212; retail sales.&nbsp; We, and particularly Chair Cecilia Rouse of the CEA, are in very close contact with the President and senior staff, always updating him on economic conditions.&nbsp; So there&#8217;s nothing I&#8217;ve told you today that he doesn&#8217;t know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so in terms of his preparation for the potential of a recession, he&#8217;s getting advised on that on a day-to-day basis?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; He is getting full information, just as I hope I&#8217;ve given you today, on current economic conditions and anything we can see around the corner.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jared.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you for your time.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; My pleasure.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We kept you long.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Come back any time.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; My pleasure.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I forgot &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’d be a good Scrabble partner.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; I agree.&nbsp; I agree.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And welcome back to everyone who traveled with us to the Middle East.</p>



<p>Okay, I have one thing at the top, and then we&#8217;ll get going.</p>



<p>So I want to call out a few reports from over the weekend that illustrate exactly what we are talking about when we say the impacts of the Court’s decisions are devastating, extreme, and threaten &#8212; and threaten women&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; This is the Court decisions on Dobbs that came down almost three weeks ago.</p>



<p>These reports also pull back the curtain on what some elected Republicans officials are trying to do by taking away your rights, taking away freedoms, and taking away privacy.</p>



<p>First, before Texas’s extreme abortion law took effect, it was reported that one woman there received a standard procedure for a first trimester miscarriage.&nbsp; But after the extreme law, it was reported that when she had another first trimester miscarriage, the same hospital wouldn&#8217;t perform the same standard procedure.&nbsp; Instead, they sent her home.&nbsp; They told her to return to the hospital only if her bleeding was so excessive it filled a diaper more than once an hour.</p>



<p>This is outrageous.<br><br>Now, another report we&#8217;re hearing: Republicans in Congress &#8212; more than 100 of whom have already said they&#8217;re in favor of a natio- &#8212; of a nationwide abortion ban &#8212; are being urged by extremist groups to focus on instituting such a ban at the federal level.<br><br>So I want to repeat that again: a ban at the federal level, not just state by state.<br><br>So this would criminalize doctors and other healthcare providers who provide abortions in every state across the country.&nbsp; It&#8217;s becoming clearer by the day that congressional Republicans want to strip away rights, starting with a nationwide abortion ban and moving on to marriage equality and contraception.<br><br>With that, I welcome you to your first time in the AP seat, right?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, Seung Min, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple quick questions on the Saudi trip.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if the President believes that the trip was a success and worth the criticism that he faced domestically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, following up a little bit on Kelly&#8217;s question, when precisely will Americans start to see tangible benefits coming from the trip?&nbsp; Is it the next OPEC+ meeting?&nbsp; The President did seem to indicate something in the coming weeks.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So just going back &#8212; starting with your last question first &#8212; and Jared basically touched on this, which is: We have to remember, in early &#8212; in early June, OPEC+, which is &#8212; Saudi Arabia clearly chairs OPEC+ &#8212; made that announcement that we welcomed about increasing their production 50 percent in July and August.<br><br>The conversations that the President had in Saudi Arabia, in the bilateral meeting &#8212; that he actually read out, as you all know, in a press conference that same Friday in Jeddah &#8212; they talked about energy securities.&nbsp; And Jake Sullivan actually said this as well, is that we measure &#8212; we will measure success in the &#8212; in the next couple of &#8212; next couple of weeks.&nbsp; We anticipate to be an increase of production.&nbsp; But again, it&#8217;s going to take the next couple of weeks.&nbsp; And that will be up to OPEC+.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, the President has talked, obviously, a lot about his support for a free and independent media, and so I’m wondering why the U.S. press did not get access to that greeting between President Biden and the Crown Prince and we had to rely on Saudi state media for the images of that fist bump.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, first &#8212; first thing, because I do want to touch &#8212; you asked me another question about what we believe got done.&nbsp; So let me just read off a couple of things there.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll get to your &#8212; your most recent question there.&nbsp;<br><br>So, just so that folks know: Saudi Arabia announced it will open Saudi airspace for flights to and from Israel &#8212; a historic decision that will pave the way for a more integrated, stable, and secure Middle East.<br><br>As you know, when Jake Sullivan and I gaggled on the plane when the President flew from Israel to &#8212; to Saudi Arabia, that was a historic flight.&nbsp; So just want to make sure that we &#8212; we acknowledge that.<br><br>The GCC+3 pledged billions to address food &#8212; food security resulting from Putin&#8217;s war against Ukraine.<br><br>Saudi Arabia committed to support global oil market balancing for suspended economic growth.&nbsp; This is what you were just asking me about.&nbsp; The United States has welcomed the OPEC+ decision to increase production by 50 percent.<br><br>On the climate crisis, which is also part of the agenda, we&#8217;re collecting invest- &#8212; collectively investing hundreds of billions of dollars in clean energy initiatives, increasing our climate ambition and working together to diversify supply chains and invest in critical infrastructure.<br><br>And we&#8217;re doing everything possible to extend and strengthen the U.N.-medic- &#8212; -mediated truce in Yemen, which is the first one in seven years, where 70,000 Americans work and live.&nbsp; And so, again, we&#8217;re seeing the longest peace in that &#8212; there in Yemen in some time.<br><br>To your &#8212; to your first question: Look, we &#8212; as you know, we tried ev- &#8212; we do everything that we possibly can when we go to a host country to make sure that you all have access, that there is transparency, which is why you heard from the President directly and he held a press conference that Friday in Jeddah, as I just mentioned, so that he can read out himself what &#8212; what occurred in the bilat.&nbsp; And also, you all were able to ask questions.<br><br>Sometimes it is not perfect; we understand that.&nbsp; But we want you to know we do everything that we can to make sure that you all have access.&nbsp; We did that with the bilat, by having a pool spray at the top, and other &#8212; other &#8212; other meetings as well.<br><br>So we &#8212; we do our best.&nbsp; We want to make sure, again, that you guys hear from the President directly, you get to see what is occurring in some of the &#8212; some of these meetings that are happening.&nbsp; And we will continue to make sure that we make that a priority as we &#8212; as we continue to do our travels.</p>



<p><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Does the President &#8212; now that he&#8217;s back from &#8212; from Saudi Arabia, does the President still believe that Saudi Arabia and the Crown Prince should be considered a pariah, or did this trip change his view about that?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you heard from the President again on Friday, he made very clear that how he &#8212; that he made his views very clear to the Crown Prince on that during their bilat meeting.&nbsp; And he even said it would be inconsistent &#8212; right? &#8212; for a President of the United States not to speak of our values, not to &#8212; not to talk about human rights.&nbsp; And it would be inconsistent, to be quite frank, of Joe Biden not to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>So he was very clear about where &#8212; about where he stood about Jamal Khashoggi’s death, murder.&nbsp; He mentioned it from the start of their meeting.<br><br>And when it comes to &#8212; you know, his &#8212; his comments stand.&nbsp; You know, they &#8212; he has &#8212; he has been pretty clear about that, about &#8212; about where he stands on the comments that he made during the campaign.</p>



<p>And look, I think one of the other things that I do want to be very clear about is, you know, if we&#8217;re going to talk about human rights, if we&#8217;re going to talk about our values, we believe &#8212; he believes it’s important to have that straightforward leader-to-leader conversation.<br><br>The President has talked about that many times, about how important it is to talk directly and frankly with leaders when it comes to our values, when it comes to issues like human rights.&nbsp; And he will continue &#8212; he will continue to have those conversations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yet the Saudis say that that conversation about Khashoggi never happened.&nbsp; The foreign minister says he was there and he didn&#8217;t hear the President confront MBS in that way.&nbsp; So are they lying about that?&nbsp; And if so, does that indicate that, actually, they are not getting the message?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this: The President was asked this question and he spoke to it directly.&nbsp; And I do believe that, you know, if &#8212; if anyone telling you differently about what the President said, they weren&#8217;t listening to the President himself when he was asked that question, when he spoke about how he brought up the death of Jamal Khashoggi.&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll leave &#8212; I&#8217;ll leave it to what the President said when he was asked directly most recently about that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; On the Uvalde school shooting, was the President briefed on the findings by the Texas state legislators investigating the law enforcement response, the report that was just released?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So he&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s aware of the report.&nbsp; I will say this: It is &#8212; it is devastating &#8212; the report.&nbsp; It adds &#8212; and, frankly, unacceptable &#8212; the report that came out just, I believe, just yesterday.&nbsp; You know, it adds on more questions to how law enforcements reacted, their role on that &#8212; on that day &#8212; on that tragic day.</p>



<p>As you all know, we&#8217;ve mentioned this before and you heard from the Department of Justice, they are doing their own review.&nbsp; And so I will leave that &#8212; their own independent review of what &#8212; exactly what happened that day.&nbsp; And so I will leave that to them on any further comments.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what was the President&#8217;s reaction when he was made aware of this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I wasn&#8217;t there when he was made aware, but I do know that he is &#8212; he&#8217;s aware of the report.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on oil and gas prices, Jared Bernstein came out, seemed to highlight these prices being down.&nbsp; But many industry analysts think that this could be just a temporary reprieve, that these prices could very well be going up again, maybe even in the fall.&nbsp; Oil was trading above $100 today.&nbsp; How concerned is the administration that oil and gas prices could be on the upswing again in the short term?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, the President is going to continue to do everything that he can to make sure that the &#8212; the American public gets that &#8212; continues to get that little bit of relief.</p>



<p>Look, what we&#8217;re seeing here today, what we&#8217;re seeing in the last 34 days and that 50 cents &#8212; now we&#8217;re seeing 50 cents on average per gallon that has come down. &nbsp;We see, in 30 states across the country, we see a gallon &#8212; we see gas at $3.99.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like &#8212; like Jared said, we&#8217;re not doing a victory lap, but this is important.&nbsp; This is important to note that the work that we have done, the work that we will continue to do is going to give relief &#8212; $25 a month &#8212; to American families.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re talking about nurses. &nbsp;We&#8217;re talking about teac- &#8212; teachers. &nbsp;We&#8217;re talking about firefighters.&nbsp; This is going to have a real impact on their lives.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and so, look, you know, what we&#8217;re looking at is what we&#8217;re seeing currently, what we&#8217;re seeing at this moment. &nbsp;&nbsp;And I think it&#8217;s important to lift that up.<br><br>And again, the 1 million barrels a day from the Strategic Petroleum &#8212; a historic &#8212; historic action by the President; the 240 million barrels that the President was able to get leaders to do; the ethanol 15, which is the homegrown biofuels which helped lower gas prices across &#8212; in gas stations across the country &#8212; all of these actions are important.</p>



<p>Now, do we need to do more as we talk about inflation, as we talk about the elevated number that we&#8217;re &#8212; that we&#8217;re seeing in inflation?&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the President is going to continue to work with Congress to make sure that we&#8217;re lowering costs for the American families &#8212; like prescription drugs, for example.&nbsp; And if we are able to do that, we are on the cusp, as Jared was saying, to making &#8212; to really winning against one of the wealthiest special interest groups, which is Big Pharma.&nbsp;<br><br>All of these things are important to note. &nbsp;And again, we&#8217;re just going to continue doing the work.&nbsp; But also, we want to highlight what has occurred these past 34 days.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, what is the White House&#8217;s strategy now for engaging with Senator Manchin going forward?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as &#8212; as we like to say here, we’re not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp; We &#8212; you know, the President and Senator Manchin have a very close relationship.&nbsp; We will continue to have the conversations that we have been having with him for the past 18 months on a different &#8212; a variety of issues. &nbsp;But again, not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp;<br><br>But we do want to &#8212; want to lift up, you know, what we&#8217;re &#8212; what&#8217;s about to happen.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re on the cusp of doing with the reconciliation bill is going to impact tens of millions of Americans lives.&nbsp; And that matters as we’re looking at healthcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When it comes to climate change, you saw the President&#8217;s statement just recently: If Senate doesn&#8217;t act on that and doesn&#8217;t take action on climate, he has a contingency plan, which is using his executive authority to make sure that we take &#8212; take on climate &#8212; climate change in a way that&#8217;s going to be effective.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have anything to read out to you on that particular action.&nbsp; But again, we&#8217;re not going to negotiate from here, and we&#8217;re going to just continue to make sure that we deliver for the American public.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you feel like Senator Manchin led the White House on with regard to climate?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate in public here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to lean in or give any &#8212; pull back the curtain on private conversations.</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re &#8212; we are prepared to act if need be, if Senate is not able to include the climate provisions that we have discussed.</p>



<p>But again, what we&#8217;re seeing right now with &#8212; with the reconciliation as it relates to Medicare and being able for Medicare to negotiate bringing down drug prices, that is an important step.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re going to continue to do the work.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when you say and the President says he&#8217;s prepared to act on climate, what&#8217;s the timeframe for that?&nbsp; Do you wait until the fall?&nbsp; Do you get started before that?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the overall timeframe?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a timeline for you at this point.&nbsp; As you know, discussions, negotiations are currently happening.&nbsp; And so we will see where the Senate lands.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You spoke before the trip about advising the President about reducing contact due to COVID and the variants.&nbsp; And we saw some fist bumping, but we also saw some embraces and some handshakes and so forth.&nbsp; So just for record-keeping purposes, has the President had a negative test since he returned home?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I would have to check with our team.&nbsp; As you know, he gets regularly tested, as &#8212; as &#8212; you know, as the advice from his doctor.&nbsp; So he has a regular cadence that his doctor decides on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We did provide, on &#8212; on the gaggle last week, I provided that he had tested negative on his &#8212; right before heading out to the Middle East.&nbsp; And then we sent out a pool note, as &#8212; I believe as we were going to Saudi Arabia, because there were testing requirements, and he had tested negative then.</p>



<p>I will work to get that information for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If we could make certain of that &#8212;</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Absolutely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; since we don’t see him in public today.</p>



<p>And the First Lady of Ukraine is coming and has scheduled for a visit with Dr. Biden.&nbsp; Do you expect the President will drop in on that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don’t have any more details to share with you.&nbsp; I know she’s meeting with Secretary Blinken today.&nbsp; She’s meeting &#8212; this is the First Lady of Ukraine &#8212; is also going to be meeting with Administrator Power.<br><br>Once we have more information on our side on what the schedule looks like this week and if that includes her, we will certainly share that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, I &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I’ll come to you after.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just following up on something &#8212; something the Vice President said today.&nbsp; Does the President agree with her that the recent Supreme Court decision on abortion access is similar to slavery?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I have not seen her comments.&nbsp; I would like to see her comments for myself before &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The comment was, “We know, NAACP, that our country has a history of claiming ownership over human bodies.&nbsp; And today, extremists, so-called leaders, are criminalizing doctors and punishing women from making healthcare decisions for themselves.”</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, she is correct: Today&#8217;s decisions are criminalizing doctors and essentially taking the rights away from women, taking the freedom away from women, really taking away people&#8217;s privacy.&nbsp; That does matter, and that is important.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And she’s invoking slavery.&nbsp; So the President agrees?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, for me &#8212; I appreciate you reading out what she said &#8212; I need to actually see exactly what was &#8212; what was &#8212; what was said and in what &#8212; in what complete context.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I need to do as a spokesperson for the administration.</p>



<p>But I will say that second part of what you just said, the Vice President is actually right.&nbsp; I just &#8212; I just &#8212; at the top, I just laid out what women are going through in this country because of an extreme decision that SCOTUS made.&nbsp; Because of what they did, it is going to upend and change the lives of women across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have to be &#8212; we &#8212; now we have to be mindful about contraception, we have to be mindful about marriage equality, because they have made it really clear &#8212; extreme Republicans, ultra-MAGA Republicans have made it clear that that is what they&#8217;re going after next.&nbsp; So that does matter.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then following up about this comment that the Saudis say did not happen but the President says did happen: Did you personally hear the President raise the issue of Khashoggi’s murder with MBS?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I trust the President.&nbsp; He &#8212; he made those comments, as you heard directly from him, during &#8212; during the press conference.&nbsp; And he said at the top of the meeting, he mentioned Jamal Khashoggi.</p>



<p>And so &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you did not hear him say that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying to you that the President himself &#8212; I was not in the meeting, to answer that question.&nbsp; But the President himself said and laid out very clearly &#8212; and &#8212; and just to be clear, that press conference happened because he wanted to make sure that you all heard from him directly.&nbsp; That was the President&#8217;s decision.&nbsp; He wanted to make sure that he read out what occurred in the bilateral meeting with &#8212; with the Saudi &#8212; Saudi Arabia government.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; so, ultimately, we get back from this trip, there&#8217;s no new peace talks in the Middle East, there&#8217;s no new commitment to increase oil production in the Gulf.&nbsp; So what was the point of this trip?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just read out earlier, Peter, of all of the things that had occurred that we &#8212; some of the do-outs or the &#8212; some of the things that we were able to get done during this trip.</p>



<p>Look, I want to &#8212; let&#8217;s step back for a second and talk about what the President was trying to do on this trip.&nbsp; If you look at this region, the Middle East, it&#8217;s a critical region. The President &#8212; his intent was to make sure that there was not a vacuum in the region so that you didn&#8217;t have China and Russia stepping in trying to fill that vacuum.</p>



<p>And so it&#8217;s important for the United States to make sure that we&#8217;re having those conversations, direct leader-to-leader conversations, and that we &#8212; and that we talk about our national security, we talk about food security, we talk about climate change.&nbsp; All are issues that are important to the American family.</p>



<p>And so as it relates to the oil production &#8212; I talked about and Jared talked about what OPEC &#8212; OPEC+ did early in June &#8212; we are confident that we will be able to measure how &#8212; the success of those conversations that the President had in the next several weeks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not insist on a commitment though?&nbsp; He gets back with no commitment, and the price of oil per barrel shot up.&nbsp; Is that what the President wanted, to go there and have the price of oil get more expensive?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let&#8217;s &#8212; so, again &#8212; but again, we have seen gas prices go down in the past 34 straight days &#8212; go down &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Aren’t they still $2 a gallon higher than when you guys took office though?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; First of all, we have to look at the imp- &#8212; at how we got there, right?&nbsp; You think about the war that Russia has taken on in Ukraine &#8212; an unmitigated war, a war that is brutal and that has had an effect on the price gases going up almost $2.&nbsp; We have talked about that endlessly.&nbsp; And also, we are also in a once-in-a-generation pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there are outside factors that has led to gas prices going up, to food prices going up, to inflation going up.&nbsp; So that is really important.</p>



<p>What we have seen in the last 34 days is that gas prices have gone down by 50 &#8212; on average, by 50 cents a gallon.&nbsp; That matters.&nbsp; That matters to teachers, that matters to firefighters, that matters to nurses, that matters to everyday people.&nbsp; And the President is going to continue to do the work to make sure the prices go down.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to go &#8212; I&#8217;m going to continue, Peter.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Actually, let me try and go to people I haven&#8217;t called on.&nbsp; Go ahead, Jenny.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Jared was just talking about the broader reconciliation bill, which would have increased taxes on the wealthy, and he said this is not something that he views as inflationary.&nbsp; You know, you guys have talked about how this would reduce the deficit.</p>



<p>So with Senator Manchin saying his exact, you know, concern with doing a bill like this is inflation, does the White House regard that claim as credible?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: We have heard from economic experts out there.&nbsp; We have heard from even Jason Furman, folks who are critical of us who have said that &#8212; said the opposite: that the President&#8217;s plan on reconciliation will actually bring down inflation &#8212; an anti-inflation bill, if you will.</p>



<p>And if you look at &#8212; if you look at &#8212; when you bring down the deficit, as you all know, that actually will help inflation.</p>



<p>So, look, I&#8217;ll lead you to the expert.&nbsp; I am not an economic expert.&nbsp; But they have said themselves this is an anti-inflation bill and it will help &#8212; help with that fight and what we&#8217;re trying to do, which is our number one economic priority, the President&#8217;s number one economic priority, which is bring inflation down.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you don&#8217;t really see Senator Manchin’s claim that inflation is why he pumped the brakes on it as a credible claim?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I can’t &#8212; I am not a spokesperson for Senator Joe Manchin.&nbsp; As you know, I am a spokesperson for the President of the United States.&nbsp; And what I can tell you is what experts have said &#8212; economic experts have said.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s where I will send you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on the CHIPS bill, which seems like actually it’s moving forward this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, congrats.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a provision that seems to be a little bit fluid on whether or not to prohibit certain investments if you take semiconductor subsidies in China.&nbsp; Intel is one of the companies that is lobbying against this.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House stance on this?&nbsp; And do you have a message for Intel and companies like that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: The CHIPS Act is intended to bolster American competitiveness and our own domestic supply chain security.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we continue to support strong guardrails, as you &#8212; as you&#8217;re alluding to there, Jenny, which also have bipartisan support in Congress, to make sure CHIPS incentives generate more semiconductor investment here in the U.S., not in China.&nbsp; So &#8212; and guardrails help slow the growth of investment in China.&nbsp; That is why such an important part of the bill &#8212; it is such an important part of the bill.&nbsp; And &#8212; and we believe in strong guardrails.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Ken.&nbsp; I said I would get back to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Karine, on Ukraine, President Zelenskyy replaced his head of domestic intelligence and the prosecutor general.&nbsp; He said during the weekend that hundreds of treason investigations have been opened on new employees of law enforcement agencies.&nbsp; Is there any concern that Russia may be infiltrating Ukraine security networks and undermining the war effort?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I mean, I&#8217;ll say this: You know, we, per usual, don&#8217;t speak to any personnel arrangements or domestic politics.&nbsp; That is not something that I will do from him here. But I&#8217;ll say this: For our part, we will continue to work with our partners in Ukraine to help them defend against Russian aggression and with the Ukrainian Prosecutor General&#8217;s office as they document the war crimes and atrocities that Russian forces in Ukraine are committing.&nbsp; We also continue to support Ukraine&#8217;s ongoing anti-corruption reforms as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Senator Cruz, over the weekend, said on his podcast that the Supreme Court was clearly wrong in overreaching when it legalized same-sex marriage in 2015.&nbsp; What is the White House view on that?&nbsp; Is &#8212; does that raise a lot of concerns?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I’ll &#8212; it should &#8212; it should raise concerns.&nbsp; As we know from the Dobbs decision, one of the things that we saw from &#8212; from <s>Judge</s> <s>Thompson</s> [Justice Thomas] is that they&#8217;re looking to go further, whether it&#8217;s privacy, contraception, or marriage equality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, you know, you all know that this President has supported marriage equality for some time.&nbsp; This is something that he believes in, and this is something that he will &#8212; he will continue to fight for.</p>



<p>I’m trying to call folks I haven’t called on.</p>



<p>Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Did the President urge Saudi Arabia to stop purchasing oil from Russia?&nbsp; Because Saudi Arabia has actually doubled its Russian oil imports this quarter, which is, of course, helping Russia’s cash flow.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out for you on that.&nbsp; As you know, at the G7, one of the conversations that came up when the President was there recently in Europe, in Germany specifically, was how to put a cap on Russia &#8212; Russia oil.&nbsp; That is a conversation that was started.&nbsp; It is continuing on the staff level.&nbsp; And that, as you know, will have an effect on &#8212; on the price of Russia&#8217;s oil.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re continuing to have those discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you spoke earlier about the President&#8217;s contingency plan regarding taking executive actions on climate, but do you believe the President can still keep the commitments he made to world leaders on reducing emissions through executive actions if Congress fails to act?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to do everything that we can to make sure that we are taking action on climate &#8212; the climate crisis.&nbsp; And so, again, the President has &#8212; I think Jared read this all &#8212; read this already, but just want to reiterate what he said: From day one, he fina- &#8212; the President finalized regulations to rapidly phase out super pollutants.&nbsp; He jumpstarted the offshore industry.&nbsp; And he set the strongest-ever emissions standard for cars and trucks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is something that is incredibly important to the President.&nbsp; He thinks it is &#8212; it is urgent to act on the climate crisis, to take action.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why if Congress &#8212; Senate doesn&#8217;t act on the climate component of reconciliation, he&#8217;s ready to take executive &#8212; use his executive authority.</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to see who I haven’t called on.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Senator McConnell says President Biden planned to nominate Chad Meredith, an anti-abortion Federalist Society member for Kentucky District Judge position as a, quote, “personal friendship gesture.”&nbsp; Why would the President do that when he&#8217;s vowed that DOJ will do everything in their power to protect women&#8217;s access to abortion?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So what I&#8217;ll say on that is that, as you heard from Rand Paul, he was not ready &#8212; he&#8217;s not &#8212; he&#8217;s not ready to move forward with the blue <s>chip</s> [slip] &#8212; is that process in the Senate.&nbsp; And so we are not going to be nominating Chad Meredith.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was it initially a personal friendship gesture, as Senator McConnell said?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That part of &#8212; of your comment is not something that I&#8217;m aware of.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just telling you where we are currently at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But generally speaking, why was the President planning to nominate Mr. Meredith in the first place, given that he has said that DOJ would do everything in its power to protect abortion access for women?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, that doesn&#8217;t &#8212; that doesn&#8217;t change anything.&nbsp; DOJ is going to do everything in its power.&nbsp; You heard directly from the President about that.&nbsp; You heard &#8212; he signed an executive order on what DOJ is going to do and what &#8212; and formalizing what DOJ is going to do, and formalizing what HHS is going to do.</p>



<p>That is something that the President is in &#8212; is very much committed to.&nbsp; And certainly, he&#8217;s not going to back away from that.&nbsp; He wants to make sure that women&#8217;s rights are protected. Just talked about what could happen next, which is a national ban on abortion, which would be devastating for so many women across the country.&nbsp; We talked about what else Republicans are thinking about doing when it comes to contraception, when it comes to privacy, when it comes to marriage equality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is &#8212; this is a very serious time.&nbsp; And we need to make sure that we are paying attention to what potentially could &#8212; could be happening next.&nbsp; And so, again, I don&#8217;t have much more to add on your question.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Is the administration in touch with the authorities in Ghana?&nbsp; I know the &#8212; Ghana declared today their first &#8212; their first-ever outbreak of Marburg virus disease.&nbsp; Is the White House in touch with them?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that last part.&nbsp; The what disease?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Marburg.&nbsp; It’s called Marburg &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Mar- &#8212; okay, let me &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; virus disease.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, let me go back to the team and get more info on &#8212; for you on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, what&#8217;s your strategy in reassuring the international community that, yes, the President met with the killer of Saudi Arabia but the U.S. remain committed in human right?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; so this is what I said earlier to someone who asked me: The President be- &#8212; the President believes that it is important &#8212; as we are talking about human rights, as we are talking about American values, it is important to have those frank and direct conversations with leaders and be very, very clear on where we stand as a country.<br><br>This is what the President &#8212; you heard directly from him when he held a press conference in Jeddah, as I&#8217;ve stated many times at this point today, this afternoon.&nbsp; He made that very clear.&nbsp; He spoke directly, he spoke firmly, and that is a convers- &#8212; a continuing conversation that he is going to have.<br><br>Human rights issues come up frequently when he is meeting leader-to-leader.&nbsp; That will not stop.&nbsp; That will not end.&nbsp; And this is something that the President has been committed to for &#8212; for his entire career.<br><br>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Just picking up on climate, you mentioned that there&#8217;s no timeline on the administration taking action.&nbsp; But does the administration have an executive order or executive plans ready?&nbsp; Or is &#8212; does there need to be a process to consult, to plan?&nbsp; I mean, how far along are you in the process?&nbsp; I mean, how have you been preparing for the contingency?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you at this time, is what I was trying to say.&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to comment on any specific action.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the process &#8212; of the policy process, and certainly don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President.<br><br>But what I &#8212; the point that we are trying to make here is that he is committed to taking action on climate &#8212; on climate change, on clim- &#8212; taking action on climate.<br><br>But right now, I just don&#8217;t have anything to share at this point.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is there anything you can share on what &#8212; how has the administration been in the process of preparing for this type of contingency?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’m &#8212; I&#8217;m not getting ahead of the policy process.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; Can you just say when the President will announce his decision on China tariffs?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I &#8212; we &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything more to read out for you on China tariffs.<br><br>Look, the way that it was handled by the last administration was &#8212; was &#8212; you know, they &#8212; it got &#8212; it was bungled.&nbsp; If you &#8212; if you &#8212; if I’m going to be really, you know, honest here, it was not done in an effective way.&nbsp; China has not done their part.&nbsp; And so, the President wants to make sure that &#8212; that his team is looking at every option, is looking at exactly how to move forward.<br><br>We just don&#8217;t have an announcement to share or anything to preview at this time.</p>



<p><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to go back to Senator Manchin and the energy provisions, he said on the radio, on Friday, that he didn&#8217;t tell Senator Schumer that he was out on the energy and climate provisions, just that he wanted to see another month of inflation data.&nbsp; So if it&#8217;s such a crisis that the President is bent on dealing with &#8212; the climate crisis &#8212; why not wait another month to see what the inflation data, which the administration thinks will be better, look like and see if you can get Senator Manchin on board for legislation?&nbsp; Is the President effectively saying he doesn&#8217;t believe that the odds are good of that happening if he waited an extra month?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp; Well right now the Senate is still hav- &#8212; are still in talks; they&#8217;re still negotiating.&nbsp; And so the President has put &#8212; put forth a contingency plan.&nbsp; If that climate change provision that we have been discussing is not in that Senate reconciliation plan, he will act.&nbsp;<br><br>But right now, we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re letting the negotiations happen.&nbsp; We&#8217;re letting that process continue.&nbsp; Again, we don&#8217;t negotiate in public.<br><br>But again, what we&#8217;re trying to say here is the President is &#8212; is ready to act when &#8212; if needed.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, because in his statement he said he wants a bill by August, which would seem to rule out waiting for Senator Manchin.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, the process is still &#8212; is still happening.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I’m not going to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; It &#8212; we are &#8212; what is today?&nbsp; July &#8212; I don&#8217;t even know.&nbsp; July 18th?&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And so, let &#8212; we&#8217;re going to let &#8212; let the Senate work on the reconc- &#8212; reconciliation bill, let them have the &#8212; the conversations and negotiations.&nbsp; I’m just not going to get ahead of that at this time.</p>



<p><br>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, Ashley.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Asking sort of the flip side of Jim&#8217;s question, I&#8217;m curious: Was there anything Senator Manchin ever conveyed to the White House that gave you guys any reason to believe that a West Virginia Democrat, in a state that Trump won by almost 40 points, who&#8217;s accepted millions of dollars from the fossil fuel industry would ever support any sort of climate provision?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to comment on private conversations.&nbsp; Again, that is not something that we do here.&nbsp; We say this all the time.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to comment on any back-and-forth that has occurred with Senator Manchin or any other congressional member.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to let the Senate continue to negotiate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When it comes to what we are seeing right now with the prescription drugs &#8212; I have said this; Jared said this &#8212; that is &#8212; that is &#8212; we&#8217;re on the cusp of a big win here, which is incredibly important for tens of millions of Americans, as we speak about Medicare and them being allowed to negotiate drug prices.</p>



<p><br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So just following up briefly: More broadly, I mean, do you have any reason to believe that you didn&#8217;t waste your time trying to get Senator Manchin on board for any sort of climate, you know, legislation?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to get into private conversations.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; All right, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; I would like to ask about Moscow using energy as a weapon in Europe.&nbsp; There is a growing fear that Russia will not restore natural gas deliveries to Europe after its ongoing annual maintenance of Nord Stream 1, which could lead to a serious crisis in Europe, to gas rati- &#8212; rationing.&nbsp; How concerned is the President that it may weaken Europe&#8217;s resolve?&nbsp; And what the U.S. is doing to help?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So a couple of things.&nbsp; I just want to lay this down, because it&#8217;s an important question that we want to address.<br><br>So following, as you know, the further invasion of Ukraine, Russia continues to use natural &#8212; natural gas as a political and economic weapon, as you’re &#8212; as you&#8217;re stating, Merrick.&nbsp;<br><br>Russia&#8217;s energy corrosion has put pressure on energy markets, raised prices for consumers, and threatened global energy security.<br><br>These actions only underscore the importance of the work both the United States and the European Commission are doing to end our reliance on Russian energy.</p>



<p>President Biden formed a task force, as you all know &#8212; we&#8217;ve announced that here &#8212; on European energy security with EU President von der Leyen.&nbsp; The task force has met regularly to discuss options to reduce Europe&#8217;s depen- &#8212; demand for natural gas.&nbsp; It has also met with key stakeholders to promote the deployment of heat pumps, smart thermostats, and energy demand response solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are also partnering to diversify energy supplies to Europe.&nbsp; Since March, global LNG exports to Europe have &#8212; have risen by 75 percent compared to 2021, while the U.S. LNG exports to Europe have nearly tripled.&nbsp; So, we continue to work with our European partners to reduce the dependence on energ- &#8212; of Europe on Russian energy, to be exact.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that enough to help Europe to survive the winter?&nbsp; Russia may at any point, anytime, cut gas &#8212; natural gas deliveries to Europe.&nbsp; It&#8217;s real fear in Europe right now.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, we understand that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we created the task force, and the task force is going to do everything that we can to make sure that we deal that the depend- &#8212; that we deal with the dependence that Europe &#8212; European countries have on &#8212; on Russian oil.</p>



<p>Look, we have seen &#8212; I just laid out &#8212; we have seen some progress.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to just kind of continue to work with our European partners.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;d like &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I was calling the gentleman in front.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On abortion: In two weeks, Kansas is going to vote &#8212; they&#8217;re going to be the first state to vote on the abortion issue.&nbsp; How much stake is the administration putting on the result of that election, given the fact that, you know, they&#8217;re going to be (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I can&#8217;t speak directly to any specific elections.&nbsp; Look, the President has made clear: When we &#8212; when we &#8212; when we talk about &#8212; when we talk about choice and we talk about where we are currently with abortion, when we talk about Republicans who are trying to make a national ban across the country, this is very serious, dangerous outcomes that could &#8212; that are &#8212; that we&#8217;re facing with.</p>



<p>And so the President has been very clear: To make sure that Americans get their voices heard and take it to the ballot box, that is the way that we&#8217;re going to see real change.&nbsp; That is the way that we can use our political power.</p>



<p>He&#8217;s going to continue to say that but, at the same time, do everything that he can as &#8212; from his executive authority, to &#8212; to what he can with the federal government, to protect &#8212; to protect women.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then marriage came up earlier.&nbsp; The House is expected to vote on the Protect Our Marriage Act, I think tomorrow.&nbsp; How much work will the administration be doing to try and get that bill through the Senate where it&#8217;s going to face much more (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we support that act, and we &#8212; we applaud &#8212; we applaud Congress for moving forward.</p>



<p>As I mentioned earlier when I was just asked a question about marriage equality, this is &#8212; this is an issue that the President has been fighting for and speaking about for many, many years.&nbsp; And so this is certainly something that we support.</p>



<p><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One of my colleagues at Politico are reporting today that the ACLU obtained, and has since released, records publicly from DHS that show use of mobile location data harvested from apps on hundreds of millions of phones.&nbsp; DHS was then able to use 336,000 location data points across North America.<br><br>This started under the Trump administration, and contracts have been renewed under the Biden administration, basically tracking &#8212; knowing where people are.<br><br>When it comes to what DHS does, the work that DHS does, does the President stand by using location data on this scale, especially in light of concerns of the use of phone data when it comes to period-tracking apps, which the administration has talked about quite a bit?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I have not seen this data, so I need to take a look at it so that I can respond in a way that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s fulsome and be able to answer your question.&nbsp; I just haven&#8217;t seen that data.&nbsp; But I refer you at &#8212; any more specifics on that &#8212; clearly, I’ll refer you to the Department of Homeland Security.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But in general, does the administration &#8212; how does the administration feel about using location data on their &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Honestly, Eugene, I just need &#8212; in order for me to respond to your question, I just need to see exactly what you&#8217;re asking me about and what &#8212; and what the data is.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t do that without knowing the specifics.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And back to the firing of the Prosecutor General in Ukraine, how concerned is the administration, given how closely she&#8217;s been working with AG Garland?&nbsp; And she was also replaced by someone who&#8217;s been credibly accused of corruption.&nbsp; How concerned is the administration (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll say this: Like I said, we don&#8217;t get involved and don&#8217;t comment on any political domes- &#8212; domestic politics that happens in another country.<br><br>We&#8217;re going to continue to work closely with Ukraine on their fight for democracy, on their fight against Russia&#8217;s aggression, and also their corruption reform.&nbsp; As I just stated, we’ll work &#8212; we’ll continue to work with them on that.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll take one more question.&nbsp; Let me &#8212; go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Without congressional action on climate, does the White House, does the President see any viable path for reaching his goal of the U.S. cutting carbon emissions in half by 2030?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that again.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t hear you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Without congressional action on climate, does the President see any viable path to reaching his goal of cutting carbon emissions in half by 2030?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, again, negotiations are still happening, and so we leave that to Senate and see exactly what is &#8212; what the next &#8212; what the process is go- &#8212; where the process is going to land.</p>



<p>The President is, again, ready to act, ready to take executive authority &#8212; use his executive authority if &#8212; if that climate change provision is not included in the reconciliation bill.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics or get into hypotheticals at this time, but we&#8217;re going to continue &#8212; again, to just let the Senate work.</p>



<p>I’m &#8212; MJ, I know you had a question.&nbsp; I’m going to let you go ahead and ask a question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he think that goal can be reached just using executive authority?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to get into hypotheticals.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see where negotiations go.&nbsp; The President &#8212; as you know, as we have said &#8212; he is committed to taking on &#8212; taking on climate change.&nbsp; He thinks that it is urgent to do that; there&#8217;s an urgent matter to do that now.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so we&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to let the negotiations continue.&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from public or speak to hypotheticals.</p>



<p>Go ahead, MJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have two quick questions.&nbsp; First, on the baby formula: The recent data indicates that more than 20 percent of formula products are still out of stock.&nbsp; Just wondering what the White House&#8217;s assessment is right now of why that is the case, particularly given that we&#8217;ve seen, you know, for weeks now, a ton of formula being flown into the country.&nbsp; And does it have a sense of when things will actually start to normalize?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: The federal government has worked in lockstep with private &#8212; private sector to ramp up domestic production and to increase the supply of safe infant formula, which we understand is incredibly critical for families across the country as they&#8217;re trying to make sure that they&#8217;re feeding their &#8212; their babies, their children, safe &#8212; safe baby formula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is what this is all about &#8212; safety &#8212; and that&#8217;s our priority here, but also making sure that we&#8217;re doing everything that we can to get &#8212; to get that out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re ramping up domestic production, including invoking the Domestic Production Act, as you all know, which has allowed companies to increase production.&nbsp; We&#8217;re increasing imports.&nbsp; Already, the FDA has granted enforcement discretion for companies to import over 524.1 million 8-ounces bottles worth of infant formula, including over 5 million bottles of medical specialty formula, which is important as you&#8217;re asking me about formula and bottles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And third, we&#8217;re enhancing WIC flexibilities by waiving rules and restrictions that prevented low-income mothers from getting formula.&nbsp; All 50 states have taken action issuing more than 200 waivers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, this is a priority, continues to be a priority for us.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to do everything that we can to increase production.&nbsp; But &#8212; and &#8212; but again, we want to make sure that the safety is first.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just had one more follow-up on the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Saudi trip.&nbsp; When the President came back from his trip, he was asked if he regretted the fist bump with the Saudi Crown Prince, and he said, “Why don&#8217;t you guys talk about something that matters?”&nbsp; Can you just help us understand why he suggested that that fist bump did not matter?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s the thing: I think the way that the President looks at this is &#8212; is what were the issues, the agenda that was discussed, the policies that were &#8212; that were discussed, and what were the deliverables.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, when the President goes out to &#8212; just across the country and has these meetings, it is very important &#8212; you hear us talk about this all the time &#8212; having that leader-to-leader conversation.&nbsp; This is a President that has been, you know, a senator for decades.&nbsp; He was the Vice President.&nbsp; He was the President.&nbsp; He understands how &#8212; how this &#8212; these interaction works.&nbsp; He understands how these relationship works.&nbsp; He has &#8212; he has experience in it that is &#8212; that he believes is incredibly critical and important.</p>



<p>Look, again, when he went to the Middle East, it was making sure that there was not a void for countries like Russia or China to &#8212; to step into; to make sure that we were responding to Iran; to make sure that he had conversations not just with Saudi Arabia, but 12 &#8212; a dozen other leaders that were at the GCC+3.&nbsp; And not only that &#8212; he was in Israel right before he got to Jeddah.</p>



<p>So these are important &#8212; he believes these are important policies that are going to help the American public.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what he&#8217;s there for.&nbsp; When he goes out &#8212; yes, the region is important; yes, the region is critical.&nbsp; There&#8217;s national security conversations that need to be had and other agenda items that need to be talked about.&nbsp; But also, we&#8217;re talking about the Americans’ interests.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about how important it is to make sure that we are delivering as well here domestically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that is &#8212; that is the focus of the President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But on that comment, he does certainly understand why for a lot of people, including Jamal Khashoggi’s family or colleagues &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, absolutely.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that fist bump and that meeting with MBS mattered a lot, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll say this: The President spoke to &#8212; he was asked directly about Khashoggi, his fiancée.&nbsp; And he &#8212; you know, our hearts go out to &#8212; to her.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Our hear- &#8212; our hearts go out to his family, of course, and to his colleagues.&nbsp; Of course, we understand the pain that they are &#8212; that everyone is going through.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why when the President came into office, he released the Khashoggi report &#8212; something that the last administration did not do.&nbsp; This is a promise that he made to Congress.&nbsp; This was a promise that he made to the American people, to do that.&nbsp; And he took it a step further to make sure that there was the Khashoggi ban, which is that &#8212; which deals with visa and travel &#8212; and that has been used more than 70 times.</p>



<p>But we understand the pain that people are feeling, but he also wants to make sure &#8212; he also wants to make sure that we&#8217;re talking about the policy, that we&#8217;re talking about the agenda, that we&#8217;re talking about what occurred that is going to help the American public as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll see you tomorrow.</p>



<p>4:39 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with New Jersey State Legislators on Reproductive Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/18/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-new-jersey-state-legislators-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 02:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened more than 20 New Jersey state legislators, local leaders, and advocates who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights. Today’s meeting in Atlantic City, New Jersey follows engagements about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with health care providers, faith leaders, constitutional law and privacy experts,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened more than 20 New Jersey state legislators, local leaders, and advocates who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights. Today’s meeting in Atlantic City, New Jersey follows engagements about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with health care providers, faith leaders, constitutional law and privacy experts, advocates, state Attorneys General, and other state legislators. The Vice President convened state legislators at the White House on July 8, 2022; in Orlando, Florida on July 14, 2022; and in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania on July 16, 2022.<br> <br>The Vice President thanked the state legislators for their work protecting abortion access, highlighting the legislation passed so far to codify the right to abortion, provide funding to support reproductive health care services, and protect providers and privacy. The Vice President also thanked the leaders for pursuing further action to protect access to care, including by passing additional legislation. She also encouraged the legislators to look for ways to support and coordinate with state legislators from other states as part of a broad coalition to protect abortion access.<br> <br>The participants discussed how people do not need to give up their own beliefs to agree that the government should not interfere with women’s decisions over their own bodies. They agreed that everyone deserves to have access to health care and noted the importance of keeping equity at the center of the conversation. The leaders also discussed the need to improve maternal health care systems across New Jersey and the country, noting the connection between maternal health care and reproductive health care. The Vice President told the state legislators, local leaders, and the advocates that she looks forward to continuing to work together to protect reproductive rights and freedoms.<br> <br><strong>Speakers </strong></p>



<ul><li>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Administrator Chiquita Brooks-LaSure</li><li>New Jersey Attorney General Matthew Platkin</li><li>New Jersey Senate Majority Leader Teresa Ruiz</li><li>New Jersey Assemblywoman Mila Jasey</li><li>Roslyn Rogers Collins, President and CEO, Planned Parenthood of Metropolitan New Jersey</li><li>Alejandra Sorto, Campaign Strategist for the American Civil Liberties Union of New Jersey</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
