<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 13:55:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the April Jobs&#160;Report￼</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-april-jobs-report%ef%bf%bc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 13:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we learned that the economy created 428,000 jobs in April – bringing the total number of jobs created since I took office to 8.3 million: record setting job creation in my first 15 months in office.  Our plans and policies have produced the strongest job creation economy in modern times.  The unemployment rate now&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we learned that the economy created 428,000 jobs in April – bringing the total number of jobs created since I took office to 8.3 million: record setting job creation in my first 15 months in office.  Our plans and policies have produced the strongest job creation economy in modern times.  The unemployment rate now stands at 3.6% —the fastest decline in unemployment to start a President’s term ever recorded. There have been only 3 months in the last 50 years where the unemployment rate in America is lower than it is now. This is a direct result of the American Rescue Plan, our COVID vaccination program, and my plan to grow our economy from the bottom up and middle out.  When I took office, there were around 20 million people relying on unemployment benefits to feed their families; today, that number is around 1 million – the lowest since 1970.   We are building an economy that values the dignity of work.<br> <br>There’s no question that inflation and high prices are a challenge for families across the country, and fighting inflation is a top priority for me. The continued strength of our job market and the savings that families have built up over the last year means that our economy faces the challenges of COVID-19, Putin’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, and global inflation from a position of strength. There’s more work to do. I encourage Congressional Republicans to join us in our efforts to lower prices for families across the country, by making more in America, strengthening our supply chains, and cutting the energy and prescription drug costs.<br> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Celebrates Launch of AM Forward and Calls on Congress to Pass Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/fact-sheet-biden-administration-celebrates-launch-of-am-forward-and-calls-on-congress-to-pass-bipartisan-innovation-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AM Forward will help lower costs for American families by improving the competitiveness of America’s small-and-medium-sized manufacturers, creating and sustaining high-paying manufacturing jobs, and improving supply chain resilience through adoption of additive manufacturing President Biden’s top economic priority is to fight inflation by lowering costs that working families face, and lowering the federal deficit. One&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>AM Forward will help lower costs for American families by improving the competitiveness of America’s small-and-medium-sized manufacturers, creating and sustaining high-paying manufacturing jobs, and improving supply chain resilience through adoption of additive manufacturing</em></p>



<p>President Biden’s top economic priority is to fight inflation by lowering costs that working families face, and lowering the federal deficit.</p>



<p>One of the best ways to lower the cost of the goods and services that families rely on is to make more things in America, with more secure, resilient supply chains. We’ve learned this the hard way during this crisis – when brittle supply chains and hollowed out manufacturing resulted in backlogs, bottlenecks and higher prices for families.</p>



<p>President Biden’s plan to fight inflation addresses this problem head on. Thanks to the President’s leadership, we are in the midst of an American manufacturing boom with over $200 billion of investments in new manufacturing facilities and record-setting job creation. The Biden Administration has spurred unprecedented job growth and the fastest economic recovery in nearly four decades. Since taking office, President Biden’s actions have resulted in the creation of 7.9 million jobs, including 473,000 in manufacturing – more jobs in the first 14 months of any President’s term ever.</p>



<p>Companies are investing in America again, bringing good-paying manufacturing jobs back home. Whether it’s semiconductors, advanced batteries, or other leading sectors, companies are opening new facilities and announcing commitments to produce the world’s most cutting-edge technologies in the United States.</p>



<p>This is just the beginning of a broad revival of American industrial might. Continuing this momentum is key to easing price pressures throughout our economy and bringing inflation down. That is why the President is committed to making more in America, strengthening our supply chains, supercharging American leadership in the industries of the future, and lowering costs for families. That starts with the historic resources in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which are rebuilding our roads, bridges, ports, airports, and making our businesses and workers more competitive globally. And we can take the next step by passing the Bipartisan Innovation Act, which will make generational investments in innovation, domestic manufacturing, and lowering prices through stronger supply chains.</p>



<p>AM Forward builds on that work and advances key Administration goals:</p>



<ul><li>More resilient and innovative supply chains, by investing in small and medium sized companies;</li><li>Growing industries of the future, overcoming coordination challenges that limit adoption of new technologies like additive manufacturing; and</li><li>Both inventing and making more in America, through investments in regional manufacturing ecosystems.</li></ul>



<p>Each of these goals is also advanced by the Bipartisan Innovation Act (BIA), which establishes a Supply Chain Office at the Department of Commerce, supports foundational technologies such as additive manufacturing, and invests in regional tech hubs as well as increasing funding for Manufacturing USA Institutes and the Manufacturing Extension Partnership.</p>



<p>Keeping pace with technological change should not be the capability of a few, or an over-the-horizon goal, out of reach for most of our manufacturing base. It should be a pillar of American industrial competitiveness – something that is broadly deployed and available to small and large companies alike. Enacting BIA will put important new technologies like additive manufacturing into the hands of entrepreneurs and companies across the country—raising the productivity and resilience of US manufacturers while lowering costs for American families. It is urgent that Congress acts quickly to pass the BIA, sending it to the President’s desk for his signature.</p>



<p>But not enough American companies are using 3D printing or other high-performance production technologies. That’s why President Biden is pleased to join several leading American companies to celebrate the launch Additive Manufacturing Forward (AM Forward), a voluntary compact between large, iconic manufacturers and their smaller U.S.-based suppliers. GE Aviation, Honeywell, Lockheed Martin, Raytheon, and Siemens Energy are the initial participants in AM Forward. These leading manufacturers will support their U.S.-based suppliers’ adoption of new additive capabilities, helping to transform shop floors across the country.</p>



<p>In additive manufacturing, producers transmit computer data to industrial 3D printers.&nbsp; In turn, these machines build parts on-demand, directly in suppliers’ own shops. Firms use this capability to reduce the number of parts required for an application, to make spare parts one at a time as needed, and design high-performing components in various industries ranging from aviation to medical devices</p>



<p>Through AM Forward, each of these iconic companies will make clear, <a href="https://www.astroa.org/amforward">public commitments</a> to purchase additively produced parts from smaller U.S.-based suppliers; train the workers of their suppliers on new additive technologies; provide detailed technical assistance to support their suppliers’ adoption of new capabilities; and engage in common standards development and certification for additive products.</p>



<p>Among other public commitments:</p>



<ul><li>GE Aviation will target small/medium sized suppliers to compete on 50% of the requests for quotes that are sent out on products made using additive or related technologies; and will target 30% of its total external sourcing of additively manufactured parts from U.S.-based SME suppliers.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Raytheon will seek SME manufacturers involvement in over 50% of its requests for quotes on products manufactured using additive technologies; the company will also seek to simplify and accelerate the procurement process of AM parts.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Siemens Energy will target to purchase 20-40% of total externally sourced AM parts and services from U.S.-based suppliers and partners. It will engage 10-20 U.S. SME suppliers to help improve their AM capability. And, it will also train 10-20 SME suppliers on inspection and post-processing best practices.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Lockheed Martin will work with its SME suppliers to conduct research to improve the performance of additive manufacturing AM techniques specifically focused on the use of 3D printing as an alternative to castings and forgings; and it will further participate in university and technical college programs for additive workforce development, including coursework and apprenticeship.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Honeywell will target U.S.-based SME suppliers to compete on request for quote packages sent out for products, machinery, manufacturing tooling, and/or manufacturing process development utilizing additive or related technologies. It will also offer technical assistance in part design, data generation, machine operation, post-processing, part inspection / quality management to its SME suppliers.</li></ul>



<p>AM Forward is a completely voluntary compact <a href="https://www.astroa.org/amforward">open to any OEM to participate</a>, provided they are willing to make public commitments to support their suppliers’ adoption of additive capabilities. It will be supported by Applied Science &amp; Technology Research Organization (ASTRO), a non-profit organization.</p>



<p>To support AM Forward, the Biden Administration has identified a range of federal programs that U.S. SME manufacturers can use to support their adoption of additive capabilities and increase their competitiveness. The Administration’s actions are focused on helping to overcome common challenges that have slowed the deployment of AM technologies, particularly among smaller manufacturers.</p>



<p>They include:</p>



<ul><li><em>Providing access to capital to our SME manufacturers: </em>Providing affordable financing to small manufacturers will support the installation of additive equipment by reducing its cost. To address this issue, the U.S. Department of Agriculture will make its Business and Industry program available to rural manufacturers to support the purchase of new additive machines, and the training necessary to upskill their workforce. The Export-Import Bank will highlight its new domestic lending program that can help SME manufacturers upgrade their existing production equipment. And the Small Business Administration will work with the participants of AM Forward on how its 504 Loan Program and Small Business Investment Company (SBIC) program can support the widespread deployment of new additive capabilities across U.S. industry.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Delivering </em><em>technical assistance from the federal government and OEMs to our SME manufacturers: </em>SME manufacturers have noted the need <a href="https://sites.lsa.umich.edu/stevensamford/wp-content/uploads/sites/552/2017/10/Samford-et-al-BAP-2017.pdf">for technical assistance</a> to utilize new production technologies like 3D printers to their fullest extent. To support AM Forward, the Department of Energy will make its Manufacturing Demonstration Facility at Oak Ridge National Laboratory available to SME manufacturers to test new additive techniques. The Manufacturing Extension Partnership will provide enhanced technical assistance; and the Department of Defense (DOD) will use its Mentor Protégé Program to reimburse the cost to the large OEM participants in AM Forward for providing technical assistance to their smaller U.S.-based suppliers owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals. DOD’s Manufacturing Technology Program Office will work with America Makes, a DOD-sponsored Manufacturing Innovation Institute, and AM Forward members on a pilot standardization project.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Investing in the additive manufacturing workforce</em>: To fully benefit from the use of additive capabilities, SME manufacturers must train their workforce differently to successfully deploy additive capabilities, including upskilling workers. America Makes will thus develop curriculum for workforce training with AM Forward participants; and, along with the U.S. Department of Labor, will assist manufacturers in launching apprenticeship programs in additive manufacturing.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Setting industry standards</em>: Finally, since 3D printing requires different standards and process certifications, the U.S. Department of Commerce – through the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) – will conduct measurement science research to overcome key barriers to widespread use of metals-based additive manufacturing, develop the technical basis for new high-priority standards, and disseminate these results to AM Forward participants through leadership of standards development within ASTM International, International Organization for Standardization (ISO), American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME), and other standards bodies.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vice President Harris Statement on the Passing of Norman&#160;Mineta</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/05/vice-president-harris-statement-on-the-passing-of-norman-mineta/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A son of California, Norm Mineta worked tirelessly to make America stronger, safer, and more just. Decades after experiencing the injustice of internment, he devoted his career to public service, serving in the U.S. Army and fighting for civil liberties for all.  As the Mayor of San Jose, CA, Secretary Mineta saw the powerful role that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>A son of California, Norm Mineta worked tirelessly to make America stronger, safer, and more just. Decades after experiencing the injustice of internment, he devoted his career to public service, serving in the U.S. Army and fighting for civil liberties for all. <br> <br>As the Mayor of San Jose, CA, Secretary Mineta saw the powerful role that infrastructure played in connecting individuals to economic opportunity and fought to get his community the resources they needed. This was a fight that he relentlessly continued through ten terms in Congress and as a Cabinet Secretary.<br> <br>Secretary Mineta laid the foundation for Asian-American leaders across the nation and helped lead our nation through some of its most trying times. His leadership included the co-founding of the Asian Pacific American Institute for Congressional Studies and the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus, of which I was proud to be a member. <br> <br>I will cherish our conversations over the years. We all owe Secretary Mineta a debt of gratitude for his legacy of fighting to make this country live up to its promise.<br> <br>The Second Gentlemen and I are holding Secretary Mineta’s wife Danealia, and his entire family in our hearts.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden and First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at a Cinco De Mayo&#160;Reception</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/05/remarks-by-president-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-at-a-cinco-de-mayo-reception/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 23:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[4:47 P.M. EDT THE FIRST LADY:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And welcome to the White House!&#160; (Applause.) AUDIENCE MEMBER:&#160;&#160;La Casa Blanca!&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; THE FIRST LADY:&#160; Yes! The Battle of Puebla, which Cinco de Mayo celebrates, lasted for only a single day.&#160; Defending the small town of central Mexico wasn’t a major strategic victory in the Franco-Mexican War.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>4:47 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And welcome to the White House!&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp;&nbsp;<em>La Casa Blanca</em>!&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Yes!<br><br>The Battle of Puebla, which Cinco de Mayo celebrates, lasted for only a single day.&nbsp; Defending the small town of central Mexico wasn’t a major strategic victory in the Franco-Mexican War.&nbsp; But the fact that a rag-tag group of soldiers, outnumbered 3 to 1, could defeat Napoleon’s French Foreign Legion was a victory of the heart.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>It showed the determination and the backbone of the Mexican people.&nbsp; It inspired other cities to believe that they, too, could stand against the odds.<br><br>And the reverberations of that battle traveled north to the United States.<br><br>This holiday reminds us that the threads of our history and our heritage are woven together.&nbsp; We inspire one another.&nbsp; We shape each other.<br><br>Our relationship with Mexico is special.&nbsp; And I’m so grateful to be joined today by the First Lady of Mexico &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Dr. Gutiérrez &#8212; Beatriz.&nbsp; From our love of poetry and literature to our shared passion to education, we have so much in common.<br><br>You know, Joe always says that politics is personal, and I’m grateful to continue building our friendship.&nbsp; Actually, we already have plans for what we’re going to do next time we’re together.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Ooh.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you’re invited, Joe.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Don’t think I am.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; It’s not only our history that is tied to Mexico, but our future as well.&nbsp; We are stronger when we face the challenges of our modern world together.&nbsp;<br><br>And when we recognize our shared heritage, we can better understand and celebrate the true beauty and diversity of America.<br><br>A few years ago, at the National LULAC Conference, I met with a young group of Mexican Americans and other Latino leaders.<br><br>They told me about the issues that were on their minds: education, climate change, healthcare, and jobs &#8212; just like anyone their age.&nbsp; But what struck me was that they said that they didn’t often feel seen or heard.&nbsp;<br><br>And that touched my heart.&nbsp; Don’t we owe them better?<br><br>Since then, I’ve held conversations to hear from different generations of Latinos from across this country.<br><br>And again and again, I’ve seen the unique gifts of this community &#8212; the common threads that tie us together.<br><br>I’ve been reminded that our differences are precious and that our similarities infinite.<br><br>The former Poet Laureate of the United States and a proud Chicano &#8212; did I say that right?<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yeah!<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Oh, I should ask you.&nbsp;<br><br>Juan Felipe Herrera once said: “Diversity really means becoming complete as human beings &#8212; all of us.&nbsp; We learn from each other.&nbsp; If you’re missing on that stage, [you] learn less.&nbsp; We all need to be on that stage.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The White House &#8212;&nbsp;<em>Casa Blanca</em>&nbsp;&#8212; (laughter) &#8212; is the People’s House &#8212; your house.&nbsp; And the story of America is the story of you, the story of all of us.<br><br>So, thank you for helping us celebrate our nation’s Mexican American heritage today.&nbsp; And Happy Cinco de Mayo!&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And now, my husband, your President, and mine: Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We love you, Joe!&nbsp; We really do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m glad some woman in this crowd loves me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Well, thank you, Jill.&nbsp; I&#8217;m honored to welcome all of you to the White House, especially our distinguished guest, the First Lady. &nbsp;I&#8217;m going to go down and say hi.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>(The President shakes the hand of First Lady Gutiérrez Müller.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Jill doesn’t let me get in these conversations, so I want to &#8212; (laughter) &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>And Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona. &nbsp;Where are you, Miguel?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Yeah, where is my Mig- &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He&#8217;s here.&nbsp; There he is.&nbsp; He&#8217;s educating people in the back.&nbsp; There you go.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Oh, hi!&nbsp; Hi, Miguel.&nbsp;<br><br>Did you see Naomi too?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Did I &#8212;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Naomi.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t see Naomi.&nbsp;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; She&#8217;s over here.&nbsp; How can you miss her?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; I&#8217;ll tell you what &#8212; hi, Naomi.&nbsp; How are you?&nbsp; That&#8217;s my granddaughter.&nbsp; My oldest &#8212; our oldest granddaughter and &#8212;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; And her fiancé.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; and her &#8212; I can&#8217;t see.&nbsp;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; And Peter.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And Peter.&nbsp;<br><br>You all have to know all this, you know?&nbsp; It&#8217;s really important.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Secretary of Interior Deb Haaland.&nbsp; Where&#8217;s Deb?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; She&#8217;s here.&nbsp; Deb, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>And one of my best buddies when we served together and, I think, probably one of the best ambassadors we&#8217;ve ever had to Mexico or anywhere else: Ken Salazar.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Madam First Lady, we were campaigning &#8212; and this is off-script here, I know &#8212; but we were campaigning when I was seeking the vice presidency with President Obama, and we were in western &#8212; eastern Colorado.&nbsp; And we were about to walk out, and we were at a beautiful renovated railroad station and a railroad that is no longer functioned as a interstate railroad, but it was magnificent.&nbsp;<br><br>And he kept telling me &#8212; he said, &#8220;Now, look, Joe, there&#8217;s a couple of thousand people across the track.&#8221;&nbsp; And he said, &#8220;They’re Latinos, so you got to be get- &#8212; you got to be &#8212; you got to be respectful.&#8221;&nbsp; And I&#8217;m like, &#8220;I&#8217;m not going to respectful?&#8221;&nbsp; And &#8212; and I said &#8212; he said, &#8220;And you don&#8217;t understand about &#8212; about prejudice.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t unders- &#8212; you don&#8217;t get it.&#8221;&nbsp; And I listened to him and listened.&nbsp; And finally &#8212; then he pointed out &#8212; he said, &#8220;Look, my family has been here 400 years.&#8221;&nbsp; And I said, &#8220;Well, mine has not been here that long.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s any &#8212; anywhere…” &#8212; anyway, so, we talked a little bit longer.&nbsp; And he kept talking about, &#8220;Be careful.&#8221;&nbsp; Remember this?&nbsp;<br><br>In this beautifully renovated station.&nbsp; I mean, it was gorgeous.&nbsp; And it was about the size of &#8212; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; it’s is from here to the far hedge, and about halfway into the crowd &#8212; about 30, 40 feet wide.&nbsp; And there was nothing in there except there was linden wallpaper.&nbsp; And there were these brass plaques about every six or eight feet around the entirety of the &#8212; of the reception room.&nbsp; And I said, &#8220;I think…&#8221; &#8212; I said, &#8220;I genuinely understand.&#8221;&nbsp; He said, &#8220;No.&#8221; &nbsp;I said &#8212; I turn, I said, &#8220;Take a look what they say.&nbsp; It says, &#8216;No Irish allowed.'&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; &#8220;No Irish allowed,&#8221; because it was renovated to exactly what it was in 1869.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t really know, but anyway, I just wanted to remind &#8212;<br><br>But, Ken, you&#8217;re one of the best ambassadors I think we have anywhere in the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>You know, along with all the mayors &#8212; how many mayors are here today &#8212; American mayors?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Wow.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And how many diplomats are here from various parts of the world?&nbsp;&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You can raise your hand.&nbsp; It&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t want to be seen.&nbsp; It&#8217;s like, &#8220;You know, I don&#8217;t know.&#8221;&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure he wants to &#8212; you know.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And how many advocates and community leaders are here?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Teachers!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, teachers.&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, I sleep with a teacher every night.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Same one.&nbsp; The same one.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; If I didn’t like teachers, I’d be sleeping alone.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’d be &#8212;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; You’re a teacher too.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; in a different place.&nbsp;<br><br>As Jill said: Cinco de Mayo is a day to celebrate freedom and resilience, and, you know, it’s also day to celebrate friendship.&nbsp;<br><br>And President López Obrador, when &#8212; he was kind enough to come up and see me here in the Oval and the White House in November.&nbsp; And he pointed to a patriot &#8212; a &#8212; excuse me, a portrait over the mantle of the &#8212; of the &#8212; in the White House, in the Oval Office.&nbsp; And it’s a picture of &#8212; it’s a big portrait of Franklin Delano Roosevelt hanging on the wall.&nbsp; And he told me that he liked Roosevelt because he was the President who initiated the Good Neighbor Policy between our two nations.&nbsp; We talked about that for a while.<br><br>And I told him that today the United States and Mexico are more than good neighbors; we’re genuine, true friends, partners.&nbsp; And there’s an unshakable bond strengthened by mutual respect and our shared commitment to the prosperity and security of both our nations.&nbsp;&nbsp;It’s not our backyard; it’s our front yard.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you very much, Madam<s>President</s>&nbsp;[First Lady].&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Those bonds are further strengthened by our shared history and heritage &#8212; culture, pride, and countless contributions of Mexican Americans, and the heritage and culture of an essential part of the American culture.&nbsp; It’s just &#8212; it’s just part of American culture.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And that’s why I made it a priority to build a government that looks like America, including the most diverse Cabinet ever assembled &#8212; including, by the way, two Mexican Americans: Xavier Becerra, as &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the Department of Health and Human Services, as well as Isabel Guzman, who is leading the Small Business Administration.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And many, many more folks throughout the administration.<br><br>Beyond &#8212; beyond representation, we’re also focused on delivering results for Latino families.&nbsp;<br><br>Through the American Rescue Plan, our vaccination effort and our &#8212; was centered on equity and ensured that Latinos were vaccinated at the same rate everyone else was.&nbsp; As a matter of fact, they’re vaccinated at a slightly higher rate than everyone else was.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And to make sure relief checks were delivered to 1,400,000 spouses and nearly 3,700,000 children of mixed status families where mom or dad is a citizen.&nbsp; Because every family deserves food on the table, a roof over their head, and a little breathing room.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We cut the Latino child poverty rate by an estimated 40 percent because of the Child Tax Credit.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And we surged funding to community health centers, which disproportionately serve Latino communities.<br><br>And, by the way, I met last week at the White House with five incredible Latino entrepreneurs.&nbsp; They’re part of an amazing story &#8212; a boom of new small businesses in America.<br><br>In America today, there are more new small businesses being created and small business creation &#8212; more jobs than ever before.&nbsp; And Latino entrepreneurs are leading the way, starting new businesses last year at the fastest rate in more than a decade &#8212; 23 percent faster than the pre-pandemic levels.&nbsp;<br><br>The reason I mention this is it’s a big deal.&nbsp; The prosperity and jobs for Latino communities affects everybody.&nbsp;<br><br>And we’re working to fix our immigration system as well.&nbsp; As I said &#8212; (applause) &#8212; it’s important.&nbsp; As I said in my State of the Union Address, we can secure our borders and keep lit the torch of liberty.<br><br>On my first day in office, I sent an immigration bill to Congress that would provide a pathway to citizenship for immigrants contributing to our economy.&nbsp; That’s &#8212; we are &#8212; we &#8212; you know, we are an immigrant nation.&nbsp; I mean, we &#8212; we litera- &#8212; I mean, we say that, but people act like they don’t believe it.&nbsp; We are an immigrant na- &#8212; and that is our strength.&nbsp; That is our strength.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But if Congress won’t act on broader reform, let’s pass the bills that have bipartisan support &#8212; for DREAMers and those&nbsp;Temporary Protected Status farm workers, essential workers.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s not only the right thing to do but it’s, economically, the smart thing to do as well.<br><br>And most of all, we’re going to continue to fight for the rights and opportunities and dignity of Mexican Americans and all Latinos in America.&nbsp;<br><br>I might point out &#8212; and Jill and I talk about this: If we don’t get smart in this country, and the other team doesn’t understand what’s going on &#8212; you know, 25 out of every 100 children in grades kindergarten through senior in high school speak Spanish.&nbsp; Twenty-five out of every one hundred.&nbsp; It’s overwhelmingly in the interest not only of those kids, but of all Americans that we invest &#8212; we invest in the community.&nbsp; And we’ll conquer and honor and lift up all those folks who, in fact, are &#8212; have gotten in the way.<br><br>You know, Mexican American culture is a great contribution for &#8212; to America.&nbsp;<br><br>And soon we’ll also see the broader Latino community culture celebrated through the creation of the newest Smithsonian Museum &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the National Museum of the American Latino.&nbsp; It’s a big deal.&nbsp; And I look forward to seeing it take its rightful place here in Washington to help share the remarkable stories and incredible contributions our Latinos have contributed to this nation &#8212; the entire Latino community.&nbsp; And for now, though, let’s celebrate today.&nbsp; Let’s celebrate today.<br><br>And I just want you to know &#8212; I can’t tell you how much we’re looking forward to this day.&nbsp; I’m glad it held off.&nbsp; Thank you, God.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But I hope &#8212; I hope you all have a good time today.&nbsp; And, again, Madam First Lady, you’re welcome here.&nbsp; And I want to take you in and show you my office too, if you’d come.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; I’ll you show you Franklin Roosevelt, okay?&nbsp;<br><br>Well, thank you all.&nbsp; God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>5:01 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Costa Rica to Attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Rodrigo Alberto de Jesús Chaves&#160;Robles</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/05/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-republic-of-costa-rica-to-attend-the-inauguration-of-his-excellency-rodrigo-alberto-de-jesus-chaves-robles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to San José, Costa Rica to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Rodrigo Alberto de Jesús Chaves Robles as President of the Republic of Costa Rica on May 8, 2022. The&#160;Honorable Miguel Cardona, United States Secretary of Education,&#160;will lead the delegation. Members&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to San José, Costa Rica to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Rodrigo Alberto de Jesús Chaves Robles as President of the Republic of Costa Rica on May 8, 2022.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;Honorable Miguel Cardona, United States Secretary of Education,&nbsp;will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong></p>



<p>The Honorable Cynthia Telles, United States Ambassador to the Republic of Costa Rica</p>



<p>The Honorable Uzra Zeya, Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights, U.S. Department of State</p>



<p>The Honorable Cristóbal Alex, Special Assistant to the President and White House Deputy Cabinet Secretary</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Chancellor Scholz of&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/05/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-chancellor-scholz-of-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 20:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany.  The leaders underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected by the violence.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany.  The leaders underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected by the violence. The President welcomed Germany’s provision of security assistance and recent pledge of additional humanitarian aid, as well as their close partnership throughout this crisis.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment Meeting with Grassroots Worker&#160;Organizers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/05/readout-of-task-force-on-worker-organizing-and-empowerment-meeting-with-grassroots-worker-organizers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 19:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris and Labor Secretary Marty Walsh held a roundtable discussion with a diverse group of young, grassroots worker organizers to discuss their extraordinary efforts to organize unions in their workplaces, and how their efforts can inspire workers across the country to make the choice to join or organize a union. The&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris and Labor Secretary Marty Walsh held a roundtable discussion with a diverse group of young, grassroots worker organizers to discuss their extraordinary efforts to organize unions in their workplaces, and how their efforts can inspire workers across the country to make the choice to join or organize a union. The roundtable was led by the Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment, which the Vice President chairs with Secretary Walsh as vice-chair.</p>



<p>President Biden stopped by the discussion and thanked the worker organizers for their leadership in organizing unions, the inspiration they offer to workers across the country who may want to organize, and their contributions to the worker organizing momentum that is growing across the country.</p>



<p>Vice President Harris and Secretary Walsh listened to the worker organizers tell the stories of why they and their co-workers organized unions in their workplaces and how they did it. Among other things, the workers talked about fair pay, paid leave and health care benefits, their commitment to co-workers, and the desire for basic dignity and respect as important motivators for their organizing efforts. They also described some of the anti-union tactics deployed by some of the employers. The Vice President and Secretary Walsh reaffirmed that the Biden-Harris Administration is the most pro-union administration in history, and reiterated that worker power is at the core of this administration’s economic vision to rebuild the economy from the bottom up and middle out. As we experience an historically strong labor market recovery, Vice President Harris and Secretary Walsh underscored that all workers must benefit and get the dignity and respect they deserve in the workplace.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The attendees represented a wide range of industries with grassroots union organizing efforts, from warehousing to animation to retail. Attendees included Vice President Harris, Secretary Walsh, Christian Smalls, Amazon Labor Union, Laura Garza, Starbucks Workers United/Starbucks, Alex Speidel, United Paizo Workers/CWA, Rachel Gitlevich, Titmouse productions/IATSE, Jaimie Caldwell, Baltimore Public Library/IAM, and Damien Sowell, REI/UFCW-RWDSU.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Karine Jean-Pierre as White&#160;House Press&#160;Secretary</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/05/president-biden-announces-karine-jean-pierre-as-white-house-press-secretary/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 19:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52502</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anita Dunn will return as a Senior Advisor Today, President Biden announced Karine Jean-Pierre has been promoted to be Assistant to the President and White House Press Secretary.&#160;Karine will step into the Press Secretary role replacing Jen Psaki, who will depart from the White House on May 13. Statement from President Biden:&#160;“I am proud to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Anita Dunn will return as a Senior Advisor</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden announced Karine Jean-Pierre has been promoted to be Assistant to the President and White House Press Secretary.&nbsp;Karine will step into the Press Secretary role replacing Jen Psaki, who will depart from the White House on May 13.</p>



<p><em>Statement from President Biden:&nbsp;</em>“I am proud to announce that Karine Jean-Pierre will serve as the next White House Press Secretary.</p>



<p>“Karine not only brings the experience, talent and integrity needed for this difficult job, but she will continue to lead the way in communicating about the work of the Biden-Harris Administration on behalf of the American people.&nbsp;Jill and I have known and respected Karine a long time and she will be a strong voice speaking for me and this Administration.</p>



<p>“Jen Psaki has set the standard for returning decency, respect and decorum to the White House Briefing Room.&nbsp;I want to say thank you to Jen for raising the bar, communicating directly and truthfully to the American people, and keeping her sense of humor while doing so. I thank Jen her service to the country, and wish her the very best as she moves forward.”</p>



<p>The White House also announced the return of Anita Dunn as a Senior Advisor and Assistant to the President. Dunn rejoins the White House staff from her communications and political consulting firm SKDK, and will assist in advancing the President’s policy and communications objectives.<br><br><strong>Karine Jean-Pierre, Press Secretary&nbsp;and Assistant to the President</strong></p>



<p>Karine Jean-Pierre is currently the Principal Deputy Press Secretary and Deputy Assistant to the President. Karine is a long-time advisor to President Biden, having served in senior communication and political roles in the Biden Administration, the Biden campaign, and to then-Vice President Biden in the Obama Administration.</p>



<p>Prior to her role on the campaign, she served as Chief Public Affairs Officer for MoveOn.org and an NBC and MSNBC Political Analyst. Jean-Pierre served as Regional Political Director for the White House Office of Political Affairs during the Obama-Biden administration and as Deputy Battleground States Director for President Obama&#8217;s 2012 re-election campaign. She served as Southeast Regional Political Director for President Obama’s 2008 campaign, Deputy Campaign Manager for Martin O’Malley for President, Campaign Manager for the ACLU&#8217;s Reproductive Freedom Initiative, and Deputy Chief of Staff and Director of Legislative and Budget Affairs for two members in the New York City Council.</p>



<p>Previously, she worked at the Center for Community and Corporate Ethics, pushing major companies to change their business practices, and is a published author. Born in Martinique and raised in New York, Jean-Pierre is a graduate of Columbia University.<br><br><strong>Anita Dunn, Senior Advisor and Assistant to the President</strong></p>



<p>Anita Dunn is one of the nation’s top communications and political strategists, and is a close advisor to President Biden. She recently served as a Senior Advisor to President Biden, and is currently a partner and founding member of SKDK. She brings decades of experience advising Presidents and senior Democrats. She served as a chief strategist to President Obama as a senior campaign advisor and as the White House Communications Director. She has also worked in leading roles for Tom Daschle, Bill Bradley, and Evan Bayh.</p>



<p>As Senior Advisor to President Biden, Anita advised on the administration’s overall strategy and messaging, helping the President take steps and win legislative victories that helped jumpstart the economy after the pandemic. Prior to that, she served as a senior advisor on the Biden-Harris campaign, advising on all aspects of the campaign. At SKDK, Anita has worked with progressive and issue advocacy campaigns, given strategic advice to elected officials, political candidates, CEOs, nonprofits and corporations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/05/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-64/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 18:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52492</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Annie Caputo, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission for the term of five years expiring June 30, 2026.&#160; (Reappointment) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Michael M. Contrades, of Hawaii, to be United States Marshal for the District of Hawaii for the term of four years, vice Charles L. Goodwin, retired. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Bradley&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Annie Caputo, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission for the term of five years expiring June 30, 2026.&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Michael M. Contrades, of Hawaii, to be United States Marshal for the District of Hawaii for the term of four years, vice Charles L. Goodwin, retired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Bradley R. Crowell, of Nevada, to be a Member of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission for the remainder of the term expiring June 30, 2022, vice Kristine L. Svinicki, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Bradley R. Crowell, of Nevada, to be a Member of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission for the term of five years expiring June 30, 2027.&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; David C. Davis, of Illinois, to be United States Marshal for the Southern District of Illinois for the term of four years, vice Bradley A. Maxwell, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Enix Smith III, of Louisiana, to be United States Marshal for the Eastern District of Louisiana for the term of four years, vice Scott Patrick Illing.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Carlos Felipe Uriarte, of California, to be an Assistant Attorney General, vice Stephen Elliott Boyd.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Military Spouse Appreciation Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/05/a-proclamation-on-military-spouse-appreciation-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 17:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Military spouses are the rock on which their families, our military community, and our national security depend.&#160; Though most do not wear a uniform themselves, they serve and strengthen our Nation every day &#8212; providing our brave troops with support, comfort, and love.&#160; They build communities of strength on bases around the world to care&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Military spouses are the rock on which their families, our military community, and our national security depend.&nbsp; Though most do not wear a uniform themselves, they serve and strengthen our Nation every day &#8212; providing our brave troops with support, comfort, and love.&nbsp; They build communities of strength on bases around the world to care for our military family, pitching in wherever they see a need that is unmet. &nbsp;On Military Spouse Appreciation Day, we recognize the nearly one million military spouses and their vital contributions to our Nation.&nbsp; We are grateful for their selfless sacrifice and inspired by their strength, fortitude, and courage.</p>



<p>Today, America&#8217;s military spouses are a constellation of&nbsp;diverse individuals with unique backgrounds and the common attribute of uncommon resilience.&nbsp; Like their service members, they too represent the best of who we are as Americans.&nbsp; Military spouses know what it means to make sacrifices in defense of our ideals and freedoms.&nbsp; And they live with the hardship of having their life partner deployed away from home &#8212; juggling all the responsibilities of work and family while saying an extra prayer every morning that their spouse returns home safely.</p>



<p>Even during the most demanding circumstances, military spouses continue to serve, creating innovative solutions to meet the challenges we face as a Nation.&nbsp; Today, military spouses serve in dynamic leadership roles across all sectors &#8212; using their own experiences to support the needs of the communities around them.&nbsp; With enthusiasm and an entrepreneurial spirit, military spouses create businesses and support systems that serve the needs of others.</p>



<p>The Biden family is a military family, and caring for our Nation&#8217;s military spouses is something that Jill and I both deeply understand.&nbsp; While our Nation can never fully repay the&nbsp;debt we owe to our service members and their families, caregivers, and survivors, it is our sacred obligation to make sure that they receive the care and support they have earned.&nbsp; Through the First Lady&#8217;s Joining Forcesinitiative, my Administration is strengthening support for military families in&nbsp;three critical areas: &nbsp;military spouse employment and entrepreneurship, military child education, and the well-being of military families.&nbsp; We continue to seek new and better ways to do more to address the needs of our military families, especially responding to the needs of military spouses with resources and services that allow them to thrive in all aspects of life.</p>



<p>On Military Spouse Appreciation Day and every day, we are&nbsp;grateful for the extraordinary service and sacrifice of America&#8217;s military spouses.&nbsp; May we continue to lift their voices, invest in their talents, and respond to their unique needs in ways that ease their challenges and enable them to reach their goals and aspirations.&nbsp; May God bless our military families, caregivers, and survivors, and may God protect our troops.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 6, 2022, as Military Spouse Appreciation Day.&nbsp; I call upon the people of the United States to honor military spouses with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fifth day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
