<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 01:57:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration’s Unprecedented Actions to Expand and Improve Trucking&#160;Jobs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/04/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-unprecedented-actions-to-expand-and-improve-trucking-jobs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50451</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since Day 1, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken on the supply chain disruptions and price increases resulting from the decades-long lack of investment in the nation’s goods movement supply chain. The Administration enacted the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to bring our infrastructure to the 21st century, worked with ports to clear the docks and gets good&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since Day 1, the Biden-Harris Administration has taken on the supply chain disruptions and price increases resulting from the decades-long lack of investment in the nation’s goods movement supply chain. The Administration enacted the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to bring our infrastructure to the 21<sup>st</sup> century, worked with ports to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/nec/briefing-room/2022/01/20/a-record-year-for-americas-ports-and-a-look-to-the-year-ahead/">clear the docks</a> and gets good moving, launched <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-new-initiative-to-improve-supply-chain-data-flow/">a pilot initiative</a> to create the digital infrastructure to connect key stakeholders in the supply chain, and more. The result is a modern goods movement system that boosts American competitiveness and cuts families’ costs.<br><br>Trucking moves 72 percent of goods in America and is a lynchpin in our goods movement supply chain. Trucking costs <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/graph/?g=NEHY">grew more than 20 percent last year</a> as a surge in demand for goods caused by the pandemic confronted a decline in trucking employment that preceded the pandemic. The low supply of drivers is driven by high turnover and low job quality. Turnover in trucking routinely <a href="https://www.trucking.org/news-insights/turnover-remained-unchanged-large-truckload-fleets-fourth-quarter#:~:text=For%20the%20full%20year%2C%20the,72%25%20in%20the%20previous%20year.">averages 90 percent</a> for some carriers and drivers <a href="https://transportation.house.gov/imo/media/doc/2021-11-17%20Hearing%20Testimony%20-%20David%20HC%20Correll%20UPDATED.pdf">spend about 40 percent of their workday</a> waiting to load and unload goods &#8211; &nbsp;hours that are typically unpaid. Many truckers are not directly employed and operate as independent small businesses, bearing the burden of leasing, gas, insurance, and maintenance costs themselves. These financial burdens cause many to leave the profession. Trucking also draws on an older, heavily male workforce—the median age is <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat18b.htm">four years higher</a> than the overall workforce and <a href="https://www.bls.gov/cps/cpsaat18.htm">almost 90 percent</a> of the industry is men—which adds to its recruiting challenges.<br><br>Last December, the Administration confronted these challenges head on.&nbsp; The U.S. Department of Transportation and the U.S. Department of Labor <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-%E2%81%A0harris-administration-trucking-action-plan-to-strengthen-americas-trucking-workforce/">launched a Trucking Action Plan</a> to increase the supply of truck drivers by creating new pathways into the profession, cutting red tape to expand high quality training through Registered Apprenticeship, and laying the foundation for improving job quality to keep people in the profession.<br><br><strong>Major Achievements of Biden Effort to Expand and Improve Trucking Jobs:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Getting Americans Working in Better Trucking Jobs: Since President Biden took office, we have seen historic increases in trucking employment with 2021 registering as the best year for trucking employment growth since 1994 and December 2021-February 2022 as the best three-month stretch for long distance truck hiring since the 1990s. And frontline truckers’ real wages grew this year despite elevated inflation.<br></li><li>Cutting red-tape in Commercial Driver’s licensing: DOT gave states the tools to more than double new commercial driver’s license issuances in January and February 2022 compared to January and February 2021. States have issued more than 876,000 CDLs since January 2021.<br></li><li>Scaling Registered Apprenticeships in trucking to improve retention: Over 100 employers including Domino’s, Frito-Lay, and UPS launched Registered Apprenticeship programs in 90 days as DOL cut the amount of time it takes to a launch a program from months to as little as 48 hours. This could result in more than 10,000 additional apprentices.<br></li><li>Helping connect veterans to trucking careers: The trucking industry partnered with leading Veterans Service Organizations to launch <em>Task Force Movement: Life-Cycle Pathways for Veterans and Military into Trucking,</em> chaired by former Congressman and veteran Patrick Murphy, to support the recruitment and retention of veterans and military family members.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Since the launch of the plan in December, the Administration hosted seven listening sessions with over 100 participants. Continuing to listen and work with drivers is a pillar of the Administration’s work to address job quality in the DOL and DOT’s <em>Driving Good Jobs Initiative</em>. This initiative supports the trucking workforce by creating a task force on truck leasing arrangements, launching a Women of Trucking Advisory Board, and more. The Administration is also committed to addressing core job quality challenges from misclassification to hours of service to workplace safety.</p>



<p><strong>Getting Americans to Work in Better Trucking Jobs</strong><br>When President Biden took office, there were 30,000 fewer trucking jobs than in February 2020 and trucking employment had been falling even before that. But last year’s historic job growth across the economy resulted in 2021 registering as the best year for trucking job growth since 1994. Trucking employment now exceeds its pre-pandemic level by 35,000 and is higher than it was before it began to decline in 2019. Trucking employment growth over the last year was strongest in California where it exceeded 10 percent as well as Missouri, New Jersey, Ohio, and Washington where it exceeded 8 percent.</p>



<p>Long-distance truck driving has been the sector of trucking facing the most challenges, but we are now seeing fresh momentum there: December through February was the best three-month stretch for long-distancing trucking employment growth since the 1990s (data are currently only available through February).</p>



<p><strong>Cutting Red Tape: More than Doubling Commercial Driver’s License Processing Compared to 2021</strong><br>The Administration and U.S. Department of Transportation worked with states and Governors to accelerate CDL processing. DOT announced over $57 million in funding available to help states expedite CDLs, coordinated waivers, sent all 50 states a toolkit detailing specific actions to expedite licensing and worked hand-in-hand with states to address challenges. This resulted in a 112 percent increase in CDL processing in January and February 2022 compared to January and February 2021. States have issued more than 876,000 CDLs since January 2021.</p>



<p><strong>Scaling Apprenticeships: Moving the Market on How Truckers are Recruited, Trained, and Retained</strong><br>The Departments of Labor and Transportation launched the&nbsp;<a href="/www.apprenticeship.gov/90-day-trucking-apprenticeship-challenge&amp;data=04|01|benjamin.halle@dot.gov|86cf7ddd4b6a4ffb94a808d9d5eecc30|c4cd245b44f04395a1aa3848d258f78b|0|0|637776043870402562|Unknown|TWFpbGZsb3d8eyJWIjoiMC4wLjAwMDAiLCJQIjoiV2luMzIiLCJBTiI6Ik1haWwiLCJXVCI6Mn0=|3000&amp;sdata=ytX8ojo+2PmP1cmtIIw/y0H+mR/nGLZ96AJwdDE4j2s=&amp;reserved=0%3c">90 Day Trucking Apprenticeship Challenge</a>&nbsp;to jumpstart this proven workforce strategy in trucking.</p>



<ul><li>Over 100 employers across trucking, food and grocery, and the oil and gas industries launched Registered Apprenticeship programs in 90 days. This includes Domino’s, Frito-Lay, UPS, states and national partners such as FASTPORT and the International Brotherhood of the Teamsters. This proven earn and learn model of workforce training will help employers and labor develop and retain a skilled workforce. Apprentices are already hitting the road with NFI and Total Transportation each hiring over 50 apprentices after launching new programs under the Apprenticeship Challenge.</li></ul>



<p>With these 100 employers and 7 trade associations now offering apprenticeships, we have nearly doubled the number of programs nationwide. This could, in turn, double the number of registered apprenticeships in 2022 and result in more than 10,000 new registered apprenticeships. As a point of comparison, annual trucking employment growth averaged 24,000 in the decade before the pandemic.</p>



<ul><li>Through the Apprenticeship Challenge, industry associations are now leading on the expansion of trucking apprenticeships and will be across the U.S. for years to come. This includes the American Trucking Association, the National Tank Truck Association, FMI (the Food Industry Association), the National Minority Trucking Association, the North American Punjabi Trucking Association, and the Truckload Carriers Association. And the Trucking Alliance, where every member carrier – among the largest long-haul companies that collectively employ more than 80,000 drivers &#8211; committed to offer truck driver registered apprenticeships in more than 200 apprenticeship locations in 36 states across the country.<br></li><li>Over 70 additional employers of all sizes and industry segments including Sysco and WM (Waste Management Inc.) are in the process of developing and launching apprenticeship programs.<br></li><li>DOT <a href="https://www.fmcsa.dot.gov/safedriver">launched the <em>Safe Driver Apprenticeship Pilot</em></a>, established through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, to safely connect American adults under the age of 21 to good-paying jobs in the trucking industry through Registered Apprenticeship.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Connecting Veterans to Trucking: Forging Partnerships to Help Veterans and Transitioning Service Members Enter Trucking</strong><br>The Administration worked with Veterans Service Organizations and related associations representing more than 4 million veterans and military family members to create ways for the industry to attract, train, place, and retain veterans in trucking jobs. This builds on the already strong connection between veterans and trucking as&nbsp;<a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2019/06/america-keeps-on-trucking.html#:~:text=At%20least%20one%20in%2010,a%20disability%20than%20other%20workers.">at least one in ten truckers are veterans</a>, which is double the rate of workers overall.</p>



<ul><li>The trucking industry partnered with leading Veterans Service Organizations like the Veterans of Foreign Wars, the American Legion, and the Union Veterans Council to launch <em>Task Force Movement: Life-Cycle Pathways for Veterans and Military into Trucking,</em> chaired by former Congressman and veteran Patrick Murphy, to support the recruitment and retention of veterans and military family members in trucking.<br></li><li>DOL partnered with FASTPORT to connect transitioning service members with apprenticeship and employment opportunities in the trucking industry, while DOD has committed to improve its credentialing programs for all service members—200,000 of whom <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/vets/programs/tap#:~:text=Every%20year%2C%20approximately%20200%2C000%20men,the%20military%20to%20civilian%20transition">transition out of military service each year</a>.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Continuing the <em>Driving Good Jobs</em> Initiative to Improve the Quality of Trucking Careers</strong><br>The Administration launched the new <em>Driving Good Jobs</em>&nbsp;initiative between DOL and DOT to commit to ongoing work to ensure trucking jobs are good jobs. Over the last 90 Days, the Administration held a number of listening sessions and engagements with drivers, unions and worker centers, industry, and advocates to ensure their voices and experiences are shaping future actions across key areas. The initiative will maintain a focus on:</p>



<ul><li><strong><em>Ensuring a safe and inclusive industry for women</em></strong>: Expanding opportunities for women in trucking, including by creating safe and inclusive work environments, is critical for increasing trucking supply. This includes:<br></li><li>The <em>Women of Trucking Advisory Board </em>will review and report on challenges facing woman drivers and those interested in joining the profession, such as on-the-job safety risks, mentorship, quality training, and opportunities for advancement. &nbsp;DOT <a href="https://www.fmcsa.dot.gov/newsroom/fmcsa-announces-call-applications-women-trucking-advisory-board">has begun</a> soliciting nominations.<br></li><li>The Administration is announcing a Day of Action in April, coinciding with Sexual Assault Awareness and Prevention Month, to raise awareness and advocate for the prevention of sexual assault and sexual harassment in trucking. We will call on industry to commit to actions to promote safe training and work environments including zero-tolerance policies for sexual assault, improving sexual harassment training, and more.<br></li><li>The Administration is taking steps to ensure drivers entering the profession have a safe environment. DOT is now highlighting whistleblower and coercion protections for individuals facing sexual harassment and unsafe training conditions in its Entry Level Driver Training Program FAQ, which will be distributed to the 11,000 training providers. DOL is identifying employers in the trucking industry that have built supportive and inclusive workplaces for women and developing a “train the trainer” module for new Registered Apprenticeships sponsors who would receive a “seal of approval” upon completion to indicate training programs follow model gender-responsive training standards.<br></li><li><strong><em>Truck Leasing:</em></strong> DOT, DOL, and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB), have stood up a Truck Leasing Task Force to address predatory truck leasing arrangements and identify actions that could make leases more equitable and transparent.&nbsp; The Task Force will review and report on<strong> c</strong>ommon leasing arrangements, arrangements that result in outsize and unanticipated debt for incoming drivers, and more.<br></li><li><strong><em>Detention Time and Compensation Studies: </em></strong>DOT released a scope of work to study driver detention time &#8212; the loading and unloading time that is often unpaid — and its impact on safety and compensation. This study will provide a detailed understanding of wait time’s effects on drivers across jurisdictions and industry sectors. DOT is also partnering with the National Academies of Science to study the impact various methods of driver compensation have on safety and retention.<br></li><li><strong><em>Truck Parking: </em></strong>Lack of truck parking across the country is about more than just inconvenience, it impacts safety and retention as exhausted drivers have nowhere to rest. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law (BIL) provides funding in at least five programs that states can use to address truck parking while requiring states to include an analysis of truck parking needs in their State freight plans, laying the foundation to understand local needs.<br></li><li><strong><em>Strengthening workplace safety and worker’s rights: </em></strong>DOL and DOT will continue coordination on critical truck driver labor, employment and safety protections, including releasing new guidance and information for drivers about their workplace rights, and employers about their obligations. Additionally, they are conducting joint outreach and education to employers and drivers about these rights and responsibilities under federal wage and hour law. &nbsp;The Administration is committed to addressing core challenges, such as worker misclassification, while expanding high-road employer practices to build a next generation trucking workforce.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Mass Shooting in&#160;Sacramento</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/03/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-mass-shooting-in-sacramento/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 01:57:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, America once again mourns for another community devastated by gun violence. In a single act in Sacramento, six individuals left dead and at least a dozen more injured. Families forever changed. Survivors left to heal wounds both visible and invisible. I want to thank the first responders in Sacramento, and all those across the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, America once again mourns for another community devastated by gun violence. In a single act in Sacramento, six individuals left dead and at least a dozen more injured. Families forever changed. Survivors left to heal wounds both visible and invisible.</p>



<p>I want to thank the first responders in Sacramento, and all those across the United States, who act every day to save lives. We know these lives were not the only lives impacted by gun violence last night. And we equally mourn for those victims and families who do not make national headlines.</p>



<p>But we must do more than mourn; we must act. That is why my Administration has taken historic executive action to implement my comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy — from standing up gun trafficking strike forces to helping cities across the country expand community violence interventions and hire more police officers for community policing.</p>



<p>We also continue to call on Congress to act. Ban ghost guns. Require background checks for all gun sales. Ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines. Repeal gun manufacturers’ immunity from liability. Pass my budget proposal, which would give cities more of the funding they need to fund the police and fund the crime prevention and intervention strategies that can make our cities safer. These are just a few of the steps Congress urgently needs to take to save lives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the Commissioning Commemoration Ceremony of the USS&#160;Delaware</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/02/remarks-by-president-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-commissioning-commemoration-ceremony-of-the-uss-delaware/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 19:56:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Port of WilmingtonWilmington, Delaware 11:50 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; My name is Joe Biden.&#160; I am Jill’s husband.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; It’s always a good day when I get to celebrate Delaware or spend time with service members and their families or introduce Jill.&#160; That’s a trifecta in my family.&#160; Governor Carney, Senator Carper, Senator Coons, Congresswoman&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Port of Wilmington<br>Wilmington, Delaware</p>



<p>11:50 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; My name is Joe Biden.&nbsp; I am Jill’s husband.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>It’s always a good day when I get to celebrate Delaware or spend time with service members and their families or introduce Jill.&nbsp; That’s a trifecta in my family.&nbsp;<br><br>Governor Carney, Senator Carper, Senator Coons, Congresswoman Blunt Rochester, Secretary Del Toro, Commander Horton, and all the crew members and families of the USS Delaware: I’m genuinely honored to be with you.&nbsp;<br><br>This latest ship to carry the USS Delaware is part of a long &#8212; the name &#8212; is part of a long tradition of serving our nation proudly and strengthening our nation’s security &#8212; the security of the United States of America &#8212; not just us, but our Allies and partners around the world as well.&nbsp; In fact, it’s already been doing that for some time.<br><br>So I just want to say thank you to everyone &#8212; to everyone involved in bringing this submarine into service: for those who laid the keel, for those sailors who will crew it and all &#8212; through all the years to come.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I want you to know that I’ve had an incredible partner.&nbsp; Jill has watched over the progress of the USS Delaware for years.<br><br>The daughter of a Navy signalman during World War Two, the mother of a member of the Delaware National Guard, the grandmother of children who experienced having their father deployed away from home for a year at a time.&nbsp; She always holds our military and their families in her heart.&nbsp; And that is not hyperbole; that’s real.<br><br>And I’m deeply proud of the work she is doing as First Lady with Joining Forces initiative she started with Michelle Obama when&nbsp;<s>she</s>&nbsp;[I] was Vice President and now carries on.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As First Lady, she doesn’t &#8212; she’s been to more military installations around the world.&nbsp; She’s hosted more than 20 events for military families.&nbsp;<br><br>And she’s working &#8212; working to expand economic opportunities for military spouses who &#8212; by the way, in the words of Keats, “They also serve who only stand and wait.”&nbsp; And a submariner’s spouse stands and waits a lot.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And to help military kids for the support they need.&nbsp; And to make sure survivors and caregivers have the resources they deserve.<br><br>It’s a true passion for Jill and for our entire family.<br><br>As your Commander-in-Chief, I believe it is our sacred obligation as a nation to prepare and equip those troops that we send into harm’s way and to care for them and their families when they return home.&nbsp;<br><br>Now &#8212; now it’s my honor to introduce your First Lady, the sponsor of this great vessel, Jill Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I must admit, I never get tired of saying that.<br><br>As this ship’s sponsor, it’s my pleasure to welcome so many distinguished guests, and especially the Secretary of the Navy and Admirals Gilday and Caudle.<br><br>Commander Horton, Senior Chief Grammer, and the entire crew of the USS Delaware, it’s an honor to share this special day with you and your families.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>I especially want to welcome some of my good friends from Delaware Boots on the Ground.&nbsp; You know, working with you connected me to a community of incredible military families.&nbsp; And all these years later, your work continues to inspire me, and I hope you can see your influence in our Joining Forces initiative.<br><br>So, where are my Delaware Boots on the Ground members today?&nbsp; Where are they sitting?&nbsp;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; They’re down.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; They’re down.&nbsp; They’re down.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Wow, you’re down there?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The state of Delaware has loved the Bidens and cheered for us in most of our triumphant moments.&nbsp; It has carried us through the darkest times in our lives with a kindness that asks for nothing in return.&nbsp;<br><br>Delaware is family.<br><br>I’ll never forget the pride I felt when I stood at the Pentagon with Secretary of the Navy Ray Mabus, as well as you, Tom, to announce that I would be this ship’s sponsor.&nbsp; The USS Delaware was nothing more than a drawing then.&nbsp;<br><br>In 2016, my grandson, Hunter, joined me for the keel laying.&nbsp; And I think he felt the important connection that our family has to service then, and it was such a special moment for both of us.&nbsp;<br><br>Then, in 2018, I traveled to Newport News for the christening &#8212; seeing that simple drawing come to life in a shower of champagne.&nbsp; And I saw the truth of what Secretary Mabus said when it all began, that this vessel will always uphold the First State’s motto of “liberty and independence.”<br><br>So it’s difficult to put into words how much it means to be a part of the USS Delaware family.&nbsp; It is an incredible honor that I take seriously.&nbsp; I have cherished getting to know this community &#8212; from bowling with you at Newport News, to spending time with your families at Fort Groton for the holiday last December.<br><br>I’ve seen the heart of this crew, and it makes me feel both proud and humbled to be your shipmate for life.<br><br>Today’s celebration, like so many things in the past few years, is just a bit out of the ordinary.<br><br>At the beginning of the pandemic, the Delaware became the first ship ever commissioned while underwater, underway.&nbsp; It was a challenge to put a ship in service in the middle of a global pandemic, but you rose to the occasion as you always do.<br><br>Even if we are a little delayed in our celebration, today marks the beginning of an incredible journey: this ship’s long and faithful service to our country.<br><br>We may not know what’s to come, but we do know this: The challenges will be met with the honor, distinction, and valor of the 125 sailors who serve on her decks.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You will lead with unparalleled character and courage.<br><br>Of course, commissionings also mark a beginning for the families of the sailors, as well.&nbsp; Though the spouses and the children, parents and siblings with us today will stay on dry land, a piece of their hearts will sail away again and again.&nbsp; You too have a mission; you too serve our nation.<br><br>And as we look at this warship, we see its steel bulkheads and unbreakable hull.&nbsp; We see that it’s strong enough to withstand the most crushing pressure and slip silently through the deadliest waters.&nbsp;<br><br>And yet, so much of its power is unseen: the engines and sonar, the rudders that give it direction and purpose.<br><br>You, the families of this crew, may not wear a uniform, but with your love and support and with your sacrifice and devotion, you are as critical to our mission as the rudder is to this submarine.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Sailors, as you venture to new waters, know that the families who remain ashore will not be forgotten by your President or by me.&nbsp; We are working every day to honor the sacrifices that all of you make.<br><br>When our son, Beau, deployed to Iraq, another military mom shared with me a prayer &#8212; one I said every night while he was deployed.&nbsp; And it goes like this:<br>&nbsp;May the deep waters bring you more solace than strife.<br><br>May the friendships you find warm the cold walls of this vessel with laughter.&nbsp;<br><br>May you feel the glow of each goodbye embrace long after the horizon has lost the shore.&nbsp; May that light illuminate even the dimmest berthing.<br><br>May you always return home safely to the arms of the people who love you most.<br><br>And may God bless our troops and your families no matter where your journey takes you.&nbsp;<br><br>Amen.&nbsp;<br>Governor Carney, Senators Carper and Coons, Congresswoman Blunt Rochester, thank you for this celebration today.<br><br>And to our sailors: Thank you for your service and sacrifice.&nbsp; Thank you for allowing me to be your shipmate for life.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Everybody is here?&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR CHIEF PETTY OFFICER GRAMMER:&nbsp; Yes, ma’am.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Okay, shipmates: Officers and crew of the USS Delaware, man our ship and bring her to life!<br><br>USS DELAWARE CREW:&nbsp; Aye aye, ma’am!<br><br>12:01 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden Marking the Occasion of&#160;Ramadan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/statement-by-president-biden-marking-the-occasion-of-ramadan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50378</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Jill and I extend our best wishes to Muslim communities here in the United States and around the world on the beginning of the blessed month of Ramadan. For so many around the globe, including fellow Americans all across the country, this sacred month is a time for reflection and spiritual growth. Communities come together&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Jill and I extend our best wishes to Muslim communities here in the United States and around the world on the beginning of the blessed month of Ramadan.</p>



<p>For so many around the globe, including fellow Americans all across the country, this sacred month is a time for reflection and spiritual growth. Communities come together to practice forgiveness and resilience, to show compassion and generosity of spirit to those in need, of giving, and to celebrate the many blessings of life with loved ones.</p>



<p>This year, the simple act of breaking the fast will be an even more poignant reminder of the joys of health, family, and community.&nbsp; And we will continue to hold in our hearts all those families grieving a lost loved one who are facing an empty chair at the table.</p>



<p>As we continue to rebuild from the pandemic, we must also continue all of our efforts to stand with all those who are suffering and vulnerable around the world, those who are facing persecution or hardship.&nbsp; As the Holy Qur’an teaches, “whoever does even an atom’s weight of good will see its results.”</p>



<p>Every day, we see heartbreaking accounts of lost lives and the images of families and children struggling to survive. These tragedies remind us of our common humanity—and the common teaching of all great faiths, including Islam—that we should always do unto others as we would have done unto us. During this holy month, as Muslims everywhere honor God’s great mercy let us also renew our shared commitment to show kindness, mercy, and understanding to one another.&nbsp; Let us honor the simple yet profound truth that all people are equal in dignity and rights. That’s why the United States will continue to speak out for human rights everywhere&#8211;including for Uyghurs in China, Rohingya in Burma, and other Muslim communities all over the world.</p>



<p>From the Biden family to yours, and from the People’s House to your own homes, Jill and I wish you and your loved ones a blessed and prosperous month. <em>Ramadan Kareem</em>!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Diplomacy in the Middle East&#160;Region</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-diplomacy-in-the-middle-east-region/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 23:02:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50426</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we approach the Holy Month of Ramadan this weekend, we welcome the proactive diplomacy underway with our friends and partners across the Middle East region.  These efforts are central to President Biden’s agenda of forging a more secure and integrated Middle East region through a combination of deterrence against adversaries and diplomacy wherever possible&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As we approach the Holy Month of Ramadan this weekend, we welcome the proactive diplomacy underway with our friends and partners across the Middle East region.  These efforts are central to President Biden’s agenda of forging a more secure and integrated Middle East region through a combination of deterrence against adversaries and diplomacy wherever possible to reduce tensions and de-escalate ongoing conflicts.   </p>



<p>This approach was manifest this week.  </p>



<p>On Monday, Secretary of State Blinken attended a historic meeting in Israel together with the Foreign Ministers of Bahrain, Egypt, Israel, Morocco, and UAE.  This group of countries agreed to form permanent working groups with an aim to improve security and livelihoods across the region.  We now aim to further expand this circle of like-minded states.  Today’s conclusion of a Free Trade Agreement between the UAE and Israel exemplifies the new opportunities that are emerging in the region and upon which our administration is working to facilitate and strengthen.  </p>



<p>Secretary Blinken also visited Ramallah, where he reaffirmed President Biden’s commitment to doing all that we can to ensure Israelis and Palestinians share equal measures of freedom, dignity, security and prosperity.  Later in the week, King Abdullah II hosted the first-ever visit by an Israeli head of state, President Isaac Herzog, to Jordan.  We are grateful for the visionary role of these leaders and for the important role that King Abdullah II plays as custodian over the Holy Sites in Jerusalem, particularly over the upcoming Holy Days.</p>



<p>We also stand by our friends who face threats from terrorists, as seen over the past week in Israel.  President Biden spoke with Prime Minister Bennett on Wednesday and offered all appropriate assistance in the wake of these barbarous attacks against innocent civilian.  Our entire administration stand behind our Israeli allies as they work to confront threats to their citizens.  </p>



<p>Ending the war in Yemen has been a consistent focus of our administration over the past year.  Today, after months of relentless UN-led diplomacy backed by the United States and our partners, the UN’s Special Envoy to Yemen  announced a 60-day truce under which military operations will cease and restrictions on the flow of goods and people into and out of Yemen will ease.  President Biden welcomed this initiative and commended the leadership of Saudi Arabia and Oman in helping to finalize it.  We are hopeful that this initiative will establish a new foundation for political talks and a lasting settlement to end the suffering of the Yemeni people once and for all. </p>



<p>Even as we work to end the war in Yemen, there can be no doubt about President Biden’s commitment to supporting the defense of our partners, including the UAE and Saudi Arabia.  Earlier this week, the Treasury Department announced significant new sanction designations against Iran’s missile procurement network pursuant to Executive Order 13382, which targets weapons of mass destruction proliferators and their supporters.  We will continue to use all appropriate authorities to hold Iran and its proxy groups accountable for threats against our friends and partners.   </p>



<p>As this past week has shown, diplomacy is forging opportunities to secure a more peaceful and prosperous region even as we work to deter and counter threats against our partners and interests.  The United Stands will stand with its friends – and we are hopeful that this upcoming Holy Month of Ramadan will bring comfort and peace to peoples across the Middle East region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki and Member of the Council of Economic Advisers Jared Bernstein, April 1,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/01/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-member-of-the-council-of-economic-advisers-jared-bernstein-april-1-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 22:49:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:41 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, on my first day back, I am delivering Jared Bernstein to all of you, who we are thrilled to have to give some brief remarks on the economic news today and answer some questions.&#160; And then we will do a briefing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:41 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, on my first day back, I am delivering Jared Bernstein to all of you, who we are thrilled to have to give some brief remarks on the economic news today and answer some questions.&nbsp; And then we will do a briefing as long as we can before the President departs.<br><br>With that, I will turn it over to Jared.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jen.&nbsp; Today’s jobs report provides yet another indicator that, as the President said this morning, quote, “our economy has gone from being on the mend to being on the move.”&nbsp;<br><br>In the first conversation I had with the President when he was a candidate, he explained his view that we faced a dual health and economic crisis, and that we could not attack one without attacking both.&nbsp;<br><br>That intervention became the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; And the historically strong labor market we see in today’s jobs report is a testament to not just the President’s correct diagnosis and prescription, but his insistence that the plan be quickly and efficiently implemented to get COVID and economic relief &#8212; shots in arms and checks in pockets &#8212; into the system.&nbsp;<br><br>Today we learned that we’ve got an unemployment rate of 3.6 percent, a tick above its pre-pandemic rate of 3.5.&nbsp; We’ve got an historically unprent- &#8212; unprecedented run, with data back to 1939, of 11 months in a row with job gains north of 400,000, yielding an also unprecedented 7.9 million jobs since President Biden took office.<br><br>We have &#8212; in one of the most welcome trends we at CEA are seeing in the job market &#8212; increased labor force participation, and we have strong wage growth, particularly for middle- and lower-paid workers.<br><br>Getting under the hood of the report a bit: As you know, at the Council of Economic Advisers, we&#8217;re careful to not over-interpret one month of data, and therefore we always cite the three-month average, which in this case is the first quarter of this year.<br><br>With the upward revisions in today’s report, the average monthly gain over the quarter is 562,000 jobs per month.<br><br>Now, to provide some context for that growth pace, last month marked 23 months since employment hit its pandemic low.&nbsp; At a comparable point in the last expansion, the three-month av- &#8212; three-month average of job growth was 229,000, making the current jobs recovery more than twice as fast.<br><br>The Black unemployment rate ticked down by four tenths to 6.2 percent, just two tenths above its pre-pandemic rate.<br><br>As noted, one of the most important indicators in the current job market is labor force participation.&nbsp; Rising participation rates will facilitate a closer alignment of strong labor demand with labor supply, helping to support working families and to boost our real economic output.<br><br>Last month, labor force participation ticked up by a tenth overall and by a significant three tenths for the closely watched “prime-age workers” category, which focuses on workers age 25 to 54.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean that people who are over 54 are no longer &#8220;prime,&#8221; but that&#8217;s a different discussion.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>The prime-age participation rate in March was just a half a point below its pre-pandemic rate, and it is up by an historically strong 1.4 percentage points since President Biden took office.&nbsp;<br><br>In other words, last month&#8217;s bump was not a monthly blip but is part of an ongoing trend.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a trend &#8212; and also, in a trend that&#8217;s highly consistent with President Biden&#8217;s “Make It In America” Agenda, factory employment was up 38,000 last month and 473,000 since the President took office.<br><br>In other words, we are in the midst of a &#8212; of the fastest business cycle recovery of manufacturing employment in more than 50 years.<br><br>Now, as you know, we economists are always looking for policy lessons that we can apply to our work as we deal with a complex, ever-changing, and ever-challenging global economy.&nbsp;<br><br>In that regard, today’s job &#8212; jobs market provides a clear lesson.&nbsp; American employers and workers have taken every headwind thrown at them and just kept humming along.&nbsp; As the President said today, quote, “The headwinds…of Delta, Omicron, and even [the] war in Europe&#8221; have not been able to derail our job &#8212; our record jobs recovery.&nbsp; End quote.<br><br>It is unequivocally clear that one of the most important policies behind that result is the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>Of course, our work is not done, and we are actively addressing challenges faced by American households, especially uncomfortably high inflation.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know, just yesterday the President authorized the release of 1 million barrels per day for the next six months from our Strategic Petroleum Reserve, the largest release from our national reserves in history.&nbsp; And this morning, countries across the world agreed to release tens of millions of additional barrels into the market.<br><br>This work is, of course, highly complementary to our near-term work in speeding the pace at which goods move from ship-to-shelf and to our longer-term agenda, including the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s projects &#8212; projects to strengthen and increase the resiliency of our infrastructure and supply chains.<br><br>That, in turn, is complemented by the Bipartisan Innovation Act, which is geared towards making more in America, strengthening supply chains, and breaking up bottlenecks like semiconductor chips that are raising prices for consumers.&nbsp;<br><br>Our legislative agenda is also focused on reducing some of the toughest strains on family budgets, including prescription drugs, the costs of child and elder care, healthcare premiums, the cost of housing, and education.<br><br>But the fact that all of this work is occurring against the backdrop of one of the tightest, most welcoming labor markets on record is both a testament to the President’s policy agenda and to the unceasing energy and efforts of the American people.<br><br>Thank you, and we&#8217;ll move to your questions.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; The President said today that he thinks part of the impact of this will be easing the supply chain crunches.&nbsp; With more people in jobs, it&#8217;ll smooth out that &#8212; I wondered your view on that.&nbsp;<br><br>And in particular, we&#8217;re seeing new COVID lockdowns in China.&nbsp; That has, in the past, sort of fueled supply chain crises down the line.&nbsp; What is your view on that right now, as we sit here?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Let me start with &#8212; let me start with the first part of your question.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m glad you asked it because it&#8217;s one of the more important, kind of, under-the-hood indicators in today&#8217;s jobs report that should really get the attention of anyone who&#8217;s follos- &#8212; following the very issues you&#8217;ve raised.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things that needs to happen in this labor market is to the very strong labor demand that in my comments, as you say, as you &#8212; as you heard, I associated with some of the very important benefits of the Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Very strong labor demand needs to better align with labor supply.&nbsp;<br><br>The way that happens is through increased labor force participation rates.&nbsp; Now, as I mentioned, in March, that ticked up by a tenth of a percent, but I also cited what we call the prime-age rate, which is for workers 25 to 54.&nbsp; Labor economists like to look at that prime-age rate because it takes out teenagers and retirees and looks at &#8212; at folks who are most connected, typically, to the job market.&nbsp; That ticked up three tenths of a percent in March.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But more importantly &#8212; and again, we have long stressed that especially when you&#8217;re looking at these monthly numbers, you&#8217;ve got to look to the trend.&nbsp; That indicator is up by 1.4 points since this President took office.&nbsp; And if you look at the pace at which the labor force participation rate is increasing, it is faster in this recovery than any of the past four or five recoveries.&nbsp;<br><br>So that kind of development better aligns the very strong labor demand with labor supply in ways that will ease some of the &#8212; some of the price pressures, as the President referenced today.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You asked about &#8212; oh, China.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Whether that can counteract &#8212; you know, what is the net effect of China locking down but more Americans being in the workforce on the supply chains in the U.S.?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, these &#8212; these are precisely the kinds of issues that we have been tracking ever since this pandemic came on the scene.&nbsp; We know that we are still in a &#8212; an economy where the pandemic &#8212; a global economy where the pandemic is playing a role.&nbsp;<br><br>But as I stressed in my comments today &#8212; and the President said the same thing.&nbsp; I guess I&#8217;m saying the same thing he said, to be more accurate.&nbsp; If you look at, you know, &#8220;the headwinds…of Delta, Omicron, and even war in Europe&#8221; have not been able to derail our record jobs recovery.<br><br>Yes, there&#8217;s uncertainty, there are headwinds, and some of those headwinds are amplified by Putin&#8217;s unprovoked war in Ukraine.&nbsp; And yet we see, month after month, American employers and American workers shaking off those headwinds, creating record number of jobs and creating such an important economic backdrop for American households to get by in this challenging period.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mike?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Jared.&nbsp; So, what &#8212; the chart that you showed that was up there before with the huge bar for Biden, at what point does it become more fair to stop measuring the growth in jobs and the growth in the economy against the recovery from the depths of the pandemic, and begin to be more fair to measure President Biden&#8217;s progress at increasing from the pre-pandemic levels?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, I think that it&#8217;s already fair to do that in the following sense: If you look at some of the indicators, whether it&#8217;s jobs themselves, payroll employment &#8212; yeah, you&#8217;re right, this is not showing the time series; this is just the bar.&nbsp;<br><br>But if you look at the time series, you will see a &#8220;V&#8221; when things tanked and they came back pretty quickly.&nbsp; Same thing with labor force participation.<br><br>And I&#8217;m going to put this &#8212; I had a great slide; we weren&#8217;t able to get it together here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to put it on my twitter thread later &#8212; @EconJared46 &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; later today.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Give him a follow.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; And it will show the same thing, which is you see a &#8220;V,&#8221; and then you see a period of an ongoing trend start out and continue &#8212; and, in the case of labor force participation for prime-age workers, even accelerate a bit.<br><br>And I think that we&#8217;re 23 in &#8212; 23 months into a recovery now.&nbsp; I think it is completely legitimate to cite these numbers in terms of an ongoing trend, very much fueled by a virtuous cycle of strong consumers creating demand for goods and services, which in turn leads to strong labor demand month after month, driving the kind of numbers we saw today.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But just one quick follow-up.&nbsp; I mean, we&#8217;re still not back to pre-pandemic employment levels, correct?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And most of the indications, most of the measurements that Americans might want to &#8212; want you to say &#8212; to measure President Biden against is not like, &#8220;Okay, well, we dug ourselves out of the hole, but how much further are we getting above where we would have been had the pandemic not started?&#8221;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when do you guys start having to measure against that and measure against, like, &#8220;Okay, we&#8217;re now 500,000, a million jobs above where &#8212; you know, where we were before the terrible pandemic&#8221;?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So, there are a variety of ways to look at that.&nbsp; I would commend you to some work recently by Moody&#8217;s, which looks at counterfactuals &#8212; the idea of what might have happened had we not had the Rescue Plan.&nbsp; And in every case, you&#8217;re going to see job gains and unemployment declines, you know, well ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>I remember the unemployment number &#8212; that the unemployment rate might be 2 percentage points higher than it is right now but for the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>You&#8217;re right that jobs are not back to their pre-pandemic peak yet.&nbsp; They’re still 1.6 million or 1 percent below their pre-pandemic level, but they are climbing back at a rate &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>Look, I told you: 1.6 million from &#8212; and an average monthly job growth rate of 562,000 per month.&nbsp; So do &#8212; do the math.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; you know, that&#8217;s three months out.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, I&#8217;m not predecting [sic] &#8212; I’m not predicting that&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying if you extend the trend, that&#8217;s what you&#8217;d see.<br><br>But I think the most important point that we&#8217;re talking about here is that there is an ongoing labor market recovery with strong momentum that is delivering really solid job opportunities to American families, and that is such an important backdrop given the challenges that those families face in today&#8217;s economy.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nandita.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; A quick question about the President&#8217;s comments this morning: He was talking about the SPR release as a “wartime bridge.”&nbsp; And if you could talk a little bit about what he meant when he said that.&nbsp; Is it a wartime bridge to energy independence, maybe getting companies to ramp up production?&nbsp; Is it a wartime bridge to the Iran deal?&nbsp; Or a wartime bridge to perhaps both?<br><br>And secondly, conversations with a lot of oil and gas companies’ CEOs have been ongoing for several weeks now.&nbsp; Have there been sort of any specific commitments that the White House has been able to get from them when it comes to ramping up production?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So, on your first question, I think the way to think about this is it&#8217;s kind of a walk-and-chew-gum moment.&nbsp; I think of the bridge that the President was talking about as very much from the perspective of the American consumer who is facing real pressures at the pump.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, the last time we did a SPRO release &#8212; an SPR release, we saw oil prices fall quite quickly, and prices at the pump followed &#8212; were down at least 10 cents a gallon, as I remember, pretty close out of the gate.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Now, if you look just in the last day or two &#8212; I looked before I came up here &#8212; I saw oil is down about $7 a barrel &#8212; something around 7 or 8 percent since the President made his call.&nbsp; And so, when he&#8217;s talking about a bridge, he&#8217;s talking about helping American consumers with this aggressive, historically large distribution of barrels from the Strategic Reserves.<br><br>The idea of the &#8212; of the President&#8217;s clean energy and sustainable economy and decarbonization agenda is very much alive, very much ongoing, and that&#8217;s the chew-gum part.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, we have to make sure we help consumers get through this difficult period and help to bring to down the impact as best we can of the Putin price hike.&nbsp;<br><br>But at the same time, we simply cannot give any sort of short shrift to our clean energy agenda that is so essential for building not just a sustainable future, but a future of good jobs here in America.<br><br>One final point.&nbsp; When the &#8212; while the &#8212; while the strategic oil release should have the impacts that I and the &#8212; earlier, the President said today, that doesn&#8217;t mean that the impacts of the conflict in Ukraine are somehow no longer in play.&nbsp; They are still in the picture, and, of course, we will &#8212; we will follow them, particularly from the impact of commodity prices &#8212; food and energy specifically &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any commitments from the &#8212;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; &#8212; but not exclusively.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; any commitments from the companies specifically?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a readout on those conversations.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Steve.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jared, a month from today, the student loan payment pause is due to expire, and a number of congressional Democrats sent the President a letter yesterday, saying it was their sense that borrowers right now “are not financially prepared to shoulder another bill” as they deal with the increased price of food and gas and other necessities.&nbsp; First, do you agree with that sentiment?&nbsp; And second, is it your advice to the President that he extend the payment pause?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So, first of all, what did you ask me if I agreed with?&nbsp; Sorry.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just the sentiment that borrowers are not now prepared financially to take on another bill &#8212; the student loan payment.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; You know, I think that that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s a very specific question about a very specific group of people.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I&#8217;ve been talking largely today about the impact of a jobs market that&#8217;s generating historical levels of job gains &#8212; 7.9 million jobs since this President got here.&nbsp; And, of course, those benefits are occurring to families all across the nation and all across the income scale.<br><br>For the group that you&#8217;re talking about, many of them do face real challenges making debt payments, and I would say that&#8217;s kind of a different conversation than the one we&#8217;re having right now.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, I believe Ron has leaned into that in ways that I&#8217;m not remembering right now, but do you have any comments on that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; I like this.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, we’re doing it together.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any comments on Ron joining in?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Clearly, a decision that will need to be made in advance of the timeline.&nbsp; And obviously, we factor the impacts of, you know, economic data on ranges of groups of people, including students.&nbsp;<br><br>But I don&#8217;t have anything to announce at this point in terms of any decision that will be made in advance of the timeline.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well said.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, sorry.&nbsp; Kristen, go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Jared, the President has tapped the Strategic Reserve twice before and &#8212;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; it still hasn&#8217;t had the desired impact.&nbsp; Why is this time going to be different?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So, as I said a moment ago, I think that I would definitely challenge the claim that it hasn&#8217;t had the desired impact.&nbsp; We saw both in the last release and in this release the price of oil come down quite quickly.&nbsp; The price of oil, as I checked before I came on here, was down about $7 per barrel.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know that the last time &#8212; check it out, because these data are actually quite accessible.&nbsp; Look at what happened to the price &#8212; the retail price of gasoline after the last release.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, there &#8212; it&#8217;s a global market and there&#8217;s a lot of moving parts, but it is a fact that the price of gasoline fell about 10 cents per gallon shortly after it.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, if your point is that these releases from the Str- &#8212;&nbsp; releases from the SPR don&#8217;t have a &#8212; you know, don&#8217;t have a structural, long-term impact on oil markets, that&#8217;s why the President used the metaphor of a bridge today.&nbsp; The idea is to help consumers as they go &#8212; is to help consumers as they deal with elevated inflationary pressures more broadly &#8212; and specifically with some of the impacts of the Putin price hike on energy costs.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the &#8212; that&#8217;s what the release is targeted towards.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more very quickly.&nbsp; Yesterday, Kate was briefing and she said that “all options are on the table” as it relates to next potential steps that the President may or may not support.&nbsp; Does the President think that a gas tax holiday is a good idea right now?&nbsp; Is that something that he could get behind?&nbsp; Obviously, it&#8217;s gaining a lot of momentum in the states.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;m not going to legislate from here or even get into ongoing policy considerations beyond saying: When we say “all options are on the table,” we mean it.&nbsp; And that option is &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think it’s a good policy?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Do I personally think it&#8217;s a good policy?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Broadly.&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I think it’s a &#8212; I think that all options are on the table and all options, including that one, should be on the table.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Jacqui, you got to be the last one.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Jared, yesterday, you know, Brian talked about the Strategic Petroleum Reserve and buying back oil when prices are cheaper in the future.&nbsp; But, you know, long term, as you just mentioned, the release does not solve the problem of the structural deficit in the market.&nbsp;<br><br>It &#8212; and, you know, this administration talks about how you&#8217;re pushing for domestic producers to ramp up production, but how is that going to happen?&nbsp; Like the fees yesterday that were announced were &#8212; are sort of a push to get them to use these, you know, leases, not all of which may produce any energy.&nbsp; But beyond that, the answer I got yesterday was: Long-term, our focus is on, you know, clean energy, and that&#8217;s why the President invoked the DPA to try to get, you know, battery parts for electric vehicles.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>That was not, you know, the answer that the oil industry was looking for.&nbsp; The &#8212; that answer for, you know, what the long-term plan is &#8212; shifted away from fossil fuels.&nbsp; So how are they going to ramp up production?&nbsp; And why can you say that prices are going to be cheaper in the future where it doesn&#8217;t seem like there any friendlier energy policies?<br><br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, first of all, let me just be very clear and specific: When I &#8212; my comment on retail &#8212; the retail costs of gas at the pump, relating to the SPR release, is very much an empirical pattern that we&#8217;ve seen time and again where an SPR release occurs, the price of oil comes down, we see that at the pump.&nbsp; And, as I suggested, that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a time-limited function.&nbsp; The President called it a &#8220;bridge.&#8221;&nbsp; You&#8217;re sort of saying, “A bridge to what?”<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; And I understand that.&nbsp; Well, look, if you believe, as I do, that this is still a global mark- &#8212; that energy is still a global market and still a competitive market, what you expect to see is: At a particular price point where oil is, actually, probably above &#8212; oil is probably above that price point &#8212; and certainly has been even higher in recent weeks &#8212; historically, that has led to greater energy production.&nbsp;<br><br>And one of the things you hear the President saying in so many words is that we&#8217;d like to see that kind of production, that kind of response from the impact of market forces on these &#8212; the decisions of these energy companies.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Now, if you don&#8217;t see that market response, I think you have to ask yourself why.&nbsp; And that involves the kinds of commentary you&#8217;ve heard the President make about industry concentration; about the need for competitiveness; the importance of having an adequate level of competition within our key industries, whether its energy or meatpacking.&nbsp; Because absent &#8212; in the presence of excessive concentration and absent adequate competition, price levels can be higher than they otherwise would.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So I very much support the President&#8217;s rhetoric and the &#8212; the way in which he&#8217;s leaned into that problem.&nbsp;<br><br>But historical &#8212; historically, we expect price signals in the energy market to have the effect that they&#8217;ve had, and we will continue to nudge the companies to move in that direction.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But when lenders hear, you know, “What&#8217;s your long-term solution?”&nbsp; And they &#8212;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; “When lenders,” you said?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lenders.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Uh-huh.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When &#8212; we’re talking about a long-term solution, and then, you know, the administration&#8217;s talking about clean energy.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s not sending the signal to lenders that this is a safe place for investment; that &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a &#8212; this administration is saying plainly, “We want to increase domestic production.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That&#8217;s the sort of language they&#8217;re looking for.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t really agree with that framing in the following sense.&nbsp; I think by “lenders” &#8212; I think &#8212; like, I&#8217;m thinking of investors.&nbsp; And, you know, investors in the energy sector &#8212; if you look at the profitability, if you even look at some of the buybacks and the share prices &#8212; investors in that sector have been doing quite well.&nbsp; And that tells you right there that there is a price point wherein it is very possible for an energy producer to be highly successful and to make a lot of money in today&#8217;s economy.&nbsp;<br><br>And in fact, what we&#8217;d like to &#8212; I think one of the messages the President has been trying to convey to them &#8212; that is on behalf of the American consumers, we&#8217;re asking you to respond to those price signals so that people can have an easier time of getting through this tough period.&nbsp;<br><br>Now at the same time, we have a medium- and a long-term agenda that is absolutely existentially important to us to move towards a sustainable economy.&nbsp; And we do that in a way that creates great opportunities for both firms, employers, and for workers.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So again, this is not an either-or; it is a both-and.&nbsp; And I see a very &#8212; I see very much an economic structure in energy markets where they can both engage in robust production today and plan for a much cleaner energy future.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Jared, for joining us.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You&#8217;re always welcome.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We will keep you honest and &#8212; as long &#8212; as long as you can stay before you need to gather.&nbsp; And we’ll keep you updated.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to track closely from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, are you leaving for MSNBC?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just have a couple of quick updates for you from the top.&nbsp;<br><br>One is: In the State of the Union, the President called on the &#8212; out the ocean shipping carriers who raised their prices by as much as 1,000 percent during the pandemic.&nbsp; These costs pass through to American businesses and families, and contribute to inflation.<br><br>And just a month after the President spoke about this at the State of the Union, the Pres- &#8212; the Senate yesterday passed overwhelmingly bipartisan legislation to reform the ocean shipping industry and lower costs for American farmers, businesses, and consumers.&nbsp;<br><br>And additionally this week, the Department of Justice announced that it successfully stopped a merger between two companies that make the cranes that move shipping containers on and off of ships at our nation’s port &#8212; ports.&nbsp; The merger would have harmed American consumers by reducing competition in the supply chain and would have put our global supply chain at risk.&nbsp; And so these steps, obviously, are positive step forward &#8212; steps forward.&nbsp;<br><br>I also wanted to note that, today, the Department of Homeland &#8212; Health and Human Services and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services made important announcements in response to the Vice President’s call to action to improve health outcomes.<br><br>Beginning today, as many as 720,000 pregnant and postpartum people across the United States could be guaranteed Medicaid and Children’s Health Insurance Program coverage for up &#8212; for a full 12 months after pregnancy thanks to the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>Finally, for the week ahead &#8212; so, next week &#8212; sorry, I had one more thing after this.&nbsp; On Monday, the President will deliver remarks on progress made on his administration’s Trucking Action Plan to strengthen our nation’s supply chains.<br><br>On Tuesday, he will deliver remarks celebrating the success of the Affordable Care Act and Medicaid in extending affordable health insurance to millions of Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>And on Wednesday, the President will address thousands of national, state, and local building trades lend- &#8212; leaders from across the country at the North America&#8217;s Building Trades Unions’ Legislative Conference.<br><br>Finally, as you know, the United States is delivering a significant amount of security assistance to Ukraine every day.&nbsp; Over the past few weeks, we have delivered more than $350 million of security assistance to Ukraine, which the Pentagon has described as an &#8220;unprecedented pace.&#8221;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we welcome the UK’s donors conference yesterday and its announcement that allies and partners will provide coastal defense systems, which is something that President Zelenskyy has asked for and is something that President Biden discussed extensively with Allies at NATO last week.<br><br>More than 30 nations have now sent security assistance to Ukraine, thanks in part to the leadership of the President and our diplomacy.&nbsp;<br><br>So why don’t I &#8212; we’re going to get to as many people as possible.&nbsp; Darlene, why don’t you kick us off.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Welcome back.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One question on Russia and two, quickly, on two other subjects.&nbsp; Russia says that an apparent attack by Ukraine on one of its fuel depots is making it harder for Russia to stay engaged in the talks to end the war.&nbsp; And I was wondering what the White House thinks of this suggestion from Russia that Ukraine’s actions are the ones that are potentially standing in the way of peace over there.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ve &#8212; we have seen those reports.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not in a position to comment on the Kremlin’s statements. I would note Ukraine has not made any statements or confirmation of these reports.&nbsp;<br><br>I would also note that this is a war that President Putin started &#8212; a brutal war with Russia&#8217;s forces continuing to bombard cities across Ukraine and commit terrible acts of violence.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen the people of Ukraine fight valiantly in the face of unprovoked Russian brutality, but there is one aggressor here, and that is President Putin and the Russian military at his direction.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, on Title 42 &#8212; the announcement that it’s going to be lifted on May 23rd: Can you talk a little bit about why the restrictions aren’t lifted sooner than May 23rd, perhaps even immediately?&nbsp; People who want to come to the country to seek asylum will now have to wait seven weeks to do so when the CDC says that restriction is no longer necessary.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Well, it has always been the case and continues to be the case that this is a health directive determined by the CDC, so let me start there.&nbsp; But I would also say that implementation of their decision requires an interagency process, specifically leadership of the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; I would note the statement that was put out by Secretary Mayorkas.&nbsp; And it requires the implementation of appropriate COVID-19 mitigation protocols, also scaling up capacity and scaling up, you know, resources needed.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so, it was always going to be important to have an implementation period, and the timeline reflects that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then the last question is: Is there any comment on the vote in Staten Island by Amazon workers to unionize?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Becoming the first in Amazon to do that.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President was glad to see workers ensure their voices are heard with respect to important workplace decisions.&nbsp; He believes firmly that every worker in every state must have a free and fair choice to join a union and the right to bargain collectively with their employer.&nbsp; The Amazon workers in Staten Island made their choice to organize a grassroots union and bargain for better jobs and a better life.<br><br>Go ahead, MJ.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, just in light of the fuel depot fire in Russia, what is the U.S.’s general position on potential future attacks by Ukraine on Russian soil?&nbsp; Does the U.S. believe that it is up to the Ukrainians to decide whether such potential attacks are justified?&nbsp; Or does it generally believe that those kinds of attacks should be discouraged because they would be seen as being escalatory?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, given we have not confirmed or commented specifically on the reports from here and neither has Ukraine, I&#8217;m not going to get into a future hypothetical.&nbsp;<br><br>What I would just reiterate again is that this is a war of aggression by the Russian leadership, by President Putin that has left millions of people displaced, homeless; has targeted civilians, hospitals, and other innocent people across Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>We know who the aggressor is; that is President Putin and Russia.&nbsp; And beyond that, I don&#8217;t have any comment on military tactics.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said yesterday that Vladimir Putin appears to be self-isolating, that he appears to have maybe fired or put under house arrest certain advisors.&nbsp; Does the U.S. have a clearer sense of which advisors are currently advising Putin and who has his ear?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President was speaking yesterday to public reporting, so we don&#8217;t have more details to speak to at this point in time.&nbsp;<br><br>But I would say, to go back to a couple of days ago and the information that was put out by the administration that was reflected &#8212; that came through our intelligence agencies, what we do know is that this war is not going how President Putin had planned; that his intention of winning a quick war, defeating Ukraine &#8212; the Ukrainians quickly is not how it has played out.&nbsp; We have seen troops be demoralized.&nbsp; We have seen troops run out of equipment that they need on the Russian side.&nbsp; And that is clearly not what he had planned.<br><br>In terms of who is advising him, I don&#8217;t have more specifics on that front from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more on a separate topic.&nbsp; You&#8217;re obviously not the only person in the administration recently to test positive for COVID.&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of whether there have been discussions lately at the White House about what would happen if President Biden were to test positive for COVID?<br><br>Help us understand what working from home, quarantining, running the country would look like if the President were to get COVID.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that &#8212; this wasn&#8217;t exactly your question, but let me reiterate this point &#8212; is that we take steps over and beyond CDC recommendations and guidelines here.&nbsp;<br><br>I would note that while I tested positive about 12 days ago, if my math is correct, I waited to return to the office until I had a negative test.&nbsp; And that is our protocol here &#8212; or the protocol I was held to.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Also, we take steps in advance of meeting the President.&nbsp; Anyone who&#8217;s meeting the President is going to have a test that day.&nbsp; And we also take social distancing steps in meetings when warranted.<br><br>In terms of &#8212; look, we recognize that COVID-19 remains a transmissible disease, especially recent variants.&nbsp; And while I&#8217;m not going to get into a future hypothetical of any of our additional principals, since &#8212; since the Second Gentleman had tested positive &#8212; testing positive &#8212; I would note that the President of the United States can work from anywhere, can run the country from anywhere.&nbsp; And we have the capacity to not only prepare for that but to support anything that is needed.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just a quick follow-up on the Staten Island vote.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s obviously a big moment for the labor movement in this country &#8212; the first union at Amazon.&nbsp; Has the President had a chance to speak to labor leaders?&nbsp; Or is he planning to issue a statement?&nbsp; Is he planning to talk about it at all?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything planned to preview for you in terms of an official statement.&nbsp; I&#8217;m speaking, of course, on his behalf.&nbsp;<br><br>Obviously, as you know, the President has been a longtime supporter of the right to organize, the right to &#8212; for workers to organize and plan for better jobs and a better life.&nbsp; And certainly, my comments reflect that.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen just &#8212; oh, sorry.&nbsp; I had a quick follow-up &#8212; just comments from a senior Treasury official this morning that said, sort of, the sanctions that have been imposed by the U.S. and its allies on Russia is sort of pushing Russia to become a closed economy.&nbsp; That is obviously presuming that, you know, China and others are not sort of making some of the materials that they get from the West available to them.&nbsp;<br><br>Has the administration noted any sort of change in stance when it comes to China, you know, and Russia?&nbsp; Or is it &#8212; you know, is there any evidence that they&#8217;re providing perhaps military, economic support?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our assessment has not changed since our National Security Advisor spoke to this.&nbsp; What I would point out for you too, as well, is the strong statements that came from European leaders, given their meeting on exactly this topic today, which certainly we share the sentiment.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lots of urgent issues discussed here, but with the helicopter approaching, one little bit of housekeeping.&nbsp; Is it true that you are leaving the White House to work for MSNBC?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, you can&#8217;t get rid of me yet, Ed.&nbsp; I have nothing to confirm about my length of public service or planned service, or anything about consideration about next plans.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m very happy to be standing with all of you here today, after it felt like a never-ending, endless time in my basement quarantining away from my family.&nbsp; Believe it or not, I missed you all a lot.&nbsp;<br><br>And my focus every day continues to be speaking on behalf of the President; answering your questions, as tough as they may be at many times, as difficult as they may be to answer at many times.&nbsp; And I hope that I meet my own bar of treating everybody with fairness and being equitable.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just because this has been raised by our colleagues, by people who are observing this process: Is it ethical for you to continue conducting this job while negotiating with a media outlet?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I have always gone over and above the stringent ethical and legal requirements of the Biden administration, and I take that very seriously.&nbsp; And as is standard for every employee of the White House, I have received rigorous ethics counseling, including as it relates to any future employment.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve complied with all ethics requirements and gone beyond, and taken steps to recuse myself from decisions as appropriate.<br><br>And so, I hope that all of you &#8212; I&#8217;ve been working with all of you some time &#8212; would judge me for my record and how I treat all of you, both in the briefing room and otherwise.&nbsp; And I try to answer questions from everybody across the board.&nbsp; I know everybody in the back of the room may not always be pleased with me, but I try my best.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I will &#8212; I will certainly continue to do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a follow?<br><br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br><br>Q&nbsp; &nbsp; Are you good?&nbsp; Can I follow?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Go ahead, Kristen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, given the reports, which have now been confirmed by multiple media outlets, how can you continue to be an effective briefer if you do, in fact, have plans to join a media outlet?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I have nothing, again, to announce about any conversations or any future plans.&nbsp; And at whatever time I leave the White House, I can promise you the first thing I&#8217;m going to do is sleep and spend time with my three- and six-year-old who are my most important audiences of all.<br><br>But I would say, Kristen, that, again, I have done &#8212; have taken the ethics, legal requirements to the highest &#8212; very seriously in any discussions, in any considerations about any future employment, just as any White House official would.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve taken steps beyond that to ensure there&#8217;s no conflicts.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I understand what you&#8217;re saying.&nbsp; But I guess the question is: How is it ethical to have these conversations with media outlets while you continue to have a job standing behind that podium?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there are a range of stringent ethical and legal requirements that are imposed on everybody in this administration and many administrations past about any conversations you&#8217;re having with future employers.&nbsp; That is true of any industry you&#8217;re working in.&nbsp; And I have abided by those, and tried to take steps to go beyond that as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, broadly speaking, is it the policy of this White House to allow staffers to have discussions, even indirectly, with institutions that impact and affect their jobs and your job here?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it is the policy of this White House to ensure that anyone who is having conversations about future employment does so through consultation with the White House Counsel&#8217;s Office and ensuring they abide by any ethics and legal requirements.&nbsp; And those are conversations that I have taken very seriously and abided by every component of.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back of the room?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay, so let me go to Sabrina and we can go &#8212; and then we can wrap.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Can you confirm &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said you missed us.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; reports that the U.S. &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; okay, I know.&nbsp; It may be that people who may have to see the President depart and I don’t want to hold anyone back.&nbsp; But I also am happy to answer your question and a couple of others if people want to stay.&nbsp; But if people need to &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>Are they gathering right now?&nbsp; Sorry to interrupt your train of thought here.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. BATES:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you confirm reports that the U.S. has been providing Ukraine with protective equipment such as gas masks, hazmat suits, and other materials because of a possible chemical weapons attack from Russia?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, the United States and members of the international community have, of course, repeatedly warned about the potential for Russia to use chemical or biological weapons in Ukraine and that Moscow is possibly planning a false-flag operation.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In an effort to assist our Ukrainian partners, the U.S. government is providing the government of Ukraine with lifesaving equipment and supplies that could be deployed in the event of Russia &#8212; Russian use of a chemical and biological weapon against Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>It does not compromise our domestic preparedness in any way, shape, or form &#8212; just for everybody&#8217;s awareness &#8212; but we are providing it as we are providing a range of materials and equipment.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one quick question on another subject.&nbsp; The House passed a bill today that would remove marijuana from the federal schedule of controlled substances.&nbsp; Every Democrat, save for two, voted in favor of this bill.&nbsp; Does the President support the legislation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that, as the President said during the campaign, our current marilan- [sic] &#8212; marijuana laws are not working.&nbsp; He agrees that we need to rethink our approach, including to address the racial disparities and systemic &#8212; (Briefing Room door opens) &#8212; oh, okay &#8212; inequities in our criminal justice system, broaden research on the effects of marijuana, and support the safe use of marijuana for medical purposes.&nbsp;<br><br>We look forward to working with Congress to achieve our shared goals, and we’ll continue having discussions with them about this objective.&nbsp;<br><br>Jacqui, go ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay, we got to wrap up in a second here.&nbsp; And then I’ll go to Karen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Madam, one more &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The back?&nbsp; Back of the room?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, so they’re &#8212; you guys got to wrap.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, do you have a reaction to the IEA saying they’re going to commit more oil reserves (inaudible)?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we gather now?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it a gather?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we go or &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m sure we will get you a &#8212; let me &#8212; let us get you a thorough comment on that.&nbsp; I will say, as the President conveyed in his announcement yesterday, certainly working with the global community to ensure we are meeting the supply shortages in the global community at this time is part of our effort to reduce gas prices for Americans, given it’s a global oil market.&nbsp; So this is a part of that.<br><br>And we will get to a more comprehensive &#8212; I&#8217;m here and in my office if you guys have &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; quick que- &#8212;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; can you take my question on inflation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Real quick.&nbsp; Today, the President blamed Putin&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine for not just higher gas prices, but also higher food prices.&nbsp; Inflation was at 7.4 percent in January, before the invasion.&nbsp; In February, it went up to 7.9 percent.&nbsp; Putin didn’t invade until the 24th.&nbsp; So, March is really going to show the impact of the invasion, and that report doesn&#8217;t even come out until April 12th.&nbsp;<br><br>So how are people supposed to believe the Putin price hike is to blame for food prices going up when the timeline doesn&#8217;t add up?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s what the President is reflecting on: One, the price of gas has gone up by approximately a dollar or more since Putin started lining up troops at the border.&nbsp; This is something that outside economists have spoken to as well, not just the administration.&nbsp; And those are just factual details about how much the price of gas has gone up.&nbsp; We know that&#8217;s a huge impact, and when you say inflation, people think the cost on their pocketbook and the impact on their budgets.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The second piece, on the availability of food: We know that different markets around the world are impacted by the lack of production in Ukraine and other &#8212; because of the war.&nbsp; And we know that that could impact global food prices.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it hasn’t happened yet.&nbsp; And this is the first time we&#8217;ve heard the President blame Putin for higher food prices.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think what the President is looking at is what the impact has been in a lot of areas that are leading to price increases on people&#8217;s pocketbooks and where we could see it increasing over the course of time.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m here in my office.&nbsp; I’ll see you all soon.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>END&nbsp; 3:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Senior Administration Travel to&#160;India</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/readout-of-senior-administration-travel-to-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 22:24:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh was in New Delhi to discuss ways to deepen U.S.-India economic cooperation and advance our shared interest in a free and open Indo-Pacific. Singh also continued our close consultations with Indian counterparts about the destabilizing economic impacts of Russia’s war against Ukraine. Singh met with Principal Secretary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, Deputy National Security Advisor Daleep Singh was in New Delhi to discuss ways to deepen U.S.-India economic cooperation and advance our shared interest in a free and open Indo-Pacific. Singh also continued our close consultations with Indian counterparts about the destabilizing economic impacts of Russia’s war against Ukraine. Singh met with Principal Secretary P.K. Mishra, Minister of Commerce and Indian G20 Sherpa Piyush Goyal, Foreign Secretary Harsh V. Shringla, Deputy National Security Advisor Vikram Misri, and Department of Economic Affairs Secretary Ajay Seth. Singh consulted with Indian counterparts on the goals and mechanisms of U.S. sanctions imposed on Russia and ways to cooperate on addressing global food insecurity and global energy prices. Singh and his counterparts also advanced ongoing discussions about the development of an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, delivering high-quality infrastructure through Build Back Better World, the development of an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, and strengthening the global economy. The conversations were productive and both sides committed to continue their close consultations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on Historic Investments in Economic Development in Underserved&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/01/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-historic-investments-in-economic-development-in-underserved-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 22:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Delta Center StageGreenville, Mississippi THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Please have a seat.&#160; Good &#8212; it&#8217;s so good to be with you all.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Good afternoon. Ms. Joyce, I want to thank you for that introduction.&#160; You know, I had the honor of visiting her shop earlier&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Delta Center Stage<br>Greenville, Mississippi</em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Please have a seat.&nbsp; Good &#8212; it&#8217;s so good to be with you all.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br><br>Ms. Joyce, I want to thank you for that introduction.&nbsp; You know, I had the honor of visiting her shop earlier today.&nbsp; And it took me back.&nbsp; I shared with her &#8212; you know, my mother would make our clothes often.&nbsp; She would make &#8212; I remember in particular a couple of very fancy dresses she made.&nbsp; And going to the shop, I saw those fancy dresses that Ms. Joyce was making, and I thought &#8212; it really took me back.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know what it means to have a place like that in the community where you can go and where families go and where it is intergenerational, in terms of the families that are impacted by the work that happens in places like that.<br><br>So, I want to thank you for allowing me to visit with you today and to visit your store.<br><br>Mayor Errick Simmons, where are you?&nbsp; I know you&#8217;re here.&nbsp; There you are.&nbsp; I want to thank you for welcoming us &#8212; so warmly welcoming us.&nbsp; The mayor met me on the tarmac as I landed, and I thank you for the warm welcome and your role of leadership.<br><br>&nbsp;It is good to be in this beautiful place.&nbsp; And so good to be here, of course, with Chairman Bennie Thompson &#8212; where is he?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I will tell you, he is a true champion for the people of this state.&nbsp; And I didn&#8217;t dare make this trip plan without checking in with Bennie Thompson &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to seek his advice and approval.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But I will tell you, in all seriousness, I have seen him, over the years, during the time that we have worked together, in the halls of the Capital, in these very ornate rooms in our United States Capital &#8212; sometimes when the camera is on, sometimes when the cameras are off &#8212; and he is the same person always.&nbsp; He is always fighting for the people of Mississippi.&nbsp; Always.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And I&#8217;ve had the pleasure of seeing him twice this week because &#8212; or last week, actually &#8212; because we were at the White House when the Pre- &#8212; together when the President signed into law the Emmett Till Antilynching Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; yes &#8212; which was a step toward finishing some unfinished business.<br><br>Also here with us today is the great Bill Bynum, the CEO of Hope Credit Union.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And Mr. Bynum, as you know, has helped connect so many people in Mississippi and across the South with opportunity and, yes, with hope to be all they can be.&nbsp;<br><br>And I shared with a couple of folks earlier &#8212; I did check in with him actually after we first came into office, because this has been a very longstanding area of focus and priority for me, which is to support our small businesses.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d been hearing for years about work of Bill Bynum and so checked in with him at the very beginning.&nbsp;<br><br>And he told me at the very beginning, during the height of the restriction &#8212; COVID &#8212; so we couldn&#8217;t really travel &#8212; and he said, &#8220;Well, Madam Vice President, if you really want to see what&#8217;s going on, you come to the Mississippi Delta.&#8221;&nbsp; So here I am.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; So here I am.<br><br>&nbsp; And so, Greenville is a city that knows so much and, in particular, knows resilience.&nbsp; In 1927, the waters of the Mississippi rose and covered every square foot of this city for three months.&nbsp; And when the water receded, the people of Greenville cleaned up and moved back in.&nbsp;<br><br>Over the past two years, like so many communities around our nation, you have faced incredible challenges.&nbsp; And you have met those incredible challenges with incredible strength.</p>



<p>Greenville is a place built by the ambition and the aspiration of its people.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As an extension of the fact that America is a place that was built by the ambition and aspiration of its people.&nbsp; America is a nation built by people who see what can be, unburdened by what has been.&nbsp;<br><br>People with the ambition and the aspiration to transform dreams into reality: to buy a house, to get an education, to start a business, to leave something behind for the next generation.&nbsp; That energy drives our entire nation forward, and it creates jobs, it accelerates innovation, it strengthens our communities, it expands our economy, and it makes our nation more globally competitive.&nbsp;<br><br>And as you know, turning ambition and aspiration into action often requires capital &#8212; capital to start and grow a business or buy or renovate a home.&nbsp;<br><br>And it requires financial services &#8212; services like checking and savings accounts, credit cards and lines of credit, financial information and good advice.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know well, not everyone in our country, sadly, can access this essential support.&nbsp;<br><br>Consider this: Black entrepreneurs are three times more likely to report that they did not apply for credit for fear of being turned away by a bank.&nbsp; Black and Latino homeowners are rejected at a higher rate when applying for home loans from traditional financial institutions, even when they have credit profiles similar to other applicants.&nbsp; Many Asian American business owners, in particular immigrant business owners, face language barriers that limit their ability to access capital and banking services.&nbsp;<br><br>And people who live in rural communities often lack access to traditional banking services of any kind.&nbsp; This includes many Native Americans and, here in the Mississippi Delta, many Black folks.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, let us acknowledge also that while they play an important role in the growth of our economy, traditional banks have not always seen the vision of small-business owners of color, small-business owners who are women, small-business owners who live in rural areas, and small-business owners who serve low-income communities.&nbsp;<br><br>Community lenders, on the other hand, were created to see that vision and to support it.&nbsp; These lenders predominantly serve overlooked and underserved communities.&nbsp; The people who run these institutions often live and work in those communities.&nbsp; They know the people to whom they are lending.&nbsp; They understand the community, their needs, their challenges, and their strengths.&nbsp;<br><br>When they make a loan, they often personally feel its impact because, of course, they are there, linked with the community.&nbsp; And so, community lenders often see the potential that others might overlook.&nbsp;<br><br>Potential like Hope Credit Union saw in Ms. Joyce.&nbsp; Hope Credit Union loaned Joyce just over $10,000, an amount too small for most traditional banks to bother lending.&nbsp; But it was an amount that was transformative for Ms. Joyce and for Greenville.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Across our nation, small businesses are engines of economic prosperity.&nbsp; And this is especially true in rural areas and in Mississippi, where over 99 percent of all businesses are small businesses.&nbsp;<br><br>Rural small businesses train and hire local workers.&nbsp; They provide essential products and services to customers that they often see on a daily basis and face to face.&nbsp; And they know and understand, and they help ensure residents have the opportunities they need to remain in the places they love.<br><br>And these businesses do not just create prosperity, they also build community.&nbsp; So often &#8212; in my experience and, I’m sure, yours &#8212; small-business owners are not only leaders in<br>business, they are community leaders.&nbsp; They are civic leaders.&nbsp; They sponsor the local softball team.&nbsp; They mentor and hire young people from the community.&nbsp; They are role models.&nbsp; And now, as we all know well, rural small businesses also face unique challenges that businesses in urban areas sometimes do not.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, many operate in communities that do not have access to affordable or accessible high-speed Internet or in communities where the roads and bridges are in desperate need of repair.&nbsp;<br><br>So, our administration is dealing with that too.&nbsp; And we have made, we are proud to say &#8212; again, thanks to the Congressman and so many others &#8212; historic investments to address these challenges.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invests $110 billion to repair our nation&#8217;s roads and bridges, to help customers and employees better access small businesses.&nbsp; And the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law invests $65 billion to ensure that every person in our nation has access to affordable high-speed Internet.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And we know that part of why that is important is, of course, the subject today: Small businesses need to reach their customers.&nbsp; They need to buy supplies, even run their cash register.&nbsp; And all of that will be helped by having access to high-speed Internet.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we are fighting every day to ensure that small businesses have access to capital and the banking services they need to thrive.&nbsp; And that is why we are all here today.<br><br>Mississippi has one of the highest concentrations of community lenders of any state in our nation &#8212; (applause) &#8212; with more than 100 CDFIs &#8212; these Community Development Financial Institutions &#8212; holding assets of over $35 billion.<br><br>Those institutions have helped so many small-business owners, like Joyce, start, grow, and protect their small business.&nbsp; And they deserve more support.&nbsp;<br><br>So, like many of the lenders here with us today, expanding our nation&#8217;s investment in these institutions has been a priority of mine for years.&nbsp; When I was senator, I helped secure $12 billion for community lenders as part of a COVID-19 relief bill &#8212; because we clearly know from Joyce’s story the connection there.<br><br>Of the approximately $10 billion that has already been allocated from that investment, more has gone to community lenders in Mississippi than to lenders in any other state.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And now, our administration is working with our partners &#8212; the Secretary of the Treasury, Janet Yellen, and the Administrator of the SBA, Isabella Guzman &#8212; to broaden the reach of community lenders.&nbsp;<br><br>So I&#8217;m going to offer a couple of examples.&nbsp; Back in 2011, the Small Business Administration launched what was called the Community Advantage pilot loan program.&nbsp; Through this program, the SBA partially guarantees loans made by community lenders.&nbsp; It allows community lenders to make more investems [sic] &#8212; more investments in underserved communities and to make loans to entrepreneurs that others have deemed too risky.<br><br>Earlier this week, I was proud to announce that our administration is extending, expanding, and improving the Community Advantage program so that more small businesses will be able to benefit.&nbsp; And our work does not stop there.<br><br>Families across the nation are feeling the rising cost of housing.&nbsp; Now, there are many reasons homes are becoming more expensive to buy and to rent.&nbsp; Here is one of the most significant: Our country simply does not have enough houses.&nbsp; That is why in the budget that our administration released this week, we proposed $5 billion in funding over 10 years for community lenders to invest in construction and rehabilitation projects.&nbsp;<br><br>That will increase the number of affordable homes available to rent and to buy.&nbsp; And it will help to lower the cost of living of families throughout our country.<br><br>And I&#8217;ll end with this:&nbsp;You know, when the pundits &#8212;<br>you know, in the evening news &#8212; they talk &#8212; when they talk about economic opportunity &#8212; right? &#8212; and they&#8217;re asked their opinion about economic opportunity, have you ever noticed that they will often refer to Wall Street or Silicon Valley?&nbsp;<br><br>Well, from my perspective, I think they should be talking about places like Greenville.&nbsp; (Applause.) (Laughs.)&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Because, you know, this is a place that can help us take the temperature of how we&#8217;re doing and because this is a place that is filled with people with talent and tenacity and vision &#8212; people who, when given the opportunity, will build something extraordinary.<br><br>And there are communities like Greenville across the South and across our nation &#8212; reservoirs of ambition and aspiration just waiting to be tapped.&nbsp;&nbsp; That is why we invest in community lenders.&nbsp; And that is why we will keep working to build an economy that includes everyone.&nbsp; And that is why we will keep working to ensure that every person in our nation, no matter where they live or who they are, has an opportunity not only to succeed but to thrive.&nbsp;<br><br>Because when we do, we&#8217;re very clear, we lift up communities like Greenville and we lift up our small businesses, and all of America benefits.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all very much.&nbsp; Take care.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Statement on UN-Mediated Truce in&#160;Yemen</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/president-biden-statement-on-un-mediated-truce-in-yemen/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 21:03:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I welcome the announcement today of a two-month truce in the Yemen conflict. This initiative is a long-awaited reprieve for the Yemeni people. It entails a halt to all military activities by any party inside Yemen and across its borders, the entry of fuel ships into Hudaydah port, and the renewal of commercial flights to and from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I welcome the announcement today of a two-month truce in the Yemen conflict. This initiative is a long-awaited reprieve for the Yemeni people. It entails a halt to all military activities by any party inside Yemen and across its borders, the entry of fuel ships into Hudaydah port, and the renewal of commercial flights to and from Saan’a to agreed destinations. These are important steps, but they are not enough. The ceasefire must be adhered to, and as I have said before, it is imperative that we end this war. After seven years of conflict, negotiators must undertake the hard and necessary work to reach political compromises that can bring about an enduring future of peace for all the people of Yemen. I am grateful for the leadership role of Saudi Arabia and Oman in bringing this initiative to fruition before the Holy Month of Ramadan. I am also grateful for the hard work of the Yemeni Government and the confidence they have placed in UN-led mediation. The United States of America will work to deter threats to our friends and partners as we continue to strive for de-escalation and peace throughout the region. I wish the people of Yemen a peaceful Ramadan, and assure them of our ongoing commitment to help end this terrible war. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/01/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Robert Godec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Thailand Vinay Singh, Nominee for Chief Financial Officer, Department of Housing and Urban Development Kalpana Kotagal, Nominee for Commissioner on the Equal&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Robert Godec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Thailand</li><li>Vinay Singh, Nominee for Chief Financial Officer, Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Kalpana Kotagal, Nominee for Commissioner on the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Robert Godec, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Thailand</u></strong></p>



<p>Robert F. Godec, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Career Minister, currently serves as Senior Coordinator for Afghanistan in the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration at the U.S. Department of State. Prior to that, he was Acting Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of African Affairs. He previously served as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary and as Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of African Affairs. Earlier, Godec was Deputy Commandant and International Affairs Advisor at the National War College. He was U.S. Ambassador to Kenya from 2013 to 2019. Godec was also Chargé d’Affaires a.i. at U.S. Embassy Nairobi, Kenya in 2012. Before his assignment in Nairobi, Godec was the Principal Deputy Coordinator for Counterterrorism in the Bureau of Counterterrorism in the Department of State. Previously, he served as U.S. Ambassador to Tunisia. Godec has also served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs and was Deputy Coordinator for the Transition in Iraq. He served as Acting Deputy Chief of Mission and Minister Counselor for Economic Affairs at U.S. Embassy Pretoria, South Africa. His other positions include Economic Counselor at U.S. Embassy Nairobi, Kenya; Assistant Office Director for Thailand and Burma in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs; and Director for Southeast Asian Affairs at the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative.</p>



<p>A member of the Foreign Service since 1985, Godec has a Master’s degree from Yale University, as well as a Bachelor’s degree from the University of Virginia. He is the recipient of two Presidential Meritorious Service Awards, numerous Senior Performance Awards, and a Distinguished Honor Award. He speaks French and German.</p>



<p><strong><u>Vinay Singh, Nominee for Chief Financial Officer, Department of Housing and Urban Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Vinay Singh, a Certified Public Accountant, is currently a Senior Advisor to the Administrator at the U.S. Small Business Administration (SBA), assisting agency teams to deliver organizational efficiencies to better serve our communities’ small businesses. Singh has 25 years of private sector leadership experience with a deep understanding of finance, analytics, and strategy.</p>



<p>Prior to his role at SBA, Singh was a Partner and Chief Operating Officer for the Infrastructure practice at KPMG in India. As a senior member of the executive team, he led several organizational transformation projects, leveraging technology to improve profitability and decision-making. As Lead Partner for the World Bank Group account, he supported global sustainability projects focused on solving urban and rural challenges in housing, water, energy, and economic development. Previously, Singh served in the Obama-Biden Administration as a Deputy Assistant Secretary (U.S. Field). He played a key role in leading trade and investment policy and promotion efforts to better market conditions for U.S. companies. In his early years as a Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA) and Project Management Professional (PMP), Singh helped several companies improve operational and financial performance. He holds an MBA from Widener University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kalpana Kotagal, Nominee for Commissioner on the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Kalpana Kotagal is a Partner at Cohen Milstein, a member of the firm’s Civil Rights &amp; Employment practice group, and Co-Chair of the firm’s Hiring and Diversity Committee. She is co-author of the seminal legal template the “Inclusion Rider.” Kotagal is a diversity, equity, and inclusion expert, and represents disenfranchised people in employment and civil rights litigation involving issues related to Title VII, the Equal Pay Act, the Americans with Disabilities Act, the Family and Medical Leave Act, and the Fair Labor Standards Act.</p>



<p>Kotagal was a Harvard Law School Wasserstein Public Interest Fellow and was named an “Employment Law MVP” by <em>Law360 </em>in 2018, recognizing the top five most influential employment lawyers in the United States. Kotagal sits on the Boards of Directors of A Better Balance and Public Justice Foundation. She is co-chair of the Alumni Advisory Board on Equity &amp; Inclusion at the University of Pennsylvania Law School, a member of the American Constitution Society Task Force on #MeToo in the Legal Profession, and serves on the Advisory Board of the People’s Parity Project. The daughter of immigrants from India, Kotagal earned her B.S. and an A.B., with honors, from Stanford University and her J.D., <em>cum laude</em>, from the University of Pennsylvania Law School. Prior to joining Cohen Milstein, Kotagal served as a law clerk to the Honorable Betty Binns Fletcher of the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit. She resides in Cincinnati, Ohio with her husband and two sons.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
