<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:49:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: S. 566 and S.&#160;583</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/bills-signed-s-566-and-s-583/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:49:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, February 22, 2022, the President signed into law:&#160;S. 566, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 42 Main Street in Slatersville, Rhode Island, as the Specialist Matthew R. Turcotte Post Office. Thank you to Senators Reed and Whitehouse and Representatives Cicilline and Langevin for their leadership.&#160;S. 583, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, February 22, 2022, the President signed into law:<br>&nbsp;<br>S. 566, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 42 Main Street in Slatersville, Rhode Island, as the Specialist Matthew R. Turcotte Post Office.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Reed and Whitehouse and Representatives Cicilline and Langevin for their leadership.<br>&nbsp;<br>S. 583, the &#8220;Promoting Rigorous and Innovative Cost Efficiencies for Federal Procurement and Acquisitions Act of 2021&#8221; or the &#8220;PRICE Act of 2021,&#8221; which encourages identification and promotion of best practices for acquisition techniques and procurement practices.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Peters, Ernst, Carper, and Collins, and Representatives Neguse and Salazar for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Virtual Event on Securing Critical Minerals for a Future Made in&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/22/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-virtual-event-on-securing-critical-minerals-for-a-future-made-in-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47668</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court Auditorium 3:50 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Tom.&#160; Tom Conway, you going to say hi to me? &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MR. CONWAY:&#160; Mr. President, how are you? &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I haven’t seen you in such a long time.&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MR. CONWAY:&#160; Oh, it’s been a while.&#160; You doing all right? &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Yeah,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium</p>



<p>3:50 P.M. EST</p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Tom.&nbsp; Tom Conway, you going to say hi to me?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. CONWAY:&nbsp; Mr. President, how are you?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I haven’t seen you in such a long time.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. CONWAY:&nbsp; Oh, it’s been a while.&nbsp; You doing all right?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah, you’re one of the only reasons I’m sitting in this chair.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; How are you?&nbsp; Gavin, how are you, man?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; (Inaudible) President.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good to see you.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; I’m good.&nbsp; I’m good.&nbsp; I had an over/under that you were going to do this today.&nbsp; I’m impressed.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; I am impressed.&nbsp; Thank you for not canceling on us.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, are you kidding me?&nbsp; We don’t have much going on, you know, other than Russia and Ukraine and &#8212; anyway.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we start?&nbsp; I guess I’m starting, huh?&nbsp; I guess I already started.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; I want to thank everybody joining us today virtually, including California’s outstanding governor, Gavin Newsom, who I went out to help with a recall and he won in spite of me &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; again.&nbsp; But &#8212; along with leaders from industry and labor and local communities, each of whom we’re going to hear from shortly.&nbsp; And, here at the White House, with Jennifer Granholm, our former governor and Energy Secretary; Gina McCarthy, our National Climate Advisor; and Kathleen Hicks, the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we’re here to make an announcement that sounds a little complex on the surface, but, really, it’s about something quite simple.&nbsp; It’s all about the belief we share that to build a truly strong economy, we need a future that’s made in America.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Almost exactly a year ago, I issued an executive order</p>



<p>to prioritize strengthening our domestic supply chains.&nbsp; Because what I found out was that, you know, if I was going to follow through on my commitment to say we were going to make it in America and build it America and have all of it built in America, we needed a supply chain that was &#8212; that was reliable.&nbsp; And &#8212; and including in critical materials like lithium, graphite, rare earth materials, which are badly needed for so many American products, but were so much in &#8212; we were in so desperate need of.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; These minerals power phones and computers, household appliances, electric vehicles and batteries, solar panels, wind turbines, and so much more.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Without these minerals, we simply cannot fun- &#8212; they can’t function.&nbsp; And we expect to &#8212; demand to &#8212; for them to increase by 400 to 600 percent over the next several decades.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And up to now, we’ve had to import a significant portion of them &#8212; close to 100 percent importation &#8212; from other countries, particularly China, Australia, and Chile.&nbsp; And when I signed the executive order last year, I was determined to change that.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we’ve seen what happens when we become dependent on other countries for essential goods like computer chips &#8212; everyone has become aware of that, because the computer chips are so badly needed.&nbsp; Why do the cost of automobiles skyrocket and become about a third of the reason for the increase in inflation?&nbsp; It&#8217;s because they didn’t have the computer chips.&nbsp; You can’t build an automobile today without those chips.&nbsp; As well as personal protective equipment and so much more.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when it comes to clean energy, China has spent years</p>



<p>cornering the market on many of the materials that power the technologies that we rely on.&nbsp; That’s why I committed us to build a clean energy supply chain stamped “Made in America.”</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And “Made in America” means using products, parts, and materials, as well as minerals, right here that are in the United States of America, we get them.&nbsp; It means betting on American workers.&nbsp; And it takes a federal government that doesn’t just give up lip service to buying America but actually takes action.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My economic strategy &#8212; building from the bottom up and the middle out &#8212; is why in my first year as President we had the greatest year ever in job growth in American history: 6.6 million jobs.&nbsp; Faster economic growth in nearly &#8212; the fastest in nearly four decades.&nbsp; And that’s why America added 375 [thousand] manufacturing jobs last year &#8212; the highest increase in nearly 30 years.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that’s why we’ve seen major announcements in recent weeks from companies like Intel, General Motors, Union Pacific Railroad, and more, building new facilities here in America, investing in American workers and buying American products and paying prevailing wages, Tom &#8212; prevailing wages, a union wage.&nbsp; They created tens of thousands of good-paying jobs in Ohio, Michigan, Pennsylvania, Tennessee &#8212; all across the country.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And today, we’re announcing a new effort that’s going to help us, in my view, keep that drumbeat for good-paying jobs, strengthen our national and economic security, and ensure that we can continue to build a future that’s made in America in a way that lives up to our values.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we’re announcing a major investment in domestic production of key minerals and materials.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, as I mentioned, China &#8212; China controls most of the global market in these minerals.&nbsp; And the fact that we can’t build a future that’s made in America if we ourselves are dependent on China for the materials that power the products of today and tomorrow.&nbsp; And this is not anti-China or anti anything else; it’s pro-American.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why I’m taking action.&nbsp; Through the Department of Defense &#8212; and I have Deputy Secretary to my &#8212; there you go, I thought to my right; the governor is to my &#8212; the Deputy Secretary is here &#8212; we’re investing $35 million in MP Materials, currently America’s only rare earth mining and processing operation, to help create a fully domestic supply chain for the magnets that power electric vehicle motors, wind turbines, and so much more.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We know that when the federal government invests in innovation, it powers up the private sector to do what they do best.&nbsp; And that’s what we’re seeing happen.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MP Materials is announcing a $700 million investment</p>



<p>in the magnet supply chain, creating 350 good-paying jobs.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Berkshire Hathaway Energy Renewables is breaking ground for a new facility this spring in your state &#8212; I know Gavin knows more about this than I do, but he &#8212; in &#8212; in California to test the new process to pull lithium, which is used for batteries for phones, for cars from underground sources in California’s Imperial Valley in a way that’s environmentally sustainable.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last week, Redwood Materials announced a partnership</p>



<p>with Ford and Volvo to recycle lithium-ion batteries so you’ll be able to produce more of those batteries, taking out the minerals and reprocessing them so they can be used to power electric vehicles, reducing the need for new mining.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that’s just the beginning, in my view.&nbsp; These new investments are going to do more than create good-paying jobs.&nbsp; They’re also going to set America up to lead the world in building a clean energy economy and the clean energy future.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As we build the economy, we’re going to build around wor- &#8212; build it around working Americans.&nbsp; That means making sure that labor is at the table, that Tribes and the people from the community are at the table from day one, and that environmental protections are paramount.</p>



<p>We have to ensure that these resources actually benefit folks in the communities where they live, not just the shareholders.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s going to create good-paying union jobs, and that produces more sustainability.</p>



<p>You know, so &#8212; so we can avoid the historical injustices that too many mining operations left behind in American towns.&nbsp; I come from Scranton, Pennsylvania.&nbsp; It used to be an anthracite coal mine.&nbsp; And mining is mining is mining, but there&#8217;s all kinds of it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we’re working to modernize America&#8217;s mining laws and regulations, some of which are 150 years old.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why I&#8217;ve asked the Secretary of Energy, Governor Granholm &#8212; Senator [sic] Granholm &#8212; senator &#8212; Secretary Granholm &#8212; but you&#8217;re my governor, former governor &#8212; to visit the Imperial Valley in California and hear directly from local residents how this will impact on them.</p>



<p>I know everybody is excited about the opportunities ahead.&nbsp; So, with that, I’m &#8212; we&#8217;re going to hear from Jim Litinsky, CEO of MP Materials. &nbsp;And, Jim, let&#8217;s start with a question: What will the Defense Department&#8217;s $35 million investment allow you to do in your process?</p>



<p>MR. LITINSKY:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an honor to be here today.&nbsp; This DOD investment delivers on your call to action of a year ago to restore America&#8217;s supply chains.&nbsp; So your investment will complement more than $700 million that MP will invest by 2024 to create an American rare earth magnetics supply chain.&nbsp; As you said, these magnets are essential to our economy and the clean energy transition.</p>



<p>So, my team is committed to bringing this supply chain home, and we are doing so with an operation that is a benchmark for innovation and environmental sustainability.</p>



<p>You know, we proudly operate in the state of California, under the very high standards that should make all Americans proud.&nbsp; You know, we founded this company five years ago.&nbsp; At the time, Mountain Pass was in care and maintenance with only eight employees.&nbsp; Many actually doubted that it could ever be restored, but we got to work and built a great company poised to become an American champion.</p>



<p>So, I hope that our story is a symbol of what is possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One thing I&#8217;ve learned, Mr. President, is that American manufacturing spirit is second to none when we all work together.&nbsp; But the truth is: Multi-billion-dollar supply chains do not move overnight.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to require capital.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to require perseverance.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to require strong coordination between the upstream and the downstream.&nbsp; And most importantly, it&#8217;s going to require a true commitment from leadership across the board.</p>



<p>And, sir, convening this group today sends a powerful signal that is a catalyzing effect.&nbsp; So I want to thank you and your team.&nbsp; Thank you to the DOD.&nbsp; Thank you to Governor Newsom and everyone assembled here today.</p>



<p>I also want to recognize the 400 American heroes at MP who report to work every day with an unwavering commitment to see this mission through.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Jim, do me a favor, for listeners: Tell me a little bit about the process that you undertake to allow us to compete with China, for example, and other countries, in terms of providing access to this rare material.&nbsp; Rare &#8212; I mean, you know &#8212; what we&#8217;re looking for.</p>



<p>MR. LITINSKY:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Well, sir, the good news is, we are currently the second-largest producer in the world.&nbsp; And we have &#8212; and this may be a little detailed for those who don&#8217;t know about mining, but we have a dry tailings process, and 95 percent of the water we utilize is recycled.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that means that not only are we competing globally, but we are also doing so in a way that, you know, as I&#8217;ve said, all Americans can be proud of.&nbsp; We are &#8212; you know, I can say confidently we are the most environmentally friendly rare earth operation in the world.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I was told by our &#8212; my environmental guru here that &#8212; she pointed out to me that, by 2025, we&#8217;re going to be producing 500,000 electric vehicles per year.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll &#8212; you&#8217;ll be able to provide material for 500,000 electric vehicles per year.&nbsp; Is that right?</p>



<p>MR. LITINSKY:&nbsp; That&#8217;s right, sir.&nbsp; We&#8217;re &#8212; we announced GM as a foundational customer for a magnetics facility that we are building.&nbsp; And so, I think the really important thing here is we are investing across the board, end to end, exactly as you have called for, so that we can have actually every aspect of this supply chain in the United States of America.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Do I yield you now or do I go on?</p>



<p>ADMINISTRATOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; You can go on.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I can go on?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Alicia, tell me about you &#8212; what you guys are doing.</p>



<p>MS. KNAPP:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an honor to be here with you today to talk about the exciting work we&#8217;re doing in Imperial County, California, and the benefits it could bring to the local community.</p>



<p>So, at BHE Renewables, we are working not just to secure a domestic source of lithium, but we&#8217;re working to secure the most abundant source of lithium in the United States, using the world&#8217;s most environmentally friendly technology, and providing economic and employment benefits in one of the most disadvantaged communities &#8212; counties in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, if this seems ambitious, it is.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no one better suited to take on an ambitious task like this than Berkshire Hathaway Energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been operating geothermal plants in the Imperial Valley for 40 years, and we&#8217;re currently operating 10 geothermal plants by bringing superheated brine from several miles beneath the Earth&#8217;s surface and using steam from that brine to generate clean baseload power.&nbsp; And then we reinject the brine into the geothermal reservoir.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what that means is that, right now, we are pumping 50,000 gallons per minute of lithium-rich brine to the surface.&nbsp; And because there is no proven commercially viable technology, we&#8217;re pumping it right back down into the ground.&nbsp; So, the good news is that we are currently undertaking two demonstration plant projects to prove that we can recover that lithium as we have it above ground in a commercially viable manner.</p>



<p>So, the first of those demonstration plants is actually going to come online this April.&nbsp; And in that phase, we will extract lithium from the brine.&nbsp; And that project is supported by a $6 million grant from the California Energy Commission.&nbsp; Thank you, Governor Newsom.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the second phase of the demonstration is supported by a $14.9 million grant from the Department of Energy.&nbsp; So, thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>And in that phase, we will take the lithium we recovered in the first phase and convert it to battery-grade lithium compounds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If both of these demonstration projects are successful, we would then be in a position to begin construction of our first commercial plant in 2024 and, by 2026, be commercially extracting lithium from our geothermal brine.</p>



<p>As we undertake these demonstration projects, we&#8217;re engaging with the Lithium Valley Commission, which is a group of Tribal leaders, local community representatives, labor leaders, and environmental justice groups.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re engaging with them from day one to make sure that lithium production in the Imperial Valley is done in a way that benefits everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also investing in local education.&nbsp; So, recently, we donated $130,000 to the Westmoreland Union Elementary School District, and we committed $25,000 in scholarships for STEM education at the local Imperial Valley College.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also working with local educational institutions to develop programs &#8212; training programs, curriculum, internships, and hands-on opportunities at our site &#8212; to help prepare the local residents for future careers in the geothermal and/or lithium business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re definitely committed to delivering a secure lithium future and are living up to the values that you&#8217;ve laid out for us, Mr. President.&nbsp; So thank you, again, for the opportunity.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s really important.&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; we have to learn the lessons from the past couple hundred years of mining, generally.&nbsp; And I &#8212; I really mean it. And &#8212; and I understand &#8212; I&#8217;m told &#8212; I&#8217;m looking at my notes here &#8212; I&#8217;m told that you&#8217;re providing scholarships for local students taking STEM courses.&nbsp; Is that right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. KNAPP:&nbsp; It is, yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And are you going to be developing internships as well?&nbsp; I mean, this is &#8212; I &#8212; correct me, Governor, if I&#8217;m wrong, but I think this has the fifth-highest unemployment rate in California and a poverty rate that is over 24 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, this ought to be not only good for lithium but good for &#8212; for the residents, I mean, if you&#8217;re really going to do that.&nbsp; Are you?&nbsp; Are you going to stick there in the community?</p>



<p>MS. KNAPP:&nbsp; Yes, absolutely.&nbsp; Like I said, we&#8217;ve been in this community for almost 40 years.&nbsp; We have been working with local educational institutions to develop the curricula that will train the workers for the lithium business of the future.</p>



<p>Also, internships, which apply to, you know, engineers.&nbsp; And &#8212; and things like that.&nbsp; And on-site, hands-on training opportunities for folks in the local community as well.</p>



<p>So, whatever your interest is &#8212; if it&#8217;s a four-year college, a two-year college, going straight to work &#8212; we&#8217;re making sure that we have opportunities for you at our plants in the Imperial Valley.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good.&nbsp; Well, we came up with a Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill that provided only $4 billion to help in this process.&nbsp; So I hope it &#8212; I &#8212; I ho- &#8212; stick with what you&#8217;re &#8212; what you&#8217;re saying.&nbsp; I appreciate it.</p>



<p>I mean, the $4 billion is for electric batteries.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a &#8212; you know, which you&#8217;re a big part of.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, well, thank you.&nbsp; And &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. KNAPP:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Now, you got to let me know when I&#8217;m supposed to stop here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, Silvia &#8212; where is Silvia?&nbsp; There you are, Silvia.&nbsp; How are you, Silvia?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PAZ:&nbsp; I&#8217;m doing (inaudible).</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You&#8217;re the Executive Director of the &#8212; of the operation.&nbsp; Can you tell me a little about what you&#8217;re going to be doing?</p>



<p>MS. PAZ:&nbsp; Yes, I&#8217;m &#8212; well, thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; And, really, it&#8217;s a privilege to be joining you here, along with the governor of my state and all of the industry leaders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you &#8212; I am the Executive Director of Alianza Coachella Valley.&nbsp; I also chair the Lithium Valley Commission.&nbsp; And, really, this &#8212; we have a great opportunity to really meet the community where they are.&nbsp; So I thank you for recognizing that the Salton Sea region is already battling with some of the highest unemployment rates.&nbsp; We were also one of the regions that are hardly &#8212; hardest hit by the COVID pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, for the last 10 years, Alianza has been working alongside community members to address the issues that they see most important to their lives &#8212; the issues that a lot of times prevent barriers to them having real opportunities for economic progress.&nbsp; And those issues have been issues around infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when we&#8217;re talking about infrastructure, we&#8217;re also talking about the same infrastructure that left our mostly agricultural community at a disadvantage when it came to being able to protect themselves from COVID.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re talking about an area that houses &#8212; is home to the largest body of water, the Salton Sea, that is facing environmental degradation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, when we &#8212; our community hears about the excitement around lithium, there is a cautious optimism because it falls around this context: a community that has seen unfulfilled promises.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And could this be a game changer?&nbsp; Yes, it could, if done right.&nbsp; What does it mean to do it right in the context of the community I just described?&nbsp; It means that we are going to have to double down on the investments going beyond incentivizing career and educational pathways.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need to make sure that there&#8217;s investments to get this community ready.&nbsp; When we talk about the potential of lithium, we need to capture as many of the jobs as possible.&nbsp; We need to be able to capture as many of the supply chain elements as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But if I look at my community and I see that when there&#8217;s a high wind, you know, our powerlines fall, it leaves our communities without power, we have a long ways to go.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re really counting on the incentives that are coming from the federal level, that are coming from the state level to be able to do this right for our communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We want to be at the table and help you understand what it means to us to have a prosperous economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to &#8212; at the federal level, we&#8217;re investing billions of dollars in making sure that you have resilience in your energy supplies.&nbsp; For example, you talk about, you know, the electric power and &#8212; and transmission lines and the like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, there&#8217;s a lot going on.&nbsp; But one of the things that I&#8217;m glad to hear you continue to talk about is that, you know, when the tough stuff had to be done before we had environmental laws that really made a difference, all those fenceline communities, all those communities next to the places where they&#8217;re being done, suffered all the downside and didn&#8217;t get much of the benefits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s my hope and my expectation that those communities, like the farming community that rep- &#8212; that you represent, that you&#8217;re talking about, get the benefit of being able to be employed and being able to generate a living from what&#8217;s going to be happening here and are protected environmentally.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, building out a battery supply chain in the region where you live, what kind of impact will that have on your residents, do you think?&nbsp; What &#8212; what&#8217;s your worry?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s your expectation and hope?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. PAZ:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; The worry is that we can do this in an environmentally friendly manner, that it will not cause further environmental degradation in an area that&#8217;s already suffering from it.&nbsp; The hope is that we can really be transformative, that our community can be much more engaged from the beginning, determining where potential investments should go; that they can have a seat at the table when we&#8217;re talking about community workforce agreements and determining what percent of labor should come from the local region.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if you ask me and you ask my colleagues on the ground &#8212; all of them &#8212; right? &#8212; we should prioritize local hiring.&nbsp; We want good jobs, quality jobs that are paying benefits.&nbsp; And we want to make sure, again, that this community is transformed beyond only building the industry up.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have a beautiful landscape, but we also have a landscape that needs additional infrastructure &#8212; roads, access to parks, access to the outdoors.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I think we have the right pieces to build from.&nbsp; There is &#8212; the values that you&#8217;ve mentioned are in alignment with the values that the community is asking for.&nbsp; The framework that I know Governor Newsom will talk about is in alignment with what we&#8217;re asking for.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now, the hard part is in the details in implementing it and making sure that all of us can be working and having those tough discussions, whether it&#8217;s going to be that we&#8217;re asking for fees, royalties, community benefit agreements, and that we really let the community determine what those benefits ought to be.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gov, I think you agree that one of the great things about the country is that we don&#8217;t have to choose jobs over the environment or public health.&nbsp; And committing to the highest environmental standards could even be one of our nation&#8217;s most competitive advantages, if we&#8217;re smart about it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about that &#8212; you and I.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What steps are you taking, together with industry workers, local communities to &#8212; and Tribal nations &#8212; to help us secure domestic sources of critical minerals in the right way?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; Yeah, well, first of all, I can&#8217;t impress upon you, Mr. President, how important your words are to the community.&nbsp; You heard that in Silvia, reflected in her comments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But look, at the end of the day, there &#8212; there is anxiety that &#8212; you know, with the &#8212; what we refer to as “the Saudi Arabia of lithium” down there in Imperial Valley, this extraordinary economic opportunity that now presents itself &#8212; that people can be left behind.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to hear you reinforce that frame that it&#8217;s not just about growth in the abstract, it&#8217;s about inclusion, it&#8217;s about reconciling the past in making sure that our values are front and center in our policy to accelerate into the future.&nbsp; And so, just those words are important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I want you to know: We&#8217;re following up by codifying them and organizing, with Silvia and her team, with a community benefits package focusing not just on the economic opportunity but making sure that the growth and inclusion strategies include local hires, include local benefits in a sustainable way.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what&#8217;s so exciting, from my perspective, because it &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s an old African proverb that says, “You want to go fast, go alone.&nbsp; But if you want to go far, go together.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the opportunity to set this up where we can go deep in these conversations today, where we can accelerate those investments, presents itself anew.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re giving us an enormous amount of energy in this space with these new resources and a resourceful mindset where we also can address the twin problem which you began with, and that is national security and recognizing and reconciling the world we&#8217;re living in, and what are the trendlines that define that world, and becoming more supply chain &#8212; less dependent, but more independent in providing those domestic opportunities.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I&#8217;m very prideful, Mr. President, California is still the most dominant manufacturing state in America.&nbsp; Twenty-six percent of your jobs &#8212; American jobs came out of California in December &#8212; twenty-six percent.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;re really proud of the American job recovery.&nbsp; We’re really proud of California&#8217;s approach.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s around creating policy that it can accelerate that growth but, again, with this mindset around sustainability.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, thank you for, again, your leadership.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re really looking forward.&nbsp; We think this is big.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t want to understate it.&nbsp; We also don&#8217;t want to overstate it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re still doing a lot of the due diligence.&nbsp; But if it&#8217;s as big as it appears to be, this is a game changer in terms of our efforts to transition to low-carbon green growth and to radically change the way we produce and consume energy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is a hinge moment in the history that you&#8217;re making, not just here today but the work you&#8217;ve been doing the last year.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thanks, Gov.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; I agree with you.&nbsp; This is one of those moments.&nbsp; It&#8217;s one of those inflection points in history.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve been saying that &#8212; you and I, we&#8217;ve spent a lot of time together.&nbsp; You and I both talked about there&#8217;s certain &#8212; there&#8217;s so much that has the potential to change for the better, to fundamental &#8212; like the idea of all of us here talking about the combination of the economic, the &#8212; the technological breakthroughs, coupled with the impact on doing it in environmentally sound ways to produce changes in the nature of communities.&nbsp; And I think it just has enormous opportunity.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as someone was pointing out to me today, your economy in California is bigger than about the size of Russia&#8217;s &#8212;</p>



<p>GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; For real.&nbsp; No &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; Twice.&nbsp; It’s twice the size, Mr. President.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Twice.&nbsp; Yeah, I know.</p>



<p>GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; Fifth-largest economy in the world, so treat us well.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; But who’s paying attention, right?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>No, but all kidding aside, it’s been great.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s mainly because I think &#8212; I&#8217;m going to turn this over to Gina McCarthy to facilitate the remainder of this conversation &#8212; but I think it&#8217;s in part because of the next guy she&#8217;s going to represent, the President of the United Steelworkers.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s a different section.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But anyway, thanks, Gov.&nbsp; Appreciate it, Gavin.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; GOVERNOR NEWSOM:&nbsp; I appreciate you.</p>



<p>ADMINISTRATOR MCCARTHY:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, and stick around.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to ask the press corps if they don&#8217;t mind leaving at this point.&nbsp; And then we&#8217;ll start up the conversation again, if you don&#8217;t mind.</p>



<p>4:19 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on Russia&#160;Sanctions</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/22/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-russia-sanctions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 23:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  3:34 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining today.&#160; So, as a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official,&#8221; and the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; For your awareness but not for reporting, the speaker on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Via Teleconference</em><strong> </strong></p>



<p>3:34 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining today.&nbsp; So, as a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official,&#8221; and the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For your awareness but not for reporting, the speaker on the call is [senior administration official].&nbsp; And I think they&#8217;re going to have some remarks to start at the top, and then we can take some questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Yes, I&#8217;ll make a few comments at the top and then happy to answer any of your questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Russia’s long-previewed invasion of Ukraine has now begun, and our response has also begun.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, we responded swiftly and in a united fashion with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; The speed and coordination of the response was historic.&nbsp; We announced our first tranche of sanctions in less than a day with Allies and partners from the European Union, from the United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, and Australia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This response was taken much faster and goes much further than what we did in 2014.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me say a few words about the details of the package.&nbsp; First, after consultations overnight with Germany, Russia&#8217;s Nord Stream 2 natural gas pipeline will not become operational.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an $11 billion investment and a prized gas pipeline controlled by Russia that will now go to waste, and it sacrifices what would have been a cash cow for Russia&#8217;s financial coffers.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not just about the money.&nbsp; This decision will relieve Russia&#8217;s geostrategic chokehold over Europe through its supply of natural gas, and it&#8217;s a major turning point in the world&#8217;s energy independence from Russia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, we&#8217;ve made a demonstration of the power of our financial sanctions.&nbsp; And make no mistake, this is only the sharp edge of the pain we can inflict.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, again, in lockstep with our Allies, we&#8217;re fully blocking from the U.S. and European financial systems the fifth-largest Russian financial firm, which is V.E.B. &#8212; a glorified piggy bank for the Kremlin that holds more than $50 billion in assets.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also fully blocking a $35 billion bank, Promsvyazbank, that finances the activities of the Russian military.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In plain English, the full block of these banks means they can no longer make any transactions with the U.S. or Europe, and their assets in our respective financial systems are frozen.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And let me be totally clear: No Russian financial institution is safe if this invasion proceeds.&nbsp; We are ready to press a button to take further action on the very largest Russian financial institutions, including Sperbank and VTB, which collectively hold almost $750 billion in assets &#8212; or more than half the total in Russia as a whole.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Third, together with our Allies, we&#8217;ve also cut off the Russian government, the Russian Central Bank, and its sovereign wealth funds from U.S. financing.&nbsp; Europe has taken a very similar measure.&nbsp; That means the Kremlin can no longer raise money from the U.S. and Europe, and its new debt can no longer trade in U.S. or European markets.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fourth, we have fully sanctioned a group of Russian elites and their family members.&nbsp; These individuals have shared in the corrupt gains of the Kremlin, and they will now share in the pain.&nbsp; Other Russian elites and their family members are now on notice that additional actions could be taken on them as well.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me also just take a minute to address a key part of the President&#8217;s speech on energy.&nbsp; We were quite deliberate to make sure that the pain of our sanctions is targeted at the Russian economy, not ours.&nbsp; So none of the measures are designed to disrupt the flow of energy to global markets, and we are now executing a plan in coordination with major oil consumers and oil producers towards our collective interest to secure the stability of global energy supplies.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me just stop there and take your questions.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; So, I just want to &#8212; you know, throughout the last couple of months, there’s been talk from administration officials about the idea of starting high and staying high.&nbsp; This appears, perhaps, more as starting medium.&nbsp; And I was wondering how does this square with the bigger idea of starting high and staying high, not having things like SWIFT in this first tranche of sanctions.&nbsp; And what was the thinking on not including some sort of levy to reinforce the German’s move on Nord Stream 2?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, sure.&nbsp; So, first of all, these are &#8212; we are starting high.&nbsp; These are severe costs that we’re imposing.&nbsp; Nord Stream 2, for example, is Putin&#8217;s prized pipeline.&nbsp; He poured $11 billion into building the pipeline.&nbsp; It would have provided billions of dollars each year in revenues.&nbsp; That is now shut down after very close consultations overnight with Germany.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, you know, we made a demonstration out of two very significant Russian financial institutions, both of which have close ties to the Kremlin and the Russian military.&nbsp; They control over $80 billion in assets.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re clearly &#8212; I&#8217;m clearly signaling and the President has signaled we&#8217;re prepared to take action on other Russian banks, including the very largest ones.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then I think it is very significant that the U.S. and Europe have fully cut off the Russian government, its central bank, and its sovereign wealth funds from financing &#8212; from receiving financing from the U.S. and Europe.&nbsp; Over time, that&#8217;s going to mean higher borrowing costs, less capacity to invest, lower growth, lower productive capacity, and less overall ability for Putin to exert leverage on the world stage.&nbsp; So these costs are severe.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The second point I would make is: Look, this is the beginning of an invasion and this is the beginning of our response.&nbsp; If Putin escalates further, we will escalate further, using both financial sanctions and export controls, which we&#8217;ve yet to unveil.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to also underline: Our response goes well beyond sanctions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to fortify NATO&#8217;s eastern flank to reinforce our sacred commitment to defend every inch of Allied territory.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You heard the President say that additional troops and equipment are going to be shifted within Europe to the Baltics.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to provide defensive military assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; Already, we’ve provided $650 billion in the past year &#8212; the most ever.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to work with Allies and partners to prepare for economic assistance that can help Ukraine become a successful alternative to Russian-style kleptocracy, which may be Putin&#8217;s greatest fear of all.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [Senior administration official], did you ha- &#8212; were you saying something?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; I think &#8212; [senior administration official], I think you were done, so I think we&#8217;re good for a second question, please.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, please.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, who are the Russian elites that are being sanctioned?&nbsp; Do they include Vladimir Putin?&nbsp; And if Putin is not included, why not?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so I&#8217;ll name the Russian elites, which also includes their family members &#8212; and I apologize for the mispronunciation:&nbsp; Aleksandr Bortnikov and his son, Denis; Sergei Kiriyenko and his son, Vladimir; and Petr Fradkov, who is the CEO of Promsvyazbank.&nbsp; So these individuals and their relatives are all now fully blocked.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With respect to President Putin, I’ll just repeat what the President has said is: And all options remain on the table.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I guess I just wanted to ask: You know, if we’re not going with the maximum sanctions right now, is there a fear that this sort of concedes the breakaway territories to the Ukrainian control &#8212; or to Russian control, rather?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Would you have gone bigger if not for &#8212; you know, we know that there was some reluctance in Europe heading into to this.&nbsp; And so, if you could at all talk about how this package came together and how European concerns weighed on what you went forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, I was also wondering if you had an update on the &#8212; the summits, both with Lavrov and Putin, that had been sort of floated &#8212; the Lavrov one later this week &#8212; in light of what&#8217;s happened.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Hi, Justin.&nbsp; So, again, I mean, these &#8212; these are severe costs that we’re imposing today: shutting down Nord Stream, fully blocking two major financial institutions, cutting off the Russian government from Western financing.&nbsp; They’re severe actions, but this was the beginning of an invasion, and therefore this is the beginning of our response.</p>



<p>And I think, more fundamentally, just to get your question directly: No one should think that our ultimate goal is to max out on sanctions.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not an end to themselves.&nbsp; Sanctions are meant to serve a higher purpose, which is to deter and prevent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we want to prevent a large-scale invasion of Ukraine that involves the seizure of major cities, including Kyiv.&nbsp; We want to prevent large-scale human suffering, possibly tens of thousands of lives that could be lost in a full-scale conflict.&nbsp; And we want to prevent Putin from installing a puppet government that bends to his wishes and denies Ukraine the freedom to set its own course and choose its own destiny.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what this is all about.</p>



<p>With respect to the potential discussions between Secretary Blinken and Minister Lavrov, I would just refer you to the State Department.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken is about to give remarks, and I think he&#8217;ll have more to say on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; I wanted to ask, regarding SWIFT: At what point in the &#8212; and, I guess, the steps that Putin can take &#8212; perhaps, you know, taking a wider swath, going beyond these republics &#8212; is SWIFT going to be used or pulled from?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And second of all, should Americans expect for some higher gas prices in the coming weeks or months?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Hi, Franco.&nbsp; So, with respect to SWIFT, as I mentioned last Friday and as you&#8217;ve seen today, SWIFT is not part of the first package of sanctions that we&#8217;ve rolled out.</p>



<p>And look, we think there are other severe measures that have comparable impact on Russia that we can take in lockstep with Europe and that don&#8217;t have the broader spillover costs.&nbsp; But I &#8212; we are not taking SWIFT off the table.&nbsp; It will remain an option that we can deploy, depending on &#8212; depending on how Russia makes its next move.</p>



<p>With respect to gas prices, energy prices, you know, I&#8217;ll just &#8212; I know there&#8217;s been some talk about whether energy prices are moving higher because of the Nord Stream 2 decision, and I would just emphasize: They are not moving higher because Nord Stream 2 is halted.&nbsp; They&#8217;re moving higher because they&#8217;re worried that Putin will weaponize energy supply and hold the world hostage.</p>



<p>So, the right response is to reduce Europe&#8217;s addiction to Russian gas, and that&#8217;s what today&#8217;s action does.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in the meantime, we&#8217;ll continue to work with Europe to surge natural gas supplies from all over the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I mentioned at the outset of this call, with respect to oil, we have an ongoing effort right now to execute on a plan that&#8217;s in coordination with oil producers and oil consumers to make sure the world knows we&#8217;re going to have stable energy supplies.  And I think &#8212; I expect you&#8217;ll be hearing more from other countries very soon about that coordination effort.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; (Inaudible) anyone have that sanctions deter Vladimir Putin, whether they&#8217;ve been small or large.&nbsp; Is there anything else in your toolkit beside sanctions?&nbsp; Because he doesn&#8217;t seem to be responding to these.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And was there any thinking that, given what President Zelenskyy said in Munich this weekend, you should start big &#8212; bigger &#8212; with SWIFT and other things that might get his attention rather than escalating slowly?</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thanks, Andrea.&nbsp; Well, you know, sanctions &#8212; they work over time.&nbsp; And the pain is mounting in Russia.&nbsp; The stock market &#8212; if you look at its performance since November, it&#8217;s down more than 30 percent.&nbsp; The currency over the same time period is &#8212; has lost over 10 percent of its value.&nbsp; The interest rate that the markets are charging the Russian government to borrow has now spiked well above 10 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, if you look back to 2014 when we imposed sanctions, the comments coming out of the leadership of the Russian government suggest that were it not for the costs that we imposed then, which are similar to what we&#8217;re imposing now, Putin may have gone much further, perhaps all the way to Kyiv.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, sanctions are not the only tool in our toolkit.&nbsp; As I mentioned, export controls are a key component of our potential sanctions response.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re similar in concept to financial sanctions.&nbsp; In both cases, we’re denying something to Russia that they need and they can&#8217;t replace from anywhere else or produce at home.</p>



<p>And so, export controls are really potent because we&#8217;re talking about critical technology inputs that Russia needs to diversify its economy, modernize its economy.&nbsp; And we are fully prepared with a very large number of countries across the world to implement those export control measures if the invasion proceeds.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; I think &#8212; could we do our last question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you mentioned the sanctions would hit new issues of sovereign debt.&nbsp; Are there any &#8212; is there any impact on existing issues trading in the secondary market?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s your assessment of the ability or the willingness of Chinese financial institutions to fill the void left by the U.S. and Europe?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; David, so this &#8212; we&#8217;ve designed these sanctions so that Russia cannot raise money from U.S. investors.&nbsp; And Europe has implemented a very similar measure.&nbsp; And so, it&#8217;s the primary market that matters in terms of raising money.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve directed our sanction towards that portion of the market.</p>



<p>Whether &#8212; as to whether China can replace U.S. and European investors: I mean, I think the numbers speak for themselves in terms of the percentage of the total that Dollars and Euro represent as a &#8212; as a source of borrowing.&nbsp; Also, just as currencies that are used to make payments, to receive payments, and also to store wealth, store value.&nbsp;</p>



<p>China&#8217;s share on all those metrics I just mentioned are in the low single digits.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s &#8212; it is &#8212; it is nowhere close to a substitute for the Western financial system.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining today.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to “senior administration official.”&nbsp; The embargo lifts officially now.&nbsp; If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me, and we&#8217;ll make sure to get back to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>3:52 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Libya</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-libya/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 23:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.  In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to Libya declared in Executive Order 13566 of February 25, 2011, and expanded in Executive Order 13726 of April 19, 2016, is to continue in effect beyond February 25, 2022.<br><br>Libyans confront ongoing instability originating from actions Colonel Muammar Qadhafi, his government, and close associates took against the people of Libya in 2011.  Civil conflict in Libya will continue until Libyans resolve their political divisions and foreign military intervention ends.  Because many of these divisions relate to access to resources, a serious risk remains that, if not protected, Libyan state assets will be misappropriated by parties determined to undermine the ongoing United Nations peace process, including former members of the Qadhafi government, members of the Qadhafi family, or Qadhafi&#8217;s close associates.  The diversion of these resources could prolong and deepen the current instability in Libya, which benefits ISIS and other terrorist groups that pose a serious threat to the national security of the United States and the security of regional partners.  We run the risk of military escalation if sanctions do not remain in effect, particularly since those who reject dialogue and obstruct and undermine Libya&#8217;s democratic transition remain interested in exploiting the wealth of the Libyan people to advance their narrow self-interest and perpetuate conflict in the country.<br><br>The situation in Libya continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States, and we need to protect against the diversion of assets or other abuse by persons hindering Libyan national reconciliation, including Qadhafi&#8217;s family and associates.<br><br>Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13566 with respect to Libya.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely, <br><br>                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Libya</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-libya-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 23:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 25, 2011, by Executive Order 13566, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions of Colonel Muammar Qadhafi, his government, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On February 25, 2011, by Executive Order 13566, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions of Colonel Muammar Qadhafi, his government, and close associates, which took extreme measures against the people of Libya, including by using weapons of war, mercenaries, and wanton violence against unarmed civilians.&nbsp; In addition, there was a serious risk that Libyan state assets would be misappropriated by Qadhafi, members of his government, members of his family, or his close associates if those assets were not protected.&nbsp; The foregoing circumstances, the prolonged attacks, and the increased numbers of Libyans seeking refuge in other countries from the attacks caused a deterioration in the security of Libya and posed a serious risk to its stability.</p>



<p>On April 19, 2016, the President signed Executive Order 13726, which expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13566.&nbsp; The President found that the&nbsp;ongoing violence in Libya, including attacks by armed groups against Libyan state facilities, foreign missions in Libya, and&nbsp;critical infrastructure, as well as human rights abuses, violations of the arms embargo imposed by United Nations Security Council Resolution 1970 (2011), and misappropriation of&nbsp;Libya&#8217;s natural resources threaten the peace, security, stability, sovereignty, democratic transition, and territorial integrity of Libya, and thereby constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.</p>



<p>The situation in Libya continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States, and measures are needed to protect against the diversion of assets or other abuses by members of Qadhafi&#8217;s family, their associates, and other persons hindering Libyan national reconciliation.</p>



<p>For this reason, the national emergency declared on February 25, 2011, and expanded on April 19, 2016, must continue in effect beyond February 25, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13566.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.<br>                              </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>February 22, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Parents to Discuss Efforts to Invest in Children and Cut the Cost of Child&#160;Care</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-parents-to-discuss-efforts-to-invest-in-children-and-cut-the-cost-of-child-care/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 22:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Secretary Xavier Becerra, Gender Policy Council Director Jen Klein, and Deputy Assistant to the President for Economic Mobility Carmel Martin hosted a conversation with parents and their children at the White House to discuss the need to cut the crushing child care costs families face and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Secretary Xavier Becerra, Gender Policy Council Director Jen Klein, and Deputy Assistant to the President for Economic Mobility Carmel Martin hosted a conversation with parents and their children at the White House to discuss the need to cut the crushing child care costs families face and increase the supply of high-quality child care.</p>



<p><br>The Administration officials highlighted President Biden’s plans to make the largest investment in child care and preschool in the nation’s history, saving most working families more than half of their spending on child care and expanding the number of high-quality child care providers. The President’s plan would also enable states to deliver two years of free pre-school for every 3- and 4-year old in a setting of their parents’ choice – from public schools and child care providers to Head Start. They reiterated that early learning experiences help children succeed later in life; research shows that every $1 invested in high-quality early childhood care and education can yield $3 to $7 over the long-run, as children do better in school, are more likely to graduate high-school and college, and earn more as adults.</p>



<p><br>The parents attending the event shared that the high costs of child care and the difficulty of finding quality, affordable child care near their homes made it challenging for them to provide for their families and remain in the workforce. One family member noted spending more than $2,000 a month in child care expense and the immense strain that put on their family’s expenses. The families discussed how the pandemic exacerbated many of the challenges they were already facing when it comes to child care and emphasized how the President’s plans will help families access high-quality early childhood care and education.</p>



<p>You can watch a recording of today’s event by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQ0dVUiApBU">clicking here</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: United&#160;States Imposes First Tranche of Swift and Severe Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/fact-sheet-united-states-imposes-first-tranche-of-swift-and-severe-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 21:31:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, Russian President Vladimir Putin of Russia recognized two regions of Ukraine as independent states and today claimed that recognition to include all of the Donbas region. The Russian Parliament also authorized the deployment of additional Russian forces into this Ukrainian territory.&#160; As President Biden and our Allies and partners have made clear, we will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, Russian President Vladimir Putin of Russia recognized two regions of Ukraine as independent states and today claimed that recognition to include all of the Donbas region. The Russian Parliament also authorized the deployment of additional Russian forces into this Ukrainian territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As President Biden and our Allies and partners have made clear, we will impose significant costs on Russia for Russia’s actions. Today, the Administration is implementing the first tranche of sanctions that go far beyond 2014, in coordination with allies and partners in the European Union, United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, and Australia. And as President Biden promised, we worked with Germany to ensure the Nord Stream 2 pipeline will not move forward.</p>



<p>The President has directed the following measures:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Full blocking sanctions on two significant Russian financial institutions.</strong> The Secretary of the Treasury will impose full blocking sanctions on two large state-owned Russian financial institutions that provide key services crucial to financing the Kremlin and the Russian military: Vnesheconombank and Promsvyazbank and their subsidiaries. Collectively, these institutions hold more than $80 billion in assets and finance the Russian defense sector and economic development. These measures will freeze their assets in the United States, prohibit U.S. individuals and businesses from doing any transactions with them, shut them out of the global financial system, and foreclose access to the U.S. dollar.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanded sovereign debt prohibitions restricting U.S. individuals and firms from participation in secondary markets for new debt issued by the Central Bank of the Russian Federation, the National Wealth Fund of the Russian Federation, and the Ministry of Finance of the Russian Federation.</strong>  These prohibitions will cut off the Russian government from a key avenue by which it raises capital to fund its priorities and will increase future financing costs. It denies Russia access to key U.S. markets and investors.</li><li><strong>Full blocking sanctions on five Russian elites and their family members: Aleksandr Bortnikov (and his son, Denis), Sergei Kiriyenko (and his son, Vladimir), and Promsvyazbank CEO Petr Fradkov.</strong> These individuals and their relatives directly benefit from their connections with the Kremlin. Other Russian elites and their family members are on notice that additional actions could be taken against them.</li><li><strong>Today,</strong> <strong>the Secretary of the Treasury will determine that any institution in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy is a target for further sanctions.</strong> Over 80% of Russia’s daily foreign exchange transactions globally are in U.S. dollars and roughly half of Russia’s international trade is conducted in dollars. With this action,no Russian financial institution is safe from our measures, including the largest banks. </li></ul>



<p>These actions come in addition to steps being taken by our Allies and partners and represent our first response to Russia’s actions. As President Biden made clear, Russia will pay an even steeper price if it continues its aggression.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Announcing Response to Russian Actions in&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/22/remarks-by-president-biden-announcing-response-to-russian-actions-in-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 21:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:22 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Trying to make up your mind, huh?&#160; (Laughter.) Well, good afternoon.&#160; Yesterday, Vladimir Putin recognized two regions of Ukraine as independent states and he bizarrely asserted that these regions are no longer part of Ukraine and their sovereign territory.&#160; To put it simply, Russia just announced that it&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>2:22 P.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Trying to make up your mind, huh?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Well, good afternoon.&nbsp; Yesterday, Vladimir Putin recognized two regions of Ukraine as independent states and he bizarrely asserted that these regions are no longer part of Ukraine and their sovereign territory.&nbsp; To put it simply, Russia just announced that it is carving out a big chunk of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last night, Putin authorized Russian forces to deploy into the region &#8212; these regions.&nbsp; Today, he asserted that these regions are &#8212; actually extend deeper than the two areas he recognized, claiming large areas currently under the jurisdiction of the Ukraine government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;s setting up a rationale to take more territory by force, in my view.&nbsp; And if we listen to his speech last night &#8212; and many of you did, I know &#8212; he&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s setting up a rationale to go much further.</p>



<p>This is the beginning of a Russian invasion of Ukraine, as he indicated and asked permission to be able to do from his Duma.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s begin to &#8212; so, I&#8217;m going to begin to impose sanctions in response, far beyond the steps we and our Allies and partners implemented in 2014.&nbsp; And if Russia goes further with this invasion, we stand prepared to go further as &#8212; with sanction.</p>



<p>Who in the Lord&#8217;s name does Putin think gives him the right to declare new so-called countries on territory that belonged to his neighbors?&nbsp; This is a flagrant violation of international law, and it demands a firm response from the international community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the last few months, we have coordinated closely with our NATO Allies and partners in Europe and around the world to prepare that response.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve said all along and I&#8217;ve told Putin to his face a mon- &#8212; a month a- &#8212; more than a month ago that we would act together and the moment Russia moved against Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russia has now undeniably moved against Ukraine by declaring these independent states.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, today, I&#8217;m announcing the first tranche of sanctions to impose costs on Russia in response to their actions yesterday.&nbsp; These have been closely coordinated with our Allies and partners, and we&#8217;ll continue to escalate sanctions if Russia escalates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re implementing full blocking sanctions on two large Russian financial institutions: V.E.B. and their military bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re implementing comprehensive sanctions on Russian sovereign debt.&nbsp; That means we’ve cut off Russia&#8217;s government from Western financing.&nbsp; It can no longer raise money from the West and cannot trade in its new debt on our markets or European markets either.</p>



<p>Starting <s>tomorrow</s> [today] and continuing in the days ahead, we will also impose sanctions on Russia&#8217;s elites and their family members.  They share in the corrupt gains of the Kremlin policies and should share in the pain as well. </p>



<p>And because of Russia’s actions, we’ve worked with Germany to ensure Nord Stream 2 will not &#8212; as I promised &#8212; will not move forward.</p>



<p>As Russia contemplates its next move, we have our next move prepared as well.&nbsp; Russia will pay an even steeper price if it continues its aggression, including additional sanctions.</p>



<p>The United States will continue to provide defensive assistance to Ukraine in the meantime.&nbsp; And we’ll continue to reinforce and reassure our NATO Allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, in response to Russia’s admission that it will not withdraw its forces from Belarus, I have authorized additional movements of U.S. forces and equipment already stationed in Europe to strengthen our Baltic Allies &#8212; Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania.</p>



<p>Let me be clear: These are totally defensive moves on our part.&nbsp; We have no intention of fighting Russia.&nbsp; We want to send an unmistakable message, though, that the United States, together with our Allies, will defend every inch of NATO territory and abide by the commitments we made to NATO.</p>



<p>We still believe that Russia is poised to go much further in launching a massive military attack against Ukraine.&nbsp; I hope I’m wrong about that &#8212; hope we’re wrong about that.&nbsp; But Russia has only escalated its threat against the rest of Ukrainian territory, including major cities and including the capital city of Kyiv.</p>



<p>There are &#8212; there are still well over 150,000 Russian troops surrounding Ukraine.&nbsp; And as I said, Russian forces remain positioned in Belarus to attack Ukraine from the north, including war planes and offensive missile systems.</p>



<p>Russia has moved troops closer to Ukraine’s border with Russia.&nbsp; Russia’s naval vessels are maneuvering in the Black Sea to Ukraine’s south, including amphibious assault ships, missile cruisers, and submarines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russia has moved supplies of blood and medical equipment into position on their border.&nbsp; You don’t need blood unless you plan on starting a war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And over the last few days, we’ve seen much of the playbook that Secretary Blinken laid out last week at the United Nations Security Council come to pass: a major increase in military provocations and false-flag events along the line of contact in the Donbas; dramatically staged, conveniently on-camera meeting of Putin’s Security Council to grandstand for the Russian public; and now political provocation of recognizing sovereign Ukrainian territory as so-called independent republics in clear violation, again, of international law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Putin has sought authorization from the Russian parliament to use military force outside of Russian territory.&nbsp; And this set the stage for further pretexts and further provocations by Russia to try to justify further military action.</p>



<p>None of us &#8212; none of us should be fooled.&nbsp; None of us will be fooled.&nbsp; There is no justification.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Further Russian assault into Ukraine remains a severe threat in the days ahead.&nbsp; And if Russia proceeds, it is Russia, and Russia alone, that bears the responsibility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we respond, my administration is using every tool at our disposal to protect American businesses and consumers from rising prices at the pump.&nbsp; As I said last week, defending freedom will have costs for us as well, here at home.&nbsp; We need to be honest about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as we will do &#8212; but as we do this, I’m going to take robust action and make sure the pain of our sanctions is targeted at the Russian economy, not ours.</p>



<p>We are closely monitoring energy supplies for any disruption.&nbsp; We’re executing a plan in coordination with major oil-producing consumers and producers toward a collective investment to secure stability and global energy supplies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This will be &#8212; this will blunt gas prices.&nbsp; I want to limit the pain the American people are feeling at the gas pump.&nbsp; This is critical to me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the last few days, I have been in constant contact with European leaders, including with Ukrainian President Zelenskyy.&nbsp;&nbsp;Vice President Harris met in person with leaders in Germany over the weekend at the Munich Conference, including President Zelenskyy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At every step, we have shown that the United States and our Allies and partners are working in unison &#8212; which he hasn’t been counting on &#8212; Mr. Putin.&nbsp; We’re united in our support of Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;re united in our opposition to Russian aggression.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we’re united in our resolve to defend our NATO Alliance.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re united in our understanding of the urgency and seriousness of the threat Russia is making to global peace and stability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, the world heard clearly the full extent of Vladimir Putin’s twisted rewrite of history, going back more than a century, as he waxed eloquently, noting that &#8212; well, I’m not going to go into it, but nothing in Putin’s lengthy remarks indicated any interest in pursuing real dialogue on European security in the year 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He directly attacked Ukraine’s right to exist.&nbsp; He indirectly threatened territory formerly held by Russia, including nations that today are thriving democracies and members of NATO.&nbsp; He explicitly threatened war unless his extreme demands were met.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is no question that Russia is the aggressor.&nbsp; So we’re clear-eyed about the challenges we&#8217;re facing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nonetheless, there is still time to avert the worst-case scenario that will bring untold suffering to millions of people if they move as suggested.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States and our Allies and partners remain open to diplomacy if it is serious.&nbsp; When all is said and done, we’re going to judge Russia by its actions, not its words.</p>



<p>And whatever Russia does next, we&#8217;re ready to respond with unity, clarity, and conviction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ll probably have more to say about this as we &#8212; if it moves on.&nbsp; I’m hoping diplomacy is still available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>2:32 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Kuleba of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-foreign-minister-kuleba-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 20:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba of Ukraine to reaffirm the United States’ commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. President Biden updated Foreign Minister Kuleba on the United States’ response to Russia’s decision to recognize the purported “independence” of the so-called DNR and LNR regions of Ukraine, including&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba of Ukraine to reaffirm the United States’ commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. President Biden updated Foreign Minister Kuleba on the United States’ response to Russia’s decision to recognize the purported “independence” of the so-called DNR and LNR regions of Ukraine, including the Executive Order issued last night and new sanctions announced today. He also affirmed that the United States would continue providing security assistance and macroeconomic support to Ukraine. President Biden reiterated the readiness of the United States, in close cooperation with our Allies and partners, to respond swiftly and decisively to any further Russian aggression against Ukraine. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Securing a Made in America Supply Chain for Critical&#160;Minerals</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/fact-sheet-securing-a-made-in-america-supply-chain-for-critical-minerals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration, Companies Announce Major Investments to Expand Domestic Critical Minerals Supply Chain, Breaking Dependence on China and Boosting Sustainable Practices Critical minerals provide the building blocks for many modern technologies and are essential to our national security and economic prosperity. These minerals—such as rare earth elements, lithium, and cobalt—can be found in products from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration, Companies Announce Major Investments to Expand Domestic Critical Minerals Supply Chain, Breaking Dependence on China and Boosting Sustainable Practices</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Critical minerals provide the building blocks for many modern technologies and are essential to our national security and economic prosperity. These minerals—such as rare earth elements, lithium, and cobalt—can be found in products from computers to household appliances. They are also key inputs in clean energy technologies like batteries, electric vehicles, wind turbines, and solar panels. As the world transitions to a clean energy economy, global demand for these critical minerals is set to skyrocket by 400-600 percent over the next several decades, and, for minerals such as lithium and graphite used in electric vehicle (EV) batteries, demand will increase by even more—as much as 4,000 percent. The U.S. is increasingly dependent on foreign sources for many of the processed versions of these minerals. Globally, China controls most of the market for processing and refining for cobalt, lithium, rare earths and other critical minerals.</p>



<p>Executive Order 14017 (E.O.)<em>, </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/24/executive-order-on-americas-supply-chains/"><em>America’s Supply Chains</em></a>, signed one year ago this week, ordered a review of vulnerabilities in our critical mineral and material supply chains within 100 days. In June, the Biden-Harris Administration released a first-of-its-kind <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/100-day-supply-chain-review-report.pdf">supply chain assessment</a> that found our over-reliance on foreign sources and adversarial nations for critical minerals and materials posed national and economic security threats.</p>



<p>In addition to working with partners and allies to diversify sustainable sources, the reports recommended expanding domestic mining, production, processing, and recycling of critical minerals and materials—all with a laser focus on boosting strong labor, environmental and environmental justice, community engagement, and Tribal consultation standards.</p>



<p><strong>Today, President Biden will meet with Administration and state partners, industry executives, community representatives, labor leaders, and California Governor Gavin Newsom to announce major investments in domestic production of key critical minerals and materials, ensuring these resources benefit the community, and creating good-paying, union jobs in sustainable production.</strong></p>



<ul><li>President Biden will announce that the Department of Defense’s Industrial Base Analysis and Sustainment program has awarded MP Materials <strong>$35 million</strong> to separate and process heavy rare earth elements at its facility in Mountain Pass, California, establishing a full end-to-end domestic permanent magnet supply chain. Paired with this catalytic public funding announcement, MP Materials will announce it will invest another <strong>$700 million </strong>and create more than 350 jobs in the magnet supply chain by 2024. Currently, China controls 87 percent of the global permanent magnet market, which are used in EV motors, defense systems, electronics, and wind turbines.<br></li><li>Berkshire Hathaway Energy Renewables (BHE Renewables) will announce that this spring, they will break ground on a new demonstration facility in Imperial County, California, to test the commercial viability of their sustainable lithium extraction process from geothermal brine as part of a <strong>multibillion-dollar</strong> investment in sustainable lithium production over the next five years. If successful, this sets the company a path towards commercial scale production of battery grade lithium hydroxide and lithium carbonate by 2026. Imperial Valley contains some of the largest deposits of lithium in the world. Once at scale, BHE Renewables facilities could produce 90,000 metric tons of lithium per year.<br></li><li>Redwood Materials will discuss a pilot, in partnership with Ford and Volvo, for collection and recycling of end-of-life lithium-ion batteries at its Nevada based facilities to extract lithium, cobalt, nickel, and graphite. This builds upon Redwood’s recent announcements including a joint venture with Ford to build a recycling facility in Tennessee and its intention to begin construction on a new cathode manufacturing facility in Nevada in 2022.<br></li><li>Secretary Granholm will discuss DOE’s first-of-its-kind<strong> $140 million</strong> <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-launches-140-million-program-develop-americas-first-kind-critical-minerals-refinery" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">demonstration project</a> funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law (BIL) to recover rare earth elements and critical minerals from coal ash and other mine waste, reducing the need for new mining. This project will deliver on the work of the Interagency Working Group on Coal and Power Plant Communities and Economic Revitalization by creating good-paying manufacturing jobs in legacy coal communities.<br></li><li>She will also discuss <strong>$3 billion</strong> in <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-administration-doe-invest-3-billion-strengthen-us-supply-chain-advanced-batteries">BIL funding</a> to invest in refining battery materials such as lithium, cobalt, nickel, and graphite, and battery recycling facilities, creating good-paying clean energy manufacturing jobs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>These are only the latest in announcements by major companies committing to domestic sourcing of critical minerals and materials:</strong></p>



<ul><li>MP Materials <a href="https://mpmaterials.com/articles/mp-materials-to-build-us-magnet-factory-enters-long-term-supply-agreement-with-general-motors/">recently announced</a> construction of a rare earth metal, alloy and magnet manufacturing facility in Texas and a long-term supply agreement with General Motors to power the motors in more than a dozen of GM’s EV models. Production will begin next year, with capacity to produce enough magnets to power 500,000 EV motors annually.<br></li><li>In addition to BHE Renewables, Controlled Thermal Resources (CTR) and EnergySource Minerals have established operations in Imperial County to extract lithium from geothermal brine. GM will source lithium for EV batteries from CTR. The companies are also working with the state-authorized Lithium Valley Commission to develop a royalty structure that would invest profits from their operations in infrastructure, health, and educational investments for the residents of the surrounding region.<br></li><li>Tesla intends to source high-grade nickel for EV batteries from Talon Metals’ Tamarack nickel project under development in Minnesota. Talon Metals and the United Steelworkers (USW) have established a <a href="https://talonmetals.com/talon-metals-and-steelworkers-union-partner-to-advance-the-tamarack-nickel-project-for-us-ev-battery-supply-chain/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">workforce development partnership</a> for the project to train workers on next-generation technologies in the local community and from mining regions in the U.S. facing declining demand. As part of this partnership, Talon has agreed to remain neutral in any union organizing efforts by USW.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ahead of the one-year anniversary of E.O. 14017 this Thursday, the Administration has taken action across the Federal government to secure reliable and sustainable supplies of critical minerals and materials, while also upholding the Administration’s labor, environmental and environmental justice, and equity priorities:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Updating outdated mining laws and regulations.</strong> This year, the Mining Law of 1872 turns 150. This law still governs mining of most critical minerals on federal public lands. Today, the Department of Interior (DOI) <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-launches-interagency-working-group-mining-reform">announced</a> it has established an Interagency Working Group (IWG) that will lead an Administration effort on legislative and regulatory reform of mine permitting and oversight. The IWG released a list of Biden-Harris Administration <a href="https://www.doi.gov/sites/doi.gov/files/biden-harris-administration-fundamental-principles-for-domestic-mining-reform.pdf">fundamental principles for mining reform</a> to promote responsible mining under strong social, environmental, and labor standards that avoids the historic injustice that too many mining operations have left behind. The IWG will deliver recommendations to Congress by November. They will also host extensive public input and comment sessions to ensure an inclusive process, and will work with the relevant agencies to initiate updates to mining regulations by the end of the calendar year.<br></li><li><strong>Updating and prioritizing the Federal list of critical minerals. </strong>Today, pursuant to the Energy Act of 2020, DOI will update its Federal list of critical minerals, listing minerals essential to economic or national security and vulnerable to disruption. To focus the work of Federal agencies on sourcing critical minerals, the Administration will direct agencies to prioritize the production and processing of minerals necessary to produce key products like batteries, semiconductors, and permanent magnets, consistent with our strong environmental, social and labor principles.<br></li><li><strong>Strengthening critical mineral stockpiling. </strong>DOE, DOD, and the Department of State signed a memorandum of agreement (MOA) to better coordinate stockpiling activities to support the U.S. transition to clean energy and national security needs. In October, President Biden streamlined the National Defense Stockpile by signing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/10/31/executive-order-on-the-designation-to-exercise-authority-over-the-national-defense-stockpile/#:~:text=This%20order%20confers%20authority%20related,stockpiling%20for%20national%20defense%20purposes." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">E.O. 14051</a> to delegate authority release of strategic and critical materials to the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
