<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 18:27:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/19/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-economy-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 18:27:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24431</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:43 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good morning.&#160; Tomorrow marks exactly six months since my administration began.&#160; I think it’s a fitting moment to take a look at our economy &#8212; where we were six months ago, what we’ve achieved since then, and what I believe we’ve &#8212; I believe where we’re headed.&#160;Before I took&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:43 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good morning.&nbsp; Tomorrow marks exactly six months since my administration began.&nbsp; I think it’s a fitting moment to take a look at our economy &#8212; where we were six months ago, what we’ve achieved since then, and what I believe we’ve &#8212; I believe where we’re headed.&nbsp;<br>Before I took office, there was a lot of folks out there &#8212; a lot of folks out there making some pretty bold predictions about how things would turn out.&nbsp; You might remember some of the predictions.&nbsp; That if I became President, we’d, quote, “see a depression the likes of which we’ve never seen.”&nbsp; End of quote.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, it’s true that the economy was sputtering before I got here, adding only 60,000 jobs per month for the three months before I was sworn in.&nbsp; But now, six months later, we’ve changed that.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve gone from 60,000 jobs per month to 60,000 jobs every three days &#8212; more than 600,000 jobs per month since I took office.&nbsp; More than 3 million new jobs all told.&nbsp; That’s the fastest growth, I’m told, at this point in any administration’s history.<br><br>Another prediction &#8212; that is my favorite one, I must add &#8212; is that if I got elected, I’d bring the end to capitalism.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I never understood that one, but we’ve heard &#8212; we’ve heard it an awful lot.&nbsp; Well, in six months into my administration, the U.S. economy has experienced the highest economic growth rate in nearly 40 years.&nbsp;<br><br>And we know we’ve &#8212; and now we knew that we needed to launch a war-time effort to get the &#8212; America vaccinated and pass a powerful American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br><br>We did both those things.&nbsp; And now, the forecasters have doubled their projections for growth this year in the economy to 7 percent or higher. &nbsp;In fact, the U.S. is the only developed country in the world where growth projections today are stronger than they were before the pandemic hit.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, companies across the country are giving workers a raise.&nbsp; Unusual thing.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And the number of new unemployment claims has been cut by more than half since I took office.&nbsp;<br><br>And by the way, two weeks ago, I issued a major executive order promoting fair and open competition, which is the cornerstone &#8212; the cornerstone of American capitalism, banning non-compete clauses that suppress workers’ wages; lowering the price of things like hearing aids, prescription drugs, Internet service; along with dozens of other actions.&nbsp;<br><br>Folks, it turns out capitalism is alive and very well.&nbsp; We’re making serious progress to ensure that it works the way it’s supposed to work: for the good of the American people.<br><br>So, for all those predictions of doom and gloom, six months in, here’s where we stand: record growth, record job creation, workers getting hard-earned breaks.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, we’ve brought this economy back from the brink.&nbsp; And we designed our strategy not only to provide for a temporary boost, but to lay the foundation for a long-term boom that brings everyone along.<br><br>You know, that’s why we designed the American Rescue Plan to help not just all those &#8212; everyone at once, but over the course of a full year and beyond so we could help families and small businesses weather the ups and downs of our &#8212; as the economy recovers from an historic pandemic. &nbsp;And I &#8212; there are going to be ups and downs.<br><br>We saw a great example of that just last week.&nbsp; For the first time, monthly payments began going out to nearly every working family raising a child in the United States of America.&nbsp; Thanks to the expanded Child Tax Credit in the American Rescue Plan: $300 a month going out for each child under the age of six, and $250 for every child 6 through 17, every month for the next six months, with more coming in the spring.&nbsp;<br><br>That money is a game-changer.&nbsp; For some, it’s a lifesaver.&nbsp; Think of the single mom, struggling to put food on the table each month.&nbsp; The parent who has to tell their kid, “I’m sorry, honey, but we can’t afford those dance classes or the sports team you want to play on this fall.&nbsp; We can’t do it.”&nbsp; You know, they can’t wait for the credit against their taxes to be coming next year as a tax credit.&nbsp; They need cash in their pockets today.&nbsp;<br><br>For families with the least, this money will do the most &#8212; dramatically reducing child poverty in America.&nbsp; And for millions of middle-class families, it will give them a little bit of breathing room every month.&nbsp; That’s just one example of how we’re building an economy from the bottom up and the middle out. &nbsp;<br><br>But despite that progress, we cannot afford to be complacent.&nbsp; We know that our economic recovery hinges on getting the pandemic under control.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, and by fully vaccinating 160 million Americans, 80 percent of our seniors, we’ve fundamentally changed the course of the pandemic &#8212; from one that threatens all Americans, to a disease that has the most severe impacts only on the unvaccinated people in the country.&nbsp; But we can’t let up, especially since and because of the Delta variant, which is more transmis- &#8212; more transmissible and more dangerous.&nbsp;<br><br>Unfortunately, cases are now rising, particularly in communities with very low vaccination rates.&nbsp; Just four states account for nearly 40 percent &#8212; four states, 40 percent of all cases last week.&nbsp; Virtually all hospitalizations and deaths are occurring among unvaccinated Americans.&nbsp; These tragedies are avoidable.&nbsp;<br><br>The data couldn’t be clearer: If you’re fully vaccinated, you have a high degree of protection against severe illness, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp; If you’re unvaccinated, you are not protected.&nbsp;So, please, please get vaccinated. &nbsp;Get vaccinated now. &nbsp;It works. &nbsp;It’s safe. &nbsp;It’s free. &nbsp;It’s convenient.<br><br>You know, this virus doesn’t have to hold you back any longer.&nbsp; It doesn’t have to hold our economy back any longer.&nbsp; But the only way we put it behind us is if more Americans get vaccinated.<br><br>We also know that as our economy has come roaring back, we’ve seen some price increases.&nbsp; Some folks have raised worries that this could be a sign of persistent inflation.&nbsp; But that’s not our view.&nbsp; Our experts believe and the data shows that most of the price increases we’ve seen are &#8212; were expected and expected to be temporary.<br><br>The reality is, you can’t flip the global economic light back on and not expect this to happen.&nbsp; As demand returns, there’s going to be global supply chain challenges.&nbsp; We’ve seen that in semi-conductors, which are used in automobiles.&nbsp; That global shortage has slowed vehicle production, creating a temporary spike in car prices.&nbsp; That’s a real challenge.&nbsp; And my administration is doing everything we can to address it.&nbsp; But again, these disruptions are temporary.&nbsp;<br><br>Lumber prices are another example.&nbsp; They spiked early in our recovery, but in recent weeks, they’ve began to fall &#8212; they’ve fallen by more than 50 percent.&nbsp;<br><br>In the hospitality industry, prices are returning to where they used to be.&nbsp; Economists call all of these things “transitory effects.”&nbsp; And they account for about 60 percent of the price increases we’ve seen over the last few months.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, I want to be clear: My administration understands that if we were to ever experience unchecked inflation over the long term that would pose real challenges to our economy.&nbsp; So while we’re confident that isn’t what we are seeing today, we’re going to remain vigilant about any response that is needed.&nbsp;<br><br>As I made clear to Chairman Powell of the Federal Reserve when we met recently, the Fed is independent.&nbsp; It should take whatever steps it deems necessary to support a strong, durable economic recovery.&nbsp; But whatever different views some might have on current price increases, we should be united on one thing: passage of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, which we shook hands on.&nbsp; We shook hands on it.&nbsp; And my Build Back Better plan will be a force for achieving lower prices for Americans looking ahead.&nbsp; It’s another reason why these investments are so important.&nbsp;<br><br>If we make a prudent, multi-year investments in better roads, bridges, transit systems, and high-speed Internet, and a modern, resilient electric grid, here’s what will happen: It breaks up the bottlenecks in our economy. &nbsp;Goods get to consumers more rapidly and less expensively.&nbsp; Small businesses create and innovate much more seamlessly.&nbsp; If we increase the availability of quality, affordable childcare, eldercare, paid leave, more people will enter the workforce.&nbsp;<br><br>These steps will enhance our productivity &#8212; raising wages without raising prices.&nbsp; That won’t increase inflation.&nbsp; It will take the pressure off of inflation, give a boost to our workforce, which leads to lower prices in the years ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>So, if your primary concern right now is inflation, you should be even more enthusiastic about this plan.&nbsp; And as we promote &#8212; as we promote fair competition in our economy through the executive order I mentioned, it will drive down prices even further.&nbsp; New businesses will get in the game, competing against those giant corporations who have been free to ramp up prices because they haven’t had any real competition.<br><br>Look, the bottom line is this: What the best companies do and what we as a country should do is make smart, sustainable investments with appropriate financing to make this nation more productive, to advance America’s leadership on clean energy to win the jobs of the future while meeting the threat of climate change, and to ensure that all working Americans benefit from the growth they’re helping produce.&nbsp;<br><br>The independent experts who have analyzed my plans have found that they would do just that: expand output and enable millions of Americans to enter the labor workforce now, just this year &#8212; not just for the next &#8212; but not just this year, but for decades in the future.&nbsp; It’s not temporary.<br><br>This is the best strategy to create millions of jobs and lift up the middle-class families and grow wages and keep prices affordable for the long term.&nbsp;<br><br>What we can’t do is go back to the&nbsp;same old trickle-down theories that gave us nearly $2 trillion in deficit-financed corporate tax giveaways that did nothing to make our economy more productive or resilient. &nbsp;The same people who cheered on that approach are now telling us it isn’t [is] a problem if big companies have actually to compete for workers and offer them a fair wage with some dignity.<br><br>I could not disagree more.&nbsp; We can’t go back to the old, failed thinking.&nbsp; We need to grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out, as I’ve said before.&nbsp;<br><br>The investments I’m proposing are investments the American people want and investments that our country needs.&nbsp; And if we get this done, a wide range of independent forecasters project that it will have an incredibly significant impact on GDP and jobs &#8212; good-paying jobs with prevailing wages.&nbsp; And the majority of these jobs will go to people without a college degree.&nbsp;<br><br>I’ve said it before, and it’s true: This is a blue-collar blueprint for building an American economy back.&nbsp; Simply put, we can’t afford not to make these investments.&nbsp; And we’re going to pay for them responsibly as well, by ensuring that our largest corporations and the very wealthiest among us pay their fair share by reforming our international tax system with a minimum global tax, which we’ve led the world to agree to.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me close with this: When I arrived in office, it had been a long time since the government had worked for the people.&nbsp; Things had been great for big corporations and folks at the top.&nbsp; Those 55 major corporations that paid zero in income tax while making billions in profits, they had no complaints.&nbsp;<br><br>But when I took office, I made a commitment &#8212; a commitment to the American people that we were going to change that paradigm so working families could have a fighting chance again to get a good education; to get a good job and a raise; to take care of the elderly parent or the child with the disability and still be able to go out and earn a good living; to stop losing hours of their lives stuck in traffic because the streets are crumbling; or waiting for slow, spotty Internet to connect them to the world.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s what the economy we’re building is all about. &nbsp;That’s why we passed the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; And that’s why we need the investment of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and my Build Back Better plan.&nbsp;<br><br>Our economy has come a long way over the last six months.&nbsp; We can’t slow down now.&nbsp; We can make this boom we’re experiencing today one that will ensure that all Americans have an opportunity to share in it for years to come.&nbsp; And we can show the world that American democracy can deliver for the people.&nbsp;<br><br>I look forward to continuing to build this economy.&nbsp; And I’m incredibly optimistic about what we’re going to be able to build together in the next six months and the years to come.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all for listening.&nbsp; May God bless you.&nbsp; And I’ll take a few questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, you said last week that companies and platforms like Facebook are “killing people” by letting them &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Let me (inaudible) precisely what I said.&nbsp; I’m glad you asked me that question.&nbsp; One, I had just read that &#8212; on the Facebook &#8212; Facebook pointed out that &#8212; it was pointed out that Facebook, of all the misinformation, 60 percent of that misinformation came from 12 individuals.&nbsp; That’s what the article said.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I was asked that question about what do I think is happening.&nbsp; Facebook isn’t killing people; these 12 people who are out there giving misinformation &#8212; anyone listening to it is getting hurt by it.&nbsp; It’s killing people.&nbsp; It’s bad information.<br><br>My hope is that Facebook, instead of taking it personally &#8212; that somehow I’m saying Facebook is killing people &#8212; that they would do something about the misinformation &#8212; the outrageous informa- &#8212; misinformation about the vaccine.&nbsp; That’s what I meant.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have they done enough in your opinion to stop &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I haven’t &#8212; to be completely honest with you, I don’t know that they did anything today.&nbsp; Up to &#8212; over the weekend, I don’t think they had.&nbsp; But I don’t know.&nbsp; I don’t know the answer to that question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you hold them accountable if they don’t do more to stop the spread?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m &#8212; when you say “hold accountable,” I just want to &#8212; I’m not trying to hold people account- &#8212; I’m trying make people to look at themselves.&nbsp; Look in the mirror.&nbsp; Think about that misinformation going to your son, your daughter, your relatives, someone you love.&nbsp; That’s what I’m asking.<br><br>All the way in the back.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; At what point would you consider inflation unchecked to a point at which you would either consider taking action or you would want to see the Fed take action?<br><br>And secondly, why do you believe that the budget bill is appropriate legislation for a pathway to citizenship?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, first of all, I think we need to find pathways to citizenship.&nbsp; The budget bill is an appropriate way to get around the filibuster to be able to make a judgment as to whether or not they should have a pathway.&nbsp; That’s for the Parli- &#8212; Parliamentarian to decide, though &#8212; not for Joe Biden to decide.<br><br>Your first ques- &#8212; part of the question was?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was on inflation.&nbsp; You mentioned unchecked inflation.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nobody suggesting there&#8217;s unchecked inflation on the way &#8212; no serious economist.&nbsp; That’s totally different.&nbsp;<br><br>I mean, look, the stock market is higher than it has been in all of history, even went down this month &#8212; even down this month.<br><br>Now, I don’t look at the stock market as a means by which to judge the economy like my predecessor did.&nbsp; But he&#8217;d be very &#8212; he’d be talking to you every day for the last five months about how the stock market is so high &#8212; higher than any time in history, still higher than any time in history.<br><br>So, that’s not how I judge whether or not we have economic growth.<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, on China and cyber hacking &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; She jumps up before you do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Effectively, your administration is naming and shaming China, but no sanctions.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; And is that effective enough?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They’re still determining exactly what happened.&nbsp; The investigation is not finished.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all very much.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On China real quick &#8212; on China real quick: What is your understanding of the biggest difference between what they&#8217;ve done versus what Russia has done in terms of cyber hacking?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’d take a longer explanation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have all the time in the world.&nbsp; What is it?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, we don’t.&nbsp; I have to go see the King of Jordan.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, to the best of my knowledge &#8212; and I’m getting a report tomorrow morning on this, a detailed report &#8212; my understanding is that the Chinese government, not unlike the Russian government, is not doing this themselves, but are protecting those who are doing it and maybe even accommodating them being able to do it.&nbsp; That may be the difference.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should the Olympics go forward, Mr. President?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They are.<br><br>12:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on Guantanamo Bay</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/19/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-guantanamo-bay/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 16:24:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24403</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 9:04 A.M. EDT SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Good morning, everyone. Thanks for participating in today’s call, which is on background and attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221; The contents of this call are embargoed until completion of the call. For your awareness, the leaders on the call this morning are [senior administration officials]. A reminder, though:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>9:04 A.M. EDT<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Good morning, everyone. Thanks for participating in today’s call, which is on background and attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official.&#8221;<br> <br>The contents of this call are embargoed until completion of the call. For your awareness, the leaders on the call this morning are [senior administration officials]. A reminder, though: For purposes of this call, they are &#8220;senior administration [official] 1&#8221; and &#8220;senior administration official 2.&#8221;<br> <br>With that, we turn it over to SAO-1.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Hi. Good morning, and thank you for joining us today as we announce news related to Guantanamo Bay Detention Facility. Today, the Biden administration announces that, earlier this morning, Abdul Latif Nasir has been repatriated to the Kingdom of Morocco.<br> <br>The United States is grateful to the Kingdom of Morocco for its willingness to support ongoing U.S. efforts to close the Guantanamo Bay Detention Facility.<br> <br>You may recall that, in 2016, the Periodic Review Board process determined that law of war detention of Abdul Latif Nasir no longer remained necessary to protect against a continuing significant threat to the national security of the United States. Therefore, the Periodic Review Board recommended that Mr. Nasir be authorized for repatriation to his native country of Morocco, subject to security and humane treatment assurances.<br> <br>However, the steps necessary to effectuate that repatriation were unable to be concluded prior to the end of the Obama administration.<br> <br>On June 17th of this year, the Department of Defense notified Congress of its intent to repatriate Mr. Nasir to Morocco, and, in consultation with our Moroccan partners, we have undertaken a responsible transfer.<br> <br>The Biden administration remains dedicated to a deliberate and thorough process focused on responsibly reducing the detainee population and ultimately closing of the Guantanamo facility.<br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: All right. With that, we’ll turn it over to SAO-2 for brief remarks.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Good morning, and thank you for joining us. The Periodic Review Board &#8212; or &#8220;PRB&#8221; &#8212; process is a discretionary, interagency process established by Executive Order 13567 to determine whether the law of war detention of a particular detainee remains necessary to protect against a continuing significant threat to the security of the United States.<br> <br>The PRB membership includes a cross-section of the national security community. Each panel consists of one senior career official from each of the Departments of Defense, Homeland Security, Justice, and State; the Joint Staff; and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence. The PRB’s decisions are subject to review by the Review Committee, comprised of the principals of those departments and agencies.<br> <br>The Department of Defense developed and administers the Periodic Review Board process for eligible Guantanamo Bay detainees, including the provision of personal representatives to assist the detainees in the process. Detainees may also have the assistance of private counsel in the process at no expense to the government.<br> <br>In making a determination as to the eligibility for transfer, the Board is given access to a comprehensive, up-to-date assessment of the information about the detainee: information submitted in any previous PRB hearings; any statements from the detainee, family members, and the detainee’s personal representative and personal counsel; medical information about the detainee, including mental health information; and an assessment of conditions in the detainee’s home country.<br> <br>The PRB assesses that information together with the detainee’s testimony at the hearing, should he choose to participate, to determine whether continued detention remains necessary to address a continuing significant threat.<br> <br>This transfer we are discussing today was certified by the Secretary of Defense in accordance with the requirements as outlined in the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016, and Congress was appropriately notified.<br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: And with that, we can go ahead and open up for questions.<br> <br>Q  Hi, guys. Thanks for doing this. Can you tell us anything about whether this is any kind of beginning of an acceleration of trying to repatriate more Guantanamo prisoners? And can you tell us more about military prosecutors asking, a couple days ago, to wipe from the record, you know, information gleaned from torture and that decision? Thanks very much.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, thanks. This is SAO-1. So, I will say that, at the present moment, 10 detainees &#8212; there are 39 detainees remaining at Guantanamo Bay; 10 detainees have been recommended for transfer by the Periodic Review Board. We are continuing to rely on that PRB process to determine whether law of war detention remains necessary to protect against a continuing significant threat to the national security of the U.S.<br> <br>But for those detainees that have been recommended for transfer, the administration is very much focused on looking to pursue transfer, but I&#8217;m not able to get into the specifics of the process underway.<br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>Q  Hi, thanks. I’m just going to try that again. How many &#8212; of the 10 that’s been recommended for transfer &#8212; how many is the administration, I guess, negotiating over with other countries to take them? And can you give us any sense of what countries you’re talking to? And who has the lead on that for the administration &#8212; like, who is the person who’s actually got point for negotiating to transfer people (inaudible)?<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah. Sure. So, again, I’m not able to share specifics of the state of diplomatic negotiations at present. But, again, we’re very much focused on the (inaudible) deliberate and thorough process to responsibly reduce the detainee population, and that does, indeed, include identifying locations for transfer for the detainees that have been recommended for transfer thus far.<br> <br>I want to underscore that, as we’ve demonstrated today, the Biden administration will apply all the necessary diplomatic resources to facilitate the transfer of detainees found eligible. So, the Department of State is the lead for engaging in those diplomatic negotiations.<br> <br>Q  Hi, thanks for doing this. I just want to follow up on &#8212; regarding Mr. Nasir, is he going to be detained in Morocco, or is he going to be released under some sort of monitoring there?<br> <br>And also, can you give us an idea &#8212; just give us &#8212; I think it would helpful just for everyone to have, like, the overall breakdown of the 39 people. You mentioned that there were 10 people in the PRB process or who had been approved. Can you &#8212; and can you say how many are subject to a military commission process? How many are approved for a potential transfer? All of that, just so we have those numbers of the 39 that remain. Thanks.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah. Thanks. And I’m going to have to refer you to the government of Morocco for further information on the status of Mr. Nasir now that he’s been repatriated.<br> <br>With regard to the breakdown, I don’t want to risk getting a number off, so I’d like to take that &#8212; take that back, and we’ll get back to you with the proper breakdown just to ensure that I give you exact accuracy.<br> <br>Thanks.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: I can chime &#8212; “SAO-2” can chime in on the exact breakdown of people.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Okay, thanks.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: So, following this transfer today, there are 39 detainees at Guantanamo Bay. Ten are eligible for transfer. Seventeen are eligible for a Periodic Review Board. Ten are involved in the military commissions process. And two detainees have been convicted.<br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thank you for your math.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Okay, everyone, we have some &#8212; we have limited time on the call. I just wanted to, again, thank everyone for participating this morning.<br> <br>Again, everything is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” Contents are embargoed until completion of this call.<br> <br>[Redacted.] And at this time, we’re going to conclude the call.<br> <br>9:14 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 1285 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/19/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-1285-of-the-national-defense-authorization-act-for-fiscal-year-2020/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 16:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24415</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 1285 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Delegation of Authority Under Section 1285 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 301 of title 3, United States Code, I hereby delegate to the Secretary of Defense the authority and functions vested in the President by section 1285(a) through (e) of Public Law 116-92 on the use of military force and support of partner forces to the Congress.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The United States, Joined by Allies and Partners, Attributes Malicious Cyber Activity and Irresponsible State Behavior to the People’s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/19/the-united-states-joined-by-allies-and-partners-attributes-malicious-cyber-activity-and-irresponsible-state-behavior-to-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States has long been concerned about the People’s Republic of China’s (PRC) irresponsible and destabilizing behavior in cyberspace. Today, the United States and our allies and partners are exposing further details of the PRC’s pattern of malicious cyber activity and taking further action to counter it, as it poses a major threat to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States has long been concerned about the People’s Republic of China’s (PRC) irresponsible and destabilizing behavior in cyberspace. Today, the United States and our allies and partners are exposing further details of the PRC’s pattern of malicious cyber activity and taking further action to counter it, as it poses a major threat to U.S. and allies’ economic and national security.</p>



<p><strong>An unprecedented group of allies and partners – including the European Union, the United Kingdom, and NATO – are joining the United States in exposing and criticizing the PRC’s malicious cyber activities.</strong></p>



<p>The PRC’s pattern of irresponsible behavior in cyberspace is inconsistent with its stated objective of being seen as a responsible leader in the world. Today, countries around the world are making it clear that concerns regarding the PRC’s malicious cyber activities is bringing them together to call out those activities, promote network defense and cybersecurity, and act to disrupt threats to our economies and national security.</p>



<p>Our allies and partners are a tremendous source of strength and a unique American advantage, and our collective approach to cyber threat information sharing, defense, and mitigation helps hold countries like China to account. Working collectively enhances and increases information sharing, including cyber threat intelligence and network defense information, with public and private stakeholders and expand diplomatic engagement to strengthen our collective cyber resilience and security cooperation. Today’s announcement builds on the progress made from the President’s first foreign trip. From the G7 and EU commitments around ransomware to NATO adopting a new cyber defense policy for the first time in seven years, the President is putting forward a common cyber approach with our allies and laying down clear expectations and markers on how responsible nations behave in cyberspace.</p>



<p>Today, in coordination with our allies, the Biden administration is:</p>



<p><strong><u>Exposing the PRC’s use of criminal contract hackers to conduct unsanctioned cyber operations globally, including for their own personal profit.</u></strong></p>



<p>The United States is deeply concerned that the PRC has fostered an intelligence enterprise that includes contract hackers who also conduct unsanctioned cyber operations worldwide, including for their own personal profit. As detailed in public charging documents unsealed in October 2018 and July and September 2020, hackers with a history of working for the PRC Ministry of State Security (MSS) have engaged in ransomware attacks, cyber enabled extortion, crypto-jacking, and rank theft from victims around the world, all for financial gain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In some cases, we are aware that PRC government-affiliated cyber operators have conducted ransomware operations against private companies that have included ransom demands of millions of dollars. The PRC’s unwillingness to address criminal activity by contract hackers harms governments, businesses, and critical infrastructure operators through billions of dollars in lost intellectual property, proprietary information, ransom payments, and mitigation efforts.</p>



<p><strong><strong><u>[United States Department of Justice] imposing costs and announcing criminal charges against four MSS hackers.</u></strong></strong></p>



<p>The US Department of Justice is announcing criminal charges against four MSS hackers addressing activities concerning a multiyear campaign targeting foreign governments and entities in key sectors, including maritime, aviation, defense, education, and healthcare in a least a dozen countries. DOJ documents outline how MSS hackers pursued the theft of Ebola virus vaccine research and demonstrate that the PRC’s theft of intellectual property, trade secrets, and confidential business information extends to critical public health information. Much of the MSS activity alleged in the Department of Justice’s charges stands in stark contrast to the PRC’s bilateral and multilateral commitments to refrain from engaging in cyber-enabled theft of intellectual property for commercial advantage.</p>



<p><strong><u>Attributing with a high degree of confidence that malicious cyber actors affiliated with PRC’s MSS conducted cyber espionage operations utilizing the zero-day vulnerabilities in Microsoft Exchange Server disclosed in early March 2021</u></strong>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before Microsoft released its security updates, MSS-affiliated cyber operators exploited these vulnerabilities to compromise tens of thousands of computers and networks worldwide in a massive operation that resulted in significant remediation costs for its mostly private sector victims.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have raised our concerns about both this incident and the PRC’s broader malicious cyber activity with senior PRC Government officials, making clear that the PRC’s actions threaten security, confidence, and stability in cyberspace.</p>



<p><strong><u>The Biden Administration’s response to the Microsoft Exchange incident has strengthened the USG’s Cyber Defenses. &nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<p>In the past few months, we have focused on ensuring the MSS-affiliated malicious cyber actors were expelled from public and private sector networks and the vulnerability was patched and mitigated to prevent the malicious cyber actors from returning or causing additional damage.</p>



<ul><li><strong>As announced in April, the U.S. Government conducted cyber operations and pursued proactive network defense actions to prevent systems compromised through the Exchange Server vulnerabilities from being used for ransomware attacks or other malicious purposes</strong>. The United States will continue to take all appropriate steps to protect the American people from cyber threats. Following Microsoft’s original disclosure in early March 2021, the United States Government also identified other vulnerabilities in the Exchange Server software. Rather than withholding them, the United States Government recognized that these vulnerabilities could pose systemic risk and the National Security Agency notified Microsoft to ensure patches were developed and released to the private sector. We will continue to prioritize sharing vulnerability information with the private sector to secure the nation’s networks and infrastructure.<br></li><li><strong>The U.S. Government announced and operated under a </strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/04/19/statement-by-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-cyber-and-emerging-technology-on-solarwinds-and-microsoft-exchange-incidents/"><strong>new model</strong></a><strong> for cyber incident response by including private companies in the Cyber Unified Coordination Group (UCG) to address the Exchange Server vulnerabilities.</strong> The UCG is a whole-of-government coordination element stood up in response to a significant cyber incident. We credit those companies for being willing to collaborate with the United States Government in the face of a significant cyber incident that could have been substantially worse without key partnership of the private sector. We will build on this model to bolster public-private collaboration and information sharing between the United States Government and the private sector on cybersecurity.<br></li><li><strong>Today, the National Security Agency, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Agency, and the Federal Bureau of Investigation released a cybersecurity advisory to detail additional PRC state-sponsored cyber techniques used to target U.S. and allied networks, including those used when targeting the Exchange Server vulnerabilities</strong>. By exposing these techniques and providing actionable guidance to mitigate them, the U.S. Government continues to empower network defenders around the world to take action against cybersecurity threats. We will continue to provide such advisories to ensure companies and government agencies have actionable information to quickly defend their networks and protect their data.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>The Biden Administration is working around the clock to modernize Federal networks and improve the nation’s cybersecurity, including of critical infrastructure.</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>The Administration has </strong><strong>funded five cybersecurity modernization efforts across the Federal government to modernize network defenses to meet the threat</strong>. These include state-of-the-art endpoint security, improving logging practices, moving to a secure cloud environment, upgrading security operations centers, and deploying multi-factor authentication and encryption technologies.<br></li><li><strong>The Administration is implementing President Biden’s </strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/12/fact-sheet-president-signs-executive-order-charting-new-course-to-improve-the-nations-cybersecurity-and-protect-federal-government-networks/"><strong>Executive Order</strong></a><strong> to improve the nation’s cybersecurity and protect Federal government networks</strong>. The E.O. contains aggressive but achievable implementation milestones, and to date we have met every milestone on time including:<br><ul><li>The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) convened a workshop with almost 1000 participants from industry, academia, and government to obtain input on best practices for building secure software.</li><li>NIST issued guidelines for the minimum standards that should be used by vendors to test the security of their software. This shows how we are leveraging federal procurement to improve the security of software not only used by the federal government but also used by companies, state and local governments, and individuals.&nbsp;</li><li>The National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) published minimum elements for a Software Bill of Materials, as a first step to improve transparency of software used by the American public. &nbsp;</li><li>The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) established a framework to govern how Federal civilian agencies can securely use cloud services.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>We continue to work closely with the private sector to address cybersecurity vulnerabilities of critical infrastructure</strong>. The Administration announced an Industrial Control System Cybersecurity Initiative in April and launched the Electricity Subsector Action Plan as a pilot. Under this pilot, we have already seen over 145 of 255 priority electricity entities that service over 76 million American customers adopt ICS cybersecurity monitoring technologies to date, and that number keeps growing. The Electricity Subsector pilot will be followed by similar pilots for pipelines, water, and chemical.<br></li><li><strong>The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) issued Security Directive 1 to require critical pipeline owners and operators to adhere to cybersecurity standards. </strong>Under this directive, those owners and operators are required to report confirmed and potential cybersecurity incidents to CISA and to designate a Cybersecurity Coordinator, to be available 24 hours a day, seven days a week. The directive also requires critical pipeline owners and operators to review their current practices as well as to identify any gaps and related remediation measures to address cyber-related risks and report the results to TSA and CISA within 30 days. In days to come, TSA will issue Security Directive 2 to further support the pipeline industry in enhancing its cybersecurity and that strengthen the public-private partnership so critical to the cybersecurity of our homeland.</li></ul>



<p>By exposing the PRC’s malicious activity, we are continuing the Administration’s efforts to inform and empower system owners and operators to act. We call on private sector companies to follow the Federal government’s lead and take ambitious measures to augment and align cybersecurity investments with the goal of minimizing future incidents.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on Malicious Cyber Activity Attributable to the People&#8217;s Republic of China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/19/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-malicious-cyber-activity-attributable-to-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24373</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[6:02 P.M. EDT SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Thank you for joining us on a Sunday evening.&#160; So, we wanted to give you an embargoed preview of tomorrow’s announcement by the U.S. government and our allies and partners about the People’s Republic of China and malicious cyber activities. This call is on background, attributable to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>6:02 P.M. EDT<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us on a Sunday evening.&nbsp; So, we wanted to give you an embargoed preview of tomorrow’s announcement by the U.S. government and our allies and partners about the People’s Republic of China and malicious cyber activities.<br><br>This call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the contents will be embargoed until 7:00 a.m. Eastern, tomorrow, Monday, July 19th.&nbsp; By joining this call, you are agreeing to these ground rules.<br><br>Just for your awareness and not for reporting, joining us today is [senior administration official].&nbsp; With that, I’m going to turn it over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; And I echo [senior administration official]’s “thanks” for making Sunday, this evening, a work day, and for joining us this evening &#8212; particularly on a nice, summer day.&nbsp; Really, really appreciate your time, and I look forward to hearing your questions.<br><br>So, just kicking this off: The United States has long been concerned about the People’s Republic of China’s irresponsible and destabilizing behavior in cyberspace.&nbsp; Tomorrow, the U.S. and our allies and partners are exposing further details of the PRC’s pattern of malicious cyber activities and taking further action to counter it, as it poses a major threat to the U.S. and allies’ economic and national security.&nbsp;<br><br>The PRC’s pattern of irresponsible behavior in cyberspace is inconsistent with its stated objective of being seen as a responsible leader in the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Tomorrow, countries around the world are making it clear that concerns regarding the PRC’s malicious cyber activity is bringing them together to call out those activities, promote network defense and cybersecurity, and act to disrupt threats to our economies and national security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, specifically, for tomorrow, three things.&nbsp; First, an unprecedented group of allies and partners &#8212; including the European Union, the United Kingdom, Australia, Canada, New Zealand, Japan, and NATO &#8212; are joining the United States in exposing and criticizing the PRC’s Ministry of State Security’s malicious cyber activities.&nbsp; This is the first time NATO has condemned PRC cyber activities.&nbsp;<br><br>We will show how the PRC’s MSS &#8212; Ministry of State Security &#8212; uses criminal contract hackers to conduct unsanctioned cyber operations globally, including for their own personal profit.&nbsp; Their operations include criminal activities, such as cyber-enabled extortion, crypto-jacking, and theft from victims around the world for financial gain.&nbsp; In some cases, we’re aware of reports that PRC government-affiliated cyber operators have conducted ransomware operations against private companies that have included ransom demands of millions of dollars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, the National Security Agency, Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, and Federal Bureau of Investigation &#8212; NSA, CISA, and FBI &#8212; will expose over 50 tactics, techniques, and procedures Chinese state-sponsored cyber actors used when targeting U.S. and allied networks, along with advice for technical mitigations to confront this threat.&nbsp;<br>Third, the United States government, alongside our allies and partners, will formally attribute the malicious cyber campaign utilizing the zero-day vulnerabilities in the Microsoft Exchange Server disclosed in March &#8212; a number of months ago &#8212; to malicious cyber actors affiliated with the MSS with high confidence.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve raised our concerns about both the Microsoft incident and the PRC’s broader malicious cyber activity with senior PRC government officials, making clear that the PRC’s actions threaten security, confidence, and stability in cyberspace.&nbsp; The U.S. and our allies and partners are not ruling out further actions to hold the PRC accountable.&nbsp;<br><br>No one action can change China’s behavior in cyberspace and neither can just one country acting on its own.&nbsp; Our allies and partners are a tremendous source of strength and a unique American advantage, and our collective approach to cyber threat information sharing, defense.<br><br>Hence, these efforts &#8212; our cooperation with the EU, NATO, and the Five Eyes countries in this effort &#8212; will allow us to enhance and increase information sharing, including cyber threat intel and network defense information with public and private stakeholders, and expand diplomatic engagement to strengthen our collective cyber resilience and security cooperation.&nbsp;<br><br>Moreover, tomorrow’s actions are an example of how we continue to build on the progress made from the President’s first foreign trip.&nbsp; From the G7 and EU commitments around ransomware, to NATO adopting a new cyber defense policy for the first time in seven years, we’re putting forward a common cyber approach with our allies and laying down clear expectations on how responsible nations behave in cyberspace.</p>



<p>And now let me just take a few minutes to talk about how the Biden administration continues to mitigate the impact of PRC’s malicious cyber activities and implement an ambitious plan to modernize U.S. cybersecurity defenses.&nbsp;<br><br>In order to protect the American people and interests, the U.S. government announced in April that it conducted cyber operations and pursued proactive network defense actions to prevent systems compromised through the Exchange Server vulnerabilities from being used for ransomware attacks or other malicious purposes.&nbsp;<br><br>The U.S. government also announced previously that we identified additional vulnerabilities in the Microsoft Exchange Server software and immediately shared them with the company to facilitate the development and release of patches to minimize systemic risk.&nbsp; The contrast between Chinese and U.S. behavior in this case is notable.<br><br>The United States announced and operated under a new model for cyber incident response by including private-sector entities in our Cyber Unified Coordination Group &#8212; the whole-of-government coordination group, run from the White House, established in response to a significant cyber incident &#8212; resulting in increased visibility and stronger public-private collaboration.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We continue to work with likeminded partners and allies to incentivize technological advancement, deploy trustworthy technologies, like open standards based secure 5G.&nbsp;<br><br>The Biden administration is committed to promoting an open, interoperable, reliable, and secure Internet that reflects our values of respect for privacy and civil liberties.&nbsp;<br><br>And as you all know, we’re working around the clock to modernize federal networks and improve the nation’s cybersecurity, including of critical infrastructure.<br><br>The administration has funded five cybersecurity modernization efforts across the federal government to modernize network defenses to meet the threat.&nbsp; These include state-of-the-art endpoint security, improving logging practices, moving to a secure cloud environment, upgrading security operations centers, and deploying multi-factor authentication and encryption technologies.&nbsp; The latter could be deployed fully within six months.<br><br>You will note, once you see the NSA, CISA, and FBI product, how many of the Chinese tactics, techniques, and procedures are addressed with these five cybersecurity modernization efforts.<br><br>The administration is implementing President Biden&#8217;s executive order to improve the nation’s cybersecurity and protect federal government networks.<br><br>As you know, the EO contains aggressive but achievable implementation milestones, and, to date, we have met every milestone on time.&nbsp; And I want to highlight four that are particularly meaningful to enduring cybersecurity improvements across both government and private sector systems, and highlight the partnerships we&#8217;re building with the private sector.<br><br>First, NIST, of the Department of Commerce, convened a workshop with almost 1,000 participants from industry, academia, and government to get input on best practices for building secure software.&nbsp; And then, using that input, NIST issued guidelines for the minimum standards that should be used by vendors to test the security of their software.<br><br>This shows how we&#8217;re leveraging federal procurement to improve the security of software not only used by the federal government but used by companies, state and local governments, and individuals.<br><br>Third, NTIA, also of Commerce, published minimum elements for a Software Bill of Materials &#8212; a first and core step to improve transparency of software used by the American public.&nbsp;<br><br>And finally, DHS&#8217;s CISA established a framework to govern how federal civilian agencies can securely use cloud services.<br><br>We continue to work closely with the private sector to address cybersecurity vulnerabilities of critical infrastructure.&nbsp; The administration announced an Industrial Control System Cybersecurity Initiative, as you all know, in April, and launched the Electricity Subsector Action Plan as a pilot.<br><br>Using this pilot &#8212; under this pilot, we have already seen over 145 of 255 priority electricity entities that the Department of Energy and DHS identified that service over 76 million American customers adopt ICS cybersecurity technologies to date, and the number keeps growing.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re going to follow this pilot with efforts &#8212; similar pilots for pipelines, water, and chemical because they all face the same threat and they all have similar gaps in cybersecurity technology rollout.<br><br>Next, the Transportation Security Administration issued Security Directive 1 to require critical pipeline owners and operators to adhere to cybersecurity standards.<br><br>So, recapping: By exposing the PRC’s malicious activity with allies and partners, we&#8217;re continuing the administration’s efforts to inform and empower system owners and operators to act at home and around the world.<br><br>And we call on private sector companies to follow the federal government’s lead and take ambitious measures to augment and align cybersecurity investments with the goal of minimizing future incidents.<br><br>And, with that, again, thanks so much for your time, and I look forward to your questions.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official], thanks for dropping all this on a Sunday night.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Can you tell me a lot more about this MSS-affiliated ransomware attack?&nbsp; Is it a ransomware group that we may be familiar with the name?&nbsp; Did they attack an American target?&nbsp; Any other details?&nbsp; When did it happen?&nbsp; Has it been prolific?&nbsp; We&#8217;re just so used to it being Russian and Eastern European groups.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, first, Kevin, I appreciated the sardonic nature of your comment.&nbsp; I do have to smile; we&#8217;ve worked &#8212; you know, the team has been working this, especially with other countries to gain their &#8212; to join our attribution for a number of months, and now we drop it on a Sunday evening.&nbsp; So, thank you so much and appreciated the comment.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll try to do better in the future.<br><br>With regard to the ransomware activity, that is indeed the case.&nbsp; This was surprising to us.&nbsp; And in fact, one of the reasons that we&#8217;ve put so much work into this attribution is because it really gave us new insights on the MSS&#8217;s work and on the kind of aggressive behavior that we&#8217;re seeing coming out of China.&nbsp;<br><br>I can&#8217;t speak to further details of the ransomware <s>attack </s>[attacks], but it literally was what we think about with ransomware: a ransom request &#8212; a large ransom request made to an American company.&nbsp; And really raised concerns for us with regard to the behavior and, frankly, as I noted, with regard to the fact that, you know, individuals affiliated with the MSS conducted it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey there.&nbsp; Have you confronted China with this information?&nbsp; And what was their response?&nbsp; And what type of punishment are you talking about doing here?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, the U.S. government has raised its concerns about both this incident and China&#8217;s broader malicious cyber activity with senior Chinese government officials &#8212; you know, making clear that these actions threaten security, confidence, and stability in cyberspace.&nbsp; And in fact, this message is sending an additional strong, united message of accountability to China.&nbsp;<br><br>The first important piece is the publicly calling out the pattern of irresponsible malicious cyber activity, and doing it with allies and partners.&nbsp; I noted that this was NATO&#8217;s first public attribution to China of this kind of malicious cyber activity.&nbsp; So, we think we&#8217;re at that first important stage of bringing awareness and buy-in to this attribution, and focusing us together on our collective security efforts, promoting network defense, and other actions needed to disrupt these threats.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I wanted to ask you about the attribution of the Microsoft Exchange hack.&nbsp; There was some thought that perhaps that could have come earlier than this evening.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if there&#8217;s any sort of explanation as to whether there was a complicating factor that made this a process that took, sort of, longer than other attributions that the administration has made so far.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Eric.&nbsp; Good question, and it&#8217;s a fair one.&nbsp; Two parts: One is, there was really new attributes in the Microsoft Exchange hack in the breadth of compromises &#8212; tens of thousands of systems around the world; in the MSS itself; in the fact that we were also attributing, as I noted, the ransomware and for-profit funds by individuals on the MSS payroll &#8212; that, really, we wanted to have, you know, high confidence in that assessment.&nbsp;<br><br>Second, we really wanted to combine it with network (inaudible) information &#8212; malware signatures, other indicators of compromise. &nbsp;And what&#8217;s particularly cool, we will see in tomorrow&#8217;s CISA, NSA, and FBI releases is it also includes a JSON file to really allow entities to visualize the compromises as well, to really make it more than just flat text.<br><br>And then &#8212; I think, most importantly &#8212; we worked with allies and partners around the world to share the details of the attribution, because there were victims globally around the world from this activity, and to really gain and invite them to join us on the attribution, on the network defense &#8212; collective defense partnership, which we felt was really critical to conveying our criticism and our concerns about the irresponsible malicious cyber activities coming out of China.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks so much, [senior administration official], for doing this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you can tell us a little bit more about what this announcement will look like tomorrow.&nbsp; Are we going to see press conferences on the part of these various countries or simply coordinated statements all coming out at the same time?<br><br>And then can you tell us how the tactics and goals of these Chinese actors differ from what you see coming out of Russian cyber-hacking attempts?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Really good question.&nbsp; So, in the morning, you&#8217;ll see the EU release; you&#8217;ll see the NATO release.&nbsp; You will see us release a White House factsheet that describes this further, and then some potential further related releases coming out tomorrow morning.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, with regard to your second question about how is it different &#8212; really good question.&nbsp; It was one that I think Kevin was inferring a bit earlier.&nbsp; First, showing how the MSS is using criminal contract hackers to conduct unsanctioned cyber operations globally, including for their own personal profit.&nbsp; Now, that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s very significant.&nbsp; Showing the cyber-enabled extortion, crypto-jacking &#8212; again, all for financial gain of PRC-government-affiliated cyber operators &#8212; is significant.&nbsp;<br><br>On the Russian side, to your point, we sometimes see individuals moonlighting.&nbsp; And we see, you know, some connections between Russian intelligence services and individuals.&nbsp; But this kind of &#8212; the MSS use of criminal contract hackers to conduct unsanctioned cyber operations globally is distinct.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks again for doing this and setting up the call.&nbsp; Yeah, just a couple clarifying points.&nbsp; So, is the information coming out tomorrow going to specifically blame the Microsoft Exchange Server attack on these MSS-affiliated hackers?&nbsp;<br><br>And, in terms of &#8212; you said a couple times now these are, sort of, criminal contract hackers.&nbsp; Can you give us &#8212; is there any sort of a better sense about the direct knowledge or insight from the Chinese government, from the PRC into what was actually going on here in terms of was this a freelancing operation, was this on the side, versus something that the government was actually aware of and, in some ways, you know, actually did okay.<br><br>And then, separately from that, I think a lot of folks have wondered why Russia was hit with such a strong penalty following SolarWinds and some other malign cyber activity.&nbsp; And this appears to be really just a naming and shaming rather than any sort of punitive steps being taken.&nbsp; Can you sort of just explain a little bit further why there seems to be that difference, especially given how reckless it appears this operation was?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Dustin.&nbsp; Appreciate the question.&nbsp; So, first, tomorrow, the U.S. government, along with our allies and partners, will be formally attributing the Microsoft Exchange campaign, which utilized the &#8212; the malicious (inaudible) which utilized the zero-day vulnerabilities in Exchange to malicious cyber actors affiliated with the MSS with high confidence.&nbsp; So, yes.&nbsp;<br><br>And MSS is using, knowledgeably, criminal contract hackers to conduct unsanctioned cyber operations globally.&nbsp; So, yes, that is very much with the Ministry of State Security’s knowledge.&nbsp;<br><br>And then to your point about SolarWinds and the &#8212; really the distinction between the U.S. approach on SolarWinds with Russia, and with regard to here: So, we&#8217;ve made clear that we&#8217;ll continue to take actions to protect the American people from malicious cyber activity, no matter who&#8217;s responsible.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re not ruling out further actions to hold the PRC accountable.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re also aware that no one action can change the PRC’s behavior, and neither can one country acting on its own.&nbsp; So we really focused initially in bringing other countries along with us.&nbsp; And this is really an unprecedented group of allies and partners holding China accountable.&nbsp; I mentioned it&#8217;s the first time NATO has condemned PRC cyber activities.&nbsp;<br><br>So we&#8217;re really &#8212; we felt like the core takeaway here is that we&#8217;re making it clear to China that for as long as these irresponsible, malicious cyber activities continue, it will unite countries around the world who are all victims to call them out, promote network defense and cybersecurity working together in that way.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think the final piece &#8212; and I think you&#8217;ve heard me say this many times before, Dustin &#8212; there&#8217;s an “us and them” aspect.&nbsp; And I think it&#8217;s very important that we focus sometimes on the “us” &#8212; that we ensure cybersecurity and resiliency at home.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re putting a huge amount of work into an ambitious whole-of-government, whole-of-nation, and international plan to modernize U.S. cybersecurity defenses.&nbsp; We have the EU, NATO, and the Five Eyes joining us to increase information sharing, increasing cyber threat intelligence &#8212; things like the international coalition we&#8217;re building on ransomware; and really expanding that diplomatic engagement to strengthen our collective cyber resilience.&nbsp;<br><br>So we view that &#8212; the gaining the buy-in, the working together on collective defense &#8212; as really key to defending ourselves from the PRC’s malicious cyber activity and continuing to hold them accountable.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thank you for doing this on a Sunday night.&nbsp; I just wanted to follow up on our conversation from last week.&nbsp; You did not want to really get into REvil and where they had gone.&nbsp; But you did indicate that that it is beneficial to often talk about operations that are carried out.&nbsp; So I was wondering if you could tell us what more you know about why they have disappeared and any possible role by the U.S. or Russia?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; So, Alex, you’re using every opportunity, huh?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>So, first, we are watching &#8212; I think, as many of you are &#8212; some of what we&#8217;re seeing in tracking channels that demonstrate that, you know, at least from looking at the open source information, the REvil’s spokesperson’s account may have been banned from Russian hacking channels.&nbsp; And we continue to see that REvil infrastructure remains down.&nbsp;<br><br>We think that&#8217;s a very positive thing.&nbsp; This is a group that has brought tremendous negative impact to victims around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve continued to convey to the Russian government that we hold Russia accountable for activities occurring out of &#8212; by criminals operating out of Russia.&nbsp; And we continue to look for continued progress &#8212; clearly, not only in infrastructure being down, but in the more enduring way, in criminals who do these activities being brought to justice as well.&nbsp;<br><br>So it&#8217;s probably not a satisfying answer.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; as you&#8217;ve heard, you know, [senior administration official] and others say multiple times &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to turn off this activity like the light switch.&nbsp;<br><br>We know this will &#8212; it didn&#8217;t begin in a week or month; it&#8217;s been &#8212; increased tremendously over the last number of years.&nbsp; And we have our four-part counter-ransomware strategy &#8212; which you all know &#8212; from resilience, to focusing on cryptocurrencies, to working with countries around the world to build a coalition to hold Russia and other countries accountable, to really focusing on disrupting actor’s infrastructure, and funding payments.&nbsp;<br><br>So within that four-part strategy, we view this as a very hopeful progress and steps.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re watching closely for continued developments in those areas.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;m curious if you could say anything about the other aspects of the activity that you&#8217;re attributing.&nbsp; You talked about Exchange, you talked about that particular ransomware example that you saw.&nbsp; But anything surprising and in the broader, you know, series of, you know, the mosaic of campaigns that you&#8217;re attributing here?<br><br>And then, second, did any countries that you shared this information with as part of, you know, rounding up other allies to join the attribution, did any of them decline to join?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a good question, Eric.&nbsp; So, first, anything surprising &#8212; I was actually &#8212; I think what we saw really surprising and new here was the use of criminal contract hackers, as I said, to conduct this unsanctioned cyber operation and the &#8212; really, the criminal activity for financial gain.&nbsp; That was really eye-opening and surprising for us.&nbsp;<br><br>I think the second thing we would say is, you know, the scope and scale of the compromises using the Microsoft Exchange zero-day vulnerability &#8212; tens of thousands of computers around the world.&nbsp; That was really of real significance and was very eye-opening to us as well.&nbsp;<br><br>And then finally, you asked the second question with regard to countries who turned us down &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re expecting additional countries in the coming weeks.&nbsp; So, as of yet, you know, we’re really excited about the breadth of this attribution, the first time for NATO, the really global nature &#8212; you see the Five Eyes, you see Japan, you see European countries.&nbsp;<br><br>So that&#8217;s really significant.&nbsp; And I think it highlights just the number of victims of Chinese malicious cyber activity and the degree to which countries increasingly recognize that there&#8217;s power in collective defense and that working together will be just far more effective in countering this activity.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, again, for joining us today.&nbsp; Just as a reminder, this call is embargoed until tomorrow, 7:00 a.m., Monday, July 19th.&nbsp; It&#8217;s attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m sorry if you didn&#8217;t get to your question.&nbsp; But if you do have further questions, please feel free to reach out to me over email or phone.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, thanks for your time and have a good rest of your Sunday.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I just echo [senior administration official]’s thanks to you all.&nbsp; And have a good rest of the Sunday.&nbsp; And thanks, as always, for just the partnership on informing the broader American people about cyber.&nbsp; We really appreciate it.&nbsp; Good night.<br><br>6:27 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on Nelson Mandela International Day</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/18/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-nelson-mandela-international-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24315</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For the last 12 years, the world has celebrated July 18 as Nelson Mandela International Day to honor the memory of a truly transformative leader and to shine a light on the legacy of South Africa’s first President elected by its citizens of all races. Nelson Mandela fought apartheid, presided over a new, democratic constitution&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For the last 12 years, the world has celebrated July 18 as Nelson Mandela International Day to honor the memory of a truly transformative leader and to shine a light on the legacy of South Africa’s first President elected by its citizens of all races. Nelson Mandela fought apartheid, presided over a new, democratic constitution for all the people of South Africa, and showed the world the power of leadership that prioritized human dignity above all—that lifted up the rights of everyone rather than seeking to elevate oneself. Today, I join people around the world in commemorating and honoring Nelson Mandela’s extraordinary global legacy by renewing our commitment to root out systemic racism and to champion equity and equality for all people.</p>



<p>Mandela’s commitment to justice, peace, and democracy allowed him to build bridges that spanned the artificial lines and divisions that tear people apart. Through dialogue, partnership, and respect for the capacity of every individual, he helped deliver a rainbow nation of all South Africans that was able to grow and thrive—but the work he began is never finished. I extend my condolences to the families of the victims of recent violence in South Africa. South Africa’s efforts to heal divisions are Nelson Mandela’s legacy carried forward, and it is in this spirit we reiterate our unwavering support to equity, peaceful dialogue, and respect for the rule of law.</p>



<p>On behalf of the people of the United States, we honor Nelson Mandela, and his vision for Africa and a brighter world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Senior Administration Delegation Trip to Uzbekistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/17/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-senior-administration-delegation-trip-to-uzbekistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 18:01:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security, Dr. Elizabeth Sherwood-Randall, led a US&#160;delegation with representatives from the White House National Security Council, Department of Defense, and Department of State to a high-level international conference in Tashkent, Uzbekistan to promote security, prosperity, and regional connectivity between Central and South Asia and to strengthen&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, the Assistant to the President for Homeland Security, Dr. Elizabeth Sherwood-Randall, led a US&nbsp;delegation with representatives from the White House National Security Council, Department of Defense, and Department of State to a high-level international conference in Tashkent, Uzbekistan to promote security, prosperity, and regional connectivity between Central and South Asia and to strengthen cooperation with the United States.<br><br>Dr. Sherwood-Randall delivered opening remarks recognizing 30 years of partnership between the United States and the countries of Central Asia, as well as the U.S. Government’s commitment to realizing the region’s potential as a transit, trade, and energy hub. Dr. Sherwood-Randall emphasized the importance of infrastructure development that safeguards the environment and meets the highest international standards, consistent with the aims of the new G7-led Build Back Better World initiative.<br><br>She participated in a roundtable meeting of the C5+1 diplomatic platform for Central Asia, where member countries had the opportunity to discuss the significant challenges arising from the Covid-19 pandemic and instability in Afghanistan, as well as the need to enhance regional cooperation on economic and security matters of shared interest. Members of the C5+1&nbsp;<a href="https://www.state.gov/joint-statement-of-the-c51-on-the-international-conference-central-and-south-asia-regional-connectivity-challenges-and-opportunities">issued</a> a Joint Statement outlining their goals for further collaboration.<br><br>Dr. Sherwood-Randall had the opportunity to meet with the conference host, Uzbekistan’s President Shavkat Mirziyoyev, and also held bilateral meetings with officials from Uzbekistan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, and Kazakhstan to identify concrete opportunities to enhance security in the region, address humanitarian concerns, and increase vaccinations in order to stem the spread of Covid-19.&nbsp; She was joined by U.S. Special Representative for Afghanistan Reconciliation Ambassador Zalmay Khalilzad and US Ambassador to Uzbekistan Daniel Rosenblum. &nbsp;The delegation met with Afghan President Ashraf Ghani and Afghan Foreign Minister Haneef Atmar to discuss the evolving security situation in Afghanistan, U.S. support for the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces, and U.S. diplomatic support for a negotiated political settlement to the conflict.&nbsp; The delegation also met with Indian Minister of External Affairs Subrahmanyam Jaishankar to discuss regional security for Afghanistan and counterterrorism cooperation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. On the One Year Anniversary of the Passing of Congressman John Lewis</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/17/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-the-one-year-anniversary-of-the-passing-of-congressman-john-lewis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 16:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Days before he died one year ago today, Jill and I spoke with John Lewis for the last time. He was in those final days as he was throughout his remarkable life – at peace and full of dignity and grace. Instead of answering our concerns for him, he asked us to remain focused on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Days before he died one year ago today, Jill and I spoke with John Lewis for the last time. He was in those final days as he was throughout his remarkable life – at peace and full of dignity and grace. Instead of answering our concerns for him, he asked us to remain focused on the unfinished work – his life’s work – of healing and uniting this nation.<br><br>Over the past six months in office, we find ourselves often reflecting on that last conversation. For all the historic progress we have made as a nation to beat this pandemic and repair and rebuild the economy, we know there is more work to do to deliver the promise of America to all Americans. That means ensuring equity remains at the heart of our vaccine effort and that health care is a right not a privilege. It means building an economy that respects the dignity of working people with good jobs and good wages. It means ensuring equal justice under law is real in practice and not just a promise etched in stone.<br><br>Perhaps most of all, it means continuing the cause that John was willing to give his life for: protecting the sacred right to vote. Not since the Civil Rights Movement of the 1950s and 1960s have we seen such unrelenting attacks on voting rights and the integrity of our elections – from the Big Lie to the insurrection on January 6th to the new waves of voter suppression and a new front of election subversion.<br><br>John once said, “<em>Freedom is not a state; it is an act</em>.” On this day of remembrance, let us continue to act. &nbsp;<br><br>I again call on Congress to pass the For the People Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act so I can sign them into law. And as a nation, let us act and forge a coalition of Americans of every background and political party — advocates, students, faith leaders, labor leaders, business executives — and raise the urgency of this moment.<br><br>For We the People, for our democracy, for America itself – we must act.&nbsp;<br><br>With John’s spirit guiding us, we must be unafraid and never, ever give up.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on DACA and Legislation for Dreamers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/17/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-daca-and-legislation-for-dreamers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 12:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 2012, the Obama-Biden Administration created the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy, which has allowed hundreds of thousands of young immigrants to remain in the United States, to live, study, and work in our communities. Nine years later, Congress has not acted to provide a path to citizenship for Dreamers. Yesterday’s Federal court&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In 2012, the Obama-Biden Administration created the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy, which has allowed hundreds of thousands of young immigrants to remain in the United States, to live, study, and work in our communities. Nine years later, Congress has not acted to provide a path to citizenship for Dreamers.</p>



<p>Yesterday’s Federal court ruling is deeply disappointing. While the court’s order does not now affect current DACA recipients, this decision nonetheless relegates hundreds of thousands of young immigrants to an uncertain future. The Department of Justice intends to appeal this decision in order to preserve and fortify DACA. And, as the court recognized, the Department of Homeland Security plans to issue a proposed rule concerning DACA in the near future.</p>



<p>But only Congress can ensure a permanent solution by granting a path to citizenship for Dreamers that will provide the certainty and stability that these young people need and deserve. I have repeatedly called on Congress to pass the American Dream and Promise Act, and I now renew that call with the greatest urgency. It is my fervent hope that through reconciliation or other means, Congress will finally provide security to all Dreamers, who have lived too long in fear.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White House Spokesperson Jen Psaki on the Visit of Prime Minister Mustafa al-Kadhimi of Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/16/statement-by-white-house-spokesperson-jen-psaki-on-the-visit-of-prime-minister-mustafa-al-kadhimi-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden looks forward to welcoming the Prime Minister of Iraq, Mustafa Al-Kadhimi, to the White House on July 26, 2021. The Prime Minister’s visit will highlight the strategic partnership between the United States and Iraq and advance bilateral cooperation under the Strategic Framework Agreement. The visit will also focus on key areas of shared&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden looks forward to welcoming the Prime Minister of Iraq, Mustafa Al-Kadhimi, to the White House on July 26, 2021. The Prime Minister’s visit will highlight the strategic partnership between the United States and Iraq and advance bilateral cooperation under the Strategic Framework Agreement. The visit will also focus on key areas of shared interest including through education, health, cultural, energy, and climate initiatives. President Biden also looks forward to strengthening bilateral cooperation with Iraq on political, economic, and security issues to include joint efforts to ensure the enduring defeat of ISIS.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
