<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:13:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Message to the Congress on Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United&#160;States Nationals&#160;Home</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/message-to-the-congress-on-bolstering-efforts-to-bring-hostages-and-wrongfully-detained-united-states-nationals-home/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57836</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order declaring a national emergency with respect to hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United&#160;States nationals. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.), I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order declaring a national emergency with respect to hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United&nbsp;States nationals.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals are heinous acts that undermine the rule of law.&nbsp; Terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or other gain &#8212; as well as foreign states that engage in the practice of wrongful detention, including for political leverage or to seek concessions from the United States &#8212; threaten the integrity of&nbsp;the international political system and the safety of United&nbsp;States nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; I have determined that hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals abroad constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 19, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United&#160;States Nationals&#160;Home</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/07/19/executive-order-on-bolstering-efforts-to-bring-hostages-and-wrongfully-detained-united-states-nationals-home/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 14:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-taking Accountability Act (22 U.S.C. 1741 et seq.) (Levinson Act), the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-taking Accountability Act (22 U.S.C. 1741 <em>et seq.</em>) (Levinson Act), the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq</em>.) (NEA), section 212(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952 (8 U.S.C. 1182(f)), and section 301 of title 3, United States Code,</p>



<p>I, Joseph R. Biden JR., President of the United States of America, find that hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals are heinous acts that undermine the rule of law. &nbsp;Terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or&nbsp;other gain &#8212; as well as foreign states that engage in the practice of wrongful detention, including for political leverage or to seek concessions from the United States &#8212; threaten the&nbsp;integrity of the international political system and the safety&nbsp;of United States nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; I&nbsp;therefore determine that hostage-taking and the wrongful detention of United States nationals abroad constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; I hereby declare a national emergency to deal with this threat.</p>



<p>The United States Government must redouble its efforts at home and with partners abroad to deter these practices and to secure the release of those held as hostages or wrongfully detained.&nbsp; Processes established under Executive Order 13698 of June 24, 2015 (Hostage Recovery Activities) and Presidential Policy Directive 30 of June 24, 2015 (U.S. Nationals Taken Hostage Abroad and Personnel Recovery Efforts) (PPD-30) have facilitated close interagency coordination on efforts to secure the safe release of United States nationals taken hostage abroad, including engagement with the families of hostages and support of diplomatic engagement with partners abroad.&nbsp; This order reinforces the roles, responsibilities, and commitments contained in those directives and seeks to ensure that &#8212; as with hostage recovery activities &#8212; interagency coordination, family engagement, and diplomatic tools are enshrined in United&nbsp;States Government efforts to secure the safe release and return of United States nationals wrongfully detained by foreign state actors.&nbsp; This order also reinforces tools to deter and to impose tangible consequences on those responsible for, or complicit in, hostage-taking or the wrongful detention of a&nbsp;United States national abroad.</p>



<p>Accordingly, I hereby order:</p>



<p><a><u>Section</u></a> 1.&nbsp; <a></a>Executive Order 13698 and PPD-30 shall continue to apply to United States hostage recovery activities.&nbsp; Nothing in this order shall alter the responsibilities of the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell (HRFC), the Hostage Response Group (HRG), or the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs (SPEHA), established by Executive Order 13698, with respect to hostage recovery activities under Executive Order 13698 or PPD-30.&nbsp; Nor shall this order alter the scope of PPD-30, which applies to both suspected and confirmed hostage-takings in which a United&nbsp;States national is abducted or held outside of the United&nbsp;States, as well as to other hostage-takings occurring abroad in which the United States has a national interest, but does not apply if a foreign government confirms that it has detained a United States national.</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The HRG shall, in coordination with the National Security Council&#8217;s regional directorates as appropriate, convene on a regular basis and as needed at the request of the National Security Council to work to secure the safe release of United States nationals held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The HRG, in support of the Deputies Committee of the National Security Council and consistent with the process outlined in National Security Memorandum 2 of February 4, 2021 (Renewing the National Security Council System), or any successor memorandum, shall:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;identify and recommend options and strategies to the President through the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs to secure the recovery of hostages or the return of wrongfully detained United States nationals;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;coordinate the development and implementation of policies, strategies, and procedures for the recovery of hostages or the return of wrongfully detained United States nationals;</p>



<p>(iii) &nbsp;coordinate and deconflict policy guidance, strategies, and activities that potentially affect the recovery or welfare of United States nationals held hostage or the return or welfare of United States nationals wrongfully detained abroad, including reviewing proposed recovery or return options;</p>



<p>(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;receive regular updates from the HRFC, the Office of the SPEHA, and other executive departments and agencies (agencies), as the HRG deems appropriate, on the status of United States nationals being held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad and measures being taken to effect safe releases;</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;receive regular updates from the Department of State on all new wrongful detention determinations; and</p>



<p>(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;where higher-level guidance is required, make recommendations to the Deputies Committee of the National Security Council.</p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The SPEHA shall report to the Secretary of State on a regular basis and as needed to advance efforts to secure the safe release of United States nationals wrongfully detained abroad.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The SPEHA shall, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;coordinate diplomatic engagements and strategy regarding hostage and wrongful detention cases, in coordination with the HRFC and relevant agencies, as appropriate and consistent with policy guidance communicated through the HRG;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;share information, including information acquired during consular interactions and engagements, regarding wrongful detention cases with relevant agencies to facilitate close interagency coordination;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; draw on the experience and expertise of the HRFC to support efforts to return wrongfully detained United States nationals, including by providing support and assistance to the families of those wrongfully detained;</p>



<p>(iv) &nbsp;&nbsp;develop and regularly update, in coordination with relevant agencies, strategies for wrongful detention cases for review by the HRG;</p>



<p>(v) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;ensure, in coordination with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, that relevant agencies have access to necessary information, including intelligence information, on wrongful detention cases to inform strategies and options; and</p>



<p>(vi) &nbsp;&nbsp;share, in coordination with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, relevant information, including intelligence information, on developments in wrongful detention cases with the families of wrongfully detained United States nationals, in a timely manner, as appropriate and consistent with the protection of sources and methods.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; To ensure that the United States Government provides a&nbsp;coordinated, effective, and supportive response to wrongful detentions, the Secretary of State shall identify adequate resources to enable the SPEHA to:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;ensure that all interactions by executive branch officials with the family of a wrongfully detained United States national occur in a coordinated fashion and that the family receives consistent and accurate information from the United States Government, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law;</p>



<p>(ii) &nbsp;&nbsp;provide support and assistance to wrongfully detained United States nationals and their families throughout their detention, including through coordination with the HRFC, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law; and</p>



<p>(iii) &nbsp;provide support and assistance to United States nationals upon their return to the United States from wrongful detention, including through coordination with the HRFC and the Department of Health and Human Services, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law.</p>



<p>Sec. 4.&nbsp; The SPEHA, in coordination with the HRG, the HRFC, and relevant agencies, as appropriate, shall identify and recommend options and strategies to the President through the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs to reduce the likelihood of United States nationals being held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad.&nbsp; The options shall seek to counter and deter hostage-takings and wrongful detentions by terrorist organizations, foreign governments, and other actors by imposing costs on those who participate in, support, or facilitate such conduct.&nbsp; The strategies shall seek to deter any effort to engage in hostage-taking or the wrongful detention of United States nationals abroad through cooperation with like-minded foreign governments and organizations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 5.&nbsp; The Secretary of State shall publicly or privately designate or identify officials of foreign governments who are involved, directly or indirectly, in wrongful detentions, as appropriate and consistent with applicable law, including section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2022 (Division K of Public Law 117-103).</p>



<p>Sec. 6.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;All property and interests in property of the following persons that are in the United States, that hereafter come within the United States, or that are or hereafter come within the possession or control of any United States person, are blocked and may not be transferred, paid, exported, withdrawn, or otherwise dealt in:</p>



<p>(i) &nbsp;&nbsp;any foreign person determined by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Attorney General:</p>



<p>(A)&nbsp; to be responsible for or complicit in, to have directly or indirectly engaged in, or to be&nbsp;responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the hostage-taking of a United States national or the wrongful detention of a United States national abroad;</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; to have attempted to engage in any activity described in subsection (a)(i)(A) of this section; or</p>



<p>(C) &nbsp;to be or have been a leader or official of an entity that has engaged in, or whose members have engaged in, any of the activities described in subsections (a)(i)(A) or (a)(i)(B) of this section relating to the leader&#8217;s or official&#8217;s tenure;&nbsp;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; any foreign person determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General:</p>



<p>(A)&nbsp; to have materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of:</p>



<p>(1)&nbsp; any activity described in subsection (a)(i)(A) of this section; or</p>



<p>(2)&nbsp; any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order;</p>



<p>(B)&nbsp; to be owned, controlled, or directed by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order; or</p>



<p>(C)&nbsp; to have attempted to engage in any activity described in subsection (a)(ii)(A) of this section.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or any license or permit granted prior to the date of this order.<a></a></p>



<p>Sec. 7.&nbsp; (a) &nbsp;The unrestricted immigrant and nonimmigrant entry into the United States of noncitizens determined to meet one or more of the criteria set forth in section 6(a) of this order would be detrimental to the interests of the United States, and the entry of such persons into the United States, as immigrants or nonimmigrants, is hereby suspended, except when the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, determines that the person&#8217;s entry would not be contrary to the interests of the United States, including when the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, so determines, based on a recommendation of the Attorney General, that the person&#8217;s entry would further important United States law enforcement objectives.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The Secretary of State shall implement this authority as it applies to visas pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, may establish.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; The Secretary of Homeland Security shall implement this order as it applies to the entry of noncitizens pursuant to such procedures as the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may establish.</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; Such persons shall be treated by this section in the same manner as persons covered by section 1 of Proclamation 8693 of July 24, 2011 (Suspension of Entry of Aliens Subject to United Nations Security Council Travel Bans and International Emergency Economic Powers Act Sanctions).</p>



<p>Sec. 8.&nbsp; <a></a><a></a>I hereby determine that the making of donations of the types of articles specified in section 203(b)(2) of IEEPA (50 U.S.C. 1702(b)(2)) by, to, or for the benefit of any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order would seriously impair my ability to deal with the national emergency declared in this order, and I hereby prohibit such donations as provided by section 6 of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 9.&nbsp; <a></a>(a)&nbsp; Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.</p>



<p>Sec. 10.&nbsp; For those persons whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order who might have a constitutional presence in the United States, I find that because of the ability to transfer funds or other assets instantaneously, prior notice to such persons of measures to be&nbsp;taken pursuant to this order would render those measures ineffectual.&nbsp; I therefore determine that for these measures to be effective in addressing the national emergency declared in this order, there need be no prior notice of a listing or determination made pursuant to section 6 of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 11.  The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.  The Secretary of the Treasury may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury.  All agencies of the United States Government shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to carry out the provisions of this order.</p>



<p>Sec. 12.&nbsp; <a></a>Nothing in this order shall prohibit transactions for the conduct of the official business of the United States Government by employees, grantees, or contractors thereof.</p>



<p>Sec. 13.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, is hereby authorized to submit recurring and final reports to the Congress on the national emergency declared in this order, consistent with section 401(c) of the NEA (50 U.S.C. 1642(c)) and section 204(c) of IEEPA (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1703(c)).</p>



<p>Sec. 14.&nbsp; For purposes of this order:&nbsp;</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; the term &#8220;foreign person&#8221; means any citizen or national of a foreign state (including any such individual who is also a citizen or national of the United States, provided such individual does not reside in the United States) or any entity not organized solely under the laws of the United States or existing solely in the United States;</p>



<p>(c)  the term &#8220;hostage-taking&#8221; has the same meaning as provided in PPD-30, which is the unlawful abduction or holding of a person or persons against their will in order to compel a third person or governmental organization to do or to abstain from doing any act as a condition for the release of the person detained;</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; the term &#8220;noncitizen&#8221; means any person who is not a citizen or noncitizen national of the United States;</p>



<p>(e)&nbsp; the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity;</p>



<p>(f)&nbsp; the term &#8220;United States national&#8221; means:</p>



<p>(i)   a &#8220;national of the United States&#8221; as defined in 8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22) or 8 U.S.C. 1408; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; a lawful permanent resident with significant ties to the United States;</p>



<p>(g)&nbsp; the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States; and</p>



<p>(h)  the term &#8220;wrongful detention&#8221; means a detention that the Secretary of State has determined to be wrongful consistent with section 302(a) of the Levinson Act.</p>



<p>Sec. 15.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp; &nbsp;the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of&nbsp;Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; July 19, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden Welcoming Important Steps Towards EU Integration for Albania and North&#160;Macedonia </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/statement-by-president-biden-welcoming-important-steps-towards-eu-integration-for-albania-and-north-macedonia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 13:15:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States welcomes the important steps the European Union is taking to advance the integration of the Western Balkans into the Euro-Atlantic community by opening EU accession talks with Albania and North Macedonia. In a moment when Russia has shattered peace in Europe, it is more important than ever to support the aspiration for a Europe whole, free, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States welcomes the important steps the European Union is taking to advance the integration of the Western Balkans into the Euro-Atlantic community by opening EU accession talks with Albania and North Macedonia. In a moment when Russia has shattered peace in Europe, it is more important than ever to support the aspiration for a Europe whole, free, and at peace. A democratic, secure, and prosperous Western Balkans remains essential to this vision. The United States will continue to be a strong and reliable partner as those nations work to defend human rights, strengthen democratic reforms, and uphold the rule of law. The steps that the EU, Albania, and North Macedonia have taken in recent days should inspire all EU aspirants in the region to increase their commitment to strengthening their democracies.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Builds on Efforts to Bring Home American Hostages and Wrongful&#160;Detainees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/19/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-builds-on-efforts-to-bring-home-american-hostages-and-wrongful-detainees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57814</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden reaffirms his commitment to bring home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained abroad by issuing a new executive order (E.O.), Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United States Nationals Home. This E.O. expands the tools available to deter and disrupt hostage-taking and wrongful detentions. &#160;It creates new ways to impose&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden reaffirms his commitment to bring home Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained abroad by issuing a new executive order (E.O.), <em>Bolstering Efforts to Bring Hostages and Wrongfully Detained United States Nationals Home</em>. This E.O. expands the tools available to deter and disrupt hostage-taking and wrongful detentions. &nbsp;It creates new ways to impose costs on terrorist organizations, criminal groups, and other malicious actors who take hostages for financial, political, or other gains and thus threaten the integrity of the international political system and the safety of U.S. nationals and other persons abroad.&nbsp; This E.O. advances the unwavering commitment of the United States to bring home Americans who are held hostage or wrongfully detained.<br><br>In addition, the Biden-Harris Administration is introducing a new risk indicator—the “D” indicator—to the State Department’s Travel Advisories to inform American travelers of the risk of wrongful detention by a foreign government.&nbsp; This additional risk indicator will highlight the elevated risk that Americans face in particular countries and provide Americans with comprehensive safety and security information with which to make informed travel decisions.&nbsp; The “D” indicator joins the existing “K” indicator that covers risk of kidnapping and hostage-taking by non-state actors, as well as a range of other existing risk indicators.&nbsp; State Department Travel Advisories are continuously revised and updated based on a comprehensive review of all available safety information and ongoing developments.<br><br>The executive order will generate expanded and enhanced ways to address the hostage-taking and wrongful detention of Americans abroad.&nbsp; This E.O. reflects the Biden-Harris Administration’s continued commitment to bringing them home.&nbsp; In particular, this E.O. draws on the 2020 Robert&nbsp;<em>Levinson</em>&nbsp;Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability&nbsp;<em>Act and </em>reinforces the Administration’s tool kit in key ways.&nbsp; Specifically, this E.O.:</p>



<ul><li>Reinforces the U.S. Government’s efforts to support families of Americans wrongfully detained or held hostage overseas;</li><li>Authorizes agencies to impose costs and consequences, including financial sanctions, on those who are involved, directly or indirectly, in hostage-taking or wrongful detentions to support expanded and ongoing interagency efforts;&nbsp;</li><li>Directs relevant parts of the U.S. Government to bolster their engagement and sharing of relevant information, including intelligence information, consistent with the protection of sources and methods, with families regarding their loved ones’ status and U.S. Government efforts to secure their release or return, as appropriate; and</li><li>Charges experts across the interagency to develop options and strategies to deter future hostage-taking and wrongful detentions.</li></ul>



<p>This E.O. is informed by our regular communications with the families and other stakeholders who have undertaken incredible advocacy efforts on behalf of their loved ones.  The Biden-Harris Administration appreciates the continued diligence of such families and considers them essential partners in our efforts to bring Americans home.  President Biden and experts across the Administration will draw on this E.O. to advance our efforts and remain committed to reuniting Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained with their families. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and CEA Member Jared&#160;Bernstein</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/07/19/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-cea-member-jared-bernstein/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 12:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:16 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160;&#160; Hello.&#160; Good afternoon, everybody. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Good afternoon. MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160;&#160; Okay.&#160; So today I’d like to welcome Jared Bernstein, member of the Council of Economic Advisers, back to the briefing room.&#160; Jared is here to talk about the strong economic progress we&#8217;re making and the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:16 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So today I’d like to welcome Jared Bernstein, member of the Council of Economic Advisers, back to the briefing room.&nbsp; Jared is here to talk about the strong economic progress we&#8217;re making and the enormous opportunities Congress has ahead to continue that progress.<br><br>We’re really glad to have him here again.&nbsp; And, Jared, I welcome you back to the podium.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, thank you so much.&nbsp; I have an opening statement, after which I&#8217;ll take questions.</p>



<p>President Biden, who grew up in a family where the price of gas was a kitchen table issue, has elevated easing price pressures as his top economic priority.&nbsp; We economists think of this in terms of inflation, inflationary expectations, interest rate changes &#8212; a vast array of complicated concepts and measurements.</p>



<p>But the fact is that it comes down to affordability and the need among American households for a bit of breathing room in making ends meet.&nbsp; Therefore, we&#8217;re very happy to report that the current drop in the price of gas, down 50 cents per gallon over the past 34 days, is one of the fastest decline in retail gas prices in a decade.</p>



<p>At current prices, the average American driver will spend about $25 per month less on gasoline than they would have if prices had stayed at their June peak.&nbsp; Economy wide, that means American drivers are saving around $190 million each day from lower gas prices.&nbsp; And since gasoline prices affect the prices of other goods and services through transportation costs &#8212; food is a good example &#8212; both households that drive and households that don&#8217;t yield some benefit from lower gasoline prices.</p>



<p>Now, the decline in retail gas price is not a daily blip.&nbsp; The chart behind me shows that gasoline prices have declined every single day for the past 34 days.&nbsp; Just yesterday, we witnessed the largest single-day decline in national gas prices since 2008.</p>



<p>As we all know, in contrast to the, quote, “law of one price” they teach in Econ 101, gas prices vary from place to place.&nbsp; But according to an industry analyst, around 20,000 gas stations across over 30 states are now charging less than $4 per gallon.</p>



<p>Now, we know this is a volatile market; that&#8217;s one reason we&#8217;re highlighting a trend here and not a blip.&nbsp; But if you look at the about $20 decline in the price of oil since early June, as well as the drop in &#8212; that&#8217;s on the next chart &#8212; as well as the drop in the wholesale gas price, we think it&#8217;s reasonable to expect more gas stations to lower their prices in response to lower input costs and thus, barring unforeseen market disruptions, to see average prices fall below $4 per gallon in more places in coming weeks.</p>



<p>While there&#8217;s a lot that goes into setting the global oil and gas price, the historic actions taken by President Biden to address the impact of Putin&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine have helped and continue to help to increase the global supply of oil and therefore are in the mix of factors driving down the price.</p>



<p>Because the President&#8217;s announcement on releasing 180 million barrels from our Strategic Petroleum Reserve and another 60 million from our global partners was back in March, I suspect there are people who forget about this critically important intervention in energy markets.&nbsp; But this action is very much in play in today&#8217;s market, currently releasing a record 1 million barrels of oil per day on average and 84 million barrels so far.</p>



<p>These releases have had an outsized effect at a time when the market is especially tight.&nbsp; In fact, as one leading oil market analyst put it, quote, “The U.S. has become the world&#8217;s oil barrel of last resort, single handedly keeping prices in the energy market from exploding even higher by selling a large chunk of its Strategic Petroleum Reserve.”&nbsp; End quote.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Two further points before I take &#8212; we take your questions.</p>



<p>As gas prices are coming down, our labor market, which is where working-age families get most of their income, remains historically very strong.&nbsp; Job gains continue to come in at historically high levels.&nbsp; Private sector employment has surpassed its prior peak.&nbsp; And the jobless rate has been at 3.6 percent &#8212; just about its pre-pandemic level &#8212; for four months in a row.</p>



<p>As someone who has carefully tracked labor market recoveries for decades, I assure you that this one is already in the record books for the speed of its recovery.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s no question that the American Rescue Plan, with its shots in arms and checks in pockets, helped to achieve that goal.</p>



<p>Finally, while the lower gas price creates some much-needed breathing room, American households need a lot more.&nbsp; Congress has enormous opportunities to help by continuing progress on both prescription drug costs, the cost of health coverage, and long-term growth with CHIPS Act.</p>



<p>I cannot overemphasize the importance, at this moment in our economic expansion, for taking action on these crucial supports for family budgets and for long-term growth and economic security.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And Karine will call on folks.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Jared, is the administration preparing for a recession?&nbsp; And how do you react to companies, like Apple, and banks saying today that they intend to slow hiring because the economy is slowing?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So let me tell you a little bit about the way the National Bureau of Economic Research Business Cycle Dating Committee &#8212; that&#8217;s the group that decides recessions &#8212; makes their call.</p>



<p>They weigh a couple of variables pretty heavily, and one of them is payroll employment.&nbsp; Now, based on payroll employment &#8212; which, by the way, of course, relates to the unemployment rate, 3.6 percent &#8212; an historically very low unemployment rate for the past four months &#8212; those kinds of statistics are anything but recessionary.</p>



<p>Now, that&#8217;s very much a look at the job market today.</p>



<p>Slightly more forward-looking is: If you look at consumers &#8212; and, by the way, the bank reports, I thought, had this in their earnings reports &#8212; they talked about the strength of the American consumer.&nbsp; If you look at retail sales from just last week, you&#8217;ll see American consumers still helping to fuel an economy that&#8217;s delivering really remarkable job gains.</p>



<p>So I think &#8212; and, by the way, that in itself relates to something I kind of referenced in my opening comments: the fact that not only do people have the benefit of an historically strong job market behind them, a real tailwind in this economy, many also still have excess savings; this is one of the things that’s helping to fuel consumer spending, which, again, is 70 percent of our economy.</p>



<p>So I think if you look at the strength of the current economy, if you look at the strength of the labor market, if you look at the strength of consumer spending, you would conclude that where we are right now remains solidly within expansion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just one follow-up to that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we all remember, a year ago, other colleagues of yours stood here and said inflation was transitory and was not going to last, and it was certainly not going to go up to where we are now.&nbsp; Do you think it&#8217;s possible in a couple of months you might regret standing here and saying we&#8217;re not about to be in a recession?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, I want to be very clear what I&#8217;m saying.&nbsp; What I&#8217;m saying is that based on &#8212; based on consumer spending, based on payroll employment, based on where the unemployment rate is, I think we can confidently say that these numbers that we&#8217;re posting are very much inconsistent with a recessionary call, given where we are right now.</p>



<p>I think that is the most accurate way to assess the answer to that question.</p>



<p>When it comes to transitory, I think the answer there is that we were careful, when we were talking about that, to consistently reference the forecasts that were out there, the view on inflation’s trajectory by not only pretty much every forecaster we could find, but of course, the Federal Reserve as well.</p>



<p>And so this was a period where we, you know, hadn&#8217;t seen new variants of the &#8212; of the virus; where the war in Ukraine, of course, was not yet a reality.</p>



<p>So I think that if you look at the &#8212; look at the general trajectory of where the forecasts were pointing in there, that was generally the way in which we tried to talk about that.&nbsp; And I think that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s worth going back and seeing.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, MJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jared, Senator Manchin said that he is a no-go on the climate deal because he has concerns about inflation.&nbsp; Is there a scenario where you all try to wait for better inflation news and then try again on that front?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, let me just start by saying, you know, “better inflation news,” I mean, that&#8217;s a &#8212; again, getting into a level of forecasting that I&#8217;m not going to do in this period of uncertainty.</p>



<p>What I can very much assure you, though, is that the price of gas is considerably lower in July than it was in June, and this is something the President referenced when the June CPI report came out.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re talking about, as I mentioned in my opening comments, a situation where the price of gas is falling at about the fastest rate it has in a decade and where more than 20,000 gas stations now are selling gas for less than $4 a gallon.  That will show up as some easing of prices.   <br><br>I think when it comes to reconciliation, the President has a view that was very clearly laid out in a statement last Friday: He will always follow a legislative path to get the deal done for the American people to deliver the kind of relief, both near term and long term, that he came here to administer.  But if &#8212; if that &#8212; if part of that legislative path to reconciliation closes, we have other options.<br><br>We can certainly pursue reconciliation with two critically important policies &#8212; lowering the cost of prescription drugs and lowering the cost of health insurance premiums to folks who get that from the &#8212; from the exchanges.<br><br>Particularly on the &#8212; those are both really important.  Let me say a couple of words about them.<br><br>When you&#8217;re talking about the exchanges, you&#8217;re talking about 13 million people who are looking at a potential increase in their average premiums of $800 a year.<br><br>Now, the Center on Budget, where I used to work, did a calculation showing that for a couple 60 years old with $45,000 &#8212; so not rolling in dough, exactly &#8212; failing to extend these enhanced premiums would raise their premium costs by $1,900. <br><br>Now let&#8217;s talk about prescription drugs for a second.  Presidents from both parties have long tried to accomplish this critically important measure to stop prohibiting Medicare from competing in &#8212; in the market to lower drug prices for our seniors.<br><br>Now, I think you have to ask yourself why it is that in other countries people pay two to three times less than we do for the same drugs.  The same pill costs two to three times more here than it does there.<br><br>The relief that we could deliver to our seniors, from allowing &#8212; allowing prescription drugs to compete, as the President has stressed, is not just essential for their living standards and their wellbeing; it is a way to actually ease inflationary pressures.<br><br>So this is a very clear choice of whether you stand with Big Pharma or whether you stand with American seniors and the Medicare program &#8212; which, by the way, would be $100 billion better off over 10 years if we can achieve this in reconciliation.<br><br>Now, the Democrats appear to be aligned on that.  And that &#8212; that, along with the &#8212; with the premium coverage, would be an absolutely huge win for reconciliation.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Ashley.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Following up on Jeff&#8217;s question about transitory inflation, I&#8217;m curious what made the White House realize that the phrase was inaccurate and also politically problematic.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I think it has to do with the &#8212; I&#8217;m going to use an economics word &#8212; the periodicity, which is &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The what?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I’m &#8212; see, this is &#8212; this is why you do a better job than I do.<br><br>I think it has to do with the ambiguity about the length of that word is what it has to do with.&nbsp; I think it has to do with the ambiguity about the length of that word.<br><br>Some people hear “transitory,” and they&#8217;re going to think weeks and months.&nbsp; Others hear “transitory” &#8212; particularly, probably, economists who are used to the broader ups and downs of cycles &#8212; and think longer periods.<br><br>And I think the lack of specificity about the cadence that was implied by that word &#8212; the temporal cadence implied by that word &#8212; led to a level of ambiguity that wasn&#8217;t serving the debate very well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what about just the second part about “politically problematic”?&nbsp; Was that something you were hearing from voters, seeing show up in polls that that language was hurting the President (inaudible)?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I think that when it comes to, you know, politically problematic, you&#8217;ve heard the President say in recent days that this is &#8212; that the inflation is unacceptably high and that bringing it down is his absolute number one domestic priority.&nbsp; And I think that that is all you need to know in terms of what he is dispatching his economics team to do in that front.<br><br>Now, I also think &#8212; and let&#8217;s not lose this, because I think it&#8217;s really important, and this is why I tried to focus in on my comments at the top &#8212; is that his actions &#8212; this is &#8212; this is not just forward-looking; it is, but it&#8217;s not just forward-looking.&nbsp; Actions he has taken thus far are providing real relief to the American people, okay?<br><br>His release of oil from the Strategic Reserves, his increase in E15 ethanol &#8212; these are not the only reasons that the price is behaving as you saw in those charts, but they are in the mix.<br><br>The President&#8217;s actions taken thus far are helping to provide real relief, real breathing room for the American consumers at the pump.<br><br>So this is not just an aspirational goal of this President.&nbsp; This is something he and his team are actively working on.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; In the back.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, sir.&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; The first quick one is &#8212; I guess, does the council have an estimate for how much the administration&#8217;s regulatory changes have combatted or contributed to regulation &#8212; to inflation thus far?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I think, in many ways, we&#8217;ve been talking about a lot of that already.&nbsp; I mean, I just mentioned the E15 ethanol waiver, so that&#8217;s a waiver that helps increase the supply of gas &#8212; gasoline, particularly in the Midwest.<br><br>I think, certainly, if you broaden, sort of, the regulatory scope to consider executive actions and rule changes, you see a lot more.&nbsp; I mentioned the Strategic Reserve release.<br><br>We&#8217;ve talked &#8212; we haven&#8217;t talked about this yet, but the President has made real progress in helping to ameliorate food price pressures through issues that include double cropping, taking action on fertilizer prices, ocean shipping.<br><br>So all of these are actions that he&#8217;s taken.&nbsp; In some cases, they&#8217;ve involved legislation, but in many cases they haven&#8217;t.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then my second question: Tomorrow marks the one-year anniversary of President Biden insisting that high prices and inflation, in the President&#8217;s words, were “expected to be temporary.”&nbsp; A lot of my colleagues have asked similar questions, but I&#8217;m wondering how much faith can the American public put in future White House assessments about the economy, about inflation after they saw that inflation number increase month after month, and before the Russian invasion of Ukraine?<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Well, let me say two things.&nbsp; First of all, I tried to answer as fulsomely as I could, some of that &#8212; part of that question earlier.&nbsp; But let me ask you to focus on what we&#8217;re trying to talk about today, which is something that is happening in the here and now.<br><br>The chart is not up, but that first chart, which we can certainly make available to you, that shows we&#8217;re not talking about looking around any corner here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about what has happened in the past 34 days to prices at the pump.&nbsp; They’ve fallen 50 cents, and you heard me go through some of the numbers in terms of the relief for American drivers.<br><br>At the same time, we are not stopping there.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; This is nothing close to a victory lap, because we have much more to do to achieve the President&#8217;s agenda of helping families get some breathing room in this tough environment, which is characterized by, of course, such highly elevated prices.<br><br>Now, if you can help people with prescription drugs, drugs that cost two or three times less in other countries for the same pill; if you can help a 60-year-old couple with a $45,000 income not have to pay another $1,900 to get their insurance coverage, you are accomplishing the President&#8217;s goals.<br><br>Now, to do that, we need Congress to align and work with us.&nbsp; And, you know, Democrats &#8212; many Democrats are there when it comes to prescription drugs.<br><br>This is something that President Trump said he wanted to achieve.&nbsp; And, you know, he didn&#8217;t get there.&nbsp; This President is pushing hard to achieve that goal.<br><br>One last point on this.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve talked about mostly near-term relief, because that&#8217;s so important for families who are seeking a little bit of breathing room right now.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s another piece of legislation on the docket.&nbsp; And that, of course, is CHIPS.&nbsp; And this is something that has had real bipartisan support.&nbsp; I believe it got &#8212; I believe an earlier version got 68 votes in the Senate.<br><br>I think it is absolutely and critically important for this nation to invest in domestic production of microprocessors.&nbsp; Again, not only would this be a criti- &#8212; not only would this be a highly favorable investment for growth and for jobs, it would be disinflationary, because one of the areas where we see inflationary pressures is, of course, in autos, which now very much depend on chips.<br><br>To be clear, that&#8217;s not a near-term intervention.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not going to show up, you know, in the next couple of months.&nbsp; But longer term, absolutely.&nbsp; Supply chain, same thing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Aren’t you having it both ways, Jared?&nbsp; Because when the gas prices go up, it&#8217;s got nothing to do with the President; when we see some decline, you want him to get the credit.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Look, I think that &#8212; that there&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s no both-way thinking here at all.&nbsp; I think that there has been a consistent, I think, pressure on this White House to try to do everything it could to ameliorate inflationary pressures.&nbsp; And the President has reacted from the beginning, talking about how this was such an important priority to alleviate these pressures on behalf of the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>So what did he do?&nbsp; He put his head down and got to work, and got us to work, to do everything we could to achieve that goal.<br><br>He then presided over the largest historical release of barrels of oil from the Strategic Reserve &#8212; 180 million barrels.&nbsp; Then he talked to global partners to get them to kick in another 60 million.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So when they rose, it was Putin’s fault.&nbsp; When they’re coming down, he gets the credit.&nbsp; Is that (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah, I very much disagree with that framing.&nbsp; I think what’s happening here is a President who is working tirelessly to address the largest constraint &#8212; probably the toughest constraint &#8212; facing American households right now: the budgetary impacts of these elevated prices.&nbsp; And we’re showing you here today some real results, partially &#8212; that partially derived from concrete efforts he’s taken.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Go ahead, Eugene.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the different economic data releases we’ve seen, they aren’t really consistent with each other.&nbsp; So, out of all of the choices of indicators, what does the administration see as the most important indicators for how the economy is doing?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; That’s a great question.&nbsp; So, there is no most important indicator at the CEA.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A group of indicators then.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah, a group of them. &nbsp;So, at the CEA, we &#8212; we just &#8212; we just look at all of them.</p>



<p>And I think where I would take your question is that &#8212; we don&#8217;t give all of them &#8212; it&#8217;s sort of like I was talking to this gentleman before about the different weights that economists put on these variables when we&#8217;re trying to assess the conditions of the business cycle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think this is particularly relevant in the area of GDP. So, in terms of real GDP, if you look at consumer spending and business investment, you actually see some very solid numbers. And these are some of the numbers &#8212; and particularly consumer spending &#8212; retail sales, consumer spending, personal income, taking out transfers &#8212; these are some of the measures that the Business Cycle Dating Committee look at, and so we&#8217;re looking at them too.</p>



<p>And if you get under the hood of the GDP report from the Q1 &#8212; and we&#8217;ll probably be &#8212; and we&#8217;ll certainly be getting under that same hood in Q2 &#8212; one of the things you see is consistently strong consumer spending.</p>



<p>Now consumer spending is 70 percent of our economy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s actually uniquely high.&nbsp; In Europe, it&#8217;s about 55.&nbsp; In China, it&#8217;s about 45.&nbsp; So, you know, I could tell you stories about my family and some of the orders that I&#8217;ve seen come in from our own consumer preferences.&nbsp; They’re &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; this is a very &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Please do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; This is a &#8212; I won’t.&nbsp; I’m &#8212; this is a very acquisitive nation &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; &#8212; when you compare our consumer spending shares to other countries.</p>



<p>So, when you&#8217;re looking at an economy with a 70 percent consumer spending share, and then you look at a labor market, which is, of course, as I said in my comments &#8212; which is, of course, where most working people get their income; it’s from the labor market &#8212; and you look at the level of elevated savings, which, again, has the fingerprints of the Rescue Plan on it, you get a sense of what we&#8217;re looking at in terms of economic indicators that continue to fuel pretty robust consumer spending.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s an important, I think, element of the current economy.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let’s take a few more.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, a quick one on student loan debt and cancellation.&nbsp; Does the White House believe &#8212; does the White House have any concern that canceling any amount of student loan debt will further aggravate inflation?&nbsp; And what kind of a status update can you give us on the President&#8217;s deliberations on that?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President and give you any kind of a status update.</p>



<p>What I will say are things that, you know, I myself have said and NEC Director Brian Deese has said &#8212; that if you think about the inflationary implications of student debt relief and you think about the &#8212; those of restart &#8212; restarting payments &#8212; they push in different directions.&nbsp; And we think that the &#8212; we think, broadly speaking, that the &#8212; those effects would essentially neutralize.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Nancy.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jared.&nbsp; You said over the weekend that the President is going to look to enact his climate agenda with or without Congress.&nbsp; But realistically, how much of it can he enact without Congress, especially now that the Supreme Court has tied his hands to some degree when it comes to emissions regulations at the EPA?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; I think, realistically, there is a lot he can do and there is a lot he will do.&nbsp; The President will aggressively fight to attack climate change because he knows it&#8217;s one of the reasons he&#8217;s here.&nbsp; And it is absolutely core to transitioning from where we are to where we need to be.</p>



<p>Now, I think I&#8217;ve given you a fulsome sense today of &#8212; that both of the sides of that transition are important: affordability at the pump, yes, but we also have to plot a path to clean energy.</p>



<p>I said over the weekend that it&#8217;s kind of unfathomable to me that &#8212; that one wouldn’t appreciate this urgency.&nbsp; If you look at the costs to our economy of floods, of droughts, of fires; if you look at the global economy and you see the kinds of heat waves that are occurring right now, scientists will tell you all day that this very much relates to global warming.&nbsp; You&#8217;re talking about something like 100, 120 billion dollars a year in costs to our economy.</p>



<p>If you think about the geopolitical costs occurring when a Russian plutocrat weaponizes energy and fossil fuels and funds this unjust aggression against Ukraine with it, you get another sense of just how important it is to intervene.&nbsp; And this all comes from conversations we&#8217;ve had with the President.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how urgent this is.</p>



<p>Now, you asked what can he do.&nbsp; Let me start by telling you a little bit about what he has done.&nbsp; He has taken unprecedented action already to tackle the climate crisis.&nbsp; He&#8217;s invoked the &#8212; and this is non-legislative &#8212; he&#8217;s invoked the Defense Production Act to make more clean energy in America.&nbsp; He&#8217;s jumped-started the offshore wind industry.&nbsp; He has set the strongest emissions standards ever.&nbsp; And it is our firm belief that he can and will continue to do so if the legislative path is closed to him.&nbsp; But he will also pursue that path as well.&nbsp; And this is how important and urgent it is to him.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So then why do you think that &#8212; you know, you just laid out the costs of inaction.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yep.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Clearly, Senator Manchin believed that the cost of action was too high in the face of high inflation.&nbsp; Why do you think you weren&#8217;t able to convince him that the cost of doing nothing would be higher?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;m just &#8212; I just don&#8217;t have a great answer to that question.&nbsp; I mean, I think what we can do &#8212; and, you know, I hope I&#8217;ve been a little bit convincing here in my conversation, but, you know, I&#8217;ve worked for Joe Biden for a long time, and I’ve found him to be profoundly convincing in this area.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, he&#8217;s someone who&#8217;s been in the Senate for decades, so it&#8217;s not like he grew up in a world where climate change and global warming were, you know, the top of the agenda.&nbsp; But his understanding of that, his deep appreciation of the urgency of what I&#8217;ve just described of you is &#8212; is as high as I&#8217;ve been stressing in my comments today.</p>



<p>So, I find &#8212; you know, I, personally, and I think lots of other people &#8212; there were 81 million people who voted for him &#8212; find him extremely convincing on this.&nbsp; And when he says &#8212; you know, when “Fightin’ Joe Biden” says he&#8217;s going to keep fighting for this issue, you know, I think we should all believe him.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Two more.&nbsp; Go ahead, Franco.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; Thanks, Jared.&nbsp; You talked earlier about the importance of the prescription drugs efforts, but you also kind of took a sigh of deep breath when asking the inability to convince Manchin on climate change.&nbsp; I mean, how &#8212; or how is the reduced or the smaller reconciliation package &#8212; I mean, does the White House feel that&#8217;s a defeat?&nbsp; And if not, how not so?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Not even close.&nbsp; I mean, the &#8212; accomplishing the prescription drug agenda that the President has been talking about and underscoring since before the campaign &#8212; I was his chief economist when he was the Vice President lo these many years ago, and he was talking about the importance of it back then.</p>



<p>I remember briefing him on these points about how prescription drugs are two to three times more expensive here; how we could save Medicare $100 billion over 10 years by injecting competition into &#8212; into this &#8212; into this space.&nbsp; That just resonated with him, I think, probably ever since he&#8217;s been aware of the issue.&nbsp; And achieving that would be an absolutely landmark goal not just on behalf of American seniors and their living standards, but on behalf of this absolutely essential and much-loved program called Medicare.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But considering where the original proposal was, I mean &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So, let me &#8212; I see where you&#8217;re going.&nbsp; So, considering where the original proposal was, I want to refer you to the comments I just made.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sure, we will &#8212; this President will always try to pursue a legislative pla- &#8212; path to get the best deal for the people who sent him up here to do just that.</p>



<p>But if that path closes, he will find another path.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll keep working on the legislative path.</p>



<p>Joe Biden is someone who’s been pulling legislative rabbits out of hats for, you know, 30 &#8212; for three or four decades now, and he&#8217;s going to continue to do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, whatever paths are open to &#8212; whatever paths are open to us, we will take.&nbsp; When those paths are closed, we&#8217;re going to find other paths.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how important this agenda is.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jim.&nbsp; And then Kelly O, you’ll have the last one.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back to reconciliation.&nbsp; Obviously, one of the parts of the President&#8217;s agenda had been a global tax deal that this administration has led the world in sealing.&nbsp; But now, because of the dropped tax provisions in reconciliation, the United States will not be in compliance with the deal that it negotiated essentially.&nbsp; How can you possibly expect the rest of the world to follow along if the U.S. is not going to actually be in compliance with the deal?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:  So, let me say a few things about that, kind of warming up to the answer, because I want to just give a little bit of a runway.  First of all, I do want to give &#8212; I do want to give a real shout-out to Secretary Yellen, who&#8217;s worked very hard in this space and has accomplished a lot in terms of working with our global partners.</p>



<p>And I think one of the things you got when Joe Biden came to the White House is a President who was going to reengage with global partners in a way that delivered the progress we&#8217;ve made thus far.</p>



<p>I also want to say something about this idea that has come up in some recent discussions that somehow increasing taxes leads to higher inflation.&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard for me to even put the phrase together because I think it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s really &#8212; it&#8217;s really the other way.</p>



<p>When you &#8212; when you increase taxes, particularly on those the most &#8212; particularly on those at the highest incomes &#8212; so you&#8217;re not talking about people who are liquidity constrained for whom inflation is nearly the problem that it is for middle- or lower-income people.&nbsp; When you&#8217;re talking about tax increases for those at the top of the income scale, this is deficit reducing, and reducing the deficit is disinflationary, not inflationary.</p>



<p>By the way, just a side note here &#8212; I was just looking at some of these numbers in my preparation for the shows I did yesterday: The budget deficit has come down 77 percent in this fiscal year, in the nine months of this fiscal year, from October 21 through June 22.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the largest decline on record over that part of a fiscal year.&nbsp; And I know some people say, “Well, that&#8217;s all just spending coming off of the Rescue Plan.”&nbsp; In fact, spending is down &#8212; spending is down eigh- &#8212; I think I have these numbers right.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Spending is down 18 percent.&nbsp; Receipts &#8212; tax receipts are up 26 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll put these later out on my blog today, @EconJared46.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to put these out, so I have these I &#8212; I&#8217;m pretty sure I&#8217;m remembering them correctly.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About the global tax deal?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;ll get back to that in a second.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; So, deficit reduction &#8212; deficit reduction is disinflationary, and tax increases, you know, fit into that.</p>



<p>Now, in terms of the global tax deal, there&#8217;s a lot of moving parts going on with that right now, Jim.&nbsp; The President remains fully committed to this; the Treasury Secretary fully committed to this.&nbsp; We have a staff that&#8217;s worked on this intensely for month after month after month.&nbsp; And it is &#8212; it is &#8212; any rumors of its demise are hugely premature.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, Kelly O, last question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have one quick follow-up and then one question.&nbsp; On the issue, right off the bat, that Jeff asked about &#8212; preparing for a recession: Understanding that you made it clear that you don&#8217;t see those factors, how important is it for you to give the President guidance on what could trigger a recession so that he can take action?</p>



<p>And then secondly, what have you learned from your national security colleagues about what came out of Saudi Arabia and how that might affect gas prices and your expectations on what OPEC and others might do in a few weeks?&nbsp; “In a few weeks” is what the President had said.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Let me start with the second part of your question.&nbsp; We saw Saudi Arabia say it would work to increase its capacity for oil production.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d refer you to them for more information on that.</p>



<p>Remember, they&#8217;re a key member, of course, of the OPEC cartel.&nbsp; And as the President said, we welcomed their decision &#8212; OPEC’s decision &#8212; to increase production by 50 percent above what was planned for July and August.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s already in the mix.</p>



<p>Now, in terms of keeping the President abreast of these issues, one of the things we do at CEA &#8212; I don&#8217;t know how &#8212; this is one of the ways we spend a lot of our time, and I suspect folks know about it, but just so you know &#8212; is that every economic report that we get, we write up and we put it in the President&#8217;s book: industrial production, GDP, jobs, inflation, every &#8212; retail sales.&nbsp; We, and particularly Chair Cecilia Rouse of the CEA, are in very close contact with the President and senior staff, always updating him on economic conditions.&nbsp; So there&#8217;s nothing I&#8217;ve told you today that he doesn&#8217;t know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so in terms of his preparation for the potential of a recession, he&#8217;s getting advised on that on a day-to-day basis?</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; He is getting full information, just as I hope I&#8217;ve given you today, on current economic conditions and anything we can see around the corner.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you so much, Jared.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you for your time.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; My pleasure.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We kept you long.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Come back any time.</p>



<p>MR. BERNSTEIN:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; My pleasure.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I forgot &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’d be a good Scrabble partner.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; I agree.&nbsp; I agree.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And welcome back to everyone who traveled with us to the Middle East.</p>



<p>Okay, I have one thing at the top, and then we&#8217;ll get going.</p>



<p>So I want to call out a few reports from over the weekend that illustrate exactly what we are talking about when we say the impacts of the Court’s decisions are devastating, extreme, and threaten &#8212; and threaten women&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; This is the Court decisions on Dobbs that came down almost three weeks ago.</p>



<p>These reports also pull back the curtain on what some elected Republicans officials are trying to do by taking away your rights, taking away freedoms, and taking away privacy.</p>



<p>First, before Texas’s extreme abortion law took effect, it was reported that one woman there received a standard procedure for a first trimester miscarriage.&nbsp; But after the extreme law, it was reported that when she had another first trimester miscarriage, the same hospital wouldn&#8217;t perform the same standard procedure.&nbsp; Instead, they sent her home.&nbsp; They told her to return to the hospital only if her bleeding was so excessive it filled a diaper more than once an hour.</p>



<p>This is outrageous.<br><br>Now, another report we&#8217;re hearing: Republicans in Congress &#8212; more than 100 of whom have already said they&#8217;re in favor of a natio- &#8212; of a nationwide abortion ban &#8212; are being urged by extremist groups to focus on instituting such a ban at the federal level.<br><br>So I want to repeat that again: a ban at the federal level, not just state by state.<br><br>So this would criminalize doctors and other healthcare providers who provide abortions in every state across the country.&nbsp; It&#8217;s becoming clearer by the day that congressional Republicans want to strip away rights, starting with a nationwide abortion ban and moving on to marriage equality and contraception.<br><br>With that, I welcome you to your first time in the AP seat, right?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, Seung Min, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple quick questions on the Saudi trip.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if the President believes that the trip was a success and worth the criticism that he faced domestically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, following up a little bit on Kelly&#8217;s question, when precisely will Americans start to see tangible benefits coming from the trip?&nbsp; Is it the next OPEC+ meeting?&nbsp; The President did seem to indicate something in the coming weeks.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So just going back &#8212; starting with your last question first &#8212; and Jared basically touched on this, which is: We have to remember, in early &#8212; in early June, OPEC+, which is &#8212; Saudi Arabia clearly chairs OPEC+ &#8212; made that announcement that we welcomed about increasing their production 50 percent in July and August.<br><br>The conversations that the President had in Saudi Arabia, in the bilateral meeting &#8212; that he actually read out, as you all know, in a press conference that same Friday in Jeddah &#8212; they talked about energy securities.&nbsp; And Jake Sullivan actually said this as well, is that we measure &#8212; we will measure success in the &#8212; in the next couple of &#8212; next couple of weeks.&nbsp; We anticipate to be an increase of production.&nbsp; But again, it&#8217;s going to take the next couple of weeks.&nbsp; And that will be up to OPEC+.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And also, the President has talked, obviously, a lot about his support for a free and independent media, and so I’m wondering why the U.S. press did not get access to that greeting between President Biden and the Crown Prince and we had to rely on Saudi state media for the images of that fist bump.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, first &#8212; first thing, because I do want to touch &#8212; you asked me another question about what we believe got done.&nbsp; So let me just read off a couple of things there.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll get to your &#8212; your most recent question there.&nbsp;<br><br>So, just so that folks know: Saudi Arabia announced it will open Saudi airspace for flights to and from Israel &#8212; a historic decision that will pave the way for a more integrated, stable, and secure Middle East.<br><br>As you know, when Jake Sullivan and I gaggled on the plane when the President flew from Israel to &#8212; to Saudi Arabia, that was a historic flight.&nbsp; So just want to make sure that we &#8212; we acknowledge that.<br><br>The GCC+3 pledged billions to address food &#8212; food security resulting from Putin&#8217;s war against Ukraine.<br><br>Saudi Arabia committed to support global oil market balancing for suspended economic growth.&nbsp; This is what you were just asking me about.&nbsp; The United States has welcomed the OPEC+ decision to increase production by 50 percent.<br><br>On the climate crisis, which is also part of the agenda, we&#8217;re collecting invest- &#8212; collectively investing hundreds of billions of dollars in clean energy initiatives, increasing our climate ambition and working together to diversify supply chains and invest in critical infrastructure.<br><br>And we&#8217;re doing everything possible to extend and strengthen the U.N.-medic- &#8212; -mediated truce in Yemen, which is the first one in seven years, where 70,000 Americans work and live.&nbsp; And so, again, we&#8217;re seeing the longest peace in that &#8212; there in Yemen in some time.<br><br>To your &#8212; to your first question: Look, we &#8212; as you know, we tried ev- &#8212; we do everything that we possibly can when we go to a host country to make sure that you all have access, that there is transparency, which is why you heard from the President directly and he held a press conference that Friday in Jeddah, as I just mentioned, so that he can read out himself what &#8212; what occurred in the bilat.&nbsp; And also, you all were able to ask questions.<br><br>Sometimes it is not perfect; we understand that.&nbsp; But we want you to know we do everything that we can to make sure that you all have access.&nbsp; We did that with the bilat, by having a pool spray at the top, and other &#8212; other &#8212; other meetings as well.<br><br>So we &#8212; we do our best.&nbsp; We want to make sure, again, that you guys hear from the President directly, you get to see what is occurring in some of the &#8212; some of these meetings that are happening.&nbsp; And we will continue to make sure that we make that a priority as we &#8212; as we continue to do our travels.</p>



<p><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Does the President &#8212; now that he&#8217;s back from &#8212; from Saudi Arabia, does the President still believe that Saudi Arabia and the Crown Prince should be considered a pariah, or did this trip change his view about that?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you heard from the President again on Friday, he made very clear that how he &#8212; that he made his views very clear to the Crown Prince on that during their bilat meeting.&nbsp; And he even said it would be inconsistent &#8212; right? &#8212; for a President of the United States not to speak of our values, not to &#8212; not to talk about human rights.&nbsp; And it would be inconsistent, to be quite frank, of Joe Biden not to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>So he was very clear about where &#8212; about where he stood about Jamal Khashoggi’s death, murder.&nbsp; He mentioned it from the start of their meeting.<br><br>And when it comes to &#8212; you know, his &#8212; his comments stand.&nbsp; You know, they &#8212; he has &#8212; he has been pretty clear about that, about &#8212; about where he stands on the comments that he made during the campaign.</p>



<p>And look, I think one of the other things that I do want to be very clear about is, you know, if we&#8217;re going to talk about human rights, if we&#8217;re going to talk about our values, we believe &#8212; he believes it’s important to have that straightforward leader-to-leader conversation.<br><br>The President has talked about that many times, about how important it is to talk directly and frankly with leaders when it comes to our values, when it comes to issues like human rights.&nbsp; And he will continue &#8212; he will continue to have those conversations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yet the Saudis say that that conversation about Khashoggi never happened.&nbsp; The foreign minister says he was there and he didn&#8217;t hear the President confront MBS in that way.&nbsp; So are they lying about that?&nbsp; And if so, does that indicate that, actually, they are not getting the message?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this: The President was asked this question and he spoke to it directly.&nbsp; And I do believe that, you know, if &#8212; if anyone telling you differently about what the President said, they weren&#8217;t listening to the President himself when he was asked that question, when he spoke about how he brought up the death of Jamal Khashoggi.&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll leave &#8212; I&#8217;ll leave it to what the President said when he was asked directly most recently about that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; On the Uvalde school shooting, was the President briefed on the findings by the Texas state legislators investigating the law enforcement response, the report that was just released?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So he&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s aware of the report.&nbsp; I will say this: It is &#8212; it is devastating &#8212; the report.&nbsp; It adds &#8212; and, frankly, unacceptable &#8212; the report that came out just, I believe, just yesterday.&nbsp; You know, it adds on more questions to how law enforcements reacted, their role on that &#8212; on that day &#8212; on that tragic day.</p>



<p>As you all know, we&#8217;ve mentioned this before and you heard from the Department of Justice, they are doing their own review.&nbsp; And so I will leave that &#8212; their own independent review of what &#8212; exactly what happened that day.&nbsp; And so I will leave that to them on any further comments.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what was the President&#8217;s reaction when he was made aware of this?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I wasn&#8217;t there when he was made aware, but I do know that he is &#8212; he&#8217;s aware of the report.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on oil and gas prices, Jared Bernstein came out, seemed to highlight these prices being down.&nbsp; But many industry analysts think that this could be just a temporary reprieve, that these prices could very well be going up again, maybe even in the fall.&nbsp; Oil was trading above $100 today.&nbsp; How concerned is the administration that oil and gas prices could be on the upswing again in the short term?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, the President is going to continue to do everything that he can to make sure that the &#8212; the American public gets that &#8212; continues to get that little bit of relief.</p>



<p>Look, what we&#8217;re seeing here today, what we&#8217;re seeing in the last 34 days and that 50 cents &#8212; now we&#8217;re seeing 50 cents on average per gallon that has come down. &nbsp;We see, in 30 states across the country, we see a gallon &#8212; we see gas at $3.99.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like &#8212; like Jared said, we&#8217;re not doing a victory lap, but this is important.&nbsp; This is important to note that the work that we have done, the work that we will continue to do is going to give relief &#8212; $25 a month &#8212; to American families.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re talking about nurses. &nbsp;We&#8217;re talking about teac- &#8212; teachers. &nbsp;We&#8217;re talking about firefighters.&nbsp; This is going to have a real impact on their lives.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and so, look, you know, what we&#8217;re looking at is what we&#8217;re seeing currently, what we&#8217;re seeing at this moment. &nbsp;&nbsp;And I think it&#8217;s important to lift that up.<br><br>And again, the 1 million barrels a day from the Strategic Petroleum &#8212; a historic &#8212; historic action by the President; the 240 million barrels that the President was able to get leaders to do; the ethanol 15, which is the homegrown biofuels which helped lower gas prices across &#8212; in gas stations across the country &#8212; all of these actions are important.</p>



<p>Now, do we need to do more as we talk about inflation, as we talk about the elevated number that we&#8217;re &#8212; that we&#8217;re seeing in inflation?&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the President is going to continue to work with Congress to make sure that we&#8217;re lowering costs for the American families &#8212; like prescription drugs, for example.&nbsp; And if we are able to do that, we are on the cusp, as Jared was saying, to making &#8212; to really winning against one of the wealthiest special interest groups, which is Big Pharma.&nbsp;<br><br>All of these things are important to note. &nbsp;And again, we&#8217;re just going to continue doing the work.&nbsp; But also, we want to highlight what has occurred these past 34 days.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, what is the White House&#8217;s strategy now for engaging with Senator Manchin going forward?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as &#8212; as we like to say here, we’re not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp; We &#8212; you know, the President and Senator Manchin have a very close relationship.&nbsp; We will continue to have the conversations that we have been having with him for the past 18 months on a different &#8212; a variety of issues. &nbsp;But again, not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp;<br><br>But we do want to &#8212; want to lift up, you know, what we&#8217;re &#8212; what&#8217;s about to happen.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re on the cusp of doing with the reconciliation bill is going to impact tens of millions of Americans lives.&nbsp; And that matters as we’re looking at healthcare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When it comes to climate change, you saw the President&#8217;s statement just recently: If Senate doesn&#8217;t act on that and doesn&#8217;t take action on climate, he has a contingency plan, which is using his executive authority to make sure that we take &#8212; take on climate &#8212; climate change in a way that&#8217;s going to be effective.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have anything to read out to you on that particular action.&nbsp; But again, we&#8217;re not going to negotiate from here, and we&#8217;re going to just continue to make sure that we deliver for the American public.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you feel like Senator Manchin led the White House on with regard to climate?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate in public here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to lean in or give any &#8212; pull back the curtain on private conversations.</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re &#8212; we are prepared to act if need be, if Senate is not able to include the climate provisions that we have discussed.</p>



<p>But again, what we&#8217;re seeing right now with &#8212; with the reconciliation as it relates to Medicare and being able for Medicare to negotiate bringing down drug prices, that is an important step.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re going to continue to do the work.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And when you say and the President says he&#8217;s prepared to act on climate, what&#8217;s the timeframe for that?&nbsp; Do you wait until the fall?&nbsp; Do you get started before that?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the overall timeframe?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a timeline for you at this point.&nbsp; As you know, discussions, negotiations are currently happening.&nbsp; And so we will see where the Senate lands.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You spoke before the trip about advising the President about reducing contact due to COVID and the variants.&nbsp; And we saw some fist bumping, but we also saw some embraces and some handshakes and so forth.&nbsp; So just for record-keeping purposes, has the President had a negative test since he returned home?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So that&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I would have to check with our team.&nbsp; As you know, he gets regularly tested, as &#8212; as &#8212; you know, as the advice from his doctor.&nbsp; So he has a regular cadence that his doctor decides on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We did provide, on &#8212; on the gaggle last week, I provided that he had tested negative on his &#8212; right before heading out to the Middle East.&nbsp; And then we sent out a pool note, as &#8212; I believe as we were going to Saudi Arabia, because there were testing requirements, and he had tested negative then.</p>



<p>I will work to get that information for you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If we could make certain of that &#8212;</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Absolutely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; since we don’t see him in public today.</p>



<p>And the First Lady of Ukraine is coming and has scheduled for a visit with Dr. Biden.&nbsp; Do you expect the President will drop in on that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don’t have any more details to share with you.&nbsp; I know she’s meeting with Secretary Blinken today.&nbsp; She’s meeting &#8212; this is the First Lady of Ukraine &#8212; is also going to be meeting with Administrator Power.<br><br>Once we have more information on our side on what the schedule looks like this week and if that includes her, we will certainly share that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, I &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, I’ll come to you after.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just following up on something &#8212; something the Vice President said today.&nbsp; Does the President agree with her that the recent Supreme Court decision on abortion access is similar to slavery?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I have not seen her comments.&nbsp; I would like to see her comments for myself before &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The comment was, “We know, NAACP, that our country has a history of claiming ownership over human bodies.&nbsp; And today, extremists, so-called leaders, are criminalizing doctors and punishing women from making healthcare decisions for themselves.”</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, she is correct: Today&#8217;s decisions are criminalizing doctors and essentially taking the rights away from women, taking the freedom away from women, really taking away people&#8217;s privacy.&nbsp; That does matter, and that is important.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And she’s invoking slavery.&nbsp; So the President agrees?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, for me &#8212; I appreciate you reading out what she said &#8212; I need to actually see exactly what was &#8212; what was &#8212; what was said and in what &#8212; in what complete context.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what I need to do as a spokesperson for the administration.</p>



<p>But I will say that second part of what you just said, the Vice President is actually right.&nbsp; I just &#8212; I just &#8212; at the top, I just laid out what women are going through in this country because of an extreme decision that SCOTUS made.&nbsp; Because of what they did, it is going to upend and change the lives of women across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have to be &#8212; we &#8212; now we have to be mindful about contraception, we have to be mindful about marriage equality, because they have made it really clear &#8212; extreme Republicans, ultra-MAGA Republicans have made it clear that that is what they&#8217;re going after next.&nbsp; So that does matter.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then following up about this comment that the Saudis say did not happen but the President says did happen: Did you personally hear the President raise the issue of Khashoggi’s murder with MBS?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I trust the President.&nbsp; He &#8212; he made those comments, as you heard directly from him, during &#8212; during the press conference.&nbsp; And he said at the top of the meeting, he mentioned Jamal Khashoggi.</p>



<p>And so &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you did not hear him say that.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying to you that the President himself &#8212; I was not in the meeting, to answer that question.&nbsp; But the President himself said and laid out very clearly &#8212; and &#8212; and just to be clear, that press conference happened because he wanted to make sure that you all heard from him directly.&nbsp; That was the President&#8217;s decision.&nbsp; He wanted to make sure that he read out what occurred in the bilateral meeting with &#8212; with the Saudi &#8212; Saudi Arabia government.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; so, ultimately, we get back from this trip, there&#8217;s no new peace talks in the Middle East, there&#8217;s no new commitment to increase oil production in the Gulf.&nbsp; So what was the point of this trip?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just read out earlier, Peter, of all of the things that had occurred that we &#8212; some of the do-outs or the &#8212; some of the things that we were able to get done during this trip.</p>



<p>Look, I want to &#8212; let&#8217;s step back for a second and talk about what the President was trying to do on this trip.&nbsp; If you look at this region, the Middle East, it&#8217;s a critical region. The President &#8212; his intent was to make sure that there was not a vacuum in the region so that you didn&#8217;t have China and Russia stepping in trying to fill that vacuum.</p>



<p>And so it&#8217;s important for the United States to make sure that we&#8217;re having those conversations, direct leader-to-leader conversations, and that we &#8212; and that we talk about our national security, we talk about food security, we talk about climate change.&nbsp; All are issues that are important to the American family.</p>



<p>And so as it relates to the oil production &#8212; I talked about and Jared talked about what OPEC &#8212; OPEC+ did early in June &#8212; we are confident that we will be able to measure how &#8212; the success of those conversations that the President had in the next several weeks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not insist on a commitment though?&nbsp; He gets back with no commitment, and the price of oil per barrel shot up.&nbsp; Is that what the President wanted, to go there and have the price of oil get more expensive?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let&#8217;s &#8212; so, again &#8212; but again, we have seen gas prices go down in the past 34 straight days &#8212; go down &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Aren’t they still $2 a gallon higher than when you guys took office though?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; First of all, we have to look at the imp- &#8212; at how we got there, right?&nbsp; You think about the war that Russia has taken on in Ukraine &#8212; an unmitigated war, a war that is brutal and that has had an effect on the price gases going up almost $2.&nbsp; We have talked about that endlessly.&nbsp; And also, we are also in a once-in-a-generation pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So there are outside factors that has led to gas prices going up, to food prices going up, to inflation going up.&nbsp; So that is really important.</p>



<p>What we have seen in the last 34 days is that gas prices have gone down by 50 &#8212; on average, by 50 cents a gallon.&nbsp; That matters.&nbsp; That matters to teachers, that matters to firefighters, that matters to nurses, that matters to everyday people.&nbsp; And the President is going to continue to do the work to make sure the prices go down.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to go &#8212; I&#8217;m going to continue, Peter.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Actually, let me try and go to people I haven&#8217;t called on.&nbsp; Go ahead, Jenny.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Jared was just talking about the broader reconciliation bill, which would have increased taxes on the wealthy, and he said this is not something that he views as inflationary.&nbsp; You know, you guys have talked about how this would reduce the deficit.</p>



<p>So with Senator Manchin saying his exact, you know, concern with doing a bill like this is inflation, does the White House regard that claim as credible?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: We have heard from economic experts out there.&nbsp; We have heard from even Jason Furman, folks who are critical of us who have said that &#8212; said the opposite: that the President&#8217;s plan on reconciliation will actually bring down inflation &#8212; an anti-inflation bill, if you will.</p>



<p>And if you look at &#8212; if you look at &#8212; when you bring down the deficit, as you all know, that actually will help inflation.</p>



<p>So, look, I&#8217;ll lead you to the expert.&nbsp; I am not an economic expert.&nbsp; But they have said themselves this is an anti-inflation bill and it will help &#8212; help with that fight and what we&#8217;re trying to do, which is our number one economic priority, the President&#8217;s number one economic priority, which is bring inflation down.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you don&#8217;t really see Senator Manchin’s claim that inflation is why he pumped the brakes on it as a credible claim?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I can’t &#8212; I am not a spokesperson for Senator Joe Manchin.&nbsp; As you know, I am a spokesperson for the President of the United States.&nbsp; And what I can tell you is what experts have said &#8212; economic experts have said.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s where I will send you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on the CHIPS bill, which seems like actually it’s moving forward this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, congrats.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a provision that seems to be a little bit fluid on whether or not to prohibit certain investments if you take semiconductor subsidies in China.&nbsp; Intel is one of the companies that is lobbying against this.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House stance on this?&nbsp; And do you have a message for Intel and companies like that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: The CHIPS Act is intended to bolster American competitiveness and our own domestic supply chain security.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we continue to support strong guardrails, as you &#8212; as you&#8217;re alluding to there, Jenny, which also have bipartisan support in Congress, to make sure CHIPS incentives generate more semiconductor investment here in the U.S., not in China.&nbsp; So &#8212; and guardrails help slow the growth of investment in China.&nbsp; That is why such an important part of the bill &#8212; it is such an important part of the bill.&nbsp; And &#8212; and we believe in strong guardrails.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Ken.&nbsp; I said I would get back to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Karine, on Ukraine, President Zelenskyy replaced his head of domestic intelligence and the prosecutor general.&nbsp; He said during the weekend that hundreds of treason investigations have been opened on new employees of law enforcement agencies.&nbsp; Is there any concern that Russia may be infiltrating Ukraine security networks and undermining the war effort?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I mean, I&#8217;ll say this: You know, we, per usual, don&#8217;t speak to any personnel arrangements or domestic politics.&nbsp; That is not something that I will do from him here. But I&#8217;ll say this: For our part, we will continue to work with our partners in Ukraine to help them defend against Russian aggression and with the Ukrainian Prosecutor General&#8217;s office as they document the war crimes and atrocities that Russian forces in Ukraine are committing.&nbsp; We also continue to support Ukraine&#8217;s ongoing anti-corruption reforms as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Senator Cruz, over the weekend, said on his podcast that the Supreme Court was clearly wrong in overreaching when it legalized same-sex marriage in 2015.&nbsp; What is the White House view on that?&nbsp; Is &#8212; does that raise a lot of concerns?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I’ll &#8212; it should &#8212; it should raise concerns.&nbsp; As we know from the Dobbs decision, one of the things that we saw from &#8212; from <s>Judge</s> <s>Thompson</s> [Justice Thomas] is that they&#8217;re looking to go further, whether it&#8217;s privacy, contraception, or marriage equality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, you know, you all know that this President has supported marriage equality for some time.&nbsp; This is something that he believes in, and this is something that he will &#8212; he will continue to fight for.</p>



<p>I’m trying to call folks I haven’t called on.</p>



<p>Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Sorry.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Did the President urge Saudi Arabia to stop purchasing oil from Russia?&nbsp; Because Saudi Arabia has actually doubled its Russian oil imports this quarter, which is, of course, helping Russia’s cash flow.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything to read out for you on that.&nbsp; As you know, at the G7, one of the conversations that came up when the President was there recently in Europe, in Germany specifically, was how to put a cap on Russia &#8212; Russia oil.&nbsp; That is a conversation that was started.&nbsp; It is continuing on the staff level.&nbsp; And that, as you know, will have an effect on &#8212; on the price of Russia&#8217;s oil.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re continuing to have those discussions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you spoke earlier about the President&#8217;s contingency plan regarding taking executive actions on climate, but do you believe the President can still keep the commitments he made to world leaders on reducing emissions through executive actions if Congress fails to act?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to do everything that we can to make sure that we are taking action on climate &#8212; the climate crisis.&nbsp; And so, again, the President has &#8212; I think Jared read this all &#8212; read this already, but just want to reiterate what he said: From day one, he fina- &#8212; the President finalized regulations to rapidly phase out super pollutants.&nbsp; He jumpstarted the offshore industry.&nbsp; And he set the strongest-ever emissions standard for cars and trucks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is something that is incredibly important to the President.&nbsp; He thinks it is &#8212; it is urgent to act on the climate crisis, to take action.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why if Congress &#8212; Senate doesn&#8217;t act on the climate component of reconciliation, he&#8217;s ready to take executive &#8212; use his executive authority.</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to see who I haven’t called on.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Senator McConnell says President Biden planned to nominate Chad Meredith, an anti-abortion Federalist Society member for Kentucky District Judge position as a, quote, “personal friendship gesture.”&nbsp; Why would the President do that when he&#8217;s vowed that DOJ will do everything in their power to protect women&#8217;s access to abortion?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So what I&#8217;ll say on that is that, as you heard from Rand Paul, he was not ready &#8212; he&#8217;s not &#8212; he&#8217;s not ready to move forward with the blue <s>chip</s> [slip] &#8212; is that process in the Senate.&nbsp; And so we are not going to be nominating Chad Meredith.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was it initially a personal friendship gesture, as Senator McConnell said?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That part of &#8212; of your comment is not something that I&#8217;m aware of.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just telling you where we are currently at this time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But generally speaking, why was the President planning to nominate Mr. Meredith in the first place, given that he has said that DOJ would do everything in its power to protect abortion access for women?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, that doesn&#8217;t &#8212; that doesn&#8217;t change anything.&nbsp; DOJ is going to do everything in its power.&nbsp; You heard directly from the President about that.&nbsp; You heard &#8212; he signed an executive order on what DOJ is going to do and what &#8212; and formalizing what DOJ is going to do, and formalizing what HHS is going to do.</p>



<p>That is something that the President is in &#8212; is very much committed to.&nbsp; And certainly, he&#8217;s not going to back away from that.&nbsp; He wants to make sure that women&#8217;s rights are protected. Just talked about what could happen next, which is a national ban on abortion, which would be devastating for so many women across the country.&nbsp; We talked about what else Republicans are thinking about doing when it comes to contraception, when it comes to privacy, when it comes to marriage equality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is &#8212; this is a very serious time.&nbsp; And we need to make sure that we are paying attention to what potentially could &#8212; could be happening next.&nbsp; And so, again, I don&#8217;t have much more to add on your question.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Is the administration in touch with the authorities in Ghana?&nbsp; I know the &#8212; Ghana declared today their first &#8212; their first-ever outbreak of Marburg virus disease.&nbsp; Is the White House in touch with them?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that last part.&nbsp; The what disease?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Marburg.&nbsp; It’s called Marburg &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Mar- &#8212; okay, let me &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; virus disease.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, let me go back to the team and get more info on &#8212; for you on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, what&#8217;s your strategy in reassuring the international community that, yes, the President met with the killer of Saudi Arabia but the U.S. remain committed in human right?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; so this is what I said earlier to someone who asked me: The President be- &#8212; the President believes that it is important &#8212; as we are talking about human rights, as we are talking about American values, it is important to have those frank and direct conversations with leaders and be very, very clear on where we stand as a country.<br><br>This is what the President &#8212; you heard directly from him when he held a press conference in Jeddah, as I&#8217;ve stated many times at this point today, this afternoon.&nbsp; He made that very clear.&nbsp; He spoke directly, he spoke firmly, and that is a convers- &#8212; a continuing conversation that he is going to have.<br><br>Human rights issues come up frequently when he is meeting leader-to-leader.&nbsp; That will not stop.&nbsp; That will not end.&nbsp; And this is something that the President has been committed to for &#8212; for his entire career.<br><br>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Just picking up on climate, you mentioned that there&#8217;s no timeline on the administration taking action.&nbsp; But does the administration have an executive order or executive plans ready?&nbsp; Or is &#8212; does there need to be a process to consult, to plan?&nbsp; I mean, how far along are you in the process?&nbsp; I mean, how have you been preparing for the contingency?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you at this time, is what I was trying to say.&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to comment on any specific action.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the process &#8212; of the policy process, and certainly don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President.<br><br>But what I &#8212; the point that we are trying to make here is that he is committed to taking action on climate &#8212; on climate change, on clim- &#8212; taking action on climate.<br><br>But right now, I just don&#8217;t have anything to share at this point.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is there anything you can share on what &#8212; how has the administration been in the process of preparing for this type of contingency?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’m &#8212; I&#8217;m not getting ahead of the policy process.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; Can you just say when the President will announce his decision on China tariffs?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I &#8212; we &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything more to read out for you on China tariffs.<br><br>Look, the way that it was handled by the last administration was &#8212; was &#8212; you know, they &#8212; it got &#8212; it was bungled.&nbsp; If you &#8212; if you &#8212; if I’m going to be really, you know, honest here, it was not done in an effective way.&nbsp; China has not done their part.&nbsp; And so, the President wants to make sure that &#8212; that his team is looking at every option, is looking at exactly how to move forward.<br><br>We just don&#8217;t have an announcement to share or anything to preview at this time.</p>



<p><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to go back to Senator Manchin and the energy provisions, he said on the radio, on Friday, that he didn&#8217;t tell Senator Schumer that he was out on the energy and climate provisions, just that he wanted to see another month of inflation data.&nbsp; So if it&#8217;s such a crisis that the President is bent on dealing with &#8212; the climate crisis &#8212; why not wait another month to see what the inflation data, which the administration thinks will be better, look like and see if you can get Senator Manchin on board for legislation?&nbsp; Is the President effectively saying he doesn&#8217;t believe that the odds are good of that happening if he waited an extra month?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp; Well right now the Senate is still hav- &#8212; are still in talks; they&#8217;re still negotiating.&nbsp; And so the President has put &#8212; put forth a contingency plan.&nbsp; If that climate change provision that we have been discussing is not in that Senate reconciliation plan, he will act.&nbsp;<br><br>But right now, we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re letting the negotiations happen.&nbsp; We&#8217;re letting that process continue.&nbsp; Again, we don&#8217;t negotiate in public.<br><br>But again, what we&#8217;re trying to say here is the President is &#8212; is ready to act when &#8212; if needed.</p>



<p><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, because in his statement he said he wants a bill by August, which would seem to rule out waiting for Senator Manchin.</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, look, the process is still &#8212; is still happening.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I’m not going to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; It &#8212; we are &#8212; what is today?&nbsp; July &#8212; I don&#8217;t even know.&nbsp; July 18th?&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And so, let &#8212; we&#8217;re going to let &#8212; let the Senate work on the reconc- &#8212; reconciliation bill, let them have the &#8212; the conversations and negotiations.&nbsp; I’m just not going to get ahead of that at this time.</p>



<p><br>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead, Ashley.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Asking sort of the flip side of Jim&#8217;s question, I&#8217;m curious: Was there anything Senator Manchin ever conveyed to the White House that gave you guys any reason to believe that a West Virginia Democrat, in a state that Trump won by almost 40 points, who&#8217;s accepted millions of dollars from the fossil fuel industry would ever support any sort of climate provision?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not going to comment on private conversations.&nbsp; Again, that is not something that we do here.&nbsp; We say this all the time.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to comment on any back-and-forth that has occurred with Senator Manchin or any other congressional member.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to let the Senate continue to negotiate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When it comes to what we are seeing right now with the prescription drugs &#8212; I have said this; Jared said this &#8212; that is &#8212; that is &#8212; we&#8217;re on the cusp of a big win here, which is incredibly important for tens of millions of Americans, as we speak about Medicare and them being allowed to negotiate drug prices.</p>



<p><br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So just following up briefly: More broadly, I mean, do you have any reason to believe that you didn&#8217;t waste your time trying to get Senator Manchin on board for any sort of climate, you know, legislation?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to get into private conversations.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; All right, go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; I would like to ask about Moscow using energy as a weapon in Europe.&nbsp; There is a growing fear that Russia will not restore natural gas deliveries to Europe after its ongoing annual maintenance of Nord Stream 1, which could lead to a serious crisis in Europe, to gas rati- &#8212; rationing.&nbsp; How concerned is the President that it may weaken Europe&#8217;s resolve?&nbsp; And what the U.S. is doing to help?</p>



<p><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So a couple of things.&nbsp; I just want to lay this down, because it&#8217;s an important question that we want to address.<br><br>So following, as you know, the further invasion of Ukraine, Russia continues to use natural &#8212; natural gas as a political and economic weapon, as you’re &#8212; as you&#8217;re stating, Merrick.&nbsp;<br><br>Russia&#8217;s energy corrosion has put pressure on energy markets, raised prices for consumers, and threatened global energy security.<br><br>These actions only underscore the importance of the work both the United States and the European Commission are doing to end our reliance on Russian energy.</p>



<p>President Biden formed a task force, as you all know &#8212; we&#8217;ve announced that here &#8212; on European energy security with EU President von der Leyen.&nbsp; The task force has met regularly to discuss options to reduce Europe&#8217;s depen- &#8212; demand for natural gas.&nbsp; It has also met with key stakeholders to promote the deployment of heat pumps, smart thermostats, and energy demand response solutions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we are also partnering to diversify energy supplies to Europe.&nbsp; Since March, global LNG exports to Europe have &#8212; have risen by 75 percent compared to 2021, while the U.S. LNG exports to Europe have nearly tripled.&nbsp; So, we continue to work with our European partners to reduce the dependence on energ- &#8212; of Europe on Russian energy, to be exact.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that enough to help Europe to survive the winter?&nbsp; Russia may at any point, anytime, cut gas &#8212; natural gas deliveries to Europe.&nbsp; It&#8217;s real fear in Europe right now.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, we understand that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we created the task force, and the task force is going to do everything that we can to make sure that we deal that the depend- &#8212; that we deal with the dependence that Europe &#8212; European countries have on &#8212; on Russian oil.</p>



<p>Look, we have seen &#8212; I just laid out &#8212; we have seen some progress.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to just kind of continue to work with our European partners.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;d like &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I was calling the gentleman in front.&nbsp; Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On abortion: In two weeks, Kansas is going to vote &#8212; they&#8217;re going to be the first state to vote on the abortion issue.&nbsp; How much stake is the administration putting on the result of that election, given the fact that, you know, they&#8217;re going to be (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I can&#8217;t speak directly to any specific elections.&nbsp; Look, the President has made clear: When we &#8212; when we &#8212; when we talk about &#8212; when we talk about choice and we talk about where we are currently with abortion, when we talk about Republicans who are trying to make a national ban across the country, this is very serious, dangerous outcomes that could &#8212; that are &#8212; that we&#8217;re facing with.</p>



<p>And so the President has been very clear: To make sure that Americans get their voices heard and take it to the ballot box, that is the way that we&#8217;re going to see real change.&nbsp; That is the way that we can use our political power.</p>



<p>He&#8217;s going to continue to say that but, at the same time, do everything that he can as &#8212; from his executive authority, to &#8212; to what he can with the federal government, to protect &#8212; to protect women.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then marriage came up earlier.&nbsp; The House is expected to vote on the Protect Our Marriage Act, I think tomorrow.&nbsp; How much work will the administration be doing to try and get that bill through the Senate where it&#8217;s going to face much more (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we support that act, and we &#8212; we applaud &#8212; we applaud Congress for moving forward.</p>



<p>As I mentioned earlier when I was just asked a question about marriage equality, this is &#8212; this is an issue that the President has been fighting for and speaking about for many, many years.&nbsp; And so this is certainly something that we support.</p>



<p><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One of my colleagues at Politico are reporting today that the ACLU obtained, and has since released, records publicly from DHS that show use of mobile location data harvested from apps on hundreds of millions of phones.&nbsp; DHS was then able to use 336,000 location data points across North America.<br><br>This started under the Trump administration, and contracts have been renewed under the Biden administration, basically tracking &#8212; knowing where people are.<br><br>When it comes to what DHS does, the work that DHS does, does the President stand by using location data on this scale, especially in light of concerns of the use of phone data when it comes to period-tracking apps, which the administration has talked about quite a bit?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I have not seen this data, so I need to take a look at it so that I can respond in a way that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s fulsome and be able to answer your question.&nbsp; I just haven&#8217;t seen that data.&nbsp; But I refer you at &#8212; any more specifics on that &#8212; clearly, I’ll refer you to the Department of Homeland Security.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But in general, does the administration &#8212; how does the administration feel about using location data on their &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Honestly, Eugene, I just need &#8212; in order for me to respond to your question, I just need to see exactly what you&#8217;re asking me about and what &#8212; and what the data is.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t do that without knowing the specifics.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And back to the firing of the Prosecutor General in Ukraine, how concerned is the administration, given how closely she&#8217;s been working with AG Garland?&nbsp; And she was also replaced by someone who&#8217;s been credibly accused of corruption.&nbsp; How concerned is the administration (inaudible)?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll say this: Like I said, we don&#8217;t get involved and don&#8217;t comment on any political domes- &#8212; domestic politics that happens in another country.<br><br>We&#8217;re going to continue to work closely with Ukraine on their fight for democracy, on their fight against Russia&#8217;s aggression, and also their corruption reform.&nbsp; As I just stated, we’ll work &#8212; we’ll continue to work with them on that.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll take one more question.&nbsp; Let me &#8212; go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Without congressional action on climate, does the White House, does the President see any viable path for reaching his goal of the U.S. cutting carbon emissions in half by 2030?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that again.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t hear you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Without congressional action on climate, does the President see any viable path to reaching his goal of cutting carbon emissions in half by 2030?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, again, negotiations are still happening, and so we leave that to Senate and see exactly what is &#8212; what the next &#8212; what the process is go- &#8212; where the process is going to land.</p>



<p>The President is, again, ready to act, ready to take executive authority &#8212; use his executive authority if &#8212; if that climate change provision is not included in the reconciliation bill.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics or get into hypotheticals at this time, but we&#8217;re going to continue &#8212; again, to just let the Senate work.</p>



<p>I’m &#8212; MJ, I know you had a question.&nbsp; I’m going to let you go ahead and ask a question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he think that goal can be reached just using executive authority?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to get into hypotheticals.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see where negotiations go.&nbsp; The President &#8212; as you know, as we have said &#8212; he is committed to taking on &#8212; taking on climate change.&nbsp; He thinks that it is urgent to do that; there&#8217;s an urgent matter to do that now.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so we&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to let the negotiations continue.&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not going to negotiate from public or speak to hypotheticals.</p>



<p>Go ahead, MJ.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have two quick questions.&nbsp; First, on the baby formula: The recent data indicates that more than 20 percent of formula products are still out of stock.&nbsp; Just wondering what the White House&#8217;s assessment is right now of why that is the case, particularly given that we&#8217;ve seen, you know, for weeks now, a ton of formula being flown into the country.&nbsp; And does it have a sense of when things will actually start to normalize?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll say this: The federal government has worked in lockstep with private &#8212; private sector to ramp up domestic production and to increase the supply of safe infant formula, which we understand is incredibly critical for families across the country as they&#8217;re trying to make sure that they&#8217;re feeding their &#8212; their babies, their children, safe &#8212; safe baby formula.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is what this is all about &#8212; safety &#8212; and that&#8217;s our priority here, but also making sure that we&#8217;re doing everything that we can to get &#8212; to get that out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re ramping up domestic production, including invoking the Domestic Production Act, as you all know, which has allowed companies to increase production.&nbsp; We&#8217;re increasing imports.&nbsp; Already, the FDA has granted enforcement discretion for companies to import over 524.1 million 8-ounces bottles worth of infant formula, including over 5 million bottles of medical specialty formula, which is important as you&#8217;re asking me about formula and bottles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And third, we&#8217;re enhancing WIC flexibilities by waiving rules and restrictions that prevented low-income mothers from getting formula.&nbsp; All 50 states have taken action issuing more than 200 waivers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, this is a priority, continues to be a priority for us.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to do everything that we can to increase production.&nbsp; But &#8212; and &#8212; but again, we want to make sure that the safety is first.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I just had one more follow-up on the &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Saudi trip.&nbsp; When the President came back from his trip, he was asked if he regretted the fist bump with the Saudi Crown Prince, and he said, “Why don&#8217;t you guys talk about something that matters?”&nbsp; Can you just help us understand why he suggested that that fist bump did not matter?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s the thing: I think the way that the President looks at this is &#8212; is what were the issues, the agenda that was discussed, the policies that were &#8212; that were discussed, and what were the deliverables.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, when the President goes out to &#8212; just across the country and has these meetings, it is very important &#8212; you hear us talk about this all the time &#8212; having that leader-to-leader conversation.&nbsp; This is a President that has been, you know, a senator for decades.&nbsp; He was the Vice President.&nbsp; He was the President.&nbsp; He understands how &#8212; how this &#8212; these interaction works.&nbsp; He understands how these relationship works.&nbsp; He has &#8212; he has experience in it that is &#8212; that he believes is incredibly critical and important.</p>



<p>Look, again, when he went to the Middle East, it was making sure that there was not a void for countries like Russia or China to &#8212; to step into; to make sure that we were responding to Iran; to make sure that he had conversations not just with Saudi Arabia, but 12 &#8212; a dozen other leaders that were at the GCC+3.&nbsp; And not only that &#8212; he was in Israel right before he got to Jeddah.</p>



<p>So these are important &#8212; he believes these are important policies that are going to help the American public.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what he&#8217;s there for.&nbsp; When he goes out &#8212; yes, the region is important; yes, the region is critical.&nbsp; There&#8217;s national security conversations that need to be had and other agenda items that need to be talked about.&nbsp; But also, we&#8217;re talking about the Americans’ interests.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about how important it is to make sure that we are delivering as well here domestically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that is &#8212; that is the focus of the President.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But on that comment, he does certainly understand why for a lot of people, including Jamal Khashoggi’s family or colleagues &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, absolutely.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that fist bump and that meeting with MBS mattered a lot, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll say this: The President spoke to &#8212; he was asked directly about Khashoggi, his fiancée.&nbsp; And he &#8212; you know, our hearts go out to &#8212; to her.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Our hear- &#8212; our hearts go out to his family, of course, and to his colleagues.&nbsp; Of course, we understand the pain that they are &#8212; that everyone is going through.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why when the President came into office, he released the Khashoggi report &#8212; something that the last administration did not do.&nbsp; This is a promise that he made to Congress.&nbsp; This was a promise that he made to the American people, to do that.&nbsp; And he took it a step further to make sure that there was the Khashoggi ban, which is that &#8212; which deals with visa and travel &#8212; and that has been used more than 70 times.</p>



<p>But we understand the pain that people are feeling, but he also wants to make sure &#8212; he also wants to make sure that we&#8217;re talking about the policy, that we&#8217;re talking about the agenda, that we&#8217;re talking about what occurred that is going to help the American public as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll see you tomorrow.</p>



<p>4:39 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with New Jersey State Legislators on Reproductive Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/18/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-new-jersey-state-legislators-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 02:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57821</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened more than 20 New Jersey state legislators, local leaders, and advocates who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights. Today’s meeting in Atlantic City, New Jersey follows engagements about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with health care providers, faith leaders, constitutional law and privacy experts,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened more than 20 New Jersey state legislators, local leaders, and advocates who are fighting on the frontlines to protect reproductive rights. Today’s meeting in Atlantic City, New Jersey follows engagements about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with health care providers, faith leaders, constitutional law and privacy experts, advocates, state Attorneys General, and other state legislators. The Vice President convened state legislators at the White House on July 8, 2022; in Orlando, Florida on July 14, 2022; and in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania on July 16, 2022.<br> <br>The Vice President thanked the state legislators for their work protecting abortion access, highlighting the legislation passed so far to codify the right to abortion, provide funding to support reproductive health care services, and protect providers and privacy. The Vice President also thanked the leaders for pursuing further action to protect access to care, including by passing additional legislation. She also encouraged the legislators to look for ways to support and coordinate with state legislators from other states as part of a broad coalition to protect abortion access.<br> <br>The participants discussed how people do not need to give up their own beliefs to agree that the government should not interfere with women’s decisions over their own bodies. They agreed that everyone deserves to have access to health care and noted the importance of keeping equity at the center of the conversation. The leaders also discussed the need to improve maternal health care systems across New Jersey and the country, noting the connection between maternal health care and reproductive health care. The Vice President told the state legislators, local leaders, and the advocates that she looks forward to continuing to work together to protect reproductive rights and freedoms.<br> <br><strong>Speakers </strong></p>



<ul><li>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Administrator Chiquita Brooks-LaSure</li><li>New Jersey Attorney General Matthew Platkin</li><li>New Jersey Senate Majority Leader Teresa Ruiz</li><li>New Jersey Assemblywoman Mila Jasey</li><li>Roslyn Rogers Collins, President and CEO, Planned Parenthood of Metropolitan New Jersey</li><li>Alejandra Sorto, Campaign Strategist for the American Civil Liberties Union of New Jersey</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By Vice President Harris In A Roundtable Discussion With New Jersey State Legislators On Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-a-roundtable-discussion-with-new-jersey-state-legislators-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 02:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City Convention CenterAtlantic City, New Jersey THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Madam Administrator, and to all the leaders here for, out of your busy schedules and all that you are addressing right now, to join in this conversation.  We have here leaders who are national leaders, in addition to being state and local leaders&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Atlantic City Convention Center<br><em>Atlantic City, New Jersey</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you, Madam Administrator, and to all the leaders here for, out of your busy schedules and all that you are addressing right now, to join in this conversation.  We have here leaders who are national leaders, in addition to being state and local leaders &#8212; elected leaders, community leaders, organization leaders, stakeholders.  And so I thank you all.<br><br>Every woman in America should be free to make decisions about their life, in terms of, in particular, the choices that they have and should be able to have about their reproductive health.<br><br>And with the Dobbs decision, the United States Supreme Court took a recognized constitutional right from the people on America, from the women of America.  And we do believe, I do believe this is a national healthcare crisis.<br> <br>When we look at this issue, every woman should be able to make decisions about their bodies and their life without government interference, and if they so choose, in consultation with their pastor, their priest, their rabbi, their family, their physician.<br><br>What we are seeing around the country are extremist so-called leaders who are passing laws with the intention of criminalizing public health professionals, punishing women for making decisions that are intimate, private decisions that should be protected, in terms of the privacy and the autonomy with which women should be able to live and have the power over the most intimate issues that could affect their lives.<br><br>And I think it&#8217;s important to note that you don&#8217;t have to abandon your faith or your beliefs to agree that the government should not be interfering with her decision, that woman&#8217;s decision, over her body and her life.<br><br>The government should not be interfering, and no one has to abandon their faith or their belief to agree that certain decisions are not the government&#8217;s to make, and that is one of them.<br><br>So the President feels very strongly about this issue.  And our administration is fighting at a national level to protect the health, the safety, and the wellbeing of women.<br><br>President Biden recently signed executive orders to protect women&#8217;s access to abortion by medication, and also, we are taking executive action to ensure that women are protected in terms of their constitutional right to interstate travel.<br><br>In addition, we are demanding that the United States Congress codify Roe, which means put into law the protections that Roe provided.<br><br>But we know that this fight is not only at a national level, it is also at a state level.  I have been traveling around the country.  I have met with leaders from many states that are directly impacted by these laws.<br><br>There is an election coming up in 113 days.  And those elections will matter at every level.  Who is your district attorney will matter.  Who is your governor will matter.  Who is your attorney general will matter.  Who is the secretary of state will matter.<br><br>So I urge everyone to pay attention to this election and understand that right now, with the Court&#8217;s decision, a lot of the rules and the laws that are being put in place are occurring and the enforcement of those laws occurring at a local and state level.<br><br>So, do pay attention to these elections coming up in, again, about 113 days, I believe.<br><br>And &#8212; and that brings me to why we are here today in New Jersey.  I have, in &#8212; in the travels and conversations that we&#8217;ve been having, looking for national models of what is working in the face of what&#8217;s not working.  And the legislators who are here today, and their colleagues and others and &#8212; and the attorney general, have been doing model work here in New Jersey in protecting a woman&#8217;s ability to make decisions about her body.<br><br>I will also note that, here in New Jersey, there is also work that is highlighting the Venn diagram, if you will, around these issues in that we are finding that in many of the states where there is an intent and there is work being done to deprive women of their right to make decisions about their own reproductive health and their care, the same people, and in those same states, we are finding laws being passed to restrict the ability of people to vote.<br><br>And, again, here in New Jersey, you all are doing some outstanding work to expand the right to vote to ensure that all people who are entitled to vote will be able to do so in an unfettered way.<br><br>And so I look forward to lifting up the work that you all have been doing here to protect these fundamental rights.<br><br>I will also add that it is my firm belief that the Dobbs decision is just the beginning of what is an agenda that is about also attacking other rights that flow from the right to privacy, including access to contraception and same-sex marriage.<br><br>And so when we think about this issue, let us understand that it has wide-ranging impact.  And we, as the American people who believe in the strength and the purpose of a democracy, we who believe that the Constitution of the United States was designed to protect certain fundamental rights, we must understand what is at stake &#8212; all of us &#8212; in this moment and, for that reason, stand up and fight for the right of everyone to have their constitutional rights protected.<br><br>So with that, I thank you all again, and I&#8217;m looking forward to our discussion.  And I&#8217;ll turn it back to the administrator to &#8212; to lead that discussion.<br><br>END<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/18/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-75/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 21:20:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[   L. Felice Gorordo, of Florida, to be United States Alternate Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development for a term of two years, vice Erik Bethel, resigned.      Kimberly Ann McClain, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, vice Leonard Wolfson. # # #]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>   L. Felice Gorordo, of Florida, to be United States Alternate Executive Director of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development for a term of two years, vice Erik Bethel, resigned.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">     Kimberly Ann McClain, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, vice Leonard Wolfson.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: U.S. Government Women Peace and Security Report to&#160;Congress</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/07/18/fact-sheet-us-government-women-peace-and-securityreport-to-congress/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 18:39:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017 (P.L. 115-68) (WPS Act) codified the United States Government’s decades-long, sustained commitment to the principles of the Women, Peace, and Security Agenda.&#160; This Agenda stemmed from the historic 2000 United Nations Security Council Resolution 1325, which has since been further supported by a growing body of policies&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017 (P.L. 115-68) (WPS Act) codified the United States Government’s decades-long, sustained commitment to the principles of the Women, Peace, and Security Agenda.&nbsp; This Agenda stemmed from the historic 2000 United Nations Security Council Resolution 1325, which has since been further supported by a growing body of policies to affirm gender equity and equality in security, peace-making, and peacekeeping, here in the United States and globally.</p>



<p>Conflict has disastrous impacts on affected communities and devastating economic costs globally. Women, as half the world’s population, must be engaged as leaders and key participants in responding to the complex challenges of global peace and security. &nbsp;The world is more peaceful, safe, and prosperous when women can fully participate in all facets of economic, social, and political life—and their human rights are respected.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;For the Biden-Harris Administration, the WPS agenda is a cornerstone of U.S. government efforts geared to averting and preventing conflict, including bolstering the implementation of the <a href="https://www.state.gov/stability-strategy/">U.S. Strategy to Prevent Conflict and Promote Stability</a> and the <a href="https://www.state.gov/atrocity-prevention/">U.S. Strategy to Anticipate, Prevent and Respond to Atrocities</a>.&nbsp; WPS is also a core theme throughout the National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality, which makes gender equity a strategic imperative across the domestic and foreign policy of the Biden-Harris Administration. This important lens is informing our work to avert and respond to crises, from the conflict-related sexual violence we are witnessing in Ukraine to the underrepresentation of women in civic participation in Guatemala.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The report issued today is the second report to Congress evaluating the USG’s progress towards advancing the goals of &nbsp;<a href="https://www.state.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/WPS_Strategy_10_October2019.pdf">2019 U.S. Women Peace and Security Strategy</a> and includes overviews of efforts undertaken by the four departments and agencies involved in the Strategy: the Department of Defense (DoD), Homeland Security (DHS), the Department of State (State), and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID). &nbsp;&nbsp;The reports summarize progress made in the WPS Strategy’s four Lines of Effort (LOEs): 1) Participation; 2) Protection; 3) Internal Capabilities; and 4) Partnerships.</p>



<p>To review the report, please visit:&nbsp; <a href="https://www.state.gov/us-women-peace-and-security-congressional-report-2022/">U.S. Women Peace and Security Congressional Report 2022</a>.&nbsp; Below are highlights from each agency’s reports:</p>



<p><strong><u>Department of State.</u></strong><strong>&nbsp; </strong>The Department continued its focus on WPS implementation through monitoring, evaluation, and learning exercises and strengthened engagement with key partners, such as civil society leaders. During the Fiscal Year (FY) 2021 reporting period, the Department continued engagement with civil society, non-governmental organizations (NGOs), the private sector, and partner governments; increased its training of personnel on WPS; and increased use of gender analysis in projects and strategic frameworks by 25 percent compared to FY 2020. Additionally, Department programs, training, and funding for WPS increased from FY 2020 to FY 2021.&nbsp; During the reporting period, the Department invested approximately $110 million in assistance programming to advance WPS. The Department also integrated WPS principles into its internal processes, including 231 notice of funding requests (NOFOs) and requests for proposals (RFPs) requiring a gender analysis – up from only 12 reported in FY 2020. As part of the Department’s ongoing internal review of its WPS data call and to streamline the report, the Department revised or removed some indicators for this reporting period (FY 2021).</p>



<p><strong><u>U.S. Agency for International Development.</u></strong>&nbsp; In accordance with the commitments of USAID’s WPS Implementation Plan, USAID increased its efforts to consult with local women leaders, civil society, including faith-based organizations, as well as academia in countries affected by crisis and conflict. In FY 2021, USAID supported the participation of over 77,000 women in leadership, conflict mediation, legal, political, and peacebuilding processes, and provided critical health care, psychosocial support, legal aid, and economic services to more than 5.3 million gender-based violence survivors. In FY 21, USAID invested over $243 million in programming designed to empower and protect women and girls in countries affected by crisis, conflict, violent extremism, and natural disasters.</p>



<p><strong><u>Department of Homeland Security.</u></strong>&nbsp; In FY 2021, there were significant accomplishments across the four DHS LOEs. The Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers (FLETC) trained 8,458 women in both basic and advanced law enforcement training programs; Initiative 2023 was launched to increase the number of women in law enforcement by 30 percent no later than 2023; and the U.S. Secret Service celebrated its 50th anniversary of admitting female agents. DHS led the Unified Coordination Group, a whole-of-government, whole-of-society effort to resettle more than 76,000 vulnerable Afghans, including women leaders, human rights activists, humanitarian workers, journalists, and other at-risk individuals across the United States. Through this effort, and Operation Allies Welcome (OAW), the Department also promoted the protection of Afghan women and girls through such initiatives as listening sessions with stakeholders on civil and human rights considerations. In addition to Department-wide efforts, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) conducted targeted trainings regarding the global treatment of women and highlighted key issues such as Female Genital Mutilation/Cutting (FGM/C).</p>



<p><strong>Department of Defense.</strong>&nbsp; The Department of Defense (DoD) WPS Strategic Framework and Implementation Plan (SFIP) established three Defense Objectives to support the WPS Strategy’s Lines of Effort (LOEs): (1) modeling and employing women’s meaningful participation in the Joint Force; (2) promoting partner nation women’s participation in all occupations in the defense and security sectors; and (3) ensuring partner nations protect women and girls, especially during conflict and crisis.&nbsp; In FY 2021, DoD spent $5.5 million to establish policies and programs to advance implementation of the Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017 (Public Law 115-68), hire and train qualified personnel, and integrate WPS into relevant training curriculum and professional military education for the Armed Forces. In modeling women’s meaningful participation, Air Force General Jacqueline Van Ovost took command of U.S. Transportation Command and Army General Laura Richardson took command of U.S. Southern Command. The Department initiated use of $3 million from the International Security Cooperation Programs (ISCP) Account to conduct security cooperation (SC) programs that incorporate gender analysis and advance women’s participation in defense institutions and national security forces. This work was complemented by the Department’s efforts to support an Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault in the Military, which prompted historic reforms to preventing and addressing sexual and gender-based violence across the force—reaffirming DoD’s commitment to advancing WPS goals within our military.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the 113th NAACP National&#160;Convention</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/07/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harrisat-the-113th-naacp-national-convention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 17:48:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=57796</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Atlantic City Convention CenterAtlantic City, New Jersey 11:54 A.M. EDT&#160;THE VICE PRESIDENT: &#160;Good morning, everyone!&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Good morning!&#160; Good morning.&#160; Have a seat.&#160; Please, have a seat.&#160;&#160;Oh, it is so good to be here with all my sisters and brothers.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160;Let me just thank Vice Chair Boykin-Towns for that incredible introduction.&#160; It means so much.&#160;&#160;My&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Atlantic City Convention Center<br><em>Atlantic City, New Jersey</em></em></p>



<p>11:54 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;Good morning, everyone!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Good morning!&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Have a seat.&nbsp; Please, have a seat.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Oh, it is so good to be here with all my sisters and brothers.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me just thank Vice Chair Boykin-Towns for that incredible introduction.&nbsp; It means so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My team was back there and said, my goodness, you know, over the years, we’ve &#8212; we’ve actually &#8212; we’ve done some things, and it’s nice to know that it is having the impact that it is having.&nbsp; So I want to thank you, Madam Vice Chair, for that introduction.&nbsp; It really means a lot.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Johnson, thank you for your years of dedicated partnership and leadership &#8212; (applause) &#8212; yes &#8212; on the issue of voting rights and so many more issues that challenge our nation and its people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I have worked with President Johnson over the years, where we have been in small rooms, where we have been in the Oval Office, where we have been in large rooms such as this.&nbsp; He is the same person wherever he is.&nbsp; And he is a person who is always fighting for the people and the best of who we can be as a nation.&nbsp; And I admire and respect the hard work and determination that you put into this most important position as the president of our NAACP.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>So, to the Board of Directors, chapter presidents, ACT-SO and Next Gen leaders, and the entire NAACP membership; to Secretary Marcia Fudge, who was with us today &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to my pastor, Reverend Dr. Amos C. Brown; to all of you: Greetings.&nbsp; Greetings.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I just want to, if you don’t mind for a moment, take a moment of personal privilege to talk about Dr. Brown.&nbsp; He has been on this journey with me every step of the way, from when I first thought about running for public office almost two decades ago.&nbsp; And he has been such a voice of leadership, more leadership, and leadership in our nation.&nbsp; And so I want to thank you, Dr. Brown, for all that you are &#8212; all that you are.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as many of you know, I am a proud lifetime member of this organization.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; And I have had the distinct pleasure of addressing this conference many times over the years.&nbsp; And I am honored today to address you for the first time as Vice President of the United States.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I stand today on the shoulders of the legendary lawyers of this organization &#8212; Thurgood Marshall, Charles Hamilton Houston, Constance Baker Motley &#8212; who were, of course, among the greatest heroes of the Civil Rights Movement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Just last March, I stood in the Rose Garden, at the White House, with Ms. Michelle Duster, the great-granddaughter of a founder of the NAACP and one of our nation&#8217;s greatest journalists, Ida B. Wells.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we were there to address some very unfinished business &#8212; business of this organization &#8212; which was to watch President Joe Biden sign the Emmett Till Antilynching Act.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I was proud to introduce that act when I served in the United States Senate, along with Senator Cory Booker &#8212; New Jersey’s own &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and Congressman Bobby Rush, who I think is here but has been a great leader over the years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This legislation was a result of years of determined action by civil rights organizations, including the NAACP.&nbsp; Even though it took a staggering 122 years to finally make lynching a federal crime but, it must be said, even though it took that long, the NAACP was never deterred and always determined.<br>&nbsp;<br>Core to the identity of this organization is the unwavering commitment to move our nation forward no matter how long it might take.&nbsp; For more than a century, the NAACP has fought to ensure the wellbeing of Black communities and, by extension, all communities in our country.&nbsp; This organization has fought to secure, for all people, the rights guaranteed in our nation&#8217;s Constitution, driven by the ability to see America as it can be, unburdened by what has been.<br>&nbsp;<br>This organization and the people who make up this organization &#8212; will we see a nation in which the promise of opportunity, of justice, of freedom can be made real for all people?<br>&nbsp;<br>And I bring you greetings from our President, Joe Biden, who wants &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to make clear that he and I, of course, share in the vision of the NAACP.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You see, we see and are prepared to address the disparities that are holding so many people back in our nation &#8212; disparities that we see in education, in economic opportunity, in housing, healthcare, and more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>To address those disparities and to advance the fight for civil rights, President Biden and I have put equity at the center of all that we do.&nbsp; And that begins with our children.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The great Thurgood Marshall once said that every child has a right &#8212; I will now quote &#8212; &#8220;to an equal start in life and an equal opportunity to reach their potential.&#8221;&nbsp; I believe, to move our nation forward, we must fight to make sure all of the children of our community have that equal opportunity of which he spoke.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that is why together, all of us here, fought to extend the Child Tax Credit, which lifted nearly 40 percent of Black children out of poverty last year alone.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It is why we passed a tax cut to give working families up to $8,000 a year to give folks more room in their budgets to buy for their children food, medication, and school supplies.<br>&nbsp;<br>It is why we are fighting to make sure home healthcare is accessible and affordable.&nbsp; Because we all know we have far too many children, for example, in our communities who have disabilities and their parents need support.&nbsp; They need help.&nbsp; And so, this is the work we are doing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, because we know that when we invest in the education of our children, we are really investing in the future of our nation.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That is why, as Madam Vice Chair mentioned, we invested an historic 5.8 billion &#8212; that’s with a “B” &#8212; billion dollars in our HBCUs so they will remain the center of academic excellence.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Leaders of the NAACP: To move our nation forward, we must also &#8212; as has been discussed &#8212; make sure that our mothers, our daughters, our sisters, and our aunties have the healthcare that they need to thrive.&nbsp; And that is why we are leading the fight to address the maternal health crisis.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, in America, Black women are three times as likely to die from pregnancy-related causes.&nbsp; Native American women are more than twice as likely to die.&nbsp; Rural women are more than one and a half times more likely to die.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we have elevated, for an obvious reason, the issue of maternal health so it will be a national priority.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And building on the work that we have done together over the years, for the first time I was proud to convene women from around the country at the White House to discuss this critical issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we took action then, because it can’t just be about words, to provide resources to hire and train doulas, to advance culturally competent care &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and to research the contributors to maternal mortality, because included in those contributors are racial bias in the healthcare delivery system; included in those contributors are the stressors that Black women face in life.&nbsp; And we need to research and make clear and speak honestly about all of those issues, again, as a national priority.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, we worked with states to expand Medicaid postpartum, because the way it had been working, Medicaid was covering two months postpartum.&nbsp; Now, she just gave birth to a human being.&nbsp; So we are now extending and working with states that it will be expanded to 12 months of postpartum care.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And that will benefit over a quarter million women.<br>&nbsp;<br>Leaders of the NAACP: To continue to move our nation forward, we must also take action to address the economic inequities that are holding back so many people in our nation, which is why, together, we are fighting to build more opportunity for wealth in our communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, we are investing billions of dollars in minority and women entrepreneurs.&nbsp; We are &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we are addressing systemic inequities in homeownership, which, of course, is an issue this organization has been fighting for, for years, as integral to the Civil Rights Movement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as you know, it is because of a clear history of segregation, restrictive covenants, and redlining that long denied Black homeowners the opportunity to take full advantage of the wealth-building power of homeownership.&nbsp; That inequity continues today in the home appraisal system.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I am proud that our administration, led by Secretary Marcia Fudge &#8212; (applause) &#8212; is working to eliminate racial bias in home appraisals so that Black and Latino families can fully realize the true value of their homes and pass that value to their children and grandchildren.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Homeownership is one of the greatest sources in the community of intergenerational wealth.&nbsp; However, we know that, still, in this ongoing fight for civil rights on housing, that we are hearing the cases of, for example, a Black family trying to sell their home, and they get the appraisal and they just know it is not the true value of their home.&nbsp; And so you&#8217;ve heard the stories about how they&#8217;ll then encourage friends of the family &#8212; a white family &#8212; to come in.&nbsp; And then the white family will put the pictures up of their family.&nbsp; And then that appraisal gets done, and it&#8217;s for a much higher value.&nbsp; Same house.&nbsp; Same neighborhood.<br>&nbsp;<br>So this is a real issue.&nbsp; And with the leadership of Marcia Fudge, we are dealing with that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, we know that to protect this progress &#8212; the progress we have achieved so far &#8212; and to ensure justice for all, we must have better representation on our federal courts.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And with your support, I am proud to say that our administration has appointed the most diverse group of judges in the history of the United States &#8212; (applause) &#8212; including a woman who I have come to know and admire, who is the first Black woman appointed to the United States Supreme Court: Justice Ketanji Brown Jackson.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We got to stand for that one.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, leaders of the NAACP, together we have fought hard to move our nation forward.&nbsp; And yet, we must recognize there are those who are fighting to drag us backward: extremist, so-called leaders, who are attempting to undermine our democracy and assault our most fundamental freedoms &#8212; the freedom to be safe from gun violence, the freedom to make decisions about our own bodies, and the freedom to vote.&nbsp; So I will address them in turn.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, the freedom from gun violence.&nbsp; So, recently, I visited Buffalo, New York, to attend the funeral of an 86-year-old grandmother who went to the grocery store after, as she often did, spending the day with her husband who was in a nursing home &#8212; Mrs. Whitfield.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I went to Highland Park, Illinois, where there were strollers and lawn chairs scattered up and down a street where there was supposed to be a parade for July 4th.&nbsp; There &#8212; as in Uvalde, Texas; as in Greenwood, Indiana, just last night; and in so many communities across our nation &#8212; scenes of ordinary life have been turned into war zones by horrific acts of gun violence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Mass shootings have made America a nation in mourning.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not only the mass shootings.&nbsp; We see it in our communities every day, and it is no less tragic or outrageous.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Think about it: Black people are 13 percent of America&#8217;s population but make up 62 percent of gun homicide victims.&nbsp; This issue of the need for reasonable gun safety laws is a real issue when we are talking about the civil right, the right that all communities should have, to live in a place that is safe without weapons of war running those streets.<br>&nbsp;<br>And understand: The number of guns manufactured in this country tripled over the last 20 years.&nbsp; Today we have more guns in our nation than people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, earlier this month, the President signed the first federal gun safety law in nearly 30 years.&nbsp; And it was an important and necessary step.&nbsp; But we need to do more.&nbsp; We must repeal the liability shield that protects gun manufacturers.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we must renew the assault weapons ban.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, an assault weapon, like many things, there’s a design &#8212; there’s a purposeful design.&nbsp; Well, for the assault weapon, the design is to kill a lot of human beings quickly.&nbsp; There is no reason for weapons of war on the streets of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>We must also take steps to protect other fundamental freedoms, including the freedom for a woman to make decisions about her own body.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, you know, on this subject, it’s important to note that to support a woman’s ability &#8212; not her government, but her &#8212; to make that decision does not require anyone to abandon their faith or their beliefs.&nbsp; It just requires us to agree the government shouldn’t be making that decision for her.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And think about it: For the first time in generations, the United States Supreme Court &#8212; the highest court of our land; the former court of Thurgood Marshall &#8212; took away a constitutional right, that had been recognized, from the people of America, from the women of America.<br><br>We know, NAACP, that our country has a history of claiming ownership over human bodies.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And today, extremists, so-called leaders are criminalizing doctors and punishing women for making healthcare decisions for themselves &#8212; personal decisions that it is her right to make in consultation with her doctor, her pastor, her priest, her rabbi, her loved ones, not her government telling her what to do.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And these so-called leaders &#8212; so-called &#8212; claim that, “Well, you know, we just think that this is a decision that should be made by the folks in the states.&nbsp; People in the states can vote on this.”&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; But at this moment, many of those same so-called leaders are the same ones who are passing laws to restrict the ability of people to vote.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Laws &#8212; they’re passing laws, the same people &#8212; laws that ban drop boxes and restrict early voting; laws that make it illegal to give people food and water for waiting in line to vote.&nbsp; Undemocratic laws.&nbsp; Un-American laws.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I asked my team to &#8212; you know, I &#8212; remember Venn diagrams?&nbsp; Those three circles.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And then let’s just see where they overlap.<br><br>So I asked my team &#8212; I said, you know, “Do a Venn diagram on two circles for me and, in particular, the overlap of states that are attacking the freedom to vote and attacking women&#8217;s freedoms over their own bodies.&nbsp;&nbsp; There are 10 states that are doing both.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Here&#8217;s the point: Our freedoms are all connected.&nbsp; Consider the freedom to vote.&nbsp; The freedom to vote is the freedom that unlocks all others.&nbsp; Is &#8212; it is a catalyst for economic justice, for social justice, for racial justice.&nbsp;&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And generations of leaders gave their sweat, their tears, their blood in its defense.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, earlier this year, many of us were together in Selma, Alabama &#8212; as we have been before &#8212; this year to commemorate the 57th anniversary of Bloody Sunday.&nbsp; Standing there, shoulder-to-shoulder with leaders who return to the Edmund Pettus Bridge every year, it was clear: While we will honor the history of the movement, we must recognize the dream of the movement remains unfinished.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, no matter how many times they push us back, we will continue to march forward.&nbsp; And we will pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act and the Freedom to Vote Act.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Friends: Freedom, liberty, and democracy are on the ballot this fall.&nbsp; And we need to make sure that our voices are heard.&nbsp; There is a midterm coming up in about &#8212; I think it’s 113 days, maybe 112 days &#8212; 112 days.&nbsp; We’re not going to be able to get these days back, so each one of these days we must, with a sense of urgency, ensure that the American people know their voi- &#8212; their vote matters.&nbsp; It is their voice; that the right to vote is something that the leaders of this organization and its founders knew to be at the core of all of the other rights and freedoms to which we are entitled.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we know what we need to do.&nbsp; And, in particular, to protect the freedom to vote and a women’s right to make decisions about her own body, we need people who will defend our rights up and down the ballot, from district attorneys to state attorneys general, from local sheriffs to governors.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we need two more votes in the United States Senate.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>We will not &#8212; and the President has been clear &#8212; we will not let the filibuster stand in our way of our most essential rights and freedoms.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, leaders of the NAACP: Together, we have accomplished much, but we still have much to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>To move our nation forward, President Biden and I ask for you to do what you have always done: continue to build coalitions of Americans of all ages and races and backgrounds; continue to do so with the knowledge that we have so much more in common than what separates us; continue to activate and organize communities in every state; continue to use your power to sh- &#8212; to fight for our shared vision of America.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as I often will refer to her, the great Coretta Scott King &#8212; who joined the NAACP as a young college student &#8212; once said that freedom must be earned and won in each and every generation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today &#8212; and I look at the young leaders here in particular &#8212; (applause) &#8212; yes.&nbsp; Today, it is our collective turn, but we’re counting on you all, because today we have been called to create a more fair, more equal, and more just America.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, today, let us recommit to answering the call.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>God bless you.&nbsp;&nbsp; And God bless the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;12:22 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
