<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 22:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before a Meeting With Business and Labor Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-meeting-with-business-and-labor-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24819</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 4:43 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, I’m delighted you’re all here.&#160; I’m meeting with a group of labor and business leaders who &#8212; and this is one of those meetings I’ve been looking forward to. They&#8217;re not here to negotiate with one another.&#160; The good news is they&#8217;ve been here negotiating &#8212; not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>4:43 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I’m delighted you’re all here.&nbsp; I’m meeting with a group of labor and business leaders who &#8212; and this is one of those meetings I’ve been looking forward to.</p>



<p>They&#8217;re not here to negotiate with one another.&nbsp; The good news is they&#8217;ve been here negotiating &#8212; not negotiating &#8212; supporting what we’re trying to get done on the infrastructure bill.</p>



<p>And I know that we&#8217;re looking for this bipartisan effort to get this infrastructure bill passed.&nbsp; As you all know, and they share my belief that it&#8217;s both in the interest of business and labor to get this done.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and it’s about &#8212; not about energy versus environment, it’s not about business versus labor; it’s all about, basically, a race to the future.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve been traveling the world lately and &#8212; back out where I used to spend a lot of time, in the G7 and meeting with the summits with the Russians, as well as NATO.&nbsp; And I tell you, the rest of the world is looking to see whether we can get something done.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The single-biggest issue &#8212; I know you’ve travelled the world, all of you &#8212; and the fact is that they’re trying to figure out whether we&#8217;re so divided that we can&#8217;t get something done.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I&#8217;m convinced that they&#8217;re convinced now that we have an opportunity to make some real fundamental changes that generate growth in the future.</p>



<p>You know, the days used to be that we were in a position where the United States invested more money in research and development three, four decades ago than any nation in the world.&nbsp; Now we’re number eight.&nbsp; And it used to be that China was &#8212; was number nine, and now they&#8217;re number two.</p>



<p>This is about a race for the 21st century.&nbsp; And you know &#8212; and what we&#8217;re doing here is, in this race for the future, it&#8217;s about connecting Americans &#8212; all Americans, rural and urban &#8212; to high-speed Internet, repairing our roads and our bridges so that we can, in fact, no longer be ranked number 9 or 10 in terms of infrastructure in America.&nbsp; Back to what we used to be &#8212; we used to lead the world.</p>



<p>You know, electrify our school buses and our transit systems.&nbsp; And we’re going to build national charging networks for electric vehicles; eliminate the nation&#8217;s lead service pipes.&nbsp; We got 400,000 home- &#8212;</p>



<p>I mean, there&#8217;s just a whole lot we can do that&#8217;s going to put a lot of people to work.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to improve the life of a lot of people.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to update our power grid &#8212; which, as you saw what happened to Texas last year, there&#8217;s a lot we can do.&nbsp; It’s going to generate &#8212; and, Lonnie, your (inaudible) is going be awful busy, and &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. STEPHENSON:&nbsp; We&#8217;re ready.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going &#8212; we have to win the comp- &#8212; we really do.&nbsp; This is not hyperbole.&nbsp; We have to win the competition for the 21st century.&nbsp; That’s really what&#8217;s at stake, and I think you all know that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the Bipartisan Infrastructure does, in my view.</p>



<p>I want to thank everyone here for supporting it.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to get into the details, among all of us, about what we think about what needs to be improved, what can be made better or worse.&nbsp; You know, so, we want everybody to be engaged.</p>



<p>So, thank you all, folks, for being here.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to now get down to business.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what conversations have you had with public health officials about possibly changing the mask mandate for vaccinated Americans?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ll respond to the COVID question quickly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We follow the science.&nbsp; What&#8217;s happening now is all the major scientific operations in this country and the 25-person group we put together are looking at all the possibilities of what&#8217;s happening now.</p>



<p>We have a pandemic among the nonvaccinated &#8212; those who are not vaccinated.</p>



<p>If you are vaccinated, you are safe.&nbsp; If you are vaccinated, you have over a 98 percent chance of never catching the virus at all.&nbsp; And if you catch it, you&#8217;re likely to &#8212; overwhelming proof, so far, is you&#8217;re not going to be hospitalized, you&#8217;re not going to be sick, you&#8217;re going to probably have no signs that you had it, and you are not going to die.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a simple proposition.</p>



<p>And what they&#8217;re doing is they&#8217;re going into &#8212; investigating every aspect of any change that could or might take place.</p>



<p>But the vaccines are good against all of the variants that are out there, including the Delta variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you so much for being here.</p>



<p>4:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at Signing of H.R. 1642, the VOCA Fix to Sustain the Crime Victims Fund Act of 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-h-r-1642-the-voca-fix-to-sustain-the-crime-victims-fund-act-of-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 22:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24817</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room  3:18&#160;P.M. EDT&#160;&#160;(&#8220;Hail to the Chief&#8221; is played.)&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Every time I hear that, I wonder when he&#8217;s coming.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Please, everybody sit down.&#160; Thank you.&#160;Let me begin by doing something no speaker should ever do &#8212; by apologizing.&#160; I got a little tied up in that other office I work in, Pat,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room </p>



<p>3:18&nbsp;P.M. EDT&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(&#8220;Hail to the Chief&#8221; is played.)<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Every time I hear that, I wonder when he&#8217;s coming.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Please, everybody sit down.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me begin by doing something no speaker should ever do &#8212; by apologizing.&nbsp; I got a little tied up in that other office I work in, Pat, and I apologize for keeping you waiting because I know you&#8217;re all as equally busy as I am.&nbsp; And I want to thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, I think is a day of hope.&nbsp; And I mean that.&nbsp; A day of hope and healing for victims or crime and organizations that support those victims of crime.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to thank the Vice President and the Second Gentleman, Senators Durbin &#8212; I think he&#8217;s here; I thought I saw him.&nbsp; Senators Durbin and Baldwin and Grassley and Graham and Murkowski.&nbsp; Representatives Nadler and Fitzpatrick and Jackson-Lee and Wagner and Scanlon.&nbsp; And everyone who has helped make possible this moment, including so many of you who are here today that I haven’t mentioned.<br>&nbsp;<br>When someone commits a crime, it’s &#8212; it&#8217;s not enough to bring the predator to justice; we also need to support the victims.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s something that, way back &#8212; 150 years ago, when I was Chairman of the Judiciary Committee, we spent a lot of time working on and setting up victims&#8217; funds.&nbsp; That’s what this Crime Victims Fund does.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In many years of working on the issue, I&#8217;ve visited an awful lot of domestic violence shelters.&nbsp; Every time I&#8217;d go into a city, I would quietly &#8212; before I went to where I was supposed to be &#8212; quietly slip in and spend time in a domestic violence shelter to speak to the people giving the services of people getting the services.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, many times, the body language that you&#8217;d see when you walked in was one of the victims of crime finding themselves almost curled up, Dianne, in a ball.&nbsp; They were still suffering from a serious, serious &#8212; not only physical abuse they received, but, quite frankly, the emotional abuse.&nbsp; And you can see the pain.&nbsp; You can see the pain was still with them, and you wondered when was this going to abate, no matter what we did.<br>&nbsp;<br>According to the CDC &#8212; and I&#8217;m &#8212; I think Senator Feinstein remembers &#8212; I got in trouble because when I was pushing the legislation, way back in those days, I said, &#8220;I&#8217;m convinced that women who are victims of domestic violence suffer from post-traumatic stress no different than a solider being shot at regularly.&#8221;&nbsp; You come home and every time your significant other would come home, if dinner wasn’t ready, they smashed your head against the wall.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no &#8212; there&#8217;s no difference than being shot at.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the CDFE [sic] &#8212; the CDC, two years later, came out and said, &#8220;Survivors can experience mental health problems and such depression and the symptoms of post-traumatic stress syndrome.&#8221;&nbsp; Even before research confirmed it, you could see it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there are economic costs for survivors as well &#8211;medical costs, lost productivity from work, and navigating the court system.&nbsp; That’s why Victims Compensation Program helps victims and their families cover the costs they&#8217;d suffered from the crime.&nbsp; They can &#8212; there can be counseling and medical bills; lost wages because you couldn’t work; paying for temporary housing for a family fleeing abuse; even fixing a broken door kicked down by an abuser.&nbsp; And, you know, the vast majority of children out in the street are the children who are, in fact, the children of abused women.&nbsp; It can also be a long-term support survivors need to heal, every time, in every single sense of the word.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In 2019, these victim compensation funds went directly to over 230,000 victims &#8212; 230,000.&nbsp; These funds also got to states, territories, and Tribes to support thousands of victim services organizations.&nbsp; These organizations have provided services and support to over 13 million survivors.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, by the way, last night, some of you heard me talk about the need for more policing that understands the need for communities and citizens.&nbsp; These funds will also go to law enforcement agencies to support training on how to respond to victims who have experienced trauma.<br>&nbsp;<br>In 1984, I was proud to support the &#8212; the passage of the Victims of Crime Act, and created &#8212; that created this fund.&nbsp; I&#8217;m also proud to sign the law that significantly strengthened it today.&nbsp; This fund doesn&#8217;t take a dime of taxpayers’ money; it uses fines and penalties paid by convicted federal criminals. However, fines from what are called “non-prosecutorial agreements” or defendant &#8212; or “deferred prosecution agreements” did not go into this Victims Crimes Fund in the past.<br>&nbsp;<br>Since there&#8217;s been more and more of these agreements in recent years, the fund is being depleted.&nbsp; That meant dramatic cuts in the funding it could provide for victims and for organizations to support these victims.<br>&nbsp;<br>Between 2017 and today, the amount of money in these funds has gone down 92 percent, which has resulted in a 70 percent reduction in victims assistance programs and grants.&nbsp; This means that, for a lot of victims, the help they need isn&#8217;t there any longer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>When my son Beau was the Attorney General of the state of Delaware, he took pride in getting more support more quickly to victims, especially to protect and care for child victims.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I know that, as the San Francisco DA and the California Attorney General, Vice President Harris expanded support for victims of crime and launched one of the nation&#8217;s first medical centers focused on treating childhood trauma caused by violence in a home or in a community.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This bill is going to allow us to make &#8212; make sure that all the fines and penalties that are from federal cases go into the victims &#8212; the Crime Victims Fund to rebuild this fund, because it&#8217;s badly needed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is going to enable us to provide more help and support to victims of domestic violence, sexual assault, child abuse, trafficking, and other crimes all across America.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In order to provide more access and safety and services for victims of gender-based violence, it&#8217;s long past time to re- &#8212; reauthorize and strengthen the protections through the Violence Against Women Act.&nbsp; Please.&nbsp; Please.&nbsp; You know, you can &#8212; (applause).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know from experience you all can come together in a bipartisan, bicameral way and to pass this bill.&nbsp; We need to do the same thing to reauthorize the Violence Against Women Act without further delay.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, after these changes in the Victims Crime Act passed this week, a leader from one of the state&#8217;s &#8212; state&#8217;s Coalition Against Domestic Violence sent a letter to her national organization.&nbsp; And she wrote about working in the shelter where their ability to serve people rose and fell based on the fundings of victim services.&nbsp; She told the story of a client she lost to domestic violence homicide because the budget cuts left them without space at the shelter or staff needed to help this particular woman.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Upon learning about the law I&#8217;m about to sign today, she wrote, and I quote &#8212; I quote, “I think about her every day.&nbsp; This is going to be truly lifesaving,” end of quote.&nbsp; This is what you&#8217;ve done &#8212; truly lifesaving.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In closing, I want to thank those angels working on the frontlines to help these victims, especially during this pandemic that’s made the work both more difficult, more in demand, and more dangerous.&nbsp; And I want to thank the advocates who mobilized and bring together these important changes in the law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are thousands of people out there who may not know about the work you did to get this bill passed, but they’ll know that they are getting the help they need to put their lives back together and move toward healing and toward justice.&nbsp; I will now have the great honor of signing the bill.&nbsp; And I’d invite the sponsors to come on up and stand with me if you’re willing.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>(The act is signed.)<br>&nbsp;<br>This is one of those deals where what they did is literally, not figuratively, going to change the lives of women and children and some men out there.&nbsp; So, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>3:30 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki and Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, July 22, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/22/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-and-secretary-of-commerce-gina-raimondo-july-22-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12:41 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Thursday.&#160; Okay, we have a special guest.&#160; Happy to welcome back Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo.&#160;&#160;Today, she will be telling us about a new economic development initiative that the Department is launching, thanks to the American Rescue Plan.&#160; She&#8217;ll take a couple of questions.&#160; After that, as always,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>12:41 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Thursday.&nbsp; Okay, we have a special guest.&nbsp; Happy to welcome back Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, she will be telling us about a new economic development initiative that the Department is launching, thanks to the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; She&#8217;ll take a couple of questions.&nbsp; After that, as always, I&#8217;ll be the bad cop.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, I’ll turn it over to Secretary Raimondo.<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s see here.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; So, as the President often says and as we all know, we&#8217;re on the road to recovery.&nbsp; And today, with this announcement, we mark a real step forward in that recovery.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As Jen just said, the President signed the American Rescue Plan into law, intended to get our country back on its feet.&nbsp; And thanks to that law, I&#8217;m thrilled right now to be announcing the launch of a transformative $3 billion economic development initiative that will be running out of the Department of Commerce.&nbsp; I&#8217;m even more excited to say that, starting today, this afternoon, every community in America can begin applying for that funding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We believe that this is the largest local economic development initiative that the Commerce Department has ever made.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s a testament to the President&#8217;s commitment to do far more than simply recover, but to build back better and make sure every community and every American is included in our comeback.<br>&nbsp;<br>Everybody ought to benefit from this $3 billion initiative &#8212; from working mothers working to balance multiple jobs; to young adults looking for work; to factory workers or retail workers who lost their job in the pandemic &#8212; many of them mid-career and they&#8217;re wondering, “What happens to me now?&nbsp; What happens to me next?”<br>&nbsp;<br>These funds &#8212; this initiative has been specifically designed to make sure that we are going to be providing high-quality, real jobs for you and for your community.<br>&nbsp;<br>What we saw during the pandemic, and what we all know, is that some people did very well.&nbsp; Those who were doing well did very well.&nbsp; But millions of Americans continue to struggle, and it&#8217;s uneven.&nbsp; Those who continue to struggle &#8212; it&#8217;s been disproportionately women, people of color, communities of color, rural communities, and Tribes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We know 2 million American women dropped out of the labor force since the start of the pandemic, mostly because of lack of affordable childcare and paid leave.&nbsp; So, ensuring that these $3 billion are distributed equity is core to our investment strategy.&nbsp; We know that equity is good for workers, good for business, and good for the economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As many of you know, I&#8217;m the former governor of Rhode Island, and, as a governor, I saw what good-paying jobs mean to American families and mean to communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This initiative has the potential to create, we believe, 300,000 jobs in the near term, revitalize dozens of communities around America, and drive innovation in unser- &#8212; underserved communities and revitalize depressed economies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The good news is the Department of Commerce&#8217;s Economic Development Agency has been doing this for decades.&nbsp; They have a track record of success.&nbsp; In fact, I saw that, on Monday, when I was in Albany, where EDA’s investment over the last 10 years have helped that city and region become a global semiconductor and bio-science hub.&nbsp; And, in fact, the employment growth rate there has grown by 30 percent in those industries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This initiative that I&#8217;m announcing today will bring that type of transformative growth to communities all over the country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, at the end of the day, as the President has so often said, our economy can&#8217;t recover until everybody in every community is included.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I&#8217;d like to briefly describe the components of this $3 billion initiative.&nbsp; It begins with what we&#8217;re calling the “Build Back Better Regional Challenge”.&nbsp; This is a $1 billion challenge for up to 30 regions across the country seeking to revitalize their economies.&nbsp; It&#8217;s designed to focus on innovation and spur projects that grow new industries and scale existing ones.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Secondly is what we&#8217;re calling the “Good Jobs Challenge,” which allocates a half a billion dollars towards industry-led workforce training and apprenticeship programs with a particular focus on women, people of color, and underserved communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Importantly, we have designed this so that funds can also be used for support services like childcare and transportation while folks are getting trained so we make sure they &#8212; they get to the finish line of the training and get a job.<br>&nbsp;<br>For the hard &#8212; hard-hit communities hit hardest by the loss of travel and tourism, we’re providing $750 million to accelerate the recovery of trarel [sic] &#8212; travel tourism and outdoor recreation.&nbsp; Through the economic adjustment assistance, we&#8217;re offering a half a billion dollars to hundreds of communities across the country to create new jobs, spur economic development, and put Americans back to work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our “Indigenous Communities Commitment” sets aside $100 million to meet the needs of Indigenous communities with everything from broadband to health centers and more &#8212; deliberately designed to be flexible to meet the needs of the community.<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, we are making a $300 million commitment to invest in economic development in coal-affected communities.&nbsp; We believe that this $300 million investment in coal communities is the largest economic development that EDA has ever made in coal communities.&nbsp; And we know that it will enable these communities to recover, diversify their economies, and grow.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, these grants together reflect the values and priorities of President Biden&#8217;s Build Back Better agenda, and they, alongside of the Jobs Plan, will accelerate America&#8217;s economic recovery and help the country continue to get back to work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, spread the word.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll be &#8212; applications go live this afternoon, and we look forward to working with communities around America.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Jeff.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Madam Secretary, two questions.&nbsp; One, can you explain how people can apply for these grants?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And two, on a separate topic:&nbsp; The Commerce Department has a Supply Chain Advisory Committee.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on what you&#8217;re doing about chips and other supply issues?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So, as I said, this afternoon, on the EDA website &#8212; the EDA website applications will be live.&nbsp; So we want to get this money out the door as quickly as possible.&nbsp; EDA has six regional offices around the country, which we will be working with.&nbsp; But this is &#8212; I want to clarify: This money is for states, cities, counties, nonprofits, universities &#8212; not for companies.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s coalitions of nonprofits in communities, specifically designed to be locally led and managed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re doing a lot on the chip shortage.&nbsp; I am engaging almost daily with industry.&nbsp; We are working as hard as we can to get the House to pass the CHIPS Act or their version of USICA.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re putting plans in place right now, already, on the team to invest the $52 billion.&nbsp; We need to incentivize the manufacturing of chips in America.&nbsp; And so, we are very focused on putting the pieces in place so that can happen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With regard to the EDA grants, I understand that you&#8217;re going to judge some of these by return on investment.&nbsp; How are you defining ROI, given that that can often exclude priorities like gender and racial equality?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; So, our number one investment priority is equity.&nbsp; And as our team decides which &#8212; these are &#8212; this is a competitive grant process.&nbsp; By the way, I think that the fact of the competition will help communities to come together as a community and put their best ideas forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>In order to qualify to get the money, you have to prove to us that equity &#8212; you&#8217;ll have an equity lens.&nbsp; And whether it&#8217;s job training that you&#8217;re doing, you have to give &#8212; you know, I have to make sure that women, people of color, veterans, people who&#8217;ve been left out will be included in this.<br>&nbsp;<br>So it&#8217;s a lens that we&#8217;re going to take across the $3 billion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, like, whoever does it the best?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Exactly.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Rachel.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What type of &#8212; thank you, Madam Secretary.&nbsp; What type of follow up will there be?&nbsp; You&#8217;re emphasizing equity, but will you be following up to make sure that that money is distributed fairly to the communities that you&#8217;re speaking of that really do need it?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Great question.&nbsp; So, we are deeply committed for this to be transparent.&nbsp; Everything is going to be online.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be on our website.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be a wide-open, transparent process.&nbsp; And we are, at the get-go, putting in place accountability measures.&nbsp; And this is something I am very serious about &#8212; having been a governor, being on the ground.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to track every penny to make sure that it&#8217;s doing what it&#8217;s supposed to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the ROI &#8212; the ROI is jobs. We think we can create, in the short term, hundreds of thousands of jobs, and fundamentally revitalize dozens of communities around America so that, a few years from now, we’ll create 300,000 jobs; 10 years from now, we will have communities that are a beehive of economic activity that, five years ago, were distressed.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nancy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Secretary Raimondo.&nbsp; A few days ago, the U.S. government and governments around the world accused China of malicious cyber activities.&nbsp; Have you gotten any reaction from your Chinese government counterparts about these accusations?<br>And do you believe that the statements alone are going to be enough to change Chinese behavior if they aren&#8217;t paired with punitive measures like tariffs or sanctions?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So I have not had &#8212; to answer your first question, the answer is: No, I have not had any interaction.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Pre- &#8212; President Biden has been very clear on this: There will be consequences.&nbsp; And we will use all tools at our disposable [sic] &#8212; at our disposal in order to protect Americans and American businesses.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Tamara.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You mentioned that some of this money would go to communities hit hard by the loss of travel and tourism.&nbsp; Do you have a sense of how big that hit has been and how &#8212; what share of that is because of the public health-related travel bans?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; So, we know that nearly every community in America has been affected.&nbsp; And I want to be clear that, of the $750 million, every state will receive something.&nbsp; So, $500 million is going out as quickly as we can in the next few weeks, and everyone will participate.&nbsp; And then, $200 [million] or so is competitive.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think that it&#8217;s im- &#8212; I think the answer to your question is &#8212; it&#8217;s impossible to answer &#8212; or I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don’t think it&#8217;s possible to figure it out that way.&nbsp; But we do know, about a year and a half ago, we shut down travel and tourism.&nbsp; I lived it in Rhode Island &#8212; you know, Newport, Narragansett, Block Island closed; we shut it down.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re still trying to build back after that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so that&#8217;s what this money is intended to do: to help these communities to get back into the business of tourism and travel.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kelly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How would you assess, Madam Secretary, the work &#8212; worker shortage that many employers are finding &#8212; that they&#8217;re having difficulty getting back up, especially in some of the hospitality and tourist areas?<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; It’s &#8212; it is acute.&nbsp; There &#8212; there is &#8212; every business I talk to says that they need to find talent.&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t know if I would call it a “shortage,” per se; I would say there&#8217;s a skills gap.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we put so much money of this $3 billion &#8212; you know, a half a billion of $3 billion is just for skill development, apprenticeship, high-quality job training.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I hear all the time is &#8212; from companies &#8212; “We are ready to hire, but people need to have the skills.&nbsp; They need digital skills, cybersecurity skills, data &#8212; you know, data skills, cloud computing skills.”&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what we have to get at the business of.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And by the way, we need to make sure that women and people of color and people in rural areas have those digital skills so they can get those good jobs.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what this is about.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what I hear most often from companies.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Kaitlan is going to have to be the last one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary.&nbsp; Last week, the President said he would have an update for us on international travel restrictions in a few days.&nbsp; Do you have any update on that?&nbsp; And do you believe it&#8217;s time for the U.S. to reopen its borders?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY RAIMONDO:&nbsp; I do not have an update on that except to say a couple of things: International travel is vital, and it&#8217;s vital to commerce.&nbsp; And we are taking a methodical approach based on data and based on science.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My primary message with respect to that and to the American people: Get vaccinated.&nbsp; Like, increasingly, this is a disease of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; Ninety-seven percent of people in hospitals with COVID are unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, if you&#8217;re asking me, you know, what can we do to get our economy back on track &#8212; get vaccinated.&nbsp; Because as more people do that, then we can continue to think about opening travel, going back into the office, et cetera.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary Raimondo.&nbsp; We appreciate you.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick follow up on training?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; She&#8217;s got to go.&nbsp; Busy day.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Couple items for you at the top.&nbsp; This afternoon, the President will bring together leaders from both the labor and business community at the White House to talk about the critical need to invest in America&#8217;s economic strength by passing the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>While some of the participants at this roundtable may have sat across the negotiating table in the past, now they&#8217;ve joined together as part of a broad coalition of labor and business leaders backing this plan.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re joined in their support by bipartisan leaders in Washington, governors, mayors, and an overwhelming majority of the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I also wanted to note that today the Department of Justice is announcing, or has announced, the launch of five gun trafficking strike forces in regions around the country to combat the uptick in gun crimes that we&#8217;ve seen over the last 18 months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of this announcement, the Attorney General and Deputy Attorney General will visit the headquarters of ATF in Washington before the Attorney General travels to Chicago to meet with the leaders from the Chicago Police Department and attend a listening session with participants in a group that offers innovative programming to reduce gun violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>The regional strike forces we&#8217;ve talked about a bit in the past, but they will leverage existing resources to ensure sustained efforts across city and state boundaries to help stem the supply of illegally trafficked firearms in five key regions: New York, Chicago, Los Angeles, the San Francisco Bay Area/Sacramento region, and Washington, D.C.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this is part of the administration&#8217;s comprehensive crime reduction strategy announced last month by &#8212; at the White House with Attorney General Garland.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to targeting gun traffickers to keep guns out of the hands of criminals, the President&#8217;s plan bolsters local law enforcement efforts by giving them the resources they need to hire more police officers and engage in effective community policing.&nbsp;<br><br>I also wanted to note that, this afternoon, the President will sign H.R. 1652, which will help strengthen and restore funding for the Crime Victims Fund, which has lost billions of dollars over the last five years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This was originally passed in 1984 and &#8212; which established the Crime Victims Fund, which received most of its fundings &#8212; funds through deposits from criminal fines and penalties from convictions in federal cases and does not receive any appropriated funding of taxpayer dollars.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The awards grants the &#8212; this &#8212; the awards grants to states, local governments, and other entities through DOJ Office for Victims of Crime.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, Josh.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Three subjects.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, given the spread of the Delta variant, return to offices, is the administration looking at new mask guidance, as reported by The Washington Post?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know that the head of the CDC, our public health arm, just spoke to this earlier this morning and made clear that there had not been a decision to change our mask guidance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two, it&#8217;s being reported that President Biden plans to impose sanctions on Cuban officials because of the attacks on protesters.&nbsp; Can you outline the administration&#8217;s goals with regard to those sanctions?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I can confirm for all of you that there will be more from the Department of Treasury and the Department of State later this afternoon on sanctions.&nbsp; And the announcement will be coming from then &#8212; from them.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I &#8212; in terms of our approach to Cuba and what we&#8217;re trying to accomplish, we have, of course, condemned mass detention, sham trials, and disappearances that are attempts to threaten the Cuban people into silence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We continue to call for swift &#8212; the swift release of peaceful protesters who have unjustly been detained.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made clear over the last week that addressing this moment was a priority for the administration and for President Biden, and that he has &#8212; he had asked his team to look into a range of options that would both help the Cuban people, help provide humanitarian assistance, help look into addressing issues like the lack of Internet access, and that also sanctions authority was a part of those considerations.&nbsp; So this is an announcement that will be coming later this afternoon.<br><br>I&#8217;d also note that we&#8217;ll continue to engage closely and coordinate with our international partners, from the OAS to the U.N. and others, to collectively condemn the actions of the Cuban government.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then last, real quick, National Association of Realtors says that home prices are up 24.3 percent from a year ago to $363,300 &#8212; a record.&nbsp; Are home prices too high for an economy that&#8217;s supposed to be growing from the bottom up and middle out?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say the President is quite focused on making sure we&#8217;re doing everything we can to help middle-class families as the economy is recovering and as there are ongoing challenges in our economy that have been longstanding, including supply chain issues, which you and many others are quite familiar with.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as he talked about a little bit last night, there are a range of factors that impact that &#8212; the shortage of lumber that is starting to pick back up has, of course, impacted the building of new homes, which has raised the pri- &#8212; the prices of older homes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, his focus and a big focus of this administration is on addressing supply chain issues to help address some of these skyrocketing prices in the market.&nbsp; But, also, he is focused on providing assistance to renters, to homeowners, and others to get through this period of time in our economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, today, China rejected a WHO plan for a second phase of an investigation into the origins of the coronavirus, including audits of laboratories and markets.&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s reaction to that?&nbsp; And how will this impact the U.S. dealing with China on this going forward?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first reiterate that we &#8212; the United States supports the WHO plan for phase two, which commits to ensuring these studies are scientific, transparent, expert-led, and free from interference.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have certainly seen the PRC’s comments again rejecting phase two of a WHO study.&nbsp; We’re deeply disappointed.&nbsp; Their position is irresponsible and, frankly, dangerous.&nbsp; Alongside other member stat- &#8212; member count- &#8212; states around the world, we continue to call for China to provide the needed access to data and samples.&nbsp; And this is critical so we can understand to prevent the next pandemic.&nbsp; This is about saving lives in the future.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not a time to be stonewalling.&nbsp;<br><br>I would note that we believe in a multilateral approach; that has not been an approach that has been taken prior to the President taken office &#8212; taking office, and that has been a big focus of his strategy &#8212; strategy as it relates to our engagement with China.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; and that relates to our approach to global health security, which is why we rejoined the WHO on day one.&nbsp; Unfortunately, phase one, as you all know, did not yield the data and access from China that we think is necessary.&nbsp; But our support for a multilateral approach and the phase two plan is because it&#8217;s rigorous and science-based.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But most importantly, it&#8217;s not just the United States calling for this.&nbsp; As a part of our renewed engagement and our efforts to build a coalition of support around the world with allies and partners, we&#8217;re joined by the international community on this &#8212; partners and multilateral organizations who are also calling for and pressuring China to be engaged in the sta- &#8212; the second phase of this discussion.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note &#8212; I&#8217;m almost done; there&#8217;s a lot to say about this topic.&nbsp; In Cornwall, which many of you were with us &#8212; with us for that trip, the G7 leaders, together, called for a transparent, evidence-based investigation, including in China.&nbsp; And after the phase one study, we were joined by allies and partners across the world in a joint statement calling for a transparent and independent analysis expressing our concerns over the lack of access and urging momentum.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s clear China isn&#8217;t living up to their obligations.&nbsp; What our focus is on is building this multilateral effort and support for putting pressure on and making clear that it&#8217;s unacceptable and dangerous.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you foresee any consequences for China for this decision?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of any policy process.&nbsp; I will tell you that, again, our approach to China, as it relates to global health security, is going to continue to be in a coordinated fashion with our international partners.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one last one on China.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They also started a new crackdown in Hong Kong, this time on children&#8217;s book authors.&nbsp; Any thoughts on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we have expressed many times before &#8212; unfortunately, because there has been reason to express many times before &#8212; our concerns about the crackdown on freedom of speech, freedom of media, a crackdown on &#8212; on human rights activists in Hong Kong.&nbsp; And we continue to express that.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You mentioned there had not been a decision to change the guidelines on wearing a face mask for fully vaccinated Americans.&nbsp; But have there been any conversations within the administration about possibly changing those guidelines?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we are guided by the science, and we&#8217;re guided by our public health experts.&nbsp; And any decision would come from the CDC.&nbsp; The head of the CDC spoke to this earlier this morning.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So conversations within the administration &#8212; that&#8217;s what the Washington Post was also reporting: There were early conversations in the administration about possibly changing those guidelines.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ve seen the reporting, but what I can tell you is that there has been no decision to change our mask guidelines.&nbsp; Any decisions about public health would be driven by the CDC.&nbsp; But, of course, we are engaged with public health experts and the CDC about how to continue to attack the virus.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve never said that battle is over; it&#8217;s still ongoing.<br><br>It would be more concerning &#8212; or should be more concerning to all of you and the American people &#8212; if we were not having those conversations.&nbsp; So, there are certainly conversations about steps we can and should take.&nbsp; But I think Dr. Walensky was quite clear this morning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one quick follow-up.&nbsp; We heard the CDC Director today warn about the rise in the Delta variant, saying that it&#8217;s spreading with incredible efficiency.&nbsp; At what point would the White House reconsider the protocols for the President and for administration officials?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re guided by the public health guidance and the CDC guidelines, and that&#8217;s what we abide by here.&nbsp; They have not changed those, and so we continue to abide by the guidelines we have announced to all of you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Obviously, there are a lot of parents who are wondering what school is going to look like in the fall.&nbsp; And last night, the President said this, quote, “The CDC is going to say that everyone under the age of 12 should probably be wearing a mask in school.&nbsp; That&#8217;s probably what&#8217;s going to happen.”&nbsp; Has the CDC indicated that that is in fact their position already &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They already &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and how soon could we hear from them about that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They did already announce that several weeks ago as a part of their CDC guidance for schools &#8212; because anybody under 12 is not eligible to be vaccinated, so they would not be vaccinated, and so therefore they should be wearing a mask.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Got it.&nbsp; Also, we now know that Hunter Biden is going to be able to meet with prospective buyers at two art shows where his paintings are going to be on display later this year.&nbsp; How does this square with the goal of keeping him in the dark about the buyers of his art as a means to prevent even the appearance of undue influence?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, this showing that was &#8212; that you&#8217;re referencing was previously public.&nbsp; He&#8217;s not going to have any conversations related to the selling of art.&nbsp; That will be left to the gallerist, as was outlined in the agreement that we announced just a few weeks ago.&nbsp;<br><br>We believe this is a reasonable system that has been established that allows for Hunter Biden to work in his profession within appropriate safeguards.&nbsp; So he&#8217;s not going to discuss anything related to the selling of art.&nbsp; And I would reiterate that the gallerist will be the only person who handles transactions or conversations in that vein and will reject any offer that is out of the ordinary.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Wouldn&#8217;t it be more transparent to just release the names of the buyers so that everyone would know who purchased this art and how much they paid?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t &#8212; we won&#8217;t know who the buyers are; Hunter Biden won&#8217;t know who the buyers are.&nbsp; So, I think the re- &#8212; the origin, I think, of this line of questioning, which is understandable, is about whether this would provide un- &#8212; provide a situation for undue influence.&nbsp; But we won&#8217;t know who they are, so there&#8217;s no scenario where they could provide influence.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Couldn&#8217;t they just announce on social media that they bought a painting?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I think we have set up a system which we feel is appropriate &#8212; has appropriate safeguards.&nbsp; We believe that Hunter Biden, just like any child of a President, should be able to pursue their professions and their passions.&nbsp; And any selling of the art would be through the gallerist.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On schools, first: Now that the Education Department admits they made a mistake in their guide for reopening by in- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; How so?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, they included advice from the Abolitionist Teaching Network, and they came out and said that was not supposed to be in there.&nbsp; Is the administration going to follow up with school districts to make sure that the Abolitionist Teaching Network material is not in lesson plans?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, just to be clear, for the context &#8212; because I know you love context of what &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; you&#8217;re asking about here &#8212; what you&#8217;re referring to is a citation in a report of which there were 1,000 citations.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m quite impressed with your researchers for finding one of a thousand citations.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It was an error in a lengthy document to include this citation.&nbsp; This specific site does not endor- &#8212; we &#8212; does not represent the administration&#8217;s view, and we don&#8217;t endorse the recommendations of this group.&nbsp; And I believe it&#8217;s been removed or is in the process of being removed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But we are close to the schools reopening.&nbsp; And is there any concern if you don&#8217;t endorse this material that was in there &#8212; citation or not &#8212; that it&#8217;s in lesson plans?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that &#8212; as we &#8212; we said many times before &#8212; we don&#8217;t dictate or recommend specific curriculum decisions from the federal government.&nbsp; That is and will continue to be handled at the local level.&nbsp; And we believe that the American people trust teachers to make those decisions, not government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on masks: A few weeks ago, the President said we were “closer than ever to declaring our independence from a deadly virus.”&nbsp; Is that still the case if you guys are now reportedly considering asking vaccinated people to wear masks again?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, the CDC Director, who oversees decisions along those lines and all of our public health decisions, made clear that that was not a decision that had been made, just a few hours ago.&nbsp; So, I point out that first.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, I would say: What the President was referring to and continues to talk about, as he did last night at a town hall, is that we&#8217;re quite proud of the progress that&#8217;s been made.&nbsp; People over 65 &#8212; more than 80 percent are vaccinated.&nbsp; Almost 70 percent of adults are vaccinated.&nbsp; A hundred and sixty-two million Americans are vaccinated.&nbsp; That is certainly progress.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we are still at war with the virus; we&#8217;ve never said that would be over.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve always said that we&#8217;d be &#8212; continued to &#8212; continuing to focus on ensuring we&#8217;re meeting people where they are and getting them vaccinated, keeping them safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, the President said, in May, &#8220;vaxxed or masked.&#8221;&nbsp; Is &#8212; I think a lot of people got the vaccine because they were hearing him say, &#8220;If you get the vaccine, you don&#8217;t have to wear masks anymore.&#8221;&nbsp; So &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And that continues to be CDC guidance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you can say that that&#8217;s going to be the guidance forever?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I am not the CDC Director.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand, but people don&#8217;t care who tells him to wear a mask.&nbsp; If it&#8217;s the White House &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They should care.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; if it&#8217;s the White House or the CDC, what difference does it make?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Shouldn&#8217;t they care if it&#8217;s a doctor or medical expert or a spokesperson?&nbsp; I think most Americans actually do care.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s the government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Kelly, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a conversation about encouraging people to make the personal choice that Dr. Walensky talked about today &#8212; if they, for example, are vaccinated but live in a state with low vaccination rates or have other considerations?&nbsp; Is part of your messaging going to be encouraging the personal choice piece on mask wearing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that is currently our messaging, right?&nbsp; So I would say that for communities, where there are lower rates of vaccination &#8212; and, as we know, that&#8217;s really concentrated in only a handful of states across the country where most of the cases are coming from, as we&#8217;ve seen the rise in the Delta variant, which is more transmissible, and, if you&#8217;re not vaccinated, it is transferring, no question, more quickly across people &#8212; people should wear masks.&nbsp; And that is something we will continue to encourage leaders and civic leaders and educators and people who are trusted voices in communities to make clear.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And those are vaccinated people you&#8217;re referring to &#8212; to make the personal choice to wear the mask in those high-rate areas?&nbsp; That’s what I&#8217;m asking about.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s not the advice of the CDC at this point in time, so that is not a message we are conveying to people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Dr. Walensky said today that it can be a personal choice with the vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Of course.&nbsp; Of course, it can be.&nbsp; And some people make that decision because they are immunocompromised, because they have family members, because they just want an extra layer of protection, and we should all respect that.&nbsp; But it is not proactive guidance that the CDC is providing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last night, the President said, “You&#8217;re not going to get COVID if you have these vaccinations.”&nbsp; Why did he say that when that is not what the science says?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what the science says is that 97 percent of hospitalizations are people who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; So, yes, there are cases of individuals who are vaccinated, to be absolutely clear, who &#8212; who do have &#8212; gotten COVID.&nbsp; It is a very small percentage and a small number of people.<br>&nbsp;<br>And those cases &#8212; vast, vast, vast majority are asymptomatic and they have &#8212; they have minor symptoms, which means that you are largely protected.&nbsp; That was the point he was trying to make last night.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a couple of days since we talked about the breakthrough case on the campus here and that you acknowledged there were additional breakthrough cases.&nbsp; Can you give us, now, the number of breakthrough cases that have occurred during the Biden presidency?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, that our medical experts, our health experts have been conveying from the beginning, as have we, that there would be cases of individuals who are vaccinated who tested positive for COVID.&nbsp; There are 2,000 people who work on the campus, and, of course, that means that, just statistically speaking, there will be people who are vaccinated individuals who get COVID on the campus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I announced yesterday or conveyed yesterday was what our policy would be moving forward.&nbsp; But, no, I don&#8217;t think you can expect that we&#8217;re going to be providing numbers of breakthrough cases, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Really?&nbsp; That&#8217;s not transparency to give us a number &#8212; not the names, but a number of these cases?&nbsp; You must have that information.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Kelly, I think, one, we&#8217;re in a very different place than we were several months ago.&nbsp; The vast, vast, vast majority of individuals who are vaccinated who get COVID will have &#8212; will be asymptomatic or have mild cases.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Every individual at this White House has been offered a vaccine, and we have been very clear that we will be transparent with anyone who has had close proximity contact with the President or any of the four principles, as deemed by the White House Medical Unit, with all of you.&nbsp; And if they &#8212; if they approve having their name released, we will also release their names, but we will protect their privacy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That will be our policy moving forward, and we understand and agree that that is in the public interest.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, last night, at the CNN Town Hall, the President was asked by an &#8212; a restauranteur about the worker shortage that the Commerce Secretary just called “acute.”&nbsp; She described it as a “skills gap,” but the restauranteur said that he had, right now, job openings that he can&#8217;t fill.&nbsp; And he asked the President if there&#8217;s anything that his administration can do to help him and his business.&nbsp; The President seemed to struggle with an answer.&nbsp; Is there anything that his administration can do to help that restauranteur or people who are similarly situated with this acute worker shortage?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that we have already implemented &#8212; and the money has gone out the door &#8212; goes &#8212; it continues to go out the door for our Restaurant Restabilization Program &#8212; something that was a part of the American Rescue Plan and helped many, many hundreds of restaurants across the country stay open, reopen.&nbsp; And that was assistance that came from the American Rescue Plan that the President signed into law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think what the President was noting is that, at this point in time, it&#8217;s also a workers’ market.&nbsp; And in some places, it may be that you have to pay more wages in order to attract workers.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have all the details, of course, about his individual circumstance, but we implemented a major program that helped restaurants stay open &#8212; something we strongly supported, we advocated for as a part of the package.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I can ask a follow-up to the question about the President&#8217;s son and the art gallery event.&nbsp; You said that Hunter Biden is not going to discuss anything related to the sale of his art.&nbsp; Is that a promise that has been made in writing?&nbsp; And if so, is that an agreement that could be made available to the public?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m making that clear to all of you now that that is an agreement that has been made as a part of this &#8212; as a part of these events.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is it in writing?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can check and see if there&#8217;s more detail.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But I think it&#8217;s pretty clear what the agreement is, so I&#8217;m not sure it&#8217;s more complicated than that.&nbsp; But I will see if there&#8217;s more to provide.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; One on masks and then one quick one on the Fed after that.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci told reporters earlier today that there isn&#8217;t enough research to know whether breakthrough cases can result in long COVID.&nbsp; The President has repeatedly told the public that, you know, they should &#8212; they&#8217;re safe from the worst effects of COVID.&nbsp; How can he be sure without this research?&nbsp; And if there&#8217;s even a chance that breakthrough cases can result in long COVID, why not recommend masks more widely?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what the President is referring to &#8212; one, we&#8217;ve seen some interesting polling over the last week &#8212; I believe it was a CBS poll &#8212; that showed that vaccinated people in the country are more fearful about the Delta variant than unvaccinated people.&nbsp; That&#8217;s clearly concerning to us because unvaccinated people should be more fearful.&nbsp; And what the President wanted to convey to people in the country is the impact and effect of getting vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we also know statistically that 97 percent of hospitalizations are for people who are unvaccinated and that the vast majority of cases are asymptomatic or have very mild symptoms, which the health and medical experts will tell you &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We’re talking about the long-term &#8212; long-term effects here &#8212; right? &#8212; which we don’t know yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s true.&nbsp; There&#8217;s still research about a range of components of the impacts of COVID over the long term, which our health and medical leaders will advise us on.&nbsp; They also have not changed their guidance on masks.&nbsp; That is not a determination that&#8217;s being made by &#8212; from a political standpoint or from anyone in the White House.&nbsp; That is something the CDC and our health and medical experts are advising on, and they look at a range of factors.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the Fed.&nbsp; Is the President concerned at all that choosing a new Federal Reserve Chairman during a period of economic uncertainty and inflation could complicate economic recovery or spook the markets?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I just have nothing to preview for you in terms of the end of the term next winter.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, you already asked.&nbsp; Go ahead, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On infrastructure, Senator Carper, one of your allies, said that he wants to make sure that the water infrastructure measures that the Senate already passed and the Surface Transportation Reauthorization bill that passed out of his committee are also included in the infrastructure agreement.&nbsp; I know that the bipartisan group said yesterday that they were 99 percent of the way there.&nbsp; I know there are some issues that Republican lawmakers are working out with the White House right now.&nbsp; Are Senator Carper’s concerns also something that the White House is aware of and working on at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re certainly aware of the concerns that have been expressed, or asks or requests by a range of members.&nbsp; This is typically what happens, as you all know, in this period of time where we&#8217;re very close to a point where there&#8217;s going to be a vote on a motion to proceed.&nbsp; And everybody who has initiatives, who has priorities is going to make their voice heard.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a part of the process.&nbsp; We respect that.&nbsp; So, certainly, we&#8217;re engaged in discussions, as is the leadership.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I would also note that &#8212; that we are &#8212; we see clear signs of momentum.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re quite &#8212; we were quite encouraged by the letter &#8212; yesterday&#8217;s letter signed by 11 Republicans and 11 Democrats showing positive signs about being able to go forward soon.&nbsp; And the President is, of course, eager to deliver these economic ben- &#8212; benefits to Americans in red states and blue states that they&#8217;ve long been waiting for.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think there&#8217;s flexibility to add more money to this bill for those measures that were &#8212; got wide support on the Hill, in the Senate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think there was a clear agreement that the President and members of both parties stood outside of the White House and announced just a few weeks ago.&nbsp; Of course, there will be final discussions over the coming days as they work to finalize the bill text.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on the filibuster: The President said last night that getting rid of it would throw the entire Congress into chaos and nothing will get done, and that&#8217;s sort of his justification for not getting rid of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With maybe the exception of anything that can kind of be done along party lines and perhaps this infrastructure bill as well &#8212; likely this infrastructure bill &#8212; is anything getting done?&nbsp; Will anything get done, you know, that can&#8217;t just be done through reconciliation, you know, once we get past this infrastructure thing?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And/or if the things that can&#8217;t get done are things like voting rights that are so big &#8212; or dealing with climate or immigration &#8212; is there really any difference between having the filibuster in place and getting rid of it?&nbsp; What&#8217;s sort of the President&#8217;s justification for not getting rid of it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the President doesn&#8217;t make the decision on filibuster rules or parliamentary rules in the Senate; the Senate does.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll leave that to the Senate.&nbsp; It also requires the majority in the Senate to support a rule change.&nbsp; And so, what he was referring to is simply what that process would look like and the fact that there are some in the Senate who have said they would halt all business if that conversation were to happen.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, in some means, he was reporting out what is publicly known about what the process might look like moving forward.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll leave it to all of you to whip count on how many votes there would be for filibuster changes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; and you&#8217;re saying that there is &#8212; that he&#8217;s not engaging on this.&nbsp; He has kept &#8212; continually talked about wanting to move back to the talking filibuster.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; And &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he is weighing in on a part of the filibuster (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And &#8212; and he talked about that last night.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And talked about the fact that it shouldn&#8217;t be so easy to be obstreperous &#8212; I think is a word he’s used before I’ve wanted to use in here &#8212; and it shouldn&#8217;t be so easy to prevent legislation from moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I’ll also note that, you know, the President ran for office because he felt that people&#8217;s fundamental rights were being violated by the last President.&nbsp; And voting rights and racial equality is central to what he wants to do as President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So he has already taken a number of steps.&nbsp; He will continue to advocate for the For the People Act &#8212; which every Democrat voted to advance after he worked the phones &#8212; and the John Lewis Voting Rights Act.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He and the Vice President have launched an all-of-government effort to protect and advance voting rights in every way we can through the executive branch after his executive order.&nbsp; And the White House Counsel&#8217;s Office Legislative team, Public Engagement team, and the Domestic Policy team all remain very engaged on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So he is going to use every lever at his disposal.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to continue to elevate these issues, but he does not, alone, make changes to the &#8212; or does not even have a official role in making changes to procedures in the Senate.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Anne.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the Delta variant: We heard the President, last night, speak at some length about the effects on individual Americans &#8212; what the consequences are from this new, highly transmissible variant if you&#8217;re not vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wonder to what extent is he worried, are you worried about the effects &#8212; one step beyond that &#8212; on his agenda and the things that he wants to do this fall if we do end up where the trajectory currently is with basically two camps.&nbsp; You have safe, vaccinated Americans, and you have unsafe, unvaccinated Americans.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He has said before he wants to be President for everyone and have an agenda to match.&nbsp; How can that come true, moving into the fall, if you have so many people in this country who are still at risk of hospitalization and death?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So just so &#8212; I&#8217;m just trying to understand your question.&nbsp; How will &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The impact on the agenda &#8212; his agenda.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In what way though?&nbsp; Like his legislative agenda?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I mean, his &#8212; yes.&nbsp; His general agenda for improving the lives of Americans &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; across a variety of spheres, as he&#8217;s talked about, movingly, several times, including last night.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What he wants to do &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, no, I just wanted to make sure I understood your question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, look, I think that he said in the beginning, and he reiterated last night, that getting the pandemic under control, protecting Americans from the spread of the virus has been, continues to be his number one priority.&nbsp; And that he&#8217;s going to govern for all Americans &#8212; Democrats, independents, Republicans, even people who did not vote for him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, one of the reasons that he does &#8212; did an event like the town hall last night, and one of the reasons why he speaks about what the dire impacts are of the spread of the most transmissible version of the virus we&#8217;ve seen to date is because he wants people to be protected.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve seen, in a lot of these states, there has been a &#8212; you know, misinformation traveling.&nbsp; There has been a, in some cases, a political bent of who is and isn&#8217;t getting vaccinated, unfortunately.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We don&#8217;t want this to be a partisan issue.&nbsp; So, he&#8217;s going to keep at it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure on his legislative agenda how that &#8212; I don&#8217;t know how to make that connection, but it will continue to be his priority moving forward.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on Iraq: the Iraqi Prime Minister will be here Monday.&nbsp; In April, the administration said that the U.S. and Iraq have agreed to eventually withdraw U.S. combat forces and that talks would take place beginning then &#8212; toward that end.&nbsp; Can you give us an update on where those talks stand, and whether the President will be able to announce either a date certain or more specific plans about the withdrawal of U.S. combat forces on Monday?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, well, I&#8217;m not going to get too far ahead of the meeting, which won’t surprise you.&nbsp; But I will tell you that &#8212; I will remind you, I should say &#8212; as Prime Minister Kadhimi stated publicly last week &#8212; even with the decreasing need for U.S. forces with a combat role on Iraq, his government is requesting continuing support from the United States and the coalition for training and enabling its forces, logistics, intelligence sharing, and other areas of security cooperation.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve responded to that request and the discussions between our delegations have been extremely constructive and are ongoing.&nbsp; U.S. military forces are in Iraq, at Iraq&#8217;s invitation, to support Iraqi forces in their fight against ISIS.&nbsp; We routinely discuss the activities of U.S. forces in Iraq and evolution of the mission, from the height of the ISIS campaign to today, where ISIS remains a threat but major combat operations have ended and Iraqi capacity has increased significantly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, this is an ongoing discussion.&nbsp; We &#8212; I would note the Prime Minister&#8217;s comments.&nbsp; Our delegations will continue to discuss.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more to say &#8212; I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;ll have more to say after their meeting.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to ask questions on Tokyo Olympic Games.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First Lady Jill Biden is bound to attend the opening ceremony.&nbsp; The Opening ceremony’s creative director was fired yesterday for &#8212; over the Holocaust joke he made in 1990s.&nbsp; Does White House have any comment on that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly, we support that decision and disagree with his comments &#8212; offensive comments.&nbsp; The First Lady will still plan to attend the Opening Ceremony to support U.S. athletes and represent the U.S. government at the highest level.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Florida Governor DeSantis was talking about mask mandates for kids earlier this morning.&nbsp; And he said, “We&#8217;re not doing that in Florida.&nbsp; We need our kids to breathe.&nbsp; We need our kids to be able to be kids.”&nbsp; He said “It’s terribly uncomfortable for them to do it.”&nbsp; That obviously goes against the CDC guidance &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for kids under 12 who aren&#8217;t vaccinated and what the President said last night.&nbsp; Is that putting kids in Florida at risk?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as a parent myself &#8212; and I know you are one &#8212; if I were a parent in Florida, that would be greatly concerning to me because kids under the age of 12 are not vaccinated; they&#8217;re not eligible yet.&nbsp; As the President said last night, obviously it&#8217;s going to be led by the FDA, but certainly we hope that will be soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But that puts kids at risk.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not aligned with public health guidelines.&nbsp; We know masks are not the most comfortable thing.&nbsp; I will say, my kids are quite adjusted to them, as I know many kids are.&nbsp; So, certainly, we would have concern about any step that doesn&#8217;t abide by public health guidelines and we think it puts people at greater risk.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President frustrated that in the fall when kids go back to school across the country that there could be very different standards for kids under 12?&nbsp; And is there something that he can do about that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President can speak out, as he did last night, about the risks of the Delta variant that is more transmissible than any variant we&#8217;ve seen to date, about the risk to young people of the spread of COVID, and about the fact that the CDC has put out clear guidelines, clear mitigation steps that can be taken to keep families safe, kids sape &#8212; safe, individuals safe, and then there are a range of steps that people can take.&nbsp;<br><br>I think what&#8217;s notable about the CDC education guidelines is that it made very clear it&#8217;s important for kids to be back in school, and that that&#8217;s important for their mental health.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important for kids to be learning.&nbsp; We don’t want to put kids behind who &#8212; you know, and create some sort of an additional educational gap.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But there are recommendations by the public health experts for a reason; he&#8217;ll continue to elevate them.&nbsp; But ultimately, those decisions will be made by local school districts.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kaitlan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Can you confirm that White House officials are involved in these discussions about whether or not they need to update the mask guidance?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the CDC Director made clear that was not a decision made.&nbsp; We are regularly in touch and have regular meetings with our public health officials, including the CDC, about how to continue to address the virus.&nbsp; That shouldn&#8217;t surprise anyone.&nbsp; On &#8212; those conversations cover a range of topics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I think the most important thing for the public is that there hasn&#8217;t been a decision made.&nbsp; It will always be led with public health guidance.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve made that very clear this morning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s just unusual that no one will confirm the discussions are actually happening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think because the report on it was a little breathless about what it implied was happening when the CDC Director said that&#8217;s not a decision that&#8217;s been made.&nbsp; And we want to be clear to the public: Nobody is being advised &#8212; who&#8217;s vaccinated &#8212; to wear a mask.&nbsp; That is not what the public health guidelines says.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the White House concerned about the messaging aspect of this, given not having to wear a mask is often a perk of being vaccinated that the White House and other top health officials have touted?&nbsp; So, are you concerned that if there is a change to the mask guidance for vaccinated individuals when they&#8217;re indoors that it would be harder to sell vaccinations, essentially?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there hasn&#8217;t been a change.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s pretty clear now that if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you don&#8217;t wear &#8212; need to wear a mask.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re not vacckinate [sic] &#8212; vaccinated &#8212; that’s a hard word &#8212; you do &#8212; you should wear a mask, according to the public health guidelines.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not a prediction that the CDC Director made this morning.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We certainly know that it is important &#8212; even as parents, as Karen was asking about before &#8212; when you have kids, you&#8217;re not wearing a mask.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not wearing a mask at the playground, or I&#8217;m not wearing a mask, you know, indoors; my kids are still wearing masks.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not terribly confusing to people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you know, we&#8217;ll continue to communicate, convey what the accurate public health guidelines is.&nbsp; Nothing has changed about that.&nbsp; And, of course, we have ongoing discussions about how to keep the American people safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just related to that, is the White House position still the same on vaccine verification?&nbsp; Have there been any conversations about promoting businesses choosing to verify vaccinated status for attending concerts or dining indoors?&nbsp; Is there &#8212; is there any discussion around vaccine verification, or changing the posture?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is not &#8212; our position has not changed, nor do I anticipate it would, on guidance coming from the federal government.&nbsp; It is also entirely appropriate for private-sector entities and universities and hospitals to make decisions about how to keep their community safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If we can go back to the President&#8217;s comment about ending the filibuster, how it would create chaos &#8212; what did that mean exactly?&nbsp; What kind of chaos would be created?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as I answered &#8212; I think it was Jen&#8217;s question, over here, in response to her question &#8212; what the President was speaking to is the fact that it&#8217;s a parliamentary process.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not something you&nbsp;<s>wage</s>&nbsp;[wave] a magic wand to change.&nbsp; It will require the majority of votes in the Senate.&nbsp; There would be debate about that process in the Senate.&nbsp; And there are manys &#8212; many individuals in the Senate who have been clear that they would throw the Senate into chaos and halt all progress.&nbsp; So, I think he was reporting out on what you all have publicly reported on yourself.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in regards to Senator Carper, since there&#8217;s no room to lose a Democrat in this, what is the White House doing to get him back on board?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that he&#8217;s characterized himself as &#8220;not on board&#8221; with the infrastructure bill that is incredibly popular and supported by the majority of people across the country, but we also understand and recognize that, in the process of legislating, there are periods where people want to have their voice heard &#8212; we support that; have asks they want to make; have components they want to see in legislation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s the part of the messy process of legislating.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what&#8217;s ongoing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re engaged with a range of members, including, of course, Senator Carper and, of course, working closely with Senate leadership as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just following up on Anne&#8217;s question on Iraq.&nbsp; There has been criticism on the part of the administration that there is a lack of clarity on what the U.S. wants to achieve in Iraq.&nbsp; So, can you explain, beyond defeating ISIS or controlling ISIS, what is it exactly that the President wants to do in Iraq, and perhaps a timeline?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I&#8217;m not sure I can say much more than what I said to &#8212; which it was an extensive answer, I will say &#8212; to Anne&#8217;s question, which was that we are in Iraq at the invitation of Iraqi leadership, obviously.&nbsp; And they have asked our military to remain &#8212; to continue to play a role in &#8212; their government is requesting continuing support from us and the coalition for training and enabling their forces &#8212; its forces, logistics, intelligence sharing, and other areas of security cooperation.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the Prime Minister spoke to last week.<br>&nbsp;<br>I also noted that we are in ongoing discussions with them.&nbsp; The Prime Minister is going to be here next week, but I don&#8217;t think I have much more to preview for you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you clarify what is the President&#8217;s latest position on his proposal to partition Iraq, or soft partition Iraq, that he has supported in the past?&nbsp; Can you give us clarification on what&#8217;s his latest position on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think he&#8217;s made that proposal in any recent time, but he&#8217;s looking forward to the meeting with the Prime Minister.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick question on Guantanamo Bay.&nbsp; I heard you say, last week &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that the goal is to close the detentions facility there.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess 39 detainees remain.&nbsp; What are the next steps that the administration is taking to close Guantanamo Bay?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would point you to the Department of Defense and their leadership on this effort.&nbsp; I &#8212; there are 39 detainees who remain at Guantanamo Bay; 10 are eligible for transfer, of course; 17 are eligible for a Periodic Review Board; 10 are involved in the military commissions process; 2 detainees have been convicted.&nbsp; So, I would point you to the Department of Defense, and they can outline more specifically.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; I got to go because we got to go see the President.<br>&nbsp;<br>All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) breaking news (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not going anywhere.&nbsp; We&#8217;re here, Brian.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>1:32 P.M.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 1652</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/bill-signed-h-r-1652/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 20:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24805</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, July 22, 2021, the President signed into law: H.R. 1652, the “VOCA Fix to Sustain the Crime Victims Fund Act of 2021,” which requires funds collected from deferred prosecution and non-prosecution agreements to be deposited into the Crime Victims Fund; increases the crime victim compensation formula grant to provide eligible programs with 75&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, July 22, 2021, the President signed into law:<br><br>H.R. 1652, the “VOCA Fix to Sustain the Crime Victims Fund Act of 2021,” which requires funds collected from deferred prosecution and non-prosecution agreements to be deposited into the Crime Victims Fund; increases the crime victim compensation formula grant to provide eligible programs with 75 percent of the amounts awarded during the preceding year; allows states to waive a requirement that programs promote victim cooperation with law enforcement; and allows or requires states to waive matching requirements for grant funds under certain circumstances.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawal Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/nominations-and-withdrawal-sent-to-the-senate/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24799</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Andrew Philip Hunter, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Air Force, vice William Roper. &#160; &#160; &#160;Jonathan Kanter, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Attorney General, vice Makan Delrahim, resigned. &#160; &#160; &#160;Thomas R. Nides, of Minnesota, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Andrew Philip Hunter, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Air Force, vice William Roper.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jonathan Kanter, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Attorney General, vice Makan Delrahim, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Thomas R. Nides, of Minnesota, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the State of Israel.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Graham Scott Steele, of California, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, vice Bimal Patel, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Tom Udall, of New Mexico, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to New Zealand, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Independent State of Samoa.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Tamara Cofman Wittes, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Michael T. Harvey.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>     Andrew Philip Hunter, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of the Army, vice Bruce D. Jette, which was sent to the Senate on July 20, 2021.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Measures on Cuba</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-measures-on-cuba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“The United States stands with the brave Cubans who have taken to the streets to oppose 62 years of repression under a communist regime.” – President Biden The world watched on July 11 as tens of thousands of Cuban citizens marched in cities across Cuba to demand freedom from both the pandemic and from the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>“The United States stands with the brave Cubans who have taken to the streets to oppose 62 years of repression under a communist regime.” </em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"><em>– President Biden</em></p>



<p>The world watched on July 11 as tens of thousands of Cuban citizens marched in cities across Cuba to demand freedom from both the pandemic and from the decades of repression and economic suffering to which they have been subjected by Cuba&#8217;s authoritarian regime. The United States stands with the Cuban people, and therefore addressing the moment and the ongoing situation in Cuba is a top priority for the Biden-Harris Administration. At President Biden’s direction, the United States is actively pursuing measures that will both support the Cuban people and hold the Cuban regime accountable.  </p>



<p><strong>Holding the Cuban Regime Accountable</strong><br>On July 22, the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) sanctioned one Cuban individual and one Cuban entity for serious human rights abuse, pursuant to Executive Order 13818, which builds upon and implements the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act and targets perpetrators of serious human rights abuse and corruption around the world. This action targets the Cuban Minister of Defense and the Brigada Especial Nacional del Ministerio del Interior of the Cuban Ministry of the Interior for their role in facilitating the repression of peaceful, pro-democratic protests in Cuba that began on July 11.</p>



<p><strong>Engaging the International Community</strong><br>The Administration remains deeply concerned about the welfare of the hundreds of protestors who have been unjustly detained and disappeared simply for demanding their most fundamental rights.  The President continues to call for the swift release of those peaceful protestors who have been unjustly detained. The Administration is also actively engaged with the Organization of American States (OAS), the United Nations, and our international partners to collectively condemn the violence and repression upon the Cuban people for demanding freedom.<br><br><strong>Ensuring Cuban Citizens Have Internet Access</strong><br>The Administration is actively collaborating with the private sector to identify creative ways to ensure that the Cuban people have safe and secure access to the free flow of information on the Internet. The President continues to call on Cuba’s leaders to reinstate and to maintain access to all Internet and telecommunications services for all people within its border, and condemns the use of partial or complete Internet shutdowns and network restrictions imposed by the Cuban Government, which restricts the exercise of human rights and disrupts access to essential services. The intentional blocking of access to the Internet should be strongly condemned by the international community.<br><br><strong>Listening to Cuban American Leaders</strong><br>The Administration has been consistent in its belief that Cuban-Americans are the best ambassadors for freedom and prosperity in Cuba. The Administration will continue to meet with Cuban American leaders and stakeholders as they work to help elevate the voices of demonstrators in Cuba, and provide their recommendations for how the U.S. government can help.<br><br><strong>Reviewing the Remittances Policy</strong><br>The Administration is focused on letting families support one another, by maximizing the flow of remittance payments to the Cuban people. This is a complex issue that requires a measured and thoughtful approach in coordination with experts that will help to inform the Administration’s policy.  The Administration’s guiding principle is ensuring that funds, to the greatest extent possible, get to the Cuban people without a portion of the proceeds being siphoned off by the regime. The President remains concerned that remittances do not reach their intended recipients, including some of the most vulnerable populations on the island, and instead are being used as a stopgap to treat their government&#8217;s failures. <br><br><strong>Restaffing U.S. Embassy Havana</strong><br>The Administration is working to enhance our ability to provide Consular services to the Cuban people given their dire circumstances under an oppressive authoritarian regime. The re-staffing of our Embassy in Havana will serve to enhance our diplomatic, civil society, and Consular service engagement all of which are part of our demonstrated effort to support the Cuban people and their desire for freedom. The Administration is also mindful of the fact that USG personnel have suffered grave injuries while posted to Cuba. Before augmenting our staff in Havana we must do our utmost to ensure that they can safely and securely serve in Cuba.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/22/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-46/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 18:02:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:09 A.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&#160; Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Fauci will present on the effectiveness of the vaccines and cases among the vaccinated, and I will discuss our work to get more people vaccinated and help states curb&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:09 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Fauci will present on the effectiveness of the vaccines and cases among the vaccinated, and I will discuss our work to get more people vaccinated and help states curb the spread of the virus.&nbsp; And Dr. Murthy will talk about the on-the-ground work we’re supporting in communities to get more people vaccinated.&nbsp; And then we’ll open it up for questions.<br><br>Over to Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp; Yesterday, CDC reported 46,318 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is at about 37,700 cases per day, and this represents an increase of 53 percent from the prior seven-day average.&nbsp; The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 35,000 per day &#8212; an increase of about 32 percent from the previous seven-day period.&nbsp; And the seven-day average of daily deaths has also increased to 237 per day &#8212; and increase of about 19 percent from the previous seven-day period.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I want to speak about our need to come together against a common enemy &#8212; SARS-CoV-2 and the Delta variant.&nbsp; The Delta variant is spreading with incredible efficiency and now represents more than 83 percent of the virus circulating in the United States.&nbsp; Compared to the virus we had circulating initially in the United States at the start of the pandemic, the Delta variant is more aggressive and much more transmissible than previously circulating strains.&nbsp; It is one of the most infectious respiratory viruses we know of and that I have seen in my 20-year career.&nbsp;<br><br>We recognize that some of you are still thinking about whether you will get vaccinated.&nbsp; Maybe you&#8217;re seeing your local officials stepping forward publicly to get vaccinated, or maybe you&#8217;re watching on local news that your community hospitals are getting full.&nbsp; Or scarier still, maybe COVID-19 sickness has tragically hit you or your community closer to home.<br><br>If you are still on the fence, if you still have questions about the vaccines, we welcome them.&nbsp; My request to you is this: Ask your questions.&nbsp; Talk to your healthcare provider.&nbsp; Talk to your pharmacist.&nbsp; Talk to your friends and neighbors who have gotten vaccinated and get your questions answered so that you feel comfortable and informed in making this critical decision.&nbsp; And, please, continue to do the things that we know work to protect you and your family until you are fully vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>If you are not vaccinated, please take the Delta variant seriously.&nbsp; This virus has no incentive to let up, and it remains in search of the next vulnerable person to infect.<br><br>Please consider getting vaccinated and take precautions until you do.&nbsp; And if you&#8217;ve already had COVID infection, CDC guidance strongly recommends that you get vaccinated.&nbsp; It gives you longer-lasting and more robust protection with the breadth and depth of coverage needed to conquer the variants currently circulating in this country.&nbsp;<br><br>To those of you who&#8217;ve already gotten vaccinated: I know you&#8217;re watching the rise in cases and have questions about what it means for you.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;re probably worried about two things: whether you will still get COVID despite being vaccinated and which activities are safe.&nbsp;<br><br>Let&#8217;s start with the first concern.&nbsp;&nbsp; Being fully vaccinated gives you a high degree of protection against infection and an even a higher degree of protection against severe illness, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp; That is what these vaccines were designed for and what the clinical trials studied, and the vaccines generally do their job quite well.<br><br>These vaccines are some of the most effective that we have in modern medicine.&nbsp; And the good news is that, current scientific evidence shows that our current vaccines are working as they did in clinical trials, even against the Delta variant.<br><br>Importantly, our data showed that infections are much less common in vaccinated people compared to unvaccinated, and most illness in vaccinated individuals is asymptomatic or mild.&nbsp; The most important public health step is to increase the vaccination coverage in all communities in the U.S. and globally.&nbsp;<br><br>There are places in this country where cases are high and cases caused by the Delta variant are also really high, and many of these areas have low vaccine coverage.&nbsp; In areas with high vaccine coverage and low rates of disease transmission, the chances of you coming in close contact with someone who is infectious is relatively low.<br><br>In contrast, in areas with low vaccine coverage and high transmission, there is a much higher chance of you coming in close contact with one or many persons who are infectious and that, in those cases, the greatest risk is for those who are not fully vaccinated.<br><br>Whether you are vaccinated or not, please know we, together, are not out of the woods yet and you will want to make thoughtful decisions to protect your health and the health of your family and your community.&nbsp; We are yet at another pivotal moment in this pandemic, with cases rising again and some hospitals reaching their capacity in some areas.&nbsp; We need to come together as one nation, unified in our resolve to protect the health of ourselves, our children, our community, our country, and our future with the tools we have available.<br><br>With that, I will turn it over to Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; What I&#8217;d like to address for the next few minutes is the phenomenon that many have been speaking about lately, and that is the occurrence of infection after full vaccination.&nbsp;<br><br>So, let&#8217;s just give a bit of a background on the first slide.&nbsp; What do we mean by that?&nbsp; That is the detection of SARS-CoV-2 equal to or 14 days after completion after all recommended doses of what would be an FDA EUA-authorized vaccines.<br><br>It&#8217;s important to remember, as I&#8217;ll get to in a moment, that infections after vaccination are expected.&nbsp; No vaccine is 100 percent effective.&nbsp; However, even if a vaccine does not completely protect against infection, it usually, if it&#8217;s successful, protects against serious disease.&nbsp; And that’s what I&#8217;d like to spend a moment on.<br><br>If I could have the next slide.<br><br>This is a slide that I put together several years ago in trying to describe the situation with vaccines against the standard childhood and adult diseases, as well as the difficulty we were having with developing vaccines against HIV.<br><br>And when you think about vaccines being successful or unsuccessful &#8212; i.e. a failure &#8212; you really have to look at it in multiple subsets.&nbsp; For example, one element of a successful vaccine &#8212; in one in which there&#8217;s no illness, but there&#8217;s no replication of the virus, no dissemination of the virus, and clearance of the virus.&nbsp; That is something that is an unusual feat for a vaccine to give truly what we call &#8220;sterilizing immunity.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then, there&#8217;s is also, within the framework of a successful vaccine, one in which there&#8217;s no clinical illness, but there is replication of the virus.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t disseminate throughout the body.&nbsp; It stays at the level of entry &#8212; be that the upper airway, the GI tract, or what have you.<br><br>Another element of a successful vaccine is one in which there might be mild illness that really does not interfere with the function of a person; that has replication; mild &#8212; very mild dissemination, but ultimately the virus is cleared.&nbsp;<br><br>You have a failure of a vaccine when, actually, you get frank disease.&nbsp; In other words, you haven&#8217;t prevented the disease caused by the virus or the pathogen in question.&nbsp; In this place, you get substantial replication; you get substantial dissemination; and unless you have a lethal virus that kills the patient, ultimately the virus is cleared from the body.&nbsp;<br><br>So what we&#8217;re talking about when we talk about infection after vaccination, which is clearly being discussed now in the context of the Delta variant &#8212; by no means does that mean that you&#8217;re dealing with an unsuccessful vaccine.&nbsp; The success of the vaccine is based on the prevention of illness.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s just look at that very briefly.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>These are the data that I&#8217;ve shown you multiple times about the efficacy of the Pfizer BioNTech and the Moderna: 95 and 94 percent respectively.&nbsp; Note: It is not 100 percent effective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Next slide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The same holds true for the J&amp;J, which, in the United States, is 72 percent effective against clinically recognizable disease &#8212; not 100 percent effective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, if you go to the last slide, what we&#8217;re really dealing with is effectiveness against serious disease leading to hospitalization and, in some cases, death.</p>



<p>And since the Delta variant is, as Dr. Walensky said, now 83 percent in this country, it&#8217;s the one we&#8217;re dealing with.&nbsp; So even though we are seeing infections after vaccination &#8212; referred commonly to as &#8220;breakthrough infections&#8221; &#8212; the effectiveness against severe disease is still substantial, which is, yet again, another argument which all of us say continually, &#8220;Get vaccinated.&nbsp; It offers good protection against disease.&#8221;</p>



<p>With that, we&#8217;ll go back to Jeff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you both, Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; It is clear that we&#8217;re experiencing what many other countries are experiencing: increased case counts driven by the more transmissible Delta variant.<br><br>We are concerned with the rise in cases among the unvaccinated, but we are also clear that we are in a very different situation than we were earlier this year for three reasons.</p>



<p>First and foremost, as Dr. Fauci just showed, our vaccines work.&nbsp; Fully vaccinated individuals have a high degree of protection against severe illness, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp; While we will see some cases among those who are vaccinated, as to be expected with any vaccine, these cases are generally mild and oftentimes asymptomatic, which is just more proof that the vaccines work.&nbsp; In fact, unvaccinated individuals account for virtually all &#8212; 97 percent &#8212; of the COVID hospitalizations and deaths in the U.S.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, we have fully vaccinated 162 million Americans, including 80 percent of those most vulnerable &#8212; individuals 65 years and older.&nbsp; As a result, we have fundamentally changed the course of this pandemic.&nbsp; The threat is now predominantly only to the unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>The data is clear: The case increases are concentrated in communities with low vaccination rates.&nbsp; In fact, the counties with the highest case rates have significantly lower vaccination rates than counties with lower case rates.&nbsp; This week, just three states &#8212; Florida, Texas, and Missouri; three states with lower vaccination rates &#8212; accounted for 40 percent of all cases nationwide.&nbsp; For the second week in a row, one in five of all cases occurring in Florida alone.&nbsp; And within communities, these cases are primarily among unvaccinated people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The third reason we&#8217;re in a different situation than earlier in the year is that we&#8217;re continuing to make more progress by increasing the number of vaccinated Americans.&nbsp; Importantly, states with the highest case rates are actually seeing their vaccination rates go up.&nbsp; In fact, in the past week, the five states with the highest case rates &#8212; Arkansas, Florida, Louisiana, [Missouri, and] Nevada &#8212; had a higher rate of people getting newly vaccinated compared to the national average.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a very positive trend.&nbsp; For the second week in a row, states with lower vaccination and higher case rates are seeing their vaccination rates grow faster than the national average.&nbsp; People in these states are feeling the impact of being unvaccinated and responding with action.&nbsp; And across the country, in the past 10 days, more than 5.2 million Americans have gotten a shot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, each day, hundreds of thousands of Americans are choosing to protect themselves, their kids, and their neighbors by getting their first shot.&nbsp; And just as importantly, hundreds of thousands more are getting their second shot on the way to being fully vaccinated.&nbsp; These Americans are stepping up and doing their part.&nbsp; Each shot matters.&nbsp; Each additional person fully vaccinated is a step closer to putting this pandemic behind us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re making continued progress in our fight against the virus.&nbsp; And today, we&#8217;re announcing additional resources to get more shots in arms and combat surges, particularly in rural communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President said last night, unvaccinated Americans know and trust people in their own communities to help get them accurate information about vaccines and help answer their questions.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we are announcing that we were sending $100 million to rural health clinics to support vaccine education and outreach efforts in these communities where we are generally seeing low vaccine uptake.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This funding, made possible by the American Rescue Plan, will provide nearly 2,000 rural health clinics the resources they need to better reach unvaccinated Americans in their communities with information about COVID-19 and the vaccines and answers to their questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we work to get more shots in arms, we&#8217;re also doubling down on our efforts to detect, prevent, and respond to outbreaks caused by the Delta variant.&nbsp; Testing and building testing capacity is a key part of our surge response because we know quickly detecting cases allows us to help prevent outbreaks and contain the virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last week, we announced $400 million in American Rescue Plan funding for 1,540 small rural hospitals for COVID-19 to increase testing capacity in rural America.&nbsp; And today, as part of our efforts to reach more vulnerable individuals, we&#8217;re making an additional $1.6 billion investment in American Rescue Plan funding to bolster testing and mitigation measures in high-risk congregate settings, including homeless shelters, mental health and substance abuse treatment centers, domestic violence shelters, and prison systems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These resources will help local health officials and communities identify potential outbreaks before they happen and prevent the further spread of COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our COVID-19 Surge Response Teams are also working with governors and local public health officials to identify specific needs on the ground and provide federal resources and support to fight outbreaks due to the spread of the Delta variant.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are now providing CDC&#8217;s technical expertise, including on genetic sequencing, data analysis, and outbreak response to Missouri, Illinois, and Colorado.<br><br>FEMA will be deploying mobile vaccination clinics in North Carolina.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, HHS Secretary Becerra is traveling to Nevada, where we have deployed federal resources and 100 personnel from FEMA and HHS to support local health officials as they work to mitigate the spread of Delta and increase vaccinations.&nbsp;<br><br>In closing, our whole-of-government response continues to do everything we can to get more Americans fully vaccinated and protected from the virus, and help states and communities curb the spread of the Delta variant.</p>



<p>As the President said last night, it&#8217;s up to each and every single American to do their own part.&nbsp; We know everyone&#8217;s vaccination journey is different.&nbsp; We are ready to get more Americans vaccinated whenever, wherever they&#8217;re ready.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, please, if you are unvaccinated, consider vaccination today.&nbsp; It&#8217;s free, it&#8217;s available, it&#8217;s easy, it works, and it&#8217;s never, never been more important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to Dr. Murthy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Well, thank you so much, Jeff.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s great to be with all of you again today.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll start just by acknowledging the obvious &#8212; what we&#8217;re all seeing in the numbers &#8212; that it is troubling to see this rise in COVID cases, and it&#8217;s another reminder that we&#8217;re not out in the woods yet.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s important, also, that we not lose sight of how far we&#8217;ve come.</p>



<p>Cases are down dramatically from their January peak when we were averaging 200,000-plus cases a day.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve gotten more than 161 million people fully vaccinated, which means they have a high degree of protection against COVID-19.&nbsp; And every day, hundreds of thousands of people are still choosing to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That is all good news.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One fact that has been proven time and time again during this past year is that vaccines save lives.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why 99.5 percent of COVID-19 deaths and 97 percent of possible hospitalizations are among the unvaccinated.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also why nearly every death from COVID-19 is a preventable tragedy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to share a few updates about how we&#8217;re continuing to support people in making their decisions about the vaccine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, we are ramping up our work with trusted messengers in key communities.&nbsp; This summer, we&#8217;ve seen people in every community stepping up to get their loved ones and neighbors vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been really encouraging.&nbsp; And these groups include faith communities from the group Choose Healthy Life, which has worked with powerful networks of 48 Black churches in five cities to test and vaccinate people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It also includes the American Muslim and Multifaith Women&#8217;s Empowerment Council, which has engaged their communities through phone banking, text banking, social media, and door-to-door canvassing.</p>



<p>Healthcare professionals have also been stepping up, have more conversations with your patients.&nbsp;<br><br>And earlier this summer, the Alpha Chapter of the Chi Eta Phi sorority, a service organization made up of nurses, had more than 1,145 conversations about vaccinations at barber shops, grocery stores, and throughout their communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also continuing to work with the student COVID-19 Community Corps, where students participate in calls to learn best practices and hear from their peers about how they can talk about vaccines with their friends and family and community members.<br><br>And we&#8217;re working with platforms like Twitch to answer user questions about the vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But very importantly, we&#8217;re also increasingly asking vaccinated people to help get their family and friends vaccinated.&nbsp; And the importance of this last item &#8212; family and friends talking to family and friends &#8212; is underscored by recent data, which found that one out of five adults who were unsure about the vaccine in January have now been vaccinated.&nbsp; And when asked what changed their mind, it was talking to family, friends, and their doctors, and seeing that people they knew had been safely vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>So we need to keep having these conversations, reminding people that vaccination is still the best way to keep our family and friends safe from the worst outcomes of COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second way that we&#8217;re gaining ground against the virus is by addressing health misinformation.&nbsp; Last week, I issued a Surgeon General&#8217;s Advisory to call the nation&#8217;s attention to the threat of health misinformation.&nbsp; Since then, we&#8217;ve continued to emphasize what individuals can do to stop health misinformation in its tracks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That includes asking everyone to raise their own bar for sharing health information by checking to make sure that it&#8217;s backed by credible, scientific sources.&nbsp; As we say in the advisory, “If you are not sure, don&#8217;t share.”&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll continue to say that on social media, in a video PSA that we&#8217;ve created and released, and in conversations we&#8217;re convening with people around the country.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re also mobilizing other stakeholders to address misinformation &#8212; from technology companies and healthcare professionals, to researchers and community-based organizations.&nbsp; In fact, right after this briefing, my office will be hosting a conversation with community organizations around the country to discuss the steps that they can take to stop the spread of health misinformation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Here&#8217;s the bottom line: Misinformation is a threat to our health, and the speed, scale, and sophistication with which it is spreading is unprecedented.&nbsp; I will not hesitate to say that and to call for greater accountability and action to address health misinformation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A word about equity, though.&nbsp; We recognize that equity must be at the center of our work to confront health misinformation and here&#8217;s why: because unequal access to the healthcare system, education, and technology means that some people have more limited access to accurate information than others.&nbsp; And when those people instead encounter health misinformation, it can worsen their health outcomes, which exacerbates health inequities in what becomes a vicious cycle.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ultimately, while the threat of the Delta variant is here, while climbing infection rates are what we&#8217;re seeing day to day, primarily among the unvaccinated, it is more important than ever before that we not let our guard down.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m asking everyone to please talk to your family and friends about getting vaccinated because you could be saving their life.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s the people-powered movement that we&#8217;ve got to expand in our country.&nbsp; We made great progress thanks to the hard work of millions of people across this country.&nbsp; We should not forget that.&nbsp; And we should be proud of it, but we have more work to do to end this pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I look forward to taking your &#8212; some of your questions.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll turn it back to you, Jeff.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thanks, Doctor.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s open it up for a few questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe we&#8217;re having trouble hearing the questions, if the questions have begun.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, we&#8217;re taking a minute to sort through this technical issue.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay, we can hear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; This question is for Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; Last night, President Biden indicated that the vaccine may be approved for children under 12 as soon as August, September, or October.&nbsp; Is there anything you can share about what led to that timeframe, and what any preliminary data shows so far for children who are participating in clinical trials?&nbsp; And one more quick thing on this: Do you anticipate approval will be for all children under 12 at once or likely be separated by age groups?&nbsp;</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; So, maybe I&#8217;ll just say that we&#8217;re looking at the clinical trial data now.&nbsp; We&#8217;re waiting for the clinical trial data to come in.&nbsp; The approval of the data and the authorization will be a regulatory FDA decision.&nbsp; So, after we have seen the clinical trial data &#8212; I have not seen them myself &#8212; after we will see them, then they will go to the FDA for their regulatory process of authorization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, anything to add there?&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re having trouble hearing Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, Jeff, we were on mute.&nbsp; No, just to underscore what Dr. Walensky said, and that is that the clinical trials that are in progress are doing an age de-escalation; that relates the second part of the questioner’s question.&nbsp; So they&#8217;ll do 12 to 9 years old, 9 to 6, 6 to 2, and then 6 months to 2 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The data are being collected right now.&nbsp; Ultimately, as Dr. Walensky correctly said, this will be a regulatory decision based on the data that&#8217;s accumulated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll just reiterate what we&#8217;ve talked about before, which is the FDA is the gold standard for vaccine review and approval.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll run an independent and rigorous scientific process.&nbsp; And when that process is complete, the American people can rest assured that the FDA maintained those world-class standards throughout this period.<br><br>Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s try Sabrina again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; Just wanted to make sure that you can hear me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:  Yes. <br><br>Q     All right, thank you so much.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Thank you.<br><br>Q     Perhaps it&#8217;s a question for Dr. Fauci, who talked about how effective the vaccines are at preventing severe illness.  I&#8217;m curious if we know more about what the risk of breakthrough cases resulting in<br>long COVID is?  And given how recently people have been vaccinated, how long might it take to start identifying trends among possible long-haul patients who&#8217;ve been vaccinated?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:  Well, that&#8217;s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a &#8212; an object of a very intensive study right now following individuals with various levels of seriousness of disease as to what the incidence and prevalence will be of long COVID.  We don&#8217;t have enough information right now to give you an accurate number of what that incidence is, but that&#8217;s something that is being very actively followed right now. <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Elizabeth Weise at USA Today.<br><br>Q     Great.  Thanks so much for taking my call.  This is a question for Dr. Walensky.  I&#8217;ve been talking to epidemiologists, and one of their concerns is that the CDC’s masking policy lacked teeth, so most people just took it to mean they didn&#8217;t need to wear a mask at all.  San Francisco is now contemplating requiring proof of vaccination to get into bars and restaurants.  Other people have suggested that masking regulations change if cases go above 5 per 100,000.  Are there any thoughts in the works of either clarifying or changing CDC’s masking policy?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:  Thank you, Elizabeth.  You know, as we have said consistently, the greatest risk right now is to those who are unvaccinated.  And we have consistently and repeatedly said, “If you are unvaccinated, you need to be wearing a mask to protect yourself and others around you.”  And we need more people to get vaccinated to stop this pandemic. <br><br>So, overall, the CDC recommendations haven&#8217;t changed.  Fully vaccinated people are protected from severe illness.  And we&#8217;ve always said that communities and individuals need to make the decisions that are right for them based on what&#8217;s going on in their local areas. <br><br>So, if you&#8217;re in an area that has a high case rate and low rates of vaccination where Delta cases are rising, you should certainly be wearing a mask if you are unvaccinated.  If you are vaccinated, you get exceptional protection from the vaccines.  But you have the opportunity to make the personal choice to add extra layers of protection if you so choose.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Michael Shear at New York Times.<br><br>Q     Hi, can you hear me?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Yes.<br><br>Q     Okay, thanks.  This is for Jeff probably.  One specific and one general question.  The specific question is: There was this report overnight about the White House discussing masks &#8212; discussing mask mandates in light of L.A. County&#8217;s decision and the rise of the Delta variant.  Can you, you know, tell us whether that report is correct?  Is the White House, in fact, having high-level discussions about that?<br><br>And then, on a broader level, I wonder if you could sort of reflect on the moment that we&#8217;re in compared to where we were just two weeks &#8212; two or so weeks ago, you know, when the President welcomed the &#8212; sort of the world back to normal with a Fourth of July party on the White House lawn and it felt like we were going in a very different direction.  You know, how &#8212; the President said yesterday wa- &#8212; he was frustrated by all of this.  How &#8212; you know, how much of a different place are we in?  And what is all this portend for everybody going back to school and work in the fall?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  So, on masking, I think you just heard a &#8212; a very strong summary from Dr. Walensky, and that&#8217;s where we are.  We will follow the science, and public health guidance is made by Dr. Walensky and her team at the CDC. <br><br>So, we will continue to follow the science and follow CDC on mask guidance &#8212; or mask re- &#8212; mask recommendations.  I think the President captured it well last night, and it&#8217;s consistent with his message on July 4th.  We&#8217;ve made significant progress with 162 million people fully vaccinated.  And fully vaccinated people have a high degree of protection, even against the more transmissible Delta variant. <br><br>If you are not vaccinated &#8212; as the President spoke to unvaccinated people last night and back on July 4th &#8212; you need to get vaccinated or you do not have a high degree of protection for yourself, for your friends, and for your family and your community. <br><br>So, you know, we&#8217;ve made significant progress.  We’re in a very different place than we were several months ago by getting 162 million people vaccinated, but we have a lot more work to do.  And unvaccinated people need to roll up their sleeves as soon as possible and begin their vaccination routine.<br><br>Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Time for a couple more questions.  Let&#8217;s go to Kaitlan, CNN. <br><br>Q     Thanks so much.  Dr. Walensky, I just want to circle back on this just so we have complete clarity.  Is the CDC considering right now changing its mask guidance for people who are fully vaccinated?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:  We are always looking at the data as the data come in.  Our ma- &#8212; our guidance has been clear since &#8212; since we put it out several months ago, and that is: If you are unvaccinated, you should continue to wear a mask and protect yourself against others around you.  And more importantly, you should go and get vaccinated to get better layers of protection. <br><br>We have always said that communities &#8212; local communities have to look at what is going on locally, as we have very heterogenous country right now.  In areas that have a high amount of disease and low amounts of vaccination, that, you know &#8212; if you&#8217;re unvaccinated, you should absolutely be wearing a mask.  If you&#8217;re vaccinated, you have exceptional levels of protection from the vaccine, and you may choose to add an extra layer of protection by putting on your mask, and that’s a very individual choice.  That has been consistent with our CDC guidance since we put it out.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Last &#8212; let me do one more question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:  Let’s go to Tamara Keith at NPR. <br><br>Q     Thank you so much for taking my question; it’s two questions, but I’ll make it quick.  A lot of people who&#8217;ve gotten the J&amp;J vaccine are wondering if they can or should get an mRNA booster.  I know it&#8217;s not recommended at this time, but are you recommending against it?  Or should patients and their doctors make a decision about that? <br><br>Also, wanted to get an update: In early June, you announced a plan to share 80 million doses globally by the end of June.  It’s middle of late July.  What has stopped you from meeting that goal? <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Okay, why don&#8217;t we start with the J&amp;J vaccine booster question, Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:  Yes, thank you, Jeff.  The J&amp;J vaccine &#8212; the data that I showed on the efficacy slide &#8212; was one of the slides I showed &#8212; is a very effective vaccine.  There is no reason to believe right now that people who have taken the J&amp;J vaccine are in need of a booster dose of any sort.  There are no data to indicate that that is the case.  Back to you, Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  On the global front, as you know, we &#8212; the President has committed to sharing 580 million doses of vaccine to the world.  Half a billion doses of Pfizer being donated to those hundred or so countries most in need.  This is, by far, the largest-ever donation of COVID-19 vaccines by a single country. <br><br>We shared the 80 million by the end of June, and they have now shipped.  So they have &#8212; they’re in the air or they’ve arrived in the recipient country.  And we’ll continue to share tens of millions of doses across the summer months, beyond the 80 million.<br><br>Thank you for joining, and we look forward to seeing everybody at the next briefing.  Thank you.</p>



<p>11:44 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_22July2021_for-transcript-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_22July2021_for-transcript-1.pdf </a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on Continuing Crackdown in Cuba</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-continuing-crackdown-in-cuba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 17:51:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I unequivocally condemn the mass detentions and sham trials that are unjustly sentencing to prison those who dared to speak out in an effort to intimidate and threaten the Cuban people into silence. The Cuban people have the same right to freedom of expression and peaceful assembly as all people. The United States stands with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I unequivocally condemn the mass detentions and sham trials that are unjustly sentencing to prison those who dared to speak out in an effort to intimidate and threaten the Cuban people into silence. The Cuban people have the same right to freedom of expression and peaceful assembly as all people. The United States stands with the brave Cubans who have taken to the streets to oppose 62 years of repression under a communist regime.<br> <br>Today, my Administration is imposing new sanctions targeting elements of the Cuban regime responsible for this crackdown—the head of the Cuban military and the division of the Cuban Ministry of the Interior driving the crackdown—to hold them accountable for their actions. This is just the beginning–the United States will continue to sanction individuals responsible for oppression of the Cuban people.<br> <br>As we hold the Cuban regime accountable, our support for the Cuban people is unwavering and we are making sure Cuban Americans are a vital partner in our efforts to provide relief to suffering people on the Island. We are working with civil society organizations and the private sector to provide internet access to the Cuban people that circumvents the regime’s censorship efforts. We are reviewing our remittance policy to determine how we can maximize support to the Cuban people. And we are committed to restaffing our embassy in Havana to provide consular services to Cubans and enhance our ability to engage with civil society, while ensuring the safety of U.S. diplomats serving in Cuba.<br> <br>Advancing human dignity and freedom is a top priority for my Administration, and we will work closely with our partners throughout the region, including the Organization of American States, to pressure the regime to immediately release wrongfully detained political prisoners, restore internet access, and allow the Cuban people to enjoy their fundamental rights.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How the Build Back Better Plan Will Create a Better Future for Young Americans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/22/fact-sheet-how-the-build-back-better-plan-will-create-a-better-future-for-young-americans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 16:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Although there has been a strong economic recovery under President Biden, young adults have now lived through two historic economic downturns. In 2008, many young workers without a college degree lost their jobs. In 2020, at the height of the pandemic, the highest proportion of young adults between the ages of 18 and 29 were&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Although there has been a <a href="https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/PAYEMS%20https:/fred.stlouisfed.org/series/GDP">strong economic</a> recovery under President Biden, young adults have now lived through two historic economic downturns. In 2008, many young workers <a href="https://www.bls.gov/opub/ted/2009/mar/wk5/art03.htm?view_full">without a college degree lost their jobs</a>. In 2020, at the height of the pandemic, the <a href="https://www.pewresearch.org/fact-tank/2020/09/04/a-majority-of-young-adults-in-the-u-s-live-with-their-parents-for-the-first-time-since-the-great-depression/">highest proportion of young adults between the ages of 18 and 29 were living at home with their parents</a> since the Great Depression and unemployment for young adults reached a <a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/young-workers-covid-recession/">peak of 24.4 percent</a>, and was even higher for young adults of color. The <a>economic events of the past 15 years have made the </a><a href="https://www.epi.org/publication/young-workers-covid-recession/">path to the middle class difficult</a> for many young Americans.</p>



<p>Young adults are facing additional challenges on their path to economic security, including barriers to home ownership, unaffordable or hard to find child care, and the existential threat of climate change. Home ownership <a href="https://www.newamerica.org/millennials/reports/emerging-millennial-wealth-gap/homeownership-and-living-arrangements-among-millennials-new-sources-of-wealth-inequality-and-what-to-do-about-it/">rates are at a historic low for young adults</a>. Child care for two children costs <a href="https://www.childcareaware.org/millennial-map/">at least 50 percent of the median millennial&#8217;s salary</a> in 47 states, as well as in the District of Columbia. And the climate crisis poses <a href="https://climate.nasa.gov/effects/">an urgent threat</a> to our environment, our health, our communities, our national security, and our economy.</p>



<p>President Biden&#8217;s Build Back Better plan is a once-in-a-generation investment that responds to the historic challenges facing the country, including young Americans. President Biden knows that it is not enough to restore us to where we were prior to the pandemic – we need to build back better. That means making it easier for American families to break into the middle class, and easier to stay in the middle class.&nbsp; It means reducing the cost of things that working people depend on. And, he knows that, in order to secure a brighter, more equitable future, we need to support young adults, many of whom are dealing with the long-term consequences of two economic downturns.</p>



<p><strong>Education and Workforce Opportunities</strong></p>



<p>Thirteen years of school is <a href="https://cew.georgetown.edu/cew-reports/americas-divided-recovery/">no longer enough</a> to be prepared for the jobs of today&#8217;s economy. At the same time, the cost of education beyond high school has become unaffordable for too many students across the country. The <a href="https://www.nasfaa.org/issue_brief_double_pell">value of Pell Grants</a> over the last nearly 50 years has fallen from covering more than 75 percent of the cost of a four-year degree at a public university to under 30 percent, forcing millions of low-income students to take on debt. Additionally, as more young Americans rejoin the workforce or seek out new opportunities in a changing economy, <a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/building-americas-job-skills-with-effective-workforce-programs-a-training-strategy-to-raise-wages-and-increase-work-opportunities/">there is a greater need for skills development opportunities</a> for workers of all kinds that lead to high-quality jobs. To expand education and workforce opportunities, the Build Back Better plan will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Ensure that postsecondary education is accessible and affordable for young adults, and that students who enroll are ultimately successful: </strong>Millennials have grown up in and graduated into an economy <a href="https://cew.georgetown.edu/cew-reports/americas-divided-recovery/">where the majority of jobs created between 2010 and 2016 require some education beyond high school</a>. Because of this, they are the <a href="https://youngamericans.berkeley.edu/2020/01/29/college-attainment/">most educated generation</a>, but have faced challenges along the way. While more young adults from <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/pdf/Indicator_CPA/coe_cpa_2018_05.pdf">low-income backgrounds are enrolling in college,</a> the Pell Grant has not kept up with the increase in cost. This has contributed to an increasing reliance on debt. The Build Back Better plan makes an education beyond high school more affordable and accessible by providing two years of free community college and by making college more affordable for low- and middle-income students at Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs), Tribal Colleges and Universities (TCUs), and institutions such as Hispanic-serving institutions, Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions, and other minority-serving institutions (MSIs). This is bolstered by increasing the maximum Pell Grant by nearly $1,500 to help all eligible low-income students pay for a two- or four-year degree. Finally, President Biden recognizes that access is not enough &#8211; students need support to obtain a credential or degree. The Build Back Better plan invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at community colleges and institutions that serve students from our most disadvantaged communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Build the capacity of the existing workforce development systems:</strong> The United States has underinvested in the workforce development system for decades. In 2018, for example, we spent <a href="https://data.oecd.org/socialexp/public-spending-on-labour-markets.htm">less than one quarter</a> of the average that other advanced economies spend on workforce and labor market programs as a share of GDP. This lack of investment <a href="https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/sites/default/files/page/files/20161220_active_labor_market_policies_issue_brief_cea.pdf">impacts</a> all of us: better educated workers create spillover effects for other workers and lack of employment has negative social impacts on communities. President Biden is calling on Congress significantly increase investments in American workforce development infrastructure and worker protection. This includes registered apprenticeships and pre-apprenticeships, creating one to two million new registered apprenticeships slots, and strengthening the pipeline for more women and people of color to access these opportunities through successful pre-apprenticeship programs such as the Women in Apprenticeships in Non-Traditional Occupations. &nbsp;It also invests in sector-based training programs, which are comprehensive training programs that include wraparound services, paired with high-quality training and effective partnerships between educational institutions, unions, and employers &#8212; guaranteeing placement in a good quality, in-demand job. The sector-based training investments will provide millions of workers &#8211;particularly young workers, women and workers of color &#8211;with pathways into high job-quality sectors including, clean energy, manufacturing and infrastructure. This will ensure these underserved groups have greater access to new infrastructure jobs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Help for Young Adults Who Care for Their Families</strong></p>



<p>The hope of a middle-class life has gotten further and further out of reach for too many American families, as the costs of raising children – from child care to <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/women/news/2021/02/05/495504/quick-facts-paid-family-medical-leave/">taking leave time</a> to care for a child or family member – have grown. The cost of child care is now <a href="https://www.epi.org/child-care-costs-in-the-united-states/">more than in-state tuition at public four-year colleges</a> in over half of the country. Difficulty in finding high-quality, affordable child care and lack of access to preschools leads some parents to drop out of the labor force entirely, some to reduce their work hours, and others to turn down a promotion. When a parent drops out of the workforce, reduces work hours, or takes a lower-paying job early in their careers, they can suffer lifetime consequences on earnings, savings, and retirement. Similarly, high costs and increasing shortages of care for disabled and elderly people leave many to rely on unpaid caregiving – <a href="https://press.aarp.org/2020-5-14-Caregiving-in-the-US-Report">nearly a quarter of millennials are providing care for a family member</a>. To help young adults care for their families, the Build Back Better plan will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Create free universal pre-K: </strong>President Biden is calling for a national partnership with states to offer free, high-quality, accessible, and inclusive preschool to all three-and four-year-olds, benefitting five million children and saving the average family $13,000 when fully implemented. This historic investment in America’s future will prioritize high-need areas and enable communities and families to choose the settings that work best for them, including schools, child care centers, family child care providers, Head Start, and other community-based providers. The President’s plan will also ensure that all publicly-funded preschool is high-quality, with low student-to-teacher ratios, developmentally appropriate curriculum, and supportive classroom environments that are inclusive for all students.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Guarantee access to high-quality, affordable child care for low- and middle-income families and offer universal free preschool to all three- and four-year old children.</strong>&nbsp; Families will pay only a portion of their income based on a sliding scale. For the most hard-pressed working families, child care costs for their young children would be fully covered, and families earning up to 1.5 times their state’s median income will pay no more than 7 percent of their income for all children under age five. When fully implemented, this plan will save the average family $14,800 each year, help parents better manage work and care, and produce lifetime benefits for children. &nbsp;The President’s plan would also make permanent the dramatic expansion of the Child and Dependent Care Tax Credit (CDCTC) enacted in the American Rescue Plan. With this expanded credit, families can receive up to half of what they spend on child care for children under age 13, up to a total of $4,000 for one child or $8,000 for two or more children.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Create a national comprehensive paid family and medical leave program</strong>. The program will ensure workers receive partial wage replacement to take time to bond with a new child, care for a seriously ill loved one, deal with a loved one’s military deployment, find safety from sexual assault, stalking, or domestic violence, heal from their own serious illness, or take time to deal with the death of a loved one. It will guarantee 12 weeks of paid parental, family, and personal illness/safe leave by year 10 of the program, and also ensure workers get three days of bereavement leave per year starting in year one. The program will provide workers up to $4,000 a month, with a minimum of two-thirds of average weekly wages replaced, rising to 80 percent for the lowest wage workers. Additionally, the plan has an inclusive definition of family, ensuring workers can care for and be cared by a loved one who is not related by blood.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Significantly expand the Child Tax Credit and deliver it monthly</strong>. The Build Back Better proposal would extend the Child Tax Credit (CTC) expansion first enacted in the American Rescue Plan from $2,000 to $3,000 per child six years-old and above, and to $3,600 per child under six. Parents can use this tax credit on everything from diapers to putting more food on the table to paying the rent or mortgage. For a family with two parents who earn a combined $100,000 per year and have two children under six, the Child Tax Credit expansion means the family’s credit would go from $4,000 total to $7,200 total, an additional $3,200 per year in tax relief. For a family with two parents who earn a combined $24,000 per year and have two children under six, the expansion means even more; they would see roughly an additional $4,400 in tax relief because the full credit was not previously available to them. The Build Back Better proposal makes the credit fully refundable on a permanent basis, so that low-income families—the families that need the credit the most—can benefit from the full tax credit. An <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/american-rescue-plan-act-includes-critical-expansions-of-child-tax-credit-and">estimated 66 million children</a> (90 percent) are already poised to benefit from the expanded tax credit, including over 9 million Black children and over 17 million Latino children.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Housing Affordability and Access</strong></p>



<p>Homeownership remains stubbornly out of reach for young Americans due to interrelated issues of rising costs and scarcity of supply. Millennial renters <a href="https://www.apartmentlist.com/research/millennial-homeownership-2021">report</a> declining optimism about the prospect of homeownership and cite affordability as their greatest concern. But even for the majority of millennials who aspire to own a home, high rental costs, plus other expenses that many carry, make it difficult to save up money to buy a home. A recent <a href="https://www.apartmentlist.com/research/millennial-homeownership-2021">survey</a> of millennial renters showed that 63% of renters planning to buy a home had no down payment savings. Whether they seek to own a home or not, a lack of housing supply drives up housing costs for young renters and homeowners alike. To help renters and homeowners, the Build Back Better plan will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Expand access to federal subsidies that will enable the construction or rehabilitation of more than 1 million affordable rental housing units.</strong> President Biden’s Build Back Better Plan would bolster funding for successful housing subsidy programs to produce and preserve housing that is affordable for very- and extremely-low income renters. This includes investments in the HOME Investment Partnerships program, the Housing Trust Fund, and the Capital Magnet Fund. The President is also proposing authorizing $2 billion in new project-based rental assistance agreements for the first time in more than 20 years to help even more working families access affordable housing. Together, these investments will produce, preserve, and retrofit more than a million affordable rental housing units in big cities and small towns across the country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Build and rehabilitate more than 500,000 homes for low- and middle-income homebuyers.</strong> President Biden is calling on Congress to take immediate steps to spur the construction and rehabilitation of homes for underserved communities. Specifically, he is calling on Congress to pass the innovative, bipartisan Neighborhood Homes Investment Act (NHIA). Offering $20 billion worth of NHIA tax credits over the next five years will result in approximately 500,000 homes built or rehabilitated, creating a pathway for more families to buy a home and start building wealth.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Incentivize the removal of exclusionary zoning and harmful land use policies</strong>. For decades, exclusionary zoning laws – like minimum lot sizes, mandatory parking requirements, and prohibitions on multifamily housing – have inflated housing and construction costs and locked families out of areas with more opportunities. President Biden’s plan seeks to help jurisdictions reduce barriers to producing affordable housing and expand housing choices for people with low or moderate incomes. The Build Back Better Plan will create an incentive program that awards flexible and attractive funding to jurisdictions that take concrete steps to reduce barriers to affordable housing production.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Climate Crisis</strong></p>



<p>The climate crisis is one of the greatest threats America and the global community face. And it is this younger generation that will inherit the worst impacts of this crisis. That is why on Day 1, President Biden mobilized the whole of government to tackle the climate crisis, rejoined the landmark Paris Agreement, and set an ambitious and achievable goal of cutting emissions by 50-52% below 2005 levels by 2030. To meet this goal, this Build Back Better plan will make once-in-a-generation investments in clean energy and infrastructure that can help tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice in communities across the country. To address the climate crisis for young Americans, the Build Back Better plan will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in clean energy manufacturing right here in America. </strong>The plan will provide tax cuts for businesses and consumers to deploy clean energy technology like renewables, battery storage, and electric vehicles. These along with investments for retooling factories and growing supply chains will spur demand for more domestic manufacturing. This will not only grow our capacity to build these technologies here in America, but also create millions of good-quality jobs when paired with strong labor standards and a free and fair choice to join a union and bargain collectively. When paired with an Energy Efficiency and Clean Electricity Standard (EECES), it will help get America on track to meet the goal of 100 percent carbon pollution-free electricity by 2035 and zero net emissions economy-wide by 2050.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Create a new Civilian Climate Corps. </strong>In 1933 President Roosevelt established the Civilian Conservation Corps, a popular New Deal program that transformed the American landscape and put unemployed Americans back to work. During the 9 years of the program’s existence, more than three million young men ages 18-28 served for up to two years earning $30 per month – the equivalent of $600 per month in today’s economy – in addition to meals and lodging. Today there is an opportunity to put a new generation of climate, conservation, and resilience workers to work – paid a living wage and provided a pathway to public service or good-paying union jobs. The plan will enlist a new, diverse generation of Americans to work conserving our public lands and waters, bolstering community resilience, and advancing environmental justice – all while maximizing the creation of accessible training opportunities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in Clean Energy and Energy Efficiency Block Grants to spur thousands of local projects</strong>. This includes installing community solar in disadvantaged communities, replacing street lights with LED bulbs manufactured in America, and making upgrades to a community center to cut its electricity bills—that prioritize worker empowerment and advance environmental justice.&nbsp; These block grants will support states and local governments that are stepping up to lead on climate—by implementing policy measures that accelerate progress toward clean energy goals</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden After Marine One Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/22/remarks-by-president-biden-after-marine-one-arrival-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 14:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24731</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn (July 21, 2021) THE PRESIDENT:&#160; We answered enough questions today.&#160; The only reason I&#8217;m stopping: I feel badly you&#8217;re here this hour of the night.&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, can you clarify what you said about no &#8212; that there&#8217;s no &#8212; no one in the Democratic Party is anti-police?&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I didn&#8217;t say that.&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(July 21, 2021)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We answered enough questions today.&nbsp; The only reason I&#8217;m stopping: I feel badly you&#8217;re here this hour of the night.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, can you clarify what you said about no &#8212; that there&#8217;s no &#8212; no one in the Democratic Party is anti-police?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t say that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know that you said you don&#8217;t want to defund the police &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I said that that &#8212; that is not the Democratic Party&#8217;s position.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m the Democratic Party; I am President.&nbsp; So is the Speaker of the House and so is the –- the Majority Leader.&nbsp; We are not the defunding the police.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And are there people who &#8212; in the Democratic Party, who want to defund the police?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Are there people in the Republican Party who think we&#8217;re sucking the blood out of kids?<br>&nbsp;<br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
