<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 21:46:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Transatlantic&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/18/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-transatlantic-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 21:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden spoke today with Transatlantic leaders about the likelihood of further Russian aggression against Ukraine.&#160; Together they expressed deep concern over Russia’s continued build-up of forces, reiterated their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and discussed the importance of further economic assistance to Ukraine.&#160; They pledged to continue pursuing diplomacy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden spoke today with Transatlantic leaders about the likelihood of further Russian aggression against Ukraine.&nbsp; Together they expressed deep concern over Russia’s continued build-up of forces, reiterated their strong support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, and discussed the importance of further economic assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; They pledged to continue pursuing diplomacy to de-escalate tensions while ensuring readiness to impose swift, coordinated economic costs on Russia should it choose further conflict.&nbsp; The leaders also discussed efforts to ensure the defense and security of NATO’s eastern flank.</p>



<p>Participants in the call included Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada, European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen, European Council President Charles Michel, President Emmanuel Macron of France, Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy, NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg, President Andrzej Duda of Poland, President Klaus Iohannis of Romania, and Prime Minister Boris Johnson of the United Kingdom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;6617</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/18/bill-signed-h-r-6617/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47518</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, February 18, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 6617, the &#8220;Further Additional Extending Government Funding Act,&#8221; which provides fiscal year 2022 appropriations to Federal agencies through March 11, 2022, for continuing projects and activities of the Federal Government.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, February 18, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 6617, the &#8220;Further Additional Extending Government Funding Act,&#8221; which provides fiscal year 2022 appropriations to Federal agencies through March 11, 2022, for continuing projects and activities of the Federal Government.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris’s Meeting with Baltic&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/18/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-baltic-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 17:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris met today with President Egils Levits of Latvia, President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania, and Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia in Munich, Germany. This meeting was part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s extensive engagement with Allies on a unified approach to Russia’s aggressive actions. The leaders discussed their readiness for a swift Transatlantic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris met today with President Egils Levits of Latvia, President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania, and Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia in Munich, Germany. This meeting was part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s extensive engagement with Allies on a unified approach to Russia’s aggressive actions. The leaders discussed their readiness for a swift Transatlantic response should Russia further invade Ukraine, including through adjustments to U.S. and NATO force posture, and implementation of financial sanctions and export controls.<br> <br>Vice President Harris emphasized that our commitment to Article 5 of the NATO Treaty is ironclad and that we stand united with our NATO Allies in opposing Russian aggression. The leaders also discussed efforts to strengthen NATO’s deterrence and collective defense.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris, President Levits of Latvia, President Nausėda Of Lithuania, and Prime Minister Kallas of Estonia Before Multilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-president-levits-of-latvia-president-nauseda-of-lithuania-and-prime-minister-kallas-of-estonia-before-multilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 17:08:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47505</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Commerzbank Filiale MünchenMunich, Germany 2:55 P.M. CEST VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I am here in Munich because it is a top priority for President Biden and myself that we are continuously engaged with and working with our Allies and partners around the world, and that we work always on strengthening those relationships.&#160; And&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Commerzbank Filiale München<br>Munich, Germany</em></p>



<p>2:55 P.M. CEST<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I am here in Munich because it is a top priority for President Biden and myself that we are continuously engaged with and working with our Allies and partners around the world, and that we work always on strengthening those relationships.&nbsp; And certainly, the last several months have been evidence of the work we have done collectively, all of us, in that pursuit.</p>



<p>A lot of attention is obviously being given today and the last couple of months to the issue of Russia and its aggression on the Ukrainian border.&nbsp;<br><br>And the focus for us in working together is to further coordinate &#8212; in terms of the work that we have been doing, the dedication of resources, and, certainly, the dedication of priority &#8212; to address that issue and what may be the ramifications; to do this work at the highest levels of our governments, understanding that our work together and our unity is a sign of the strength of our nations individually and collectively.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m here to also talk with our friends and our Allies and our partners so that we can continue to strategize, understanding this is a dynamic situation and will require us to be in constant contact around, again, our priorities, whatever challenges may exist, but also the work that we will continue to do to strengthen and coordinate our resources.</p>



<p>Today, we will discuss a number of issues that surround our shared concerns about Russia&#8217;s activities and the responses that we are prepared to make.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our work together has been and will continue to be about strengthening our ability to deter activity in terms of aggressive activity by Russia as it relates to Ukraine; and about our collective defense and, again, the resources and the commitment that we have to our shared and collective defense.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m looking forward to the conversation and that being the basis of the work that we will continue to do to further reinforce our Alliance.</p>



<p>We have made clear and will continue to make clear that as we are willing and able and committed to the deterrence and the defense issue on this matter, we are also concerned and prioritize the importance of diplomacy.</p>



<p>We understand and we have made clear that we remain open to diplomacy.&nbsp; The onus is on Russia at this point to demonstrate that it is serious in that regard.</p>



<p>I recognize the threats at this moment, historically and going forward, to our friends &#8212; Latvia, Lithuania, and Estonia.&nbsp; We stand with you.&nbsp; I am here personally to say that.&nbsp; We stand with you on this and many other issues in the spirit of our Alliance and our mutual interests and priorities.&nbsp; And we stand together, all of us, as NATO Allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States remains committed to Article 5.&nbsp; And our position has always been and will continue to be that Article 5 is ironclad.&nbsp; And the spirit behind it &#8212; an attack on one is an attack on all &#8212; remains our perspective.</p>



<p>I do believe, I think we all know, our greatest strength is our unity.&nbsp; This is a moment that has made that clear: that our unity is evidence and is a measure of our strength.</p>



<p>And with that, I look forward to our conversation.&nbsp; And I thank you all for the work you do.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>And with that, I would like to turn to President Levits of Latvi- &#8212; Latvia.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT LEVITS:&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; First of &#8212; first of all, I would like to thank you for this conversation and the possibility &#8212; occasion to exchange our views on the actual situation in Europe.</p>



<p>And I would like, also, to thank the United States for the engagement in Europe, for the security in our region, and for the deployment of additional military personnel and military equipment in our region in order to strengthen the eastern flank of NATO.</p>



<p>I would like to say that the aggression of Russia &#8212; and this is a Russian case, not a Ukrainian case &#8212; aggression of Russia against Ukraine is not only against Ukraine, but also against Europe, against the democracy, against the West et al.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because Russia is challenged by democracy, it is difficult for Russia to see that there could be a democratic Ukraine because it could have some repercussions in Russia.</p>



<p>I would say that our task is to avoid the hot phase of the confrontation.&nbsp; And it is only possible if the answer of the West is united and very strong, and so that the cost-benefit calculation for Russia is negative and clearly negative.</p>



<p>And what does this mean?&nbsp; I think this answer is our response consists of four elements.&nbsp; The first element is sanctions &#8212; very, very serious sanctions.&nbsp; And President Biden said already to President Putin this already a few times.</p>



<p>This is the second: military and economically and financial support of Ukraine so that Ukrainians can defend themselves.&nbsp; Also, this is a second element &#8212; very important.</p>



<p>The third element is the strengthening of the military defense capacity in the eastern flank, especially in Baltics, especially in Poland.&nbsp; And the co- &#8212; bilateral cooperation with U.S. in this respect is already going on, but we should strengthen that.</p>



<p>And the fourth element is a dialogue.&nbsp; It’s a dialogue in order to keeps the channel for Russia open to go back to, I would say, normal international behavior.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; and all the four elements together, this should be a very strong answer to Russia so that we can say that avoiding of the hot phase of confrontation depends from us &#8212; from the West, from NATO.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; President Nausėda from Lithuania.<br><br>PRESIDENT NAUSĖDA:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Your Excellency, your Vice President, my colleagues: This is wonderful opportunity to meet you here in Munich and, of course, discuss those issues which are critically important for the security of our countries and also the security of the whole region.&nbsp;<br><br>You see here at the table the keen supporters of transatlantic bond, because the Baltics states understand probably so good that very effective security architecture could be built only with the contribution of United States.<br><br>You know that we have just celebrated the fifth anniversary of establishment of Enhanced Forward Presence in Lithuania.&nbsp; So, this is a good reason to say thank you for every Ally of NATO.<br><br>And now we are challenged by the events in Ukraine, but we should not take those events along the border with Ukraine only individually as a security problem of Ukraine.&nbsp; Of course, it means the security problem of the whole region.<br><br>And I like to say that there is no security of Ukraine without talking and discussion of security of the region.&nbsp; So, security for Ukraine means security for Baltic States; security of Ukraine means the security of Europe.&nbsp;<br><br>So today, the ghost of war is lingering in Europe.&nbsp; Unfortunately, we have to admit it.&nbsp; And we see provocation of possible military conflict in Ukraine.&nbsp; But in my eyes, I see that probably Russia keeping both alternatives open.&nbsp; While one al- &#8212; one alternative is to keep tension without the military conflict, the second alternative is open military intervention into Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>I think everything is our &#8212; in our hands in order to prevent this.&nbsp; And the best formula &#8212; peace formula &#8212; in my eyes is deterrence.&nbsp; The more we are united, the more we have firm stance on what is happening in Ukraine, the better we will send the signals to Russia not to start what they intend to do.&nbsp;<br><br>And in this regard, I would say that it is critically important for the security of our region to see more presence of United States troops.&nbsp; So, this is the reason why we really ask for permanent presence of United States troops in Lithuania.&nbsp; You know that we have these troops now on a rotational basis.&nbsp; And probably, this is very good time moment to talk about even more, higher, strong engagement into the security of our region.&nbsp;<br><br>So, Madam Vice President, thank you for this opportunity.&nbsp; I hope that we will have more details to discuss during our conversation.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And Prime Minister Kallas, Eston- &#8212; Estonia.<br><br>PRIME MINISTER KALLAS:&nbsp; Yes, thank you.&nbsp; Great to &#8212; we are very grateful for this meeting and also all the meetings that we have had with the U.S. administration.&nbsp; It means a great deal to us.&nbsp;<br><br>And, first of all, I would also like to stress what my Latvian colleague already said: It&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s about democracy, really.&nbsp; Why Russia is doing this is that he doesn&#8217;t want democracy to prevail in Ukraine.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, it is very important that we prevent this from happening.&nbsp;<br><br>We stay united, as you stressed as well.&nbsp; This is extremely important.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m super happy that we have been united all this &#8212; all this process.&nbsp; We are saying the same thing &#8212; all the Allies, independent, whether it&#8217;s a big one or a small one, which is very important.&nbsp;<br><br>And being a small country, like all the Baltic countries really are, we have all lost our independence to Russia once, and we don&#8217;t want it to happen again.&nbsp;<br><br>And therefore, we &#8212; we really think that this is &#8212; this is very important that we understand what is at stake here.&nbsp; And also, being a small country, it is very important.&nbsp; And we are very grateful that a big Ally like U.S. constantly consults with us; you know, gives us information; keeps us posted.&nbsp; This means &#8212; this means a great deal to us that we are, you know, equal Allies.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know it takes a lot of effort from your side, because there are lots of Allies to be in contact with, but &#8212; but I can speak for all of us: We are very grateful for this.&nbsp;<br><br>And we also feel that you are listening to our worries, which is &#8212; which is not that, you know, make a tick in the box that you have consulted, but actually we feel that you also hear us.&nbsp;<br><br>Our support to Ukraine is unwavering.&nbsp; And Ukraine needs all the political but also military support we can give.&nbsp; And of course, we as Allies decide the practical help regarding, you know, Ukraine &#8212; each country separately &#8212; but &#8212; but I think the message must be very clear.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; and also, what &#8212; what my colleagues already said: The rapidly deteriorating security situation also reflects or influences our region.&nbsp; And it demands a stronger military presence in Europe.&nbsp; And also, Russian troops and &#8212; and missiles in Belarus have also deteriorated the situation in the Baltic countries.&nbsp;<br><br>If &#8212; if you look at the map, we are like a peninsula in terms of NATO.&nbsp; And therefore, we welcome the decisions already made by U.S. administration to deploy additional forces in Europe.&nbsp; And we also hope that you increase the presence in the Baltic countries.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3:08 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Day Of Remembrance Of Japanese American Incarceration During World War&#160;II</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/18/day-of-remembrance-of-japanese-american-incarceration-during-world-war-ii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:24:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Eighty years ago, on&#160;February 19, 1942, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed Executive Order 9066, stripping people of Japanese descent of their civil rights. &#160;That order and the subsequent actions carried out by the Federal Government represent one of the most shameful chapters in our Nation&#8217;s history. &#160;On this Day of Remembrance of Japanese American Incarceration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Eighty years ago, on&nbsp;February 19, 1942, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed Executive Order 9066, stripping people of Japanese descent of their civil rights. &nbsp;That order and the subsequent actions carried out by the Federal Government represent one of the most shameful chapters in our Nation&#8217;s history. &nbsp;On this Day of Remembrance of Japanese American Incarceration During World War II, we acknowledge the unjust incarceration of some 120,000 Japanese Americans, approximately two-thirds of whom were born in the United States.<br><br>Despite never being charged with a crime, and without due process, Japanese Americans were forcibly removed from their homes and communities and incarcerated, simply because of their heritage.&nbsp; For years, many Japanese Americans lived in harsh, overcrowded conditions, surrounded by barbed wire fences and armed guards. &nbsp;Not only did they lose their homes, businesses, property, and savings &#8212; they also lost their liberty, security, and the fundamental freedoms that belong to all Americans in equal measure.<br><br>I have always believed that great nations do not ignore their most painful moments &#8212; they confront them with honesty and, in doing so, learn from them and grow stronger as a result.&nbsp; The incarceration of Japanese Americans 80 years ago is a reminder to us today of the tragic consequences we invite when we allow racism, fear, and xenophobia to fester.<br><br>Today, we reaffirm the Federal Government&#8217;s formal apology to Japanese Americans whose lives were irreparably harmed during this dark period of our history, and we solemnly reflect on our collective moral responsibility to ensure that our Nation never again engages in such un-American acts.&nbsp; We acknowledge the intergenerational trauma and loss that the incarceration of Japanese Americans has caused. &nbsp;We also uplift the courage and resilience of brave Japanese Americans who, despite being unjustly incarcerated, formed powerful communities and marshalled incredible dignity and strength.<br><br>Many of those whose families were incarcerated volunteered or were drafted to serve in combat &#8212; courageously serving in the 100th Infantry Battalion, Military Intelligence Service, Women&#8217;s Army Auxiliary Corps, Army Nurse Corps, and the 442nd Regimental Combat Team with unwavering patriotism.&nbsp; The all-Japanese American 100th Infantry Battalion and the 442nd Regimental Combat Team became two of the most decorated and distinguished military units in our Nation&#8217;s history.&nbsp; Countless Japanese Americans carry forward this legacy of extraordinary service today, and their work to preserve the history of this period strengthens our Nation and our democracy.<br><br>We reflect on the bravery of civil rights leaders like Fred Korematsu, Minoru Yasui, Gordon Hirabayashi, and Mitsuye Endo, and that of every Japanese American who organized and sought redress. &nbsp;Their efforts helped bring about the first Day of Remembrance, led President Jimmy Carter to sign the law creating the Commission on Wartime Relocation and Internment of Civilians, and spurred President Ronald Reagan to sign the Civil Liberties Act of 1988, which provided monetary reparations to living survivors and an official apology to the Japanese American community. &nbsp;At the same time, we also acknowledge the painful reality that Japanese Latin Americans, who were taken from their Central and South American homes and incarcerated by the United States Government during World&nbsp;War&nbsp;II, were excluded from the Civil Liberties Act of 1988.<br><br>Today, the National Park Service helps preserve several Japanese American incarceration camps. &nbsp;These tangible reminders of our history provide important spaces for reflection and learning about the injustices born of prejudice. &nbsp;Preserving incarceration sites as national parks and historic landmarks is proof of our Nation&#8217;s commitment to facing the wrongs of our past, to healing the pain still felt by survivors and their descendants, and to ensuring that we always remember why it matters that we never stop fighting for equality and justice for all.&nbsp; My Administration is committed to maintaining these national parks and landmarks for future generations and to combating xenophobia, hate, and intolerance &#8212; including through the reestablished White House Initiative on Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders. &nbsp;In the words of&nbsp;Dr. Frank Kitamoto, who was incarcerated as a child, &#8220;This is not just a Japanese American story but an American story with implications for the world.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>The words we use to describe the historical and present treatment of communities of color and other underserved communities have profound meaning. &nbsp;Today, we recognize that euphemistic terms that we have collectively used in the past &#8212; such as &#8220;assembly centers,&#8221; &#8220;relocation,&#8221; or &#8220;internment&#8221; &#8212; do not adequately describe the injustice experienced by some 120,000 people; we recognize the forced removal and mass incarceration of Japanese Americans and others during World War II; and we reaffirm our commitment to <em>Nidoto Nai Yoni</em><em>,</em> which translates to &#8220;Let It Not Happen Again.&#8221;<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim&nbsp;February&nbsp;19, 2022, as a Day of Remembrance of Japanese American Incarceration During World War II. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to commemorate this injustice against civil liberties and civil rights during World&nbsp;War&nbsp;II; to honor the sacrifice of those who defended the democratic ideals of this Nation; and to commit together to eradicate systemic racism to heal generational trauma in our communities.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighteenth day of February, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Eating Disorders Awareness Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/18/a-proclamation-on-national-eating-disorders-awareness-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 16:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47495</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Eating Disorders Awareness Week provides an opportunity to draw attention to one of the most serious mental health conditions impacting the lives of Americans and their families today.&#160; Eating disorders &#8212; including binge-eating, bulimia nervosa, and anorexia nervosa &#8212; affect people of all backgrounds and genders. &#160;Nearly 1 in 10 Americans are expected to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Eating Disorders Awareness Week provides an opportunity to draw attention to one of the most serious mental health conditions impacting the lives of Americans and their families today.&nbsp; Eating disorders &#8212; including binge-eating, bulimia nervosa, and anorexia nervosa &#8212; affect people of all backgrounds and genders. &nbsp;Nearly 1 in 10 Americans are expected to develop an eating disorder in their lifetime.&nbsp; In recent years, there has been a troubling surge in eating disorders among children, older adults, military service members, and transgender individuals. &nbsp;When undiagnosed or untreated, eating disorders can have serious &#8212; even fatal &#8212; consequences, which is why improving mental health services and support is so important.</p>



<p>The COVID-19 pandemic has been especially challenging for individuals with eating disorders.&nbsp; National eating disorder hotlines have seen a more than 70&nbsp;percent spike in the volume of calls and chats since the pandemic started.&nbsp; Research shows that the number of hospitalizations for eating disorders has doubled during that same time period.</p>



<p>Despite the fact that eating disorders have among the highest mortality rate of any mental illness, the shame and stigmatization of eating disorders often prevent people who are suffering from seeking help.&nbsp; That is why it is important to make more people aware that, with early detection and medical intervention, full recovery from an eating disorder is possible.</p>



<p>My Administration is working to improve access to treatment, recovery, and social support for everyone currently living with an eating disorder as well as for their caregivers, families, and friends.&nbsp; Through the National Institute of Mental Health, we are working to develop better therapies and interventions.&nbsp; My Administration is also working to ensure that eating disorder care and treatment are treated the same as any other medical conditions by health insurance plans.&nbsp; Funding from the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) provides health care providers, families, caregivers, and community members the tools, training, and resources to recognize the symptoms of an eating disorder so that referrals to specialty providers and treatment can be provided as early as possible.</p>



<p>We are also working to increase access to mental health services and support for young people, who are uniquely vulnerable to eating disorders.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan included $122 billion to help schools reopen safely, enabling them to support the mental health of their students.&nbsp; I have also called for doubling the number of school-based health counselors, social workers, and nurses.&nbsp; Together, these resources will be essential to addressing the mental health needs of our Nation&#8217;s youth.</p>



<p>To all those families who have watched a loved one face an eating disorder and to all those who are currently facing or recovering from an eating disorder &#8212; you are in our hearts and you are not alone.  It is within our power to reduce the burden of eating disorders on the lives of Americans and their families.  As we work toward these improvements, immediate assistance is available for those in need of help.  The SAMHSA National Helpline at 1-800-662-4357 is a confidential, free, 24-hour-a-day, 365-days-a-year information and referral service.  For anyone experiencing a crisis, immediate help is also available by calling the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline at 1-800-273-TALK.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim February 21 through February 27, 2022, as National Eating Disorders Awareness Week.&nbsp; I encourage citizens, government agencies, private businesses, nonprofit organizations, and other interested groups to join in activities that will increase awareness of what Americans can do to prevent eating disorders and improve access to care and other support services for those currently living with an eating disorder.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighteenth day of February, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Meeting with NATO Secretary General&#160;Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/18/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-stoltenberg/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 15:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Munich, Germany, and underscored our enduring commitment to the Transatlantic Alliance. They emphasized their shared support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They also discussed the continued readiness of the U.S. and NATO to engage in dialogue with Russia, as well as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris met today with NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg in Munich, Germany, and underscored our enduring commitment to the Transatlantic Alliance.</p>



<p>They emphasized their shared support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. They also discussed the continued readiness of the U.S. and NATO to engage in dialogue with Russia, as well as efforts to strengthen NATO’s deterrence and collective defense in response to potential further Russian aggression against Ukraine. The Vice President reiterated that the U.S. commitment to Article 5 and the security of its NATO Allies is ironclad.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 15:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47483</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Commerzbank Filiale München Munich, Germany 1:22 P.M. CEST VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&#160; Mr. Secretary General, thank you for all of the work that you have been doing over the course of eight years in your role of leadership.&#160; As I mentioned to you earlier, this is the first meeting that I&#8217;m taking in Munich, and that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Commerzbank Filiale München </em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Munich, Germany</em></p>



<p>1:22 P.M. CEST<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Mr. Secretary General, thank you for all of the work that you have been doing over the course of eight years in your role of leadership.&nbsp;<br><br>As I mentioned to you earlier, this is the first meeting that I&#8217;m taking in Munich, and that is intentional.&nbsp; The President and I feel very strongly, as does our country, that our Alliance and our relationship and commitment to NATO is enduring, that it is being highlighted without any question over the course of the last several months.<br><br>We believe that the relationship has only strengthened.&nbsp; And as we go forward, we believe that it will continue to be one of the most critical relationships that we have.&nbsp;<br><br>I also want to thank you for the commitment that you have made throughout your career to the importance of the transatlantic Alliance &#8212; understanding its history and understanding its role in terms of international norms and rules, what we must do to ensure security, also with the interests of mutual prosperity.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, we are obviously dealing with the concern about what is happening in Ukraine.&nbsp; As a member of NATO, we feel very strongly and will always be committed to the principle of territorial integrity and sovereignty.&nbsp;<br><br>I am here to ensure that through our discussions and the discussions I will have with other of our Allies, that we continue, as these hours and days progress, to stay in close contact.<br><br>We understand this is a dynamic moment in time.&nbsp; And so, the work that we are doing on a daily basis and sometimes on an hourly basis &#8212; to strengthen the relationship; to check in, in terms of our strategic imperative &#8212; is critically important.&nbsp; And that is one of the reasons that I am here.<br><br>So, I thank you again for all that you do and all that you have done.&nbsp; We remain, of course, open to and desirous of diplomacy as it relates to the dialogue and the discussions we have had with Russia.&nbsp;<br><br>But we are also committed if Russia takes aggressive action to ensuring there will be severe consequence in terms of the economic sanctions we have discussed. And we know the Alliance is strong in that regard.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, I thank you for your leadership as a partner in that effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really a great pleasure to meet you and to be able to sit down and to address some of the very serious and security challenges we face together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And NATO remains the cornerstone for our security &#8212; the security of Europe and for North America.&nbsp; And therefore, I&#8217;m extremely grateful for your personal commitment to our Alliance, to the transatlantic bond, and also the very strong and staunch commitment to NATO from the Biden-Harris administration not only in words, but also in deeds.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We see it on the ground in Europe now.&nbsp; On Friday, I went to Romania and met U.S. troops there.&nbsp; And they always impress me with their professionalism, their dedication.&nbsp; And, of course, to have U.S. troops &#8212; more U.S. troops in Europe now, in this critical time for our security, really demonstrates the North American and the U.S. commitment to our shared security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also welcome the fact that European Allies are stepping up, also increasing their presence in the eastern part of the Alliance and also investing more in defense.</p>



<p>So, the reality is that North America and Europe are doing more together now than have done for many years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS: &nbsp;Yes.</p>



<p>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; That&#8217;s important to deal with the aggressive actions of Russia, but also to address a more competitive world, the security consequences of the rise of China.&nbsp; We have to stand together in North America and Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, yeah, thank you for your leadership, your commitment, and I look forward to our meeting.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 1:26 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Kansas Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/17/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-kansas-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 02:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47474</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Kansas and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms and straight-line winds on December 15, 2021. Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Kansas and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe storms and straight-line winds on December 15, 2021.<br> <br>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe storms and straight-line winds in the counties of Barton, Brown, Clay, Cloud, Doniphan, Edwards, Ellis, Ellsworth, Ford, Geary, Gove, Graham, Grant, Gray, Greeley, Hamilton, Haskell, Hodgeman, Jewell, Kearny, Lane, Lincoln, Logan, Marshall, Meade, Mitchell, Morris, Morton, Nemaha, Ness, Osborne, Ottawa, Pawnee, Republic, Rice, Riley, Rooks, Rush, Russell, Saline, Scott, Sheridan, Smith, Stafford, Stanton, Stevens, Sumner, Trego, Wabaunsee, Wallace, Washington, Wichita, and Wyandotte.<br> <br>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.<br> <br>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named DuWayne Tewes as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.<br> <br>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.<br> <br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Draghi of&#160;Italy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/17/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-draghi-of-italy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 23:50:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47471</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy.&#160;The leaders reviewed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. They&#160;reaffirmed their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and their readiness to impose severe economic costs on Russia if it further invades Ukraine.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy.&nbsp;The leaders reviewed ongoing diplomatic and deterrence efforts in response to Russia’s continued military build-up on Ukraine’s borders. They&nbsp;reaffirmed their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity and their readiness to impose severe economic costs on Russia if it further invades Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
