<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 02:53:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Senate Passage of Bipartisan Gun&#160;Legislation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-senate-passage-of-bipartisan-gun-legislation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 02:53:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tonight, after 28 years of inaction, bipartisan members of Congress came together to heed the call of families across the country and passed legislation to address the scourge of gun violence in our communities. Families in Uvalde and Buffalo &#8211; and too many tragic shootings before &#8211; have demanded action. &#160;And tonight, we acted. This&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Tonight, after 28 years of inaction, bipartisan members of Congress came together to heed the call of families across the country and passed legislation to address the scourge of gun violence in our communities. Families in Uvalde and Buffalo &#8211; and too many tragic shootings before &#8211; have demanded action. &nbsp;And tonight, we acted.</p>



<p>This bipartisan legislation will help protect Americans. Kids in schools and communities will be safer because of it. The House of Representatives should promptly vote on this bipartisan bill and send it to my desk.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of&#160;1961</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/23/memorandum-on-the-delegation-of-authority-under-section-506a1-of-the-foreign-assistance-act-of-1961-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 02:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&#160;hereby delegate to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Delegation of Authority Under Section 506(a)(1)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;621 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA), I&nbsp;hereby delegate to the Secretary of State the authority under section&nbsp;506(a)(1) of the FAA to direct the drawdown of up to an aggregate value of $450 million in defense articles and services of the Department of Defense, and military education and training, to provide assistance to Ukraine and to make the determinations required under such section to direct such a drawdown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris’s Meeting with State Attorneys General on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/readout-of-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-state-attorneys-general-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened Attorneys General from seven states to discuss the fight for reproductive rights. The roundtable followed recent meetings about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with health care providers, faith leaders, and constitutional law, privacy, and technology experts, and was part of the Administration’s work to build coalitions and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">Today, Vice President Kamala Harris convened Attorneys General from seven states to discuss the fight for reproductive rights. The roundtable followed recent meetings about reproductive rights that the Vice President held with health care providers, faith leaders, and constitutional law, privacy, and technology experts, and was part of the Administration’s work to build coalitions and preparedness in response to the attack on reproductive rights.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Vice President told the Attorneys General that they play a pivotal role in defending a woman’s right to make decisions about her own body. She spoke about how Attorneys General have a role in protecting the health, safety, and wellbeing of the women in their state — and as a result, can consider the various authorities they have to defend reproductive rights and freedoms, including access to abortion. The officials shared the steps they have taken so far to protect access to reproductive health care in their states, and they discussed their powers under their authority as their state’s chief legal officers.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Vice President thanked the Attorneys General for their leadership in safeguarding our nation’s most fundamental rights and freedoms. She encouraged them to continue striving for new ways to protect reproductive rights.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Participants:</strong></p>



<ul><li>Attorney General Josh Kaul (Wisconsin)</li><li>Attorney General Aaron Ford (Nevada)</li><li>Attorney General Kwame Raoul (Illinois)</li><li>Chief Deputy Attorney General Venus Johnson (California)</li><li>Attorney General Kathleen Jennings (Delaware) (virtual)</li><li>Attorney General Letitia James (New York) (virtual)</li><li>Attorney General Bob Ferguson (Washington state) (virtual)</li><li>Julie Chavez Rodriguez, Director of White House Office of Intergovernmental Affairs</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Meeting on the Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation&#160;Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/23/remarks-by-president-biden-before-meeting-on-the-federal-state-offshore-wind-implementation-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 22:04:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56162</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 3:24 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I want to say to the press: We have an impressive group of governors, labor leaders, and business leaders in the room here, but I&#8217;m not going to take the time to introduce everybody right now.&#160; Let me just say that &#8212; at the outset here &#8212; that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>3:24 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I want to say to the press: We have an impressive group of governors, labor leaders, and business leaders in the room here, but I&#8217;m not going to take the time to introduce everybody right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me just say that &#8212; at the outset here &#8212; that &#8212; you know, Cabinet members, as well &#8212; that I think we&#8217;re at a place where we&#8217;re reaching an exciting point where it seems like there&#8217;s been a coalescence of notion that, you know, alternative energy makes sense, and wind is a gigantic piece of it.</p>



<p>I was in Colorado, and I actually &#8212; I never thought I&#8217;d see a blade for a windmill that was 102 yards long.&nbsp; And you could literally pick up the end of it, it was &#8212; I mean, the technology is changing so incredibly.</p>



<p>But look, you know, we&#8217;re going to deepen our partnership on offshore wind as well as climate overall, and create jobs &#8212; good jobs, union jobs.</p>



<p>And I apologize, I&#8217;m always talking about unions, but the reason I talk about it, not a joke, is because they have the single-most qualified workers in the world.&nbsp; I mean, they&#8217;re the best trained.&nbsp; They &#8212; it&#8217;s like going to college.&nbsp; You got a four-year apprenticeship.&nbsp; You know, you&#8217;re getting paid a little bit when you&#8217;re doing it, but it&#8217;s a lot of work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I just think it&#8217;s really, you know &#8212; you know, building trade jobs, steel jobs, manufacturing jobs.&nbsp; And, you know, it&#8217;s not just about the future, it&#8217;s about right now.</p>



<p>Listen, we&#8217;re &#8212; I think we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;ve gone beyond &#8212; we&#8217;ve been talking about this a long time.&nbsp; We talked about this a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in &#8212; the last administration tried to block offshore wind because they thought it might cause cancer.&nbsp; Not a joke. But they actually &#8212; that’s what the last guy said.&nbsp; But it had nothing to do with that.&nbsp; What it had to do with is they just didn&#8217;t want to invest in alternative energy.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and I might add &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; about labor: Before I &#8212; when I was running, I made sure to go to all the major labor unions and tell them what my environmental plan was and why.&nbsp; And when I think “climate,” when I think “environment,” I think “jobs.”&nbsp; Jobs.&nbsp; And this &#8212; these are good-paying jobs, and they&#8217;re making a big, big difference.</p>



<p>And my administration set bold targets to start with: 30 gigawatts by 2030.&nbsp; That’s 10 million homes.&nbsp; Ten million homes with offshore wind.&nbsp; Ports turned back into economic engines, being in a position where foundries and factories are up and running &#8212; again, creating jobs.&nbsp; And a more resilient grid, harnessing technologies like battery storage.<br><br>And, by the way, I know you all know it, but I &#8212; I’m not sure everybody in the country knows it: The technology is changing so rapidly on battery technology.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just astounding what I predict you&#8217;re going to see in the next 2 to 10 years &#8212; I mean, in terms of technological changes.<br><br>And this is a real boost for energy security.&nbsp; It really changes the creation of &#8212; and jobs, and it cuts consumer costs.<br><br>And we&#8217;ve approved more project, we&#8217;ve had record-setting lease sales, and we pushed the community investment project labor agreements and domestic in &#8212; and the domestic supply chains in ways that hasn&#8217;t occurred before.<br><br>We&#8217;ve shown that we’re both open for business and as &#8212; millions of private &#8212; have spent billions in private capital, like companies that are here around this table as well.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been states who are doubling down, like the governors in this room and on the screen.&nbsp; And &#8212; and, together, you know, we&#8217;re stepping up, like union workers are in this room as well.<br><br>And, you know, I don&#8217;t think we could have had this meeting four years ago, fi- &#8212; not because of previous &#8212; I mean, it’s just so much has changed.&nbsp; There&#8217;s business, labor, governors, all coming together in ways that we weren&#8217;t before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and so I just think that it&#8217;s meant workers and communities stepping up.&nbsp; And together, we&#8217;re about to build a better America.&nbsp; I really mean that &#8212; an even better America.<br><br>And I just wanted to stop by and thank everybody.&nbsp; And I might note what one of my staff members said earlier, before I &#8212; when I was, earlier in the afternoon, talking about this.&nbsp; And that is that we&#8217;re in a position where, you know, if you take a &#8212; do you have that &#8212; where is the staff that has that &#8212; that printout of the size of these &#8212; would you mind bringing it up to me?<br><br>(A document is handed to the President.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>This I show everybody I can, and you&#8217;ve all seen it.&nbsp; You &#8212; this table knows.&nbsp; When we’re talking about &#8212; this is the rendering of the Empire State Building.&nbsp; This is the Eiffel Tower.&nbsp; This is the average onshore turbine &#8212; 460 feet.&nbsp; This is the tallest onshore turbine &#8212; 540 feet.&nbsp; This is the new GE Haliade-X 835-foot offshore wind project on Block Island.&nbsp; Look how tall it is.&nbsp; Almost up &#8212; 853 feet.</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s a reason why this is important, as you all know, but I want the press to know &#8212; is that the wind that far out in the ocean is always blowing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like it&#8217;s just every once in a while, like you&#8217;d wait on shore, where we have to deal with battery storage, storing technology, et cetera.&nbsp; It&#8217;s always blowing.&nbsp; And it can produce as much energy as a coalmine, as much energy as an oil, you know, well &#8212; wells.&nbsp; I mean, it&#8217;s just &#8212; and it&#8217;s &#8212; and it&#8217;s clean, and it&#8217;s real, and it&#8217;s continuous.</p>



<p>And so I just want to thank you all for all you&#8217;re willing to do, and particularly the private companies who are stepping up here.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s big time.&nbsp; We’re stepping up, and we&#8217;re talking billions of dollars.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not just talking a little bit of money; we&#8217;re talking billions of dollars.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;re going to get a lot done.</p>



<p>And I can&#8217;t tell you the last time I&#8217;ve been this excited about something we&#8217;re about to do, because I think we can change &#8212; literally begin to change the nature of how we generate industry &#8212; excuse me &#8212; generate energy.&nbsp; And the industry is stepping up.</p>



<p>And, by the way, I’m not &#8212; I’m going to get going too much.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Because I’m a little &#8212; I’m a little excited about it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, are you disappointed in the gun decision?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Am I disappointed in the &#8212; well, I’ll answer this one question.&nbsp; And I was just talking to the Governor of New York about this.</p>



<p>I am disappointed in the Supreme Court gun decision.&nbsp; There is one little bit of solace.&nbsp; And the &#8212; the minority making up the majority opinion has laid out that it affects not every state; it affects only 40 states.&nbsp; A lot of states it affects.</p>



<p>And the phrase that I found noticeable was: There&#8217;s a difference between states that say “may” and say “shall.”&nbsp; If you have to say you “shall” give, you “shall” do ABC, they’re the ones that are going to have problems.&nbsp; But most say “may.”&nbsp; I mean, “may” &#8212; I got it reversed &#8212; “may” and “shall.”</p>



<p>And so there are &#8212; the gun laws in 40 of these states are still in place based on the decision.&nbsp; Not good enough, but it&#8217;s &#8212; I think it&#8217;s a bad decision.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s &#8212; and I think it&#8217;s not reasoned accurately.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m disappointed.</p>



<p>Thank you. </p>



<p>3:33 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White&#160;House COVID-&#8288;19 Response Team and Public Health&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/23/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-86/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 20:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56154</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 2:40 P.M. EDT DR. JHA:&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; My name is Ashish Jha, and I am the COVID-19 Response Coordinator for the White House.&#160; First of all, apologies for the technical delays getting us started, but I am excited and delighted to get going this afternoon with two familiar faces, two colleagues who&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>2:40 P.M. EDT<br><br>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; My name is Ashish Jha, and I am the COVID-19 Response Coordinator for the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First of all, apologies for the technical delays getting us started, but I am excited and delighted to get going this afternoon with two familiar faces, two colleagues who have been tirelessly battling the pandemic since the beginning of this pandemic more than two years ago.&nbsp; You know them both well: Dr. Rochelle Walensky and Tony Fauci.</p>



<p>Today, we want to update you on a really important topic, one that many parents and, really, America has waited for for a long time: the first COVID-19 vaccines for our youngest kids.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s been nearly 18 months since the first set of vaccines became available for adults.&nbsp; And just over the last week, we saw the FDA authorize and CDC recommend vaccines for children six months and above, for the first time.</p>



<p>Now, this is an important moment for families of kids under five, but it&#8217;s a historic moment for our nation, because essentially, every American, from our oldest to our youngest, is now eligible for the protection that vaccines provide.</p>



<p>Now, we know that these vaccines are extraordinarily safe and highly effective.&nbsp; Remember, after an extensive review by career FDA and CDC scientists, they were unanimously approved by an independent group of expert scientists.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, I like to remind people it&#8217;s hard to get a group of independent scientists agree on anything, and yet 21 independent scientists who serve on VRBPAC unanimously voted in agreement that the benefits of these vaccines clearly outweigh the risks.&nbsp; And then, 12 independent scientists that make up the a ACIP agreed, recommending these vaccines for kids six months and above.</p>



<p>Now, we have been, at HHS and in the administration, have been planning and preparing for this moment for a long time.&nbsp; When the President took office, he made a commitment that &#8212; to keep all families safe from COVID-19 across America.&nbsp; The availability of these vaccines brings us that much closer to that goal.</p>



<p>Now, to make sure that these vaccines get to the families that want them, we have launched a comprehensive effort with trusted partners.&nbsp; These partners include states, local health departments, pediatricians, family physicians, rural and community health centers, and pharmacies.&nbsp; In fact, our largest federal pharmacy partners &#8212; Walgreens, CVS, and Walmart &#8212; are stepping up and are already vaccinating children, as are many pediatricians across the country.</p>



<p>Now, as I have said to all of you on many occasions, we know this vaccination program will ramp up over time.&nbsp; Remember, vaccines could not be shipped until they were authorized by the FDA on Friday.&nbsp; As of today, I can report that more than 4 million doses have been delivered within days of authorization to approximately 13,000 sites across the country.&nbsp; And as more doses are received and more sites make those doses available, that information will also become available on Vaccines.gov.</p>



<p>Now, when you look at this vaccination program for our littlest Americans, it will feel a little different than the vaccination programs we&#8217;ve run before.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s because we know parents will be turning to their pediatricians and their family physicians.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have been guided in our approach by very clear data that says that most parents want to vaccinate their littlest ones in familiar settings.&nbsp; We also know that many parents have questions.&nbsp; And we want to encourage every physici- &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry &#8212; every parent to talk to their physician, to talk to the pediatrician, to talk to the family physician.</p>



<p>We also know that confidence in vaccines builds over time.&nbsp; And I remind people that at the start of the adult vaccination program back in December of 2020, only one in three adults said they were eager to get the shot.&nbsp; Today, nearly 90 percent of adults have gotten at least one shot.</p>



<p>We know the importance of working with trusted voices and community leaders, and we&#8217;re doing just that.&nbsp; HHS has partnered with over a thousand organizations, many of which work in minority and rural communities, organizations like the National Parent Teacher Association and the Cobb Institute of the National Medical Association.&nbsp; Both of them have been great partners.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also started the COVID-19 Community Corps, an effort that has grown to include 17,000 members across healthcare, sports, rural, and faith organizations &#8212; organizations like Black Doctors for the COVID-19 Consortium and the National Indian Health Board.</p>



<p>Now, I want to address one issue that&#8217;s very important, and that is the issue of misinformation about vaccines and about kids and COVID in this pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So let&#8217;s set the record straight, because the data here is actually quite clear: Kids are better protected if they are vaccinated.&nbsp; If they are vaccinated, they are far less likely to get seriously ill.&nbsp; They&#8217;re far less likely to end up in the hospital, far less likely to end up in the ICU.</p>



<p>Tens of millions of children in the U.S. and around the world have already been vaccinated against COVID.&nbsp; And the safety profile of these vaccines is extraordinary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have three children, all of whom have been vaccinated.&nbsp; In fact, every physician I know, including and particularly pediatricians, have all vaccinated their eligible children.</p>



<p>Now, we&#8217;ve come a long way in our fight against COVID-19, with vaccines and treatments and other tools, like testing that have become widely available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m pleased to make another announcement today: The Biden-Harris administration is making more accessible tests available for individuals who are blind or visually impaired.&nbsp; These tests are available for free through COVIDTest.gov.</p>



<p>We developed this plan in close partnership with members of the disability community.&nbsp; An issue raised consistently was that individuals who are blind or low vision are often unable to utilize rapid self-tests on their own.&nbsp; The President has made clear he is committed to addressing the needs of individuals with disabilities regardless of where they live or the level of community transmission.&nbsp; Ensuring everyone has equitable access to COVID-19 testing and all other critical missio- &#8212; all other critical mitigation strategies is of the utmost importance.</p>



<p>So, in closing, the numbers in our fight against COVID-19 speak for themselves.&nbsp; Nearly three months after cases began to rise in the U.S., the deaths are actually down, and down 90 percent since the day the President took office.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; This has not happened randomly.&nbsp; Deaths are down because two out of three Americans are fully vaccinated, and half of them are boosted, because we have widespread availability of therapeutics like Paxlovid.<br><br>So, yes, we&#8217;ve made a lot of progress, but our job is not done.&nbsp; The pandemic is not over.&nbsp; And while we still have a lot of worth to &#8212; work to do, it is worth celebrating milestones.&nbsp;<br><br>And this week, as the littlest members of our society begin to get vaccinated, we need to take a moment and reflect on the good news that is.<br><br>All right, with that, I&#8217;m going to turn it over to Dr. Rochelle Walensky who will update us on the state of the pandemic and the importance of getting vaccinated &#8212; getting children vaccinated.<br><br>Over to you, Rochelle.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Ashish.&nbsp; And good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; As per my usual, I’d like to start by walking through the latest data.<br><br>So, our current seven-day daily average of cases is about 99,400.&nbsp; And that represents a decrease of about 4 percent over the prior week.<br><br>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 4,400 cases per day, which is an increase of about 2 percent over the prior week.<br><br>And as Dr. Jha noted, the seven-day average of daily deaths is about 250 per day, which is a decrease of about 16 percent over the prior week.<br><br>CDC does follow COVID-19 community levels, and that allows individuals and communities to take action to protect themselves and others based on their local community level.&nbsp; This also allows us to focus our efforts on protecting those who are most at risk of severe COVID-19 illness.<br><br>Last week, CDC reported 21 percent of the U.S. population was living in a high COVID-19 community level, and nearly 40 percent was living in a medium community level, and 39 percent was living in a low community level.<br><br>We will have updated COVID-19 community levels posted tonight, and we do anticipate things shifting among our communities across the country.&nbsp; So please go to CDC.gov where you can find your COVID-19 community level online.<br><br>As Dr. Jha noted, this past week, we&#8217;ve taken another important step forward in our fight against COVID-19.&nbsp; Following rigorous scientific review and a transparent and comprehensive discussion by ACIP on their immune response, safety, and ability of vaccines to protect children against disease, CDC expanded its COVID-19 vaccine recommendations to all children six months through five years of age.&nbsp; This makes nearly 20 million additional children eligible for vaccines.<br><br>I know there&#8217;s been a great deal of anticipation for parents surrounding the authorization and recommendation of COVID-19 vaccines for our youngest children.&nbsp; And for many, the opportunity to vaccinate their children comes as a welcome relief.<br><br>For those who may still be hesitant, I want to emphasize that COVID-19 vaccines have and continue to undergo the most intense safety monitoring in our history.<br><br>Parents, it is, of course, okay if you still have questions.&nbsp; And if you do, I encourage you to talk to your child&#8217;s provider or your local pharmacist to learn more about the benefits and, of course, the safety of these vaccines.<br><br>In the meantime, I&#8217;d like to outline why COVID-19 vaccinations for our children are particularly important.<br><br>We do know that COVID-19 illness can be serious for children and that, as parents, we are always looking to do what&#8217;s right to protect them against harm.<br><br>While we want to prevent severe outcomes for every age, it&#8217;s exper- &#8212; it&#8217;s especially concerning to see severe outcomes in our youngest children &#8212; the hospitalizations and deaths.&nbsp;<br><br>Children should not need to be hospitalized.&nbsp; They should not need to go to the ICU, to be on a ventilator, and they certainly should not lose their life to this virus at such a young age.<br><br>During the Omicron wave, we saw a huge spike in COVID-19 cases in children and the highest hospitalization rates in children than at any other point during this pandemic, especially among our youngest, ages six months through four years, who had the highest rate of hospitalization among any age group under the age of 17.<br><br>Since January 2020, we&#8217;ve lost 215 children &#8212; each six months to four years &#8212; to COVID-19.<br><br>To put that in perspective, during March 2020 through April 2022, COVID-19 was among the top five leading causes of death in every age group of children under the age of 19 and the number one infectious cause of death in children.<br><br>No parent should have to face the stress of having a child who&#8217;s severely ill.&nbsp; Protecting &#8212; protection gained from COVID-19 vaccination could be the difference between a hospitalization, a hospital &#8212; a hospital visit, or even che- &#8212; saving a child&#8217;s life.&nbsp;&nbsp; And that&#8217;s unequivocally great news for parents.<br><br>We all want to do what&#8217;s best for our children.&nbsp; And for the safest vaccine and protection against COVID-19, do go and get your child COVID-19 vaccinated.<br><br>Young children do not need to have an underlying condition to be at risk of severe disease.&nbsp; In fact, over half of children hospitalized with COVID-19 were otherwise healthy and had no underlying medical condition.&nbsp; And children who have previously had COVID-19 can also still benefit from a COVID-19 vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>Evidence has shown that vaccine immunity results in a broader neutralizing antibody response that has broader protection against variants compared with infection-induced immunity alone.<br><br>So as a parent, as a physician, and as your CDC director, I strongly encourage all parents to get their child vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Our fight against COVID-19 is not over, as Dr. Jha mentioned.&nbsp; But we are in a much better place.&nbsp; And we are now armed with vaccines for our very youngest, and we have the armamentarium in our toolbox to face this virus head on.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.</p>



<p><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; What I&#8217;d like to do over the next minute or two is to just underscore and answer preemptively some of the questions that Dr. Walensky and Dr. Jha and I have received over the last few days since the announcement was made.<br><br>Let&#8217;s just take a very quick review of the questions that people ask.&nbsp; For example, parents ask: How did they come to this conclusion?&nbsp; What was the data that led to the approval and recommendation of these drugs?&nbsp; Well, as you know &#8212; of these vaccines.<br><br>As you know, we have two in question &#8212; Moderna and Pfizer.&nbsp; Both of those have gone under extensive placebo, blinded control trials, which is the gold standard of determining efficacy and safety.<br><br>If we go first to the Moderna trial, it involves 6,400 children and infants.&nbsp; The important point to emphasize is that this is a vaccine which is two doses four weeks apart.&nbsp;<br><br>Importantly, the immune responses that were elicited by the vaccines were comparable to those responses in younger adults and in adults that were receiving a higher dose that unequivocally, in a clinical trial, led to a clinical benefit.&nbsp;<br><br>So even though this is mostly an immunological bridging study, the fact remains that it is highly correlated with a good clinical effect.<br><br>What about the safety of the Moderna?&nbsp; When you do vaccines, one of the things you address is what&#8217;s called reactogenicity.&nbsp; Namely, what&#8217;s the immediate local or systemic effect?<br><br>So in summary, and very briefly, the reactogenicity of this vaccine was essentially the same &#8212; no better or worse than what we’ve seen with any of a number of childhood vaccines that we regularly administer to our children.<br><br>There was no incidence of myocarditis or multisystem inflammatory syndrome of children.<br><br>Very quickly, moving on to the Pfizer, which was a bit different &#8212; it was in three doses.&nbsp; First doses separated by three weeks, second dose by eight weeks.<br><br>Again, the bridging immunological situation indicated that the responses that were elicited by this vaccine was equivalent to the responses in other studies, including young adults and in adults which were clearly associated with a beneficial clinical response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With regard to the safety data of Pfizer BioNTech, the same thing: The reactogenicity &#8212; for example, fevers, pain at the site &#8212; were really quite comparable to what we&#8217;ve seen in vaccines that all of us have been administering to our children over years and years.</p>



<p>The bottom line of all of this is that the FDA evaluation and analysis of the safety, effectiveness, and manufacturing data were very rigorously and comprehensively looked at to support the EUA.&nbsp; The known and potential benefits clearly outweigh the known and potential risks in this pediatric population.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we want to make sure you understand, parents, that prior to making the decision to authorize and recommend these vaccines, the FDA&#8217;s and CDC&#8217;s independent advisory committees, as you heard, were consulted and voted unanimously in support of the authorization and the recommendation.&nbsp; Therefore, we are all very enthusiastic about getting your children vaccinated with these now available products.</p>



<p>Back to you, Dr. Jha.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, Drs. Fauci and Walensky.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go ahead and go to questions.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to ask my colleague, Kevin Munoz, to get us get us going on that.&nbsp; Kevin?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Dr. Jha.&nbsp; I say this a lot, but we have to keep to one question per person.&nbsp; So, please do that so we can get through as many as we can.</p>



<p>Sheryl Stolberg, New York Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to immediately violate your admonition and ask two questions.&nbsp; The first is about the kids’ vaccines.&nbsp; I noticed on the Vaccines.gov that a lot of these pharmacies say they&#8217;ll vaccinate ages three and up, and I wondered why that is and if there&#8217;s a problem with getting vaccines to the youngest children.</p>



<p>And then &#8212; so this is for Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, I think a lot of Americans are just wondering how you&#8217;re feeling and what your experience with COVID was and how you got infected.&nbsp; And I just wondered if you could share a little bit of that.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Well, why don&#8217;t we start there?&nbsp; Tony, give us an update on how you&#8217;re feeling.</p>



<p>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m actually &#8212; Sheryl, thank you for asking &#8212; I&#8217;m feeling really fine.&nbsp; I had some mild symptoms last Tuesday.&nbsp; I checked my antigen test on Wednesday.&nbsp; It was positive.&nbsp; I had one day of symptomatology.&nbsp; I started on Wednesday on Paxlovid.&nbsp; And I was on Paxlovid for five days, and I have now finished Paxlovid and I&#8217;m still feeling really quite fine.</p>



<p>I think I&#8217;m an example, given my age, of what we&#8217;re all talking about today.&nbsp; I&#8217;m vaccinated.&nbsp; I&#8217;m doubly boosted.&nbsp; And I believe if that were not the case, I very likely would not be talking to you looking as well as I look, I think, right now.&nbsp; So, all is well with Fauci, and thank you for asking.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; You look great, Tony.&nbsp; So, indeed, thank goodness for vaccines and Paxlovid.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the issue of kids under three, this is &#8212; and vaccinating kids under three, this is really about the PREP Act. And, Rochelle, I don&#8217;t know if you know more about the details behind this to comment about why it is that some places will vaccinate kids under three and other places on won&#8217;t.</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, no, I would say much of this may be related to the PREP Act, but also ability of pharmacies to handle younger kids and also the willingness of parents to potentially want to take their younger kids to where they routinely get vaccinated, whether it&#8217;s their local community health center or their local pediatrician.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Tamara Keith at NPR.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; President Biden was recently asked if there is enough supply of vaccines for these children, and he said that, &#8220;We&#8217;ll get through at least this year,&#8221; with the current level of funding.&nbsp; I&#8217;m hoping you could verify whether that is the case and also expand out.&nbsp; Is there enough funding for every American who needs a bivalent vaccine, if one of those is developed, to be able to get that?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, so he was asked &#8212; I think I was there when he was asked this question.&nbsp; He was largely being asked about the current campaign for kids.&nbsp; And so, let me be very clear on that.&nbsp; We have more than enough Moderna and Pfizer for every child who wants one or every parent of a child who wants one for this pediatric vaccine campaign.</p>



<p>As you all know, we&#8217;ve been very open that we have moved money from other critical programs at HHS to an effort to buy some vaccines.&nbsp; We do not believe we have actually, just based on &#8212; again, without getting into the details of the contracting, which has not happened yet &#8212; we will not have enough vaccines for every American who wants one this fall and winter.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s, of course, the bivalent vaccines that we&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp; We should have enough for potentially high-risk individuals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But one of the reasons we&#8217;ve been asking for additional funding from Congress is we need funding to make sure that every American who wants a bivalent vaccine, should one be authorized by the FDA, has the ability to do that.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to MJ Lee at CNN.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; This question is for Dr. Jha.&nbsp; Just revisiting the warning that you had made last month that the U.S. could potentially see 100 million new COVID infections if Congress doesn&#8217;t approve more funding.&nbsp; Given that that was based on preliminary and early data from modelers and experts, I&#8217;m just wondering whether now, more than a month later, you have an update or a revision on the forecast for the fall and winter, or does the 100 million new infections still fall somewhere in the middle of the projections that you have been studying.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, so, MJ, as I &#8212; as I said about a month ago, we are constantly looking at a whole range of data, both internal models developed by government scientists, as well as external models.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re planning for a range of scenarios. And that&#8217;s &#8212; of course, one of the range of scenarios we have is that we could see a substantial wave of infections.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re expecting new models and new data in the upcoming weeks.&nbsp; Again, it&#8217;s always hard to make longer-term projections.&nbsp; As we get closer to the date, you get more modeling data coming out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, my feeling is that we&#8217;re going to update people with kind of both what we&#8217;re seeing in the modeling data, but also what kinds of different scenarios we&#8217;re planning for. At the end of the day &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said this before &#8212; we try not to be in the prediction business and we try to be in the planning business.&nbsp; And we have to plan for a range of scenarios, obviously always hoping that we get a very mild winter that we have very few infections.&nbsp; But hoping is not a strategy.&nbsp; We are planning for a range of different scenarios.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is the 100 million still somewhere in the ra- &#8212; the middle of the range of the projections that you&#8217;ve been seeing, since that was a warning you had made last month?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah, so it was a couple of months ago, and I said it was one of the many things that we were seeing.&nbsp; And we have not gotten any updated numbers that I can report back on today.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s go to Tom Howell at the Washington Times.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Just real quick, do you know how many of these pediatric shots have been administered this week, not just delivered?&nbsp; And can you talk about how or why the U.S. became the first country in the world to offer these vaccines to zero to four years old?&nbsp; It seems like places like the UK or Israel sometimes beat the U.S. to the punch.&nbsp; I’m just wondering why that was not the case this time.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So let me start on the second.&nbsp; And then the first question of when we will have data on vaccines administered, I&#8217;m going to turn it over to Dr. Walensky, since CDC tracks that very closely.</p>



<p>You know, we had been among the first on getting vaccines authorized for almost every age group.&nbsp; Certainly on mRNA vaccines, we were the first to do that for adults.&nbsp; And then we have moved very quickly on getting authorizations for kids 12 to 17, then 5 to 11, and now zero to 4.</p>



<p>I think it is a combination of really vigorous scientific work that&#8217;s been done by the companies in close partnership with FDA, who has been very transparent and open about the standards required to get these authorizations.&nbsp; So I think it&#8217;s been a lot of very proactive work on these vaccines that has actually made America pretty consistently a leader, certainly on the mRNA vaccines, in terms of authorizing it for different populations.</p>



<p>On the issue of how many kids have gotten vaccinated, administered doses, I&#8217;m going to turn it over to Rochelle.&nbsp; Rochelle, when are we going to be able to see data coming in on that?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, Ashish.&nbsp; We intend &#8212; we plan to be very transparent in terms of the administration numbers, as we have been for all of our cohorts of children and adults getting vaccinated and boosted.&nbsp; Right now, we&#8217;re doing the work of delivering and then, of course, the administration.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working with our immunization partners in our jurisdictions to receive the administration data.&nbsp; When we have those in a more complete fashion, we&#8217;ll be able to report those publicly.</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; All right, next question.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Meg Tirrell at CNBC.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; Just one quick one, and then another one.&nbsp; The clinical guidelines from the CDC say that the doses can be spaced for the primary series for the littlest kids from you know, four or three, depending if it&#8217;s Moderna or Pfizer, up to eight weeks.&nbsp; Just wondering how you&#8217;d advise parents to think about how far they should space out those doses.</p>



<p>And then, just more broadly, you talked about the individual protection against severe disease from these vaccines.&nbsp; What will some of the social effects be of having this vaccine available?&nbsp; Will it mean things like you won&#8217;t have to quarantine if you&#8217;re in daycare, things like that?&nbsp; What will be &#8212; what will be the effect on parents and families?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Rochelle, why don’t I have you handle both those?</p>



<p>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, so I would say part of the reason for the range is to just recognize that it may be hard to keep &#8212; especially during summertime, with travel and with kids in camp, it may be hard to be strict to do the three or four weeks.</p>



<p>But I would say if you&#8217;re at risk of severe outcomes, if you’re &#8212; certainly if you&#8217;re immunocompromised, you want to be able to be fully protected as soon as possible.&nbsp; So I would err on the earlier side of that administration course.</p>



<p>With regard to guidance for families and for updated guidance, you know, we are actively &#8212; always continuously looking at our guidance.&nbsp; I would say the most important thing to do is to get your child vaccinated and get your family vaccinated, and that will deliver the most protection to you and your family and allow you to not be at risk of severe disease.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Cheyenne Haslett at ABC News.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; To follow up on the issue of COVID funding, can you say how many vaccines you&#8217;ve been able to purchase with that money that you diverted, or when you might be able to announce that, if it&#8217;s still in negotiations?</p>



<p>And what is the plan, if that&#8217;s not going to cover all Americans &#8212; since COVID funding seems off the table &#8212; to get people vaccines, you know, even if they&#8217;re not free from the government?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Two good questions.&nbsp; So we can&#8217;t talk about numbers because the negotiations have just gotten started, so there are no numbers to report.</p>



<p>Again, just to be very clear, we&#8217;re talking about bivalent vaccines that would be purchased for this fall and winter.&nbsp; Those bivalent vaccines have not even been authorized by the FDA.&nbsp; We think the FDA is going to authorize bivalent vaccines, but we&#8217;re not sure.</p>



<p>So, first of all, we&#8217;re going to hear more from the FDA next week.&nbsp; Then, negotiators &#8212; kind of, contract negotiators on behalf of U.S. government are going to enter into contract negotiations with Moderna and Pfizer, with the resources that we&#8217;ve been able to pull together, cobble together for vaccines for the fall.&nbsp; It&#8217;s very clear we&#8217;re not going to have enough vaccines for every adult who wants one.<br><br>But &#8212; and then we continue to have conversations, and we&#8217;ll continue to have conversations, with both Republicans and Democrats on the &#8212; on the Hill.<br><br>You know, look, I &#8212; I&#8217;m an eternal optimist.&nbsp; I remain convinced that Congress is not going to walk away at this point in the pandemic, when we have made so much progress and as we are looking into a fall and winter, with a new generation of vaccines.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe Congress will walk away and say, “We&#8217;re not going to make sure that every American who wants a vaccine is able to get one.”<br><br>There isn&#8217;t &#8212; there is not a commercialization plan that somehow would be &#8212; would be ready in time for this fall and winter.&nbsp; So we really have to make sure we have the resources we need so that people who want a vaccine this fall and winter from, you know, again, this new generation of vaccines &#8212; which we&#8217;ll hear more about from the FDA in the next week or so &#8211;we&#8217;ve got to make sure that that&#8217;s available to every American.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Zeke Miller at the AP.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; Just to follow up on the last question: Is there a &#8212; has any country cut in front of the U.S. on the contracting front?&nbsp; Last month, when you were &#8212; Dr. Jha, when you were saying the U.S. needed the money now to start the contracting process, it was to prevent other countries from moving in front of the line.&nbsp; So if you can clarify, is the U.S. still at the front of the line?<br><br>And, relatedly, just on your last point there, you said there&#8217;s no commercialization plan in place for the fall.&nbsp; So if the U.S. doesn&#8217;t have money to provide free vaccines for populations that aren&#8217;t high risk &#8212; other adults, they won&#8217;t even be able to buy those vaccines out of their own pocket?&nbsp; They&#8217;re just out of luck?&nbsp; Is that the administration&#8217;s message to them right now?</p>



<p>DR. JHA:&nbsp; So, first of all, on the issue of countries, I can talk about what&#8217;s public.&nbsp; I know Germany has signed contracts for a next generation of vaccines, these bivalent vaccines.&nbsp; I believe, both with Moderna and Pfizer &#8212; although I&#8217;m not 100 percent sure &#8212; but they certainly have &#8212; what we know is that many European countries are far along in their &#8212; in their contract negotiations with these companies.<br><br>We have not entered into those negotiations.&nbsp; We&#8217;re about to, because we&#8217;ve pulled these resources together.<br><br>So, you know, this is a problem, right?&nbsp; And we want to make sure that when these vaccines get authorized by the FDA and they get produced, that Americans are able to get them in time, before we see any kind of a fall or winter surge where we just see one.<br><br>So the &#8212; one of the reasons we pulled resources from other critical programs was we just felt like we couldn&#8217;t wait any longer.&nbsp; And if we waited much longer, we would not be able to get these vaccines &#8212; certainly for our high-risk individuals &#8212; in time to protect them.&nbsp; Certainly, if we got an early surge of infections, we would be &#8212; we would really not have the vaccines we needed.<br><br>In terms of, you know, what to do for people who are not high risk for whom we may not be able to purchase vaccines &#8212; look, this is a huge challenge.&nbsp; As I said, there is not an obvious way to get these things commercialized.<br><br>If you think about it from the perspective of these companies, they&#8217;re negotiating with countries around the world.&nbsp; They have certain limitations to their &#8212; to their production capacity.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;s not an easy way to make sure that the commercial purchasers somehow get in and beat out other countries to have product available.<br><br>So, we don&#8217;t &#8212; we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re looking at all the contingencies.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t get to walk away, right?&nbsp; And it&#8217;s one thing for Congress to say, “We&#8217;re not going to support this.”&nbsp; The administration doesn&#8217;t get to do that.&nbsp; We are in this.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to figure out solutions.&nbsp; But it would be a whole lot easier to make sure every American who wants a vaccine can get one and be protected if we can get funding from Congress.</p>



<p><br>MODERATOR:  We are done, Dr. Jha.<br><br>DR. JHA:  Thank you very much, Kevin.  Thank you, everybody, for joining us.  Huge thanks to my colleagues, Drs. Walensky and Fauci.  Great to see Dr. Fauci fully recovered and doing better. <br><br>Thank you for &#8212; all of you for joining us this afternoon.  We will be back again to give you more updates, but really appreciate people taking the time.  And thank you for your patience in the beginning when we had some technical issues.  And have a great day.  Thank you.<br><br>3:12 P.M. EDT</p>



<p></p>



<p>You can view the slides <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/COVID-Press-Briefing_6.23.22.pdf">HERE</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key Regional Appointments for&#160;USDA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/president-biden-announces-key-regional-appointments-for-usda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56138</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA): Ronald Guidry, Jr., USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Louisiana Maureen Wicks, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Montana Mark Gibbons, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden appointed the following individuals to serve in key regional leadership roles at the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA):</p>



<ul><li>Ronald Guidry, Jr., USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Louisiana</li><li>Maureen Wicks, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Montana</li><li>Mark Gibbons, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Utah</li><li>Christy Davis, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Kansas</li><li>Lillian Salerno, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Texas</li></ul>



<p>These regional appointees will be critical to the President’s efforts to rebuild communities most impacted by the pandemic, the economic recovery, and climate change. They bring deep expertise in their issue areas as well as critical relationships with federal, state, tribal, and local leaders. And, consistent with the President’s commitment to building an administration that looks like America, these regional appointees represent the diversity of America and the communities they serve.<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE (USDA)</u></strong></p>



<p>The USDA’s Farm Service Agency implements agricultural policy, administers credit and loan programs, and manages conservation, commodity, disaster, and farm marketing programs in each U.S. State. Its mission is to equitably serve all farmers, ranchers, and agricultural partners through the delivery of effective, efficient agricultural programs for all Americans. State Executive Directors oversee this work, ensuring the needs of local constituents are met and that USDA resources are distributed equitably and fairly.</p>



<p>USDA’s Rural Development mission area is committed to helping improve the economy and quality of life in rural America. State Directors lead offices that offer grants, loans, and loan guarantees to help create jobs and support economic development and essential services.</p>



<p><strong><u>Ronald Guidry, Jr., USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Louisiana</u></strong></p>



<p>Ronald C. Guidry, Jr. is a native of New Orleans and a proud alumnus of St. Augustine High School and Dillard University, from which he holds a degree in Communications. In his career, Guidry has established vital relationships with the community at large as well as the agricultural community both locally and internationally.</p>



<p>Since 2018, Guidry has served as the Advisor for the USDA Farm Service Agency County Committee, which serves multiple parishes across southeastern Louisiana. As Committee Advisor, Guidry has been charged with carrying out farm service agency programs, providing diverse viewpoints, and making informed policy decisions to ensure grassroots input and local administration of federal farm programs. He is also the owner and operator of Farm Dat, a USDA Class B certified farm, where he is responsible for overall operations including management, marketing, personnel, finances, and customer service/customer relations. While he is primarily focused on the purchasing, raising, and selling of farm animals, he consistently establishes and maintains community relationships with others from varied socioeconomic and cultural backgrounds to ensure farm sustainability.</p>



<p><strong><u>Maureen Wicks, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Montana</u></strong></p>



<p>Maureen “Morb” Wicks, a dryland wheat farmer from Liberty County, Montana, has been working for Montana farmers for more than 30 years. From 1985-1995, Wicks was heavily involved in WIFE (Women Involved in Farm Economics), including serving as the Hi-Line Chapter President and helping lead several lobbying trips to Washington, D.C. to champion family farm policy issues. In 1998, Wicks was the first female elected to the Liberty County Farm Services Administration, where she served for 16 years.</p>



<p>In 2014, Wicks was elected to serve as a Liberty County Commissioner and was re-elected in 2021. During her time as a Commissioner, Wicks served on the Montana Association of Counties Agriculture Committee, Liberty County Mental Health Advisory Board, and The Liberty County Council on Aging. Wicks additionally has served on the Tiber County Water Board, the Bear Paw Development Board, and the Liberty Medical Center Board. Wicks is a member of Montana Grain Growers and the Montana Farmer’s Union. She holds a B.A. in Political Science and Government from Montana State University and also taught Government/Social Studies for more than 15 years in both rural and urban school districts in Montana.</p>



<p><strong><u>Mark Gibbons, USDA State Executive Director, Farm Service Agency, Utah</u></strong></p>



<p>Mark Gibbons is a third-generation dairy farmer from Lewiston, Utah. He has spent his life there on the farm and now the next generation is running the operation; they milk 700 cows and farm 1200 acres of ground. Gibbons has served as Utah State Farm Service Agency Executive Director, President of the Utah Farmers Union, President of the Dairy Producers of Utah, President of the Governors Agriculture Advisory Board, Vice President of the Western States Dairy Producers Trade Association, Utah State FFA Foundation Board member, and on various additional farm-related committees. He resides in Lewiston with his wife, Shanna. They have three sons and daughters-in-law and eleven grandchildren.</p>



<p><strong><u>Christy Davis, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Kansas</u></strong><strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p>Christy Cauble Davis is a fifth-generation Kansan who has dedicated her career to strengthening Kansas communities. The projects and programs Davis has facilitated statewide have generated billions of dollars in economic impact. She has served as Legislative Chair for the Kansas Downtown Development Association and on the boards of the Chase County Chamber of Commerce, Council Grove/Morris County Hospital Foundation, Preservation Action, and National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers. After serving as a local and state government executive and developing a private consulting business, Davis worked to “heighten appreciation and knowledge of the Flint Hills tallgrass prairie” as Executive Director of Symphony in the Flint Hills.</p>



<p>David, her husband Luke, and their 10-year-old son Jack live in Chase County. In 2016, they adapted a historic building in Cottonwood Falls into an award-winning laundromat. In 2019, they spurred downtown revitalization in Council Grove by rehabilitating a historic bank building to create much-needed housing and space for a new bookstore. Davis likes to participate in community activities, hike, swim, and read.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lillian Salerno, USDA State Director, Rural Development, Texas</u></strong></p>



<p>Lillian Salerno has over two decades of experience leading teams in government and industry. Salerno served six years as an official for the Obama-Biden Administration, first as the Rural Business Administrator and later as Deputy Undersecretary for Rural Development at the United States Department of Agriculture. She was a member of the White House Rural Council where she provided an unwavering voice for rural Americans. As Deputy Undersecretary for USDA, Salerno managed both political and career federal workers and created diverse internal boards and committees. She also served on the Executive Resource Board, which included issues surrounding cybersecurity, executive compensation, and resource management. In addition, Salerno led the Hispanic Women Farmers National Claims Team.</p>



<p>Salerno has led and served on numerous White House working groups including the Interagency Task Force focused on the rural opioid epidemic as well as the White House National Economic Council “Investing in Manufacturing Communities” initiative. She has testified before Congress and served as the U.S. delegate to the Organization for Economic Co-Operation and Development, serving as Vice Chair for the Working Party on Rural Development. Salerno has always played an active part in civic life and is a former U.S. Democratic Congressional candidate for the 32<sup>nd</sup> District in Texas. Salerno has a long history advocating for and protecting vulnerable populations. As a young attorney in rural Texas, Salerno was regularly designated as the court-appointed ad litem for vulnerable and Spanish-speaking Texans. Salerno holds a B.A. in Latin American Studies from the University of Texas at Austin, an M.A. in Criminal Justice from the University of North Texas, and a J.D. from Southern Methodist University and is a graduate of the Executive Leadership Program from Harvard University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Bipartisan Vote to Advance Gun Safety&#160;Legislation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/statement-by-president-biden-on-bipartisan-vote-to-advance-gun-safety-legislation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 18:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I made the heartbreaking visit to families in Newtown nearly ten years ago, I promised them then that we would take action to help keep our kids safe in the classroom. It’s taken a decade, because&#160;for too long Congress has failed to make meaningful progress on gun safety reform. Our country has endured too&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>When I made the heartbreaking visit to families in Newtown nearly ten years ago, I promised them then that we would take action to help keep our kids safe in the classroom.<br><br>It’s taken a decade, because&nbsp;for too long Congress has failed to make meaningful progress on gun safety reform. Our country has endured too many tragedies since then, most recently with the horrific shootings in Buffalo and Uvalde.<br><br>When I traveled to Uvalde last month, I heard a clear message from families there: do something. Since then, I’ve carried their message forward – enough is enough, this time we have to do something.</p>



<p>Today, with the bipartisan cloture vote in the Senate, I am glad to see Congress has moved significantly closer to finally doing something – passing bipartisan legislation that will help protect Americans.</p>



<p>Our kids in schools and our communities will be safer because of this legislation. I call on Congress to finish the job and get this bill to my desk.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in a Meeting with State Attorneys General on Protecting Reproductive Healthcare&#160;Access</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/23/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-a-meeting-with-state-attorneys-general-on-protecting-reproductive-healthcare-access/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 17:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President’s Ceremonial OfficeEisenhower Executive Office Building 12:47 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  I want to welcome these extraordinary national leaders, the attorneys general, for meeting this afternoon to talk about, I think, one of the most pressing issues in terms of one of the core responsibilities of attorneys general, which is to concern&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President’s Ceremonial Office<br><em>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</em></em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">12:47 P.M. EDT<br> <br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  I want to welcome these extraordinary national leaders, the attorneys general, for meeting this afternoon to talk about, I think, one of the most pressing issues in terms of one of the core responsibilities of attorneys general, which is to concern themselves with the safety, the health, and the wellbeing of the populations of their state and, by extension, their country.<br> <br>I do want to also mention that we &#8212; the President, myself, many of us &#8212; are deeply concerned and troubled by the Supreme Court&#8217;s ruling today.  It, I believe, defies common sense and the Constitution of the United States. <br> <br>I was in Buffalo.  I attended one of the funerals.  We have seen the massacre of 19 babies and their teachers in Uvalde.  We can go on down the list about why it, yet again, is on the front pages, so to speak, of the concern of the American people about what we can and what we have a responsibility to do in terms of reasonable gun safety laws.<br> <br>And it is for that reason that I believe that the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision today defies logic in terms of what we know we are capable of doing with reasonable gun safety laws to secure the safety and the wellbeing of the people of our nation.<br> <br>And to the subject at hand: As a former Attorney General, I know the work of these extraordinary leaders, and it is the work of being charged with great responsibility &#8212; the responsibility to safeguard some of our most fundamental rights and freedoms.<br> <br>It is the responsibility to enforce civil rights protections.  It is the responsibility to protect consumers.  It is the responsibility as a chief legal officer, which each of them has a responsibility of being, to concern themselves with making sure that the laws that are passed in their state do comport with the constitutions of their state and with the United States Constitution, and to ensure that enforcement is conducted in a way that is fair and equal in terms of the treatment of the laws and the enforcement of the laws in their state.<br> <br>And so, I thank them for being here today.  We are specifically going to talk about an extension of their responsibilities, which has to do with the responsibility to concern themselves with the priority of ensuring the health, safety, and wellbeing of the women in their state and &#8212; and the protection of their reproductive rights and freedoms.<br> <br>And so, I have asked these attorneys general to meet with us, knowing they have a pivotal role to play in defending women&#8217;s reproductive freedom and their rights to make decisions about their own bodies.<br> <br>As reproductive rights are being restricted around our country and potentially by the Supreme Court soon, I think we believe and we&#8217;ve started preliminary discussions about how attorneys general &#8212; state attorneys general have the power &#8212; may have the power, at the very least, to issue guidance to ensure that the people of their state know their rights; that they have the power to assess and potentially challenge the constitutionality of laws that are being passed in their states; and to convene legal organizations, non-profit law firms around what the legal community in their state can do, has the ability to do, to offer pro-bono services, to offer services to the folks who will be affected by the laws that are being passed in their states.<br> <br>And, of course, for those attorneys general that have the jurisdiction around criminal prosecution in their states and, therefore, law enforcement &#8212; as many of them are the chief law enforcement officer of their state &#8212; the ability to direct law enforcement resources in a way that, again, is actually effective in ensuring the safety and the wellbeing of the people of their state. <br> <br>So, this is the conversation we are going to have.  I think it&#8217;s a very important point to make that, in 43 states in our nation, the people elect their attorney general. <br> <br>And so I urge the people of our country to know the power that they have to &#8212; to have an impact on how the laws of their state are enforced by paying attention to who their attorney general is and where they stand on this important issue in terms of enforcing the principles, the spirit, and the ideals of the Constitution of the United States in a way that is about equal treatment of all people. <br> <br>And so, with that, I thank you all again, these extraordinary leaders, for convening today.  And I look forward to our discussion.  And we will now begin our discussion.  So, thank you to the press for being here.  And I&#8217;ll wish you a good day. <br> <br>END                12:52 P.M. EDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Welcoming the Wounded Warrior Project Soldier&#160;Ride</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/23/remarks-by-president-biden-welcoming-the-wounded-warrior-project-soldier-ride/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 16:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56135</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn  9:01 A.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, I’ll tell you what: Talk about recovery.&#160; Folks, welcome to the White House.&#160; It sounds corny, but this is your house. And I want to thank you, Danielle, for the introduction and the extraordinary, extraordinary service to our country and for your remarkable devotion to your fellow&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn </p>



<p>9:01 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I’ll tell you what: Talk about recovery.&nbsp; Folks, welcome to the White House.&nbsp; It sounds corny, but this is your house.</p>



<p>And I want to thank you, Danielle, for the introduction and the extraordinary, extraordinary service to our country and for your remarkable devotion to your fellow veterans and wounded warriors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Talk about getting up; my dad used to have an expression.&nbsp; Said, “If you get knocked down, just get up.”&nbsp; Just get up.&nbsp; Well, it’s a lot easier to say than do, especially in the circumstances many of you’ve been through.</p>



<p>You know, as Jill said, you all &#8212; and it&#8217;s not hyperbole &#8212; you&#8217;re a little inspiration to the nation.&nbsp; I hope you don&#8217;t forget that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you&#8217;re joined by &#8212; we&#8217;re joined by the Vice President and the First Gentleman, Doug and Kamala, today and several members of Congress as well.</p>



<p>You know, of course, we&#8217;re honored to have with us the outstanding military veterans, families, and caregivers who stood by veterans throughout everything thick and thin.&nbsp; Jill and I used to spend a lot of time when I was Vice President and then when our son was ill &#8212; Army &#8212; over at Walter Reed, looking at the families &#8212; looking at the families and the caregivers who made such a gigantic difference in the attitude and the recovery of those veterans.</p>



<p>You know, from your parents to your children and your siblings, to your battle buddies: I want to thank everyone from the Wounded Warrior Project and countless other organizations and tireless advocates on your behalf &#8212; you know, wounded and injured service members and veterans.</p>



<p>When I was Vice President, I would always look forward to this event.&nbsp; We&#8217;d have the event over the VPR as well as come over here with the President.&nbsp; And it always, always mattered.</p>



<p>Riders come from every corner of America, from all cuts of the same cloth though, all bounded by a common sense of duty, honor, service, resilience, courage, optimism, and a remarkable group of people.&nbsp; You are America.&nbsp; You are everything America wants to be.</p>



<p>Watching it in this year&#8217;s &#8212; watching this year as President, I&#8217;m prouder than ever to be standing with you all.</p>



<p>And the Biden family &#8212; to us, it&#8217;s personal.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve always been inspired by all of you who, like our son, put your country above yourself to protect our way of life.</p>



<p>This year, we have 7 active-duty riders and 21 veterans.&nbsp; Many of you come from &#8212; from a war abroad, only to fight a battle of recovery at home.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s equally as difficult; in some cases, more difficult: learning to walk again, to pick up your child again, to manage the effects of traumatic brain injury, to cope with post-traumatic stress that occurs.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not unusual.</p>



<p>I want all our veterans to know we&#8217;re so inspired by you.&nbsp; We’re in awe of the sacrifices you&#8217;ve made on behalf of all of us to defend our flag and to reach this moment.</p>



<p>You know, you&#8217;re the best America has to offer.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the best America has to offer.&nbsp; You embody the soul and the spirit of the nation.&nbsp; As I like to say, you&#8217;re the very spine of America.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the spine of this country.&nbsp; You&#8217;re who makes us what we are.</p>



<p>The riders here today and your families and caregivers, we can never thank you enough.&nbsp; And that sounds like a trite statement, but it’s literal.&nbsp; We can never thank you enough.</p>



<p>But remember: On this ride today, you&#8217;re not alone.&nbsp; You have the support of a grateful nation behind you, today and every day.&nbsp; We&#8217;re here to help &#8212; help each other and help you cross the finish line together.</p>



<p>May God bless you all.&nbsp; May God protect our troops.&nbsp; And to all &#8212; all the caregivers, again: Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>You know, Docs &#8212; I used to say &#8212; read all the time, “Docs let you live.&nbsp; Caregivers and nurses make you want to live.”&nbsp; And it makes a gigantic difference.&nbsp; So, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, may God bless you all.&nbsp; May God protect our troops.</p>



<p>And I got a horn here, somewhere.&nbsp; I’ll wait until you get on your bike.&nbsp; I’m going to stand out here though.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>9:06 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Supreme Court Ruling on&#160;Guns</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-supreme-court-ruling-on-guns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 15:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56129</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I am deeply disappointed by the Supreme Court’s ruling in New York State Rifle &#38; Pistol Association v. Bruen. Since 1911, the State of New York has required individuals who would like to carry a concealed weapon in public to show a need to do so for the purpose of self-defense and to acquire a license. More&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I am deeply disappointed by the Supreme Court’s ruling in <em>New York State Rifle &amp; Pistol Association v. Bruen. </em>Since 1911, the State of New York has required individuals who would like to carry a concealed weapon in public to show a need to do so for the purpose of self-defense and to acquire a license. More than a century later, the United States Supreme Court has chosen to strike down New York’s long-established authority to protect its citizens. This ruling contradicts both common sense and the Constitution, and should deeply trouble us all.<br> <br>In the wake of the horrific attacks in Buffalo and Uvalde, as well as the daily acts of gun violence that do not make national headlines, we must do more as a society — not less — to protect our fellow Americans. I remain committed to doing everything in my power to reduce gun violence and make our communities safer. I have already taken more executive actions to reduce gun violence than any other President during their first year in office, and I will continue to do all that I can to protect Americans from gun violence. <br> <br>I urge states to continue to enact and enforce commonsense laws to make their citizens and communities safer from gun violence. As the late Justice Scalia recognized, the Second Amendment is not absolute. For centuries, states have regulated who may purchase or possess weapons, the types of weapons they may use, and the places they may carry those weapons. And the courts have upheld these regulations.<br> <br>I call on Americans across the country to make their voices heard on gun safety. Lives are on the line.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
