<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:17:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Helps Rural&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-how-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-helps-rural-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27235</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure and Investments Act. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u></strong>, <strong><u>cut taxes</u></strong>, and <strong><u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share.<br><br><strong>LOWER COSTS<br><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, and nearly <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/press-release/poll-nearly-1-in-4-americans-taking-prescription-drugs-say-its-difficult-to-afford-medicines-including-larger-shares-with-low-incomes/">1 in 4 Americans</a> struggle to afford prescription drugs. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs.</em></strong> Rural children are <a href="https://earlylearningnation.com/2018/05/the-challenges-of-rural-pre-k/">less likely to be enrolled in pre-K programs</a> than urban and suburban children, and a third of rural children enter kindergarten without having attended pre-K. President Biden’s plan lowers child care costs and makes universal preschool a reality, providing parents access to high-quality programs in the setting of their choice. The Build Back Better Agenda would also institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, to help improve the health of new mothers and reduce wage loss.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> More than <a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2019/04/health-insurance-rural-america.html">12 percent of people living in completely rural counties</a> lacked health insurance before President Biden took office, coverage under the Affordable Care Act (even with the ACA’s premium subsidies) was too expensive for many families, and almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicaid/issue-brief/the-coverage-gap-uninsured-poor-adults-in-states-that-do-not-expand-medicaid/">2.2 million people </a>were locked out of coverage because their state refused to expand Medicaid. President Biden’s plan lowers health care costs for those buying coverage through the ACA by extending the American Rescue Plan’s cost savings, providing premium relief that is lowering health insurance costs by an average of $50 per person per month for more than 9 million people.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invests billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and minority-serving institutions.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs</em>. </strong><a href="https://www.urban.org/sites/default/files/publication/99045/rental_housing_for_a_21st_century_rural_america.pdf">One in four rural renters</a> pay over half their income in rent. The Plan’s investments help lower housing costs and increase the supply of affordable housing through tax credits and government financing, including constructing and rehabilitating more than one million sustainable rental housing units and more than 500,000 homes working families can afford. It will also make investments to preserve existing public housing as well as remove lead-based paint from housing units.<br><br><strong>CUT TAXES<br><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children. </em></strong><a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/webdocs/publications/90556/eib-200.pdf#:~:text=The%20rural%20poverty%20rate%20was%2016.4%20percent%20in,2017%20but%20remained%20highest%20among%20racial%2Fethnic%20minority%20groups.">16.4 percent of rural people</a> fall below the poverty line, struggling to pay expenses like food, rent, health care and transportation for their families. President Biden’s plan will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, lowering taxes for middle class families by providing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ARP-Fact-Sheet-AAPI-Communities.pdf">the families of more than 66 million</a> kids and an estimated <a href="https://www.cbpp.org/research/federal-tax/expanding-child-tax-credit-and-earned-income-tax-credit-would-benefit-more">10.4 million rural residents </a>across the U.S. a major tax cut – benefitting 45 percent of children from rural areas.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong>CREATE JOBS<br><em>Locally-Led Economic Development. </em></strong>Many rural economies continue to struggle with long-term job loss and economic transition. The President’s plan will create a new Rural Partnership Program to empower rural regions, including Tribal Nations and territories, with resources to attract, access, and leverage federal, private, and philanthropic resources; lead strategic and effective development projects; and create results that matter to communities.<br><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps. As part of the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, the Build Back Better Agenda would also restore American manufacturing with R&amp;D investments—including critical investments to compete on clean energy.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and students of color in particular. <a href="https://www.ncsl.org/research/education/tackling-teacher-and-principal-shortages-in-rural-areas.aspx">Rural teachers</a> have an average starting salary that is more than $7,000 less than their suburban counterparts. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will upgrade school infrastructure, address teacher shortages and improve teacher preparation, expand free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and help families purchase food during the summer.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Read about the President’s full Build Back Better Agenda here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/">https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/</a><br></em><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Will Deliver Historic Investments in American Families and&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-will-deliver-historic-investments-in-american-families-and-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:14:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27231</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Deal. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u>, <u>cut taxes</u>, and <u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share.<br><br><strong><u><strong>LOWER COSTS</strong></u></strong><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs. </em></strong>For 57 percent of children under six, there are no good choices for child care where they live. Only 44 percent of four-year-olds are served by public preschool programs. Nearly four in five private sector workers have no access to paid family leave. The President’s plan would ensure that no middle-class family pays more than 7 percent of their income for high-quality child care up to age 5—and that working families most in need won’t pay anything—saving the average family $14,800 per year. President Biden will also make universal preschool a reality, partnering with states to offer every parent access to high-quality preschool for 3- and 4- year-olds in the setting of their choice. Fully implementing this investment is projected to benefit five million families and save the average American family $13,000 per year. And the Build Back Better Agenda would institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, to help improve the health of new mothers and reduce wage loss.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan will also increase the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invest billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and minority-serving institutions. The plan also invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at institutions that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, and nearly <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/press-release/poll-nearly-1-in-4-americans-taking-prescription-drugs-say-its-difficult-to-afford-medicines-including-larger-shares-with-low-incomes/">1 in 4 Americans</a> struggle to afford prescription drugs. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> The Build Back Better Agenda would reduce health insurance premiums, saving 9 million people an average of $50 per person per month, and add dental, vision, and hearing coverage to Medicare. By closing the Medicaid gap for low-income Americans, the President’s plan would help 4 million uninsured people gain coverage. President Biden’s agenda would also expand home care for older and disabled Americans, while improving the jobs and the pay of the home care workers who care for them.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs. </em></strong>Driven by the largest shortfall of new housing units in 50 years, rents and housing prices continue to increase—with some 10.5 million renters paying more than half their incomes in rent. The Build Back Better Agenda will use tax credits and government financing to bolster affordable and resilient housing, supporting the construction or rehabilitation of more than two million homes.<br><br><strong><u><span style="text-decoration: underline">CUT TAXES</span></u></strong><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children.</em></strong> One third of all adults with children struggle to pay their usual expenses. The American Rescue Plan increased the Child Tax Credit from $2,000 per child to $3,000 per child for children over six and $3,600 for children under six. The Build Back Better Agenda will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, providing 39 million households and nearly 90 percent of American children a major tax cut and cutting child poverty nearly in half.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong><u>CREATE JOBS</u></strong><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and students of color in particular. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will address teacher shortages and improve teacher preparation, including through teacher residencies and Grow Your Own programs that produce better outcomes and develop more teachers of color. It would expand free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and help families purchase food during the summer. And the President’s plan also invests in upgrading school infrastructure, so that we have cutting-edge, energy-efficient, resilient school buildings with technology and labs that will prepare students for the jobs of the future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Helps Black&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-how-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-helps-black-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:14:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27237</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure and Investments Act. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u></strong>, <strong><u>cut taxes</u></strong>, and <strong><u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share.<br><br><strong>LOWER COSTS</strong><br><strong><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, contributing to the fact that <a href="https://www.nashp.org/states-curb-racial-inequities-in-rx-drug-affordability-with-targeted-legislation/">Black individuals use 10 to 40 percent fewer medications</a> than their White counterparts for the same illnesses. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs.</em></strong> Only<a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/how-many-children-attend-preschool-us/"> 62.6 percent of all three- and four-year-old Black</a> children are enrolled in preschool or kindergarten programs. President Biden’s plan lowers child care costs and makes universal preschool a reality for all three and four year-olds, providing parents access to high-quality programs in the setting of their choice. The Build Back Better Agenda would also institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, which will help improve Black maternal health outcomes and reduce wage losses that cause persistent earning and wealth gaps for Black women.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> Almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/uninsured/issue-brief/key-facts-about-the-uninsured-population/">3.9 million Black people</a> were uninsured in 2019 before President Biden took office, coverage under the Affordable Care Act (even with the ACA’s premium subsidies) was too expensive for many families, and almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/taking-a-closer-look-at-characteristics-of-people-in-the-coverage-gap/">1.3 million people of color</a> were locked out of coverage because their state refused to expand Medicaid. President Biden’s plan lowers health care costs for those buying coverage through the ACA by extending the American Rescue Plan’s cost savings, which helps <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/private/pdf/265581/aspe-uninsured-trends-aapi-ib.pdf">360,000 Black people </a>save an average of $50 per person per month, and allowing 328,000 uninsured Black people to gain coverage. The plan also adds  dental, vision, and hearing coverage for the more than <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/state-indicator/medicare-beneficiaries-by-raceethnicity/?dataView=1&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">5.8 million Black people on Medicare</a> and closes the Medicaid gap for low-income Americans.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invests billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at Historically Black Colleges and Universities and minority-serving institutions. The plan also invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at institutions that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs</em>.</strong><a href="https://www.enterprisecommunity.org/blog/12/20/black-renters-entered-pandemic-facing-significant-housing-challenges#:~:text=Our%20analysis%20of%20the%202019,housing%20(see%20figure%201).&amp;text=Indeed%2C%20nearly%20a%20quarter%20of,and%20had%20extremely%20low%20incomes.">30 percent of Black renters</a> pay over half their income in rent. The Plan’s investments help lower housing costs and increase the supply of affordable housing through tax credits and government financing, including constructing and rehabilitating more than one million sustainable rental housing units and more than 500,000 homes working families can afford. It will also make investments to preserve existing public housing as well as remove lead-based paint from housing units.<br><br><strong>CUT TAXES</strong><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children.</em></strong><a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf"> 22.1 percent of Black people </a>fall below the poverty line, struggling to pay expenses like food, rent, health care and transportation for their families. President Biden’s plan will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, lowering taxes for middle class families by providing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ARP-Fact-Sheet-AAPI-Communities.pdf">the families of more than 66 million</a> kids and nearly <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf">3 million Black people</a> in the U.S. a major tax cut –  cutting the Black poverty rate by 34.3 percent.  This is especially critical for the <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/women/news/2021/03/29/497658/breadwinning-mothers-critical-familys-economic-security/">85% of Black women</a> who are either sole or co-breadwinners for their families.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong>CREATE JOBS</strong><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps. As part of the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, the Build Back Better Agenda would also restore American manufacturing with R&amp;D investments—including critical investments to compete on clean energy.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and disproportionately impacting students. Only about <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/clr">7 percent of our nation’s public school teachers are Black</a>, even though Black students make up <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/cge">15 percent of public school students</a>. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-how-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-educational-equity/">advance educational equity</a> by upgrading school infrastructure, addressing teacher shortages and improving teacher preparation, increasing the diversity of the teacher pipeline, and expanding free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and helping families purchase food during the summer.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br><em>Read about the President’s full Build Back Better Agenda here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/<br></a></em><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Helps Latino&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-how-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-helps-latino-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:13:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure and Investments Act. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u></strong>, <strong><u>cut taxes</u></strong>, and <strong><u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share. President Biden and Vice President Harris have also repeatedly expressed their strong support for including immigration reform in upcoming reconciliation legislation to enable Dreamers, TPS recipients, farmworkers and essential workers to gain long-awaited pathways to citizenship. <br><br><strong>LOWER COSTS</strong><br><strong><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, contributing to the fact that <a href="https://www.nashp.org/states-curb-racial-inequities-in-rx-drug-affordability-with-targeted-legislation/">Latino individuals use 10 to 40 percent fewer medications</a> than their White counterparts for the same illnesses. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs.</em></strong> Only <a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/how-many-children-attend-preschool-us/">59.4 percent of all three- and four-year-old Hispanic children</a> are enrolled in preschool or kindergarten programs. President Biden’s plan lowers child care costs and makes universal preschool a reality, providing parents access to high-quality programs in the setting of their choice. The Build Back Better Agenda would also institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, to help improve the health of new mothers and reduce wage loss.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> Almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/uninsured/issue-brief/key-facts-about-the-uninsured-population/">10.9 million Hispanic people</a> were uninsured in 2019 before President Biden took office, coverage under the Affordable Care Act (even with the ACA’s premium subsidies) was too expensive for many families, and almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/taking-a-closer-look-at-characteristics-of-people-in-the-coverage-gap/">1.3 million people of color</a> were locked out of coverage because their state refused to expand Medicaid. President Biden’s plan lowers health care costs for those buying coverage through the ACA by extending the American Rescue Plan’s cost savings, which helps <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/private/pdf/265581/aspe-uninsured-trends-aapi-ib.pdf">730,000 Latino people </a>save an average of $50 per person per month, and allowing 580,000 uninsured Latinos to gain coverage. The plan also adds  dental, vision, and hearing coverage for the more than <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/state-indicator/medicare-beneficiaries-by-raceethnicity/?dataView=1&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">5 million Hispanic people on Medicare</a> and closes the Medicaid gap for low-income Americans.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invests billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at minority-serving institutions. The plan also invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at institutions that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs</em>.</strong> More than <a href="https://curs.unc.edu/2019/11/26/calling-it-home-latino-rental-housing-affordability/">55% of Latino renters</a> pay over 30% of their income in rent. The Plan’s investments help lower housing costs and increase the supply of affordable housing through tax credits and government financing, including constructing and rehabilitating more than one million sustainable rental housing units and more than 500,000 homes working families can afford. It will also make investments to preserve existing public housing as well as remove lead-based paint from housing units.<br><br><strong>CUT TAXES</strong><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children.</em></strong><a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf"> 21.2 percent of Hispanic people </a>fall below the poverty line, struggling to pay expenses like food, rent, health care and transportation for their families. President Biden’s plan will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, lowering taxes for middle class families by providing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ARP-Fact-Sheet-AAPI-Communities.pdf">the families of more than 66 million</a> kids and nearly <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf">4.5 million Hispanic people</a> in the U.S. a major tax cut –  cutting the Hispanic poverty rate by 39 percent. This is especially critical for the <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/women/news/2021/03/29/497658/breadwinning-mothers-critical-familys-economic-security/">61% of Hispanic</a> women who are either sole or co-breadwinners for their families.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong>CREATE JOBS</strong><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps. As part of the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, the Build Back Better Agenda would also restore American manufacturing with R&amp;D investments—including critical investments to compete on clean energy.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and students of color in particular. Only <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/clr">9 percent of our nation’s public school teachers are Hispanic</a>, even though Hispanic students make up <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator/cge">27 percent of all public elementary and secondary students</a>. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-how-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-educational-equity/">advance educational equity</a> by upgrading school infrastructure, addressing teacher shortages and improving teacher preparation, increasing the diversity of the teacher pipeline, and expanding free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and helping families purchase food during the summer.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Read about the President’s full Build Back Better Agenda here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/">https://www.whitehouse.gov/build-back-better/</a><br></em><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: How President&#160;Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda Helps Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander&#160;Communities</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-how-president-bidens-build-back-better-agenda-helps-asian-american-native-hawaiian-and-pacific-islander-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 15:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27223</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>One year ago, with the country at a crossroads, President Biden unveiled his Build Back Better Agenda. Facing a raging pandemic, unprecedented economic downturn, profound climate crisis, and persistent racial injustices, President Biden outlined an ambitious agenda that would position America not just to return to where we were, but to build back better towards a more sustainable, resilient, equitable, and prosperous future.<br><br>The Build Back Better Agenda includes President Biden’s American Families Plan and key elements of the American Jobs Plan that were not included in the Bipartisan Infrastructure and Investments Act. In Washington, this proposal is known as “reconciliation.” But the bottom line is a plan that will <strong><u>create jobs</u></strong>, <strong><u>cut taxes</u></strong>, and <strong><u>lower costs for working families</u></strong>—all paid for by making the tax code fairer and making the wealthiest and large corporations pay their fair share. President Biden and Vice President Harris have also repeatedly expressed their strong support for including immigration reform in upcoming reconciliation legislation to enable Dreamers, TPS recipients, farmworkers and essential workers to gain long-awaited pathways to citizenship.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>LOWER COSTS</strong><br><strong><em>Lower Prescription Drug Costs.</em></strong> Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, and nearly <a href="https://www.kff.org/health-costs/press-release/poll-nearly-1-in-4-americans-taking-prescription-drugs-say-its-difficult-to-afford-medicines-including-larger-shares-with-low-incomes/">1 in 4 Americans</a> struggle to afford prescription drugs. President Biden’s plan will lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Child Care Costs.</em></strong> Only <a href="https://usafacts.org/articles/how-many-children-attend-preschool-us/">57.9 percent of all three- and four-year-old Asian American</a> children are enrolled in preschool or kindergarten programs and half of <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/women/reports/2021/03/04/496703/economic-status-asian-american-pacific-islander-women/">Asian American women</a> live in areas where the supply of child care is too low to meet demand. President Biden’s plan lowers child care costs and makes universal preschool a reality, providing parents access to high-quality programs in the setting of their choice. The Build Back Better Agenda would also institute 12 weeks of paid family and medical leave, to help improve the health of new mothers and reduce wage loss.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Health Care Costs.</em></strong> More than <a href="https://www.kff.org/uninsured/issue-brief/key-facts-about-the-uninsured-population/">1.5 million AA and NHPIs</a> were uninsured in 2019 before President Biden took office, coverage under the Affordable Care Act (even with the ACA’s premium subsidies) was too expensive for many families, and almost <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/taking-a-closer-look-at-characteristics-of-people-in-the-coverage-gap/">1.3 million people of color</a> were locked out of coverage because their state refused to expand Medicaid. President Biden’s plan lowers health care costs for those buying coverage through the ACA by extending the American Rescue Plan’s cost savings, which helps <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/private/pdf/265581/aspe-uninsured-trends-aapi-ib.pdf">197,000 uninsured AAPI people</a> save an average of $50 per person per month, and allowing more than 150,000 uninsured AAPI people to gain coverage. The plan also adds dental, vision, and hearing coverage for the more than <a href="https://www.kff.org/medicare/state-indicator/medicare-beneficiaries-by-raceethnicity/?dataView=1&amp;currentTimeframe=0&amp;sortModel=%7B%22colId%22:%22Location%22,%22sort%22:%22asc%22%7D">2.3 million AAPIs on Medicare</a> and closes the Medicaid gap for low-income Americans.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Higher Education Costs. </em></strong>Education beyond high school is increasingly important to succeed in the 21<sup>st</sup> century economy, even as it has become unaffordable for too many families. The Build Back Better Agenda would provide two years of free community college—boosting the earnings of low-wage high school graduates by nearly $6,000 per year. President Biden’s plan also increases the maximum Pell Grant award by almost $1,500, and invests billions in subsidized tuition for low- and middle-income students at minority-serving institutions. The plan also invests in evidence-based strategies to strengthen completion and retention rates at institutions that serve high numbers of low-income students, particularly community colleges.<br><br><strong><em>Lower Housing Costs</em></strong><strong>.</strong><a href="https://nlihc.org/resource/new-research-highlights-housing-experiences-asian-americans-and-pacific-islanders#:~:text=AAPI%20renters%20are%20severely%20cost,renters%20are%20severely%20cost%2Dburdened.&amp;text=Bangladeshi%2C%20Vietnamese%2C%20and%20Pakistani%20renters,%2C%20and%2034%25%2C%20respectively">26 percent of Asian American renters and 27 percent of Native Hawaiians and Pacific Islander renters</a> pay over half their income in rent. The Plan’s investments help lower housing costs and increases the supply of affordable housing through tax credits and government financing, including constructing and rehabilitating more than one million sustainable rental housing units and more than 500,000 homes working families can afford. It will also make investments to preserve existing public housing as well as remove lead-based paint from housing units.<br><br><strong>CUT TAXES</strong><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Families with Children. </em></strong><a href="https://www.kff.org/infographic/health-and-health-care-for-asian-americans-native-hawaiians-and-other-pacific-islanders-nhopis-in-the-united-states/">9 percent of Asian American families and 16 percent of Native Hawaiian and other Pacific Islander families</a> fall below the poverty line, struggling to pay expenses like food, rent, health care and transportation for their families. President Biden’s plan will extend the Child Tax Credit expansion in the American Rescue Plan, lowering taxes for middle class families by providing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/ARP-Fact-Sheet-AAPI-Communities.pdf">the families of more than 66 million</a> kids and nearly <a href="https://static1.squarespace.com/static/5743308460b5e922a25a6dc7/t/601acf15866c634924d12963/1612369686861/Poverty-Reduction-Analysis-Biden-Economic-Relief-CPSP-2021.pdf">600,000 AAPI people</a> in the U.S. a major tax cut –&nbsp; cutting the AAPI poverty rate by 21.7 percent.<br><br><strong><em>Tax Cuts for Workers Without Children.</em></strong> The President’s agenda permanently extends the American Rescue Plan’s increase to the Earned-Income Tax Credit from $543 to $1,502. This will benefit roughly 17 million low-wage workers, including cashiers, cooks, delivery drivers, food preparation workers, and child care providers.<br><br><strong>CREATE JOBS</strong><br><strong><em>Workforce Training.</em></strong> The U.S. has chronically underinvested in workforce development, and millions of jobs have been going unfilled in growing sectors such as construction and health care. Through high-quality career and technical education pathways and Registered Apprenticeships, President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will invest in training programs that will prepare millions of American workers for high-quality jobs in growing sectors.<br><br><strong><em>Clean Energy Jobs. </em></strong>When President Biden thinks about climate change, he thinks jobs. To position the U.S. to tackle the climate crisis and advance environmental justice, the President’s plan would create good-paying, union jobs, establish an energy efficiency and clean energy standard, expand and extend clean energy and electric vehicle tax credits, and enlist a new Civilian Climate Corps. As part of the U.S. Innovation and Competition Act, the Build Back Better Agenda would also restore American manufacturing with R&amp;D investments—including critical investments to compete on clean energy.<br><br><strong><em>Investments in Teachers and Schools. </em></strong>Even before the pandemic, our schools faced an estimated teacher shortage of 100,000, undermining the education of our children and students of color in particular. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda will upgrade school infrastructure, address teacher shortages and improve teacher preparation, expand free school meals to an additional 9.3 million children during the school year and help families purchase food during the summer.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Employer Support Of The Guard And Reserve Week,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/08/13/a-proclamation-on-national-employer-support-of-the-guard-and-reserve-week-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 13:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27215</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since our founding, courageous men and women&#160;have vowed to serve and defend our country, protect our&#160;citizens, and uphold the principles of our Constitution.&#160; The&#160;citizen Soldiers and Airmen of the National Guard, and the&#160;Soldiers, Sailors, Airmen, Marines, and Coast Guardsmen of&#160;the Reserve, proudly carry on this tradition today.&#160; During National Employer Support of the Guard and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since our founding, courageous men and women&nbsp;have vowed to serve and defend our country, protect our&nbsp;citizens, and uphold the principles of our Constitution.&nbsp; The&nbsp;citizen Soldiers and Airmen of the National Guard, and the&nbsp;Soldiers, Sailors, Airmen, Marines, and Coast Guardsmen of&nbsp;the Reserve, proudly carry on this tradition today.&nbsp; During National Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve Week, we&nbsp;thank and celebrate the civilian employers whose support of&nbsp;our&nbsp;National Guard and Reserve members helps to sustain our&nbsp;all‑volunteer force and our national spirit of service.</p>



<p>National Guard and Reserve members are essential to the safety and security of our Nation, ready to serve at home or abroad at any moment&#8217;s notice.&nbsp; From working on the frontlines of the COVID-19 pandemic, to responding to storm damage and raging wildfires, to&nbsp;deploying overseas, supporting peacekeeping missions abroad, and conducting multilateral exercises with allies and partner nations, National Guard and Reserve members put their lives on hold &#8212; away from both their families and their civilian workplaces &#8212; to stand as a shield or a support whenever our country is in need.&nbsp; When they complete their mission, National Guard and Reserve members return to their civilian careers and fulfill their obligation of monthly weekend drills and annual trainings &#8212; always ensuring they are ready to answer the next call to serve.</p>



<p>We owe a profound gratitude to our National Guard and Reserve members, as well as their civilian employers.&nbsp; In&nbsp;supporting their talented employees&#8217; service to our Nation, employers of National Guard and Reserve members directly contribute to our military readiness and our national security.&nbsp; As our Guard and Reserve members navigate the challenges that accompany their service, many civilian employers go&nbsp;above and beyond to support our service members and their families. &nbsp;National Guard and Reserve members should not have to&nbsp;worry about their civilian employment while they are serving on a mission, and many employers are stepping up with generous pay and leave policies, extension of benefits like health care for family members, and flexibility and support for Guard and Reserve spouses to help fulfill our sacred obligation as a&nbsp;Nation to always take care of those who serve in uniform.</p>



<p>My Administration understands the national security imperative behind improving the well-being of our service members and their families as they balance the pressures of their civilian careers with the demands of military service. &nbsp;Through the First Lady&#8217;s work with Joining Forces, we are committed to supporting military and veteran families, caregivers, and survivors through economic and entrepreneurship opportunities, support for military child education, and health and well-being resources. &nbsp;Ensuring continuing economic opportunities for military and veteran families through meaningful employment is essential, and we are&nbsp;grateful for all&nbsp;of the employers who understand the value in&nbsp;hiring and retaining National Guard and Reserve members and their spouses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden family is a National Guard family, and we are forever grateful and in awe of those who, like our son Beau, understand that duty and service to others is what makes us who&nbsp;we are as Americans. &nbsp;We understand some of the unique challenges that National Guard and Reserve members and their families face &#8212; challenges that are made smaller because of&nbsp;the&nbsp;incredible, patriotic support of their employers. &nbsp;I&nbsp;encourage all Americans to join me in recognizing and thanking employers of our National Guard and Reserve members for their vast contributions to our economy, our communities, and the success of our Nation and our Armed Forces.&nbsp; I also encourage National Guard and Reserve members to recognize their employers who have gone above and beyond in supporting them with the Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve (ESGR), the Department of Defense program that promotes cooperation and understanding between civilian employers and their National Guard and Reserve employees.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim August 15 through August 21, 2021, as National Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve Week.&nbsp; I&nbsp;call&nbsp;upon the people of the United States, State and local officials, private organizations, and all military commanders to&nbsp;honor employers of National Guard and Reserve members with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this thirteenth day of August, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Appoints Members to U.S. AbilityOne&#160;Commission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/president-biden-appoints-members-to-u-s-abilityone-commission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced that he has appointed the following individuals to the U.S. AbilityOne Commission, which administers the AbilityOne Program, one of the nation’s largest sources of employment for people who are blind or have significant disabilities: Bryan Bashin, Appointee for Commissioner Christina Brandt, Appointee for Commissioner Gabriel M. Cazares, Appointee for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced that he has appointed the following individuals to the U.S. AbilityOne Commission, which administers the AbilityOne Program, one of the nation’s largest sources of employment for people who are blind or have significant disabilities:</p>



<ul><li>Bryan Bashin, Appointee for Commissioner</li><li>Christina Brandt, Appointee for Commissioner</li><li>Gabriel M. Cazares, Appointee for Commissioner</li><li>Chai Rachel Feldblum, Appointee for Commissioner</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><strong>Bryan Bashin, Commissioner</strong><br>Bryan Bashin is CEO of the Lighthouse for the Blind and Visually-Impaired in San Francisco, a 119-year-old nonprofit devoted to the comprehensive training and employment of blind people.  For 30 years his organization has employed blind workers through the National Industries for the Blind, one of the central non-profits in the AbilityOne program. Over the last 11 years, Bashin has overseen significant expansions of direct blind employment in the AbilityOne space, but most importantly in competitive, integrated workplaces. Bashin previously worked as an Assistant Regional Commissioner for the Department of Education’s Rehabilitation Services Administration (RSA) where he supervised $400 million in federal disability spending in Arizona, Nevada, California, Hawaii, and Pacific territories. From 1998 until 2004, Bashin was Executive Director of the Sacramento Society for the Blind, where he led a strong expansion of blindness services, including competitive employment programs. Bashin has also been an expert witness in cases involving employment of people with disabilities. A former science journalist, Bashin is well acquainted with industrial and technical processes and skill needs of employers. Bashin is currently a Board member of VisionServe Alliance, a membership association of more than 100 U.S. blindness agencies. <br><br><strong>Christina Brandt, Commissioner</strong><br>Christina Brandt is the CEO of an innovative nonprofit, an AbilityOne producer with over four decades of quality service to the government customer. She transformed AtWork! from a sheltered workshop paying subminimum wages to a nationally recognized best-practice provider of customized and integrated community employment for people with intellectual and developmental disabilities. As a subject matter expert, Christina has delivered training and technical assistance in multiple states, including significant work in Oregon implementing the settlement of <em>Lane vs. Brown</em>. Throughout her 46-year career she has advanced equity and inclusion for people with disabilities and was instrumental in securing Washington State’s Employment First legislation.<br><br><strong>Gabe Cazares, Commissioner</strong><br>Gabe Cazares currently serves as the Director of Mayor Sylvester Turner’s Office for People with Disabilities in the City of Houston, Texas. In this capacity, Gabe oversees the accessible and timely delivery of city services, programs, and activities for over 215,000 Houstonians with disabilities. Prior to his appointment, he served as the Manager of Government Affairs at the National Federation of the Blind in Baltimore, Maryland. There he managed the organization&#8217;s education, technology, immigrants&#8217; rights, LGBTQ, and blind entrepreneur small business policy portfolio. Gabe holds a Bachelor of Arts in Political Science with a Spanish minor from Texas State University. He and his partner, Derin Dacey, live in Houston with their 4-year-old rescue dog, Sam.<br><br><strong>Chai Feldblum, Commissioner</strong><br>Chai Feldblum is a national expert in disability law and employment. She led the drafting and negotiating of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the ADA Amendments Act of 2008. As a law professor at Georgetown University Law Center, she and her students represented non-profit organizations, including disability rights organizations, in advocating for legislation and administrative regulations to support social justice goals. Chai served as a Commissioner of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission during the Obama-Biden Administration, where she spearheaded the issuance of regulations under Section 501 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973. Those regulations established a goal of 12% representation in the federal workforce of people with all disabilities and a 2% representation of people with significant disabilities. The latter group includes people with the type of disabilities hired under the AbilityOne program. Chai is a lesbian and has a psychiatric disability of anxiety disorder.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden Administration Takes Steps to Address COVID-&#8288;19 in Rural America and Build Rural Health Back&#160;Better</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/13/fact-sheet-biden-administration-takes-steps-to-address-covid-19-in-rural-america-and-build-rural-health-back-better/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Biden Administration is taking action to improve the health of rural communities by making millions of dollars in American Rescue Plan funding available to meet immediate COVID-19 needs. This funding, which will also help rural hospitals stay open in the long run and improve the care provided to rural communities, builds on efforts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Biden Administration is taking action to improve the health of rural communities by making millions of dollars in American Rescue Plan funding available to meet immediate COVID-19 needs. This funding, which will also help rural hospitals stay open in the long run and improve the care provided to rural communities, builds on efforts the Administration has already taken to help rural communities tackle the COVID-19 crisis and improve access to health care. And these actions are only the beginning. President Biden’s Build Back Better agenda – also known as the reconciliation package – will make crucial investments in rural Americans’ health by lowering prescription drug and other health care costs, expanding access to care, and improving maternal health, and the bipartisan infrastructure legislation will improve the quality of drinking water in rural communities.</p>



<p><strong><u>NEW ACTIONS</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Helping health care providers in rural areas cover costs associated with COVID-19 and keep their doors open.</strong> The U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) is providing $8.5 billion in American Rescue Plan funding in the coming weeks to help compensate health care providers who serve rural Medicare, Medicaid, and Children’s Health Insurance Plan (CHIP) patients for lost revenue and increased expenses associated with COVID-19<strong>. </strong>These funds will help ensure that providers can effectively respond to the COVID-19 pandemic and will place them on stable financial footing to continue serving their communities into the future.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding rural hospitals and providers’ access to COVID-19 vaccines, testing, and supplies, while helping rural health care providers stay financially solvent in the long-term.</strong> The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) is using $500 million in American Rescue Plan funding to create the Emergency Rural Health Care Grant Program. The program will provide at least $350 million to help rural hospitals and local communities increase access to COVID-19 vaccines and testing, medical supplies, telehealth, and food assistance, and support construction or renovation of rural health care facilities. Applicants can also apply for recovery funds that compensate for lost revenue or staffing expenses due to COVID-19. In addition, the program will provide up to $125 million in grants to plan and implement models that help improve the long-term viability of rural health care providers, including health care networks that allow rural providers to collectively address community challenges and develop innovative solutions.</p>



<p><strong>Training new rural health care providers, including community health workers and respiratory therapists, and expanding telehealth. </strong>HHS will make $52 million from the American Rescue Plan available to train a range of health care workers to fill in-demand professions affected by the pandemic. Specifically, HHS is creating rural health networks by pairing together minority-serving institutions, community colleges, technical colleges, rural hospitals, Rural Health Clinics, community health centers, nursing homes and substance abuse providers. Networks will focus on cross-training and sustaining community health workers in rural communities; expanding the workforce to support electronic health records as well as virtual and telehealth systems; expanding the capacity of emergency medical services reduced by pandemic-driven service reductions by developing Community Paramedicine programs; and training case management staff and respiratory therapists, who will play a critical role in helping rural clinical sites better serve patients affected by long-term COVID health challenges.The application will be available in the coming weeks.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding access to pulmonary rehabilitation services.</strong> HHS is announcing that, in FY 2022, it will support a demonstration project to enhance access to pulmonary rehabilitation services in Critical Access Hospitals that serve rural communities with high rates of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). COPD is one of the leading causes of death in the U.S., and adults in rural areas are almost twice as likely to have it compared to those in urban areas.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding Veterans Affairs training programs for rural providers. </strong>The Rural Interprofessional Faculty Development Initiative (RIFDI), developed by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), is an innovative two-year training program designed to provide teaching and training skills for clinicians in rural settings, preparing rural clinicians to take on faculty roles, mentor medical professionals to serve in rural America, and grow the healthcare workforce in rural communities. By the end of this calendar year, VA will launch a new joint initiative with HHS, adding non-VA community clinicians to the program. This joint initiative will benefit up to 40 rural communities each year and enable rural clinicians to better train the next generation of clinicians who will serve rural America.</p>



<p><strong>Increasing access to telehealth.</strong> The National Institutes of Health (NIH) is announcing that it will hold a virtual <a href="https://prevention.nih.gov/research-priorities/research-needs-and-gaps/pathways-prevention/improving-rural-health-through-telehealth-guided-provider-provider-communication">public workshop</a> to identify ways to improve rural health through telehealth-guided provider-to-provider communication as part of its ongoing Pathways to Prevention series October 12-14th. With the rapid expansion of telehealth during the pandemic, this workshop will bring together key NIH partners, other federal agencies, researchers and community stakeholders to assess the existing evidence, identify gaps and develop plans to move telehealth forward. In addition, the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services recently proposed a new rule to expand access to telehealth mental health services for rural and vulnerable populations by allowing Medicare to pay for mental health visits furnished via telehealth when they are provided by Rural Health Clinics (RHCs) and Federally Qualified Health Centers (FQHCs). This proposal would expand access to Medicare beneficiaries, especially those living in rural and other underserved areas.</p>



<p><strong><u>BUILDING RURAL HEALTH BACK BETTER</u></strong></p>



<p>The President’s Build Back Better agenda – also referred to as the reconciliation package –would continue to build on these successes and deliver lower cost, higher quality health care to rural Americans.</p>



<p><strong>Lower Health Care Costs. </strong>More than <a href="https://www.census.gov/library/stories/2019/04/health-insurance-rural-america.html">12% of people living in completely rural counties</a> lacked health insurance before President Biden took office; coverage under the Affordable Care Act (even with its premium subsidies) was too expensive for many families; and <a href="/aspe.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/private/pdf/265621/aspe-data-point-medicaid-expansion-new-eligible.pdf%3c">nearly 2.3 million people</a> were not afforded coverage because their state refused to expand Medicaid. The Build Back Better agenda:</p>



<ul><li>Extends the higher premium subsidies that were a part of the American Rescue plan to keep health insurance affordable for millions of Americans, including those living in rural communities.</li><li>Adds comprehensive dental, vision, and hearing coverage for Medicare beneficiaries, expanding coverage for millions of rural Americans.</li><li>Expands Medicaid coverage in all states to cover to more rural Americans. In 2019, the rural uninsured rate was <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/reports/access-care-rural-america">nearly twice as high</a> in non-expansion states as expansion states.</li><li>Invests $3 billion in improving maternal health and tackling health disparities.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Lower Prescription Drug Costs. </strong>Americans pay 2-3 times more for their prescription drugs than people in other wealthy countries, and nearly 1 in 4 Americans struggle to afford prescription drugs. President Biden’s plan would lower prescription drug costs for Americans by letting Medicare negotiate drug prices, so consumers, including those in rural communities, are no longer at the whim of pharmaceutical companies.</p>



<p><strong>Keep More Rural Hospitals Open. </strong>The President’s Build Back Better proposal would help keep rural hospitals open by expanding Medicaid. Three quarters of rural hospitals that are vulnerable to closure are in states that have yet to expand Medicaid, and Medicaid expansion reduces the risk of rural hospital closure by 62%.</p>



<p><strong>Improve the Safety of Rural Drinking Water. </strong>The bipartisan infrastructure legislation that recently passed the Senate deals with aging water systems that threaten public health in thousands of communities nationwide. An estimated six to ten million homes still receive drinking water through lead pipes and service lines. The legislation would upgrade and modernize America’s drinking water, wastewater, and stormwater systems, tackle new contaminants, and support clean water infrastructure across rural America with $56 billion in grants and low-cost flexible loans to states, Tribes, territories, and disadvantaged communities across the country.</p>



<p><strong><u>PREVIOUS BIDEN ADMINISTRATION ACTIONS TO SUPPORT RURAL AMERICANS’ HEALTH</u></strong></p>



<p><strong>Helped Rural Communities Fight COVID-19. </strong>Rural communities have been disproportionately impacted by COVID-19 and the Administration has taken targeted steps to bolster the COVID-19 response in those areas.<strong> </strong>For example, the Administration has allocated over $4 billion to address COVID-19 challenges in rural communities. This funding—which includes funds from the American Rescue Plan—supports increased testing and mitigation efforts in small rural hospitals, Medicare-certified Rural Health Clinics, and efforts to build vaccine confidence through targeted educational immunization campaigns and vaccine outreach to rural communities. <strong></strong></p>



<p><strong>Expanded Access to Quality Health Care in Rural Communities. </strong>The President’s agenda to improve health in rural America aims to expand access to health coverage, so that families can get the care they need at an affordable price.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Lowered health insurance costs for rural Americans.</strong> In February, the Administration opened a Special Enrollment Period to provide all Americans the opportunity to obtain quality, affordable health care. More than 300,000 rural Americans have enrolled in coverage as a result of the Special Enrollment Period. And, thanks to the American Rescue Plan, millions of Americans, including Americans in rural communities, have found lower health insurance premiums on plans purchased through HealthCare.gov. Uninsured rural Americans can still find a zero- or low-premium plan – but the last day to sign up at HealthCare.gov is August 15.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Through the <a href="https://innovation.cms.gov/innovation-models/chart-model">Community Health Access and Rural Transformation (CHART) Model</a>, HHS is providing new ways for rural communities to transform their health care delivery systems. Participating rural providers can take advantage of regulatory flexibilities to structure payments in a way that rewards the quality of care and health outcomes instead of the volume of services provided.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Initiated Actions to Keep More Rural Hospitals Open.</strong> <a href="https://www.shepscenter.unc.edu/programs-projects/rural-health/rural-hospital-closures/">138 rural hospitals have shuttered</a> since 2010, with 19 hospitals closing in 2020 alone.&nbsp;For many rural communities, keeping rural hospitals open means the difference between life or death for community members. It also means jobs and economic opportunity. In addition to the American Rescue Plan funds announced today, the Administration has already taken several steps to help keep rural providers open.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Took initial action to establish a new provider type, Rural Emergency Hospitals, to fill a gap in rural care.</strong> In response to the growing concern that closures of rural hospitals and Critical Access Hospitals are leading to a lack of services for people living in rural areas and the loss of access to emergency care, HHS has taken the initial step to determine how to <a href="https://www.cms.gov/newsroom/press-releases/cms-proposes-rule-increase-price-transparency-access-care-safety-health-equity">design a new provider type</a>, Rural Emergency Hospitals (REHs). In the future, REHs will be required to furnish emergency department services and observation care and may provide other outpatient medical and health services.</li><li><strong>Promoted hospital competition and price transparency.</strong> Hospital consolidation has left many areas, <a href="https://www.gao.gov/products/gao-21-93">especially in rural communities</a>, without good options for convenient and affordable health care service. In his <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/">executive order promoting competition</a>, the President underscored that hospital mergers that reduce health care access can be harmful to patients and encouraged the Justice Department and Federal Trade Commission to review and revise their merger guidelines to ensure patients are not harmed by such mergers. He also directed HHS to support existing hospital price transparency rules and to finish implementing bipartisan federal legislation to address surprise hospital billing.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Expanded the Pipeline of Rural Health Care Workers.</strong> Increasing the number of rural individuals going to medical school or other health care training programs and returning to rural communities to provide care is critical to bolstering access to health care in rural communities.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Proposed a budget that</strong><strong> strengthens the rural health care provider pipeline. </strong>The President’s FY22 budget request includes a number of investments to build the pipeline of rural health care providers, including:<ul><li>$13 million to expand the Rural Residency Planning and Development Program to develop new residency programs in rural communities to train physicians in rural practice settings, an increase of $2 million above FY2021 enacted levels.</li></ul><ul><li>Continued support for loan repayment and scholarships for clinicians practicing in high-need rural and underserved areas through roughly $477 million in total program funding for the National Health Service Corps.</li></ul><ul><li>$20 million above FY 2021 enacted budget to continue a nationwide expansion of the Community Health Aide Program to the lower 48 states to enhance care for tribal populations. This evidence-based program, which has measurably improved access to health care in rural Alaska, has the potential to expand access to high quality care in remote and rural areas in Indian Country.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong>Provided Funding to Treat Substance Use Disorders and Address the Opioid Epidemic in Rural Communities<a>. </a></strong>The opioid epidemic has shattered families and ravaged communities. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to tackling this epidemic and ensuring support for the full continuum of prevention, harm reduction, treatment and recovery support services. The Administration has: <strong></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Improved prevention and treatment of substance use disorder. </strong>HHS announced $85.5 million in funding to rural communities to address the opioid epidemic and substance use issues in rural America. This includes 78 implementation grants to focus on prevention and treatment and 15 awards that will focus on communities addressing misuse of psycho-stimulants, such as methamphetamine.</li><li><strong>Lifted a moratorium on opioid treatment programs with a mobile component.</strong> The Drug Enforcement Administration recently lifted a decade-long moratorium on opioid treatment programs that want to include a mobile component. This <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ondcp/briefing-room/2021/06/29/biden-harris-administration-expands-treatment-to-underserved-communities-with-mobile-methadone-van-rule-2021/">rule change</a> will help remove a critical barrier to treatment for rural and other underserved communities, including incarcerated individuals.</li><li><strong>Put forward a budget to address the opioid epidemic.</strong> The President’s FY22 budget request includes $165 million to address the opioid epidemic in hard-hit rural communities, an increase of $55 million.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Prioritized Maternal Health in Rural America. </strong>Maternal mortality is rising in the U.S. Rural women experience poorer maternal health outcomes compared to their non-rural counterparts, including&nbsp;<a href="https://www.hrsa.gov/sites/default/files/hrsa/advisory-committees/rural/publications/2020-maternal-obstetric-care-challenges.pdf">higher pregnancy-related mortality</a>. Women in rural communities also experience racial, ethnic, and socioeconomic disparities in maternal health outcomes. These disparities are amplified for women living in tribal communities. The Administration has:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Funded improvements in rural maternal care</strong><strong>.</strong> HHS awarded an additional $3 million in funds for the Rural Maternity and Obstetrics Management Strategies (RMOMS) program. This program, which the Administration proposes to expand in its FY22 budget proposal, develops models and implements strategies that improve access to and continuity of maternal obstetrics care in rural communities. Applicants are required to focus on populations that have historically suffered from poorer health outcomes, health disparities, and other inequities.</li><li><strong>Put forward a budget to keep improving maternal health. </strong>The President’s discretionary budget request includes more than $200 million to reduce maternal mortality and morbidity rates nationwide, bolster Maternal Mortality Review Committees, and expand the RMOMS program, among other actions. <strong></strong></li></ul>



<p><strong>Prioritized Access to Clean Drinking Water. </strong>Across the country, water pipes and treatment plants are aging and polluted drinking water is endangering public health.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Put forward a budget prioritizing clean drinking water in low-income communities.</strong> The President’s FY22 budget proposal requests $22 million for the Rural Community Development Program, which provides grants to assist low-income communities in developing affordable and safe water and wastewater treatment facilities.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United&#160;States to Host Ninth Summit of the Americas in&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/12/united-states-to-host-ninth-summit-of-the-americas-in-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is preparing to host the Ninth Summit of the Americas in early Summer 2022. &#160;The Summit has taken place approximately once every three years since 1994 and is the only meeting of all leaders from the countries of North, South, and Central America and the Caribbean.&#160; This will be the first time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States is preparing to host the Ninth Summit of the Americas in early Summer 2022. &nbsp;The Summit has taken place approximately once every three years since 1994 and is the only meeting of all leaders from the countries of North, South, and Central America and the Caribbean.&nbsp; This will be the first time the United States has hosted the Summit since the inaugural meeting in Miami, in 1994. Additional details to follow.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on How His Build Back Better Agenda Will Lower Prescription Drug&#160;Prices</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/12/remarks-by-president-biden-on-how-his-build-back-better-agenda-will-lower-prescription-drug-prices/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 20:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=27111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 1:27 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon. Before I begin, let me say a few words about the pandemic &#8212; the pandemic of the unvaccinated.&#160; I know there are lot of people out there trying to turn a public safety measure &#8212; that is, children wearing masks in school so they can be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>1:27 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br><br>Before I begin, let me say a few words about the pandemic &#8212; the pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; I know there are lot of people out there trying to turn a public safety measure &#8212; that is, children wearing masks in school so they can be safe –- into a political dispute.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>And this isn’t about politics.&nbsp; This is about keeping our children safe.<br><br>I saw a video and reports from Tennessee of protestors threatening doctors and nurses who were before a schoolboard making the case that, to keep kids safe, there should be mandatory masks.&nbsp; And as they walked out, these doctors were threatened, these nurses were threatened.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, our healthcare workers are heroes.&nbsp; They were the heroes when there was no vaccine.&nbsp; Many of them gave their lives trying to save others.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re heroes again with a vaccine.&nbsp; They&#8217;re doing their best to care for the people refusing to get vaccinated &#8212; unvaccinated folks who are being hospitalized and dying as a result of not being vaccinated.<br><br>To the mayors, school superintendents, educators, local leaders who are standing up to the governors politicizing mask protection for our kids &#8212; thank you, thank you as well.&nbsp; Thank God that we have heroes like you, and I stand with you all, and America should as well.<br><br>Now, let me turn to the focus of today’s remarks.&nbsp; There aren’t a lot of things that almost every American can agree on.&nbsp; But I think it’s safe to say that all of us &#8212; whatever our background, our age, or where we live -– can agree that prescription drug prices are outrageously expensive in America.<br><br>Today, I’d like to talk about how we&#8217;re going to help millions of Americans save money and ease their burdens by lowering the cost of prescription drugs.<br><br>Let me start by acknowledging the groundbreaking and lifesaving work that many pharmaceutical companies are doing.<br><br>Look no further than the vaccines they are manufacturing and delivering that are helping us beat this pandemic and save lives.<br><br>But we can make a distinction between developing these breakthroughs and jacking up prices on a range of medications for a range of everyday diseases and conditions.<br><br>Right now, right here in America, we pay the highest prescription drug costs of any developed nation in the world.&nbsp; Let me say that again: of any developed nation in the world.&nbsp; About two to three times what other countries pay.<br><br>Last week, in the Oval Office, I hosted a small-business owner named Gail from Denver.&nbsp; She’s 60 years old.&nbsp; When she was 11, she was diagnosed with Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; For nearly 50 years, she’s had to take insulin to stay alive.<br><br>But you know what she told me?&nbsp; She said she doesn’t worry about becoming blind or her blood sugar dropping dangerously low &#8212; the natural worries of anyone with Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; She worries about being able to pay for her prescription drugs.<br><br>During our conversation, she pulled out a vial of insulin from her bag.&nbsp; In 2001, she said, that single vial cost $32 a bottle.&nbsp; Today, that exact same bottle, with the same exact formula &#8212; no changes &#8212; costs $280 per bottle.<br><br>Gail and her husband work hard.&nbsp; They spend wisely.&nbsp; But because of the cost of her prescription drugs, her husband may not be able to retire.&nbsp; They drive the same car, she said, she&#8217;s had for 17 years, unable to afford repairs or a new one.&nbsp; And Gail is not alone.<br><br>It’s estimated that more than 34 million Americans &#8212; 10 percent of the population of the United States &#8212; have diabetes, including more than 1.5 million of those who have Type 1 diabetes.<br><br>And the outrageous cost, affecting everyone across the board, spanning every kind of condition and disease, is similar.<br><br>I remember what it was like for my mom as she got older and moved in with us.&nbsp; Her prescription drugs were so expensive<br>that it took me, my two brothers, and my sister &#8212; three siblings &#8212; chipping in to cover the thousands of dollars in monthly costs that she did &#8212; that she had to exhaust, rather than exhaust the little savings she had, for her prescription drugs.<br><br>It’s personal to so many of us and so many of you.&nbsp; You know, for more than 1 million Americans living with multiple sclerosis, one common drug for that disease costs $7,100 per month.&nbsp; The price has gone up 1,000 percent over the last 20 years without any change in the drug.&nbsp;<br><br>For more than 1 million people with rheumatoid arthritis, a common prescription drug used to cost about $1,350 per month; that was when it was introduced back in 2003.&nbsp; Today, the same drug costs $7,700 per month &#8212; over five times more expensive without any change.<br><br>For years, the price of many prescription drugs has dramatically outpaced inflation.&nbsp; These prices have put the squeeze on too many families and stripped them of their dignity.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been forced &#8212; we force people into terrible choices, between maintaining their health, paying the rent or the mortgage, putting food on the table.&nbsp; I mean, literally.&nbsp; And that’s the case for a lot of working families and seniors, even if you can get the care you need.&nbsp;<br><br>But, today, working families and too many seniors are struggling to make it work.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, one in four Americans who take prescription drugs struggle to afford them.&nbsp; Nearly 30 percent have skipped doses, cut pills in half, or &#8212; because they can’t afford the cost.<br><br>We have to change this, and we can.<br><br>My administration has already taken significant steps to lower the cost of prescription drugs.&nbsp; Last month, I signed an executive order that has the effect of improving competition in the economy, which will result in lower prescription drug fri- &#8212; drug costs.<br><br>Right now, when a drug company seeks permission from the FDA &#8212; the Food and Drug Administration &#8212; for a certain drug to get a patent, it’s allowed &#8212; the patent &#8212; it&#8217;s allowed to exclusively sell that drug without competition for up to 12 years.&nbsp; When that time period expires, other companies can come along, make the same exact drug, and sell it cheaper.&nbsp; It&#8217;s called a &#8220;generic drug.&#8221;<br><br>But unfortunately, it often takes a long time &#8212; years and years &#8212; for this to happen. &nbsp;That’s why I’ve instructed the federal Drug Administration to get these genetic [generic] drugs to consumers faster. &nbsp;This is going to increase competition, lower drug prices for everyone.<br><br>Research shows that prices could be cut by 25 to 33 percent and save $54 billion for consumers over the next 10 years.&nbsp; Makes a gigantic difference for an average family.<br><br>Secondly, I’ve ordered the FDA to work with states and Tribes to import prescription drugs safely from Canada.&nbsp; These are drugs that the FDA has determined are safe.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re going to make sure the drugs get to the states and Tribes safely.<br><br>Colorado estimates that their version of the Drug Importation Program is going to save $35 million to $60 million a year for people in Colorado, cutting the prices down by more than 60 percent for the cost of the same drug.&nbsp;<br><br>These things &#8212; and, by the way, you know, the company that&#8217;s making these drugs and causing &#8212; and charging exorbitant prices are selling the same drug in other countries at considerably lower prices.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like there&#8217;s another company always making this drug &#8212; same outfit.&nbsp;<br><br>These thing by themselves will be a great help.&nbsp; But to really solve the problem, we need Congress to act.&nbsp; That’s what my Build Back Better plan will do.<br><br>You know, there’s long been talk &#8212; I mean, a long time, since the days when I was back in the Senate &#8212; about giving Medicare the power to negotiate lower drug prices.<br><br>Now, Medicare takes care of millions of people.&nbsp; Medicare &#8212; my plan &#8212; going to &#8212; is going to allow that.&nbsp;<br><br>Every other type of healthcare service &#8212; from the cost of a doctor’s visit, how much a doctor can charge for a visit, hospital visits, crutches, wheelchairs &#8212; Medicare is allowed to negotiate and say, &#8220;We&#8217;ll pay no more, from the Medicare, than the following amount for those things.&#8221;<br><br>As I’ve said before, the only thing Medicare is not allowed to negotiate are prices for prescription drugs. My plan gets rid of that prohibition.<br><br>The proposal I made while I was running for President is that Medicare should negotiate drug prices across the board.<br><br>Congress is currently debating a more narrow vision letting Medicare negotiate some of the most expensive drugs, particularly from those companies that don’t face competition for that drug.&nbsp; We’re going to provide that competition through &#8212; we’re going to provide that competition through Medicare.&nbsp; Medicare is going to negotiate a fair price.<br><br>Right now, drug companies will set a price at whatever the market will bear.&nbsp;<br><br>Some of you may remember when I had the Moonshot going as &#8212; when I was Vice President.&nbsp; I met with 12 drug companies.&nbsp; And I agreed I would not name them at the time; it was just a private discussion.&nbsp; I said, “If any one of you came up with a drug that cured a particular type of cancer, what do you think you should be able to charge for it?”&nbsp; They said, “Whatever the market would bear.&nbsp; Whatever it will bear.”&nbsp;<br><br>But that often means a significant number of people can’t afford it under any circumstance and they’ll die without it.&nbsp; That’s unacceptable.&nbsp;<br><br>What we’re proposing is that we&#8217;ll negotiate a base &#8212; negotiate with the company based on a fair price, one that reflects the costs of the research and development and the need for providing for a significant prof- &#8212; a profit, but that&#8217;s still affordable for consumers.<br><br>And, by the way, if there was a significant amount that’s invested in it and a fair price is very expensive, we’re going to have to figure out society can provide for that drug that will save lives if people who can’t afford it.&nbsp; But that’s what we are trying to get done.&nbsp; And it has to get done.</p>



<p>But not only that my plan caps the amount that seniors<br>have to spend on prescription drugs each year at no more than about $3,000 a year, our plan says that drug companies<br>can only raise prices based on the rate of inflation after it’s determined how much they’ve invested and what a healthy profit constitutes.<br><br>Studies have shown that if we do this, we can save seniors thousands of dollars a year.<br><br>For example, an expensive drug for a cancer called &#8220;multiple myeloma&#8221; can cost $20,000 a month.&nbsp; Twenty thousand dollars a month.&nbsp; People who need that drug pay an average of $1,300 a month out of pocket even with Medicare.<br><br>What I’m proposing would reduce the total cost by thousands of dollars and seniors would not pay more than $250 a month on average.&nbsp; That’d be a game changer.<br><br>And by the way, it isn’t just seniors who will benefit.&nbsp; This would lower prescription drug prices for all Americans<em>.</em>&nbsp; And here’s how: If Medicare prices are available to private insurance companies, then it would reduce the cost of employer-based health insurance coverage.<br><br>What that means is: Once Medicare negotiates a lower drug price for its beneficiaries, an employer-based plan shouldn’t have to keep paying whatever the drug company demands.&nbsp; They should get access to the same drug for the same price as Medicare.<br><br>So, if you’re not on Medicare &#8212; you get your prescription drugs through your employer-based plan &#8212; your plan should pay the same price for that drug as someone on Medicare.<br><br>It means drug companies would have to sell their drugs to all distributors at the Medicare price or face up to a 95 percent excise tax. &nbsp;The savings for employers and employees would be billions of dollars a year.<br><br>We don’t have to stop there.&nbsp; My plan expands Medicare by adding dental, vision, and hearing, which would make a world of difference for millions of people.<br><br>And we can take some of that savings created when Medicare is no longer forced to overpay prescription drugs and use it to pay for these additional benefits and reduce premiums, improve access for people with coverage on Medicaid and the Affordable Care Act.<br><br>You know, at the same time, we can invest in medical breakthroughs that will also reduce the costs and save lives.<br><br>Right now, when Americans overpay for prescription drugs, too many pharmaceutical companies don’t use the profit nearly enough to innovate or research.<br><br>Too many companies use it on buying back their stock, inflate their worth, drive up CEO&#8217;s salaries and compensation, and find ways to box out the competition.<br><br>In fact, according to one study, from 2016 to 2020, pharmaceutical companies spent $577 billion in stock buybacks and dividends &#8212; $56 billion more than what they spent on<br>all research and development over that same period of time.<br><br>Look, folks, they should be able to make a significant prog- &#8212; prof- &#8212; profit, but why should we be paying two or three times what every other country in the world is paying for a similar drug?&nbsp; There&#8217;s so much we can do.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, at the Defense Department &#8212; for those of you who cover the Defense area &#8212; there’s something called the DARPA &#8212; the Defense Advanced Research Project Agency &#8212; set up exclusively within the Defense Department to seek out the cutting-edge research protects that enhance our national security.&nbsp; An outfit that came up with the Internet, GPS, and a lot of stealth technology &#8212; a lot of things.&nbsp;<br><br>I’m proposing we do a similar thing.&nbsp; I propose we spend $6.5 billion for a similar agency within the National Institute of Health &#8212; the NIH –- called &#8220;Advanced Research Project Agency&#8221; &#8212; ARPA-H &#8212; like DARPA &#8212; to help speed cutting-edge research on how to detect, treat, and cure diseases like Alzheimer’s, diabetes, and cancer.<br><br>It’s personal to so many people out there, and we can do this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not criticizing companies that aren&#8217;t prepared to spend billions of dollars on certain projects to research.&nbsp; I get it.&nbsp; But if they&#8217;re not, we should, to make sure the American &#8212; Americans are covered.&nbsp;<br><br>And here’s one other big thing that will help millions of Americans afford their prescription drugs: getting them affordable health insurance.<br><br>If anyone is worried about getting health insurance during the pandemic, there’s help today.&nbsp; For those who get their insurance through the Affordable Care Act, we’re covering more people, with better benefits, and with the premiums 40 percent lower.<br><br>That means the average premium has been cut by &#8212; from $104 a month to $62 a month.&nbsp; Sixty-two dollars a month for quality health insurance that covers doctors visits, hospital care, and prescription drugs.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, one third of the consumers are buying plans through the Affordable Care Act for less than $10 a month.<br><br>Earlier this week, I announced that more than 2.5 million Americans have signed up for coverage under the Affordable Care Act since I called for the Special Enrollment Period during this pandemic.<br><br>Folks, if you don’t have insurance, you can still sign up under the Affordable Care Act through Sunday, August the 15th.&nbsp; Just go to Healthcare.gov today, and get covered.<br><br>To all those folks expressing concern about rising costs for families, I urge you to support these basic reforms<br>that will allow drug companies to still make billions of dollars, as they have a right to do, but will address one of the largest out-of-pocket expenses that families face: prescription drugs.<br><br>We can do this.<br><br>Let me close with this: I’ve long said healthcare should be a right, not a privilege in this country.&nbsp; With my Build Back Better Plan, we have an opportunity to come together and get us even closer to that reality.&nbsp;<br><br>And the American people support it by overwhelming bipartisan margins.&nbsp; This isn’t a partisan issue.&nbsp; Alzheimer’s, diabetes, cancer &#8212; they don’t care if you&#8217;re a Democrat or Republican.&nbsp; This is about whether or not you and your loved ones can afford prescription drugs you need.<br><br>I look forward to Congress getting this done.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s another area &#8212; this is another area where you can come together and make a difference in people’s lives.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you.&nbsp; May God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>1:47 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
