<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 23:53:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on U.S. Consultations with Australia, Japan, and New Zealand in&#160;Honolulu</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-u-s-consultations-with-australia-japan-and-new-zealand-in-honolulu/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 23:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 18, National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell and Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink convened a meeting in Honolulu with U.S. Navy Adm. John C. Aquilino, Commander, U.S. Indo-Pacific Command and senior officials from Australia, Japan, and New Zealand on developments in the Pacific Islands. In&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 18, National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell and Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink convened a meeting in Honolulu with U.S. Navy Adm. John C. Aquilino, Commander, U.S. Indo-Pacific Command and senior officials from Australia, Japan, and New Zealand on developments in the Pacific Islands. In Honolulu, the officials reaffirmed the four countries’ enduring and shared commitment to the Pacific Islands. The United States resolved to intensify its engagement in the region to meet 21st-century challenges, from maritime security and economic development to the climate crisis and COVID-19. We will do this in ever-closer partnership with Pacific Island nations, including through a united Pacific Islands Forum; and together with like-minded countries, within and beyond the region, including in Europe. Officials from the four countries represented also shared concerns about a proposed security framework between the Solomon Islands and the People’s Republic of China (PRC) and its serious risks to a free and open Indo-Pacific. The meeting was part of regular and extensive U.S. consultations with allies and partners on the Indo-Pacific and is part of the announced senior administration travel this week to Hawaii, Fiji, Papua New Guinea, and the Solomon Islands.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting on Reproductive Health and Rights with State Legislators from Missouri, Nebraska, and&#160;Oklahoma</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/readout-of-white-house-meeting-on-reproductive-health-and-rights-with-state-legislators-from-missouri-nebraska-and-oklahoma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 21:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51428</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, hosted a roundtable discussion with state legislators from Missouri, Nebraska, and Oklahoma to discuss their efforts to protect access to reproductive health care, in light of a series of unconstitutional attacks on women’s reproductive rights. During the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Jennifer Klein, White House Gender Policy Council Director, and Julie Chavez Rodriguez, White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director, hosted a roundtable discussion with state legislators from Missouri, Nebraska, and Oklahoma to discuss their efforts to protect access to reproductive health care, in light of a series of unconstitutional attacks on women’s reproductive rights.</p>



<p>During the meeting, state legislators reported on abortion restrictions in their states and shared steps they have taken to oppose new legislative proposals. Leaders in Oklahoma described the potential impact of recently-passed S 612, which makes providing an abortion a criminal offense in the state, with narrow exceptions. Nebraska lawmakers shared their recent success in fighting a trigger ban, which failed on the legislature floor earlier this month and would have banned abortion in the state if <em>Roe</em> were overturned. State legislators from Missouri described their efforts to oppose a number of pending restrictions. All participants underscored the devastating impact these bills would have on access to critical reproductive health care services, especially for low-income populations and those living in rural communities.</p>



<p>Senior Administration officials underscored the Administration’s support for reproductive rights and determination to protect access to health care. They thanked the legislators for their leadership in opposing and raising awareness about these dangerous bills, and made it clear that the Administration stands with them in the fight to protect reproductive health care.</p>



<p>The legislation discussed today is just a sample of the onerous and unconstitutional restrictions that have passed or are pending in states across the nation. In light of this wholesale attack on reproductive rights, Administration officials reiterated the President’s support for the constitutional right affirmed in <em>Roe v. Wade</em> and his commitment to protect women’s access to critical reproductive health care.</p>



<p>State legislators participated in today’s meeting included:</p>



<ul><li>Missouri Senator Jill Schupp</li><li>Missouri Representative Emily Weber</li><li>Nebraska Senator Machaela Cavanaugh</li><li>Nebraska Senator Adam Morfeld</li><li>Oklahoma House Minority Leader Emily Virgin</li><li>Oklahoma Representative Forrest Bennett</li><li>Oklahoma Representative Ajay Pittman</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Update on the U.S. Strategy for Addressing the Root Causes of Migration in Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/fact-sheet-update-on-the-u-s-strategy-for-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 19:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[April 2022 Vice President Harris has led the Root Causes Strategy, which aligns U.S. Government efforts to address the economic, governance, and security drivers of irregular migration from Central America.&#160; The Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive strategy combines significant U.S. Government resources with substantial private sector investments to support the long-term development of the region.&#160; To advance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>April 2022</strong></p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-strategy-to-address-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/">Vice President Harris has led the Root Causes Strategy</a>, which aligns U.S. Government efforts to address the economic, governance, and security drivers of irregular migration from Central America.&nbsp; The Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive strategy combines significant U.S. Government resources with substantial private sector investments to support the long-term development of the region.&nbsp; To advance the strategy, the Vice President met with regional leaders and traveled to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/07/fact-sheet-u-s-guatemala-cooperation/">Guatemala</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/11/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-lopez-obrador-of-mexico-before-bilateral-meeting/">Mexico</a>, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/27/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-president-castro-of-honduras/">Honduras</a> to launch new initiatives that sustainably address the root causes of migration.&nbsp; The Vice President also brought together private sector leaders through her <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/vice-president-kamala-harris-announces-new-commitments-as-part-of-the-call-to-action-for-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-central-america-now-totaling-over-1-2-billion/#:~:text=The%20Call%20to%20Action's%20six,development%3B%20and%20public%20health%20access."><em>Call to Action</em></a> initiative that has generated more than $1.2 billion in commitments to create new jobs and opportunities for people in the region.&nbsp; In addition, she has engaged partners around the world to generate new commitments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These are long-term efforts, but under the Vice President’s leadership, the Biden-Harris Administration is seeing significant progress toward creating hope for people in El Salvador, Guatemala and Honduras that a better life can be found at home.&nbsp; Highlights to date include:</p>



<ul><li>U.S. initiatives are providing micro and small businesses access to $100 million in financing to support economic recovery in the region. &nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>To combat the COVID-19 pandemic, the U.S. Government has delivered more than 15 million free-of-cost vaccine doses bilaterally and in partnership with COVAX to countries in northern Central America.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The U.S. Government has provided $26.4 million to El Salvador, $81.5 million to Guatemala and $57.1 million to Honduras to support the fight against COVID-19.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. Government support for private sector companies helped create more than 70,000 jobs.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The U.S. Government’s $300 million <em>Centroamérica Local</em> initiative is empowering local organizations to address the drivers of irregular migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. support for the region’s agricultural sector is generating increased incomes for farm families and producers.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Additional U.S. funding for school feeding programs is improving food security in northern Central America.</li></ul>



<ul><li>A new Department of Justice Anti-Corruption Task Force, which was announced by the Vice President in June 2021, is prioritizing prosecutions against corrupt actors in the region.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. sanctions and visa restrictions are targeting perpetrators of corruption and serious human rights abuse.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. training professionalized over 5,000 civilian police across the region.&nbsp; <a></a></li></ul>



<ul><li>A new task force to prevent migrant smuggling and human trafficking, which was announced by the Vice President in June 2021, is disrupting trafficking operations and its work has already led to the indictment eight leaders of human smuggling organizations.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. programs are supporting victims of unaccompanied migrant children, gender-based violence, and survivors of human trafficking.</li></ul>



<ul><li>New U.S. Government programs and scholarships are improving access to education for nearly 18,000 returning/potential migrants and at-risk youth.</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. Government partnerships with local organizations are increasing income-generating opportunities for thousands of indigenous women and girls.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>U.S. programs are empowering women entrepreneurs to launch and scale their businesses across the region.</li></ul>



<ul><li>The U.S. Government is supporting at-risk youth across the region to strengthen their ability to resist gang recruitment.</li></ul>



<ul><li>New programming in northern Central America is focused on increasing collective action to address child and forced labor and improve occupational safety and health conditions for workers in the region.</li></ul>



<p>As part of the Vice President’s <em>Call to Action</em>:</p>



<ul><li>Microsoft is connecting four million people to broadband across the region, with over one million already connected to date.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Nespresso will invest $150 million to double the number of farmers it works with in the region and begin to source coffee from El Salvador and Honduras.</li><li>Mastercard is bringing five million people into the formal financial economy while digitizing one million micro and small businesses.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Parkdale Mills is investing $150 million to support a new yarn spinning facility in Honduras and an existing facility in Virginia, supporting 500 jobs in each location.</li></ul>



<ul><li>PepsiCo is investing at least $190 million in northern Central America through 2025 to improve its plants and expand distribution routes.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>Grupo Mariposa is providing over 70,000 small-business owners with access to credit and digital services.</li></ul>



<p><em>For additional details, please review the </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/report-on-the-u-s-strategy-for-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/">Report on the U.S. Strategy for Addressing the Root Causes of Migration in Central America.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Report on the U.S. Strategy for Addressing the Root causes of Migration in Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/report-on-the-u-s-strategy-for-addressing-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 19:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51422</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris launched the Root Causes Strategy on July 29, 2021, to align U.S. Government efforts to address the economic, governance, and security drivers of irregular migration from Central America.  Tackling the persistent challenges that drive irregular migration requires sustained political will and cooperation across a broad range of stakeholders to foster long-term development&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/fact-sheet-strategy-to-address-the-root-causes-of-migration-in-central-america/">Vice President Harris launched the Root Causes Strategy</a> on July 29, 2021, to align U.S. Government efforts to address the economic, governance, and security drivers of irregular migration from Central America.  Tackling the persistent challenges that drive irregular migration requires sustained political will and cooperation across a broad range of stakeholders to foster long-term development in the region.  The Vice President has led progress on the Administration’s Strategy, including by traveling to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/07/fact-sheet-u-s-guatemala-cooperation/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Guatemala</a>, <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/11/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-lopez-obrador-of-mexico-before-bilateral-meeting/">Mexico</a>, and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/27/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-meeting-with-president-castro-of-honduras/">Honduras</a> to launch new initiatives that sustainably address the root causes of migration. </p>



<p>Recognizing the important role for the private sector, Vice President Harris brought together private sector leaders through a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/13/vice-president-kamala-harris-announces-new-commitments-as-part-of-the-call-to-action-for-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-central-america-now-totaling-over-1-2-billion/"><em>Call to Action,</em></a><em> </em>which has resulted in over $1.2 billion in private sector commitments in Central America to create new jobs and opportunities for people in the region.&nbsp; Vice President Harris also engaged partners around the world to support our work and generate new commitments.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration’s strategy represents a comprehensive approach to promoting inclusive economic growth in the region with a sharp focus on strengthening democratic governance and combatting corruption, women’s empowerment, climate change, human rights, security and curbing gender-based violence.&nbsp; It integrates various U.S. Government tools, including foreign assistance, development finance, public diplomacy, and economic sanctions and visa restrictions.&nbsp; Because the region’s long-term development will require more than just the resources of the U.S. Government, the Strategy forges strong partnerships with the private sector and international partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Mobilizing Private Sector Investment</strong></p>



<p>The Vice President’s leadership has brought together private sector leaders through a <em>Call to Action</em>.&nbsp; In collaboration with the Partnership for Central America, this has resulted in &nbsp;more than $1.2 billion in private sector commitments in Central America to create new jobs and opportunities for people in the region.&nbsp; The <em>Call to Action’s</em> six focus areas are intended to support long-term development of the region.&nbsp; They are: promoting a reform agenda; digital and financial inclusion; food security and climate-smart agriculture; climate adaptation and clean energy; education and workforce development; and public health access.</p>



<p>Companies that have made investments and commitments in the region include Microsoft, Nespresso, Mastercard, CARE International, Cargill, Grupo Mariposa, Parkdale Mills, PepsiCo, JDE Peet’s, and PriceSmart.&nbsp; These initial commitments are already bearing fruit.&nbsp; Some highlights include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Internet Access:&nbsp; </strong>Microsoft catalyzed the development of digital access training centers, clean off-grid energy, and broadband access covering a population of 1.1 million people, and is on track to connect 4 million people to broadband by 2024.</li><li><strong>Support for Farmers</strong>:&nbsp; Nespresso works with over 1,200 farms in Guatemala to improve livelihoods in the region. The company announced its first-ever coffee sourcing from Honduras and El Salvador, with plans to increase activities in the region for the next harvest season. This is part of the company&#8217;s commitment to support the region&#8217;s economy with a minimum of $150 million to be spent across coffee purchases, price premiums, and technical assistance by 2025.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Digital and Financial Inclusion</strong>:&nbsp; Mastercard committed to bring five million people in El Salvador, Guatemala and Honduras into the formal financial economy and to digitize one million micro and small businesses.<strong>&nbsp; </strong>The company established a Digital Country Partnership with Guatemala’s Ministry of the Economy, accelerating their work to bring five million people in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras into the formal financial economy.&nbsp; This will also enable one million micro and small businesses to access online payment and management systems.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Job Creation and Supply Chain Resilience</strong>:&nbsp; Parkdale Mills is investing $150 million in a new yarn spinning facility in Honduras.&nbsp; This support will provide customers with sources for purchasing one million pounds of yarn per week within the region while increasing U.S. supply chain resilience. The investment is intended to support roughly 500 employees at each location and increase indirect job growth in Honduras and in the United States, particularly in the U.S. cotton industry across 18 states. The investment also includes $24 million in new investments in solar energy, water recapture, and energy efficient HVAC systems.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Infrastructure and Renewable Energy Investments</strong>:&nbsp; PepsiCo will invest at least $190 million in northern Central America through 2025.&nbsp; The company’s planned investments include improvements to its infrastructure and manufacturing plants; expansion of new distribution routes; IT projects; and investments aligned with its “pep+” (PepsiCo Positive) agenda. This includes spreading regenerative farming practices across seven million acres (which is approximately the size of the company’s entire agricultural footprint), becoming Net Water Positive by 2030 by reducing absolute water use and replenishing watersheds, and achieving net-zero emissions by 2040 by increasing the use of renewable energy, among other efforts.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Support for Small Businesses</strong>:&nbsp; Grupo Mariposa will provide over 70,000 small-business owners with access to credit and digital services.&nbsp; It will also support 3,500 small and medium-enterprises with access to telemedicine, education, and Internet connectivity, impacting more than 200,000 people and expanding healthcare and telemedicine solutions to 2,000 remote communities. In addition, it will invest more than $10 million to grow its coffee footprint, creating more than 500 new jobs and supporting more than 400 small and medium-sized coffee producers to increase productivity and earnings potential. <a></a></li></ul>



<ul><li>CARE announced its plans to establish a $50 million Center for Gender Equity in Central America focused on women and young people and designed to reach 500,000 individual women and their families, impacting two million people in total.&nbsp; The Center will support public and private programs in the region – scaling up those that work – to support financial inclusion, women’s economic empowerment (including in the protection of labor rights and in supporting entrepreneurship), improved agricultural outcomes, and reductions in gender-based violence. In particular, CARE will support companies joining the Call to Action with technical assistance to ensure that a gender-based lens is applied to new programs and investment.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Creating Economic Opportunity</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Job Creation:</strong>&nbsp; In Fiscal Year 2021, USAID support to private sector firms in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras helped create more than 70,000 jobs, spurred $415 million in sales, and supported agricultural producers to gain access to $860 million in financing.&nbsp; In Honduras, USAID helped establish a new $20 million loan facility to lend to underserved agricultural clients, especially women agribusiness owners.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Mobilizing Investment:</strong>&nbsp; Through USAID’s Guatemalan Entrepreneurship and Development Innovation initiative, announced by Vice President Harris in June 2021, USAID has leveraged $59 million, against its $7.5 million investment, from international and local private sector partners to scale technology-driven, market-led solutions to critical development challenges throughout the country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Public-Private Partnerships:</strong>&nbsp; U.S. Government advocacy contributed to Guatemala’s first public-private partnership (PPP) project in November 2021, which will extend and repair the highway that connects the capital with the country’s primary Pacific port, Puerto Quetzal, and can serve as a model for other infrastructure investment and help Guatemalans bring their products to the global market.&nbsp; The U.S. Trade and Development Agency (USTDA), in December 2021, awarded a feasibility study grant to develop a PPP that would install LED streetlights along more than 500 kilometers of highway across El Salvador to improve safety, increase energy efficiency, and lower energy costs.&nbsp; These PPPs can serve as powerful models for future infrastructure investment collaboration in the region.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Access to Finance:</strong>&nbsp; In October 2021, the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC) disbursed $100 million to the Central American Bank for Economic Integration (CABEI) to fund financial institution intermediaries in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras which will then lend to micro, small, and medium enterprises (MSMEs) to support economic recovery in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; The DFC, with USAID funding, provided additional loan guarantees to entities in El Salvador and Honduras to enhance lending to women-led small and medium enterprises (SMEs) and SMEs in high growth sectors of the economy to support economic growth and job creation within historically marginalized communities. &nbsp;In September 2021, USAID finalized a new loan guarantee that is facilitating access to loans for SMEs in the Western Highlands of Guatemala, a region with high levels of out-migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Trade Facilitation: &nbsp;</strong>In August 2021, the Department of Commerce’s Commercial Law Development Program (CLDP) and International Trade Administration (ITA) conducted a regional trade facilitation workshop with Guatemalan customs and trade ministries. &nbsp;In May and June of 2022, CLDP will host two workshops in Honduras on customs valuation and communication. &nbsp;These workshops are part of a multiphase effort to promote transparency, cooperation, and coordination among the northern Central American governments and improve inter-regional trade.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Strengthening Health and Education</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Vaccine Doses:</strong>&nbsp; To assist people in the region in combating the COVID-19 pandemic, the U.S. Government has delivered more than 15 million free-of-cost vaccine doses bilaterally and in partnership with COVAX to countries in northern Central America.&nbsp;Vaccination rates are steadily increasing in all three countries with Guatemala at 33 percent, Honduras at 46 percent, and El Salvador at 66 percent of their populations completing the initial COVID-19 vaccination protocol.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Vaccine Financing:</strong>&nbsp; In September 2021, the DFC, in conjunction with Citigroup Inc., provided a risk management solution to Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, to mitigate risk and overcome financial hurdles with governments that are funding COVID-19 vaccine purchases through the COVAX Facility.&nbsp; Of the $383 million in political risk insurance provided to Gavi, $50 million was provided to support allocation of vaccines to Guatemala.</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp; The U.S. Government has provided $26.4 million to El Salvador, $81.5 million to Guatemala, and $57.1 million to Honduras to support the fight against COVID-19 and strengthen health systems.&nbsp; Assistance is supporting training health care workers and public health staff in critical care management and safe and effective administration of vaccines, building laboratory capacity, strengthening contact tracing efforts, sharing critical information to prevent the spread of disease, providing technical assistance for the health information systems needed to evaluate vaccine distribution equity and monitor vaccine safety, and bolstering oxygen systems to ensure availability for patients who need them in Guatemala and Honduras.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Education:</strong>&nbsp; In El Salvador in November 2021, USAID launched a $20 million Scholarships for Education Project to curb irregular migration by increasing equitable access to formal educational opportunities for 6,450 returnees and potential migrants.&nbsp; In Honduras, USAID installed Internet hotspots in 60 community learning centers and increased access to remote learning for more than 5,000 people, including more than 600 returned migrant children. USAID also completed repairs on and expansions to two schools in western Honduras, which serve more than 1,800 local students in this area of high out-migration.&nbsp; In Guatemala, USAID provided education assistance to more than 6,300 at-risk youth and launched new partnerships to strengthen English language programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Enhancing Climate Resilience and Food Security</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Humanitarian Assistance:&nbsp; </strong>Since April 2021, USAID reached approximately 1.9 million people impacted by recurrent droughts, COVID-19, and severe damage from Hurricanes Eta and Iota in northern Central America with life-saving humanitarian assistance such as emergency food assistance, health, livelihoods restoration, protection, shelter as well as water, sanitation, and hygiene (WASH) support.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Food Security:&nbsp; </strong>The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) provided $30 million to expand its Food for Progress program in Guatemala, which will enable it to reach an additional 18,000 producers.&nbsp; USDA provided $45 million to expand its McGovern-Dole school feeding, health, nutrition, and educational programming in Guatemala and Honduras, reaching an additional 124,000 beneficiaries, with a projection of nearly 400,000 beneficiaries over the life of the program.<strong>&nbsp; </strong>In addition, in Fiscal Year 2021, USAID’s Feed the Future activities in Honduras directly assisted nearly 16,000 farm families and agribusinesses in adopting technologies to increase yields.&nbsp; This assistance contributed to over $23 million in incremental sales.&nbsp; In Guatemala, USAID’s Feed the Future activities created nearly 30,000 jobs and over $76 million in sales while leveraging over $10 million in financing and $6 million in investment in the agricultural sector.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Combating Corruption</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Anti-Corruption Task Force:</strong>&nbsp; In June 2021, Vice President Harris announced the establishment of the Department of Justice’s Anti-Corruption Task Force (ACTF). The ACTF subsequently created a new tip line for reporting corruption in the region and the FBI has reviewed and followed up on the resulting tips.&nbsp; The ACTF continues to operate the tip line and relies on relationships with counterparts, witnesses, cooperators and others in the region to streamline and prioritize investigations.&nbsp; In addition, the number of Department of Justice Resident Legal Advisors (RLAs), supported by the Department of State, was increased throughout the region, and RLAs continue to work with their counterparts in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.&nbsp; In November 2021, an RLA-assisted Honduran anti-corruption unit secured guilty verdicts against the former minister of health and former minister of labor on charges of embezzlement, bribery, fraud, and money laundering.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Sanctions and Visa Restrictions:&nbsp; </strong>In December 2021, the Department of the Treasury imposed sanctions on officials in El Salvador and Guatemala in connection with public corruption pursuant to the Global Magnitsky sanctions program, which allows for the targeting of corruption and serious human rights abuse.&nbsp; In addition, the Department of State publicly designated several Guatemalan and Salvadoran officials under Section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act for their involvement in significant corruption, generally rendering them and their immediate family members ineligible for entry into the United States.&nbsp; Prior to these actions, the Department of State publicly included multiple current and former officials and private individuals on the Section 353 Corrupt and Undemocratic Actors List generally rendering these individuals ineligible for visas and admission to the United States.&nbsp;In August 2021, the United States also launched a new visa restriction authority under Section 212(1)(3)(C) of the Immigration and Nationality Act on the issuance of visas to current or former Guatemalan, Honduran, or Salvadoran government officials and other individuals believed to be responsible for, or complicit in, undermining democracy or the rule of law.&nbsp; <strong></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Audit and Oversight:</strong>&nbsp; To promote transparency and fight corruption, USAID trained 100 auditors in Guatemala’s Specialized Center for Tax and Customs Crimes to better identify tax crimes, donated computer equipment for use in field audits, and provided technical assistance on the documentation of criminal complaints.&nbsp; With USAID support, the Center has recovered nearly $80 million in tax revenue since its inception.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Advancing Democracy, Promoting the Rule of Law, and Protecting Human Rights</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Democratic Elections:</strong>&nbsp; The Department of State and USAID engaged all levels of Honduran society and the government ahead of the November 2021 presidential election to promote free, fair, and peaceful elections that reflected the will of Honduran voters.&nbsp; USAID assistance helped facilitate the country’s election through support to journalists and civil society organizations to objectively report on information about the election process, independent analyses that informed recommendations on elections security, and get out the vote campaigns.&nbsp; USAID also supported the strengthening of electoral management bodies.&nbsp; The Department of State supported training for police officers in advance of the elections, including content on the use of force and relevant election laws and procedures, and distributed 20,000 election day pocket guides to police officers emphasizing the importance of respecting the rights of all citizens to vote.&nbsp; The election, characterized by high voter turnout, resulted in the peaceful election of the country’s first woman president.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp; Across the northern Central American countries, the Department of State and USAID worked together to promote human rights, labor rights, and press freedom.&nbsp; USAID increased resources to respond to rising protection needs, providing critical support to journalists, human rights defenders, and anti-corruption champions. &nbsp;USAID provided timely assistance to more than 30 human rights defenders and democracy advocates in El Salvador, Guatemala and Honduras. &nbsp;To respond to high rates of extortion, human trafficking, and violence among marginalized sexual and gender minority individuals, USAID supported LGBTQI+ civil society organizations to address regressive policies and advocate for reforms to key laws.&nbsp; In Honduras, this included advocating for transgender individuals to be able to legally register under their chosen names, rather than the names on their birth certificates under the law governing the National Persons Registry. &nbsp;A public petition garnered more than 4,000 signatures before submission to the Honduran National Congress in November 2021.&nbsp; As the Congress considers its response, LGBTQI+ advocacy groups are engaged in related advocacy and policy efforts to further promote necessary protections. In addition, U.S. Southern Command’s Human Rights Initiative has efforts in all three northern Central American countries, helping to institutionalize respect for human rights in partner nation armed forces doctrine and professional education.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>New Technical Assistance to Promote Labor Rights:&nbsp; </strong>The Department of Labor (DOL) recently announced $20 million in new programs in northern Central America.&nbsp; Activities will focus on increasing collective action to address child and forced labor and improve occupational safety and health conditions of workers in the region.&nbsp; Efforts also will improve the ability of workers to exercise their labor rights in agricultural supply chains in Guatemala and Honduras and the textile/apparel sector in El Salvador.&nbsp; <strong>&nbsp;</strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Labor Roundtables:&nbsp;</strong>In June and July 2021, DOL hosted nine labor roundtables, convening over 50 unions and civil society organizations from the United States, El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to discuss the nexus between labor issues and migration.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>Combating Crime and Increasing Security&nbsp;</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Human Smuggling:&nbsp; </strong>In June 2021, Vice President Harris announced the creation of a regional task force to identify, disrupt, and prevent migrant smuggling and human trafficking operations.Working with partners in the region, the Departments of Justice and Homeland Security’s Joint Task Force Alpha, which targets human smuggling, continues to identify and pursue priority human smuggling cases for prosecution within the United States.&nbsp; Department of Justice RLAs, with Department of State support, are working with counterparts in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to pursue investigations and prosecutions.&nbsp; In November 2021, prosecutors mentored by RLAs obtained indictments against twenty members of a human smuggling organization (HSO) that operated throughout El Salvador and Guatemala.&nbsp; In a coordinated effort, Guatemalan police and prosecutors also executed search warrants at five locations linked to the same HSO.&nbsp; In January 2022, as part of another coordinated investigation with DHS’s Homeland Security Investigations, Guatemalan authorities executed 19 search warrants, seized over $200,000, and arrested ten Guatemalan nationals for violations of foreign law related to human smuggling and money laundering. In Honduras, U.S. government efforts resulted in the formation of a migration task force to focus on investigation and prosecution of smuggling and trafficking networks.&nbsp; Since January 2021 this and other border security programs have resulted in the arrest of 283 alleged human smugglers, the rescue of 200 minors, and a tripling in the number of migrants checked against U.S. criminal and terrorist databases.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Money Laundering:</strong>&nbsp; In November 2021, U.S.-mentored prosecutors in Honduras secured money laundering convictions against seven Honduran nationals who were high-level members of the Byron Ruiz drug trafficking organization previously convicted of aggravated drug trafficking charges in Honduras.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Civilian Law Enforcement:</strong>  The Department of State worked to professionalize security forces across the region by training more than 5,000 civilian police in calendar year 2021 on topics such as community policing, investigations, and human rights. <br></li><li><strong>Conventional Weapons Destruction:  </strong>In 2021, the Department of State provided explosive ordnance disposal and stockpile management training to 86 security forces personnel, destroyed 7.91 metric tons of obsolete munitions, and provided physical security upgrades to vulnerable weapons storage facilities in El Salvador and Guatemala to prevent the illicit pilferage and proliferation of State-held weapons which contribute to armed violence and criminal activity in the region.<br></li><li><strong>Regional Information Sharing:</strong>  The Department of State supported a regional effort to share criminal intelligence about transnational criminal organizations and associated criminals in Central America, with a focus on migrant smuggling and human trafficking.  In 2021, this effort facilitated the identification of nearly 1,200 members of transnational criminal organizations.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reinsertion of Former Offenders:</strong>&nbsp; In El Salvador, USAID supported an innovative and evidence-based reinsertion model for adult and youth populations exiting prison and gang-involvement, which in the last year has led to a 70 percent success rate of participants receiving employment or consistently participating in skill building support and not re-offending.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong></strong></li></ul>



<p><strong>Focusing on Women and Youth</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Gender-Based Violence:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp; In February 2022, USAID awarded a $5 million grant to El Refugio de la Niñez, a Guatemalan NGO, to expand education, legal, housing, medical, psychosocial and other services to survivors of trafficking in persons and unaccompanied migrant children. In September 2021, the Department of State supported the design and implementation of a specialized course for Honduran prosecutors on gender-based violence, including domestic violence, which launched with an initial class of 25 prosecutors in February 2022. &nbsp;U.S. support is helping the Honduran National Police revamp its training curriculum to focus on incidents of gender-based violence and train 911 operators on how to prioritize and route the more than 60 reports of such violence daily.&nbsp; U.S. programs are also significantly increasing post-violence victim support and resources.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Young Women&#8217;s Empowerment</strong>:&nbsp; With the June 2021 launch of its $40 million Young Women’s Empowerment Initiative, USAID is partnering with Guatemalan indigenous and women’s organizations, private sector, and international organizations to increase education, professional training, and income-generating opportunities for thousands of indigenous Guatemalan women and girls.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Women Entrepreneurs:</strong>&nbsp; The Department of State’s Academy of Women Entrepreneurs (AWE) program in northern Central America provides women participants the knowledge, networks, and access to launch and scale their businesses through a proven combination of business classes, professional mentoring, and seed money.&nbsp; In September 2021, Honduras added 315 new participants and in November 2021, Guatemala graduated a class of 120 women, including representatives from highland and Afro-Guatemalan Garifuna communities with high rates of emigration, while El Salvador graduated a class of 176 women, 36 of whom received $24,000 in seed capital to invest further in their businesses and create jobs in their communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Advancing Women’s Economic Empowerment:</strong>&nbsp; On January 4, 2022, USAID launched the <em>MujerProspera</em> (WomenProsper) challenge, seeking solutions that advance women’s economic security, employment, and/or entrepreneurship in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.&nbsp; With this challenge, USAID expects to issue up to 14 awards each valued between $150,000 and $500,000 later this spring.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>At-Risk Youth:</strong>&nbsp; Since July 2021, USAID has provided psychosocial support and family counseling, gender-based violence prevention activities, life-skills training, vocational workshops, digital inclusion, sports and arts activities, and alternative education for youth left out of the formal education system for more than 27,500 children and youth in 80 high-crime and out-migration communities of the north, central, and western regions of Honduras.&nbsp; The Department of State worked with certified Gang Resistance Education and Training (G.R.E.A.T.) instructors across Honduras to reach more than 100,000 children and help strengthen their ability to resist gang recruitment. In El Salvador, USAID launched a $20 million alliance (which includes $10 million in private sector leverage) with local partner Glasswing International to improve citizen security in targeted Salvadoran communities to help reduce irregular migration, with a goal of reaching 30,000 people (mostly youth) in five years with economic and educational opportunities.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Enhancing Partnerships</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Engaging Local Organizations:</strong>&nbsp; In November 2021, USAID announced <em>Centroamérica Local</em>, a five-year, $300 million initiative to empower local organizations in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to address the drivers of irregular migration to the United States.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Cooperation with Mexico:</strong>&nbsp; In December 2021, the United States and Mexico announced <em>Sembrando Oportunidades</em>, a new framework for development cooperation to address the root causes of irregular migration from El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.&nbsp; These efforts are underway. In El Salvador, USAID is providing scholarships to graduates of Mexico’s youth workforce program, and in Honduras, USAID and its Mexican counterpart aim to reach more than 500,000 at-risk youth with skills and experience that can lead to long-term employment.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Diplomatic Engagement Around the World to Address Root Causes</strong></p>



<ul><li>The Vice President has recognized the need to internationalize her efforts, and has been rallying partners around the world to support U.S. efforts to address the root causes of migration. The Vice President’s extensive diplomatic engagement with leaders around the world includes the following important new commitments:</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Republic of Korea</u></strong>:&nbsp; After the Vice President met with South&nbsp;Korean President&nbsp;Moon Jae-in, the Republican of Korea doubled foreign assistance to northern Central America to $220 million over five years.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Japan</u></strong>:&nbsp; The Government of Japan committed to closer collaboration and has provided nearly $22 million in assistance to the three countries of northern Central America.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong><u>Israel</u></strong>:&nbsp; The Israeli government announced it would collaborate with USAID on agriculture, watershed management, and violence prevention programs in Guatemala and Honduras.</li></ul>



<p>The Vice President&#8217;s diplomacy helped establish the United Nations Humanitarian Response Plans for Honduras, El Salvador and Guatemala. She has worked with the European Union and Canada, which have become the largest donors to the effort after the United States.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 19,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/19/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-19-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 19:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51419</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Portsmouth, New Hampshire 1:16 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Welcome to our trip to New Hampshire.&#160; I highlighted a little bit of this yesterday, so I will keep this brief. But as a reminder, we are headed to Portsmouth.&#160; Portsmouth Harbor, which we are visiting, is the only deep-water harbor in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Portsmouth, New Hampshire</p>



<p>1:16 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Welcome to our trip to New Hampshire.&nbsp; I highlighted a little bit of this yesterday, so I will keep this brief.</p>



<p>But as a reminder, we are headed to Portsmouth.&nbsp; Portsmouth Harbor, which we are visiting, is the only deep-water harbor in New Hampshire and handles approximately 3.5 million tons and nearly $2 billion of cargo a year.</p>



<p>Earlier this year, we awarded $1.7 million from the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers for maintenance dredging in Portsmouth Harbor through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the investment builds on an $18.2 million Army Corps project in Portsmouth Harbor for navigation improvement, which widened the uppermost turning basin in the river.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, the President will hear from the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, Coast Guard Commander for Sector Northern New England, and New Hampshire Port Director on the impact of these projects and funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law on the port.</p>



<p>On the ground in Portsmouth, he will also see Governor Chris Sununu; Senator Hassan; Representatives Pappas and Annie &#8212; and Kuster; the mayors of Portsmouth and Manchester; and several other state and local elected officials.</p>



<p>I also wanted to note &#8212; did you all get the P+11 readout?&nbsp; Did it come to you yet?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, I’m not sure it’s gone out.</p>



<p>So let me &#8212; let me do a couple of highlights from that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Watch out, Jen.&nbsp; The door is closing.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, thank you.&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>As you know, the President had a call with the P+11 this morning, as it was part of our close coordination with Allies and partners.&nbsp; He convened the video conference to discuss their ongoing efforts to support Ukraine in the face of Russian aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leaders reiterated their commitment to continue providing security, economic, and humanitarian assistance to Ukraine in its time of need.&nbsp; The leaders affirmed their solidarity with the Ukrainian people and condemned the humanitarian suffering caused by Russia&#8217;s unprovoked and unjustified invasion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They also discussed their respective diplomatic engagements and their coordinated efforts to continue to impose severe economic costs to hold Russia accountable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They agreed to continue to closely coordinate their efforts, including working with and through the G7, EU, and NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, with that, yes, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On the mask mandate, why is the DOJ not appealing that?&nbsp; And by not, do you &#8212; does the administration risk taking away some of your options for the future, especially if there&#8217;s some new variants?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, unless something&#8217;s happened when we got on the plane, I don&#8217;t think they&#8217;ve made any announcement at this point in time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as we&#8217;ve said, agencies are reviewing step &#8212; next steps, including the Department of Justice.&nbsp; Traditionally following a court decision, that can take a couple of days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve said from the start that our COVID response should be guided by the science and data and by experts.&nbsp; And just as a reminder, when we made this announcement, the CDC said it needed 15 days to assess the impacts of an uptick in cases on hospitalizations, deaths, and hospital capacity.&nbsp; We feel &#8212; still feel that is entirely reasonable, based on the latest science, and public health decisions shouldn&#8217;t be made by the courts.&nbsp; They should be made by public health experts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, again, I can&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the Department of Justice. &nbsp;We’ll let them make any decisions or announcements, but &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So they might still appeal, is what you&#8217;re saying?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It typically &#8212; yeah, it typically takes a couple of days to review and make an assessment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If you don&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, if you don&#8217;t appeal, do you run the risk of sending the message that all CDC mandates are optional?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to prejudge the Department of Justice and how they make considerations or assessments about whether or not they&#8217;re going to appeal.&nbsp; We obviously feel confident in our authorities here, given we put the mask mandate in place and asked for 15 additional days to evaluate data based on public health information.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was the administration unprepared for this ruling, given that you’re not sure what you&#8217;re going to do next?</p>



<p>And also, does the confusion around the mask mandate undercut the administration&#8217;s ability to kind of give people guidance on what is actually the right thing to do at this point?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would &#8212; I would dispute the notion that people are confused.&nbsp; We are here to alleviate their confusion, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the CDC continues to advise and recommend masks on airplanes.&nbsp; We&#8217;re abiding by the CDC recommendations, the President is.&nbsp; And we would advise all Americans to do that.</p>



<p>This was a ruling by the court.&nbsp; We obviously didn&#8217;t have advance notice of it.&nbsp; And it typically takes a couple of days to assess next steps in these cases.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And should the President be speaking &#8212; does the President have plans to speak more about this kind of evolution in how people should protect themselves from COVID, given the sense that precautions are lifting?&nbsp; You know, does he plan to speak out more in providing more guidance and leadership on this issue?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don’t see it as an evolution.&nbsp; We continue to believe that the CDC, which asked for 15 days to evaluate health data and information based on the fact that cases were rising in certain parts of the country &#8212; that that was entirely reasonable, and that they would, at the conclusion of that period of time &#8212; not a lengthy period of time &#8212; be able to make an evaluation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He also put out a 100-page plan just a couple of weeks ago on how to deal with this moment we are in as we address the virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What our biggest concern is right now &#8212; continues to be the fact that we don&#8217;t have funding from Congress to ensure that we can return to a point where we have programs for the uninsured, we’re able to purchased &#8212; purchase treatments for the immunocompromised, ensuring that we continue to be the arsenal of vaccines to the world.&nbsp; Those are our biggest concerns.&nbsp; And, yes, we will speak out about that and he will speak out about that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Russia and terrorism.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the admi- &#8212; I got one.&nbsp; I got one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you talked about this yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I got one.&nbsp; Hold on, Jen.&nbsp; On this same issue &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Until we land we’re (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, it’s my turn.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the issue of masking and your strategy in general, does the administration feel like your strategies have been thwarted by courts, in general?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to &#8212; as a follow-up to Nancy&#8217;s question and to Jennifer&#8217;s question, if you &#8212; if you&#8217;re not challenging this, what are the next steps?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, if the Department of Justice makes that decision, we can talk about that.&nbsp; But they haven&#8217;t made a decision yet.&nbsp; And it typically takes a couple of days &#8212; some time to make that assessment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What was the first part of your question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m thinking about the fact that I don&#8217;t think you challenged the ruling that struck down the employer vaccine mandate.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So I’m just wondering what &#8212; if you&#8217;re not going to challenge these things when they &#8212; when they get stepped out, at least in that example &#8212; we don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s going to happen with this one &#8212; what&#8217;s the next step?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not going to prejudge what the Department of Justice decides.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will say, on the employer mandate, what we did was we continued to encourage private sector companies to put in place requirements that would keep their communities safe.&nbsp; And there were a lot of big companies that had already done that &#8212; including airlines, by the way; including big hospital systems around the country &#8212; and done that effectively, efficiently without having a big drop-off of employees in their workforce.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So in this case, even as there&#8217;s not a decision yet made by the Department of Justice, we&#8217;re continuing to encourage people to wear masks in public transit.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll make that decision because it&#8217;s obviously not being implemented at this moment in time, but we&#8217;ll continue to abide by CDC guidance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the CDC changes their assessment, which certainly at some point they will, we would follow that guidance.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Russia and terrorism.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know you talked about this a little bit yesterday, but &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; I&#8217;m &#8212; and I know you saw CNN is reporting that the U.S. is considering labeling Russia a purveyor of state-sponsored terrorism.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about that?&nbsp; Is that true that you are considering that?&nbsp; Tell us a little bit about how that would work out.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me just take a step back for a second so everybody knows how this process works, which you all may already know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But for a country to be designated as a state sponsor of terrorism, the Secretary of State would have to determine that the government of that country has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.&nbsp; And only four countries have been designated to date &#8212; right? &#8212; Cuba, North Korea, Iran, and Syria.&nbsp; The designation is defined by statute, meaning Congress has written into law the exact criteria under which a state would qualify as a state sponsor of terrorism.</p>



<p>So I know my colleague over at the State Department, Ned Price, has said there &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a lot of asks that President Zelenskyy has.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking at a range of them.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update on what their process may or may not look like.&nbsp; I would point you to them to speak to that, because it&#8217;s determined by the statute from Congress, by the State Department.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, how concerned is the White House about the IMF’s prediction of seismic, you know, problems for the economy around the world due to Ukraine?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, just following on from that, is there a sense that if this goes on, which looks like it will in Ukraine, the fallout for other countries could eventually pressure the alliance the President has been building to, you know, basically dial back a bit even if the Ukrainians want to push on &#8212; maybe, like, try and force them into, you know, reaching a settlement that &#8212; yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, okay, on the second question I would say that we&#8217;ve known from the beginning that unity doesn&#8217;t happen by accident.&nbsp; It requires a great deal of work, a great deal of diplomacy, a great deal of discussion.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s part of the reason the President had the P+11 call this morning: to continue to keep other countries updated &#8212; whether it&#8217;s NATO or the G7 or other groups of countries &#8212; on what we&#8217;re considering in terms of sanctions, what we&#8217;re considering in terms of military assistance, what other countries are doing.&nbsp; Sometimes there&#8217;s equipment the Ukrainians want we don&#8217;t have; we discuss that with them as well.</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s why there&#8217;s so much time and effort &#8212; from the President, from the Secretary of State, others &#8212; is being spent on this exactly.</p>



<p>I would say on the IMF projections: You know, I would note that the projection for the United States and our growth still continues to be higher than the vast majority of the world.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And that is a sign of the strength of our economy.</p>



<p>But it is true &#8212; and we&#8217;ve said this from the beginning &#8212; that the invasion of Ukraine by President Putin and Russia is going to have a continued impact on the global economy, whether it is on the oil markets or other areas. &nbsp;And certainly, that&#8217;s something we are aware of, even as the strength of our own economy &#8212; you know, we have a strong basis to build on through this difficult time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the call this morning, the Pentagon has said that they&#8217;re concerned that the ammunition levels for Ukrainians are getting dangerously low.&nbsp; Was that something that the President brought up in trying to get Allies to provide more ammunition?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I can check on that and see if there&#8217;s anything specifically on ammunition.&nbsp; Certainly, we will continue to provide them more ammunition as we will provide them more military assistance.&nbsp; There&#8217;s obviously more money we can provide from the approved drawdown package, and the specifics of that are being worked through with the Department of Defense and our national security team.&nbsp; And that, you know, has included ammunition, and I would expect will include a range of weapons moving forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more question on the mask mandate.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I understand that the judge&#8217;s ruling is something that, you know, independent judiciary has made.&nbsp; However, you saw a lot of Americans, you know, immediately pulling off their masks in airplanes, very happy about the change.&nbsp; Is the administration concerned that the public is moving on, you know, without the CDC and that the country is in a different place where the administration is in?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would note, while I&#8217;ve seen those videos, anecdotes are not data.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And certainly, that does tell a part of the story.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t make these decisions based on politics or based on the political whims on a plane or even in a poll.&nbsp;<br><br>But I would note: In polls, they &#8212; and data &#8212; lengthier data &#8212; there are still a lot of people in this country who still want to have masks in place &#8212; either they have immunocompromised relatives, they have kids under five, whatever it may be.&nbsp;<br><br>So in the &#8212; even on the pure politics, I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a concrete story at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the President is going to, you know, New Hampshire today to talk about infrastructure, selling the benefits of that.&nbsp; He said a few months ago that people didn&#8217;t want to see him being a “Senator-President” anymore.&nbsp; They want to see him getting out there, and his schedule certainly reflects that.&nbsp;<br><br>But, you know, the Chief of Staff has talked about the calendar, you know, being short and there being only so many days in the calendar to do things.&nbsp;<br><br>Is he, at some point, going to come out and talk about what he wants to see in, potentially, a skinny Build Back Better bill, given that time is of the essence with that?&nbsp;<br><br>And we haven&#8217;t heard from him really &#8212; anything about the, you know, negotiations and the talks.&nbsp; Is he going to come out and sort of put a marker down, or is the fact that he hasn&#8217;t come out and maybe won&#8217;t come out sort of a sign that maybe that&#8217;s not really going anywhere?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, one of the decisions he also made &#8212; the President, that is &#8212; is that he wasn&#8217;t going to talk a lot publicly, because he didn&#8217;t feel it was advantageous to getting things done, about his conversations with members of all political stripes.&nbsp; And just because he&#8217;s not talking about it doesn&#8217;t mean those conversations are not happening behind the scenes.&nbsp;<br><br>And as it relates to not being a senator &#8212; or not being the “President-Senator” &#8212; I think is that &#8212; how you said it &#8212; I mean, going out in the country today and out later this week is a reflection of that.&nbsp; Going out and talking about the impacts of his policies and his agenda on the American people &#8212; in New Hampshire, out on the West Coast &#8212; that&#8217;s exactly our effort to do that and not being holed up in the Oval Office having congressional negotiations.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we assume that if there&#8217;s no one out there sort of talking about a new BBB bill, that there isn&#8217;t an agreement yet?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think if we had a bill that was ready to pass with 50 votes, we would make that clear.&nbsp; So the &#8212; but there&#8217;s a range of ongoing negotiations and discussions with senators amongst themselves, a lot of them &#8212; a lot &#8212; there&#8217;s a great deal of support for moving an agenda forward that lowers costs for the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>So, not having a public speech from the President is not a reflection of what&#8217;s happening behind the scenes.&nbsp; There&#8217;s actually a strategic decision made not to have public updates about behind-the-scenes conversations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on Title 42, there are some Democratic senators &#8212; including Senator Hassan, Senator Peters &#8212; who have expressed concerns about what happens, what comes next after Title 42 lapses.&nbsp; And I know you said yesterday that the answer, if people want changes, is congressional legislation.</p>



<p>(Gaggle interruption.)&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You good?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I’m good.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it’s unlikely that, you know, Congress is going to pass something in the next few months, if at all.&nbsp; So, as an alternative to that, can you tell us anything about any plans that are underway to try to ease the transition to a post-Title 42 &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I mean, the Sec- &#8212; the Home- &#8212; Department of Homeland Security and the Secretary put out a comprehensive plan for what they were going to do to prepare for any increase in influx.&nbsp; They put that out when we made an announcement about the timeline of implementation.&nbsp; And that’s something they’re having ongoing discussions with senators, members, and their teams and staff about.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, certainly, I’m sure they welcome suggestions or different things that can be done.&nbsp; But they did put out a comprehensive plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The issue here &#8212; the core issue is that it is being used to tie down and hold back the COVID funding.&nbsp; And our concern here is: Let’s have a conversation about immigration. &nbsp;Title 42 is not an immigration policy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the point.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a public health authority that Congress has given the CDC authority to make a determination about.&nbsp; They made the determination.</p>



<p>So, if we want to address immigration, let&#8217;s have a conversation about that.&nbsp; But let&#8217;s not hold COVID funding hostage because we&#8217;re going to have to end a range of programs that are hurt &#8212; going to hurt the American people.&nbsp; That’s the issue.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we expect any new Russia sanctions this week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There could be, Jeff.&nbsp; I think that we&#8217;re still consid- &#8212; making &#8212; doing considerations and running a process for additional sanctions, but there are some under consideration, yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you tell us anything more about these Cuba-U.S. talks that the Cubans are saying that are happening, I think, tomorrow &#8212; is that right?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me get an update on that.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t had a chance to talk to the national security team about that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also on Ukraine, can you say how much money is left in that drawdown fund that you were talking about?&nbsp; And, obviously, both Schumer and McConnell have been talking about the need for sending more money to Ukraine.&nbsp; Is the White House open to that?&nbsp; Are there discussions about that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; There&#8217;s an ongoing discussion with the Ukrainians about what they need, with Congress about what we can provide, and about how to &#8212; and briefings of them &#8212; to them, I should say, about how to spend the remaining drawdown funds.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Which is how much?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I will check on that for you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One question since we’re going to talk about climate in Portland and Seattle.&nbsp; Given that BBB is, you know, still &#8212; we’re not sure where the status of that is &#8212; I mean, what can you say about the &#8212; what message the President can send, given that his major climate initiatives are &#8212; they’re stalled in legislation as he’s trying to draw attention to work on climate this week?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law had an enormous investment in addressing the climate crisis in it, including investing in charging stations for electric vehicles across the country.&nbsp; Never has that ever been done before in that capacity.&nbsp; He has also taken a range of steps, including &#8212;</p>



<p>(Air Force One begins landing.)</p>



<p>Oh, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; okay, we got a few more &#8212; a few more seconds here.</p>



<p>&#8212; with his own authorities, including rallying automakers and auto workers around an electric transportation future; setting a national target of 50 percent electric vehicles sales by 2030; launching the EV Charging Action Plan to deploy $7.5 billion from the Bipartisan Law I mentioned; finalizing the strongest possible passenger vehicle standards in American history; issuing the U.S. Methane Emissions Restriction Action.</p>



<p>The point is: He&#8217;s not going to wait or delay taking actions to address the climate crisis.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to fight for the key components that are in Build Back Better. &nbsp;But also, the Infrastructure Law that he&#8217;s already passed, signed into law, and is implementing has a major investment in climate in it.</p>



<p>Okay, we’re about to land.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Everybody brace for landing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaking of (inaudible) calendars, have you heard the President weigh in on which states he would prefer to go first in the nominating process?&nbsp; Has he talked about that at all, as far as &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There’s a DNC process, and we trust that process to take place and move forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so the President hasn’t weighed in, as far as you know, on &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re relying on the DNC process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he has no preference?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re relying on the DNC process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he talked to the DNC Chairman about it at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have any updates on private conversations.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>1:33 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the President’s Call with Allies and&#160;Partners</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/19/readout-of-the-presidents-call-with-allies-and-partners/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 18:38:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. hosted a videoconference today with Allies and partners to discuss international support for Ukraine in the face of Russian aggression, including the ongoing provision of security, economic, and humanitarian assistance.&#160; The leaders affirmed their solidarity with the Ukrainian people and condemned the humanitarian suffering caused by Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. hosted a videoconference today with Allies and partners to discuss international support for Ukraine in the face of Russian aggression, including the ongoing provision of security, economic, and humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; The leaders affirmed their solidarity with the Ukrainian people and condemned the humanitarian suffering caused by Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion. &nbsp;They also discussed their coordinated efforts to impose&nbsp;severe economic costs to hold Russia accountable.&nbsp; They committed to continued close consultation, including working with and through the G7, EU, and NATO.</p>



<p>Joining President Biden on the call were Prime Minister Justin Trudeau of Canada, European Commission President von der Leyen, European Council President Michel, President Macron of France, Chancellor Scholz of Germany, Prime Minister Draghi of Italy, Prime Minister Kishida of Japan, NATO Secretary General Stoltenberg, President Duda of Poland, President Iohannis of Romania, and Prime Minister Johnson of the United Kingdom.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R. 3197 and H.R.&#160;5681</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/04/19/bill-signed-h-r-3197-and-h-r-5681/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 17:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51404</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Tuesday, April 19, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 3197, the &#8220;Save the Liberty Theater Act of 2021,&#8221; which directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the City of Eunice, Louisiana, by quitclaim deed and without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified parcels&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Tuesday, April 19, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 3197, the &#8220;Save the Liberty Theater Act of 2021,&#8221; which directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the City of Eunice, Louisiana, by quitclaim deed and without consideration, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to specified parcels of land.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representative Mike Johnson and Senator Kennedy for their leadership.</p>



<p>H.R. 5681, the &#8220;Shadow Wolves Enhancement Act,&#8221; which authorizes U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) to reclassify officers assigned to the tactical patrol unit on Tohono O&#8217;odham Nation land, commonly known as Shadow Wolves, as ICE special agents.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Katko, Cuellar, Cole, Joyce, Mullin, Gallego and Senators Sinema, Hoeven, Kelly, and Hassan for their leadership</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Ongoing Work to Establish Norms in&#160;Space</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/18/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-ongoing-work-to-establish-norms-in-space/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 03:33:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51384</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vandenberg AFB, CA 5:18 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Thank you, Specialist Davis, for that kind introduction.   It is wonderful to be back in California. And I want to thank the members of Congress who are with us today &#8212; Senator Alex Padilla, Representative Carbajal, and Representative&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Vandenberg AFB, CA</p>



<p>5:18 P.M. PDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Good afternoon.  Please have a seat.  Good afternoon.  Thank you, Specialist Davis, for that kind introduction.  <br><br>It is wonderful to be back in California.<br><br>And I want to thank the members of Congress who are with us today &#8212; Senator Alex Padilla, Representative Carbajal, and Representative Ted Lieu. <br><br>And thank you to Deputy Secretary of Defense Hicks and the many local elected officials who are with us this afternoon. <br><br>And thank you to all of you, in particular to the United States Space Force Guardians and the United States Space Command personnel, and to our international and commercial partners.<br><br>I think everyone here recognizes how extraordinary space is.  Whether it is satellites that orbit the Earth, humans that land on the Moon, or telescopes that peer into the furthest reaches of the universe, space is exciting.  It spurs our imaginations, and it forces us to ask big questions.  Space &#8212; it affects us all, and it connects us all.<br><br>There are so many opportunities in space for our country and for all of humanity &#8212; from science, to commerce, to national security.<br><br>All of you on this base know the importance of the space systems that you use and operate and how important they are for our national security.<br><br>Our space capabilities provide for global awareness, global connectivity, and global navigation.<br><br>And, of course, we also know the threats we face in space.<br><br>This is why our administration has proposed the largest single increase in our military space capability in our nation’s history.<br><br>And we will continue to invest so you are able to protect our interests in space which, in turn, protects our interests here on Earth. <br> <br>In recent months, you have heard the President and me talk a lot about defending international norms and rules.  Rules and norms are shared principles that guide the behavior of people and of communities.  They are common understandings of what is right, what is wrong, and what is acceptable.  <br><br>Whether it is the way we interact with our colleagues at work or the way nations interact with each other on the world stage, rules and norms provide us all with a sense of order and stability.<br><br>As we have seen in Ukraine, Russia has completely violated the set of international rules and norms established after World War Two which provided unprecedented peace and security in Europe. <br><br>In the face of Russian brutality, the world has come together to say these roles and these rules and norms must be upheld.  I am heartened to see such strong affirmation of their importance. <br><br>At the same time, our administration is working to establish new rules and norms for the new challenges of the 21st century &#8212; areas like emerging technologies, cybersecurity, and, of course, space.<br><br>In December, I convened the first National Space Council meeting under our administration.  As the Chair of the Council, I made this issue a point of emphasis.  I believe without clear norms, we face unnecessary risks in space. <br><br>The United States will continue to be a leader in order to establish, to advance, and demonstrate norms for the responsible and peaceful use of outer space.<br><br>I’ve met with leaders from around the world &#8212; countries like Singapore and France, Bahrain and India &#8212; and I’ve raised this issue.<br><br>It is clear there is strong interest among our international partners to develop these norms.  We must write the new rules of road.  And we will lead by example.<br><br>Today, we are taking a major step forward in this effort &#8212; a step that specifically addresses the problem of destructive missile tests in space, like the one Russia took in November.<br><br>That, of course, is when Russia launched a missile to destroy a satellite in space.  It is called a destructive direct-ascent anti-satellite missile test.<br><br>In 2007, China conducted a similar test.<br><br>These tests are part of their efforts to develop anti-satellite weapons systems.<br><br>These weapons are intended to deny the United States our ability to use our space capabilities by <s>distruping </s>[disrupting], destroying our satellites &#8212; satellites which are critical to our national security.<br><br>These tests, to be sure, are reckless, and they are irresponsible.  These tests also put in danger so much of what we do in space.<br><br>Here’s how: When China and Russia destroyed their respective satellites, it generated thousands of pieces of debris &#8212; debris that will now orbit our Earth for years, if not decades. <br><br>I just received a briefing from the 18th Space Defense Squadron, and their work is incredibly impressive.<br><br>So far, the 18th has identified more than 1,600 pieces of debris from the Russian test.  There are over 2,800 pieces of debris still in space from China’s test 15 years ago.<br><br>Like air traffic controllers for space, the 18th tracks debris and satellites to prevent collisions.<br> <br>This debris presents a risk to the safety of our astronauts, our satellites, and our growing commercial presence.<br><br>A piece of space debris the size of a basketball, which travels at thousands of miles per hour, would destroy a satellite.  Even a piece of debris as small as a grain of sand could cause serious damage. <br><br>We have consistently condemned these tests and called them res- &#8212; reckless.  But that is not enough.<br> <br>Today we are going further.  I am pleased to announce that as of today, the United States commits not to conduct destructive direct-ascent anti-satellite missile testing.<br><br>Simply put: These tests are dangerous, and we will not conduct them.<br><br>We are the first nation to make such a commitment.  And today, on behalf of the United States of America, I call on all nations to join us.<br><br>Whether a nation is spacefaring or not, we believe this will benefit everyone, just as space benefits everyone.<br><br>In the days and months ahead, we will work with other nations to establish this as a new international norm for responsible behavior in space.  And there is a direct connection between such a norm and the daily life of the American people. <br><br>If a satellite was taken out by debris, it could affect the daily weather forecast, GPS driving directions, and even your favorite TV station.<br><br>Critical infrastructure, like wind turbines that power our homes, well, they rely on satellites for connectivity.<br><br>Satellites help us track the climate crisis.  They enable our commercial activities.  And they help us protect our troops and our people.<br><br>All of this is threatened by the debris created by these reckless tests.<br><br>These tests also threaten the lives of astronauts in the International Space Station.<br><br>In fact, I spoke earlier this month with Mark Vande Hei who just returned from 355 days in space on the Space Station.  An American record.<br><br>While he was in space, Russia conducted its anti-satellite missile test.  He had to shelter in an escape capsule in case the Space Station was hit by debris.<br><br>Russia’s action was a threat not just to his life, but also to those of Russian cosmonauts.<br><br>Our commitment today is just one step.  Our administration has already begun to establish a broader and comprehensive set of norms.<br><br>One example is the Artemis Accords &#8212; a set of principles that will guide civil use of space.<br><br>They are designed to create a safe and transparent environment for space exploration, science, and commercial activities.<br><br>Since our administration took office, we have doubled &#8212; to 18 &#8212; the number of nations to sign on.<br> <br>As we move forward, we will remain focused on writing new rules of the road to ensure all space activities are conducted in a responsible, peaceful, and sustainable manner. <br><br>The United States is committed to lead the way and to lead by example.<br><br>The leadership of the United States in space will continue to be a source of strength for us, both at home and abroad.<br><br>And our administration, with the help of all of you here on this base, are going to ensure future generations will benefit from space just as we have today.<br> <br>So, thank you all again for all that you do on behalf of our country.<br><br>God bless you.  And God bless America.  Thank you.  (Applause.) <br><br> END                 5:32 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Readout of the April National Climate Task Force&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/18/fact-sheet-readout-of-the-april-national-climate-task-force-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Task Force kicked off Earth Week by highlighting historic progress on climate Today, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy held the eleventh meeting of the National Climate Task Force to launch a week of Administration actions leading up to Earth Day that build on President Biden’s historic progress to tackle the climate crisis and reduce emissions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Task Force kicked off Earth Week by highlighting historic progress on climate</em></p>



<p>Today, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy held the eleventh meeting of the National Climate Task Force to launch a week of Administration actions leading up to Earth Day that build on President Biden’s historic progress to tackle the climate crisis and reduce emissions across every sector of the economy – furthering the President’s efforts to lower costs for families, advance environmental justice, and build an equitable clean energy future.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Task Force received a&nbsp;briefing&nbsp;from Dr. Kate Calvin, NASA Chief Scientist and Senior Climate Advisor&nbsp;and lead&nbsp;author&nbsp;on the&nbsp;recently-published IPCC Report on Climate Mitigation. The Task Force agreed that the findings are clear&nbsp;and compelling&nbsp;–&nbsp;the world&nbsp;must&nbsp;accelerate climate action&nbsp;and&nbsp;we have the tools to fight the climate crisis&nbsp;in every part of the economy. The Task Force discussed further how the Administration’s efforts were aligned with the IPCC’s findings — focused on tackling emissions&nbsp;sector-by-sector&nbsp;by deploying record amounts of clean energy;&nbsp;electrifying our cars, trucks, and buses;&nbsp;decarbonizing industrial processes; and&nbsp;phasing&nbsp;down super-polluting HFCs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Since last Earth Day 2021, the Biden Administration has turbocharged the American offshore wind industry, jumpstarted our electric transportation future, helped weatherize homes to save families money, enlisted nature in the fight against climate change, and more – all while advancing environmental justice and creating good-paying, union jobs. The&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/climate/">National Climate Task Force</a>&nbsp;microsite has been updated to reflect these Administration accomplishments and continued climate action.<br>&nbsp;<br>Task Force members also discussed&nbsp;the importance of meeting&nbsp;Americans where they are&nbsp;and ensuring the benefits of deploying clean energy reach every community and corner of the country.&nbsp;Energy Secretary Granholm reiterated the President’s commitment to&nbsp;minimizing pain at the pump&nbsp;caused&nbsp;by President Putin’s unprovoked war against Ukraine,&nbsp;and&nbsp;Infrastructure Coordinator Landrieu emphasized the importance of helping&nbsp;all communities&nbsp;– particularly rural and disadvantaged –&nbsp;realize the benefits of the President’s&nbsp;historic infrastructure investments.<br>&nbsp;<br>As outlined by President Biden’s January 27&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/">Executive Order on Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad</a>, the Task Force is chaired by the National Climate Advisor and includes Cabinet-level leaders from more than 25 federal agencies to mobilize the Biden-Harris Administration’s implementation of a whole-of-government approach.<br>&nbsp;<br>Task Force membership is comprised of the following government officials:</p>



<ul><li>National Climate Advisor (Chair)</li><li>Secretary of the Treasury</li><li>Secretary of Defense</li><li>Attorney General</li><li>Secretary of the Interior</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture</li><li>Secretary of Commerce</li><li>Secretary of Education</li><li>Secretary of Labor</li><li>Secretary of Health and Human Services</li><li>Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Secretary of Transportation</li><li>Secretary of Energy</li><li>Secretary of Homeland Security</li><li>Administrator of General Services</li><li>CEO of AmeriCorps</li><li>Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality</li><li>Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration</li><li>Administrator of the Small Business Administration</li><li>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</li><li>Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs</li><li>Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism</li><li>Assistant to the President for Economic Policy<br>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 18,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/18/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-18-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2022 00:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 4:07 P.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; (The Easter Bunny enters the room and stands at the podium.) MS. PSAKI:&#160; Who knows who&#8217;s under here?&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; No more bunny business.&#160; (The Easter Bunny leaves the podium.) That&#8217;s the line we worked on.&#160; Do you guys like it?&#160; (Laughter.) Thank you for joining us,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>4:07 P.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><em>(The Easter Bunny enters the room and stands at the podium.)</em><br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Who knows who&#8217;s under here?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No more bunny business.&nbsp;<br><br><em>(The Easter Bunny leaves the podium.)</em><br><br>That&#8217;s the line we worked on.&nbsp; Do you guys like it?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Thank you for joining us, Easter Bunny.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there sticks and carrots?&nbsp;<br><br>(Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oooh &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Ooh, Kelly, coming with the fire today.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I like it.<br><br>Okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; A couple of items for you at the top.&nbsp; Happy Tax Day to those who celebrate, which we hope is everyone in the room.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, bring back the bunny.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; As part of Tax Day, we&#8217;re highlighting the real difference between the President and congressional Republicans.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden has a simple philosophy: The middle class deserves some financial breathing room, which is why his economic plan would give tax relief to tens of millions of families &#8212; families who work hard and deserve a little extra cushion each month.<br><br>And the President believes billionaires should pay their fair share so we can invest in our economic future and cut the deficit.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he&#8217;s calling on the top 1 percent of the top 1 percent to pay the minimum tax of 20 percent, when, right now, the wealthiest families can pay a lower average rate than teachers.<br><br>And let me be crystal clear: The President will not raise taxes for anyone making under $400,000.&nbsp;<br><br>The congressional Republican plan, however, as Senator Rick Scott outlined, couldn&#8217;t be more different.&nbsp; Republicans on Capitol Hill are more than happy to pass a nearly $2 trillion tax giveaway to the wealthy and big corporations under the previous &#8212; they were, under the previous administration.&nbsp;<br><br>But now, led by Senator Scott, Republicans want to raise taxes on the middle class, with one independent analysis showing their plan would hike taxes by an average of around $1,500 each year on 75 million American families, 96 percent of whom make under $100,000.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the plan of congressional Republicans: tax hikes for the middle class; tax hikes for the wealthy and big corporations.<br><br>President Biden disagrees.&nbsp; It&#8217;s time to put the middle class first.<br><br>Tomorrow, as you may know, the President is traveling to New Hampshire to highlight infrastructure investments to modernize our nation&#8217;s ports and waterways, and discuss how these investments will strengthen our supply chain, support local economies, and help cut costs for American families.<br><br>American ports are a cornerstone of the United States economy, but outdated infrastructure in the COVID-19 pandemic have strained their capacity and jeopardized global supply chains, which has caused delays and passed costs directly to consumers.<br><br>Thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we now have $17 billion to upgrade, repair, and maintain our nation&#8217;s port infrastructure.<br><br>As the President continues to use every tool to help bring down prices for Americans, investments that strengthen domestic supply chains and move goods faster and more efficiently are critical to lowering costs for families.&nbsp;<br><br>So, during his trip tomorrow, he will visit Portsmouth Harbor, which is the only deep-water harbor in New Hampshire and handles approximately 3.[5] million tons and nearly $2 billion of cargo a year, including critical materials to support the local economy and clean energy production.<br><br>The port recently completed a project to widen the harbor’s turning basin and will receive funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to maintain safe and efficient operations along the channel &#8212; both crucial projects to accommodate larger ships and heavier loads of cargo.<br><br>I also wanted to note &#8212; a bunch of scheduling things today &#8212; today, we are pleased to announce that we will co-host the second Global [COVID] 19 Summit virtually on May 12th, alongside Belize, Germany, Indonesia, and Senegal.<br><br>The virtual summit will redouble our efforts to end the acute phase of the pandemic and prepare for future pandemics and other health threats.<br><br>Our role in co-hosting this summit continues to highlight &#8212; is to continue to highlight American leadership in the global COVID response, with our provision to date of more than $19 billion in health, humanitarian, and economic assistance, and our commitment to provide 1.2 billon vaccine doses to the world for free, of which we have already delivered more than 500 million doses.<br><br>And while we are dedicated to continuing to lead the global COVID response, we also need Congress to urgently do its part to fund the global COVID response.<br><br>We have requested a supplemental funding package for our most urgent needs to get shots into the arms and to provide lifesaving tests, treatments, and supplies.&nbsp; And we will obviously continue to work with Congress on getting that funding when they return.<br><br>Finally, I wanted to &#8212; last thing is that we also announced that on&nbsp;<s>March</s>&nbsp;[May] 12th and 13th, the President will host the leaders of the ASEAN in Washington, D.C.&nbsp; It will build on President Biden’s participation in the October 2021 U.S.-ASEAN Summit, where the President announced $102 million in new initiatives to expand our engagement with ASEAN on COVID-19, promoting economic growth and more.<br><br>And this will, of course &#8212; we’ll have more to preview as we get closer to that trip.<br><br>Josh, why don’t you kick us off?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Happy Monday.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Happy Monday.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two subject areas.&nbsp; First, a federal judge in Florida says the CDC exceeded its authority with the mask mandate in airports.&nbsp; What’s the White House position?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The CDC recommended continuing the order for additional time &#8212; two weeks &#8212; to be able to assess the latest science in keeping with its responsibility to protect the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>So, this is obviously a disappointing decision.&nbsp; The CDC continues recommending wearing a mask in public transit.&nbsp; As you know, this just came out this afternoon.&nbsp; So, right now, the Department of Homeland Security, who would be implementing, and the CDC are reviewing the decision.&nbsp; And, of course, the Department of Justice would make any determinations about litigation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secondly, Russia is expected to virtually attend meetings of the IMF and World Bank this week.&nbsp; Is that appropriate, given the actions in Ukraine?&nbsp; And how should international organizations treat Russia?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President has made clear that he does not believe we should be operating as business as usual.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s made clear about his concerns about their participation in the G20.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;d also note that our representative there, the Secretary of Treasury, has made clear that she isn&#8217;t planning to attend events or meetings that the Russians are participating in.&nbsp; But in terms of other determinations beyond that, I don&#8217;t have any further comment.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question on this move to restart the sale of leases for drilling on public lands.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How long do you think it will take for these new leases to actually start producing?&nbsp; And what impact do you think this might have on gas prices?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say that today&#8217;s action &#8212; as you know, but for everybody &#8212; was the result of a court injunction that we continue to appeal.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not in line with the President&#8217;s policy, which was to ban additional leasing because, one, we need to move towards a more clean energy economy, which he strongly believes in, but also because there are 9,000 permits, unused, on lands that could be tapped into by oil companies, and we don&#8217;t feel they are needed.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of how long it will take to get up drilling because of the court action, I don&#8217;t have any assessment on that from here.&nbsp; I would just note that we are going to continue to fight this court injunction that is forcing our hand in allowing this to proceed, even as we have taken actions to reduce by 80 percent the areas to lease and impose stringent environmental standards.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the President has promised to slash greenhouse gas emissions in half by 2030.&nbsp; Now you&#8217;re having to expand production of fossil fuels when you promised to curtail them.&nbsp; Congress, as we know, has yet to act on many of your climate proposals.<br><br>Is the President&#8217;s ambitious climate change goal and agenda still attainable, or are these new leases going to undercut that pledge?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, these leases are not in line with our policy or the President&#8217;s view.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But whether it’s your, you know, policy or not, I mean, this is the situation that you&#8217;re in.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue &#8212; there&#8217;s &#8212; there is &#8212; obviously, we&#8217;re going to continue to fight this legal action.<br><br>But I would say that, you know, the President remains committed.&nbsp; Addressing the climate crisis is one of the four pillars that he came in &#8212; he ran on as President and he will continue to fight for.<br><br>One of the reasons that this was so troubling to him is because he is so committed to that &#8212; that objective as President.&nbsp; And we continue to propose &#8212; have continued to propose a historic investment in addressing the climate crisis, something that we will continue to discuss with Congress.<br><br>So, there are a lot of ways to get there that we will continue to work with Congress to take actions, but he has also not hesitated to take actions himself through his own authorities to take actions to help our climate.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212; but are you still confident that goal is achievable?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are continuing to pursue it, and we are going to continue to do everything we can to reach it.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Steve.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; Oh, thank you.&nbsp; House Minority Leader Kevin McCarthy is saying President Putin probably would have backed off from invading Ukraine if President Biden had shipped weapons to Ukraine sooner.&nbsp; Does the President feel he should have acted sooner?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I mean, just for facts’ sake, we sent a record amount of security assistance to Ukraine during President Biden&#8217;s first year in office &#8212; more than any other president in history &#8212; and we shared a significant amount of intelligence with Ukraine about Russia&#8217;s intentions and military movements, as you all know because we&#8217;ve talked about it in here: $3.2 billion total, $2.6 billion since this conflict started.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s in direct contrast with our predecessor who withheld hundreds of millions of dollars in military aid from Ukraine, including Javelins, which Mr. McCarthy, who was critical of us in this moment, defended at the time as, quote, “the rightful thing to do” because he claimed people believed there was corruption in the Zelenskyy administration.<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t know if that’s a question for us as much as a question for him &#8212; what has changed in that period of time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, secondly, are you planning more sanctions this week on Russia, more oligarchs?&nbsp; What can you tell us?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are continuing to review and consider additional sanctions.&nbsp; It&#8217;s been an ongoing process.&nbsp; But right now, you will &#8212; so you will see us continue to expand our sanctions targets and to continue to take steps to both further tighten our sanctions to prevent evasion and put in place additional sanctions.&nbsp;<br><br>I also wanted to note a couple of comments for anyone with questions &#8212; which probably isn&#8217;t anyone in this room, but maybe &#8212; whether these sanctions are having an impact.&nbsp; One is by the chairwoman of the Russian national &#8212; central bank, who said these sanctions are &#8212; quote, “will now begin to increasingly affect the real sectors of the economy,” and, quote, “practically every product.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>She also said that, quote, “that sanctions are being tightened almost every day,” and, quote, “the period during which the economy can live on reserves is finite,” meaning these are really having the squeeze that the President, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Treasury, and others have conveyed.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But we are continuing to review, and I expect we&#8217;ll have more in the coming days.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to quickly follow up on the mask mandate being voided by this judge, what is the White House&#8217;s assessment of what that means for travelers today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it just happened this afternoon.&nbsp; And so, the Department of Homeland Security is over &#8212; obviously oversees the implementation of this, and they&#8217;re reviewing it as we speak.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it&#8217;s still in place right now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They are doing it as we speak.&nbsp; It just came out this afternoon.&nbsp; And if there any updates while I&#8217;m out here, I&#8217;m sure we can provide them to all of you.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And President Zelenskyy told Jake Tapper yesterday that he wants President Biden to visit Ukraine and he believes that he will.&nbsp; You said last week there were no plans being made for President Biden to go.&nbsp; Is that still the case?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That has not changed.&nbsp; What our focus continues to be on is providing Ukraine, the Ukrainian government, and Ukrainian leaders a historic amount of security assistance &#8212; assistance that&#8217;s been adapted based on their needs and their successes on the grounds.&nbsp; And, obviously, that can be attributed largely to the courage and the bravery of Ukrainian leaders.&nbsp; But the second reason is because of the military assistance we provided.&nbsp;<br><br>I would note, because I know this is an understandable question you all have asked, that if anyone were to go &#8212; there&#8217;s no plans for the President to go, so let me just reiterate that &#8212; but we would not outline from here or anywhere from the government who, if, and when for security reasons.&nbsp; So we wouldn&#8217;t have any details to preview regardless.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President considering granting President Zelenskyy’s request to make Russia a state sponsor of terrorism?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So that is a process that &#8212; it&#8217;s an authority that obviously exists within the government and at the State Department.&nbsp; And in order, just broadly speaking, for any country to be designated a state sponsor of terror &#8212; and there&#8217;s only&nbsp;<s>three</s>&nbsp;[four] &#8212; North Korea,&nbsp;<s>Sudan</s>&nbsp;[Syria], and Iran &#8212; at this point in time, just for your full perspective &#8212; the Secretary of State would need to determine the government of that country has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.&nbsp; And these, of course, designations are made after careful review.<br><br>So while we have those authorities, I don&#8217;t have any update on that or prediction of that; that assessment would be made by the State Department.<br><br>What I would note, which I think is important, is that for the countries that have been designated state sponsors of terrorism &#8212; so I named a couple of them for you &#8212; that the four main categories of sanctions that result from designation under these authorities include restrictions on U.S. foreign assistance, a ban on defense exports and sales, certain controls over exports of dual-use items, and other financial restrictions.&nbsp;<br><br>And what we&#8217;ve already done to date is, of course, impose significant financial sanctions, export controls, and curtailed restrictions on financial assistance.&nbsp; So when you&#8217;re thinking about the impact, these are already a lot of steps that we&#8217;ve taken.&nbsp;<br><br>But I have nothing to predict on that front.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a &#8212; that’s a process that would have to be reviewed through the State Department.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And last question.&nbsp; Russia warned the United States last week to stop arming Ukraine or it will risk “unpredictable consequences.”&nbsp; What does the U.S. believe those consequences would be?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not going to comment.&nbsp; I mean, I&#8217;m not going to speculate on empty threats or threats by President Putin or by Russian leadership.&nbsp; What we have done here is done exactly what the President said we would do from the beginning, which is to &#8212; if they invaded, we would be providing significant security assistance, economics assistance, and support to the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to do exactly that.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to belabor this only because we&#8217;ve heard from the airlines, from airport passengers; there may be people sitting at an airport bar watching right now, wondering: If they&#8217;re boarding a flight tonight, is the mask mandate still in place?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to recommend people wear masks.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update.&nbsp; This just came out through the courts just this afternoon.&nbsp; And as soon as there is an update, we will provide that to all of you.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the White House anticipating an announcement by Homeland Security tonight?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They are assessing it right now.&nbsp; And as soon as they have an assessment and an update on additional steps, they&#8217;ll make that available.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if the DOJ, say, doesn&#8217;t stay the order tonight or first thing tomorrow morning, are passengers supposed to go maskless?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand why you&#8217;re asking, and certainly no one here is trying to provoke uncertainty with passengers.&nbsp; We also think the mask mandate should be in place and that it&#8217;s safer for individuals who are flying to continue to wear masks.<br><br>So we would say to anyone sitting out there: We&#8217;d recommend you wear masks on the airplane.&nbsp; And then, as soon as we can provide an update from here &#8212; hopefully soon &#8212; we&#8217;ll provide that to all of you.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two more related CDC things.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the ruling, the judge said that she accepts the CDC’s argument that masks limit COVID spread, but that alone is not sufficient to overcome what she concludes is a rule that exceeds the agency&#8217;s authority to put it in place.&nbsp; The administration believes otherwise.&nbsp; Right?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, otherwise we wouldn&#8217;t have put it in place to begin with.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, that, potentially, is the crux of an appeal or an attempt to stop it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, I would leave that to the Department of Justice.&nbsp;<br><br>But all &#8212; what we &#8212; what we announced last week was just a two-week extension in order to have time to assess what we&#8217;ve all seen is rising cases, and make an assessment and recommendation with that in mind.&nbsp; So, of course, it&#8217;s disappointing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s another issue the CDC is in the middle of that&#8217;s troubling some Democrats, and that is, of course, the impending end of Title 42.&nbsp; Gary Peters, who chairs the Homeland Security Committee &#8212; another Democratic senator – today, suggesting he has doubts about ending Title 42, says that Secretary Mayorkas is scheduled to be there for a budget hearing, I believe later this month or next month.&nbsp; What more, though, is the administration sharing with these Democrats and Republicans, but notably a handful of Democrats who say they don&#8217;t see a firm plan, they want more details, and the administration seems to be rushing into this with no sense of what the repercussions could be?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to remember this is not an immigration authority &#8212; for anyone who has concerns about it &#8212; nor is it an immigration plan.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never said it was.&nbsp; It is a health authority that Congress gave the CDC authority to make a determination about, about whether it needs to stay in place or not.<br><br>There is no question we have a broken immigration system, there&#8217;s more we need to do.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been saying that from the first day the President took office.&nbsp; And anyone who wants to work on that &#8212; Democrats, Republicans, anyone &#8212; how we can put smarter security in place, how we can have an asylum processing system that works, we would love to do that.<br><br>But what they&#8217;re &#8212; what is happening right now is they&#8217;re essentially holding hostage funding for COVID.&nbsp; And we are going to run out of funding &#8212; we&#8217;re already running out of funding &#8212; for key programs.&nbsp; So our issue here is let&#8217;s move forward with the COVID funding.&nbsp; We&#8217;re happy to have a discussion about the broken immigration system.&nbsp; We agree it&#8217;s broken.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s work together on addressing that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You say that because there&#8217;s this amendment to the COVID plan &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that’s the &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that would put it in place?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I say that because that&#8217;s the root issue here, isn&#8217;t it?&nbsp; I mean, anyone who&#8217;s raising concerns, they&#8217;re tying it to &#8212; they&#8217;re tying it to the COVID funding.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Republicans are, but you got a handful of Democrats who aren&#8217;t necessarily supportive of that amendment.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I understand that, but we&#8217;re also happy to work with anyone on immigration reform and any concerns they have.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it sounds like the answer is, “If you&#8217;ve got concerns, you, Congress, do something about it.”<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not “here’s what happens on May 25th, once Title 42 is gone.”<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President put forward a bill his first day in office.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not “you do something about it.”&nbsp; Let&#8217;s work together on it.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re happy to do that.&nbsp; You have different ideas, you want to talk about how to move this forward?&nbsp; Let&#8217;s do that.<br><br>At the same time, what&#8217;s happening is this COVID funding, which means people who are uninsured are not going to be able to get access to treatments, to vaccines &#8212; we&#8217;re going &#8212; and we&#8217;re not going to be able to get the fourth booster shot to everybody.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to be able to get the treatments for immunocompromised.&nbsp;<br><br>So that&#8217;s where we&#8217;re at.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why it&#8217;s important to move that funding for it.&nbsp; And, yes, our system is broken.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s address it.&nbsp; But this is a health authority, not an immigration authority.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; You said about this mask ruling out of a federal court in Florida that it&#8217;s a “disappointing decision,” and you say you continue to recommend that people wear masks.&nbsp; Why is it that we can sit here in the White House briefing room with no masks, but people can&#8217;t sit in an airplane cabin with no masks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, I&#8217;m not a doctor.&nbsp; You&#8217;re not a doctor &#8212; that I&#8217;m aware of.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re a doctor, I wasn&#8217;t aware of that today &#8212; until today.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can confirm.&nbsp; Right.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, not a doctor.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;Just making sure.&nbsp; I don’t know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Nor do you play one on TV.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nor does he play one on TV.&nbsp; There you go. &nbsp;Most days.</p>



<p>But these determinations &#8212; remember the masking guidance is &#8212; there are &#8212; is green, yellow, and red.&nbsp; We are currently in a green zone in Washington, D.C., so they’re not recommending it.</p>



<p>Some people can still wear a mask if they want to &#8212; many people do &#8212; or wear them in meetings or wear them at certain times where you&#8217;re going to be around or sitting close to people, or maybe you have an immunocompromised parent or &#8212; or friend.&nbsp; And so people make that decision.</p>



<p>And there’s &#8212; this is based on health considerations and data that the CDC looks at about transmissibility as &#8212; as we’ve seen an increase in cases on &#8212; on airplanes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, would the President support if a flight is leaving from an airport in a green zone, those people don&#8217;t have to wear masks?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, Peter, there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s been long a difference from the beginning about people on an airplane and in federal transportation vehicles and situations than where they are in locations, like we here &#8212; here continue to be, in Washington, D.C., a green zone.</p>



<p>But what we had asked for &#8212; I think it&#8217;s important to remember &#8212; is a two-week extension &#8212; or not asked for &#8212; what we had announced was a two-week extension to look at the data and make recommendations based on the data and the science about whether it should be continued or not.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On a different topic, we have new reporting that at least 23 people apprehended at the southern border in 2021 are on the terror watchlist.&nbsp; Why do you guys think it is that somebody on a terror watchlist would want to get into the United States undetected?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t make an assessment of that.&nbsp; But what I can tell you is that your data you&#8217;re citing here, it means the Border Patrol was doing their job.&nbsp; I mean, they &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212; so, sixty-two- &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; they apprehended people at the border.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; -two thousand illegal immigrants a day got away last month.&nbsp; Are you saying that you can say with certainty none of them are on a terror watchlist?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Here&#8217;s what we&#8217;re talking about: Encounters, we know, and &#8212; of suspected terrorists attempting to cross the southern border, they&#8217;re very uncommon. &nbsp;We&#8217;re talking about a few dozen annual encounters at most &#8212; at most.&nbsp; And these encounters represent significantly less than the .01 percent of total encounters per fiscal year in recent years.</p>



<p>But I&#8217;d note: These individuals, these 23 people &#8212; the Border Patrol, they stopped them.&nbsp; They prevented them from getting into the country.&nbsp; They&#8217;re protecting our homeland and keeping us safe.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the President is not worried about holes in the southern border being exploited by people trying to come in and kill Americans?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He’s grateful to the Border Patrol for doing their job and &#8212; and stopping these people and preventing them from getting into the country.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one additional question about something that happened a few months ago down at the border: We&#8217;ve been told that the mounted Border Patrol officers the President accused of whipping migrants have been notified they will not face criminal charges.&nbsp; So, when is the President going to apologize to them?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There is a process and an investigation that&#8217;s gone to the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said that they were whipping people, which would be a criminal offense.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve been told they&#8217;re not going to be criminally charged.&nbsp; So will the President &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And there was an investigation into that.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll let the Department of Homeland Security announce any conclusion of that investigation.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You accused these officers of brutal and inappropriate measures.&nbsp; Now that they&#8217;ve been told they will not be criminally charged, will you apologize to them?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And, Peter, there was an investigation into their behavior, so that investigation is playing out.&nbsp; Whenever there &#8212; it&#8217;s going to be announced, the Department of Homeland Security will announce that.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;m sure we&#8217;ll have a comment on it after that.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back on the mask issue: As the debate is going on about next steps, is there any concern in the White House that this issue &#8212; now that there are some Americans who are aware of this ruling by the Florida judge &#8212; that it could prompt some of the tensions we&#8217;ve seen on airplanes in recent months until there&#8217;s a resolution?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, Kelly, it&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; Obviously, what we&#8217;re trying to do &#8212; what we would encourage is calm in all cases.&nbsp; And because this ruling just came out this afternoon, I know the objective of everybody involved and all the necessary authorities in government is to make a determination about next steps as quickly as possible.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s certainly our hope, and we want to do everything we can to prevent that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the oil leases: Does the President see any secondary benefit to the fact that even though this is not his policy objective, that there could be some additional production that could help, given the fact that gas prices are high and there has been a push to have additional production because of the war in Ukraine, even though it&#8217;s not his policy objective?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can tell you from talking with him about this this morning, he does not.&nbsp; He believes that, as he announced and &#8212; he remains committed to the ban he called for on the expansion of &#8212; of leasing on federal lands, in part because he wants to move toward a clean energy economy &#8212; and he&#8217;s very committed to that &#8212; and address climate change, but also because there&#8217;s 9,000 unused leases that can be tapped into and used.&nbsp; And we certainly have encouraged oil companies to do that to help address, exactly as you said, the need to get more supply in the marketplace.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he see this move by the Department of Interior as a &#8212; going against his campaign pledge?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he sees &#8212; he knows that it was the result of a court injunction, as you heard Secretary Haaland say.&nbsp; And so it was &#8212; her hands were tied in many ways, as they can be, by legal &#8212; by legal requirements.</p>



<p>But what they did, which he certainly supported, was take steps to reduce by 80 percent the areas to lease.&nbsp; And they also imposed stringent environmental safeguards in order to take additional steps, even as the court injunction made them take this &#8212; these steps.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You did not mention Cuba as a state sponsor of terror. &nbsp;Should we read into that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I did not mean to not mention them.&nbsp; I wanted to cite some examples, just to give people a sense of how few there are and what kinds of countries.&nbsp; I wasn&#8217;t meant to &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re not lifting them.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not announcing new policy.&nbsp; No, I’m not.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m not announcing new policy.&nbsp; I just wanted to give an indication of what that is and how limited the number of countries are.</p>



<p>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; This is a question that comes from one of my colleagues who&#8217;s reporting in Ukraine right now.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He is wondering, you know, as conditions in Mariupol continue to disintegrate, is the United States considering any creative ways to help the Ukrainians who are under siege &#8212; for instance, sending in third-country planes or planes from a neutral organization like the Red Cross to get relief in there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, you mean humanitarian relief?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are engaged with surrounding countries, with aid organizations about a range of ways to get aid and assistance in.&nbsp; And, obviously, from the start of this, if there was &#8212; if there was an allowance or an implementation of these humanitarian corridors, it would have helped enable.&nbsp; But we can&#8217;t talk about a lot of those things from here.&nbsp; But we are going to continue to take steps to provide humanitarian assistance in every way that we can.</p>



<p>I would note &#8212; you didn&#8217;t ask this question, but just one other little update: There were four planes that arrived, of military assistance, over the course of the weekend.&nbsp; Another one tod- &#8212; is supposed to arrive today, if it hasn&#8217;t already, from the $800 million package the President announced.&nbsp; So just to give you a sense of our efforts to continue to get more assistance in.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And completely unrelated, but today on a background call about climate policy, an administration official said that the White House is in touch with a wide range of members of Congress about a reconciliation package.&nbsp; So are negotiations ongoing for Build Back Better or Building a Better America or whatever you&#8217;re calling it now?&nbsp; And are you talking about it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We &#8212; we are talking about it, whatever you call it &#8212; a reconciliation package &#8212; including getting a historic investment in climate; including lowering the cost of childcare, eldercare, and healthcare &#8212; taking all of these steps that the President has been committed to.&nbsp; These conversations have been ongoing over the course of the last several months.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And are those &#8212; is Joe Manchin involved in those conversations?&nbsp; Who are you talking to?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking to everybody across the board.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to name all the names, but they&#8217;re all included &#8212; Democrats across the board who want to get this done.<br><br>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the U.S. moving any closer to reopening its embassy in Kyiv now that Spain is joining France, Italy, and others in doing so?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly that&#8217;s our objective &#8212; is to open it.&nbsp; But what we &#8212; what we are evaluating is, obviously, security considerations and when the State Department is prepared to do that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; and we look at, kind of, who should go first and how many &#8212; and how many people and when.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s all done through the State Department.&nbsp; And they make those initial recommendations about when to return.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that certainly is our objective.&nbsp; Obviously, having a diplomatic presence on the &#8212; on the ground is important.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more thing. &nbsp;President Zelenskyy says the Russians have begun their offensive to take control of eastern Ukraine.&nbsp; What is the administration&#8217;s assessment of what&#8217;s happening there now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know that my Defense Department colleague just did a briefing, so I&#8217;d really point you to the Department of Defense for any kind of on-the-ground updates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, on CBS, Senator Coons said that without the West coming more forcefully to Ukraine&#8217;s aid, he said, quote, “I deeply worry that…we will see Ukraine turn into Syria.”&nbsp; Does the President share that concern?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not words or a phrase the President would use or we would use from &#8212; from the United States.&nbsp; Obviously, what we&#8217;ve seen to date is the Ukrainians bravely fight back against the Russians and win, essentially, the Battle of Kyiv and continue to fight back against their efforts across the country.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve known and predicted that they would move their ground game to eastern Ukraine, which is exactly what they&#8217;ve done.&nbsp; And we also have known and predicted &#8212; and when &#8212; when Jake Sullivan was here just a week or two ago, he also conveyed that they were &#8212; that Moscow was likely to launch air and missile strikes across Ukraine to cause military and economic damage.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing in Lviv and other &#8212; and other places at this point in time.</p>



<p>But what we&#8217;ve seen, I think, is them behave bravely, with huge courage, and&nbsp;they have had the success in pushing back against the Russians because of that, but also because of the military assistance provided by the United States.&nbsp; So, no, we would not share that assessment.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on the diplomatic front, are &#8212; is the administration any closer to naming an ambassador to Ukraine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly understand the question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update on that at this point from here.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I want to ask about a story some of my colleagues reported earlier today.&nbsp; Some allies of former President Trump have been pressing for statehouses around the country to pass resolutions rescinding Electoral College votes for President Biden and to bring lawsuits that seek to prove baseless claims of large-scale voter fraud.&nbsp; Legal experts have called this effort “preposterous,” but is an organized push among those allies to decertify the last election something this administration is monitoring or concerned about?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that there have been dozens of court cases that have not been won by our predecessor and people who support him in an effort to overturn the outcome of the last election.&nbsp; And our focus is on governing for the American people, delivering for the American people, and less on focusing on what he and his people are up to.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to follow up on the question earlier regarding Senator Coons’s comments.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One of the points he was making was that the U.S. needs to have a conversation about sending U.S. troops to Ukraine.&nbsp; He told “Face the Nation” yesterday, quote, “The American people cannot turn away from this tragedy in Ukraine.&nbsp; I think the…21st century turns on how fiercely we defend freedom in Ukraine, and that Putin will only stop when we stop him.”&nbsp;<br><br>What &#8212; what&#8217;s the White House&#8217;s response to this suggestion from the Senator that the U.S. needs to start having a conversation about maybe sending troops to Ukraine?&nbsp; And does the President agree that Putin will stop when we, the U.S. &#8212; only when we, the U.S., stop him?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, what I would say is, one, Senator Coons is a close friend of the President’s and the administration, and we just respectfully disagree with his proposal.&nbsp;<br><br>The President continues to &#8212; has no plans to send troops to fight a war with Russia.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t think that&#8217;s in our national security interests, in the interest of the American people.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, what our focus has been on has been obviously providing this historic amount of security assistance &#8212; military assistance, weapons to the Ukrainians &#8212; that has helped them effectively fight this war and economic assistance as well.&nbsp; This is also strengthening their hand at the negotiating table, even while we are putting in place a historic package of economic sanctions that, as I noted earlier, even the head of the Russian Central Bank is noting the im- &#8212; the devastating impact of these sanctions on the Russian economy.&nbsp;<br><br>So, that has been our strategic focus.&nbsp; Of course, we support the Ukrainians in every way possible. &nbsp;But the President is not going to fight a war with Russia.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has done or will do a lot of travel in recent days to places where &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; so-called House “frontliners” are running for reelection.&nbsp; And I wanted to know if you could talk about how much political considerations are weighed or taken into consideration when the White House decides where to send the President.&nbsp; And also, if &#8212; what kind of an impact do you think, if any, will his discussion and promotion of things like the Infrastructure Law will have on voters this fall?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m always careful about what I get into about politics from here.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve learned my lesson.&nbsp; But what I will say is that the President is proud to go out in the country &#8212; in blue states, red states, purple states &#8212; to talk about his agenda, both what he has achieved, including the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law that is rebuilding roads, rails, and bridges, and &#8212; and in replacing lead pipes around the country, expanding broadband access across the country in communities, no matter what your political party is.&nbsp;<br><br>And he&#8217;s also proud to go out and talk about his economic agenda that he&#8217;s still fighting to get passed, which includes care, healthcare, eldercare, and reducing costs.&nbsp;<br><br>And his view is that for anyone out there, when they&#8217;re out there &#8212; senators or members of Congress who are going to be talking to their communities &#8212; that standing up for his agenda and standing up for this agenda that will make the American people&#8217;s lives better is a winning argument.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I would say: I wouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to overly note the political sway of districts or states, but he&#8217;s always said he wants to be the President for all people, govern for all people, and that means talking about his agenda in red, blue, and purple states.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, going back to coronavirus, some of us recently here and around the country have been taking home tests to diagnose ourselves.&nbsp; And when those come up positive, those aren&#8217;t always reported to public health.&nbsp; And sometimes they can&#8217;t be; sometimes they won&#8217;t even accept that.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you believe that we have an accurate sense of the spread of the coronavirus right now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what&#8217;s important to remember is that, one, CD- &#8212; what &#8212; how CDC continues to track COVID cases that are reported, they do it really through hospitalizations and deaths.&nbsp; And those numbers around severe disease come directly from hospitals and states.&nbsp; And what we&#8217;re seeing through those is that we&#8217;re at the lowest level of hospitalization since the start of the pandemic; I believe we&#8217;re still at that point in time.<br><br>So, we certainly encourage people to share their test results and contact their doctor, because they may be eligible for Paxlovid or any other therapeutics.&nbsp;<br><br>But, you know, beyond that, as I think I would note, when we put out the President&#8217;s 100-page plan, we noted that our focus was really on hospitalizations, deaths, and severe cases, even as we&#8217;re encouraging people to report testing for contact tracing and other purposes when they test positive.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Title 42, there is a bipartisan group of senators &#8212; including Sinema, Manchin; some who are at risk, including Senator Kelly &#8212; who say &#8212; who are proposing the idea of letting the Surgeon General certify when the public health emergency has ended.&nbsp; Is that something the President would consider?&nbsp; And then, why or why not?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the C- &#8212; Congress gave the CDC the authority.&nbsp; So &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But this would be a change in that, and I&#8217;m wondering if you&#8217;re open to that idea.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t have any prediction of that at this point.&nbsp; The CDC is the public health authority for the country, so I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any more predictions of that.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Japanese Prime Minister Kishida just announced Japan taking in a group of refugees, which is really a big deal for Japan.&nbsp; And the Foreign Minister, Hayashi, flew back a group of refugees from Poland to Japan.&nbsp; Is the administration aware of that?&nbsp;<br><br>And then also, with the trip to Japan next month, any update on whether an interview with the President is in the offing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, it’s an interview pitch.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I said, “Oh, an interview with whom?”&nbsp; I like your style.<br><br>We certainly welcome and applaud the actions of the &#8212; of Japan and the Japanese leadership, and are grateful to their steps in taking in refugees and their humanitarian support through this conflict.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re an important partner, as you know, and have been a part of important meetings on the conflict in Ukraine in recent months, including on the President&#8217;s last trip to Europe.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I will certainly take under advisement your request.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, Eugene.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; There have been kind of a growing &#8212; growing rumblings among economists about the “R” word &#8212; recession &#8212; that coming possibly &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The “R” word.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The “R” word. &nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; I was like, “Where are we going with this?”&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) you know, it’s a scary word for everybody.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; I guess I&#8217;m just curious how the administration is viewing the possibility of that and what kind of conversations are happening right now about a possible recession.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we continue to believe &#8212; our economists, most importantly &#8212; that the United States economy will deal with challenges ahead from a position of strength because of the President&#8217;s economic plan.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s important to remember we created more jobs last year than any year &#8212; other year in history.&nbsp; We obviously have a very low unemployment rate in the country, and we&#8217;ve seen wages go up in a number of areas.&nbsp;<br><br>I would note that there was a Goldman Sachs &#8212; you may be referring to this &#8212; the Goldman Sachs analysis.&nbsp; And even in their analysis, they said, quote, “We still do not see a recession as inevitable, however, particularly since the [Fed’s] goal of cooling the economy while avoiding a recession will be helped by post-COVID normalizations in labor supply and durable goods prices.”<br><br>So our view is we&#8217;re in a period of historic job growth, strong business investments, strong consumer and business balance sheets, and normalizing supply chains.&nbsp; Those are all good signs for the economy, but obviously, we will continue to monitor any &#8212; any concerns we have about where things are headed.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And as the &#8212; if inflation continues to rise, what are the concerns about that (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the Federal Reserve continues to project that it will moderate by the end of the year.&nbsp; And they &#8212; obviously, we support their steps they&#8217;ve announced to recalibrate, and we&#8217;ve already seen some of those actions taken. But, really, the &#8212; it&#8217;s under their purview, so we would point to their projections.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So just a follow-up on Title 42.&nbsp; The issue that Democratic senators have brought up is that there isn&#8217;t a detailed plan, they think, to deal with the expected rise in migrants at the border.&nbsp; So does the White House feel confident that the administration has the necessary resources and operational plan in place to process and house and transport migrants?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would point you to the fact that the Department of Homeland Security put out a plan that they briefed members on when we announced the timeline &#8212; or the implementation period &#8212; an extended period that wasn&#8217;t immediate &#8212; at the time.&nbsp; That includes surging resources and making sure we had the type of resources available to meet any needs.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, they did put out a preparedness plan at the time, but we&#8217;re going to have continuing conversations, and we certainly welcome any engagement to do that.&nbsp; Our issue is more the hooking it with COVID funding because of the devastating impact that would have on communities across the country.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And just&nbsp;another question on the Times op-ed that Senator Warren wrote today, saying that Democrats need to deliver on more of their agenda in order to keep the majorities in Congress.&nbsp; Do you agree with that premise?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And at this point, I know you named a few of the legislative priorities already in the briefing, but is &#8212; are there a top three priorities that the White House feels they can actually get done before the midterms?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We love all of our children in the legislature around here.&nbsp;<br><br>What I will say is that, you know, we&#8217;ve talked a bit about steps to lower costs &#8212; which I know Senator Warren, of course, strongly supports as well &#8212; for childcare, for healthcare, for eldercare, for prescription drugs; these are no-brainers for most people in the country.&nbsp; And also making the tax system more fair.&nbsp; We think those are all issues that Democrats, but also a lot of people around the country, would love for us to do more on and love to talk about more.&nbsp;<br><br>We, of course, as I&#8217;ve stated a couple times in this briefing, want to get COVID funding because we think it&#8217;s essential so that we can continue a lot of the programs that have had such a huge impact on people&#8217;s lives, including for the uninsured; including in making sure we have boosters for &#8212; fourth boosters for every American who wants them, whenever people are eligible; including being able to buy enough Evusheld and for &#8212; and treatments for the immunocompromised.&nbsp; That&#8217;s hugely important to us.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, of course, we &#8212; we want to get the Innovation Act passed because we believe that that&#8217;s something that should have bipartisan support.&nbsp; And we want to make sure we have manufacturing here in the United States, something that can make us stronger over the long term.&nbsp;<br><br>There are many other things, but I would say those are a couple of the things that we will continue to fight to move forward on.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you agree with the premise that the administration and Democrats in Congress needs to get more done in order to have a shot at the majority?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say I&#8217;m not going to make political predictions from here.&nbsp;<br><br>What I will say, though, is that everybody looks at a choice and what each party is fighting for, is advocating for, has gotten accomplished, but also what their vision is for the future.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re proud of our vision.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, to go back to the virtual COVID Summit &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you&#8217;ve mentioned, again, the need for Congress to improve COVID funding.&nbsp; Does the White House see that date, May 12th, for the summit as a deadline for Congress to get that funding approved?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t, but we just see it as a reminder of how important it is that &#8212; to continue to take steps to be the provider, the va- &#8212; the arsenal of vaccines to the world, something we have already done since the &#8212; since the last summit.<br><br>While the world has made significant progress in scaling up vaccination efforts, and COVI- &#8212; and COVAX has now provided almost 1.2 billion vaccines to more &#8212; COVAX, yes &#8212; to more than 140 countries, with 80 per- &#8212; 88 percent of those contributions going to low- and middle-income countries, we&#8217;re not at the global vaccination rate that we need to be or that health experts project we want to be at.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; It&#8217;s a 70 percent vaccination target.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the global target set by the World Health Organization.<br><br>And while vaccination rates are rising, only approximately 20 percent of countries are fully vaccinated &#8212; at least seven- &#8212; at least 70 percent of their population.&nbsp;<br><br>But this is an opportunity.&nbsp; Obviously, we&#8217;re going to continue to fight for more funding here.&nbsp; But we will &#8212; to continue to press other countries to do more to help the world make progress as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And along those lines, you know, we&#8217;ve heard USAID chief, Samantha Powers, say earlier this month that if there isn&#8217;t that global COVID funding &#8212; if Congress puts something together without it &#8212; that the U.S. would then turn its back on the countries that need urgent help to boost vaccination rates.&nbsp; Will it be difficult for the U.S. to take a lead at a summit like that if that funding has not come through?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we are far and away the leader in the world.&nbsp; That will not change between now and the summit, regardless of funding.<br><br>However, we want to continue to be, and continue to be providing not just vaccine doses, but also the know-how and equipment and supplies that countries around the world need.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, more mass shootings this past weekend.&nbsp; More mass shootings; two teenage boys dead, dozens injured.&nbsp; What does the President believe is causing such a callous disregard for human life in this country?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say &#8212; and thank you for the question &#8212; these shootings are horrific and must stop.&nbsp; Our prayers are with the survivors, those who are lost, and their families.&nbsp;<br><br>I can&#8217;t attribute &#8212; obviously, these &#8212; this just happened over the weekend &#8212; the reasoning.&nbsp; But what I can tell you is that it&#8217;s a reminder of the need to take more steps to stop gun crime, something the President has strongly supported and advocated for since &#8212; for decades in public office: cracking down on gun traffickers, putting more cops on the beat, investing in community anti-crime programs, and, of course, also confirming a very qualified individual, Steve Dettelbach, to lead the ATF.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But aside from laws, you know, what &#8212; does the President have in mind, if anything, a plan to improve, to get people to respect life more, to respect other human beings, laws aside?&nbsp; You can’t legislate morality and values &#8212; right? &#8212; human life.&nbsp; Does he have &#8212; does he ever talk about that openly to you or anyone else?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think every time that you’ve seen the President talk about shootings, the impact on families, on human beings, on loved ones, on communities, he talks about that human impact.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but it also is true that in order to reduce and change the direction of crime and gun crime, which is the majority of crime, we need to change &#8212; we need to have more laws in place.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Texas Governor Abbott said that, quote, “financial pain” was necessary to get officials to take action on illegal immigration.&nbsp; Is there any sense that those border inspections did cause financial pain, that there was any disruption in the supply chain or anything like that, that you all are tracking?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, while I don&#8217;t have an extended summary &#8212; summary analysis, what I do know is that you don&#8217;t have to look farther than the comments made by business leaders, trade organizations &#8212; of all political stripes and parties &#8212; and their opposition to the unnecessary additional steps that the governor was implementing.&nbsp;<br><br>And there&#8217;s $1 million in trade crossing over the U.S.-Mexico border every minute.&nbsp; So there&#8217;s no question that putting these unnecessary inspections in place &#8212; which resulted, at the time, in the drop in commercial traffic of up to 60 to 70 percent in some ports &#8212; was having a huge impact on the local community, on businesses.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why so many people were so outspoken about it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just quickly &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; do you have an update on the plan for Ukrainian refugees?&nbsp; Will it be a parole program like you have for Afghans, or any (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, I certainly understand the question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update in this moment.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly the type of program, but there are a lot of considerations, so hopefully we&#8217;ll have more soon.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Does President Biden have confidence in Senator Dianne Feinstein?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Does he have con- &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Confidence in Senator Dianne Feinstein.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, he&#8217;s &#8212; she’s a longtime friend, a proud public servant, and someone he has long enjoyed serving with and working with.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And after that report came out last week questioning her health, did the President reach out to her at all?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates on the President’s conversations.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.<br><br>4:54 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
