<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:48:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Security Assistance to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/03/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-security-assistance-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Pike County OperationsTroy, Alabama 2:03 P.M. CDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I tell you what, Linda: If I were CEO of this company, I’d be worried.&#160; (Laughter.) Well, good afternoon, everybody.&#160; And thank you, Jim, for the invitation to be here today and, Linda, for the warm welcome today.&#160; And Congressman Sewell &#8212; -woman Sewell,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Lockheed Martin Pike County Operations<br>Troy, Alabama</p>



<p>2:03 P.M. CDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I tell you what, Linda: If I were CEO of this company, I’d be worried.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Well, good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; And thank you, Jim, for the invitation to be here today and, Linda, for the warm welcome today.&nbsp; And Congressman Sewell &#8212; -woman Sewell, thank you for all you do for the people of this state and the country and for your friendship &#8212; our friendship.</p>



<p>I wanted to come down to Alabama to make sure that the American people know what workers at this &#8212;</p>



<p>And, by the way, if you have a seat, please take it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; By the way, sometimes &#8212; the press is always fair with me, but once &#8212; every once in a while, I make a mistake &#8212; not like &#8212; well, once a speech.</p>



<p>But, at any rate, I &#8212; years ago, when I first started talking to this &#8212; for this job, I said, “Please take your seats.”&nbsp; There weren’t any seats.&nbsp; Everyone was standing.&nbsp; There were no chairs.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; So, I just wanted to make sure I checked whether you had seats.</p>



<p>Look, the American people know what workers at this facility are doing and support &#8212; to support Ukraine’s fight for freedom.</p>



<p>And the bottom line is I came to say thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; That’s the reason I’m here.</p>



<p>I’ve been on those battlefields where these missiles are fired, and I spent a lot of time going in and out of Iraq and Afghanistan &#8212; maybe a total of 40 times.&nbsp; And I tell you what: You’re &#8212; and I’ve been in Ukraine a lot prior to the war and on the border since the war.&nbsp; And it’s &#8212; it’s amazing what you’ve done.</p>



<p>We see on the news every single day the atrocities and the war crimes that are being committed by Russian forces in Ukraine, directed by Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; And it really is gut-wrenching.</p>



<p>We see the incredible bravery of the Ukrainian fighters defending their country from ev- &#8212; with everything they have.&nbsp; And, by the way, it’s not just their warriors.&nbsp; It’s not just their military.&nbsp; It’s people in the street &#8212; people in the street, staying behind.&nbsp; A lot have gotten out &#8212; 5 million &#8212; but a lot are staying, including women as well as men, staying to fight for their country.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and we know that the United States is leading our Allies and partners around the world to make sure that courageous Ukrainians who are fighting for the future of their nation have the weapons and the capacity and ammunition and equipment to defend themselves against Putin’s brutal war.&nbsp; A lot of war crimes being committed.</p>



<p>But what we don’t &#8212; what we don’t see &#8212; we don’t always see &#8212; is the work that so much of &#8212; that makes so much of this possible.&nbsp; And that’s you.&nbsp; It’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; It’s you.&nbsp; You make it possible.&nbsp; You make it possible for them to have a shot.</p>



<p>You know, during World War Two, the United States was known as the arsenal of democracy.&nbsp; There was Rosie the Riveter &#8212; who I actually got to meet, quite frankly, before she passed away &#8212; and a lot of people who, in fact, kept the &#8212; kept it going.</p>



<p>I was &#8212; a slight digression &#8212; I went over for the 50th anniversary of the &#8212; the end of World War Two.&nbsp; And I was in Normandy, and I went up afterwards with the &#8212; to the cemetery.&nbsp; And I was walking by myself.&nbsp; And it’s &#8212; it’s incredible.&nbsp; It’s immaculate.&nbsp; It’s perfectly manicured, and the headstones are all the same.</p>



<p>I looked down one row, and I saw three names &#8212; same names.&nbsp; A father and two sons who had died in the landing.&nbsp; And I was bent down, and I was reading the dates of their birth.&nbsp; And all of a sudden, I heard behind me, “Attention!”&nbsp; And I turned around and there was a gentleman who had to be in his early 80s, in a wheelchair, being wheeled by his son who &#8212; big guy &#8212; looked like Hoss Cartwright &#8212; and his &#8212; and his wife and one of their &#8212; and a daughter.</p>



<p>And he saluted me, so I saluted him, and &#8212; at the time.&nbsp; And I turned around, and I said, “Thank you for what you did.&nbsp; Thank you for saving &#8212; literally saving civilization.”</p>



<p>And he put his hand on his wife’s &#8212; his wife &#8212; his hand was on her shoulder.&nbsp; And he said, “No, no.&nbsp; She did it.&nbsp; She did it.”</p>



<p>And I looked at her, and he said, “She built the landing craft that got us in here.&nbsp; She and her friends &#8212; they’re the ones that did it.”&nbsp; And he went on.&nbsp; And he filled up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all of a sudden, it dawned on me: You’re doing it.&nbsp; You really are doing it.&nbsp; You’re making a gigantic difference for these poor sons of guns who are under such enormous, enormous pressure and firepower.</p>



<p>Those Javelins I saw &#8212; there’s 10 for every tank that there is in Ukraine right now.&nbsp; You’re changing people’s lives.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We built the weapons &#8212; no, you really do.&nbsp; But we built the weapons and the equipment that helped defend freedom and sovereignty in Europe years ago.&nbsp; But that’s true again today.</p>



<p>You know, some of the best, most effective weapons in our arsenal are those Javelin missiles, like the ones manufactured right here in Pike County.</p>



<p>They’re highly portable.&nbsp; They’re extremely effective against a wide range of armored targets.&nbsp; They can hit targets up to <s>400</s> [4,000] meters away and have a “fire-and-forget” capability.&nbsp; That means the person firing can &#8212; and I know you know it, but for anybody who may be listening &#8212; can change positions or take cover before that Javelin even strikes home and strikes the target.</p>



<p>In fact, they’ve been so important there’s even a story about Ukrainian parents naming their children &#8212; not a joke &#8212; their newborn child “Javelin” or “Javelina.”&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>So, the brave people of Ukraine, including the many civilians who have taken up arms to defend their country, deserve every ounce of credit for pushing back the Russian assault and frustrating Putin’s desire to dominate Ukraine.</p>



<p>We’re at an inflection point in history, for real &#8212; it comes along about every six or eight generations &#8212; where things are changing so rapidly that we have to be in control.</p>



<p>Folks, there’s an ongoing battle in the world between autocracy and democracy.&nbsp; Xi Jinping, the leader of China, who I’ve talked &#8212; I’ve spent more time with than any other world leader has &#8212; over 78 hours on the &#8212; either in person or on the telephone with him.&nbsp; And the fact of the matter is he just is straightforward about it.&nbsp; He says that democracies cannot be sustained in the 21st century.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; They cannot be sustained &#8212; because things are moving so rapidly, democracies require consensus, and it’s hard to get consensus, therefore they can’t keep up with an autocracy &#8212; one-man rule.</p>



<p>But that’s not going to be the case.&nbsp; If that happens, the whole world changes.</p>



<p>And because of you &#8212; in this first, really, battle, if you will &#8212; for that to determine whether that’s going to happen is because you’re making it possible.&nbsp; You’re making it possible for the Ukrainian people to defend themselves without us having to risk getting in a third world war by sending in American soldiers fighting Russian soldiers.<br><br>My dad used to have an expression.&nbsp; He’d say, “The only war worse than one that’s intended is one that’s unintended.”<br><br>You’re allowing the Ukrainians to defend themselves.&nbsp; And, quite frankly, they’re making fools of the Russian military in many instances.</p>



<p>A big part of the reason they’ve been able to keep on fighting and to make this war a strategic failure for Russia is because the United States, together with our Allies and partners, have had their back.</p>



<p>The United States alone has committed more than 5,500 Javelins to Ukraine.&nbsp; You’re changing the nation.&nbsp; You really are.&nbsp; Add to that significant supplies from our Allies and partners, as well as many thousands of other anti-tank and anti-air weapons, helicopters, armored vehicles, artillery, coastal defense systems.</p>



<p>Before Russia attacked, we made sure <s>Russia</s> [Ukraine] had Javelins and other weapons to strengthen their defenses so Ukraine was ready for whatever happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in the last two months, we continued to move even more resources and equipment at a rapid pace into Ukraine.&nbsp; We’ve made sure that there are no interruptions in the flow of equipment to Ukraine.</p>



<p>Since Russia invaded Ukraine just over two months ago, we have sent more than $3 billion in security assistance to Ukraine &#8212; alone, us &#8212; not counting our Allies.&nbsp; And that money is a direct investment in defending freedom and democracy itself.</p>



<p>Because if you don’t stand up to dictators, history has shown us they keep coming.&nbsp; They keep coming. &nbsp;Their appetite for power continues to grow.</p>



<p>And every worker in this facility and every American taxpayer is directly contributing to the case for freedom.&nbsp; And that’s something we can all be incredibly proud of, in my view.</p>



<p>Last week, I sent Congress &#8212; if you excuse a point of personal privilege, talking like an old senator &#8212; but I sent a supplemental budget &#8212; a fancy way of saying we need more money &#8212; to make sure the United States can continue to send weapons directly to the frontlines of freedom in Ukraine and to continue to provide economic and humanitarian assistance to help the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>And I urge the Congress to pass this funding quickly to help Ukraine continue to succeed against Russian aggression, just as they did when they won the Battle of Kyiv, and to make sure the United States and our Allies can replenish our own stocks of weapons to replace what we’ve sent to Ukraine.</p>



<p>As I said from the beginning, this fight is not going to be cheap, but caving to aggression would even be more costly.<br><br>We either back the Ukrainian people as they defend their country or stand by as Russia continues its atrocities and aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know what my answer is, and I think you all do too.&nbsp; I bet I know what the answer of this plant is.</p>



<p>There’s something else here that &#8212; to be understand.&nbsp; Being the arsenal of democracy also means good-paying jobs for American workers in Alabama and the states all across America where defense equipment is manufactured and assembled.</p>



<p>Two hundred and sixty-five people here at this plant are directly employed working on the Javelin program.&nbsp; All told, Lockheed Martin has brought nearly 3,000 jobs to Alabama.</p>



<p>The Armed Forces of the United States of America is going to continue to be the best-armed, most capable fighting force in the history of the world.</p>



<p>In order to do that, we have to make sure our vital defense <s>supplies</s> [suppliers] are getting the inputs and supplies they need to produce and protect and provide the full capacity.</p>



<p>I learned on the tour today that each of the Javelins you produce includes more than 200 semiconductors.&nbsp; I’ve been a broken record, as the press will tell you, on our need to be able to produce more semiconductors in the United States.<br><br>We invented the sucker, going to the moon &#8212; we, the United States.&nbsp; We’re the one that modernized it.&nbsp; We’ve done more than anybody else.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; We stopped investing in ourselves.&nbsp; We stopped investing in ourselves.<br><br>And so, now we’re back in the game, making sure that we become &#8212; we become the primary producer of those semiconductors &#8212; computer chips that power much of our modern lives.&nbsp;<br><br>They’re in our phones, our cars, almost anything that has an on/off switch.&nbsp; And the semiconductor is critical to defense production capacity, as you &#8212; you all know better than I do.</p>



<p>That’s why we are making it as hard as we can for Russia to get a hold of semiconductors and advanced technologies that it could use to upgrade its military during this conflict, and why we’re taking steps to make it easier to source what we need here in the United States during a global semiconductor shortage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just one more &#8212; there is just one more reason why Congress has to act quickly to provide the emergency funding for the so-called CHIPS Act by passing the broader Bipartisan Innovation Act so we can produce tens of millions of these chips.</p>



<p>There is something we have to focus on and something I’ve focused on from my earliest days of our administration: I’m determined to make sure the United States holds the technological high ground in competition with other nations, especially China, as we move forward.</p>



<p>Folks, you know, we &#8212; we used to invest, as a nation, years ago &#8212; 35 years ago, we invested 2 percent of our entire GDP in research and development.&nbsp; We do half of that now.&nbsp; We do half of that.&nbsp; We used to be number one in the world.&nbsp; Now we’re number 13 in the world.&nbsp; My administration &#8212; we’re changing that.<br><br>The United States used to own the innovation field.&nbsp; In fact, it was a Department of [Defense] research program that established DARPA.&nbsp; It was the first development of an anti-tank missile with advanced infrared guidance systems that culminated in today’s Javelin.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Innovation Act is going to help reverse decades-long decline in federal research and development investment.&nbsp; And it should create [jobs] and support entire families, and expand U.S. manufacturing and strengthen our national security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Where in God&#8217;s name is it written that the United States can no longer be a leading manufacturer in the world?&nbsp; We&#8217;ve created, just in the last 17 months, 465,000 permanent manufacturing jobs in America.&nbsp; We have the best workers, the most competent employees, the best science in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by funding the CHIPS Act, we&#8217;re going to ensure the semiconductors that power the economy and our national security are made here in America again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, all &#8212; all the world&#8217;s most advanced chips are made overseas.&nbsp; But the events of the past few years have proven beyond a doubt that America’s security should never be held hostage to events overseas &#8212; not a pandemic, not a war, not the politics of &#8212; ambition, or other countries.</p>



<p>Fundamentally, there&#8217;s a national &#8212; this is a national security issue.&nbsp; This is one of the reasons why the Chinese Communist Party is lobbying folks to oppose this bill.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an issue that unites Democrats and Republicans.</p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s get it done.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get it done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In her introduction, Linda said she personally touched every single solitary Javelin &#8212; 50,000 &#8212; that had been manufactured in this plant 20 years ago.</p>



<p>I was worried to shake your hand.&nbsp; I thought you may &#8212; I might be electrocuted.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But that’s where they start: right here with American skill, American craftsmanship, American patriotism.</p>



<p>And just a few days ago, the Wall Street Journal quoted a young <s>Hungarian</s> [Ukrainian] fighter saying, and I quote, “Without the Javelins, it would have been very hard to stop the enemy pushing ahead.”&nbsp; End of quote.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So these weapons, touched by the hands &#8212; your hands &#8212; are in the hands of Ukrainian heroes, making a significant difference.&nbsp; And that’s something each and every day you could and should be proud of.</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m once more urging Congress to quickly pass the supplemental funding bill for over <s>$300</s> [$30] billion to help the Ukrainians so they can keep &#8212; they can keep all of the very, very &#8212; all of you very, very busy for a while here.</p>



<p>So, again, let me end where I began.&nbsp; I came for a basic reason, from the bottom of my heart: to say thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you for what you do.&nbsp; Thank you for what you continue to do.&nbsp; Unless you go out in the field and see it, you don&#8217;t realize what a difference you&#8217;re making.&nbsp;</p>



<p>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops. Thank you so much.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:20 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, May 3,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/03/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-may-3-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 21:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52302</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Montgomery, Alabama 12:52 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Okay, given I already did an extensive rundown yesterday of what we will be doing here in Troy, why don’t we just get to your questions? Q&#160;&#160;&#160; So, the President spoke pretty passionately on the tarmac about the Alito draft being an affront&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Montgomery, Alabama</p>



<p>12:52 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, given I already did an extensive rundown yesterday of what we will be doing here in Troy, why don’t we just get to your questions?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, the President spoke pretty passionately on the tarmac about the Alito draft being an affront to basic rights.&nbsp; But he also said he was not ready to commit to ending the filibuster to codify Roe.&nbsp; Why?</p>



<p>And is there a disconnect here between the passion and what needs &#8212; what he believes needs to be done?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say the President’s position is that we need to codify Roe, and that is what he has long called on Congress to act on.</p>



<p>What is also true is that there has been a vote on the Women’s Health Protection Act which would do exactly that, and there were not even enough votes, even if there was no filibuster, to get that done.</p>



<p>So, I would note, in his written statement that we released this morning &#8212; I’m just going to reiterate what he said in this statement.&nbsp; He said, “…if the Court does overturn Roe, it will fall on our nation’s elected officials at all levels of government to protect a woman’s right to choose” &#8212; to do exactly that.&nbsp; “It will fall on voters to elect pro-choice officials this November.&nbsp; At the federal level, we will need more pro-choice senators and a pro-choice majority in the House to adopt legislation.”&nbsp; And that was speaking to exactly where we are with the votes.</p>



<p>I would note that while we’ve been in the air, Leader Schumer noted that he had plans to bring this up for a vote.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you surprised that this leaked out?&nbsp; What do you think about the leak itself?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think this is &#8212; because it is unprecedented &#8212; or almost unprecedented, depending on what historian you speak to &#8212; there&#8217;s no question that that raises eyebrows for many in the country, including those of us in the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what our focus is on right now, beyond the leak, is &#8212; is how we&#8217;re going to protect a woman&#8217;s right to make choices about her healthcare with her doctor &#8212; a right that is supported by the vast majority of the American public.</p>



<p>And some call it a political issue.&nbsp; It is not.&nbsp; It is supported by the majority of the American public.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But when you look at the solutions that you put forward in that statement or the actions that the White House was considering taking, a lot of those take time.&nbsp; So, what is the White House&#8217;s message to women around the country who are waking up today and realizing their daughters and their &#8212; you know, younger women in this country may have less constitutional rights than they had in their lifetime?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me say first: This law has not changed.&nbsp; We know that it was &#8212; the Supreme Court has said the draft itself was legitimate, but they did not say this was the final conclusion.&nbsp; So, women waking up today &#8212; their daughters still have the same rights they had yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I will note, though, that we have already seen, in a number of states, actions taken that severely limit women&#8217;s fundamental rights across the country &#8212; a right that has been law for 50 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what we have done already to date is take steps through our Gender Policy Council to provide and expand access wherever we can with our capacity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, for example, we created the Dire Need Grant awards, which provide funding to expand access to emergency contraception and family planning services, and recently announced $6.6 million in awards made to aid grantees around the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition to immediate legal action by the Department of Justice against Texas, the Attorney General released a statement in response to SB 8 that reaffirmed the Department of Justice&#8217;s commitment to using existing federal law to protect the safety of patients seeking access to reproductive health services, including abortion, pursuant to their criminal and civil enforcement of the FACE Act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s important for anybody waking up today and confused about what their rights are.&nbsp; They have rights.&nbsp; This has not changed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, the Department of Health and Human Services has announced a three-pronged, department-wide response to protect patients and providers in response to the Texas law SB 8.</p>



<p>What I would note and the President also said in his statement this morning is that he&#8217;s directed his Gender Policy Council and the White House Counsel&#8217;s Office to prepare options for an administration response to the continued and obviously more expansive attack on abortion and reproductive rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, since then &#8212; since the Texas law banned most abortions and the White House said that there was going to be a whole-of-government response to that &#8212; so, mostly, it’s just the things that you just read.&nbsp; Are there any other actions that the administration did take?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Those were some of the steps that have been announced.&nbsp; But what I would note is that we will continue &#8212; and he direc- &#8212; he has directed the Gender Policy Council and the Counsel’s Office to prepare and to be prepared to respond.</p>



<p>There are things that we know because states have said them,&nbsp;so I would note that if Roe fails, abortion would probably be illegal in about half the states.&nbsp; Up to 26 states &#8212; particularly in the South, Midwest, and West &#8212; are poised to further restrict or ban access depending on the Court&#8217;s decision.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s beca- &#8212; and partly because 13 states have trigger laws, which means that they would immediately trigger banning abortion.</p>



<p>As a result of that, tens of millions of women may lack access to reproductive healthcare services.&nbsp; Abortion bans and restrictions will also dramatically reduce access to reproductive care, particularly for women with low income, women of color, and women in rural communities.</p>



<p>We know through the data that we&#8217;ve already looked at that 75 percent of those seeking abortion are living at or below 200 percent of the federal poverty level.&nbsp; And the majority of patients seeking abortions identify as Black, Hispanic, and AAPI.</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s important for everybody to understand that the people who would be impacted the most are lower income, are people who would have to take off work, are people who would have to find a way to travel, people who would have to find a way to get childcare.</p>



<p>I would also note that 60 percent of people who seek an abortion are moms already.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, is the White House starting to put together a plan just in case the Supreme Court does overturn Roe &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is exactly what the President said in his statement.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow up on Jen &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak to a timeline of the &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I follow up on what Jen said, though?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow up on what Jen was saying, though &#8212; that back in December, you had said in a statement &#8212; we&#8217;ve heard the President say this &#8212; about the work he would be doing to work with lawmakers on codifying Roe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Can you give us examples, now that we are in early May, from that time in December of where this has been on his priority list?&nbsp; How has he engaged with lawmakers on this?&nbsp; Anything specific of what he has done beyond the Gender Policy Council.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it&#8217;s important to note that there has been a vote on this; it failed.&nbsp; It did not have even 50 votes, which means even if the filibuster were overturned, there would have not had been enough votes to get this passed.&nbsp; He has stated this many times publicly.&nbsp; This is his known position. This is many of &#8212; one of many topics he discusses with lawmakers.</p>



<p>I would note again that Leader Schumer indicated he plans to bring it up again.&nbsp; But in the President&#8217;s statement, just to reiterate, what he pointed to is the fact that there needs to be a more &#8212; more pro-choice officials after the elections in November.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the &#8212; if all the polling is correct and abortion rights folks have public sentiment on their side, why have people continued to vote for a party that wants to do away with abortion rights?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That sounds like a question for those people who vote that way.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May I circle back to Steve&#8217;s question on the leak itself?&nbsp; Does the President agree with Justice Roberts that this was an egregious act?&nbsp; And does he believe that it should be criminally prosecuted?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This would be a decision made by the Department of Justice, and we would refer to them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, is this a live issue for you to push on the campaign trail this year, to try to help elect more pro-choice people?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not &#8212; I can&#8217;t and I&#8217;m not going to speak to politics from this gaggle.&nbsp; But I would again point you to the President&#8217;s statement, where he very clearly refere- &#8212; addressed exactly that question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On court packing: Has this raised any more discussions within the White House about the Supreme Court?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, you know, the President &#8212; there&#8217;s a commission that was put together.&nbsp; The commission put together a report not on recommendations, but to look at the big legal questions that have been out there for some time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The 30-member commission &#8212; member commission, with a diversity of views, put together a report that the President has been reviewing, so we have no update on his position on expansion of the Court.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Jen, I wonder what this says about the state of our democracy that, you know, abortion is an issue that a large number, a large swath of Americans agree with, yet we continue to see these consistent attacks, you know, by a party that represents a minority of Americans.&nbsp; Does this say something about the state of our democracy?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think the reason that I felt and the President felt it was important for me to reiterate who this impacts is because, right now, this is a moment to educate the public on what the impact would be.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; It is often shorthanded &#8212; not by any of us but in public discourse &#8212; as a political issue, as a wedge issue.&nbsp; It is not a wedge issue.&nbsp; The majority of the public supports women’s fundamental rights.&nbsp;&nbsp;And the people who would be impacted overwhelmingly are lower-income and are people of color.&nbsp; And we need to be clear about that in how we communicate about it so everybody understands as we &#8212; as this battle begins.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We heard the President talk about other rights.&nbsp; He talked about birth control.&nbsp; He brough up same-sex marriage.&nbsp; Can you expand on that, of just the concern at the White House about knowing this is a draft opinion, not finalized &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; of what this means for other things and the precedent it could set?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I think what you heard the President say to all of you under the wing reflects what has been front and center on his mind.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, there&#8217;s a lot to say about this leaked report.&nbsp; And when he was &#8212; last night, his Chief of Staff called him to alert him of the news and the report, we made the decision to take some time to do a thorough and thoughtful written statement this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And obviously, he made the decision to speak to all of you under the wing.&nbsp; And what you heard him talk about is a reflection of his time as Chairman of the Judiciary Committee, as somebody who has read, reviewed, looked at many Supreme Court decisions, and the fa- &#8212; and his concern &#8212; his personal concern, his concern as President of the United States about the precedent of this or what other fundamental rights, as you heard him say, could be at risk.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Who told him that the draft was legitimate?&nbsp; Was it &#8212; like, did the Chief Justice call him, or who informed the President?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There were reports about it, and so we let him know that there had been reports right before he arrived.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So it was a White House staffer &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; who telephoned him in the car?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You mentioned that the President would, after the midterms, that he wanted to see more pro-life lawmakers in office.&nbsp; But will he be &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Pro-choice.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, pro-choice.&nbsp; Excuse me.&nbsp; Would there be &#8212; is he making any effort prior to the midterms to connect with lawmakers to try and increase the number of votes that could vote for the legislation that Senator Schumer wants to bring forward?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, you know, this is his publicly stated view, something that he has made clear privately on many occasions as well.&nbsp; But I think it&#8217;s also important to note, again, that we did not have the 50 votes.</p>



<p>If there &#8212; if there was a bill sent to his desk to codify Roe, he&#8217;d be happy to sign it.&nbsp; We did not have even 50 votes, even if the filibuster were overturned.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But does he want to spend some time to try and increase that number &#8212; work with lawmakers; make personal pleas; you know, talk to them about this?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And I think you should talk to the lawmakers about whether their minds are changeable.&nbsp; I think you saw what the President said in his statement about what we all have a responsibility to focus on in the coming months.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything that the White House thinks that there is enough votes for before the midterms?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Like what?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On anything related to abortion.&nbsp; And &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t, in this moment, make an assessment of that.&nbsp; Obviously, codifying Roe is something the President would strongly support and would be happy to sign into law.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on this visit today to Alabama, is there any concern that going and visiting the factory that is being used to make the munitions that are destroying the tanks in Russia right &#8212; or not in Russia, but in Ukraine &#8212; Russian army tanks &#8212; that it&#8217;s kind of bragging about what we&#8217;re doing and it will only escalate?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President is visiting this factory today to showcase American manufacturing, American ingenuity, and the power of the American military and capacity to support the Ukrainians as they&#8217;re fighting a war against Russian aggression.</p>



<p>And so, no, he does not have that fear.&nbsp; In fact, he feels this is an opportunity to thank the American people for their support in our effort to support the Ukrainians.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Brittney Griner &#8212; can I ask you on that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q    Now that the U.S. government considers her to be wrongfully detained by the Russian government, in practical terms, what does that new distinction mean in terms of what the administration will be doing to try and secure her release?  Will the White House talk about her case more now that it has shifted to this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  So, that is a determination we’d make in coordination with the hostage negotiator and the &#8212; and the State Department.  So, <s>Richard</s> [Roger] Car- &#8212; <s>Richard</s> [Roger]? &#8212; yes &#8212; Carstens would now be engaged in this.  So this was a determination made by the State Department and &#8212; and released, obviously, last night.<br><br>But typically &#8212; and I don’t believe this will change &#8212; in order to &#8212; to leave the space to have an outcome we all want and desire &#8212; which is to bring her and any American detained or unjustifiably detained home &#8212; we typically don’t talk about it extensively.<br><br>Q    Are you expecting Ru- &#8212; look, just one &#8212; one more Ukraine thing.  Are you expecting Russia to try to annex areas of eastern Ukraine on &#8212; by May 9th or on May 9th?<br><br>Q    And officially declare war by May 9th?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I don’t have any predictions of exactly what President Putin or the Russian military will do by May 9th.  But I think you saw a State &#8212; the State Department go out yesterday and make clear that we did assess that one of the considerations &#8212; and &#8212; and we have a valid reason to believe this, that would be straight out of Russia’s playbook &#8212; would be for them to organize sham referrals &#8212; referenda in Crimea, in Luhansk, in Donetsk, and in other places to try to del- &#8212; delegitimize democratically elected leaders and impose fake people’s councils essentially made up of the Kremlin’s puppets and proxies.<br><br>We’ve seen them do this before.  And so, what they went out yesterday to &#8212; to announce was based on our assessment &#8212; a highly credible assessment.  But in terms of the timeline, I don’t have any update on that for you.<br><br>Q    On &#8212; sorry about that.  On Javelins, you made the point yesterday they’ve been very effective, but there’s been quite a substantial drawdown &#8212; both of the Javelins and the Stingers, which has also been effective.  Are we now at a point where the Javelin and the Stinger is going to be put on a pause in what can be shipped to Ukrainians until both Lockheed and Raytheon can backfill the orders on these?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  I would say, first, the biggest challenge we have is the funding &#8212; right? &#8212; because we have a limited amount of drawdown funding left, as you know, which is why the President is also going to talk about the urgency of getting the supplemental package through.  We have about $250 million left, as you know. </p>



<p>But we &#8212; our Defense Department assesses, of course, ensuring that we have the capacity and the ability to not only deliver what we promised but also to &#8212; to backfill our needs, which is part of what we&#8217;ve requested in the &#8212; in the funding moving forward.<br><br>Q    On the threats from Russia about nuclear weapons or the loose talk about nuclear weapons, what kind of diplomatic efforts the do the &#8212; do we, the United States, have right now to talk them off of that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Well, first, we find their rhetoric to be completely unconstructive and inconsistent with what many Russian officials have said many times in the past, which is that there is no winning a nuclear war.  So, we have not made any changes in our assessment right now of &#8212; our </p>



<p>substantive assessment of what is happening on the ground.</p>



<p>But, again, we continued to encourage them to and call on them to reduce the rhetoric, given we all know that a nuclear war cannot be won.</p>



<p>Q On student debt, what does the administration think are adequate income caps for any of the student forgiveness programs?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: Well, the President talked, back on the campaign, about taking steps or looking at steps to help people making less than $125,000 a year, so that is the frame through which he&#8217;s considering &#8212; making considerations at this point.</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s Roger Carstens. Sorry, I butchered his name, and I didn&#8217;t mean to. He does very important work for the government.  Remarkable work.  Maybe some of the most important work.<br><br>Q    Thank you.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:  Thank you, everyone.<br><br></p>



<p>1:08 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/03/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-12/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 19:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: Gerald H. Acker, of Michigan, to be a Commissioner on the part of the United States on the International Joint Commission, United States and Canada, vice Jane L. Corwin, resigning. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;David Michael Capozzi, of Maryland, to be a Director of the Amtrak Board of Directors for a term of five&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>     Gerald H. Acker, of Michigan, to be a Commissioner on the part of the United States on the International Joint Commission, United States and Canada, vice Jane L. Corwin, resigning.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;David Michael Capozzi, of Maryland, to be a Director of the Amtrak Board of Directors for a term of five years.&nbsp;&nbsp;(New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Anthony Rosario Coscia, of New Jersey, to be a Director of the Amtrak Board of Directors for a term of five years.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Christopher Koos, of Illinois, to be a Director of the Amtrak Board of Directors for a term of five years, vice Thomas C. Carper, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Samuel E. Lathem, of Delaware, to be a Director of the Amtrak Board of Directors for a term of five years, vice Albert DiClemente, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Robin Lee Wiessmann, of Pennsylvania, to be a Director of the Amtrak Board of Directors for a term of five years, vice Yvonne Brathwaite Burke, term expired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/03/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-13/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52279</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Carlos Felipe Uriarte, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General for Legislative Affairs, U.S. Department of Justice Gerald H. Acker, Nominee for Commissioner &#38; Chair of the International Joint Commission Annie Caputo, Nominee for Nuclear Regulatory&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Carlos Felipe Uriarte, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General for Legislative Affairs, U.S. Department of Justice</li><li>Gerald H. Acker, Nominee for Commissioner &amp; Chair of the International Joint Commission</li><li>Annie Caputo, Nominee for Nuclear Regulatory Commission</li><li>Bradley R. Crowell, Nominee for Nuclear Regulatory Commission</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Carlos Felipe Uriarte, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General for Legislative Affairs, U.S. Department of Justice</u></strong></p>



<p>Carlos Uriarte currently serves as Vice President, Regulatory Counsel at Unite Us, a technology company that connects health and social care providers. He previously served as Chief Counsel for Investigations on the House Select Subcommittee on the Coronavirus Crisis to House Majority Whip James E. Clyburn (D-SC), and as Counsel to Representative Elijah Cummings (D-MD) on the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and to Representative Judy Chu (D-CA).  Uriarte also served in the Obama-Biden Administration as Associate Deputy Attorney General in the Office of the Deputy Attorney General at the Department of Justice, and as Senior Counsel in the Office of the Secretary at the Department of the Interior.  Uriarte began his service on Capitol Hill as a law clerk to then-Senate Judiciary Committee Chairman Arlen Specter (R-PA). </p>



<p>Uriarte holds a J.D. from the University of Pennsylvania Law School, and a B.A., <em>magna cum laude</em>, in Economics and American Culture Studies from Washington University in St. Louis. After law school, Uriarte served as a Law Clerk to the Honorable Juan R. Sánchez of the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania.</p>



<p><strong><u>Gerald H. Acker, Nominee for Commissioner &amp; Chair of the International Joint Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Gerald H. Acker is an attorney who has been involved in law and policy in Michigan for 40 years.&nbsp; He is the co-founder and managing partner of Goodman Acker PC, a law firm that specializes in dispute resolutions between individuals and insurance companies. In 2010, Acker was appointed by Governor Jennifer Granholm to serve on the Board of Directors of Blue Cross Blue Shield of Michigan. Acker was previously appointed to the Board of Directors of the Mediation Tribunal Association of Wayne County,&nbsp;where he helped to ensure fair and equitable alternative dispute resolution in Michigan’s largest county.&nbsp; In 2009, he served as the President of the Michigan Association of Justice, the largest pro civil justice organization in Michigan. Acker has also served on the Board of Directors for the Hebrew Free Loan Association and as a Chairperson for the State Bar of Michigan, Attorney Grievance Commission.</p>



<p>Acker has a B.G.S. from the University of Michigan, and a J.D. from Wayne State University. He is married to Caryn, a retired teacher, and has two children and five grandchildren.</p>



<p><strong><u>Annie Caputo, Nominee for Nuclear Regulatory Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Annie Caputo currently consults with the Idaho National Laboratory (INL) regarding international collaboration on advanced nuclear reactors.&nbsp; Prior to her work at INL, Caputo served as a professional staff member on the U.S. Senate Armed Services Committee (SASC), assisting the Committee with issues related to the National Nuclear Security Administration’s infrastructure. Preceding her SASC assignment, Caputo served as a Commissioner of the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission for three years until the term expired in June 2021.</p>



<p>Caputo previously served as a professional staff member and senior policy advisor for the Senate Environment and Public Works Committee and the House Committee on Energy &amp; Commerce from 2005 to 2018. Prior to her positions on Capitol Hill, she worked for Exelon Corporation and its predecessor company Commonwealth Edison, holding positions in both nuclear fuel and government affairs. Caputo has also served on the Board of the American Nuclear Society. Caputo earned her Bachelor’s degree in Nuclear Engineering from the University of Wisconsin-Madison. She lives in Virginia with her husband and two children.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Bradley R. Crowell, Nominee for Nuclear Regulatory Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Bradley R. Crowell serves as Director of the Nevada Department of Conservation and Natural Resources (DCNR).&nbsp; Crowell was first appointed as Director in 2016 by former Governor Brian Sandoval and was reappointed by Governor Steve Sisolak in 2019. At DCNR, he leads approximately 1000 employees across 8 divisions and manages a nearly $300 million biennial budget.&nbsp; Crowell has more than 20 years of experience in the fields of energy, environment, natural resources, climate change, and national security, including executive leadership positions in federal and state government.&nbsp; Prior to his current role, he worked for multiple Members of Congress, including former Nevada Governor and Senator Richard Bryan (D-NV) and Senator Sheldon Whitehouse (D-RI). Crowell served in the Obama-Biden Administration at the U.S. Department of Energy from 2010-2016, and was confirmed by the U.S. Senate in 2013 as the Assistant Secretary of Energy for Congressional and Intergovernmental Affairs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Crowell resides in Reno, Nevada, with his wife, Mrs. Rebecca Claypool and their 1-year-old daughter Hazel, and is a native of Carson City, Nevada.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Air Force One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/03/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George’s County, Maryland 11:24 A.M. EDT Q    What do you think of the ruling &#8212; or the draft that leaked, sir? THE PRESIDENT:  Well, first of all, I just got a call saying that it’s been announced that it is a real draft, but it doesn’t represent who’s going to vote for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews<br>Prince George’s County, Maryland</p>



<p>11:24 A.M. EDT<br><br>Q    What do you think of the ruling &#8212; or the draft that leaked, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, first of all, I just got a call saying that it’s been announced that it is a real draft, but it doesn’t represent who’s going to vote for it yet.  I hope there are not enough votes for it.<br><br>It’s the main reason why I worked so hard to keep Robert Bork off the Court.  It reflects his view almost &#8212; almost word &#8212; anyway.<br><br>Look, the idea that &#8212; it concerns me a great deal that we’re going to, after 50 years, decide a woman does not have a right to choose within the limits of the Supreme Court decision in Casey, number one.<br><br>But even more equally as profound is the rationale used.  And it would mean that every other decision relating to the notion of privacy is thrown into question. <br><br>I realize this goes back a long way, but one of the debates I had with Robert Bork was whether &#8212; whether Griswold vs. Connecticut should stand as law. <br><br>The state of Connecticut said that the privacy of your bedroom &#8212; you &#8212; a husband and wife or a couple could not choose to use contraception; the use of contraception was a violation of the law.<br><br>If the rationale of the decision as released were to be sustained, a whole range of rights are in question &#8212; a whole range of rights.  And the idea we’re letting the states make those decisions, localities make those decisions would be a fundamental shift in what we’ve done.<br><br>So, it goes far beyond &#8212; in my view, if it becomes a law and if what is written is what remains, it goes far beyond the concern of whether or not there is the right to choose.  It goes to other basic rights: the right to marry, the right to determine a whole range of things.  Because one of the issues that this Court &#8212; many of the members of the Court &#8212; a number of the members of the Court have not acknowledged is that there is a right to privacy in our Constitution.<br><br>I strongly believe there is.  I think the decision in Griswold was correct overruling; I think the decision in Roe was correct, because there’s a right to privacy.  There can be limitations on it, but it cannot be denied.<br><br>Q    Do you think this leak has irreparably changed the Court?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Beg your pardon?<br><br>Q    Do you think that this leak has irreparably changed the Court?  We’ve never seen this happen before.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, if &#8212; if this decision holds, it’s really quite a radical decision.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, again, the underlying premise &#8212; and, again, I’ve not had a chance to thoroughly go into the report &#8212; the decision.&nbsp; But it basically says all the decisions related to your private life &#8212; who you marry, whether or not you decide to conceive a child or not, whether or not you can have an abortion, a range of other decisions &#8212; whether or not &#8212; how you raise your child &#8212;</p>



<p>What does this do &#8212; and does this mean that in Florida they can decide they’re going to pass a law saying that same-sex marriage is not permissible, that it’s against the law in Florida?</p>



<p>And so, there’s a whole &#8212; it’s a fundamental shift in American jurisprudence if it were to hold.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, should the Senate do away with the filibuster to codify Roe?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m not &#8212; I’m not prepared to make those judgments now about &#8212; but, you know, I think the codification of Roe makes a lot of sense.</p>



<p>Look, think what Roe says.&nbsp; Roe says what all basic mainstream religions have historically concluded &#8212; that the right &#8212; that the existence of a human life and being is a question.&nbsp; Is it at the moment of conception?&nbsp; Is it six months?&nbsp; Is it six weeks?&nbsp; Is it &#8212; is it quickening, like Aquinas argued?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, so the idea that we’re going to make a judgment that is going to say that no one can make the judgment to choose to abort a child based on a decision by the Supreme Court, I think, goes way overboard.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What does this mean for the midterms?&nbsp; What does this mean for the Democrats’ argument in the midterms?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I haven’t thought that through yet.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do changes need to be made to the Court in light of this, if this decision holds?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I beg your pardon?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do changes need to be made to the Court in light of this, if this decision holds?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have to choose &#8212; I mean, look, one of the reasons why I voted against a number of the members of the Court: They refuse to acknowledge that there’s a 9th Amendment.&nbsp; They refuse to acknowledge there’s a right to privacy.</p>



<p>I mean, there are so many fundamental rights that are affected by that.&nbsp; And I’m not allo- &#8212; I’m not prepared to leave that to the whims and the &#8212; and the &#8212; of the public at the moment in local areas.</p>



<p>Thank you so much.</p>



<p>11:29 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/03/statement-by-vice-president-kamala-harris/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 16:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States Supreme Court has now confirmed that the draft opinion that would overturn Roe v. Wade is genuine. Roe ensures a woman’s right to choose to have an abortion. It also, at its root, protects the fundamental right to privacy. What is clear is that opponents of Roe want to punish women and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States Supreme Court has now confirmed that the draft opinion that would overturn <em>Roe v. Wade</em> is genuine.</p>



<p><em>Roe </em>ensures a woman’s right to choose to have an abortion. It also, at its root, protects the fundamental right to privacy. What is clear is that opponents of <em>Roe</em> want to punish women and take away their rights to make decisions about their own bodies. Republican legislators in states across the country are weaponizing the use of the law against women.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">The rights of all Americans are at risk. If the right to privacy is weakened, every person could face a future in which the government can potentially interfere in the personal decisions you make about your life. This is the time to fight for women and for our country with everything we have. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Occasion of World Press Freedom Day&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/03/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-occasion-of-world-press-freedom-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 15:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We live in perilous times for press freedom. At least eleven journalists have been killed in Ukraine in recent weeks. Another 11 have been wounded by gunfire. Others have been kidnapped and assaulted, and at least one remains missing.&#160; In Russia, the Kremlin has tightened its vice-grip on civil society, including through passage of a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We live in perilous times for press freedom. At least eleven journalists have been killed in Ukraine in recent weeks. Another 11 have been wounded by gunfire. Others have been kidnapped and assaulted, and at least one remains missing.&nbsp; In Russia, the Kremlin has tightened its vice-grip on civil society, including through passage of a “disinformation” law intended to silence those speaking the truth. Facing the choice of repression and censorship or the threat of retribution, Russian journalists, and other members of the media have made the difficult choice to flee their country.</p>



<p>This is the price media workers and their families are paying to tell us the story of Putin’s unjust and brutal war in Ukraine. And it is the price paid around the world by journalists who have dedicated their lives to keep the world informed and share the truth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Journalists cover war, expose corruption, document environmental damage, lift up the marginalized, champion our communities, and hold the powerful to account. And for this, too often, they are killed, jailed, raped, threatened, and harassed.&nbsp; Women journalists, long a minority in the newsroom, are disproportionately targeted, on- and offline, in these attacks.</p>



<p>In the United States, national and local media are covering a once-in-a-century pandemic, a generational reckoning on race, and the existential threat of climate change.</p>



<p>The free press is not the enemy of the people.&nbsp; Quite the opposite, when driven by a quest to illuminate and educate, not inflame or entertain, the free press is the guardian of truth.</p>



<p>Over the past five years, UNESCO estimates that 85 percent of the world’s population have experienced a decline in press freedom&nbsp; That’s why, at the first Summit for Democracy last December, I announced a series of new initiatives – from new programs to protect journalists from spurious lawsuits, to seed funding for the International Fund for Public Interest Media, to expanded support for at-risk reporters – that elevate a renewed commitment by the United States to champion fact-based reporting and independent media globally.&nbsp; Foreign governments, civil society, and the private sector also have an important roles to play in sustaining this vital work, and the United States stands ready to be a partner in all these efforts.</p>



<p>Collectively, we can and must do more to protect and sustain independent media, and to hold to account those that seek to silence voices essential to transparent, trustworthy, and responsive governance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On this World Press Freedom Day, I honor the courage and sacrifice of journalists around the world, and commend all those who strive to inform, educate, and enlighten. The work of free and independent media matters now more than ever.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/03/statement-by-president-joe-biden-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 13:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We do not know whether this draft is genuine, or whether it reflects the final decision of the Court.  With that critical caveat, I want to be clear on three points about the cases before the Supreme Court.  First, my administration argued strongly before the Court in defense of Roe v. Wade. We said that Roe is based&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We do not know whether this draft is genuine, or whether it reflects the final decision of the Court. <br> <br>With that critical caveat, I want to be clear on three points about the cases before the Supreme Court. <br> <br>First, my administration argued strongly before the Court in defense of <em>Roe v. Wade. </em>We said that <em>Roe </em>is based on “a long line of precedent recognizing ‘the Fourteenth Amendment’s concept of personal liberty’… against government interference with intensely personal decisions.” I believe that a woman’s right to choose is fundamental, <em>Roe </em>has been the law of the land for almost fifty years, and basic fairness and the stability of our law demand that it not be overturned.<br> <br>Second, shortly after the enactment of Texas law SB 8 and other laws restricting women’s reproductive rights, I directed my Gender Policy Council and White House Counsel’s Office to prepare options for an Administration response to the continued attack on abortion and reproductive rights, under a variety of possible outcomes in the cases pending before the Supreme Court. We will be ready when any ruling is issued.<br> <br>Third, if the Court does overturn <em>Roe, </em>it will fall on our nation’s elected officials at all levels of government to protect a woman’s right to choose. And it will fall on voters to elect pro-choice officials this November.  At the federal level, we will need more pro-choice Senators and a pro-choice majority in the House to adopt legislation that codifies <em>Roe, </em>which I will work to pass and sign into law.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Marc and Debra&#160;Tice</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/02/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-president-bidens-meeting-with-marc-and-debra-tice/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 23:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden met today with Marc and Debra Tice, the parents of Austin Tice, who has spent almost a decade in captivity in Syria. During their meeting, the President reiterated his commitment to continue to work through all available avenues to secure Austin’s long overdue return to his family. The President further emphasized that his Administration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden met today with Marc and Debra Tice, the parents of Austin Tice, who has spent almost a decade in captivity in Syria. During their meeting, the President reiterated his commitment to continue to work through all available avenues to secure Austin’s long overdue return to his family. The President further emphasized that his Administration will work relentlessly until Austin and other Americans held hostage and wrongfully detained worldwide are safely at home with their loved ones.</p>



<p>Today’s meeting built on multiple meetings and conversations between the Tice family and the President’s national security team, which will remain in regular contact with the Tices and other families of Americans held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad. We appreciate the bravery and candor of families enduring these harrowing experiences, and we remain committed to supporting them and, most importantly, reuniting them with their loved ones.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Reception to Celebrate Eid&#160;al-Fitr</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/02/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-reception-to-celebrate-eid-al-fitr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 22:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 4:22 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Mom, with your permission &#8212; you boys can come up on stage if you want.&#160; AUDIENCE:&#160; Awww &#8212; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Come on.&#160; Don’t worry, he’s coming.&#160; (Laughter.) (Children are brought on stage.) Well, welcome to the White House, guys.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Welcome to the White House.&#160; And Eid Mubarak.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>4:22 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Mom, with your permission &#8212; you boys can come up on stage if you want.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Awww &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; Don’t worry, he’s coming.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>(Children are brought on stage.)</p>



<p>Well, welcome to the White House, guys.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Welcome to the White House.&nbsp; And Eid Mubarak.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Eid Mubarak!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m honored to welcome Representatives Tlaib and Carson.&nbsp; I think they’re here.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I see a hand going up back there.&nbsp; All right.</p>



<p>And although she can’t be here today, I also enjoyed seeing Representative Omar over the weekend.</p>



<p>And, look, welcome to the members of the diplomatic corps and to the elected representatives and community leaders all across the country, the thinkers, and activists.&nbsp; And it’s great to have you here in the White House, all working to make our nation and our world stronger and more inclusive.&nbsp; I emphasize “inclusive.”</p>



<p>And if you’ll excuse a point of personal privilege, I want to &#8212; is &#8212; is Madinah Wilson-Anton here?</p>



<p>STATE REPRESENTATIVE WILSON-ANTON:&nbsp; Yeah, I’m here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Welcome.&nbsp; It’s good to see you.&nbsp; She represents the state of Delaware, by the way.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And I want you to know she works at the University of Delaware, at the Biden Institute.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; So, we call that “using a point of personal privilege.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And there have not been many senators from Delaware.&nbsp; It’s a small state.&nbsp; As a matter of fact, there’s never been one.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And so, I want to take advantage of it by making sure I introduce her.</p>



<p>Jill and I are so glad to host all of you on this joyous occasion.&nbsp; You know, we send our warmest greetings celebrating Eid all across the United States and, quite frankly, around the world.</p>



<p>One of the promises I made when I ran for office is that I was to restore this annual celebration, because it’s important.&nbsp; It’s important.&nbsp; Sadly &#8212; (applause) &#8212;</p>



<p>Sadly, last year, because of the pandemic, we had to hold a virtual event.&nbsp; This year, thanks to the progress we’ve made fighting the pandemic, we can fully honor my promise.</p>



<p>And it’s in no small part thanks to the courage and commitment of many Muslim frontline workers and first responders &#8212; many of them.&nbsp; Many.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to the brilliant Muslim scientists who helped pioneer the technology for COVID-19 vaccine &#8212; don’t forget that either.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Not only helping people here but people around the world.</p>



<p>At the same time, we know that that it’s a bittersweet day for many &#8212; too many families.</p>



<p>You know, even as we celebrate Eid and mark the end of the holy month of Ramadan, we also, in our hearts, have those families who lost a loved one to the pandemic.<br><br>And, by the way, I was telling the doc &#8212; you know, there’s a lot of similarities between all the three major religions here.&nbsp; But I want you to know you have a slight advantage in Ramadan.&nbsp; For Lent, I got to go 40 days.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Forty days with no sweets and no ice cream.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I did it.&nbsp; Forty.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It’s harder, guys.&nbsp; You know what I mean?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Anyway, throughout the past month, Muslims have fasted each day from dawn to dusk.&nbsp; And &#8212; while &#8212; you know, while exercising the patiences of discipline can be a solitary act, it also is something that strengthens community bonds.&nbsp; It helps communities stick together.&nbsp; Communities are &#8212; is essential &#8212; essential to the celebration of Ramadan and Eid.</p>



<p>You know, whether breaking your fast with friends or family, or joining neighbors in acts of volunteering, or gathering for nightly communal prayers special to the month of Ramadan, this is a time to reflect not just on oneself and one’s faith but on the entire community &#8212; a whole community.</p>



<p>You know, through their fast, Muslims demonstrate empathy for suffering of others, strengthening and renewing their resolve to give generously and to make the world a better place &#8212; better for all who suffer.&nbsp; And I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; I’ve witnessed it around the world.</p>



<p>This year, for the first time in decades, three Abrahamic faiths all celebrate their holy days at the same time.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; The same time.&nbsp; That’s a message, guys.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I really mean that.&nbsp; I think &#8212; I really believe it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ramadan.&nbsp; Passover.&nbsp; Easter.&nbsp; And each a time of celebration for the light that has triumphed over darkness and &#8212; and for death giving way to renewal of life.</p>



<p>You know, each of us remember the work that remains to be unfinished here on Earth &#8212; and there’s a lot of it &#8212; to which God calls all his children.&nbsp; You know, that we should strive to show kindness and mercy, understanding to one another.&nbsp; And that we should do unto others as we wish to have done &#8212; do unto us.&nbsp; Sound familiar?&nbsp; Sound familiar in every language.&nbsp; It’s similar.</p>



<p>Today, we celebrate the incredible stories of the indispensable contributions of Muslims all across this great nation.&nbsp; Muslim-Americans, a diverse and vibrant part of the United States, making invaluable cultural and economic contributions to communities all across the nation.</p>



<p>You know what I think it’s about?&nbsp; I think you understand the sense of empathy.&nbsp; How can you move without empathy to understand?&nbsp; Teachers, counselors, mentors helping young people achieve their full potential.</p>



<p>By the way, I don&#8217;t know which one of you guys is going to be President, but, you know &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; if I were you, I’d be Secretary of State.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anyway, all kidding aside, look at these young men.&nbsp; They can be anything they want in this country, if we’re smart.&nbsp; Anything.&nbsp; Anything at all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And members of the military, first responders serving with such distinction, keeping us safe at home and abroad.&nbsp; Public servants across this country and across the administration who are leading the work to address the challenges of our time.</p>



<p>I’ve said it from the beginning that my administration &#8212; and I meant it and I proved it &#8212; is going to look like America &#8212; look like America &#8212; (applause) &#8212; really &#8212; with Muslim Americans serving at every level.&nbsp; And it does.</p>



<p>Muslim Americans in my administration have key roles in</p>



<p>tackling the climate crisis, rebuilding our economy, safeguarding our health, restoring our alliances, and so much more.</p>



<p>And I’m incredibly proud to have nominated the first Muslim American ever confirmed to the federal bench.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’ve appointed the first Muslim to serve as&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And it’s especially important because today, around the world, we’re seeing so many Muslims being targeted with violence.&nbsp; No one &#8212; no one should discriminate against oppressed &#8212; or be oppressed for their religious beliefs.&nbsp; Nobody.&nbsp; Nobody.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So, today, we also remember all those who are not able to celebrate this holy day, including Muslim and Ro- &#8212; excuse me &#8212; and including Uyghurs and Rohingyas and all &#8212; all those who are facing famine, violence, conflict, and disease.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we honor &#8212; we honor the signs of hope and progress toward the world we want to see, including the ceasefire, which allowed the people in Yemen to honor Ramadan and celebrate Eid in peace for the first time in six years.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>But at the same time, we have to acknowledge that an awful lot of work remains to be done abroad and here at home.</p>



<p>Muslims make our nation stronger every single day, even as they still face real challenges and threats in our society, including targeted violence and Islamophobia that exists.&nbsp; I mean, it’s just astounding.&nbsp; And &#8212; well, I won’t go into it.&nbsp; Anyway &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; I won’t get &#8212;</p>



<p>Making our own nation more equitable, more inclusive for Muslim Americans is an essential part of the enduring work</p>



<p>to form the more perfect union.&nbsp; That’s what we seek.</p>



<p>You know, we’re the only nation in all the history of the world that’s been organized not based on a religion, race, ethnicity, geography, but on an idea.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; An idea.</p>



<p>“We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men [and women] are created equal…endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable rights…life, liberty, the pursuit of happiness” &#8212; et cetera.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve never met that goal, but we&#8217;ve never walked away from it &#8212; except one brief moment, and we&#8217;re back.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re back and making &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I really mean it.</p>



<p>And the resilience of Muslim Americans enriching the fabric of this nation is testament to Quran’s teaching: We have made you into nations and tribes so that you may know one another.&nbsp; The last part: so you may know one another.</p>



<p>Our differences should not be obstacles that divide us but opportunities to learn from one another.</p>



<p>You know, it was mentioned earlier &#8212; excuse the diversion here &#8212; but when I became Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee &#8212; I’m a &#8212; if you come to my home, in my library you’ll see a lot of contemporary theology and comparative theology.&nbsp; And I’m just &#8212; been interested in it my whole career.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I realized how little I knew about the details of Islam.&nbsp; I knew &#8212; I knew about it, but I didn’t know the difference that existed.&nbsp; I didn’t know what the hidden Imam &#8212; I mean, I &#8212; so I went out and I hired a full professor &#8212; a professor of Islamic studies who came to work with me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He thought he was only staying a year.&nbsp; Every Wednesday, he had lunch with me.&nbsp; And he said, “How much more do you need to know?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; it was a chance to seek out and build and celebrate a common community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let’s celebrate today as we move forward this year, holding this teaching in our heart.</p>



<p>I am so proud to serve this community as your President, and I’m humbled by all the amazing accomplishments reflected in this room in front of me.&nbsp; And I’m grateful to have this opportunity to join together today to renew our common commitment to shared values.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And God bless you.&nbsp; May God bless America.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p> 4:33 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
