<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 03:51:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Joint Statement Between the United&#160;States and France on the One Ocean Summit in&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/11/joint-statement-between-the-united-states-and-france-on-the-one-ocean-summit-in-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and France are committed to protecting our environment for future generations. Recognizing the transboundary aspects of plastic pollution and the importance of curbing it at its source, the United States and France support launching negotiations at the upcoming 5th UN Environment Assembly (UNEA) on a global agreement to address the full lifecycle of plastics and promote a circular&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States and France are committed to protecting our environment for future generations. Recognizing the transboundary aspects of plastic pollution and the importance of curbing it at its source, the United States and France support launching negotiations at the upcoming 5th UN Environment Assembly (UNEA) on a global agreement to address the full lifecycle of plastics and promote a circular economy.  The agreement should include binding and non-binding commitments, call on countries to develop and implement ambitious national action plans, and foster robust engagement of stakeholders to contribute toward the agreement’s objectives while complementing national government contributions.  We look forward to partnering with other countries to achieve a successful outcome at UNEA and in the development of such a global agreement. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Black Mental Health&#160;Roundtable</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/readout-of-black-mental-health-roundtable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 03:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, as part of Black History Month celebrations, the White House hosted a virtual roundtable on Black mental health and wellness. White House Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice moderated a discussion with Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, Dr. Miriam Delphin-Rittmon, from the Department of Health and Human Services; Golden Globe Award-winning actress&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, as part of Black History Month celebrations, the White House hosted a virtual roundtable on Black mental health and wellness. White House Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice moderated a discussion with Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, Dr. Miriam Delphin-Rittmon, from the Department of Health and Human Services; Golden Globe Award-winning actress and singer, Taraji P. Henson; professional tennis player and 2017 U.S. Open Champion Sloane Stephens; and WNBA MVP and Players’ Association President, Nneka Ogwumike of the Los Angeles Sparks. Participants spoke about their own mental health challenges, the importance of seeking support and self-care, and their work to end stigma. The conversation also highlighted efforts by the Biden-Harris Administration to prioritize mental health and diversify our nation’s behavioral health workforce.</p>



<p>To view the full discussion, click here. Anyone who may be experiencing a mental health challenge should know that help is available and treatment works. Call 1-800-662-HELP (4357) or visit findtreatment.gov to learn more about mental health treatment options where you live.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the President and Vice President’s Meeting with Senate Judiciary Committee&#160;Democrats</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/readout-of-the-president-and-vice-presidents-meeting-with-senate-judiciary-committee-democrats/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 02:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon, as part of their continued engagement with lawmakers in both parties about the Supreme Court nomination process, the President and Vice President hosted the Democratic members of the Senate Judiciary Committee in the Oval Office. As two former members of the committee, the President and Vice President emphasized that there are a wealth&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This afternoon, as part of their continued engagement with lawmakers in both parties about the Supreme Court nomination process, the President and Vice President hosted the Democratic members of the Senate Judiciary Committee in the Oval Office.</p>



<p>As two former members of the committee, the President and Vice President emphasized that there are a wealth of extraordinarily qualified potential nominees under consideration who are dedicated to the Constitution and the rule of law, with top-rate legal intellects, and the strongest credentials, records, and character any person could possess. And that based on these qualities, any of the candidates being reviewed would be deserving of bipartisan support.</p>



<p>The President reiterated that, having chaired the Judiciary Committee and been involved with many confirmations, he has a unique appreciation for the significance of decisions about Supreme Court nominations, and that he welcomes the perspectives of Democrats and Republicans, as well as diverse legal experts and scholars, as he decides on a nominee later this month.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Roundtable Discussion with Cabinet&#160;Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/readout-of-roundtable-discussion-with-cabinet-officials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 21:09:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House hosted a historic convening of Black Cabinet members as part of Black History Month celebrations. The convening included a discussion moderated by Senior Advisor to the President Cedric Richmond. &#160;During the discussion, officials noted their commitment to the President’s whole-of-government approach to advancing racial equity and support for underserved communities through&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House hosted a historic convening of Black Cabinet members as part of Black History Month celebrations. The convening included a discussion moderated by Senior Advisor to the President Cedric Richmond. &nbsp;During the discussion, officials noted their commitment to the President’s whole-of-government approach to advancing racial equity and support for underserved communities through the federal government and spoke to the individual experiences each brings to the departments they lead. The conversation also highlighted the significance of Black leadership in key policy areas including military service, housing, environment, foreign affairs, and the economy.</p>



<p>Participants included Defense Secretary Lloyd Austin, Housing and Urban Development Secretary Marcia Fudge, Environmental Protection Agency Administrator Michael Regan, United States Mission to the United Nations Ambassador Linda Thomas-Greenfield, Council of Economic Advisors Chair Cecilia Rouse and Office of Management and Budget Acting Director Shalanda Young.</p>



<p>On January 31, President Biden issued a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/01/31/a-proclamation-on-national-black-history-month-2022/">proclamation</a> calling on the nation to celebrate the contributions of Black Americans, honor the legacies and achievements of generations past, reckon with centuries of injustice and confront those injustices that still fester today. In the proclamation, the President also reaffirmed his commitment to advancing equity, racial justice, and opportunity for Black Americans, which began by building a Federal Government that looks like America.</p>



<p>To view the full discussion, click <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AexEaKz1FRI">here</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 20:49:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Reuben E. Brigety, II, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of South Africa. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MaryKay Loss Carlson, of Arkansas, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Reuben E. Brigety, II, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of South Africa.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MaryKay Loss Carlson, of Arkansas, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of the Philippines.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Elizabeth Shortino, of the District of Columbia, to be United States Executive Director of the International Monetary Fund for a term of two years, vice Margrethe Lundsager, resigned.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Cynthia C. Hogan, of Ohio, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Corporation for National and Community Service for a term expiring February 8, 2024, vice Lisa M. Quiroz, term expired, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Kimberly Caudle Lewis, of Alabama, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority for a term expiring May 18, 2025, vice Richard Capel Howorth, term expired, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mary Catherine Phee, of Illinois, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be a Member of the Board of Directors of the African Development Foundation for a term expiring September 27, 2021, vice Linda Thomas-Greenfield, resigned, which was sent to the Senate on April 29, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Robert Luis Santos, of Texas, to be Director of the Census for the remainder of the term expiring December 31, 2021, vice Steven Dillingham, which was sent to the Senate on April 15, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration&#8217;s Work to Lower Healthcare&#160;Costs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-biden-harris-administrations-work-to-lower-healthcare-costs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 19:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47089</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Germanna Community CollegeCulpeper, Virginia 12:49 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Mr. President.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; I could have no more have done that when I was 12 years old than fly.&#160; I used to be a stutterer.&#160; I was scared to death I would stand up and ta-ta &#8212; ta-ta-talk &#8212; talk like that.&#160; And&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Germanna Community College<br>Culpeper, Virginia</p>



<p>12:49 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I could have no more have done that when I was 12 years old than fly.&nbsp; I used to be a stutterer.&nbsp; I was scared to death I would stand up and ta-ta &#8212; ta-ta-talk &#8212; talk like that.&nbsp; And I can’t tell you how much &#8212; how proud I am of you.&nbsp; And your brother is equally as impressive as you are.&nbsp; He’s standing there &#8212; he&#8217;s sitting there two seats over.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Shannon and Joshua &#8212; and, by the way, Happy Birthday, man.&nbsp; He’s going to be 13 years old &#8212; a teenager &#8212; in a couple days.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I want you to know that lowering the cost of prescription drugs is one of the reasons why I’m here with Abigail, your congresswoman.&nbsp; And that’s what I want to talk about with you today.&nbsp; Lowering the cost of healthcare overall, as well.&nbsp; Lowering the cost of prescription drugs is important.&nbsp; And giving families like yours just a little bit more breathing room makes a gigantic difference.</p>



<p>Before I get into that, I want to say: It’s good to be here at Germanna school.&nbsp; And, by the way, Abigail, if I wanted to know anything about community colleges in Virginia, I go to my wife.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She teaches full-time and has for the last nine years.&nbsp; She’s in the classroom now at &#8212; at a community college in Northern Virginia &#8212; Northern Virginia Community College.</p>



<p>And she says &#8212; she says, “You know, the single best-kept secret in America is community colleges.”&nbsp; And it really is.&nbsp; They are so flexible.&nbsp; They can do so much &#8212; so much.&nbsp; And if I had more time &#8212; which I don’t &#8212; for all of you, I’d go into what we’re going to try to do to increase the flexibility and the funding of community colleges for people.</p>



<p>But it’s great to be here with Abigail &#8212; with Congresswoman Spanberger.</p>



<p>In every chapter of her career &#8212; in every chapter, she’s always been about one thing: service.&nbsp; Service.</p>



<p>I also want to thank Mark Warner and Tim Kaine, who &#8212; senators here &#8212; are good friends and worked closely with me on so many things when I was a senator and now as President and when I was Vice President.&nbsp; But they needed to be in Washington today because there’s votes in the Senate.</p>



<p>I also want to thank Secretary of Health and Human Services Xavier Becerra for two things.&nbsp; One, for answering my call when I asked him to come and be the Secretary.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I was worried he wouldn’t.&nbsp; And how much he’s helped us make so much progress in getting people vaccinated, getting health insurance, and making more affordable healthcare.</p>



<p>Look, healthcare is part of Abigail &#8212; congresswoman &#8212; your congresswoman’s background.&nbsp; Back in 2017, she saw her representatives in Congress vote to repeal the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp; That was one of more than 100 Republican efforts &#8212; there were 100 Republican efforts since we passed it in our last administration to repeal the Affordable Care Act.</p>



<p>But she knew that that was the exact opposite of what central Virginia badly needed.&nbsp; You needed then and you need now more access to quality healthcare that is more affordable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, when I became President of the United States, that’s what we did.&nbsp; We passed the American Rescue Plan, which made quality coverage through the Affordable Care Act more affordable than ever before, with families saving, on average, who have signed up &#8212; a family, on average &#8212; $2,400 a year in their annual premiums.</p>



<p>Compared to last year, the average monthly premium for Virginia &#8212; for Virginians has gone down more than 25 percent.</p>



<p>Over 5 million people have gained coverage through the ACA since I became President.&nbsp; As was mentioned by Xavier, over 300,000 Virginians have signed up for health insurance during open enrollment period here in Virginia.</p>



<p>And we want to go further: lowering prescription drug prices; get a cap on the amount people pay on Medicare, pay for prescription drugs; and to bring more clarity and fewer surprises when you get your bills if you&#8217;ve been hospitalized.</p>



<p>So, let me say a few words about each of these things now.</p>



<p>With regard to prescription drugs: In America, we pay the highest prescription drug prices of any nation &#8212; developed nation in the world &#8212; the highest of any.&nbsp; And it’s about two to three times higher than what other countries pay.</p>



<p>Let me give you one example.&nbsp; An anti-cancer drug to treat leukemia and lymphoma costs $14,000 a month in the United States.&nbsp; The same exact drug, made by the same exact pharmaceutical company, is sold in France and it&#8217;s $6,000 a month.&nbsp; $6,000 for the same exact drug, same exact manufacturer, same exact amounts.&nbsp; Not 14, but 6.&nbsp; That’s for a month’s supply.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, one in four Americans who need prescription drugs struggle to afford them &#8212; one in four.&nbsp; Nearly 30 percent have skipped doses of essential drugs they&#8217;re supposed to take.&nbsp; Others have simply not filled prescriptions that the doctor had given them; tried to use over-the-counter drugs or pills cut in half because they can’t afford the cost of their prescription.</p>



<p>This is the United States of America, for God&#8217;s sake.&nbsp; That’s just wrong.&nbsp; It&#8217;s simply wrong, especially since it doesn&#8217;t cost the drug companies nearly, nearly, nearly, nearly as much to make the drug or the research that went into them.</p>



<p>Let me regress for just a moment here.&nbsp; I started when &#8212; in the Obama-Biden administration an effort to deal with the Cancer Moonshot to change the way in which we deal with cancer.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m reinstituting that in my administration now.</p>



<p>And it was interesting.&nbsp; I met &#8212; we had these hearings all over the United States.&nbsp; And one of the major events we did, we &#8212; at Howard University, where there were 35 other events going on simultaneously with this.&nbsp; I had subsequently met with the heads of &#8212; I think it was 13 drug companies.</p>



<p>And I asked them &#8212; I said, &#8220;If you found a cure for a particular cancer, how much you think you should be able to charge?&#8221;&nbsp; And the response universally was, &#8220;What the market will bear.&#8221;</p>



<p>I said, &#8220;Hope I don&#8217;t get elected President, because that&#8217;s just not &#8212; what you&#8217;ll get should be treated more like a utility.&#8221;&nbsp; You should be able to make a significant progress for &#8212; let&#8217;s add up how much &#8212; and like they do in Germany &#8212; how much did it cost you all, the research and development &#8212; all the effort.&nbsp; Add it all up.&nbsp; And then, on top of that, add a significant premium for it &#8212; a profit of 20 to 30 percent above that.&nbsp; Maybe, in some cases, more.</p>



<p>But the idea &#8212; the idea you can charge whatever you want is just not going to happen in the United States of America if I have anything to do with it.</p>



<p>If you think this doesn’t affect you, it does, by the way.&nbsp; Everyone has less money in their pockets today because of high drug pric- &#8212; drug costs and health insurance.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s more expensive for everyone.</p>



<p>And the reason it is, is this is what your insurance companies pay.&nbsp; Every &#8212; all of you who have insurance, you&#8217;re paying a heck of a lot more even if you&#8217;re not using the drugs.</p>



<p>Over the past decade, healthcare costs have gone up 50 percent.&nbsp; Prescription drugs are a big chunk of that.</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s a lot of things that almost every American can agree on.&nbsp; But I think it’s safe to say that all of us &#8212; whatever our background, our age, where we live, whether we agree on prescription drugs &#8212; look, we all acknowledge they&#8217;re outrageously expensive, and in many cases, there is no relationship to cost.</p>



<p>It doesn’t need to be that way.</p>



<p>Josh and Shannon, it costs drug companies less than $10 to make a vial of that insulin.&nbsp; Less than 10 bucks.&nbsp; That’s what it costs.</p>



<p>There’s no reason you should be paying over $300 a vial for medicine you need every day to stay healthy and, in many cases, stay alive.</p>



<p>As your mom said, you got to pay $5,600 for prescriptions before your insurance even kicks in.&nbsp; You got to do the deductible.</p>



<p>Shannon, you should have peace of mind of knowing that if Joshua grows up and leaves your care &#8212; your healthcare plan, he’ll be able to choose a job without ever having to make a choice between which one has the particular healthcare coverage.</p>



<p>You know, we’re now in a position where we can cap co-pays for insulin at $35 a month.&nbsp; And it’s still a staggering profit: three and half times what it costs to produce the drug.</p>



<p>You can do that with a stroke of a &#8212; we can do that with a stroke of a pen.</p>



<p>In my Build Back Better legislation that with Abigail’s leadership passed in the House of Representatives, we can do that.&nbsp; Now we just have to get through the United States Senate, and we’re close.</p>



<p>We can do even more to lower out-of-pocket prescription costs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under my proposal, we will hold drug companies accountable for the absurd price increases.&nbsp; Here’s how: Drug companies that increase their prices faster than the rate of inflation, once the price is set, will face a steep tax.</p>



<p>This will help us end the days when drug companies could increase their prices with no oversight, no accountability, and no responsibility.</p>



<p>We’re saying to drug companies: You are finally going to become accountable when you raise prices on the American people.&nbsp; Accountability.</p>



<p>You&#8217;re still going to make a significant profit.</p>



<p>And we can take additional steps to lower drug costs for people with Medicare &#8212; something Abigail has championed.</p>



<p>Right now, the only thing Medicare is not allowed to negotiate the price of are prescription drugs.</p>



<p>For everything else covered by Medicare &#8212; a doctor’s visits &#8212; they negotiate and say, “We’ll pay no more than this much for a doctor’s visit.”&nbsp; So if the doctors don’t want to take any Medicare patients, they don’t have to.&nbsp; But if they have a Medicare patient, which there are millions of them, they cannot charge more than a certain amount.&nbsp; Crutches &#8212; we limit the amount of money they can pay for crutches.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But &#8212; but Medicare can negotiate everything except drug prices.&nbsp; The only outfit that can&#8217;t do &#8212; they &#8212; they can&#8217;t deal with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My plan is going to allow Medicare to negotiate the prices they&#8217;re prepared to pay for each individual drug.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If the company says, “I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to sell it to you at that price,” fine, but they&#8217;re going to lose millions of customers.&nbsp; Millions of customers.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re proposing &#8212; what we’re proposing is that we negotiate fair prices &#8212; one that reflects the cost of research and development and the need for significant profit, but still is affordable and has some relationship to the cost the drug company had.</p>



<p>My plan also caps the amount that seniors on Medicare have to spend on prescription drugs each year total, so that if they’re on Medicare, they’ll not have to spend out of pocket more than $2,000 a year, no matter how many drugs they’re taking, with drug companies, insurance companies, and medicine &#8212; and Medicare picking up the rest of the cost.</p>



<p>And just last month, to bring greater transparency to healthcare costs, my administration outlawed surprise billing.</p>



<p>I’ve had significant experience with hospital care.&nbsp; My son Beau, who was Attorney General of Delaware and a &#8212; won the Bronze Star in Iraq &#8212; and, I mean, excuse me, in &#8212; in dealing with being deployed overseas for a long time, for a year.&nbsp; You know, he &#8212; he came back with glioblastoma, and he died.</p>



<p>But you know what?&nbsp; You know, the fact is that &#8212; and I &#8212; I was hospitalized a long time.&nbsp; I had, a couple years ago, a cranial aneurism, was hospitalized for a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you can no longer get that surprise billings we got.&nbsp; If your healthcare plan did not cover a particular doctor but you didn’t even know he was being consulted and you get an extra bill for two to five thousand dollars &#8212; they can’t do that anymore.&nbsp; No more surprise billing.&nbsp; No more.</p>



<p>Millions of hardworking Americans will no longer have to worry about unexpected medical bills.&nbsp; And Abigail has been making sure that we bring the same transparency to drug prices.</p>



<p>A couple of years ago, Abigail worked to pass bipartisan legislation to make drug prices more transparent so you knew what you’re paying for.&nbsp; And my administration is working with Abigail to make sure we enforce that.</p>



<p>She also has been relentless in making sure the law that’s been on the books that says pharmaceutical companies need to provide rural clinics and community health centers with discounts on prescription drugs is actually enforced.&nbsp; And we’re working together on that as well.</p>



<p>I’ve long said healthcare should be a right, not a privilege, in this country.&nbsp; This isn’t a parti- &#8212; diabetes, Alzheimer’s, cancer &#8212; they’re not partisan issues.&nbsp; They’re not Democrat or Republican.</p>



<p>This is about &#8212; this is about whether or not you and your loved ones can afford the healthcare you need and the medi- &#8211; and the medicines you need to stay healthy, because we need to ease the burden on working families by making everything more affordable and accessible.</p>



<p>Look, again, slight digression: Inflation is up.&nbsp; It’s up.&nbsp; And coming from a family when the price of gas went up, you felt it in the household, you knew what it was like, it matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the fact is that, if we’re able to do the things I’m talking about here, it’ll bring down the costs for average families.&nbsp; It&#8217;ll bring down the costs for average families.&nbsp; I don’t know why they keep moving all that, but the fact is: They keep down the costs for average families.</p>



<p>And, look, the fact is that we’re in a situation now where, you know, you should have peace of mind.&nbsp; I know food prices are up, and we’re working to bring them down.</p>



<p>As I said, I grew up in a family where the price at the pump went up, you felt it.&nbsp; And I understand.&nbsp; But these things are necessities.&nbsp; We’re working to bring down prices where there are not totally what families, in fact, have to pay now.</p>



<p>You still have pay to for childcare.&nbsp; Childcare is a cost for millions of families.&nbsp; You still have to pay your prescription drug prices.&nbsp; You still have to pay for healthcare.</p>



<p>You want to lower the cost of living for people?&nbsp; Help them in those areas.</p>



<p>So, there’s more than one way for a family, when it comes to raising their standard of living.</p>



<p>I’m going to work like the devil to bring gas prices down, which I&#8217;m going to &#8212; I&#8217;m working to make sure that we keep strengthening the supply chains to bring the cost of energy and everything else and the goods that come to America down by helping the ports 24/7, by changing a whole range of things that &#8212;</p>



<p>You know, what&#8217;s happened with COVID &#8212; COVID has caused significant increase in prices in the supply chain, because when a factory shuts down in another part of the world and you need that particular product in order to finish and build whatever you’re working on, the price goes up exponentially, like for cars.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in the meantime, there is a lot we can do to give families extra breathing room.&nbsp; We can do this when we cut the cost of childcare, making sure that you don&#8217;t pay more than 7 percent of a family’s income for childcare.&nbsp; That saves thousands of dollars in families &#8212; for families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Shannon, think about what these plans would mean for you and your family.</p>



<p>We’re &#8212; already made a lot of progress on the economy.&nbsp; Last year, more jobs were created in America than in any year in American history.</p>



<p>Unemployment has dropped more than any year in American history.</p>



<p>We reduced the deficit &#8212; the federal deficit, while doing those &#8212; both those things, by $300 billion.</p>



<p>We lowered child poverty by nearly 40 percent in America, more than any year in American history, as a consequence of the Child Tax Credit.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re coming out at these challenges from a position of strength unmatched by any nation in the world.&nbsp; And I might add, and I note here just to all of you, that this does not raise anyone&#8217;s &#8212; if you&#8217;re making less $400,000, you&#8217;re not paying a single penny more in taxes &#8212; not a single penny more in taxes.&nbsp; And it does not increase the deficit because it&#8217;s paid for.&nbsp; It&#8217;s fully paid for.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve had a group of major companies, from Intel to General Motors to Ford to &#8212; down across the board &#8212; come to me and say they want to keep these programs going, increase corporate taxes to 24 percent, which they were supposed to be.&nbsp; It gets paid for.&nbsp; They understand the net effect on the economy is to grow it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know that when we invest in ourselves, there&#8217;s no limit to what we can achieve with leaders like Abigail and the brave folks like Shannon and Joshua.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All of you know here today that all this progress we&#8217;ve made is going to be just the beginning &#8212; just the beginning.&nbsp; I promise you we&#8217;re going to do so much more, and it will not &#8212; I emphasize, it will not increase the debt.&nbsp; It will not increase taxes on anyone making less than $400,000 a year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; You should be able to make a million or a billion dollars.&nbsp; Just pay a little bit of your fair share.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have over 53 companies in America that made $40 billion last year &#8212; didn&#8217;t pay a single penny in taxes.&nbsp; Not a single penny.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not right.</p>



<p>And so, you find that a lot of these corporations realize: To grow and be competitive, it makes sense just to pay a little more in taxes at the top end in order to afford this economic growth we&#8217;re creating.</p>



<p>But bringing down the cost of healthcare, bringing down the cost of prescription drugs is an easy thing for us to do.&nbsp; It can be done legally with a stroke of a pen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We just got to get Abigail&#8217;s enthusiasm that she gotten it through in the House of Representatives to the United States Senate.&nbsp; So, we may be dragging you over to the Senate to spend some time.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, there&#8217;s so much we can do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank the family for being willing to stand up here and share their story.&nbsp; And, Dad, stand up so everybody knows who you are.&nbsp; I want them to see you.&nbsp; That good-looking guy back there, that&#8217;s Dad.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Every time I&#8217;d walk out of my grandpop&#8217;s house up in Scranton, Pennsylvania &#8212; his name was Ambrose Finnegan; he was an All-American football player out in Santa Clara when he was a kid &#8212; and he used to always yell, &#8220;Joey, keep the faith.&#8221;&nbsp; And my grandmother would yell &#8212; she&#8217;d yell back, &#8220;No, Joey, spread it.&#8221;&nbsp; Let&#8217;s spread the faith and get this done.</p>



<p>Thank you very, very much.  Appreciate it.  (Applause.) </p>



<p>1:09 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to Attend the Bicentennial Celebration of the Arrival of the First Free Black Americans to the Republic of&#160;Liberia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-attend-the-bicentennial-celebration-of-the-arrival-of-the-first-free-black-americans-to-the-republic-of-liberia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47069</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Liberia to attend the Bicentennial Celebrations in Monrovia, Liberia on February 14, 2022.&#160; This marks the arrival of the first Free Black Americans to Providence Island in 1822, which led to the establishment of the City of Monrovia,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Liberia to attend the Bicentennial Celebrations in Monrovia, Liberia on February 14, 2022.&nbsp; This marks the arrival of the first Free Black Americans to Providence Island in 1822, which led to the establishment of the City of Monrovia, and in 1847, the Republic ofLiberia.</p>



<p><a></a><a></a>The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong></p>



<p>The Honorable Michael A. McCarthy, United States Ambassador to the</p>



<p>Republic of Liberia</p>



<p>The Honorable Dana Banks, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Africa, National Security Council</p>



<p>Mr. Lonnie G. Bunch III, Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution</p>



<p>Rev. Dr. Teresa Jefferson-Snorton, Bishop of the Fifth Episcopal District of the Christian Methodist Episcopal Church, Chair of the Governing Board, National Council of Churches in the United States</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Houthi Attack Against Saudi&#160;Arabia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-houthi-attack-against-saudi-arabia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 16:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States strongly condemns today’s terrorist attack against Abha in Saudi Arabia, which injured at least a dozen innocent civilians. &#160;The Houthis have claimed responsibility for this attack, and we will work with our Saudi and international partners to hold them accountable. &#160; As the President told His Majesty King Salman yesterday, we are&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States strongly condemns today’s terrorist attack against Abha in Saudi Arabia, which injured at least a dozen innocent civilians. &nbsp;The Houthis have claimed responsibility for this attack, and we will work with our Saudi and international partners to hold them accountable. &nbsp; As the President told His Majesty King Salman yesterday, we are committed to supporting Saudi Arabia in the defense of its people and territory from these attacks. &nbsp;America will have the backs of our friends in the region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PRICES WEEK FACT SHEET: The Biden-&#8288;Harris Plan to Boost the Capacity of the Economy and Lower Costs for Working&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/prices-week-fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-plan-to-boost-the-capacity-of-the-economy-and-lower-costs-for-working-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 16:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Administration this week is highlighting its comprehensive strategy to boost the capacity of the economy and lower costs for working families – from addressing supply chain bottlenecks, to making our economy more competitive, and pushing for legislation to ease everyday costs and make more in America. The President will speak to that this afternoon&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>The Administration this week is highlighting its comprehensive strategy to boost the capacity of the economy and lower costs for working families – from addressing supply chain bottlenecks, to making our economy more competitive, and pushing for legislation to ease everyday costs and make more in America. The President will speak to that this afternoon in Virginia, where he’ll discuss how we can lower the price of prescription drugs for working Americans.</em></p>



<p>Thanks in part to President Biden’s American Rescue Plan, the U.S. is in the midst of a historic economic recovery. In 2021, we saw the strongest monthly job growth ever recorded, the largest decline in unemployment ever recorded, the strongest economic growth in four decades, and an estimated nearly 40 percent decline in child poverty. Despite this progress, the U.S., along with much of the world, is grappling with elevated price increases brought on by the pandemic. These price increases hit families’ budgets, and create anxiety about the future. While experts expect inflation to moderate in the months ahead, President Biden is taking action now.</p>



<p>President Biden’s plan starts with respecting the Federal Reserve’s independence to keep elevated price increases from becoming entrenched. The Federal Reserve provided extraordinary support during the crisis. Given the strength of our recovery, and the pace of recent price increases, it is appropriate for them to recalibrate that support.</p>



<p>Beyond the Fed, the President believes that the most important thing he and Congress can do is build a more productive economy – with greater capacity to deliver goods and services to the American people. He does not agree with those who believe that the only solution is to make working families that are the backbone of our country poorer. Instead, the President is focused on building a growing economy, where folks have more choices, where more small businesses can compete, and where more goods get to market faster and cheaper. That means expanding the supply-side of the economy, over the short-, medium-, and long-term. Specifically, the Biden-Harris Administration is:<br></p>



<p><strong><u>Fixing our supply chains and infrastructure, and making more in the United States</u></strong>.</p>



<p>The Administration is restoring American manufacturing and rebuilding American infrastructure, so we can make more here at home and move goods more efficiently and reliably through the economy. In February, the President issued an Executive Order to strengthen our supply chains, and in June established the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-supply-chain-disruptions-task-force-to-address-short-term-supply-chain-discontinuities/">Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force</a> to bring a whole-of-government approach to addressing the immediate disruptions linked to the global pandemic. The <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/bipartisan-infrastructure-law/">President Biden’s historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law</a> will provide the funding needed to close vulnerabilities and improve efficiency at our ports, roads, waterways, and railroads. &nbsp;The Administration is focused on addressing challenges and boosting capacity in three key sectors: transportation, semiconductors, and agriculture.</p>



<ul><li>In <strong>the transportation sector</strong>, in 2021 the Ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach—which process 40 percent of the nation’s containerized imports—broke their 2018 record for annual containerized imports by 13 percent. After working with the Biden-Harris Administration, they also reduced the number of containers sitting on the docks for 9 days or more by 60 percent. Thanks in part to the Administration’s efforts, American retailers’ shelves were well stocked for the record-breaking holiday season and 97 to 99 percent of consumers received their packages on time or with minimal delays. The Administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/11/09/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-action-plan-for-americas-ports-and-waterways/">Ports Action Plan</a> and a <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/16/fact-sheet-the-biden-%E2%81%A0harris-administration-trucking-action-plan-to-strengthen-americas-trucking-workforce/">Trucking Action Plan</a> are helping American port operators move a record amount of goods from ships to shelves as quickly as possible and connect more Americans to good jobs in the trucking industry. And by investing in our longer-term infrastructure needs, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will help make our transportation system more effective and make it easier and cheaper for businesses to move goods to market.<br><br></li><li>In <strong>the</strong> <strong>semiconductor sector</strong>, the Administration is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/21/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-bringing-semiconductor-manufacturing-back-to-america-2/">working to expand U.S. chip manufacturing capacity</a>, bring back American manufacturing jobs, address the chip shortage, and ensure we are not exposed to these disruptions again. Auto inflation – caused in part by the global semiconductor shortage – has caused around a third of the core inflation we’ve seen in the last year. But the Administration is making important progress. In just the last few weeks, Intel and GM announced they are building new chip and EV manufacturing plants right here in the United States.&nbsp; To accelerate this progress, the President is urging Congress to pass legislation to strengthen U.S. research and development and manufacturing for critical supply chains, including semiconductors.<br><br></li><li>In <strong>the agriculture and meat processing sector</strong>, the Administration is providing financing to <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/01/03/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-action-plan-for-a-fairer-more-competitive-and-more-resilient-meat-and-poultry-supply-chain/">expand independent food processing capacity and support workers</a>; strengthening rules that protect farmers, ranchers, and consumers; and expanding access to affordable, high-quality food for those in need, including in <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/01/07/usda-announces-increased-funding-support-school-meals-and-help">schools</a>.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Fighting to lower kitchen table costs</u></strong>.</p>



<p>Even before the COVID-19 pandemic, too many working families felt the squeeze of an ever-increasing cost of living. President Biden’s Build Back Better Agenda is the most significant effort to bring down costs and strengthen the middle class in generations. In addition to major investments in children and care, climate, and health, the framework includes targeted investments that will help lower the costs families pay right away. For example, Build Back Better will lower the cost of health care, child care, and prescription drugs and provide access to free preschool for all three and four year-olds. These investments are paid for, and will increase our economy’s capacity over time by getting more people working and lowering costs families struggle with. President Biden is focused on working with Congress to enact these proposals as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>­­</p>



<p><strong><u>Protecting consumers and promoting competition</u></strong>.</p>



<p>The decades-long trend of corporate consolidation in many sectors of our economy has left consumers, innovators, and our economy worse off. Lack of competition drives up prices for consumers, with families paying higher prices for prescription drugs, hearing aids, internet service, and more.&nbsp; President Biden is focused on promoting competition to make our economy more productive, boost growth and innovation, and generate lower prices and more options for consumers. In July, the President <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/09/fact-sheet-executive-order-on-promoting-competition-in-the-american-economy/">signed a historic Executive Order</a> establishing a whole-of-government effort to boost competition in the American economy. The Order includes 72 initiatives by more than a dozen federal agencies to promptly tackle some of the most pressing competition problems across our economy. For example, in October the Food and Drug Administration released a new proposed rule that would make it possible for hearing aids to be sold over the counter without a prescription, which is expected to save people hundreds of dollars.<br><br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on January Consumer Price Index&#160;Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/10/statement-by-president-biden-on-january-consumer-price-index-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 15:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My two top economic priorities have been to create a growing economy with more good-paying jobs, and to lower the prices Americans have faced from the global problem of inflation related to the pandemic. We have seen historic success on the first priority, with the greatest year of job growth in history, Americans finding better&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>My two top economic priorities have been to create a growing economy with more good-paying jobs, and to lower the prices Americans have faced from the global problem of inflation related to the pandemic. We have seen historic success on the first priority, with the greatest year of job growth in history, Americans finding better jobs, better wages, and better benefits, along with the fastest economic growth in decades. On higher prices, we have been using every tool at our disposal, and while today is a reminder that Americans’ budgets are being stretched in ways that create real stress at the kitchen table, there are also signs that we will make it through this challenge.</p>



<p>While today’s report is elevated, forecasters continue to project inflation easing substantially by the end of 2022. And fortunately we saw positive real wage growth last month, and moderation in auto prices, which have made up about a quarter of headline inflation over the last year. We separately saw good news with new unemployment claims continuing to decline. That’s a sign of the real progress we’ve made in getting Americans back to work over the last year.</p>



<p>My administration will continue to be all hands on deck to win this fight. We will continue to rebuild our infrastructure and manufacturing, so we can make more in America and strengthen our supply chains here at home. We will continue to fight to lower costs in areas that have held back families and working people for decades, from prescription drugs to child care and elder care to their energy costs. And we will continue to promote more competition to make our markets more competitive and give consumers more choices.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
