<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:10:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Intent to Nominate and Appoint Leaders to Serve in Key Religious Affairs&#160;Roles</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/president-biden-announces-intent-to-nominate-and-appoint-leaders-to-serve-in-key-religious-affairs-roles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 18:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25519</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate and appoint individuals to serve in key roles at the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom: Rashad Hussain, Nominee for Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom Deborah Lipstadt, Nominee for Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism with the Rank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate and appoint individuals to serve in key roles at the U.S. Department of State and the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom:</p>



<ul><li>Rashad Hussain, Nominee for Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom</li><li>Deborah Lipstadt, Nominee for Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism with the Rank of Ambassador</li><li>Khizr Khan, Appointee for Commissioner of the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</li><li>Sharon Kleinbaum, Appointee for Commissioner of the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</li></ul>



<p>Today’s announcement underscores the President’s commitment to build an Administration that looks like America and reflects people of all faiths. Hussain is the first Muslim to be nominated to serve as the Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom, and Lipstadt is a renowned scholar of the Holocaust and antisemitism.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rashad Hussain, Nominee for Ambassador-at-Large for International Religious Freedom</u></strong></p>



<p>Rashad Hussain is Director for Partnerships and Global Engagement at the National Security Council.&nbsp;He previously served as Senior Counsel at the Department of Justice’s National Security Division.&nbsp;During the Obama Administration, Rashad served as U.S. Special Envoy to the Organization of Islamic Cooperation (OIC), U.S. Special Envoy for Strategic Counterterrorism Communications, and Deputy Associate White House Counsel. In his roles as Envoy, Hussain worked with multilateral organizations such as the OIC and UN, foreign governments, and civil society organizations to expand partnerships in education, entrepreneurship, health, international security, science and technology, and other areas.&nbsp;Rashad also spearheaded efforts on countering antisemitism and protecting religious minorities in Muslim-majority countries. Prior to joining the Obama Administration, Rashad worked on the House Judiciary Committee, served as a judicial law clerk to the Hon. Damon Keith on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit, and was an Associate Counsel to the Obama-Biden Transition Project.&nbsp;Rashad received his J.D. from Yale Law School, where he served as an editor of the Yale Law Journal, and Master’s degrees in Public Administration (Kennedy School of Government) and Arabic and Islamic Studies from Harvard University.&nbsp;He has also taught as Adjunct Professor of Law at Georgetown Law Center and the Georgetown School of Foreign Service.&nbsp;He speaks Urdu, Arabic, and Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Deborah Lipstadt, Nominee for Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Anti-Semitism with the Rank of Ambassador</u></strong></p>



<p>Deborah&nbsp;E.&nbsp;Lipstadt is&nbsp;Dorot Professor of Modern Jewish History and Holocaust Studies at Emory University, where she was the founding director of the Institute for Jewish Studies. She&nbsp;is&nbsp;the author of&nbsp;<em>Beyond Belief: the American Press</em>&nbsp;<em>and the Coming of the Holocaust 1933-1945</em>;&nbsp;<em>History on Trial: My Day in Court with a Holocaust Denier</em>;&nbsp;<em>The Eichmann Trial</em>;&nbsp;<em>Holocaust: An American Understanding&nbsp;</em>and&nbsp;<em>Antisemitism: Here and Now</em>.&nbsp;After the British writer and Holocaust denier David Irving sued her for libel, a&nbsp;ten-week trial in London in 2000 resulted&nbsp;in an overwhelming victory for Lipstadt. Lipstadt&nbsp;is currently on the Boards of the Jewish Forward Advisory Committee&nbsp;and&nbsp;the American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee and serves as a judge for the Rohr Prize in Jewish Literature. She has also served in several roles at the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, including&nbsp;twice as a Presidential Appointee to the Museum’s Council, and was asked by President George W. Bush to represent the White House at the 60th anniversary of the liberation of Auschwitz.&nbsp;Lipstadt was previously a member of the U.S. Department of State’s Advisory Committee on Religious Persecution Abroad and&nbsp;was a Board Member of Hillel International, The Defiant Requiem, and The Covenant Foundation.&nbsp;She&nbsp;has received numerous awards for her research and writing and is the recipient of nine honorary degrees. Lipstadt&nbsp;received a B.A. from City College in New York and an M.A. and Ph.D. from Brandeis University. She is fluent in Hebrew.</p>



<p><strong><u>Khizr Khan, Appointee for Commissioner of the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</u></strong></p>



<p>Khizr Khan, founder of the Constitution Literacy and National Unity Project, is an advocate for religious freedom as a core element of human dignity. After immigrating to the United States in 1980, he attended Harvard Law School and obtained his LL.M degree. He is licensed to practice law before the Supreme Court of the United States, various Federal District Courts, and Washington, DC and New York State courts. In his law practice, he devotes a substantial amount of his time to providing legal services to veterans, men and women serving in uniform, and their families.</p>



<p>Khizr Khan is a Gold Star parent of U.S. Army Captain Humayun Khan. Capt. Humayun Khan was a University of Virginia graduate who was killed while serving in Iraq as he stopped an attack on his camp and saved the lives of scores of U.S. soldiers and Iraqi civilians. He was posthumously awarded the Purple Heart and Bronze Star with Valor. He was buried in Arlington National Cemetery Section 60 with full military honors.</p>



<p>Khizr Khan lives in Charlottesville, Virginia. He is author of three books, including<em> An American Family-A Memoir of Hope and Sacrifice</em>, <em>Founding Documents of the United States of America</em>, and <em>This is Our Constitution</em>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sharon Kleinbaum, Appointee for Commissioner of the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom</u></strong></p>



<p>Rabbi Sharon Kleinbaum serves as spiritual leader of Congregation Beit Simchat Torah (CBST) in New York City. She was installed as CBST’s first rabbi in 1992, arriving at the height of the AIDS crisis when the synagogue was in desperate need of pastoral care and spiritual leadership. She guided the congregation through a period of loss and change, while addressing social issues and building a strong and deeply spiritual community. Under her leadership as Senior Rabbi, CBST has become a powerful voice in the movement for equality and justice for people of all sexual orientations, gender identities, and expressions. Rabbi Kleinbaum has long been involved in the fight for human rights, including religious freedom. She previously served on the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom in 2020. For many years Rabbi Kleinbaum has been ranked by <em>Newsweek</em> among the 50 most influential rabbis in America. Rabbi Kleinbaum is also a Commissioner on New York City&#8217;s Commission on Human Rights, serves on Mayor de Blasio&#8217;s Faith Based Advisory Council, and serves on the boards of the New York Jewish Agenda and the New Israel Fund.</p>



<p>Sharon Kleinbaum’s longtime leadership of Congregation Beth Simchat Torah and her outspoken activism have made her a powerful voice for religious freedom, LGBTQ rights and other human rights in America and around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the Passing of Former United&#160;States Senator of Michigan Carl&#160;Levin</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-passing-of-former-united-states-senator-of-michigan-carl-levin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 17:45:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For thirty years, Carl Levin and I served together in the United States Senate. He was one of the most honorable and decent people I have ever known. Brilliant, humble, and principled, Carl earned the trust of his constituents and colleagues by doing the work. He studied the issues in detail. He forged consensus across&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For thirty years, Carl Levin and I served together in the United States Senate. He was one of the most honorable and decent people I have ever known.<br><br>Brilliant, humble, and principled, Carl earned the trust of his constituents and colleagues by doing the work. He studied the issues in detail. He forged consensus across the aisle. He built coalitions across his beloved Michigan. With his head tilted down, his eyes peering over his glasses – Carl always looked people straight into their own eyes, listened with an open mind, and responded the way he saw it with respect.<br><br>Over the course of his thirty-six years in the Senate, the longest serving Senator in Michigan history, he showed how democracy – and our institutions – can deliver and work for the people.<br><br>As chairman and ranking member of the Armed Services Committee during my time leading the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, I saw how he built consensus to protect our national security, uphold our values, and honor the service of every patriot in uniform. He led on critical issues ranging from the nonproliferation of nuclear weapons, ending the use of torture, and recognizing the dignity of every American and allowing them to serve regardless of who they are and who they love.<br><br>A son of Detroit who never forgot where he came from, Carl always stood up for the American worker and the iconic American auto industry. In the midst of the Great Recession in 2009, with Detroit on its back and the industry on the brink, we worked together to do everything we could to get them back up. And they did because of Carl.<br><br>On education, gun safety, on holding corporate America accountable for abuse and greed, and so much more – Carl always looked out for the people.<br><br>Each time I traveled to Michigan with Carl over the years was special. We would talk about how we both got first involved in public life because of issues of civil rights and first got started in elected office – he on the Detroit City Council and I on the New Castle County Council. We would talk about the beauty of the Great Lakes and the Detroit RiverWalk. Most of all, we would talk about family.<br><br>Jill and I send our love to his beloved Barbara, their children, and grandchildren. Despite the full life he lived, we know the void his loss leaves. We know despite his courageous fight against cancer, it still leaves behind a heavy toll. We’re also thinking of our dear friends, his brother and former Congressman Sandy Levin, and his nephew Congressman Andy Levin, who share Carl’s commitment to service and country.<br><br>Carl Levin embodied the character of the people of Michigan he served throughout his remarkable career. Above all, he embodied the best of who we are as Americans.<br><br>May God bless a great American, a dear friend, and a good man.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to Japan to Attend the Closing Ceremony of the Tokyo 2020 Summer Olympic&#160;Games</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-japan-to-attend-the-closing-ceremony-of-the-tokyo-2020-summer-olympic-games/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 16:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to Japan to attend events of the Tokyo 2020 Summer Olympic Games and the Closing Ceremony on Sunday, August 8, 2021. The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation. Members of the Presidential Delegation: Mr.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to Japan to attend events of the Tokyo 2020 Summer Olympic Games and the Closing Ceremony on Sunday, August 8, 2021.</p>



<p>The Honorable Linda Thomas-Greenfield, United States Ambassador to the United Nations, will lead the delegation.</p>



<p>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</p>



<p>Mr. Raymond Greene, Chargé d’Affaires ad interim, U.S. Embassy Tokyo</p>



<p>The Honorable Marcia Bernicat, Senior Official for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment and Acting Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, U.S. Department of State.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On-the-Record Press Call by Senior Deputy Advisor Russ Travers and Ambassador Tracey Jacobson on Operation Allies&#160;Refuge</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/30/on-the-record-press-call-by-senior-deputy-advisor-russ-travers-and-ambassador-tracey-jacobson-on-operation-allies-refuge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25481</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  (July 29, 2021) 10:01 A.M. EDT&#160;MS. HORNE: Good morning, everyone.&#160; Thanks for joining us today.&#160; Today’s call will be on the record, and its contents will be embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time tomorrow &#8212; that’s Friday, July 30th.&#160;Our speakers today are going to be Senior Deputy Homeland Security Advisor Russ Travers from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"> (July 29, 2021)</p>



<p>10:01 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. HORNE: Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us today.&nbsp; Today’s call will be on the record, and its contents will be embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern Time tomorrow &#8212; that’s Friday, July 30th.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our speakers today are going to be Senior Deputy Homeland Security Advisor Russ Travers from the National Security Council and Ambassador Tracey Jacobson from the State Department Afghanistan Coordination Task Force.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Russ, we’ll turn it over to you to get started.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, Emily.&nbsp; And thanks all for joining.&nbsp; As Emily said, my name is Russ Travers.&nbsp; I&#8217;m the Senior Deputy Homeland Security Advisor at the NSC.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I think you know, on the 14th of July, the White House announced Operation Allies Refuge that would support relocations of interested and eligible Afghan nationals and their families who have supported the government and are in the SIV application pipeline.&nbsp; This is not a new program.&nbsp; Helping the brave Afghans who have supported our work in Afghanistan has been a long bipartisan priority in Washington.<br>&nbsp;<br>The original NDAA authorization for Special Immigrant Visas from Iraq and Afghanistan &#8212; it was actually passed under the second Bush administration; it was re-upped in both the Obama and the Trump administrations; and we welcome strong bipartisan support for SIVs in Congress today, including the recent passage in the House of legislation in support of streamlining the application process and increasing the overall numbers of visas authorized.<br>&nbsp;<br>Since President Biden&#8217;s announcement this April that U.S. forces would be leaving Afghanistan, the administration&#8217;s immediate focus has been on interested and eligible Afghan nationals and their families who have supported the U.S. and our partners in Afghanistan and are in the SIV application pipeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>I am immensely proud to announce our first group of Afghan special immigrants to be relocated under Operation Allies Refuge is now on their way to America.&nbsp; This flight represents a fulfillment of the U.S. commitment and honors these Afghans’ brave service in helping support our mission in Afghanistan, in turn helping to keep our country safe.<br>&nbsp;<br>America has a longstanding tradition of welcoming refugees and others to the United States.&nbsp; We, alongside our civil society partners and tens of thousands of volunteers across our nation, look forward to welcoming these friends and partners to their new communities in the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They have all completed rigorous security background checks conducted by the intelligence community and the Departments of State and Homeland Security.&nbsp; And they now join the over 70,000 Afghans who have received SIVs and started new lives in the U.S. since 2008.<br>&nbsp;<br>Their arrival is the culmination of an enormous effort across the U.S. government and one that is a high moment of our careers.&nbsp; So many of us have deep, personal connections here, whether we served at Embassy Kabul, worked alongside these Afghans as diplomats or servicemembers, or worked to advance the Afghan peace process.<br>&nbsp;<br>It is important to emphasize that our first priority is relocating to the United States about 700 Afghan principal SIV applicants and their immediate families who have completed the majority of the process including a thorough background check.<br>&nbsp;<br>Including family members, we estimate there will be approximately 2,500 Afghans in this group, and we have something over 200 people on this first flight, principal applicants and their families.<br>Once these Afghan special immigrants are paroled into the U.S. and complete a medical exam as required by law, they will be resettled to cities across the country with assistance through the United States Refugee Admissions Program.&nbsp; We expect to continue relocating applicants and their families over the course of a few weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>In closing, I want to emphasize that the safety and privacy of these brave individuals and their families has been the North Star during this entire process.&nbsp; Accordingly, we are not going to speak to any details about the routes or timing of their transit.&nbsp; You can appreciate that they are in the midst of a long, very grueling journey, and our focus right now is on welcoming them safely and protecting details that may impact the travel of future SIV arrivals.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, with that, I&#8217;ll turn thing over to Ambassador Jacobson for more detail on the State-Department-headed interagency task force.<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; Good morning everyone.&nbsp; On behalf of all the members of the task force, I want to say how honored and privileged we are to be working as part of the overall interagency effort on this important process.<br>&nbsp;<br>We launched this task force last Monday to bring together the expertise and the individuals from across the interagency to meet the President&#8217;s initial instruction to start relocating Afghans &#8212; Special Immigrant Visa applicants &#8212; before the end of July, but also to work together to find efficiencies to innovate, to streamline the process going forward to maximize the number of people that we will be able to relocate.<br>&nbsp;<br>And on our team, it&#8217;s not just the State Department.&nbsp; We also have Department of Homeland Security, Health and Human Services, and, of course, the Department of Defense.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think Russ has said most of what we have on the process, but just so you know, this initial group that we&#8217;re talking about of 700-plus principal applicants and their families that we&#8217;re bringing through, through this process, have undergone extensive screening.&nbsp; They are at the very end of the immigrant visa process, lacking only a couple of steps that we will be performing at Fort Lee.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>They have all been COVID tested.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve had a fitness-to-fly exam.&nbsp; And we have offered vaccines in Kabul to those who are interested in having them, and we will also be offering those vaccines at Fort Lee.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, at Fort Lee, they will need a medical clearance, as required by DHS, to grant them immigrant status.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what will be happening at Fort Lee &#8212; is that medical and the DHS processing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then we&#8217;re working with our partner, IOM, which will relocate people around the country.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll be taking information from them &#8212; the travelers.&nbsp; When they have particular connections in the United States &#8212; family or other connections &#8212; IOM will look to resettle them in those locations.&nbsp; And otherwise, they will go where IOM has capacity, with assistance through the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program under the State Department Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to continue to work on this.&nbsp; We will continue to relocate eligible SIV applicants and their families who have our gratitude for their service.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I also want to underscore that the U.S. partnership with Afghanistan is continuing.&nbsp; As Secretary Blinken said, &#8220;even as we&#8217;re withdrawing our forces, we&#8217;re remaining very much engaged in Afghanistan: supporting the government, economic assistance, development assistance, assistance for the security forces, and diplomacy to try to bring the parties together for a peaceful resolution of the conflict.&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our Consular Section in Kabul is going to continue processing SIVs.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re very much looking forward to our Afghan colleagues taking their first steps as new immigrants in our country and very pleased to join today on this call.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. HORNE: Thank you.&nbsp; Operator, we&#8217;re ready for some questions now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much. &nbsp;&nbsp;A question about the other Afghans &#8212; womens leaders, human rights leaders, educators.&nbsp; Is there any plan being considered to evacuate other people who are being targeted and can be targeted by the Taliban if they want to leave beyond the SIV program?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; Well, as you suggest, Andrea, the SIV program is statutory.&nbsp; It has very specific requirements and would not cover many of these individuals.&nbsp; However, U.S. Embassy Kabul can make referrals to the U.S. Refugee Admission Program for any Afghans who are well known to the embassy and have both imminent and compelling protection concerns.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this would, by definition, include women&#8217;s leaders, activists, human rights defenders, civil society, and journalists.&nbsp; So, there is that program available.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, I&#8217;d like to follow up on Andrea&#8217;s question.&nbsp; The administration has been considering doing or creating an equivalent of what &#8212; of the programs for Iraqis that has been suspended.&nbsp; It was for, I guess &#8212; I can&#8217;t remember the exact term, but it&#8217;s a special visa; it’s not an SIV.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Iraqi program was suspended because of a fraud investigation that is still going on.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if the administration is still considering creating the second category of visas for Afghans who do not meet the SIV requirements, but are U.S affiliated and under threat or other Afghans who are also under threat from the Taliban, particularly women, women pilots &#8212; that kind of person.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; Do you want to answer, Tracey?&nbsp; Want me to?<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; Sure, just to say that it&#8217;s true the administration is considering a variety of different options, and we&#8217;ll have more on that for you in the future.&nbsp; Nothing on that today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;Hi. &nbsp;Thanks very much for doing the call. &nbsp;(Inaudible) kind of a logistical question. &nbsp;How long will (inaudible) the refugee program? &nbsp;I mean, obviously, we would very much like to speak with them and do stories, which I gather isn&#8217;t going to happen at Fort Lee. &nbsp;But I&#8217;d like any information you can provide about access &#8212; media access (inaudible) these folks in the coming weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; So, excuse me, you cut out during that call a little bit, but I think what you were asking is how long do we expect them to be at Fort Lee and can you speak to the applicants afterwards.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s the question I&#8217;m going to answer, and if it was a different question, I apologize.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; No, no, that’s it.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, this is the first time we&#8217;re doing this, and it&#8217;s a sort of big lift for State PRM, for DHS, and for the NGO colleagues that are working with us to process these medical exams and the DHS adjustment of status.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking at about seven days.&nbsp; We hope, over time, to shorten that.&nbsp; But that is our planning horizon for this first flight, and we&#8217;ll see how it goes, and we will learn from the experience of this first flight and apply it to future flights.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of engaging with these individuals, you know, they&#8217;re entitled to their privacy.&nbsp; If any of them express an interest in speaking to the media &#8212; and some of them may &#8212; we will work to hook you up.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re not going to ask them to speak to the media given that these folks have, in recent days, left their entire lives behind and immigrated to the United States with just their luggage.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re going to let them settle in and resettle.&nbsp; But if any of them are keen to talk to you, we&#8217;ll let you know.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, there.&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for holding the call.&nbsp; A couple of questions about the folks who are still left behind in Afghanistan.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spoken with people in the process who say that they have a dangerous road between where they live and getting to Kabul.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t know, if they go to Kabul, how many &#8212; how long they&#8217;ll have to wait, if they&#8217;ll have to go back to their dangerous home province.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Is there any support being offered for them once they get to Kabul so they can stay there?&nbsp; And are you still considering an option of just expediting all of these applicants out to Guam or another safe area where the processing can continue and they won’t be in danger from the Taliban advances?<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; I’ll take that one, Russ, if you like.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; Sure, go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; We&#8217;re going be moving folks as fast as we logistically can.&nbsp; We do lack the capacity to bring people to Kabul from other parts of the country or to house them in Kabul itself.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>While we&#8217;re focused on this initial group of applicants who are very far along in their SIV process, bringing them to the United States, we are also looking, in the coming weeks, to start moving people who are less farther along to a third-country location so that they can be safe while their visa processing continues.&nbsp; And those individuals, when they finish that processing, will be brought to the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what I have for you now on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for holding this call and for taking my question.&nbsp; What advice do you have for SIVs in Afghanistan who haven’t heard anything yet?&nbsp; Is there someone they can contact?&nbsp; Should they be reaching out to the embassy?<br>&nbsp;<br>And I have two follow-ups.&nbsp; One is: Did you say there are 750 or 250 on the flight?&nbsp; And then how long after the pullout of troops will you continue with this program?<br>&nbsp;<br>AMBASSADOR JACOBSON:&nbsp; So, I do apologize &#8212; there were three questions there.&nbsp; As to the exact number on the flight, it is just over 200.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not 250.&nbsp; We don’t want to get into exact details, but, you know, we initially manifest the flight, and then, of course, some people who test positive for COVID are not allowed to fly, and they will have to quarantine and isolate in accordance with CDC guidelines before we will put them on another flight.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We absolutely intend to continue this program after the pullout of troops.&nbsp; In terms of who people can contact, it&#8217;s the same organization that they contact with regards to their SIV.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; the National Visa Center is the organization that fields inquiries from applicants.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. TRAVERS:&nbsp; And I would just add that the 700-plus is the cohort that we&#8217;re talking about of SIVs who are at this relevant stage &#8212; have had all their security vetting &#8212; so it&#8217;s they and their families that will be looking to relocate over the coming days and weeks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. HORNE:&nbsp; All right, thank you, everyone.&nbsp; That concludes our call.&nbsp; Reminder that the contents are embargoed until 5:00 a.m., tomorrow, Friday morning.&nbsp; And we are on the record today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks all.<br>&nbsp;<br>10:17 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden on the Arrival of the First Flight of Operation Allies&#160;Refuge</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/30/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-arrival-of-the-first-flight-of-operation-allies-refuge/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today is an important milestone as we continue to fulfill our promise to the thousands of Afghan nationals who served shoulder-to-shoulder with American troops and diplomats over the last 20 years in Afghanistan. This morning, the first flight of Operation Allies Refuge has arrived in the United States, carrying Afghans who are eligible for Special&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today is an important milestone as we continue to fulfill our promise to the thousands of Afghan nationals who served shoulder-to-shoulder with American troops and diplomats over the last 20 years in Afghanistan. This morning, the first flight of Operation Allies Refuge has arrived in the United States, carrying Afghans who are eligible for Special Immigrant Visas (SIV) and their families. These arrivals are just the first of many as we work quickly to relocate SIV-eligible Afghans out of harm’s way—to the United States, to U.S. facilities abroad, or to third countries—so that they can wait in safety while they finish their visa applications.<br><br>These first Afghans are able to come directly to the United States because they have already completed extensive background checks and security screening by the Intelligence Community and the Departments of State and Homeland Security. They will complete the final steps of their visa applications and required medical checks at Fort Lee, in Virginia, before traveling onward to begin their new lives in the United States.<br><br>I want to honor all those in the United States who have spoken out on behalf of these brave Afghans, including the proud community of veterans, who have consistently advocated for the Afghans who were by their side in the field in Afghanistan, often serving as translators and interpreters. And I want to thank the diplomats and public servants across our government and around the world who are working tirelessly as part of Operation Allies Refuge.<br><br>Although U.S. troops are leaving, we will continue to support Afghanistan through security assistance to Afghan forces, as well as humanitarian and development aid to the Afghan people to help them sustain their achievements of the past 20 years.&nbsp; We will also continue our diplomatic support for the peace process.&nbsp; We call for an immediate reduction in violence in Afghanistan, and for all regional actors to encourage the parties to return to negotiations without delay so that the Afghan people can achieve a durable and just political settlement that brings the peace and security they deserve.<br><br>Most of all, I want to thank these brave Afghans for standing with the United States, and today, I am proud to say to them: “Welcome home.”</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Meeting with Legislators on&#160;DACA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-legislators-on-daca/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 02:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25499</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today President Biden and Vice President Harris met with a group of Senators and House members who have been longtime leaders on immigration reform and integral partners in this work. &#160;They discussed their shared support for Dreamers and the actions this Administration is taking to protect them, their livelihood, and their ability to stay in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today President Biden and Vice President Harris met with a group of Senators and House members who have been longtime leaders on immigration reform and integral partners in this work. &nbsp;They discussed their shared support for Dreamers and the actions this Administration is taking to protect them, their livelihood, and their ability to stay in the United States. &nbsp;Dreamers are as American as the rest of us, and they make our country a better place with their talents and contributions.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden and Vice President Harris expressed their strong support for including immigration reform in upcoming reconciliation legislation to enable Dreamers, TPS recipients, farmworkers and essential workers to gain long-awaited pathways to citizenship.&nbsp; President Biden and Vice President Harris thanked the lawmakers for their tireless leadership on immigration reform and reiterated their dedication to establishing an immigration system that is orderly, fair, humane, and reflects American values.<br><br>Senators and House Members expressed their gratitude for the Administration’s enduring commitment and support for providing pathways to citizenship through reconciliation.<br><br>Lawmakers who participated in the meeting were:</p>



<ul><li>Senator Dick Durbin (D-IL)</li><li>Senator Catherine Cortez Masto (D-NV)</li><li>Senator Bob Menendez (D-NJ)</li><li>Senator Alex Padilla (D-CA)</li><li>Senator Ben Ray Lujan (D-NM)</li><li>Congressman Jerry Nadler (D-NY-10)</li><li>Congressman Pete Aguilar (D-CA-31)</li><li>Congresswoman Zoe Lofgren (D-CA-19)</li><li>Congresswoman Lucille Roybal Allard (D-CA-40)</li><li>Congressman Raul Ruiz (D-CA-36)</li><li>Congresswoman Linda Sanchez (D-CA-38)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/29/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I&#8217;m going to be late to a very important date.&#160; If I miss this &#8212; getting out to see my wife &#8212; I&#8217;m in trouble.&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; President Biden, how did your meeting on DACA go?&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; It went very well.&#160; What I think we sh- &#8212; I think we should include in the reconciliation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to be late to a very important date.&nbsp; If I miss this &#8212; getting out to see my wife &#8212; I&#8217;m in trouble.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, how did your meeting on DACA go?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It went very well.&nbsp; What I think we sh- &#8212; I think we should include in the reconciliation bill the immigration proposal.&nbsp; My staff is putting out a message right now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you think the country will have another wave &#8212; another peak of cases?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Say again?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you think the United States will have another wave of cases, another peak of coronavirus cases?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I hope not.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, did you talk to Kyrsten Sinema about the reconciliation package when you spoke to her on infrastructure the other day?&nbsp; She says she&#8217;s not on board with the $3.5 trillion (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; She&#8217;s on board for passing if in fact she sees all the pieces of it.&nbsp; That’s why she allowed the budget to go forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Laying Out the Next Steps in Our Effort to Get More Americans Vaccinated and Combat the Spread of the Delta&#160;Variant</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/29/remarks-by-president-biden-laying-out-the-next-steps-in-our-effort-to-get-more-americans-vaccinated-and-combat-the-spread-of-the-delta-variant/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 23:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 4:23 P.M. EDT&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Today, I want to talk with you about COVID-19. Maybe the best way to start is: In a significant part of the country, you wouldn&#8217;t have to take one of these off, you don&#8217;t have to put one on &#8212; like in my home state of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>4:23 P.M. EDT&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Today, I want to talk with you about COVID-19.<br><br>Maybe the best way to start is: In a significant part of the country, you wouldn&#8217;t have to take one of these off, you don&#8217;t have to put one on &#8212; like in my home state of Delaware, where I lived in New Castle County, where I was yesterday in Pennsylvania &#8212; because people got vaccinated.&nbsp; They got vaccinated.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t need a mask when the majority &#8212; the vast majority of people got vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, look, I want to talk about what&#8217;s really happening &#8212; what it means, what it doesn&#8217;t mean, and what we need to do this week and the months ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>From the moment I was elected, I said I&#8217;d always give it to you straight from the shoulder, and we need some straight talk right now.&nbsp; Because there’s a lot of fear and misinformation in the country, and we need to cut through it with facts, with science, with the truth.<br><br>So, what’s really happening today?<br><br>After months and months of cases going down, we’re seeing a spike in COVID cases.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going up.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Because of this new form, this new variant called the “Delta variant.&#8221;<br><br>This is a much different variant than the one we dealt with previously.&nbsp; It’s highly transmissible, and it’s causing a new wave of cases in those who are not vaccinated.<br><br>Our experts tell me that cases will go up further<br>before they start to come back down.&nbsp; But while cases are on the rise, they&#8217;re not &#8212; we’re not likely to see, according to experts, a comparable rise in hospitalizations or deaths in most areas of the country.<br><br>So, you have to ask yourself: Why is that?&nbsp; Because 164 million Americans are fully vaccinated, including 80 percent of those most vulnerable &#8212; our seniors.<br><br>So, there’s a challenge, as we knew there could be.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s also good news.<br><br>We&#8217;ve spent the last six months preparing for this possibility.&nbsp; The vaccines are highly effective.&nbsp; We have enough vaccine for everyone to get vaccinated.<br><br>And thanks to the American Rescue Plan and the hard work of the American people, we&#8217;ve administered over 325 million vaccination doses in the past six months.<br><br>We have the tools to prevent this new wave of COVID from shutting down our businesses, our schools, our society, as we saw happen last year.<br><br>I’ve said from the beginning that we will be guided by the science.&nbsp; So here’s what the science tells us:<br><br>On Tuesday, the Center for Disease Control and Prevention &#8212; the CDC &#8212; announced its new mask recommendation in parts of the country where COVID cases are substantially high, where people didn’t get vaccinated &#8212; which they define as 50 new cases for every 100,000 people in a week.<br><br>The CDC recommends you wear a mask when you’re in public and indoors, like work or in a grocery store.&nbsp; That’s true for both the vaccinated and the unvaccinated.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Because even if you’ve been fully vaccinated and protected from severe illness from COVID-19, you could have the Delta variant in your system<br>and spread it to someone who isn’t vaccinated.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We need to wear masks to protect each other and to stop the rapid spread of this virus as we work to get more people vaccinated.<br><br>And I hope all Americans who live in areas with substantial or high case rates will follow the mask guidance that’s being laid down by the CDC.&nbsp; I certainly will.&nbsp; And I have &#8212; because this is one of those areas, in Washington.&nbsp;<br><br>And at my decision &#8212; at my direction, all federal personnel and visitors to federal buildings will have to do the same thing.<br><br>As I’ve said from the beginning, a mask is not a political statement; it’s about protecting yourself and protecting others.&nbsp; Masking is one defense against the spread of COVID-19.<br><br>But make no mistake: Vaccines are the best defense against you getting severely ill from COVID-19 &#8212; the very best defense.<br><br>And you want to know how we put this virus behind us?&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I’ll tell you how: We need to get more people vaccinated.<br><br>Look, and it&#8217;s important to understand what vaccines do and what they don&#8217;t do.&nbsp; Put simply, the vaccines are designed to save lives and prevent severe illness.&nbsp; They&#8217;re highly effective at both.&nbsp;<br><br>A hundred and ninety million Americans have had at least one shot.&nbsp; Of that group, about 90 percent are done now, and 10 percent are waiting for the second shot.&nbsp;<br><br>To those folks who have one shot but not the second: Go get the second shot.&nbsp; Even if you&#8217;re overdue for the second shot, it is not too late.&nbsp; Go get the second shot now.&nbsp; Now.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line is: If you&#8217;re fully vaccinated, you&#8217;re highly protected from COVID-19.&nbsp; But I also know that many of you who are vaccinated are concerned about what&#8217;s called &#8220;breakthrough cases.&#8221;&nbsp; Yes, some fully vaccinated people will still test positive, and some will show some symptoms of COVID-19.&nbsp; That&#8217;s expected with almost every vaccine there is for other diseases.&nbsp;<br><br>But breakthrough cases remain rare and almost all are mild cases.&nbsp; In fact, virtually all hospitalizations and deaths are among the unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>I also know many of you are wondering if you&#8217;ll need a booster shot to add another layer of protection.&nbsp; As of now, my medical advisors say the answer is no.&nbsp; No American needs a booster now.&nbsp;<br><br>But if the science tells us there&#8217;s a need for boosters, then that&#8217;s something we&#8217;ll do.&nbsp; And we have purchased the supply &#8212; all the supply we need to be ready if that was called for.<br><br>Folks, the truth is, as more people get vaccinated, we are better protected as a nation to continue reopening safely and responsibly.&nbsp;<br><br>But we are not fully out of the woods yet, because what is happening in America right now is a pandemic &#8212; a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; Let me say that again: It&#8217;s a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>There are about 90 million Americans who are eligible to get the shot but haven&#8217;t gotten it yet.&nbsp; As I just mentioned, nearly all of the cases, hospitalizations, and deaths due to COVID-19 today are from unvaccinated people.&nbsp;<br><br>Last month, a study showed that over 99 percent of COVID-19 deaths had been among the unvaccinated &#8212; 99 percent.&nbsp; This is an American tragedy.&nbsp; People are dying and will die who don&#8217;t have to die.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re out there unvaccinated, you don&#8217;t have to die.&nbsp;<br><br>Read the news and you&#8217;ll see stories about unvaccinated patients in hospitals.&nbsp; As they&#8217;re lying in bed, dying from COVID-19, they&#8217;re asking, &#8220;Doc, can I get the vaccine?&#8221;&nbsp; And the doctors have to say, &#8220;Sorry, it&#8217;s too late.&#8221;<br><br>Right now, too many people are dying or watching someone they love dying and saying, &#8220;If I just got vaccinated, if I just…&#8221;&nbsp; It&#8217;s heartbreaking.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s complicated even more because it&#8217;s preventable.&nbsp;<br><br>America is divided between the majority of eligible people who are vaccinated and those who are not.&nbsp; And I understand that many of you in the majority are frustrated with the consequences of the failure of the minority to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>But I want you to know that I&#8217;m going to continue to do everything I can to encourage the unvaccinated to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That includes addressing hesitancy and misinformation head on.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, I know some of you are &#8212; who are unvaccinated think, &#8220;The development of vaccine was rushed, therefore I&#8217;m not going to take a chance.&nbsp; As a result, I think it&#8217;s not safe because it was rushed.&#8221;&nbsp; I understand.&nbsp;<br><br>But let me explain.&nbsp; Our top scientists at the National Institute of Health &#8212; the NIH &#8212; and across the country got to work applying decades of research &#8212; decades of research &#8212; let me repeat that: decades &#8212; that have already been done &#8212; the research &#8212; to develop the COVID-19 vaccine when it hit.<br><br>In the last six months, more than 325 million doses of the vaccine have been administered in the United States and billions of doses administered around the world.&nbsp; The vaccine was developed and authorized under a Republican administration, and has been distributed and administered under a Democratic administration.&nbsp;<br><br>The vaccines are safe, highly effective.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing political about them.&nbsp; Look at all the people who took a shot at it.&nbsp; They later &#8212; we learned a lot of them have already been vaccinated.<br><br>From the start, I have to compliment Republican Senate Minority Leader Mitch McConnell.&nbsp; He hadn&#8217;t made it political.&nbsp; He&#8217;s encouraged people to get vaccinated and is continuing to do so, and his state is in pretty good shape.&nbsp;<br><br>Alabama Republican Governor Kay Ivey recently spoke out to encourage vaccination.<br><br>And even the commentators on Fox who have been belittling this for a long time &#8212; some haven&#8217;t, but many have &#8212; are arguing, &#8220;Get vaccinated.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>Look, this is not about red states and blue states.&nbsp; It&#8217;s literally about life and death.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about life and death.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what it&#8217;s about.&nbsp;<br><br>You know &#8212; and I know people talk about freedom.&nbsp; But I learned, growing up at school and from my parents, with freedom comes responsibility.&nbsp; Your decision to be unvaccinated impacts someone else.&nbsp;<br><br>Unvaccinated people spread the virus.&nbsp; They get sick and fill up our hospitals.&nbsp; And that means if someone else has a heart attack or breaks a hip, there may not be a hospital bed for them.</p>



<p>If you’re unvaccinated, you put your doctor and nurses at risk &#8212; the same frontline, essential workers who put their lives on the line over the past year and have gone through hell.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, with freedom comes responsibility.&nbsp; So, please, exercise responsible judgement.&nbsp; Get vaccinated &#8212; for yourself, for the people you love, for your country.</p>



<p>&nbsp;I’m being literal when I say this: As I travel the world, almost every day a foreign leader calls me, asking can I provide his or her country more vaccines.&nbsp;&nbsp;Their people are desperate for vaccines.</p>



<p>I’m doing everything to answer those calls.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’re sending millions of vaccines to people around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;But, folks, it’s an American blessing that we have vaccines for each and every American.&nbsp;&nbsp;We’ve made it our first and top priority to have available vaccines for every eligible American and that’s never going to change as long as I’m here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it’s a shame &#8212; it’s just such a shame to squander that blessing.&nbsp;&nbsp;That’s why after six months of extraordinary work and effort, today I’m laying out additional steps we should be taking to deliver these lifesaving vaccines to more Americans.</p>



<p>First, we’re going to provide more incentives to encourage unvaccinated Americans to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That starts with paid leave to get the shot.&nbsp; We&#8217;re still hearing that people are unable to get time off from their employer to get vaccinated.&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, this is unacceptable.</p>



<p>For some time now, I’ve said you should be able to get the shot and still get paid.&nbsp; Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, the federal government is fully reimbursing any small- or medium-sized business that provides workers with paid time off to get vaccinated.</p>



<p>Employers, this costs you nothing.&nbsp; If you haven’t given employees paid time off, do it now, please.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I’m announcing that we’re taking this a step further.&nbsp;&nbsp; The federal government will now reimburse those employers to give their staffs &#8212; who give their staffs time off not only to get themselves vaccinated, but also to get their family members vaccinated.</p>



<p>That means employers can get reimbursed if they give parents time off &#8212; with paid time, paid leave &#8212; to take their kids or their own parents to get vaccinated.&nbsp; So, I’m calling on all <s>employees</s> [employers] across the country to give paid time off to get the shot or to help a family member do so.&nbsp; I promise you: It will cost you, the employer, nothing.&nbsp; You’ll be reimbursed.</p>



<p>Secondly, I’m announcing that we’ll continue the work &#8212; to work with states to encourage unvaccinated people to get vaccinated.&nbsp; In February, the grocery store chain Kroger’s offered $100 to their associates if they’d get vaccinated.&nbsp; And it worked.&nbsp; Vaccination rates moved up from 50 cent [sic] &#8212; 50 percent to 75 percent among their employees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>States like New Mexico, Ohio, and Colorado are offering similar incentive programs that have helped increase vaccination rates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, today, I’m calling on all states and local governments&nbsp;to use funding they have received, including from the American Rescue Plan, to give $100 to anyone who gets fully vaccinated. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that paying people to get vaccinated might sound unfair to folks who’ve gotten vaccinated already, but here’s the deal: If incentives help us beat this virus, I believe we should use them.&nbsp; We all benefit if we can get more people vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in addition to providing incentives to encourage vaccination, it’s time to impose requirements on key groups to make sure they’re vaccinated.&nbsp; (Clears throat.)&nbsp; Excuse me.</p>



<p>Just this week, we took an important step to protect our veterans.&nbsp; Like many civilian hospital systems are doing, the Department of Veterans Affairs will now require COVID-19 vaccines for doctors and nurses and other healthcare workers who provide medical care for our veterans.</p>



<p>We must do everything possible to protect our veterans from getting COVID when they come to get medical care they so richly earned serving their country.&nbsp; We owe them.</p>



<p>Next, since many vaccinations are required for active duty military today, I’m asking the Defense Department to look into&nbsp;how and when they will add COVID-19 to the list of vaccinations our armed forces must get.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our men and women in uniform who protect this country from grave threats should be protected as much as possible from getting COVID-19.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think this is particularly important because our troops serve in places throughout the world, many where vaccination rates are low and disease is prevalent.</p>



<p>Next, every federal government employee will be asked to attest to their vaccination status.&nbsp; Anyone who does not attest or is not vaccinated will be required to mask no matter where they work; test one or two times a week to see if they have a &#8212; they have acquired COVID; socially distance; and generally will not be allowed to travel for work.<br><br>Likewise, today, I’m directing my administration to take steps to apply similar standards to all federal contractors.&nbsp; If you want to do business with the federal government, get your workers vaccinated.<br><br>Look at the Chamber of Commerce representing tens of thousands of American businesses.&nbsp; The National Association of Manufacturers.&nbsp; The Business Roundtable, which is comprised of the largest and biggest corporations in America.&nbsp; They’re all applauding the actions the federal government is taking, and I urge them to follow suit.&nbsp;<br><br>I also commend the National Football League that has announced that if there are outbreaks among unvaccinated players and personnel, then the team risks forfeiting games.&nbsp; I urge other sport leagues at every level to take every step they can.<br><br>Every day, more businesses are implementing their own vaccine mandates.&nbsp; And the Justice Department has made it clear that it is legal to require COVID-19 vaccines.<br><br>We all want our lives to get back to normal, and fully vaccinated work places will &#8212; will make that happen more quickly and more successfully.&nbsp; We all know that in our gut.&nbsp; With incentives and mandates, we can make a huge difference and save a lot of lives.&nbsp;<br><br>I also want to speak to families with children in school.&nbsp; We can and we must open schools this fall full time.&nbsp; It’s better for our children’s mental and emotional wellbeing, and we can’t afford another year out of the classroom.&nbsp; Every school should be open, and we’re giving them the tools to be able to do so safely.&nbsp; Even in those areas where they have a higher vaccination &#8212; they have a higher rate of COVID.&nbsp;<br><br>Through the American Rescue Plan, we’ve provided schools billions of dollars to implement safety measures: better ventilation, social distancing, and other measures.<br><br>In March, when vaccinations were scarce, I prioritized teachers and school workers by utilizing our Federal Pharmacy Program.&nbsp; Almost 90 percent of educators and school staff are now vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Additionally, the CDC has provided clear guidance on how all schools can safely protect the kids and bring them back to the classroom: every student wear a mask.&nbsp; It’s that simple.<br><br>So, we’ve funded safety measures at schools, we’ve vaccinated teachers and staff, and we can mask up our kids for further protection.<br><br>But once again, there’s one more thing we need to do: Get more adolescents, ages 12 and up, vaccinated now that they’ve been cleared.&nbsp; In the past week, the good news is we’re seeing the average number of 12- to 17-year-olds getting vaccinated go &#8212; increase 22 percent per day.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I’m asking school districts to host one last pop-up vaccination clinic over the coming weeks for kids ages 12 and up.&nbsp; We’re directing the Federal Pharmacy Program to help make that happen.<br><br>Parents, get your children vaccinated.&nbsp; You do it for so many other things right now.&nbsp;<br><br>And for kids under 12, if and when the vaccines are deemed safe for them, we’ll be prepared to get the vaccines administered as quickly and as safely as possible.<br><br>Look &#8212; and as we work to vaccinate more Americans, we’re prepared for outbreaks in areas of &#8212; where there are unvaccinated people.&nbsp;<br><br>My administration has made it clear to every governor that more federal resources are available to them.&nbsp; This includes the deployment of surge teams composed of ex- &#8212; experts from the CDC and the Federal Emergency Management Agency &#8212; the FEMA.<br><br>We’re going to continue to provide states with more testing, treatments, protective equipment, personnel, mobile vaccination clinics to stem the surge of the virus among the unvac- &#8212; unvaccinated.<br><br>The pictures of hospitals in several states overloaded with patients is unnecessary, avoidable, and tragic.&nbsp; You know, we’ll help any health system overloaded and unable to cope with a spike in cases.&nbsp; We’re ready to do that.<br><br>Let me close with this:&nbsp;If you’re at home and vaccinated but anxious or even angry, or if you’re at home and unvaccinated, unbothered and unconvinced, let’s step back and see where we are.&nbsp;<br><br>Just remember how we’ve emerged from a dark winter into a hopeful spring and summer.&nbsp; But really remember just how dark that winter was.<br><br>Over 3,600 Americans were dying each and every day.&nbsp; And now, even with the surge among the unvaccinated, we’re down to that &#8212; 300 Americans a day.&nbsp; Significant.&nbsp;<br><br>Millions of people were out of work, out of homes, out of hope, and going hungry.&nbsp; Remember those long lines of people in their automobiles waiting for a box of food to be put in their trunk?<br><br>Experts and pundits said we couldn&#8217;t get the vaccines.&nbsp; And even if we could get the vaccines, we couldn&#8217;t get them in people&#8217;s arms and couldn&#8217;t get them vaccinated.&nbsp; They predicted our economy would collapse.&nbsp; But remember how we stayed focused and how we went to work?&nbsp;<br><br>In six months, we got 164 million Americans fully vaccinated.&nbsp; And because we vaccinated so many people, put in place so many safety measures, and got economic help to businesses and people most in need, our economy is recovering.&nbsp;<br><br>More than 3 million Americans are back to work since I was sworn in &#8212; a faster job growth than any previous administration.&nbsp; Any.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re experiencing the fastest economic growth in nearly four decades.&nbsp; The best in the world as of now.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, today&#8217;s GDP numbers show that in the first half of the year, our economy grew faster than any point in nearly 40 years.&nbsp; Our economy grew more in six months than most Wall Street forecasters expected for the entire year before we implemented our plan.&nbsp;<br><br>And just yesterday, we announced a bipartisan infrastructure deal that&#8217;s going to continue this momentum over the long term by making the most significant investment to rebuild America in nearly a century.&nbsp;<br><br>But we still have to face many challenges.&nbsp; We still have a lot of work to do as we readjust to a post-pandemic economy.&nbsp; But we have the right plan.&nbsp; We&#8217;re coming back.&nbsp; We just have to stay ahead of this virus.&nbsp;<br><br>I know this is hard to hear.&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s frustrating.&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s exhausting to think we&#8217;re still in this fight.&nbsp; And I know we hoped this would be a simple, straightforward line, without problems or new challenges.&nbsp; But that isn&#8217;t real life.&nbsp; We&#8217;re coming out of the worst public health crisis in 100 years, the worst economic crisis since the Great Depression.&nbsp;<br><br>As I told you before, I carry a card in my pocket &#8212; I hope I have it with me &#8212; I have &#8212; carry a card in my pocket with the number of Americans dead from COVID-19.&nbsp; As of today &#8212; this morning &#8212; the total deaths in the United States were 609,441.&nbsp; Granted, the death rate per day is way down; it&#8217;s down to 400, about, dead.&nbsp;<br><br>But that&#8217;s more deaths than World War One, World War Two, Vietnam, 9/11, Iraq, and Afghanistan wars combined. &nbsp;This is as tough as it gets.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re Americans.&nbsp; When we get knocked down, we get back up.&nbsp; That&#8217;s who we are.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we do.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why there&#8217;s no nation on Earth like us.<br><br>And we&#8217;re prepared like never before.&nbsp; We have the tools to save lives, to keep our economy growing and growing and going.<br><br>After the past six months, following the science, we know we can dramatically lower the cases in this country.&nbsp; We can do this.&nbsp; We brought our economy back to life, and we kept it going.&nbsp; We know we can send our kids back to school.&nbsp; We know we can beat this virus.&nbsp; We can do this.&nbsp; We all just have to do our part.&nbsp;<br><br>My fellow Americans, this nation has never failed when we have come together as the United States of America.&nbsp; So I say to all those who are unvaccinated: Please &#8212; please get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>And to the rest of America: This is no time to be despondent or let our guard &#8212; our guard down.&nbsp; We just need to finish the job with science, with facts, with the truth.&nbsp; And together, as Americans, we&#8217;re going to be able to beat this.<br><br>May God bless you all.&nbsp; May God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how long do you think it might be necessary to wear masks?&nbsp; And at what point do you think people might have to have a booster shot?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I said it in my talk: The booster shot is not needed now.&nbsp; It is possible that it will be needed later.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; they don&#8217;t &#8212; the science hasn&#8217;t dictated that yet.&nbsp; And the fir- &#8212; first part of your question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How long do you think people might have to wear a mask again?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, if you notice, a lot of places, people don&#8217;t have to wear masks.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get that straight.&nbsp; The places where people have gotten vaccinated, where we have a high vaccination rate, people do not have to wear a mask at all.&nbsp;<br><br>Like some of you were with me yesterday when I was up in Lehigh Valley.&nbsp; Didn&#8217;t have to wear a mask there.&nbsp; Don&#8217;t have to mask if you come home to Delaware with me &#8212; I know you love doing that.&nbsp; But you don&#8217;t have to wear a mask.&nbsp; The places people are probably going to have to wear masks: in those communities where the high rate of unvaccinated stays high and they don&#8217;t move &#8212; they don&#8217;t move to getting vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>But I think you&#8217;re going to find the patience of businesses and the patience of a lot of other people running thin.&nbsp; Because the fact is, if you had high vaccination rates, you &#8212; we wouldn&#8217;t be in the spot right now.<br><br>Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, will this set up a &#8212; an American workplace for federal workers and private sector that really is the vaccinated versus the unvaccinated?&nbsp; And is that a pressure you&#8217;re trying to harness now?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, no, I&#8217;m not &#8212; look, what I&#8217;m trying to do is keep people safe.&nbsp; I mean that sincerely.&nbsp;<br><br>So, if in fact you&#8217;re unvaccinated, you present a problem to yourself, to your family, and to those with whom you work.&nbsp; Because as pointed out &#8212; I was asked the question about, &#8220;Why would people who have already been vaccinated get it?&#8221;&nbsp; Well, you got anywhere from 2 to 3 percent, on average &#8212; the last study done &#8212; that can still get COVID.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t get very sick.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t get hospitalized.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not serious, but they can catch it.&nbsp;<br><br>And the concern is they may be able to pass it on.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s all being studied right now.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s important &#8212; thing is, if people are vaccinated, the transmission rate drops through the floor.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s all we&#8217;re trying to do.&nbsp;<br><br>Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you.&nbsp; Why not push for vaccine mandates in states, private companies, schools?&nbsp; Do you want to see those entities pass vaccine mandates?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; I&#8217;d like to see them continue to move in that direction, and that&#8217;s why I point it out.&nbsp; I had asked the Justice Department to determine whether that is &#8212; they&#8217;re able to do that legally, and they can.&nbsp; Local communities can do that.&nbsp; Local businesses can do that.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s still a question whether the federal government can mandate the whole country.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that yet.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, you said, earlier this week, that we are not headed back towards lockdowns.&nbsp; But if the science is evolving, how can you be so confident in that?&nbsp; You heard &#8212; we heard you saying, weeks ago, that &#8220;the virus [was] on the run,&#8221; but Dr. Fauci has also indicated that we are headed in the wrong direction.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, you&#8217;re take &#8212; you&#8217;re literally correct on everything you said, but it doesn&#8217;t make &#8212; come to the conclusion you&#8217;re implying.&nbsp;<br><br>It is clear that if everybody is vaccinated, the existing vaccines work to prevent death, serious illness, hospitalization.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; If every &#8212; so, if tomorrow I can wave a wand and every American was vaccinated, then in fact we&#8217;d be out of the woods.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, can something else happen a year from now?&nbsp; Can there be a different virus?&nbsp; Can there be something?&nbsp; It&#8217;s possible.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m talking about COVID and the existing variants that have come forward so far.&nbsp;<br><br>So, it makes a &#8212; it&#8217;s a simple proposition: If you&#8217;re vaccinated, you find yourself in a situation where you are &#8212; highly unlikely, even if you somehow get the virus; very small percentage do &#8212; that you are not going to be hospitalized, you&#8217;re not going to be on a ventilator, you&#8217;re not going to be sick, but you could be in a position to possibly spread it to someone who wasn&#8217;t if you have it in you.&nbsp;<br><br>Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you.&nbsp; I wanted to ask: Why not require that the people show proof that they&#8217;re vaccinated?&nbsp; And also, if you could just &#8212; with the 4 million, how much of an impact do you think this will have?&nbsp; Do you have a projection, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; A projection on what?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On how many people will get vaccinated by putting in this system?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I can&#8217;t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get in business of projecting &#8212; I &#8212; exactly how many people are likely.&nbsp; All I know is that we go through these periods, then we run up against a wall, then something happens where people realize, &#8220;Oh, my lord, this is really a problem,&#8221; and they begin to see things.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, the fact that a lot of your friends are now saying, &#8220;Get vaccinated,&#8221; who were &#8212; before were saying, &#8220;This is not a problem.&nbsp; This is all a Democratic thing.&#8221;&nbsp; With a small &#8220;d&#8221; and a capital &#8220;D.&#8221;&nbsp; I mean, there&#8217;s a lot changing.&nbsp; People are becoming aware.&nbsp; The more aware they become, then we have these surges of people going out and getting vaccinated &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what about requiring proof &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; and it just keeps building.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, sir.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; What about what?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about requiring proof, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, that is &#8212; there&#8217;s two ways to do it, and I think you&#8217;re going to see some institutions doing that.&nbsp; Like you&#8217;re going to fly abroad, you got to &#8212; you&#8217;re going to have to have proof.&nbsp; You&#8217;re not just going to be able to say, &#8220;Yeah, I got tested.&#8221;&nbsp; You got to pri- &#8212; provide proof.&nbsp;<br><br>My guess is: If we don’t start to make more progress, a lot of businesses and a lot of enterprises are going to require proof for you to be able to participate.<br><br>In the back.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;m going to take off, shortly here.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What further actions are you going to take to encourage private businesses to follow this type of model to either require vaccines or require testing or other preventative procedures?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I just did.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to keep at it.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to be talking about it around the country.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you &#8212; but are you going to reach out to private businesses, meet with them, try and actively encourage them to follow this model?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I have.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have folks from the &#8212; everyone from the Chamber of Commerce to the manufacturers, et cetera.&nbsp; So, you know, I am &#8212; am I going to call a meeting of every, you know, business in the country to come to Washington?&nbsp; And &#8212; or go on &#8212;<br><br>I have made the case repeatedly.&nbsp; I doubt whether there&#8217;s a single, solitary business that doesn’t understand that I think I think it&#8217;s smart for them to require testing, require &#8212; and if you &#8212; if you can&#8217;t demonstrate, you can&#8217;t prove you&#8217;ve been vaccinated, you have to be tested.<br><br>Q &nbsp;Secretary Austin said he was already considering mandating &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yep.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the vaccine after it was fully approved.&nbsp; Would you like to see the mandate go into effect before full approval?&nbsp; And do you think he&#8217;s open to that?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know he&#8217;s open to it.&nbsp; And the question is: When is the right time to get the most bang for the buck when you do it?&nbsp; A lot of this is timing.&nbsp; And so, I think it&#8217;s going to happen, but I &#8212; look, the one thing that you all are politely and appropriately referencing is that it&#8217;s still a temporary approval.&nbsp; So when does the final approval come?&nbsp; It usually takes a lot of &#8212; a lot of work to get &#8212; to get there.<br><br>I made a commitment I would not tell anyone in the Justice Department who they should prosecute and I would not tell the health industry that they &#8212; excuse me, the government health entities what they should say and do.&nbsp; But my expectation is they&#8217;re going to reach that conclusion in the early fall.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you very much.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, one more.&nbsp; Mr. President, you said &#8212; Mr. President, you said &#8212; Mr. President, you said, &#8220;If you are fully vaccinated, you no longer need to wear a mask.&#8221;&nbsp; And it seems &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I didn&#8217;t say that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You did.&nbsp; I have the quote.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I said if you&#8217;re fully vaccinated in an area where you do not have &#8212; well, let me clarify it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In May, you made it sound like a vaccine was &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, in May, that&#8217;s true.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the ticket to losing the mask forever, and it &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That &#8212; that is true at the time, because I thought there were people who were going to understand that getting vaccinated made a gigantic difference.&nbsp; And what happen was: A new variant came along, they didn&#8217;t get vaccinated, it was spread more rapidly, and people &#8212; more people were getting sick.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the difference.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How is the First Lady, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to find out in a minute.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I&#8217;m leaving.&nbsp;<br><br>5:01 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: S. 957 and S.&#160;1910</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/29/bills-signed-s-957-and-s-1910/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:46:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25387</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, July 29, 2021, the President signed into law: S. 957, which requires VA to have specific periods of time for the public disposal of controlled substances medications at certain VA facilities Thank you to Senators John Kennedy (LA) and Mike Braun (IN) as well as Representatives Vern Buchanan (FL-16), Susie Lee (NV-03), Mariannette Miller-Meeks (IA-02), David Trone (MD-06), and Tom&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, July 29, 2021, the President signed into law:<br><br>S. 957, which requires VA to have specific periods of time for the public disposal of controlled substances medications at certain VA facilities<br><br>Thank you to Senators John Kennedy (LA) and Mike Braun (IN) as well as Representatives Vern Buchanan (FL-16), Susie Lee (NV-03), Mariannette Miller-Meeks (IA-02), David Trone (MD-06), and Tom Rice (SC-07) for their leadership;<br><br>and<br><br>S. 1910, the “Major Medical Facility Authorization Act of 2021,” which authorizes various major medical facility construction projects of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and authorizes various appropriations to carry out those projects.<br><br>Thank you to Senators Jerry Moran (KS) and Jon Tester (MT) as well as Representatives Colin Allred (TX-32), Derek Kilmer (WA-06), Mike Levin (CA-49), Kim Schrier (WA-08), and Marilyn Strickland (WA-10) for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, July 29,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/29/press-briefing-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-july-29-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25465</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:37 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; &#160;Hi, everyone.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160;&#160; All right, let&#8217;s get going.&#160; I have some updates on now what &#8212; what was once “BIF,” now it&#8217;s “BID.”&#160; And hopefully we&#8217;ll get it to “BIB”.&#160; That&#8217;s my joke for the day.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160;&#160; All right.&#160; Okay.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Thank you so&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:37 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &nbsp;Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp;&nbsp; All right, let&#8217;s get going.&nbsp; I have some updates on now what &#8212; what was once “BIF,” now it&#8217;s “BID.”&nbsp; And hopefully we&#8217;ll get it to “BIB”.&nbsp; That&#8217;s my joke for the day.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; Get it?<br>&nbsp;<br>All right, as you all saw yesterday, the President and a bipartisan group of senators announced a deal on historic infrastructure investment that will drive economic growth and create good-paying, middle-class jobs.&nbsp; The President is deeply thankful to these senators who he&#8217;s worked closely with these past few months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This will mean breaking &#8212; break- &#8212; this will mean breakthrough investments in our roads and bridges, in public transit, in rail, connecting every American, including undeserved [sic] rural areas &#8212; underserved rural areas, to high-speed Internet, the most significant investment in clean energy transmission and electric vehicle infrastructure in our history, as well as historic investment in clean drinking water.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Combined with the President&#8217;s Build Back Better agenda, the bipartisan deal will help us create 2 million jobs a year for the next decade.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This deal is going to create good-paying union jobs building roads and bridges; working on rail; building unprec- &#8212; unprecedented infrastructure for electric vehicles; replacing poisonous lead water pipes that are hurting our children; building new, more resilient structures.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yesterday, 67 senators &#8212; which includes 17 Republicans, 50 Democrats &#8212; voted to move forward with consideration of this pas- &#8212; package, which is not only welcome because of the life-changing benefits, as I just listed out, this plan would mean for the American people, but also because of the healthy signal about American democracy it sent to the world.&nbsp; And the President&#8217;s colleagues in both parties deserve enormous credit for that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s an incredible &#8212; incredibly broad and diverse coalition behind this deal, as you all know, range &#8212; ranging from the Chamber of Commerce to AFL-CIO, and including the nation’s governors and mayors, building trades, and majorities of Republican and Democratic voters.<br>&nbsp;<br>Last week, an analysis led by John McCain’s former economic advisor found that its benefits would overwhelmingly flow to middle-class and working families as it helps create millions of jobs.<br>&nbsp;<br>A new poll out just this morning from Monmouth shows an overwhelming 70 percent of the public supports the infrastructure package.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President is also fighting for his Build Back Better Agenda, which would make transformational investments in human infrastructure and on climate, on education, the care economy, and on making healthcare affordable while extending the biggest middle-class tax cut in our history.<br> <br>Also, today, GDP numbers &#8212; today’s GDP numbers are further proof of the progress we&#8217;ve &#8212; we’ve had jumpstarting our economy.&nbsp; With today’s data, the U.S. economy has now made up the losses of the last 18 months and surpassed the pre-pandemic GDP peak.<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, in the first year of this &#8212; of the first half of this year, the economy grew at the latest [fastest] rate in nearly 40 years. &nbsp;It took two years after the last recession to return to the previous level. &nbsp;Today, it took half as long.<br>&nbsp;<br>You can see how &#8212; how far we’ve come just by looking at where we were this time last year.&nbsp; In the second quarter of 2020, we saw the largest decline in GDP on record &#8212; a decline of more than 31 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s the &#8212; that’s the story of this President’s economic plan taking us from the worst time of our economy in history to one of the best.<br>&nbsp;<br>That reversal is no &#8212; no accident.&nbsp; It’s the result of President Biden’s plan to curb COVID and deliver economic relief to families, small businesses, and economic &#8212; and communities throughout the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>At &#8212; at that strength isn’t just being reflected in today’s GDP number; it’s being seen across the economy.&nbsp; Earlier this month, we learned that the economy created eight &#8212; 850,000 jobs in June, as you all know, with average of 600,000 jobs created each month since the President took office.<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s a total of over 3 million jobs created under President Biden &#8212; more jobs than any other President’s first ha- &#8212; first four months in history.&nbsp; And importantly, we’re seeing better jobs with higher ra- &#8212; wages across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>Recent independent forecasts from the Congressional Budget Office and the International Monetary Fund both doubled their projections for America’s economic growth this year to the fastest pace in almost 40 years.<br>&nbsp;<br>The last time the economy was growing this fast, Ronald Reagan was &#8212; was telling us it was “Morning in America.”&nbsp; And I think I was about 5 years old.&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And this boom is backed by other signs across the economy: Consumer confidence is up, jobs are up, personal income is up, and unemployment is down in all 389 metro areas in the U.S. compared to last year.<br> <br>And today, I wanted to provide another update, as Jen has been doing these past couple of days, on some of the innovative ways we are reaching Americans on the importance of getting vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>As we work to get more shots in arms, we&#8217;re doubling down on empowering trusted messengers, which have been key to this process, to talk to their communities about the vaccines, including doctors across the country.&nbsp; We have been working with local doctors and local stations to get Americans their facts and answer questions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Since we started this program this summer, this effort has led to more than 400 original stories and syndicated airings &#8212; airings of local doctors’ interviews for a reach of more than 185 million broadcast and online impressions.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, beginning in August, this effort will expand even further with dozens of local African American doctors from the National Medical Association joining in, helping us elevate the voices of Black physicians and reach hard-hit communities.<br> <br>Finally, a brief preview of the President’s remarks later this afternoon: The President will deliver remarks on COVID-19 virus about where he sta- &#8212; we stand, the progress we’ve made, and the steps we need to take now to address rising cases in the nation.<br>&nbsp;<br>He will send a strong message to all Americans &#8212; unvaccinated and vaccinated &#8212; about the need to stay vigilant in our fight against the virus.&nbsp; And he’ll make clear that his administration will continue to provide every resource needed to help communities and individual &#8212; individuals across the country to curb the spread of the Delta variant and boost vaccinations.&nbsp; His remarks will highlight several new measures that his administration will take to accelerate this effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>And now &#8212; and I know you all are eager for specifics on the announcement, but we’ll have something to share shortly on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>You want to take it away, Alex?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So my first question is going to be on specifics, actually, so whatever you can share would be helpful.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a lot of questions about how exactly it would work.&nbsp; Will federal contractors be covered?&nbsp; How will the federal government collect proof of vaccination?&nbsp; And will those who refuse to follow the guidelines be subject to disciplinary action or termination?&nbsp; Is there any clarity you can offer on any of those aspects?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well &#8212; so I&#8217;m &#8212; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President, so I don&#8217;t have anything specific to share.&nbsp; But I&#8217;ll say a little bit more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I know, you know, the official details on the President&#8217;s remarks and any forthcoming guidance that &#8212; that will be coming shortly on federal workers, as you&#8217;re asking about, Alex.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I &#8212; you know, one of the things that I want to kind of touch base on again, which is what I was talking about &#8212; was &#8212; which was one of the things that was under consideration yesterday &#8212; I discussed this yesterday on the plane, on Air Force One, on our way to Pennsylvania &#8212; which is attestation of vaccination.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>For those who may not know, it means confirming a vacci- &#8212; a vaccination status or abiding by stringent COVID-19 protocols like mandatory mask wearing, even in communities not with high or substantial spread, and regular testing for federal employees is one op- &#8212; and in &#8212; is one option under strong consideration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a &#8212; this is a really helpful way to ensure a safe workplace for employees.&nbsp; It also is not dissimilar to some of the protocols that you all have put in place in some of the new &#8212; news room that you work in &#8212; including Fox, Peter, who, to my understanding, is &#8212; is asking for self-attestation to ensure a safe and healthy workplace.&nbsp; So, this is not an unusual matter.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we understand that there&#8217;s significant weight to what the federal government handles &#8212; how the federal government handles reentry.&nbsp; And a key goal of ours is to ensure we have a sustainable model to keep employers across the country &#8212; to make sure that they work in a safe workplace.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then on the SIV arrivals that are coming, can you tell us anything more about that?&nbsp; Are they coming tonight or tomorrow?&nbsp; Are they coming out of commercial charter, military flight?&nbsp; And do you know where they will be distributed when they arrive in the U.S.?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, the President, as you know, said clearly that he is &#8212; he is committed to making sure that the people who helped &#8212; who helped us these past 20 years are also taken care of and being helped as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, you know, I can tell you that the President set a clear goal.&nbsp; We will begin relocating eligible and interested Afghan SIV applicants and their families before the end of this month.&nbsp; We&#8217;re getting close to that.&nbsp; This is a whole-of-government, 24/7, worldwide effort, as you all can imagine, and we intend to meet the President&#8217;s goals.<br>&nbsp;<br>Out of just extreme caution, as you can imagine, Alex and others, and consideration for their safety and security and privacy of the Afghan special immigrants and fa- &#8212; and their families, we&#8217;re not going to discuss or confirm any details of flights at this time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more on the GDP report that you mentioned. While it showed strong economic growth, it also suggested that employers are having trouble rebuilding their inventory and may have trouble, sort of, selling goods in the coming months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And while you guys have said that inflation is just an immediate concern, doesn’t that suggest that there could be lingering inflation effects in the long run if companies are not able to build some of those &#8212; those inventories because of supply chain bottlenecks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just to say a little bit more, just to reiterate &#8212; like today&#8217;s GDP numbers are further proof of the progress we&#8217;ve made in jumpstarting our economy, as I mentioned.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With today&#8217;s data, the U.S. economy has now made up the losses of the last 18 months and surpassed the predemic [sic] peak &#8212; pre-pandemic peak, as I mentioned.<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, the last half &#8212; the last first half of the year, the economy grew at the fastest rate in nearly &#8212; early &#8212; nearly 40 years, and it took two years after the last recession to return to the previous level; today, it took half as long.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, just to give you a little bit more: Just one year ago, CBO predicted real GDP would be 3 percent below its pre-pandemic peak in the second quarter of 2021.&nbsp; Today, we learned that thanks to the shots in arms and checks in pockets, it&#8217;s now above the peak.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You can see how far we&#8217;ve come just by looking at where we were this time last year.&nbsp; In the second quarter of 2020, we saw the largest decline in GDP on record &#8212; a decline of more than 31 percent.<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s basically the story of the President&#8217;s economic plan.&nbsp; This is what he has talked about for some &#8212; for some time, especially when you look at his economic policy, making sure that no one is left behind.&nbsp; This is part of &#8212; as we can imagine, as we&#8217;ve talked about &#8212; the Build Back Better Plan.<br>&nbsp;<br>As it relates to the inflation and this GDP report, you know, we knew the restarting the economy from a standstill in the middle of a pandemic would represent some challenges along the way, but experts inside and outside the administration believe that the data show that most of the price increases we are seeing are expected to be temporary.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, this is why we continue to push for sustainable, smart policies and investment, like the Build Back Better Plan, which the President is going to continue to work hard towards.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I mentioned, this is his economic policy that he&#8217;s talked about for the past year that started with the campaign, and it&#8217;s really to make sure that we do not leave anyone behind.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now that you&#8217;ve got the infrastructure deal, does the President now turn his attention to the reconciliation bill?&nbsp; And does he hope to bring some Republicans along?&nbsp; Or do you believe you&#8217;ll just have to rely strictly on Democratic votes?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so as you can imagine, the President &#8212; this is just the beginning of the process.&nbsp; The President is committed to his Build Back Better plan, as I was just mentioning, which includes the reconciliation plan.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, as you can imagine, the President is going to continue to talk to congressional members on both sides of the aisles, as he&#8217;s been doing this past six months, to make sure that he gets support for something that is incredibly important to the American public.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And secondly, Iran has said they won&#8217;t return to the nuclear talks until their new president is in power, which takes place on August 5th.&nbsp; Do you think the talks will resume then?&nbsp; How long are you willing to wait?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this &#8212; the timing for the seventh round has not yet been announced, as you all know.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re not going to speculate to when that will be.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, we&#8217;ve demonstrated time and again that we&#8217;re prepared to move forward with a mutual return to the compliance with the JCPOA, the Iran nuclear deal.&nbsp; When Iran is done with its presidential transition process, we are prepared to plan our return to Vienna to continue with our talks.<br>&nbsp;<br>We remain interested in seeking mutual return to compliance with the JCPOA, though, as the Secretary has made clear &#8212; Secretary Blinken &#8212; this offer will not be on the table indefinitely.&nbsp; So, this is something that we are still moving forward with and determined to make happen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, can you tell me if you have a ballpark estimate of the percentage of the federal workforce that you believe is still unvaccinated?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have that number to share with you at this time.&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m happy to check with our team, but I don&#8217;t have a number to share on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you believe that the President&#8217;s announcement today &#8212; is one of the goals of this to spark more private businesses to follow suit, as we&#8217;ve already seen in the last coming days?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, you know, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President&#8217;s announcement.&nbsp; But like I said when talking about today, you know, the federal government &#8212; we see ourselves as a model for other &#8212; for other companies and other organizations.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s something that we don&#8217;t take lightly.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, as you can imagine, the President&#8217;s goal &#8212; you know, he&#8217;s going to talk about this &#8212; and the President&#8217;s goal these last six months is to really work to curb this pandemic, this virus, to fight against it, but it&#8217;s going to take all of us.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to take all of us to do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And our push, our message continues to be: We have to make sure that people get vaccinated.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to do that, as we&#8217;ve done these last six months.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much, Karine.&nbsp; We have heard from some associations ahead of the President&#8217;s announcement today &#8212; the Federal Law Enforcement Officers Association says<br>Americans have a right to privacy and choice.&nbsp; They&#8217;re accusing your administration of pushing people to undertake a medical procedure.&nbsp; Are you expecting resistance to this announcement?&nbsp; And what is your response to that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say &#8212; I&#8217;ll say this: Look, our priority is the American people.&nbsp; We have to make sure people are safe and we&#8217;re continuing to save lives.&nbsp; That is the most important thing.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how this President sees this.<br>&nbsp;<br>We listen to the science, and we provide Americans the information they need to protect themselves and help end this pandemic.&nbsp; That is key here.&nbsp; That is critical and important.&nbsp; And that is why we have strongly encouraged Americans to get fully vaccinated, taken unprecedented action to make it easier and convenient.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s very easy to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Just go to Vaccines.gov and make an appointment and get vaccinated.&nbsp; It&#8217;s so important, not just to protect yourself, but to protect your family.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so that is the goal here.&nbsp; This is what we want to do.&nbsp; We want to continue to make it easy and convenient for Americans to get a shot.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve gotten more than 300 million shots in arms.&nbsp; Sixty percent of the population is now fully vaccinated.&nbsp; That includes 80 percent of our most vulnerable &#8212; 65 and older.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so this is what the President is working towards.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we need to do and continue to do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you know, I &#8212; again, I can&#8217;t get ahead of the forthcoming announcement, but here&#8217;s what I&#8217;ll say: First, what I laid out as a strong consideration is a choice &#8212; it is a choice that employees will be able to make because largely unvaccinated people continue to spread the virus, and until we have more people who are vaccinated and are curbing the spread, there needs to be proper protocols to keep Americans safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as a large employer &#8212; the largest in this country &#8212; who cares about the individuals who keep the government running, we have an obligation to be good stewards of the workforce and ensure their health and their safety.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re taking action to protect the federal workforce so that they can continue to execute on the hard and important work of government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And just lastly, the forthcoming protocols, much of what is discussed yesterday is not dissimilar to so many other workplaces as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up really quickly: Will there be any changes to how frequently the President and the people around him are tested?&nbsp; We were told when the breakthrough cases were happening here at the White House that the President is tested every two weeks, some people around him are tested every two days.&nbsp; Any changes to that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new to provide on that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll probably have some more information forthcoming.&nbsp; But as you can imagine, we&#8217;re going to continue to follow the CDC guidelines.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For people&#8217;s expectations, if they&#8217;re federal workers and they choose not to be vaccinated, would they be responsible for the testing protocols themselves?&nbsp; Would that be provided by the federal government?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then when we look at things like masks returning and so forth, does the President feel he needs to set any kind of new timetable for people&#8217;s expectations about how long this new posture, given the Delta variant, might last?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t have anything further on your first question, Kelly.&nbsp; So, I’ll let the President speak to that very, very soon &#8212; in about a little bit more than an hour, he&#8217;ll lay out his plans and what he’s &#8212; wants to talk to the American people about.<br>&nbsp;<br>To your &#8212; to your other question &#8212; can you repeat that again?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Setting expectations.&nbsp; Since people are wearing masks now in D.C., we’ve got indoor mask requirements that’s happening in a lot of places around the country.&nbsp; We know just a few weeks ago the President had a very different approach.&nbsp; The science has changed, we&#8217;re told.&nbsp; Is he going to try to set expectations for the public?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I think the President, you know, I don&#8217;t &#8212; there&#8217;s not a goal or ex- &#8212; you know, anything like that that we&#8217;re putting forth at this moment.&nbsp; What we want to make sure is that we get our message out there and make sure people are getting vaccinated.&nbsp; That is what the science tells us, that&#8217;s how we&#8217;re going to curb this pandemic is making sure that people get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what the President tries to do every time &#8212; almost every time he is at the podium or speaking to the American people, he says that.&nbsp; He did that yesterday when I was with him in Pennsylvania.&nbsp; He started at the top of his remarks talking about how this is a pandemic for the unvaccinated and it continues to be.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to be working towards.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; So, President Biden says that we are not returning to lockdowns, shutdowns, and school closures, but he also once said that we didn&#8217;t have to wear masks anymore once we were vaccinated.&nbsp; So, why should Americans trust him now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, because we listen to the scientists; we listen to the expert.&nbsp; This is a public health situation.&nbsp; This is not about politics at all.&nbsp; This is about saving lives.&nbsp; And this is what the President is all about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He wants to make sure that we are saving lives.&nbsp; If you look at, Peter, the last six months, that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s done every day.&nbsp; And we &#8212; and you see that in the numbers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now we&#8217;re at a point where we have to double down and make it very, very clear to people that we can&#8217;t &#8212; we can&#8217;t let the pandemic win.&nbsp; We have to continue to fight.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So if you’re listening to the science, if scientists come to you at some point down the line and say, “It is our opinion that there should be shutdowns and there should be school closures,” you would do that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we listen to &#8212; like I said, we listen to the CDC and the expert and their guidance.&nbsp; Our &#8212; you know, our &#8212; the CDC is a body that is very well respected.&nbsp; And we fol- &#8212; again, we follow their guidance.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And after this new guidance came out, the head of the American Federation of Teachers, Randi Weingarten, came out to say, “We&#8217;re going to try to open up schools.”&nbsp; Is that good enough for the President &#8212; just trying?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, the President and the Secretary of Education has been very clear: By this fall, they want to see all schools open.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been very clear about that the last six months.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why, in the historic American Rescue Plan that that he signed into law in April, there are resources in that plan to make sure that schools are able to open up safely, that schools have the resources to get &#8212; to have the PPE, to get that ventilation.&nbsp; And so, the President had that in mind when he signed &#8212; when he put together that plan and signed it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But now that &#8212; after the plan was out there, now, after this new guidance, the teachers are saying they&#8217;re just going to “try.”&nbsp; Is that okay?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we’re going to continue to work closely, as we have, with local governments, with the teachers, as we’ve done and have &#8212; and continue to have those conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to add, though, that nearly 90 percent of teachers are currently vaccinated.&nbsp; That’s a good sign.&nbsp; Now we just have to make sure we also protect our kids &#8212; right? &#8212; in school; we protect their &#8212; we protect the other administrators at school, people who have &#8212; who are immunocompromised.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the CDC put out that guidance, making sure that people are wearing masks in schools.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last one &#8212; just because you talked about this administration having a priority of protecting the American people: Can you help us understand why is it that the federal government is asking vaccinated Americans to wear masks to stop the spread of COVID-19, but at the same time, federal agents are also releasing COVID-19-positive border crossers into small towns in Texas?&nbsp; How is that stopping the spread?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let&#8217;s step back for a second because I’ve &#8212; you know, this is &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Weather alert sounds.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Oh, okay.&nbsp; Very interesting.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure everything is fine.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Um &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Something I said?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It could be me.&nbsp; It may &#8212; but, you know, you did laugh at my joke, so maybe that’s a reaction to laughing at my joke.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s &#8212; I just want to be very clear here &#8212; I do want to answer your question, Peter.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, just to step back and do this 30,000-foot view: There&#8217;s been no change in Title 42.&nbsp; Families and single adults are expelled, if possible, when apprehended at the southern border.&nbsp; The majority of apprehensions that we saw at the border in June were expelled.&nbsp; Those who can&#8217;t be expelled or are &#8212; or are awaiting processing are often placed in alternative &#8212; alternatives to detention programs while their cases are being reviewed.<br>&nbsp;<br>CBP provides a migrant with PPE from the moment &#8212; from the moment they are taken into custody, and migrants are required to keep masks on at all times, including when they are transferred or in the process of being released.&nbsp; If anyone exhibits signs of illness in CBP custody, they are referred to local health systems for appropriate testing, diagnosis, isolation, and treatment.&nbsp; CBP takes its responsibility to prevent the spread of communicable diseases very, very seriously.<br>&nbsp;<br>We value our partners in local communities whose work is critical to moving individuals safely out of custody and through the appropriate immigration pathway, and assist in mitigating COVID-19 and isolating, quarantining when needed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s what I have for you, Peter.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; I know you don&#8217;t have a number, but so we understand the changes that the President is going to announce, what is the current policy for federal workers reporting their vaccination status, you know, getting tested?&nbsp; What does that look like?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’m going to not get ahead of the President here, again.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I mean, right now.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to share with you about what the current policy is at this moment.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to go back and check with the team and see what we can get from that from &#8212; for you on that, but I also don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll talk about this himself, and I just don&#8217;t want to get ahead of him.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So nothing to share on whether workers have to report anything?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I don&#8217;t have anything to share.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, yesterday, some federal whistleblowers came forward to raise concerns about the conditions inside the Fort Bliss HHS facility housing migrant children.&nbsp; They reported inadequate mental health services, filthy conditions, mismanagement.&nbsp; Has the President been briefed on this?&nbsp; Or are there any steps being taken to investigate?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I have not spoken to the President about this.&nbsp; I have not myself have seen this report to be able to talk to him about this.&nbsp; Let me, you know, check in with our team.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you could imagine, the safety of migrants, the safety of young &#8212; of young people is incredibly important to us since they are in our care, as you can imagine.&nbsp; And so this is something that I&#8217;ll check with our &#8212; with our team on.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Jenny.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; On the eviction moratorium, which expires at the end of this week &#8212; and we all saw Jen’s statement on this &#8212; my colleagues just reported that congressional Democrats are seeking to extend that through December.&nbsp; Does the White House support Congress extending it to that deadline, or do you have a different deadline in mind?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me step back for a second because this is an incredibly important issue, as you could imagine, to the American people.&nbsp; So, given the recent spread of the Delta variant, including among those Americans both most likely to face evictions and lacking vaccinations, the President &#8212; President Biden would have strongly supported a decision by the CDC to further extend this eviction moratorium to protect renters at this moment of heightened vulnerability.&nbsp; Unfortunately, as some of you might know, the Supreme Court has made clear that this option is no longer available.<br>&nbsp;<br>In June, when CDC extended the eviction moratorium until July 31st, the Supreme Court&#8217;s ruling stated that clear and specific congressional authorization via new legislation would be necessary to the CDC to extend moratorium past July 31st.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, in light of the Supreme Court&#8217;s ruling, you know, the President is going to work with Congress to make that happen, and that is something that they&#8217;re working on while &#8212; we&#8217;ll probably, hopefully, be working closely with them on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One follow-up on that.&nbsp; Some lawmakers, including Maxine Waters, are also pushing the CDC to just extend the moratorium again and then challenge the courts to overturn it.&nbsp; So, if the congressional route doesn&#8217;t work in the timeframe that you have, why not go that route and see what the Supreme Court does?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me just share a little bit about what we have been doing.&nbsp; So, we will continue an all-of-government effort to keep Americans safe and housed through the swift dispersal of Emergency Rental Assistance to states and cities, which has been pretty &#8212; which has been incredibly important to the American people.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to make sure we get the word out and so that people know that the availability of rental assistance is out there and to support grantees in ramping up their efforts.<br>&nbsp;<br>Yesterday, we held a Day of Action to promote the availability of rental assistance, which reached tens of millions of Americans.&nbsp; Last week, the Treasury released new data on Emergency Rental Assistance Program, which showed that more than $1.5 billion in assistance was delivered to eligible households in the month of June &#8212; more than what was provided in the previous five months combined.&nbsp; So, in June alone, this assistance served nearly 300,000 households, preventing them from facing eviction proceedings.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And these funds that I&#8217;m talking about current &#8212; right now can continue to be dispersed to renters and landlords in need until 2025.&nbsp; So, these Emergency Rental Assistance funds do not expire when the moratorium lifts.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re engaged on an all-of-government effort to help states and localities put additional protections in place, including encouraging diversions proceedings so renters have the opportunity to stay in their homes.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing on the government side, and we will continue to work with Congress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, lastly, on the GDP numbers, given obviously the surge in the Delta variant and the lower-than-expected number today, does the White House still believe that the emergency unemployment benefits should expire in September?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s set to expire in September, as you just mentioned.&nbsp; That is something that we&#8217;re going to keep &#8212; you know, keep look &#8212; keep an eye out.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, our country and our economy are in a much stronger place than we were in January.&nbsp; That&#8217;s just a fact.&nbsp; I talked about the &#8212; the 3 million &#8212; the more than 3 million Americans who are back at work.&nbsp; And &#8212; you know, and unemployment claims have more than halved.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we know the vaccines are working, including &#8212; including against the variants, at protecting against severe cases, deaths, and hospitalization.&nbsp; And so, when it comes to the economy, there are no significant signs at this point of the Delta variant’s impact, and would expect that much of the economy impact would be felt in the communities with lower vaccination rates, as we&#8217;ve been talking about.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doubling down on our efforts to ensure we&#8217;re reaching Americans with vaccine where they are.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s going to be our focus in the meantime.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; I know you don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President&#8217;s remarks, but I wanted to ask about the stra- &#8212; communication strategy.<br>&nbsp;<br>You&#8217;ve been calling this the &#8220;pandemic of the unvaccinated.&#8221;&nbsp; The &#8220;pandemic of the unvaccinated.&#8221;&nbsp; But that&#8217;s not really the case.&nbsp; Vaccinated people are getting it.&nbsp; They&#8217;re spreading the virus.&nbsp; Even if they&#8217;re not hospitalized, you know, why does the White House feel that calling it the &#8220;pandemic of the unvaccinated&#8221; is effective?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, let me &#8212; let&#8217;s just bring that back just a second.&nbsp; We are seeing breakthrough cases with people who are vaccinated, but not at &#8212; at a low &#8212; at a low rate.&nbsp; So just want to not scare people and make it sound like every vaccinated person is &#8212; is getting the Delta &#8212; the variant, which is not the case.&nbsp; It is small, lower cases and &#8212; with breakthroughs, in particular, of people who are vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>But what has changed, as you know, is: Because the people who &#8212; the vaccinated folks who are having those breakthroughs, they can spread it now.&nbsp; And so that is something &#8212; that is something that we should be concerned about, which is why the CDC guidance has changed, which is why we&#8217;re asking people to &#8212; they are asking people to wear a mask outside, and &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, not outside &#8212; indoors, inside.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re asking people to mask up.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the thing is, if people were to get vaccinated, then we would be in a better place to beat back the virus, including the Delta variant.&nbsp; And so we have to continue to make sure &#8212; we have to continue to make sure the unvaccinated are getting vaccinated.&nbsp; You know, that&#8217;s &#8212; I mean, when we were talking about this two months ago, the Delta variant was at 1 percent &#8212; at 1 percent.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so &#8212; and we were seeing &#8212; you know, we were vaccinating people, we were seeing the numbers go up in vaccinations.<br>&nbsp;<br>And now we&#8217;re at a point where, you know, people are just not doing that.&nbsp; And we know &#8212; we know for a fact it&#8217;s easy to get that vaccine.&nbsp; It&#8217;s free.&nbsp; It&#8217;s accessible.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we &#8212; that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re saying it is the pandemic of the &#8212; of the unvaccinated, because that is why we&#8217;re seeing this variant really taking &#8212; taking over in hospitals right now.&nbsp; Hospitalization &#8212; more than 97 percent are people who are not vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I also ask you about &#8212; the President is reportedly meeting with some Democrats about protections for DREAMers.&nbsp; Can you talk about that meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>And can you also share what type of concrete action is the President going to be doing moving forward on this?&nbsp; When are we going to see the President use some of the kind of political muscle that he has on other priorities &#8212; say, getting out on the road, for example?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s having this meeting today with congressional members.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s one way that he&#8217;s, you know, moving forward and being very active on this.&nbsp; He talked about it.&nbsp; He was asked about it when &#8212; during his town hall, last week in Ohio.&nbsp; He was incredibly passionate, as you probably remember, in talking about DACA.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you know, in light of the ruling on DACA recently, the President wanted to hear from legislators on this and discuss the path forward on DACA.&nbsp; To your point, he is being active in this process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as you all know, the same day, President Biden said that the Department of Justice intends to appeal this decision in order to preserve and fortify DACA.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s incredibly important.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as the Court recognized, the Department of Homeland Security plans to issue a proposed rule concerning DACA in the near future.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President also repeatedly called on Congress to pass the American Dreams Act and Promise Act.&nbsp; So, today, he&#8217;s meeting with Congress and going to have a conversation on a path forward.&nbsp; So he is, indeed, very engaged.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why not put it on the guidance?&nbsp; The meeting was not on the guidance.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, because it&#8217;s not a public meeting.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a meeting to have a real discussion with congressional members on how to move forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the President, as Commander-in-Chief, require members of the military to get vaccinated?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to share &#8212; more to share on that particular &#8212; particular piece.&nbsp; As you can imagine, this is &#8212; this is &#8212; this &#8212; these are decisions that, you know, departments and agencies have to make.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re not easy decisions to make.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The VA was able to do that.&nbsp; They had to go through their process to make that happen, and it was specific for folks who are dealing in the public health sector.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick follow-up.&nbsp; So would President Biden be comfortable with unvaccinated members of the military going to places around the world where vaccines are not widely and readily available to those populations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of &#8212; again, the President is going to be speaking in not &#8212; in less than an hour, so I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of him.&nbsp; Clearly, his goal is to make sure that people are safe.&nbsp; He wants to make sure his military members are safe as well.&nbsp; And so that is what he&#8217;s going to lay out today in his speech.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question about the unvaccinated.&nbsp; Based on the administration&#8217;s outreach to communities, does the White House know more about why certain Americans are still hesitant or resistant to getting the vaccine?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, it&#8217;s an individual choice.&nbsp; There are reasons for many &#8212; for different Americans to &#8212; or people who are living &#8212; living here to not get the vaccine.&nbsp; But our job is to make sure that we continue to have trusted voices, to make sure that we listen to the science, to make sure that we have that public health education out there, to let people know how important it is to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t know, you know, the different reasons of why people are not getting vaccinated.&nbsp; There are an array of reasons &#8212; misinformation is one of them; disinformation is one of them, which we had &#8212; the Surgeon General was here, not too long ago, talking about that and what &#8212; the data that he had to share and how dangerous that was &#8212; or that is &#8212; to many Americans.<br>&nbsp;<br>But our job right now, and as we have continued &#8212; as we&#8217;re going to continue to do, as we have done, is to make sure we get that information out there and people understand and listen to the science and the health experts and get vaccinated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with some major companies announcing new vaccine policy, what is the White House’s position or guidance to companies thinking of implementing similar mandates or requirements?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as you know &#8212; are you talking about verification &#8212; vaccine verification?&nbsp; Or &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Or, for instance, we learned today Danny Meyer is mandating employees and indoor diners to be vaccinated (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not &#8212; we&#8217;re &#8212; as you know, we&#8217;re not going to mandate &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re not going to do the mandating across the board for the American people.&nbsp; What we&#8217;re going to continue to do is listen to the guidance &#8212; the CDC guidance &#8212; listen to the experts, and follow what they tell us to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And &#8212; but we&#8217;re not going to be mandating anything from here.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the White House, though, encourage companies to implement their own stricter policy?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, they &#8212; yeah, they have the flexibility to do that.&nbsp; They are private companies, private organizations.&nbsp; They have the flexibility to do that &#8212; to put in mandates that works for them; that&#8217;s important to keeping their &#8212; you know, their staff safe.&nbsp; And that is important.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m told we have to wrap.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; I’ll ta- &#8212; I’ll take one more.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, can I ask a question on travel restrictions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead. &nbsp;Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; What is the difference to the administration between a vaccinated American traveling to Europe or the UK, or any other country that the U.S. has travel restrictions on, and potentially bringing back the Delta variant or some other strain of COVID, and someone who&#8217;s vaccinated from one of those countries coming here and potentially bringing one of those variants with them?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me &#8212; well, you know, the travel restrictions comes off &#8212; comes up often.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll say this for now: The administration understands the importance of international travel and is united in wanting to reopen the international travel in a safe and sustainable manner.&nbsp; The reopening process is guided by the science and public health.<br>&nbsp;<br>Given where we are today with the Delta variant, as you just &#8212; you were just laying out, Francesca, the United States will remain exist- &#8212; existing travel restriction at this point for a few reasons.&nbsp; The more transmittable Delta variant is spreading both here and around the world.&nbsp; Driven by the Delta variant, cases are rising here at home, particularly among those who are unvaccinated, and appear likely to continue &#8212; to increase in the weeks ahead.&nbsp; And the CDC just advised Americans against travel to the UK this past Monday, given their surge in cases.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Any travel from any other countries, I would refer you to them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if I could just &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what is the basis for the travel restrictions?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We can talk about this another time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks &#8212; thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I’ll see you tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>3:17 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
