<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:01:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden and President von der Leyen on occasion of the second Global COVID-&#8288;19 Summit, May 12,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/12/statement-from-president-biden-and-president-von-der-leyen-on-occasion-of-the-second-global-covid-19-summit-may-12-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53019</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States of America and the European Union are implementing the U.S.-EU Agenda for Beating the Global Pandemic, Vaccinating the World, Saving Lives Now and Building Back Better Health Security of September 22, 2021. Today, Presidents Biden and von der Leyen reaffirmed milestones in their strong cooperation towards the five headline goals of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States of America and the European Union are implementing the <strong>U.S.-EU Agenda for Beating the Global Pandemic, Vaccinating the World, Saving Lives Now and Building Back Better Health Security </strong>of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/09/22/a-u-s-eu-agenda-for-beating-the-global-pandemic-vaccinating-the-world-saving-lives-now-and-building-back-better-health-security/">September 22, 2021</a>. Today, Presidents Biden and von der Leyen reaffirmed milestones in their strong cooperation towards the five headline goals of the Agenda, and they previewed further joint action below:</p>



<p><strong><em>Vaccine equity and ‘shots-in-arms’. </em></strong>Having shared a combined total of more than one billion COVID-19 vaccine doses, and in line with a commitment to share a total of 1.9 billion doses around the world, the EU and U.S. seek to ensure ongoing <strong>deliveries are based on country demand, informed by best practices and reach ‘tarmac to arms’</strong>, with focus on sub-Saharan Africa. Through support from Team Europe and U.S. Global VAX programs, both sides recognise that vaccine equity starts with best practice donation principles including adequate and transparent planning in <strong>cooperation with governments, in-country partners, COVAX (as part of ACT-A), Africa Vaccine Acquisition Task Team (AVATT), World Health Organization (WHO), the COVID- 19 Vaccine Delivery Partnership (CoVDP), </strong>and others. Given that dose supply is currently not constrained, the partnership should pay particular attention to enhancing vaccine readiness, strengthening logistics, combating hesitancy, and building longer-term capacity by means of health systems strengthening, and immediate capability for vaccine uptake as part of the global COVID-19 Vaccine Delivery Partnership. To strengthen our partnership, the U.S. and EU will actively consult with partners including AVATT, CoVDP, and COVAX on strategies to accelerate vaccine absorption. The U.S. and EU will strengthen dialogues with multilateral development banks and global partners aiming towards better uptake of and sustainable financing for in-country vaccination operations.<br><br></p>



<p><strong><em>Strengthening global supply chains and manufacturing. </em></strong>The need to ensure vaccine and therapeutic dose supply and administration in the face of supply chain constraints led to the <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/STATEMENT_21_4847">launch</a> of the joint <strong>EU-U.S. COVID-19 manufacturing and supply chain task force </strong>in September 2021. The leaders expect that the task force will extend its activities to provide <strong>early warning of supply chain bottlenecks </strong>that could hamper global availability of vaccines and treatments, and to coordinate efforts to sustain vaccine and therapeutics production capabilities for variants and future pandemics, including in Africa.<br><br></p>



<p><strong><em>Enhanced EU-US coordination to improve global health security architecture. </em></strong>Enhancing pandemic prevention, preparedness and response (PPR) capacities requires strong international cooperation, and the U.S. and the EU are committed to cooperate to this end, including under the lines of effort of the COVID-19 Prioritized Global Action Plan for Enhanced Engagement (GAP). Enhanced PPR requires a strengthening of the global health architecture, including of the WHO at the center, and sustainable financing. Presidents Biden and von der Leyen welcomed the support of the G20 under Indonesia’s leadership, and committed to cooperate on the establishment of a new <strong>Financial Intermediary Fund (FIF) for pandemic preparedness and global health security </strong>at the World Bank, including its <strong>sustainable capitalization</strong>, governance and structure. The U.S. and EU committed to support the early design and implementation of the FIF. The leaders will also cooperate towards the conclusion of a convention, agreement or other international instrument on pandemic prevention, preparedness and response at the WHO, and targeted amendments to the International Health Regulations, in order to <strong>strengthen the global rulebook for pandemic PPR</strong>. The EU and the U.S. are working together with <strong>expert dialogue </strong>to forge consensus on targeted IHR amendments and the content of a pandemic instrument. They also recognise the importance of engagement with other partners to take forward both sustainable financing for PPR and a strengthened WHO.<br><br></p>



<p><strong><em>Preparing for the future, pathogen detection and monitoring, joint threat assessment and response. </em></strong>The EU and U.S. will collaborate to improve pathogen monitoring and threat assessment, leveraging existing and novel approaches, providing integrated surveillance, real-time monitoring, early warning systems, forecasting and analytics, intelligence exchange, supporting rapid response networks, and an ‘always-ready’ health emergency workforce to prevent or mitigate cross-border outbreaks, all within a One Health approach.</p>



<p><strong><em>Research and development for new vaccines, therapeutics and diagnostics. </em></strong>Acknowledging the importance of swiftly reacting to pandemics, the U.S. and EU support science to shorten the cycle for the development of safe and effective vaccines, therapeutics and diagnostics from 300 to 100 days following the identification of such threats and work to make them widely available. In the near term, the EU and U.S. committed to deepen <strong>cooperation to identify and evaluate variant adapted, more broadly protective, and next generation vaccines, therapeutics and diagnostics, while ensuring their safety and efficacy</strong>. The U.S. and the EU will work towards aligning R&amp;D investments with manufacturing and manufacturing capabilities development, and will conclude a formal administrative arrangement on preparedness and response for public health threats to be signed this month between the European Commission Health Emergency and Preparedness Response Authority (HERA) and the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Remembering the 1,000,000 Americans Lost to&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/12/a-proclamation-on-remembering-the-1000000-americans-lost-to-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53015</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we mark a tragic milestone: &#160;one million American lives lost to COVID-19. &#160;One million empty chairs around the dinner table. &#160;Each an irreplaceable loss. &#160;Each leaving behind a family, a community, and a Nation forever changed because of this pandemic. &#160;Jill and I pray for each of them. As a Nation, we must not&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we mark a tragic milestone: &nbsp;one million American lives lost to COVID-19. &nbsp;One million empty chairs around the dinner table. &nbsp;Each an irreplaceable loss. &nbsp;Each leaving behind a family, a community, and a Nation forever changed because of this pandemic. &nbsp;Jill and I pray for each of them.</p>



<p>As a Nation, we must not grow numb to such sorrow. &nbsp;To heal, we must remember. &nbsp;We must remain vigilant against this pandemic and do everything we can to save as many lives as possible. &nbsp;In remembrance, let us draw strength from each other as fellow Americans. &nbsp;For while we have been humbled, we never give up.&nbsp; We can and will do this together as the United States of America.</p>



<p>In memory of the one million American lives lost to COVID-19 and their loved ones left behind, I hereby order, by the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States, that the flag of the United States shall be flown at half-staff at the White House and on all public buildings and grounds, at all military posts and naval stations, and on all naval vessels of the Federal Government in the District of Columbia and throughout the United States and its Territories and possessions until sunset May 16, 2022.  I also direct that the flag shall be flown at half-staff for the same period at all United States embassies, legations, consular offices, and other facilities abroad, including all military facilities and naval vessels and stations.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twelfth day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden Marking One Million American Lives Lost to&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/12/statement-from-president-joe-biden-marking-one-million-american-lives-lost-to-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we mark a tragic milestone: one million American lives lost to COVID-19. One million empty chairs around the dinner table. Each an irreplaceable loss. Each leaving behind a family, a community, and a nation forever changed because of this pandemic. Jill and I pray for each of them. To those who are grieving, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we mark a tragic milestone: one million American lives lost to COVID-19. One million empty chairs around the dinner table. Each an irreplaceable loss. Each leaving behind a family, a community, and a nation forever changed because of this pandemic. Jill and I pray for each of them.</p>



<p>To those who are grieving, and asking yourself how will you go on without him or what will you do without her, I understand. I know the pain of that black hole in your heart. It is unrelenting. But I also know the ones you love are never truly gone. They will always be with you.</p>



<p>As a nation, we must not grow numb to such sorrow. To heal, we must remember. We must remain vigilant against this pandemic and do everything we can to save as many lives as possible, as we have with more testing, vaccines, and treatments than ever before. It’s critical that Congress sustain these resources in the coming months. &nbsp;</p>



<p>In remembrance, let us draw strength from each other as fellow Americans. For while we have been humbled, we never give up.&nbsp;We can and will do this together as the United States of America.</p>



<p>May God bless the one million American lives lost and their loved ones left behind.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Democratic National Committee&#160;Fundraiser</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/11/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-democratic-national-committee-fundraiser-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 03:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53010</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Marriott Marquis ChicagoChicago, Illinois 5:39 P.M. CDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you, Gov.&#160; Gov, you’ve been a great friend and a great partner on COVID, the economy, and so much more.&#160;&#160; And like most everybody in this room who is involved in public life, I remember them that was there first.&#160; Thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Marriott Marquis Chicago<br>Chicago, Illinois</p>



<p>5:39 P.M. CDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, Gov.&nbsp; Gov, you’ve been a great friend and a great partner on COVID, the economy, and so much more.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And like most everybody in this room who is involved in public life, I remember them that was there first.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; You made a big difference in my being able to stand here as President of the United States.&nbsp; Many of you in this audience did as well.&nbsp;<br><br>I know you&#8217;ve been here a long time, so I&#8217;m not going to make a long, formal speech to you.&nbsp;<br><br>But look, you know, I want to thank Jaime Harrison for his leadership.&nbsp; And, you know, if things were working okay until we got to South Carolina in the primary, then we won every single county.&nbsp; So thank you, Jaime.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank all of you for the support and generosity.&nbsp; I can go around the room and at least 15 of you were deeply involved with my campaign &#8212; and even before the campaign, in my career.&nbsp; So thank you for all you&#8217;ve done.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Look, you know, I&#8217;m proud of the progress we&#8217;ve made.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot more to do, but I&#8217;m proud of the progress we&#8217;ve made.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve talked about how &#8212; you know, people say, “Well, you know, Biden won.”&nbsp; Well, it was a fairly low bar to get over because of the nature of how much the last guy changed American politics.&nbsp; He changed it in a way that made it more petty.&nbsp;<br><br>When I ran &#8212; you may remember &#8212; no reason why you should, but I remember I said, “I&#8217;m running to restore the soul of America; to rebuild the backbone of the country, the middle class of America; and to try to unite the country because democracies can&#8217;t function very well unless we can arrive at consensus.”&nbsp;<br><br>I also said at the time, and I&#8217;ve been saying since then, that we&#8217;re really in a battle worldwide between democracies and oligarchies.&nbsp; The fact of the matter is, I&#8217;ve spent a lot of time with Xi Jinping &#8212; they tell me more than any other world leader has.&nbsp; When he was vice president and I was vice president, I traveled 17,000 miles with him.&nbsp; Spent a lot of time since he&#8217;s been &#8212; since I got elected President talking to him.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s a very bright guy, but very &#8212; he doesn’t have a democratic &#8212; with a small “d” &#8212; bone in his body.&nbsp;<br><br>But he knows exactly what he wants.&nbsp; He knows exactly what he&#8217;s trying to do.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s very straightforward.&nbsp; He makes the point that, at this inflection point in history, world history &#8212; and it comes about every four or five generations &#8212; this fundamental change that takes place not because of any one particular leader, but because the nature of the change occurring in the world, whether it&#8217;s technology or anything else.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And he thinks that democracies require consensus, they can&#8217;t operate quickly enough in this changing world.<br><br>Your children are going to see more change in the next 10 years than we&#8217;ve seen in the last 50 years &#8212; the last 100 years, possibly &#8212; in the world and in the United States.&nbsp; And so, there&#8217;s a lot at stake &#8212; a whole lot at stake.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I believe &#8212; and I come at this with an enormous sense of optimism.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s any nation in the world that’s better prepared to deal with the changing world than the United States of America.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re the only nation in the world that has come out of every crisis stronger than we went into it.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; Every crisis we&#8217;ve ever encountered &#8212; war, famine, whatever it was &#8212; we&#8217;ve come out stronger than when we went in.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s been my objective, because I believe the American public and the world is ready.&nbsp;<br><br>When I was first elected, I attended my first meeting of the G7 &#8212; the democracies in Europe and a few in Asia &#8212; in England.&nbsp; And I sat down and I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And they looked at me &#8212; two of them, I will not, because it was &#8212; they were private meetings &#8212; not say who said it &#8212; but two of the world leaders looked at me and said, “But for how long?”&nbsp; “But for how long?”&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things I think we &#8212; we sort of underestimate is that imagine what we&#8217;d be thinking if tomorrow we went back and the news on television showed a group of hundreds of people &#8212; not at war &#8212; breaking down the doors of the British Parliament, killing two or three of the people who work there &#8212; guards there &#8212; and doing what was done on the 6th of &#8212; the 6th of January.&nbsp; Imagine what we’d think.&nbsp;<br><br>We are the democracy of the world.&nbsp; And it really is true.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not &#8212; that it&#8217;s not chauvinism about America.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just a fact.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the things I realized that &#8212; Senator Braun and I worked a long time together.&nbsp; One of the things I realized, Carol, was that I knew that we were the essential nation as &#8212; as the former Secretary of State, who we just buried, would say &#8212; but I didn&#8217;t fully appreciate it until I became President.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about Joe Biden; it’s about the office of the presidency.&nbsp;<br><br>The rest of the world looks to us.&nbsp; They expect us to lead.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; We are the essential nation.&nbsp; We are the essential nation.&nbsp;<br><br>And that gives us so many incredible opportunities if we&#8217;re not afraid to take them and move them, and take on this new sort of petty, mean-spirited notion that has guided the other team.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s still a lot of good Republicans in the Senate.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s amazing to me how they&#8217;re cowered by Trump and how he has such concern.<br><br>I&#8217;ve had &#8212; I, obviously, will never name them, but I have &#8212; six of them have told me &#8212; senators I used to serve with; we served with; some of them you served with, Carol &#8212; said that, “You know, I agree with you on such and such a thing.&nbsp; But if I vote for it, they&#8217;ll primary and I&#8217;ll lose my seat.”&nbsp; Doesn&#8217;t go to political courage, but it goes to the recognition that there still are a lot of Republicans who want to get things done.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But we have to take on the &#8212; MAGA Republicans &#8212; “Make America Great Again” Republicans.&nbsp; I think they&#8217;re the most extreme party.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what the Republican Party is now.&nbsp; Not everybody Republican believes that.&nbsp; But the fact of the matter is, they run the show &#8212; the MAGA Republicans,<br><br>The idea that they do the things that they’re doing now, and the things that they’re saying &#8212; I think if we had sat down here five years ago, seven years ago, eight years ago, and said this was going to happen, you’d all look at me &#8212; and I would have thought myself &#8212; nuts saying some of the things that they’re saying.&nbsp; But it really is beyond the pale.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, one of the things that I think we have to do is not just talk about what we&#8217;ve done &#8212; and we don&#8217;t do that enough, and that&#8217;s my fault.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I remember, with Barack, when we passed the Affordable Care Act.&nbsp; I said, “Barack, you ought to take a victory lap.”&nbsp; And I remember what he said to me.&nbsp; He said, “We don&#8217;t have time, Joe.&nbsp; There&#8217;s too much to do.”&nbsp; Everything but locusts has landed on his desk.&nbsp; Locusts landed on my desk.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>But really, think about what we&#8217;ve done so far.&nbsp; You know, if you just do it in terms of just practical &#8212; practical application of what has usually been the mid- &#8212; the measures by which people measure whether or not an administration is functioning, we&#8217;re in a situation where we&#8217;ve gone from 2 million people with vaccinations when we took over office to 220 million fully vaccinated.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve gone from jobs &#8212; a jobs report to 428,000 jobs last month, 8.3 million jobs my first 15 months in office &#8212; more than any President has in American history.&nbsp; Well, it’s not about me.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you, but it really isn’t about me.&nbsp; What it&#8217;s about is that &#8212; you know, the Republicans say that, well, the things we did with the Recov- &#8212; with the legislation we passed is causing inflation.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Well guess what?&nbsp; The first year in office, we&#8217;ve reduced the deficit by $350 billion.&nbsp; In fact &#8212; $350 billion &#8212; reduced the deficit.&nbsp; And this year, we&#8217;re on track, in the next two months, to reduce the deficit by 1 trillion 500 billion dollars.&nbsp; Never happened before in American history.&nbsp;<br><br>But look, the biggest investments that have ever been made &#8212; and the governor talks about it and does it really well on what he’s &#8212; and how he uses the funding &#8212; is in infrastructure.&nbsp; One&nbsp;<s>billion</s>&nbsp;[trillion] two hundred&nbsp;<s>million</s>[billion] dollars in infrastructure.<br><br>We used to have the number-one infrastructure in the world &#8212; the world.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what drove our growth.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what drove our prosperity.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what moved us.&nbsp; We&#8217;re now number 14 in the world &#8212; the United States of America.&nbsp; China is now number two.<br><br>And look, the idea that we&#8217;ve sat around and haven’t moved until now &#8212; but now, we &#8212; there’s, you know, 6,000 &#8212; 60,000 miles of road in your state that we&#8217;re going to be able to take care of.&nbsp; No, I mean it.&nbsp; I know you know it.&nbsp; You know it better than anybody.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s a whole range of &#8212;<br><br>(Cellphone rings.)<br><br>I know that’s Trump calling.&nbsp; He always does this when I talk.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But &#8212; but all kidding aside, what we&#8217;re doing here is that we’ve made the biggest investments in infrastructure; historic investments in solar, wind, and battery technology &#8212; notwithstanding the fact that we still need one vote to get the $508 billion that is still left in my legislation that we thought we were going to get passed.&nbsp; We were one vote short, but we&#8217;re going to get it done.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to get it done.&nbsp;<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal: The historic investments are one thing, but, you know, one of the things I&#8217;ve tried to do when I got elected &#8212; and because I talked with many of you about this in detail beforehand &#8212; I said I&#8217;d have administration that looked like America &#8212; an administration that looked like America.&nbsp;<br><br>We have the most diverse administration in American history by a longshot &#8212; by a longshot.&nbsp; Over half our major appointees &#8212; both Senate confirmed as well as appointed &#8212; are women.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re in a situation where we have a significant number of all minorities that are &#8212; look, I mean, we&#8217;ve appointed more &#8212; more circuit court of appeals judges who are Black women than every other President in American history.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we have a &#8212; we have an associate justice about to go on the Court, God willing, who is brilliant.&nbsp; But I tell you, she&#8217;s going to be the first &#8212; I made a commitment there’d be the first Black woman on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; And it matters.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And I think because &#8212; because of how outrageous some of the things that former President Trump has done and said, I think we found ourselves at a position where it was almost like, “How could that happen?&nbsp; How can that be?”&nbsp; And I think, in a sense &#8212; until we got elected and we changed presidents, I think people started to lose faith in the capacity of the American government to deliver &#8212; to deliver, to make life better for people.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We have so many opportunities available to us.&nbsp; So many opportunities.&nbsp;<br><br>We have to remember that we&#8217;re talking about a relatively small number of people who are the MAGA Republicans.&nbsp; We may be talking about as much as one third of the electorate.&nbsp; That&#8217;s more than I&#8217;d ever thought would occur.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But we got to take the fight to them.&nbsp; We got to make our case and make it very strongly, in my opinion.&nbsp;<br><br>And, you know, we have a strong record to run on.&nbsp; The economy is &#8212; our economy is one of those that we believe is from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; Because when the middle class does well, everybody does just fine.&nbsp; The wealthy do very well.&nbsp; The poor have a road up.&nbsp; And the middle class has built the country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s who&#8217;s built the country.&nbsp;<br><br>We find ourselves protecting and expanding civil rights.&nbsp; Well, we got to speak out more.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to make sure that we make our case and keep repeatedly making our case.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And we have to have &#8212; you know, reasserting America&#8217;s leadership in the world, because we are.&nbsp;<br><br>Look at &#8212; I’ll bet you &#8212; I can tell you that there are &#8212; a vast majority of the foreign policy establishment and military establishment are surprised at how incompetent the Russians have been so far &#8212; looking at how they’ve conducted themselves.&nbsp; And yet, we &#8212; we tended to think they were 10 feet tall &#8212; many folks.&nbsp;<br><br>It doesn&#8217;t mean we won’t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to put a single American troop in Ukraine.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to make sure Ukraine has what they need to be able to defend themselves.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal: The point is that I think we have to start looking at the world as it really is.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard me say before, I think we&#8217;re &#8212; you know, about every &#8212; anywhere from three to five generations, we reach an inflection point of world history where things began to change, whether it&#8217;s because of technology, the environment, or changes in the relationship amongst nations.&nbsp; They change in a big way.&nbsp; And we have to be in a position to understand that we have the capacity to try to make sure that in this inflection point, we know what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;<br><br>And we have an opportunity to increase &#8212; increase not to decrease &#8212; the whole notion of equity in the world, the whole notion of how we look at one another, the whole notion of &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>For example, you know, Putin is in a situation &#8212; and my last discussion with him was a while ago &#8212; was, you know, his &#8212; the tundra in the Arctic in Russia is burning, burning, burning.&nbsp; No, I mean, literally burning&nbsp; &#8212; leaking methane, which is so much more dangerous than any other thing that can affect the environment.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not going to &#8212; it&#8217;s not&#8211; it&#8217;s not going to freeze again.&nbsp;<br><br>So, there&#8217;s so many things that have to be dealt with, but they present enormous opportunities if we are &#8212; and gather ourselves together and figure out who &#8212; remind ourselves of who we are and what we want to do.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And look, the other thing I&#8217;d say is that, you know, the whole idea &#8212; if this draft opinion in the Supreme Court turns out to be the opinion of the Supreme Court, it is everything that some of us talked about before.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You may remember I led the fight to defeat Robert Bork’s nomination as Associate Justice of the Supreme Court, because I was convinced &#8212;<br><br>When we started off that nominating hearing, I said &#8212; because I&#8217;d read everything he had ever written and every decision he’d ever written &#8212; and he was a bright &#8212; he was a brilliant guy.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I said to him &#8212; I said, “Judge…” &#8212; he had been a judge.&nbsp; And I said, “Judge, let me describe to you what I think your constitutional philosophy is and mine, and you tell me whether we &#8212; whether we differ, whether I accurately am portraying it.”&nbsp;<br><br>And I said, “Judge, you believe that the Constitution &#8212; the Ninth Amendment is an inkblot in the Constitution and, secondly, that there is no such thing as a right to privacy in the Constitution.&nbsp; And you believe the rights you possess are because the government gave them to you.&nbsp; They gave them to you.&nbsp; I believe the rights I possess are because I&#8217;m a child of God, because I just exist.&nbsp; And I, by implication, gave up some of those rights to the government for purposes of making society function.”&nbsp; And I went on from there.&nbsp; And he said, “I agree, it&#8217;s exactly the difference.”&nbsp;<br><br>Well, look, what we&#8217;re talking about here.&nbsp; It’s not only the brutality of taking away a woman&#8217;s right to control her own body and all the damage that does physically, psychologically, practically.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But it also, if you read the opinion &#8212; if it turns out to be the same opinion &#8212; basically says there is no such thing as a right to privacy.&nbsp; Mark my words: If that decision holds, it&#8217;s not only we&#8217;re going to be fighting for a woman&#8217;s right to control her own body and the brutality that goes along with having to give birth in a circumstance that is something beyond what &#8212; that can be tolerated, but what else is going to happen?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Mark my words: They&#8217;re going to go after the right of the &#8212; Supreme Court decision on the right of same-sex marriage.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to go after &#8212; they&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to be back to Griswold vs. Connecticut, where there was a time in Connecticut law where it said a married couple, in the privacy of their own bedroom, cannot use contraception; it was a decision &#8212; the government can make the decision you can&#8217;t do that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;re going to see these decisions up for grabs and further split the United States.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be arguing about things we shouldn&#8217;t have to argue about.&nbsp;<br><br>So I think it&#8217;s important that as we go forward &#8212; and you&#8217;re going to hear me talking more about not only what we&#8217;ve done, but what they&#8217;re trying to do.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, if you take a look at what the leader &#8212; their &#8212; the head of their campaign committee, the distinguished senator from &#8212; Republican senator from Florida &#8212; he talks about that what he has in mind is that they&#8217;re going to &#8212; he&#8217;s laid out the only plan put forward in the last years, what the Republican Party stands for, what they&#8217;re going to run on.&nbsp;<br><br>And what they say is &#8212; it&#8217;s really quite basic.&nbsp; They&#8217;re making the point that what happens is that what they&#8217;re going to be &#8212; we&#8217;re going to increase taxes on 90 percent of the American public, people making a &#8212; excuse me, 70 percent of the American public &#8212; people making under $100,000 a year are going to have tax, because the notion is everybody should pay something.&nbsp; Even a family that&#8217;s raising three kids, in fact is making 25-, 30,000 bucks a year, they should be paying federal taxes.&nbsp; Nothing for people who can afford to pay more.&nbsp;<br><br>Secondly, there is a provision in the bill they put forward &#8212; the law they&#8217;re proposing &#8212; that every five years, Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid will be on the chopping block, that Congress will have to affirmatively again vote to put them into the law.&nbsp; Otherwise, they will &#8212; it goes out of the law.&nbsp;<br><br>And you know what they&#8217;re going to do, those of you hold public office.&nbsp; If that were ever to pass and they were to take control, what they&#8217;re going to do is they&#8217;ll use that as a bargaining chip.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll say, “Unless you vote for such and such, unless you end your attempt to try to force environmental regulations in place, we&#8217;re going to cut the following elements of one of those programs.”&nbsp;<br><br>The idea that &#8212; and it&#8217;s in writing &#8212; that every five years you&#8217;d have to reauthorize Social Security, which you&#8217;ve paid into your whole life &#8212; have to reauthorize that?&nbsp; I won&#8217;t go through it all, and I&#8217;m going &#8212; taking too much of your time.&nbsp; But is really a genuinely radical agenda.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think we have to point out how radical it is &#8212; how radical it is &#8212; so people are reminded what&#8217;s at stake here, not only internationally, but domestically, in terms of people&#8217;s basic fundamental rights, in terms of education.<br><br>Did you ever think we&#8217;d be in a position in the year 2022 &#8212; we&#8217;d be talking about banning books in schools?&nbsp; I mean, you know, the idea that you cannot mention &#8212; you cannot mention to the school.&nbsp; What&#8217;s going to happen to a gay child, an L[G]BTQ child in school?&nbsp; I mean, this thing &#8212; it’s one thing to take on Disney World.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to storm Cinderella&#8217;s castle before this is over.&nbsp;<br><br>But I mean it.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; If I told you these things, I think you&#8217;d think I was crazy.&nbsp; You may think I&#8217;m crazy anyway, but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but &#8212;<br><br>So, folks, we got a lot of work to do.&nbsp; We got a lot of work.&nbsp; I think we can pick up three Senate seats.&nbsp; And I think we can increase our majority in the House, but we have to do it by more than just a couple of votes.&nbsp; We have to do it by more than a couple of votes, because it&#8217;s getting much too close.&nbsp;<br><br>If, in fact, they were to win back the House and/or the Senate, we got a different world we&#8217;re in.&nbsp; We got a different world we&#8217;re in.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, again, I&#8217;m taking too much of your time.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s why what you&#8217;re doing is so damn important.&nbsp; It really makes a difference.&nbsp; It makes a gigantic difference.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, we&#8217;re going to be hopefully having the DNC spend a lot more time and, quite frankly, money making the larger generic case.&nbsp; And we can do it honestly, without having to exaggerate or make up things that are not on the docket.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I want to thank you all so very, very much for the time and the effort.&nbsp; And I realize your time is even more valuable than your contribution because you all are people of consequence who are &#8212; have a lot you have to do.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, the &#8212; we have to make sure we keep this clear contrast on either side.&nbsp; This is &#8212; as I said, this is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party.&nbsp; This is a different breed of cat.&nbsp; I mean, all kidding aside, it really is.&nbsp; It really is.<br><br>There&#8217;s some really decent Republicans in the House and the Senate, but they&#8217;re so overwhelmed and intimidated.&nbsp; And some of them are just leaving.&nbsp; They’re giving up their seats and just moving &#8212; moving out of public life.<br><br>And, you know, if the Court follows this leaked opinion, it has the potential to generate significant enthusiasm to get out and vote, but it also has an enormous potential if &#8212; if we fail, what that will mean &#8212; what that will mean.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, folks, we &#8212; these guys are doing everything &#8212; I got involved in politics &#8212; I’ll end with this &#8212; because of civil rights.&nbsp; I come from a state that has the eighth-largest Black population in America as a percent of population: Delaware.&nbsp; We have &#8212; we&#8217;re the eighth-largest population.&nbsp;<br><br>As a matter of fact, we were one of those border states in the Civil War.&nbsp; We were a slave state, to our shame, like Maryland and &#8212; anyway.<br><br>And &#8212; and so it is &#8212; that&#8217;s what got me involved.&nbsp; I used to &#8212; we moved from Wilmington &#8212; from, excuse me, Scranton, Pennsylvania, where there were very few African Americans, down to Wilmington, to a place called Claymont, Delaware, which was a &#8212; it sits on the border of the Pennsylvania state line, where there are more oil companies and refineries than in Houston, Texas.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I went to a little Catholic school called Holy Rosary, which is &#8212; I was in third grade.&nbsp; And it was up what they call a Philadelphia pike, a four-lane access road.&nbsp; It was &#8212; where it went through the little town of Claymont.&nbsp; It was &#8212; I-95 is.&nbsp; It replaced it, in effect.&nbsp;<br><br>And I remember asking my mother &#8212; it was too dangerous to walk up because of the streets you had to cross.&nbsp; So my mother would drive me from this apartment complex we moved into.<br><br>And I remember, dropped off in the parking lot, I’d always see this bus go by.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re all Black kids in the bus.&nbsp; At the time, they weren&#8217;t called “Black kids”; there were “negroes” on the bus.&nbsp;<br><br>And I asked why.&nbsp; She told me they weren&#8217;t allowed to go to school &#8212; and this was before Brown vs. the Board in Delaware, which &#8212; and we were one of the cases &#8212; Delaware was &#8212; in Brown vs. the Board.&nbsp; And I thought to myself, “What&#8217;s going on?”<br><br>But the point is that &#8212; think about it.&nbsp; Think about it: where we are today, what we&#8217;re fighting over.&nbsp; There are more restrictive efforts to restrict the right to vote today than there’d been in my whole political career.&nbsp; I thought we were well by that.&nbsp;<br><br>I was chairman of the Judiciary Committee of the United States Senate, and I was able to extend the Voting Rights Act for 25 years.&nbsp; I got Strom Thurmond to vote to extend it.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;<br><br>And I thought, “Well, my God, we can do it.&nbsp; We can defeat hate.”&nbsp; But I made a big mistake, a lesson I learned: Hate never goes away; it just hides.&nbsp; It hides under the rocks.&nbsp; And when somebody breathes oxygen under those rocks, it comes out in ways that we never thought it would &#8212; I never thought I&#8217;d see again.&nbsp;<br><br>And look where we are now.&nbsp; Look at all the states that have changed the means by which people can vote, letting the states decide whether or not the vote counts, count the vote.&nbsp; I mean, come on.&nbsp; What in God&#8217;s name is going on?<br><br>So, there&#8217;s so much at stake.&nbsp; I&#8217;m convinced we will succeed if we make our case.&nbsp; I&#8217;m convinced that we will be able to do this.&nbsp; But we also have to understand that if we miss, what&#8217;s at stake?<br><br>A distinguished senator from your neighboring state of Wisconsin, Ron Johnson &#8212; he&#8217;s made it very clear.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going after &#8212; repeal the Affordable Care Act again.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve expanded it so people are saving 2,400 bucks a year on their &#8212; on their healthcare costs.&nbsp;<br><br>And, you know, we&#8217;re going to need to control the House and the Senate.&nbsp; And we need your support to reach out to those registered voters and convince them that it&#8217;s worth their effort, that it matters.&nbsp; It matters to us a great deal.&nbsp; It matters to them.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think that &#8212; it sounds a little melodramatic, but I can say this to a sophisticated audience involved in politics, as you all are.&nbsp; I really do think we&#8217;re still in the battle for the soul of America.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;<br><br>I wasn&#8217;t going to run again, as Billy Brodsky knows.&nbsp; We went to school together.&nbsp; I really wasn&#8217;t.&nbsp; I was a professor at the University of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; I was enjoying it.&nbsp;<br><br>But when those folks came marching out of the fields in Charlottesville, Virginia, carrying torches &#8212; torches, chanting the same anti-Semitic bile &#8212; the same anti-Semitic bile chanted in the streets of everywhere from Nuremberg to Berlin in the early ‘30s &#8212; exact language, by the way.&nbsp; Go check it out.&nbsp; Carrying swastikas, accompanied by the Ku Klux Klan.&nbsp; And a young woman was killed in the process.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And the then-President of the United States was asked &#8212; was asked the question, “What do you think?”&nbsp; He said there are very good people on both sides.<br><br>We can&#8217;t let this happen, guys.&nbsp; So, we have to &#8212; we have to &#8212; and it&#8217;s going to be hard.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be hard, because inflation is going to scare the living hell out of everybody.&nbsp;<br><br>I was raised in a family where when gas prices went up significantly and food went up, it was &#8212; it mattered to my family.&nbsp; It mattered.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re making progress, but there’s going to be a way to go.&nbsp; Our inflation rate is lower than almost any other nation &#8212; industrial nation in the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a situation where we find ourselves with supply chain problems and Putin&#8217;s gas tax in the extreme.&nbsp;<br><br>But we have a problem we have to deal with.&nbsp; In the meantime, we can&#8217;t take our eye off all that could happen if we do not prevail.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I&#8217;m counting on you all.&nbsp; I really mean it. &nbsp;And the DNC is going to have to play an increasingly important role in how we get this done.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I apologize for going on so long, but thank you very much for listening.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>6:09 P.M. CDT<br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Philippine President-Elect Ferdinand Marcos&#160;Jr.</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-philippine-president-elect-ferdinand-marcos-jr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 02:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President-elect Ferdinand Marcos Jr. of the Philippines to congratulate him on his election. President Biden underscored that he looks forward to working with the President-elect to continue strengthening the U.S.-Philippine Alliance, while expanding bilateral cooperation on a wide range of issues, including the fight against COVID-19, addressing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President-elect Ferdinand Marcos Jr. of the Philippines to congratulate him on his election. President Biden underscored that he looks forward to working with the President-elect to continue strengthening the U.S.-Philippine Alliance, while expanding bilateral cooperation on a wide range of issues, including the fight against COVID-19, addressing the climate crisis, promoting broad-based economic growth, and respect for human rights.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden at the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers 40th Annual&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/11/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-international-brotherhood-of-electrical-workers-40th-annual-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 01:37:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53003</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[McCormick Place Convention CenterChicago, Illinois 4:10 P.M. CDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hell, hello, hello!&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; I want to start off by saying two things.&#160; Number one, the only reason I&#8217;m standing here as your President of the United States of America is because of the IBEW came on with me&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">McCormick Place Convention Center<br>Chicago, Illinois</p>



<p>4:10 P.M. CDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hell, hello, hello!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; I want to start off by saying two things.&nbsp; Number one, the only reason I&#8217;m standing here as your President of the United States of America is because of the IBEW came on with me early.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And secondly, is Delaware in the house?&nbsp; Anybody from Delaware?&nbsp;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Holler loudly, man, because I want to see you after this is over.<br><br>Folks, please sit down.&nbsp; Please sit down.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, Lonnie, I want to thank you.&nbsp; You’re a de- &#8212; a dear friend and one of the great leaders of labor of our time.&nbsp; I mean that.&nbsp; You’ve been there every time.<br><br>And I also want to thank the IBEW’s Kenneth Cooper, Chris Erickson, Paul Nobel.<br><br>And as I said early on, the IBEW was with me when I was a kid running for the Senate in Delaware.&nbsp; And some of them are back there somewhere.<br><br>And I’m also proud of our Secretary of Labor &#8212; a card-carrying union member &#8212; Marty Walsh &#8212; fighting for union and worker power every day. &nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But, Lonnie, I only have one problem: Sometimes I can&#8217;t understand him.&nbsp; He talks about&nbsp;<em>cars</em>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<em>car&nbsp;barns&nbsp;&#8212;&nbsp;</em>(said in Boston accent) &#8212; and all that kind of thing.&nbsp; I wonder what he&#8217;s talking about sometimes.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s the best, man.&nbsp; If you got to be in a foxhole, you want him with you.<br><br>And, folks, there&#8217;s an expression where I come from: “You go home with them that brung you to the dance.”&nbsp; You all brought me to the dance, and I mean it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I said early on that I was going to be the most pro-labor, -union President we&#8217;ve ever had for a simple reason: You allow &#8212; (applause) &#8212; you allow workers to maintain their dignity.&nbsp; You allow them to hold their heads up high.&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp; It’s a lot more than just what you do in terms of their paychecks and their benefits, but it’s about their dignity.&nbsp;<br><br>My dad used to have an expression.&nbsp; He said, “Joey, a job is a lot more than a paycheck.&nbsp; It’s about your dignity.&nbsp; It’s about your place in the community.&nbsp; It’s about…”&nbsp; And I swear to God it’s what he&#8217;d say.&nbsp; “It’s about being able to look your kid in the eye and say, ‘Honey, everything is going to be okay.’”&nbsp;<br><br>Well, the union movement in the United States of America is the primary reason why that happened &#8212; the primary reason why that happened.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, look, there&#8217;s so much &#8212; we&#8217;ve done a lot, but there&#8217;s so much more to do.<br><br>So I &#8212; basic thing is, first of all: Thank you, thank you, thank you for your support.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>You&#8217;re the reason I&#8217;m standing here today as President.&nbsp; I’ve never forgotten not only what you’ve done for me, but what you’ve done for America.&nbsp; I’ve said this before, I&#8217;ll repeat it again &#8212; when I spoke to you a couple &#8212; about a year ago: You literally built this country.<br><br>If every investment banker in America would go on strike, not a whole hell of a lot would happen.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; If you all went on strike nationwide, the country would shut down &#8212; shut down.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>You’ve heard it a thousand times when I was running for office &#8212; a thousand times: The middle class built this country.&nbsp; Your plan was to build this economy around you, from the middle up and the bottom down &#8212; the bottom up.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m so sick and tired of trickle-down economics that only trickles to a few people.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>When the middle class does well, the poor have a way up and the wealthy do just fine.<br><br>As I&#8217;ve said, Wall Street didn’t build this country, the middle class did.&nbsp; And unions built the middle class, not labor. &nbsp;Unions built the middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That’s a tr- &#8212; it’s a fact.&nbsp; That’s a fact.<br><br>With your help, we’re seeing the strongest job creation in modern times.<br><br>We inherited an economy on the brink of a great depression &#8212; millions of people losing their jobs, losing their homes, but even more importantly, losing hope.<br><br>But look at the economy today: 8.3 million jobs in my first 15 months in office &#8212; a record.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>The unemployment rate now stands at 3.6 percent, the fastest decline &#8212; the fastest decline in unemployment at the start of any President’s term on record.<br><br>Jobs and companies are coming home again.&nbsp; We’re making “Buy America” a reality, not just a slogan.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Look, folks, our economy has gone from being on the mend to being on the move.&nbsp; You know, it started with my American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Because of it, we had the best year of state and local job growth in 20 years.&nbsp; We gave governors &#8212; great governors like the one in this state &#8212; we&nbsp;gave them a whole lot of money.&nbsp; We added back 460,000 jobs &#8212; critical state and local workers, educators, firefighters, police officers.&nbsp; This includes a record 279,000 education jobs in 2021, because they didn’t have the tax base to be able to hire them.&nbsp;<br><br>The American Rescue Plan provided eviction relief, funding for states and cities to allocate to landlords and renters &#8212; help them keep a roof over the heads &#8212; 5 million households.<br><br>Remember those long lines you’d see on the television and people lining up in all kinds of vehicles just to get a box of food in their trunk?&nbsp; How quickly we forget people were hurting.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And what did the MAGA crowd want to do?&nbsp; Forget it.&nbsp; Forget it.&nbsp;<br><br>God, this is the United States of America.&nbsp; The idea that people would have to wait in line an hour or hour and a half to get a box of food in their trunk &#8212; it’s just unbelievable.<br><br>You know, the American Rescue Plan helped 41 million people put food on the table &#8212; 41 million; the money in the pockets of hardworking Americans who, through no fault of their own, were in trouble, giving families what my dad called “just a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp;<br><br>And now, not only has “Infrastructure Week” finally arrived after four years of the other guy, we can look forward to the infrastructure decade for 10 years.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s a fact.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I know you’re all over the country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And the projects are coming to you.&nbsp; It’s not just for a year;&nbsp;it’s for the next decade &#8212; 10 years.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Here in Illinois alone there are over 6,000 miles of highway, 2,300 bridges in poor condition.<br><br>This year alone, Illinois will receive 1 billion 900 million dollars in highway funding for roads and bridges and $297 million dedicated &#8212; dedicated to funding for bridges that are in disrepair.<br><br>You know, I was going to Pittsburgh a couple of months ago, early &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Woo!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yeah, I like Pittsburgh, man.&nbsp; But I was going to Pittsburgh a couple months ago to speak. &nbsp;And as I got there, a bridge going over a culvert about &#8212; looked like about 200 yards long and about, at the top, probably 120 feet from the little creek below &#8212; totally collapsed.&nbsp; Totally collapsed.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank God one of the only things that the COVID crisis did was their kids weren’t in school; otherwise there’d be hundreds of kids in school buses going across there at the time.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This is the United States of America.&nbsp; The idea we have bridges that are collapsing, or about to collapse &#8212; I really mean it &#8212; it just drives me crazy to think about it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, look, Mayor Lightfoot talked about how Chicago has lead service pipes &#8212; more lead service pipes in drinking water than any other city in America, affecting nearly 400,000 Chicago homes.<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; That lead causes brain damage, particularly to kids, in those pipes.&nbsp; The law is going to fix that, because every American deserves to be able to turn on a spigot and drink clean water.&nbsp; Nationwide, 10 million homes.<br><br>Because of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we’ve announced nearly $3 billion to modernize more than&nbsp;<s>300</s>&nbsp;[3,000] airports across all 50 states &#8212; just like this year.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Chicago airports are going to receive &#8212; just this year &#8212; nearly $100 million that can be used to improve runways, taxiways, and terminals.<br><br>You know, some of you may remember, if you’re from New York City, when I was Vice President, I landed there to meet with a group of &#8212; to go in and speak to a union convention.&nbsp; I came back out to LaGuardia.&nbsp; And when I was in there, I said &#8212; and I walked into the terminal and there was a sign &#8212; one of the escalators wasn’t working.&nbsp; It’s the God’s truth.&nbsp; I looked up the escalator.&nbsp; It said, “Will be fixed in one month.”&nbsp;<br><br>One of the finest cities in all of America and you have a sign saying it’s going to take a month to fix an escalator.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I made a comment about that at the &#8212; at the union I spoke to and the group I spoke with.&nbsp; And it made instant news: “Biden was criticizing…”<br><br>Here’s what I said: I said, “If I took you to an airp- &#8212; blindfolded you, put you in an airport in Beijing and one in New York and I said to you, ‘Where are you: Beijing or New York?’”&nbsp;&#8212; you would’ve thought the Beijing airport was the American airport with no one in it.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; As I went back to get on Air Force Two, I’m standing there and I get off &#8212; I get out of the vehicle and I’m on the runway, and there’s nine guys and two women with their yellow, you know, bibs on and everything, who worked at the airport.&nbsp; I thought, “Oh, God.&nbsp; I’m not going to get up on the train &#8212; up on the plane.”&nbsp;<br><br>Do you know what they said?&nbsp; “Thank you. &nbsp;Thank you, thank you, thank you.”&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; They ended up investing almost a billion dollars in the airport, and it works.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This is the United States of America!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We used to have the finest infrastructure in the world.&nbsp; We were rated number one in the world; we’re now rated number 14. &nbsp;The United States of America.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; I would argue it’s because of the greed of the folks at the top not wanting to get things done.&nbsp;<br><br>But, folks, look, we’ve announced $5 billion, including $615&nbsp;<s>billion</s>&nbsp;[million] this year alone so the IBEW can get to work building a national network of 500,000 charging stations all across America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; This guy here is part of the reason.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>He won&#8217;t rem- &#8212; he won&#8217;t remember this, but I met with all the heads of &#8212; the CEOs of the major car companies.&nbsp; And you may remember General Motors back then, when I first got elected, was suing California because they said they had a higher standard for emissions than other states, and they couldn’t have a na- &#8212; a local standard higher than a federal standard.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I talked to Mary Barra.&nbsp; And about two weeks later, she called me and said, “We’re dropping our suit.&nbsp; We’re dropping our suit.”&nbsp; And I listened, and she said, “We’re going to go all electric by 2035.”&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; Five hundred thousand charging stations are going to have to be built as we build these things.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I think this guy is partially to blame.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Look, more than $20 billion so IBEW workers can modernize our electric grid, building larger and more resilient transmission lines that can withstand storms and get new and clean energy to our homes.&nbsp;<br><br>Think about it, folks: Who the hell but you crazy guys climb up poles in the middle of a storm to try to replace a generator?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, I’m serious.&nbsp; I’m genuinely serious.&nbsp; People don’t get &#8212; we have to let people know more of what you actually do.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We’re investing $65 billion so that highly skilled and certified IBEW wor- &#8212; members can deliver affordable high-speed &#8212; high-speed Internet everywhere &#8212; rural, urban, suburban.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Just this week, I announced that 40 million low-income Americans from families of four earning less than $55,000 a year will get high-speed Internet installed in their homes for free.&nbsp; Free!&nbsp; Free!&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And we worked it out with the Internet companies.&nbsp; Nearly 40 percent of households in America will qualify.<br><br>We can’t be a country where a mother has to drive up to a McDonald’s parking lot in the evening with her child just so he can get on the Internet to do his homework.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Again, this is the United States of America, for God’s sake.&nbsp;<br><br>And what this means to all of you is good-paying union jobs.&nbsp; Jobs you can raise a family on.&nbsp; Jobs that can’t be outsourced.<br><br>This law is about more than rebuilding infrastructure.&nbsp; It’s also how about rebuilding the middle class.&nbsp;<br><br>As I said, unions built the middle class.&nbsp; And that’s why we made sure that the Infrastructure Law included significant labor protections.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>For example, the overwhelming majority of the funds included in the law are subject to Davis-Bacon requirements, so folks rebuilding our country can earn a prevailing wage.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Look, it’s why we’re strongly encouraging grantees who get infrastructure funding to use project labor agreements to ensure that workers building the major projects are well-trained, highly-skilled, and have a voice on the work site.<br><br>That’s why I continue to call on Congress to fully and finally pass the PRO Act, which makes &#8212; (applause) &#8212; which makes it easier for workers to organize a union.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I’m not just saying this to be pro-union.&nbsp; I’m saying this because I’m pro-America.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, when Congress passed the National Labor Relations Act in 1935, it didn’t just say that we should “allow” unions.&nbsp; Everybody forgot this for a long time.&nbsp; What it said is: We, the federal government, should “encourage” unions and collective bargaining.&nbsp; That’s what it said.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There’s a reason for that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Let’s be clear for our Republican friends: You can’t say you’re working &#8212; you’re for working people and vote against the PRO Act.&nbsp; It’s not consistent.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Look, you all know why this matters.&nbsp; Union members get higher wages, better benefits and health insurance, paid leave; protections against discrimination and harassment; and safer and healthier workplaces.<br><br>But there’s another reason: Workers join unions to gain power.&nbsp; That’s what it’s about.&nbsp; The only way to match power is with power.&nbsp; It’s the only way it can be done.&nbsp; You can’t count on the good graces of major corporations to decide they’re going to help. &nbsp;Power is needed to be exerted to deal with power.&nbsp; Power over the decisions that affect your lives.&nbsp;<br><br>Unions provide, in one word, democracy.<br><br>Rebuilding America with union labor is also smart for business.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; This is the point I make &#8212; and, by the way, I’m not getting many arguments from CEOs.&nbsp; It’s smart for business.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; When union workers are on the job, projects are completed efficiently and professionally, and they ultimately save money.<br><br>For folks at home, maybe you’re not in a union or know anyone who is in a union, but know this: It’s hard work.&nbsp; You got to earn it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Ask a journeyman electricians, anyone &#8212; a journeymen electricians here today &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, I’m serious.&nbsp; Think about this.&nbsp; And you guys got to talk &#8212; with all due respect, you got to talk more about this.<br><br>The fact is: It takes four to five years as an apprentice &#8212; 8,000 hours of training.&nbsp; Now, granted, you get paid while you&#8217;re doing it.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But the power goes out in a storm &#8212; why do you think &#8212; who climbs up that pole while the snow and the rain are still coming down?&nbsp; Union workers.&nbsp; They&#8217;re the best workers in the world.&nbsp; You&#8217;re the most qua- &#8212; this is not &#8212; again, I&#8217;m not trying to be nice to you all.&nbsp; No, I really &#8212; I mean this sincerely.<br><br>Why, if you have the capacity, would you not hire a union worker, whatever the job is &#8212; not just IBEW, a union worker &#8212; to do the job?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Seriously.<br><br>We all talk about &#8212; you go to college for four years.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; When you got to be an apprentice and it takes up to five years to get your apprenti- &#8212; to go through the program, you&#8217;re getting a hell of an edu- &#8212; you&#8217;re working like hell.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why you&#8217;re the most qualified people in the world &#8212; not just here, in the world.<br><br>And we&#8217;re beginning to see the effects of unions and the impact on everything from what you see going on in Ukraine right now.&nbsp; Our stuff isn&#8217;t falling apart.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Theirs is.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; Theirs is.&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So, folks, their quality of work is good for the American taxpayer. &nbsp;We&#8217;re not costing the American taxpayers money.&nbsp; We&#8217;re saving them money.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, no &#8212; I &#8212; I &#8212; you guys don&#8217;t say this enough, quite frankly.&nbsp; Excu- &#8212; if you don&#8217;t mind my saying so.&nbsp; All in the family here.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t say it enough.<br><br>It’s good for families in every neighborhood where infrastructure projects are underway.<br><br>Look, but here’s the deal: Building an economy from the bottom up and middle out doesn’t happen by itself.<br><br>For example, I know folks are concerned about inflation.&nbsp; I come from a family &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; like most of you, where if the price of gasoline went up significantly and the price of food went up, that&#8217;s what we talked about at the dinner table and the kitchen table.&nbsp; It meant a lot.&nbsp; We felt it.&nbsp; We felt it.&nbsp; I understand.<br><br>That’s why I’ve got a plan to lower the costs for everyday things that make most people &#8212; who work to have, who need it.&nbsp; And that would fundamentally change the standard of living if we just made things more affordable.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s more than one way to deal with the impact on a family than what we&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to beat inflation.&nbsp; But beyond that, it&#8217;s all about the quality of life.<br><br>You know, I remember my dad used to say &#8212; if he had an opportunity &#8212; my dad, I guess, made &#8212; back in the late &#8217;60s, he probably made the equivalent of $20,000 a year.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t a bad salary, but it wasn&#8217;t great.&nbsp; He had four kids.<br><br>And if someone came along and said to my dad, &#8220;I can guarantee that your salary is going to go up 500 bucks a year every year for the next 10 years, or we can make sure your kid can go to college with a lot cheaper than it costs now.&nbsp; I can make sure your cost of electricity and energy in your home is down, not up.&nbsp; I can make sure that you&#8217;re going to be in a position where you&#8217;re going to have &#8212; the roads in front of the house are going to be paved.&nbsp; What do you ask for?&#8221;<br><br>My dad would say, &#8220;All the rest relates to my standard of living.&#8221;&nbsp; That&#8217;s what middle-class folks are concerned about.&nbsp; And not being embarrassed in front of their kids when they can&#8217;t do something that they know they should be able to do for them.<br><br>I really mean it.&nbsp; Again, it gets back to a word that&#8217;s probably overused in my house.&nbsp; As my grandfather would say, &#8220;Maybe it&#8217;s the Irish of it.&#8221;&nbsp; The word &#8220;dignity.&#8221;&nbsp; The simple dignity.<br><br>And so, there are so many things we can do that don&#8217;t do anything other than make the country better and don&#8217;t cost the taxpayers more money if we just decide to be fair and everybody would begin to pay their fair share.<br><br>Look, folks, you know, an example of my plan would be to let Medicare negotiate the price of prescription drugs like the Department of Veterans Affairs does.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We say to the &#8212; the companies that are &#8212; the drug companies, &#8220;We&#8217;re only going to pay X number of dollars for the following thing.&nbsp; If you don&#8217;t want to do that, we&#8217;re not going to buy any of your drugs.&#8221;&nbsp; Well, since you got thousands of people and when you&#8217;re talking millions of people, they say, &#8220;Okay.&#8221;<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal, going back to this idea &#8212; just making sure we have basic dignity.<br><br>You know, putting a cap on the price of insulin &#8212; many of you have children &#8212; or maybe some of you have Type 2 diabetes.&nbsp; People with Type 2 diabetes need their insulin shots.&nbsp; Need them.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not like an option &#8212; not like an option.<br><br>Well, guess what?&nbsp; It costs the drug companies 10 bucks &#8212; you hear me?&nbsp; &#8212; $10 to make that insulin and &#8212; counting in all the research and development they did to get to that point.<br><br>Yet, you know what the average cost of insulin for a month for a Type 2 diabetic is?&nbsp; And there&#8217;s 200,000 kids out there who have Type&nbsp;<s>2</s>&nbsp;[1] diabetes.&nbsp; They &#8212; the average cost is $640 a month.<br><br>Now, what the hell do you do, as a mom or a dad, if you don&#8217;t have private insurance and you don&#8217;t have coverage?<br><br>Not only do you look at your child &#8212; I mean this sincerely and from the bottom of my heart.&nbsp; You look at your child, and not only do you worry about where they&#8217;re going to live &#8212; because you got to divide up what little you have and maybe stretch it out.&nbsp; What do you think it does to you as a parent, looking at your child?&nbsp; Talk about being deprived of your personal dignity.<br><br>What the hell are we doing?&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Think of the difference that it would make for millions of Americans struggling every single month to afford insulin for their child.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Take childcare: In a city like this or any major cities in America, it costs about $14,000 a year per child who’s not at school age.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I remember.&nbsp; I was 29 years old.&nbsp; You guys helped to get me elected to the United States Senate.&nbsp; I wasn’t old enough to be sworn in.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I was down in Washington, interviewing staff before I was sworn in.&nbsp; And I got a phone call from the first responders in my state.&nbsp; They said, “You got to come home.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been an accident.”&nbsp; I said, “What happened?”&nbsp; They said, “Well, a tractor trailer broadsided your wife&#8217;s car with your three kids while they were Christmas shopping.”&nbsp; And the poor young woman they put on the phone to tell me said, “And your wife is dead.&nbsp; Your daughter is dead.&nbsp; And your boys are really hurt.”<br><br>So, I went home, obviously.&nbsp; And I didn’t want to stay in the Senate.&nbsp; I wanted no part of it.&nbsp; But because of some really fine men &#8212; one Republican and five Democrats &#8212; they convinced me that, “Well, Joe, just come and stay six months.&nbsp; Help us organize.”&nbsp; See how smart I was?&nbsp; We had elected 58 Democrats and a Democratic governor in my state that would have appointed a Democrat.&nbsp; So, I said okay.&nbsp; I thought I had to go because &#8212; to help.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, one of the things I found out was: How am I going to take care of my two little boys?&nbsp; Almost three and almost four.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford daycare.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford childcare.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; And I was making $42,000 a year, which was a lot of money, as a U.S. senator.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford it.&nbsp; Thank God I got a big family.&nbsp; My dad would say, “Family is the beginning, middle, and the end.”&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>My sister moved in, and I bought an old farmhouse.&nbsp; And my brother was single, moved in.&nbsp; Took a barn and turned it into an apartment.&nbsp; Every morning, I’d drive to the train station to drop my kids off at my mom&#8217;s.&nbsp; I had a lot of help.<br><br>But it made me realize: How about that single woman with a high-school education or less, with two little kids without a dad &#8212; how in God&#8217;s name they can make it.&nbsp; And yet, how can they go to work?&nbsp;<br><br>The point being that if we just said anyone making under &#8212; a family making under 120 grand a year would not have to pay more than 7 percent of their income for childcare, we’d cut in half the cost of childcare on a yearly basis, making it easy for &#8212; much easier for a whole lot of people to be able to work.&nbsp; It’d put over 200,000 women back in the job market who are leaving only because they can&#8217;t afford &#8212; can&#8217;t afford childcare.&nbsp;<br><br>Folks, imagine what that would mean to the standard of living for a household.<br><br>Folks, there&#8217;s no reason why we shouldn&#8217;t get a tax credit for weatherizing your homes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Make it more efficient to buy electric vehicles.&nbsp; My plan does that.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I met with nearly a dozen CEOs of America&#8217;s largest utility companies.&nbsp; Literally a dozen of them came to see me.&nbsp; They confirmed that if we pass the investments allowing families to &#8212; if they weatherize their homes, to write it off &#8212; a tax credit &#8212; it will immediately lower the bills of these families an average of $500 a year.<br><br>We can do these things without making a lot of sacrifices.&nbsp; We just asked the large corporations, the wealthiest Americans just to begin to pay part of their fair share of taxes.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>No one making less &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no one making less &#8212; no one making under $400,000 a year, I promise you, will pay an additional penny in federal taxes.&nbsp; I said that at the beginning, and I&#8217;ve kept that commitment.<br><br>Meanwhile, right now, the average billionaire &#8212; there’s about 790 of them or so in America &#8212; you know what their average tax rate is?&nbsp; Eight percent.&nbsp; E-I-G-H-T.&nbsp; Eight percent.&nbsp; Now &#8212; in federal taxes.&nbsp; But most of you are likely paying two to three times that much.&nbsp;<br><br>No billionaire should be paying a lower tax rate than a teacher, a firefighter, an electrician, a cop.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, I mean it.&nbsp; And they shouldn&#8217;t be paying 90 percent either.&nbsp; If we just moved the tax rate back to 39 percent, we’d have enough money to pay for all these things &#8212; for them, for people making tens of millions of dollars.&nbsp;<br><br>This is about fairness.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about dignity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about fiscal responsibility.<br><br>My Republican colleagues say these programs to help the working-class and middle-class people &#8212; that&#8217;s &#8212; they say that&#8217;s why we have inflation.&nbsp; They&#8217;re dead wrong.&nbsp;<br><br>Under my predecessor, the great MAGA king, the deficit increased every single year he was President.&nbsp; The first year of my presidency &#8212; the first year, I reduced the deficit &#8212; literally reduced the deficit by $350 billion.&nbsp; First year.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And this year &#8212; and this year, we&#8217;re on track to cut the federal deficit by 1 trillion 500 billion dollars &#8212; the biggest decline in debt ever in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>It matters to families, because reducing the deficit is one of the main ways that we can ease inflationary pressures.<br><br>But pay close attention.&nbsp; I believe in bipartisanship.&nbsp; Right now, the majority of our Republican friends just see things differently.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t want to solve inflation&nbsp;&#8212; inflation by lowering the costs.&nbsp; They want to solve it by raising taxes and lowering your income.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, you think I&#8217;m making this up. &nbsp;If I didn’t see the actual document, I’d think you &#8212; I was making it up.&nbsp; I happen to think it’s good &#8212; a good thing when American families have more money in their pockets.&nbsp; American workers deserve a raise.&nbsp;<br><br>All this concern &#8212; “Ameri- &#8212; wages went up 5 percent.&nbsp; Oh my God.”&nbsp; I thought that we were supposed to see happen.&nbsp;<br><br>Republicans in Congress have proposed a plan that will make working families and American families poorer.&nbsp; Now, I&#8217;m not &#8212; I &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m not usually this discreet about my Republican friends.&nbsp; I get along with a lot of them &#8212; used to anyway.&nbsp;<br><br>But Senator Rick Scott, a Republican from Florida, laid out a plan in writing &#8212; the Ult- &#8212; well, it’s called the &#8212; I call it the “Ultra-MAGA” plan &#8212; Make America Great Again plan.&nbsp; It’s in writing.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And here’s what it does: It raises taxes on 75 million American families, over 95 percent of whom earn less than $100,000 a year in a combined income.&nbsp; It would raise taxes by nearly $1,500 per family.&nbsp; It’s all in writing.&nbsp; You can go online.&nbsp;<br><br>They’ve got it backwards.&nbsp;<br><br>I’ve proposed a minimum tax for billionaires, but congressional Republicans have proposed a minimum tax for teachers, firefighters, and electricians.&nbsp;<br><br>And while on this &#8212; you know, 55 of the Fortune 500 &#8212; Fortune 500 companies in 2020 &#8212; 55 of them paid zero in federal taxes after making $40 billion.&nbsp; Forty billion dollars.&nbsp; Zero in federal taxes.&nbsp; It isn’t right.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I proposed a minimum tax for corporations that asks them to pay their fair share in taxes.&nbsp; Senator Scott’s plan lets them off, no pun intended, scot-free.<br><br>I want to strengthen Social Security benefits to make folks who have worked for their whole lives and have paid into it &#8212; make sure they have it.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to give Medicare the power to negotiate drug prices.&nbsp; I want states to continue to expand Medicaid.&nbsp;<br><br>And the ultra-MAGA Republicans’ proposal puts &#8212; here’s what it does: It puts Social Security, Medicare &#8212; this is the Republican plan now; the only one out there &#8212; and Medicaid on the chopping block every five years.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Here’s how it works: Their plan explicitly states that, every five years it will require a vote on whether or not to continue each of these programs.&nbsp; Republicans in Congress want to put Medicare’s very existence up for a vote every five years.&nbsp; Same with Social Security and Medicaid.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, really, ask yourself: How well are you going to sleep at night knowing that every five years everything you’ve paid into may not be there?<br><br>Not &#8212; this is &#8212; this is serious.&nbsp; The MAGA Republicans are going to vote on whether you’ll have Social Security, Medicare, or Medicaid and what amount you get.&nbsp; Every five years it’s reconsidered.<br><br>Now, I have to admit it’s unlikely they’ll vote Social Security totally out of existence.&nbsp; But what do you think they’re likely to do if this were to pass?&nbsp; I &#8212; I&#8217;ve been a &#8212; I&#8217;ve been in Congress a long time.&nbsp;&nbsp;I was pretty good at what I did in Congress.&nbsp; I guarantee you what they do every five years &#8212; they&#8217;ll hold hostages to get their way.<br><br>They’ll say, “If, in fact, you don&#8217;t vote for this particular thing, we&#8217;re going to cut Social Security.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to cut Medicaid.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to cut whatever.”<br><br>The idea you&#8217;d have to renegotiate Social Security every five years?&nbsp; I mean, this is in writing.&nbsp; Look it up.<br><br>You know, they&#8217;re going to say, “If you don&#8217;t stop investing in clean energy &#8212; because we don&#8217;t like it, we don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s global warming &#8212; we&#8217;re going to cut the following.”<br><br>Folks, this is not who we are.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve got to keep fighting for an economy that&#8217;s about fairness, dignity, and opportunity; that&#8217;s about America &#8212; about America.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And, folks, you know, as my mother used to say, “Out of everything bad, Joey, something good will happen if you look hard enough for it.”&nbsp; So let me close it this.<br><br>Last month, I visited the main airport in Portland, Oregon, which is undergoing major renovations being funded by the Bipart- &#8212; (applause) &#8212; being funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I met a woman named Lauren of IBEW Local 48.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; She came up to me.&nbsp; She shared what the job meant to her, how she grew up poor and was raised by a single mom, how she bounced around in different careers until she came in a &#8212; until she became an apprentice with the IBEW.<br><br>She’s putting in her years and the thousands of hours that she needs to put in to become a journeyman electrician.&nbsp; Lauren told me that the airport will symbolize the crown jewel of the Pacific Northwest but it will also symbolize something else: a better life &#8212; a better life for an IBEW member.&nbsp; That means fairness and dignity in the workplace.&nbsp;<br><br>And it’ll be a symbol for a better America because the IB- &#8212; IBEW is just getting started.<br><br>Folks, I promised you that I’d be the most pro-union President in American history &#8212; (applause) &#8212; because I know this: In a crisis, America always counts on you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; So you can count on me to keep fighting for you!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Keep going!&nbsp; Keep building!&nbsp; Keep the faith!&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>God bless you all, and may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>4:49 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the White&#160;House’s First Stakeholder Convening on Mining&#160;Reform</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/readout-of-the-white-houses-first-stakeholder-convening-on-mining-reform/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52976</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On 150th Anniversary Of 1872 Mining Law, Biden-Harris Administration Convenes Representatives from States, Tribes, The Mining Industry, Environmental Groups, Legal Experts to Discuss Much Needed Reform to Outdated Law Yesterday, the White House convened over 20 representatives from states, Tribes, the mining industry, environmental groups, labor unions, automakers, legal experts, and other stakeholders on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>On 150<sup>th</sup> Anniversary Of 1872 Mining Law, Biden-Harris Administration Convenes Representatives from States, Tribes, The Mining Industry, Environmental Groups, Legal Experts to Discuss Much Needed Reform to Outdated Law</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Yesterday, the White House convened over 20 representatives from states, Tribes, the mining industry, environmental groups, labor unions, automakers, legal experts, and other stakeholders on the 150th anniversary of the signing of the Mining Law of 1872 to discuss the need for reforms and improvements to establish strong, 21st Century environmental and engagement standards that would allow for the responsible and sustainable development of domestic hardrock minerals.<br><br>This meeting was the first external engagement of the Department of Interior-led Interagency Working Group on Mining Regulations, Laws, and Permitting, which is charged with providing recommendations to Congress on how to reform the mining law to ensure new production meets strong environmental standards throughout the lifecycle of the project, ensure meaningful community consultation and consultation with Tribal nations, and reduce the time, cost, and risk of mine permitting.&nbsp; Additional stakeholder meetings will be held over the coming months, and comments can also be submitted in response to the Request for Information that was issued by the Department of the Interior on March 31. Comments can be made through July 31, 2022 at <a href="https://www.regulations.gov/document/DOI-2022-0003-0001">Regulations.gov</a>.<br><br>Participants discussed the shared benefits, challenges, and opportunities of reforming the current system. The General Mining Law of 1872 governs the extraction of critical and valuable minerals on federal lands across the country, and has remained fundamentally unchanged since Ulysses S. Grant signed it to promote westward expansion. The law does not require royalties to be paid to the taxpayers for the extraction and sale of valuable minerals, does not include any environmental, reclamation or financial assurance provisions, and fails to have a single department in charge of mining, leaving stakeholders and companies to navigate a morass of systems and laws. As we grow the clean energy economy, critical minerals for electric vehicles, large capacity batteries, wind turbines, and other clean energy technologies, such as lithium, cobalt, and nickel, are projected to increase in demand by 400-600% in the coming decades. The current global supply chains for these minerals too often fail to adhere to strong social and environmental standards, despite the demands of the end customers and companies. Creating a modern legal framework for the socially and environmentally responsible and sustainable mining and production of these minerals is essential to the Biden-Harris Administration’s efforts to strengthen our critical supply chains; the administration <a href="https://www.doi.gov/sites/doi.gov/files/biden-harris-administration-fundamental-principles-for-domestic-mining-reform.pdf">issued</a> principles for mining reform in February to guide this effort.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>After participating in the convening, participants ranging from companies, Tribes, environmental groups, trade groups, experts, and labor unions all highlighted the importance of the discussion and common goals to improve the current system:<br><br><strong>Tom Palmer, President and CEO, Newmont Corporation</strong>: “Newmont Corporation was honored to be a part of today’s discussion with the White House on modernizing the General Mining Law. This historic gathering of diverse stakeholders, including federal and state government agencies and representatives, Native American leaders, Labor, NGOs, Academia, and consumers provided a rare opportunity to discuss updates to the Federal regulatory system to incentivize responsible domestic metals and minerals mining in a challenging global environment. We appreciate the Administration convening this productive session and initiating the discussion on the future of mining in the United States. We look forward to Newmont&#8217;s continued participation and collaboration.”&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Jennifer Krill, Executive Director, Earthworks</strong>: “Meeting the President’s climate and environmental justice goals depends on a shift in the way we source and use minerals. To ensure that our emerging clean energy system is not built on dirty mining, we must reform the rules of the road for mining and invest in creating a sustainable minerals economy. On this 150th anniversary of the 1872 Mining Law, Earthworks looks forward to working with the Biden-Harris administration and a broad group of stakeholders to promote a rapid, just, and equitable renewable energy transition using responsibly sourced materials.”<br><br><strong>Joe Britton, Executive Director, Zero Emission Transportation Association</strong>: &#8220;We had a great conversation today with a diverse array of federal, tribal, electric vehicle and critical mineral stakeholders committed to climate action, sustainable economies, and conservation. There was strong consensus on the need to both encourage community consultation and take action that reflects the urgency of responsibly procuring the critical minerals needed for climate solution technologies. ZETA thanks the Biden-Harris Administration for leading these tough discussions and looks forward to making progress on the decarbonization needed to make us all better off.”<br><br><strong>Rich Nolan, President and CEO, National Mining Association</strong>: “The NMA was pleased today to join the Biden administration’s Interagency Working Group on mining law reform at the White House. The strength of the U.S. economy depends on mining, and industry stands ready to work with the government to find a productive path forward that will help reshore essential supply chains, reduce our mineral import overreliance and build the materials industrial base needed to underpin the energy transition and the EV revolution. We look forward to continuing to contribute to the work of this important group.”<br><br><strong>Sam Penney, Chairman, Nez Perce: “</strong>The Nez Perce Tribe appreciates the White House convening the mining reform meeting today. Listening to the various perspectives of states, Tribes, and stakeholders is an important initial step. Protection of treaty reserved rights and upholding federal trust responsibility are critical aspects of mining reform.<strong>”</strong><br><br><strong>Collin O’Mara, President and CEO, National Wildlife Federation</strong>: “Responsibly mined critical minerals are essential for our clean energy future and our national security — and it’s time that we finally move our 19<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;century laws into the 21<sup>st&nbsp;</sup>century. President Biden and his administration have made it clear that they are serious about responsibly producing a secure domestic supply of critical minerals through reclamation, recycling, and new mining, while fully supporting communities and workers, remediating abandoned mines, and addressing the impacts on clean drinking water, lands, and wildlife and people alike.”<br><br><strong>Mark Bristow, President &amp; CEO, Barrick: </strong>“Barrick and Nevada Gold Mines value being part of the discussions today and look forward to continued collaboration with the federal government and other stakeholders. We support the initiative to improve the permitting process and regulatory regime with the objective of ensuring responsible mining of minerals and metals in the United States of America.”<br><br><strong>John Ruple, Professor of Law (Research) &amp; Wallace Stegner Center Fellow, S.J. Quinney College of Law, University of Utah</strong>: “The 150-year-old General Mining Law is like driving a stagecoach, and it’s time to trade in the stagecoach for an electric vehicle. Today’s meeting included a broad representation of mining stakeholders—from multinational mining corporations, to Tribes and environmentalists, to organized labor and academia—universally, we agree on the value in updating the 150-year-old general mining law to increase the supply of strategic minerals and an opportunity to improve environmental stewardship and collaboration with Native Nations. I am honored to work with the Biden-Harris Administration on efforts to bring mining law into the 21st century and to secure for America the critical minerals that we need for a transition to renewable energy in an environmentally responsible manner.”<br><br><strong>Yvette Pena-O&#8217;Sullivan, Executive Director of the Office of the President, Laborers&#8217; International Union of North America (LIUNA)</strong>: “I was pleased to be a part of the White House&#8217;s convening of stakeholders from labor, industry, environment, and tribal communities to discuss mining reform and remediation.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s meeting was an important step forward to securing a safe and domestic supply chain for critical minerals.&nbsp; The hard-working men and women of LIUNA who work on mineral mining projects too often have their livelihoods put on hold as permits are stalled due to outdated policies and a legal framework that dates to the 1870s. LIUNA commends the Biden-Harris Administration’s leadership in charting a new strategy on critical minerals that can help our nation build a vibrant clean energy economy responsibly.”&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Jason Walsh, Executive Director, BlueGreen Allilance:</strong> “As we work to grow the clean economy, demand for mined materials—such as copper, lithium, and nickel, as well as other minerals, metals, and rare earths—is only going to increase. We need&nbsp;a new national commitment to responsible mining and the reclamation and recycling of these minerals and materials. And we have to do this&nbsp;in ways that uphold our obligations to workers, communities, and the environment. We appreciate the administration convening this&nbsp;important&nbsp;conversation and we&nbsp;look forward&nbsp;to&nbsp;continuing to&nbsp;discuss and advance&nbsp;this issue with our partners.”<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After the Senate Vote on the Women&#8217;s Health Protection&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/11/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-the-senate-vote-on-the-womens-health-protection-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 21:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Q Madam Vice President, what does this vote mean? And what is your message to women and childbearing people in America about what’s next? THE VICE PRESIDENT: Yeah, so, I just presided over the Women&#8217;s Health Protective Act vote. And sadly, the Senate failed to stand in defense of a woman&#8217;s right to make decisions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Q Madam Vice President, what does this vote mean? And what is your message to women and childbearing people in America about what’s next?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT: Yeah, so, I just presided over the Women&#8217;s Health Protective Act vote. And sadly, the Senate failed to stand in defense of a woman&#8217;s right to make decisions about her own body.</p>



<p>And let&#8217;s be clear, the majority of the American people believe in defending a woman&#8217;s right, her choice to decide what happens to her own body. And this vote clearly suggests that the Senate is not where the majority of Americans are on this issue.</p>



<p>It also makes clear that a priority for all who care about this issue &#8212; a priority should be to elect pro-choice leaders at the local, the state, and the federal level, because what we are seeing around this country are extremist Republican leaders who are seeking to criminalize and punish women for making decisions about their own body.</p>



<p>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Meeting with Partnership for Central America to Drive Progress on Vice President Harris’s Call to&#160;Action</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/readout-of-meeting-with-partnership-for-central-america-to-drive-progress-on-vice-president-harriss-call-to-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 20:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris joined a meeting with National Security Advisor to the Vice President Dr. Phil Gordon, Chief Economic Advisor to the Vice President Michael Pyle, and business leaders who have invested in northern Central America under the Vice President’s Call to Action.  Launched in May 2021, the Vice President’s initiative has mobilized&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris joined a meeting with National Security Advisor to the Vice President Dr. Phil Gordon, Chief Economic Advisor to the Vice President Michael Pyle, and business leaders who have invested in northern Central America under the Vice President’s Call to Action.  Launched in May 2021, the Vice President’s initiative has mobilized over $1.2 billion in private sector investment for northern Central America and is a key pillar of the U.S. government’s comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of migration from the region.  Vice President Harris expressed her gratitude to the group for their leadership and for the success of the public-private partnership. She highlighted U.S. government efforts to support their investments in the region and address the drivers of migration, including by combatting corruption and improving governance and security. The Vice President and other attendees agreed to continue to work to deepen investments in the region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on the U.S.-ASEAN Special&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/11/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-the-u-s-asean-special-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 20:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 3:04 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&#160; So this call is on background.&#160; It is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&#160; And the contents of the call are embargoed until the end of the call.&#160; For your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker on the call today is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>3:04 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; So this call is on background.&nbsp; It is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And the contents of the call are embargoed until the end of the call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker on the call today is [senior administration official].&nbsp; So I&#8217;m going to turn it over to you to give some remarks and we can take some questions.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, guys.&nbsp; And thank you all for joining.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sorry to be a couple of minutes late.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to balance, you know, 10 delegations here in Washington, so it&#8217;s substantial.&nbsp; And I’m grateful to [moderator] and her team for arranging this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I&#8217;d like to do a couple of things today.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to explain and give you some background for the ASEAN Special Summit, which will be taking place here in Washington, D.C. &#8212; at the White House, at the Willard, and at the State Department &#8212; on Thursday and Friday.&nbsp; And then just preview quickly &#8212; and we&#8217;ll do more of this next week &#8212; the upcoming travel of the President to South Korea and Japan.</p>



<p>So, just quickly, I think as you know, President Biden very much looks forward to welcoming the leaders of ASEAN to Washington, D.C. &#8212; again, on Thursday or Friday &#8212; for full days of discussions the 12th and 13th for what we are calling a U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is the first time in its 45-year history that ASEAN leaders will be welcomed together to Washington, D.C.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had summit meetings before in the region, and also during the Obama administration, there was a meeting in Sunnylands.&nbsp; But this is the first time they&#8217;ve gathered together in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>So just by way of background, guys: So, you know, we think this is important for obvious reasons.&nbsp; You know, there is a daily urgent set of demands as the West, the transatlantic community is engaging deeply on what&#8217;s going on on the battlefield in Ukraine.&nbsp; And that obviously takes an enormous amount of time, focus, energy, and resources currently of the senior leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it is also the case there is a deep recognition that fundamental long-term challenges are playing out in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And the United States is committed and determining to ensuring that our engagement in the region is broad, is broad-based, and is sustained.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So part of that will be the hosting of the summit.&nbsp; Part of it will be the trip to South Korea and Japan.&nbsp; And as part of each of those stops, there&#8217;ll be a range of engagements, including the fourth Quad meeting at the leader level in just over a year.&nbsp; That will be hosted by Prime Minister Kishida in Tokyo on the 24th of May, next week or the week after next.</p>



<p>So for the U.S.-ASEAN Summit, the program is as follows:</p>



<p>On Thursday, tomorrow, Speaker Pelosi and other senior leaders from Capitol Hill will welcome the ASEAN leaders to the Capitol for a bipartisan working lunch.&nbsp; And, obviously, this is important because, for many years, one of the most important areas of engagement for Capitol Hill was in Southeast Asia, and that continues.</p>



<p>And so, it&#8217;s important that the leaders from the region see the bipartisan commitment to the Indo-Pacific that we certainly have seen over the course of the last year and half.</p>



<p>After that, the ASEAN leaders will move to the Willard, where they will meet senior American business leaders and CEOs to discuss ways of strengthening economic cooperation between one of the most dynamic regions on the planet and the United States.</p>



<p>They will be joined by a variety of folks, including Secretary of Commerce Raimondo and U.S. Trade Representative Ambassador Tai.&nbsp; There will be discussions at this session about key challenges ahead in technology, post-COVID recovery, issues associated with climate and energy.&nbsp; The desire is to have these senior &#8212; these senior business leaders from across the United States engage and think about how to engage more directly going forward, given the dynamism in the region as a whole.</p>



<p>After that, President Biden will be hosting the ASEAN Leaders for an intimate dinner in the White House, for an opportunity to listen to the leaders about their aspirations for where they want to take ASEAN and how the United States can help in that in the period ahead.</p>



<p>Day two: Vice President Harris and Secretary of State Blinken will host ASEAN leaders for a working lunch at the State Department, and it&#8217;s focused primarily on &#8212; the lunch &#8212; on maritime cooperation, pandemic recovery, and health security.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vice President Harris will also host a discussion with ASEAN leaders and other Cabinet officials from across the interagency regarding climate action, clean energy, and sustainable infrastructure.</p>



<p>Let me just take a moment here that &#8212; I think part of the ambition of this summit is to broaden and deepen not only the level of engagement in the U.S. government but in certain key parts of the government like the State Department, the White House, and DOD, but to broaden it across every element of our government.</p>



<p>So we are seeking discussions and programs on education, on maritime domain awareness, on forestry across the board.&nbsp; So the idea here is to make sure that the ASEAN leaders see the breadth and depth, again, of the U.S. commitment to ASEAN as a whole.</p>



<p>And as you know, this is building on an area of expertise for &#8212; and interest for Vice President Harris.&nbsp; She traveled to the region at the end of last year, and she&#8217;s interested and excited to engage with the leaders about opportunities for U.S. &#8212; enhancing U.S. ties with Southeast Asia going forward.</p>



<p>And then, later in the afternoon, President Biden will host a discussion with ASEAN leaders on how to deliver directly for people in the region and beyond.</p>



<p>So, you know, I think the desire here is to have an intense set of discussions with, again, all our senior officials who will all be present and business leaders to indicate how seriously we take the relationship between the United States and ASEAN.</p>



<p>And I think you can expect to see the United States taking steps to deepen our longstanding cooperation in a whole host of areas.&nbsp; We’ve got some ideas for how to pursue new avenues of dialogue.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to be thinking about how to invest in our countries and work on driving inclusive prosperity.</p>



<p>And I think it is also clear that the United States will also focus on efforts to promote respect for human rights, the rule of law, and good governance.&nbsp; And we will together address the ongoing crisis and challenges in Burma.</p>



<p>On the President&#8217;s &#8212; so I’ll just take a minute, [senior administration official], really quickly &#8212; the President&#8217;s travel.&nbsp; He will be going &#8212; he will be going to South Korea to meet the new President who has just been sworn in.&nbsp; And he will then be proceeding to Japan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll have more details on the travels as we get closer, but I just want to understand that &#8212; you know, I want you to understand that, really, since the President&#8217;s inauguration, we&#8217;ve done a lot in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll just give you a couple of examples for background in your stories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re the first administration that has taken the Quad &#8212; that&#8217;s the United States, Australia, India, and Japan &#8212; to the leader level.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had a number of meetings, and they all &#8212; again, as I’ve indicated &#8212; they will meet in Tokyo on the President&#8217;s travel.</p>



<p>We have decided for the first time in seven decades to share sensitive nuclear submarine technology with another country.&nbsp; We launched AUKUS that binds and bonds Australia, Great Britain, and the United States in a fundamental endeavor to deliver on the promise of nuclear-powered submarines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this partnership will also include more areas of technology cooperation with other countries.&nbsp; We’ll have more to report on that as we go forward.</p>



<p>I think what we have also seen is substantial engagement in the Pacific.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; clearly, the Indo-Pacific is a broad region, and too often we speak a lot about Southeast Asia, Northeast Asia, India.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s equally important to focus on the Pacific, and you will be seeing indications of that going forward.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also broadened and deepened our discussion with Europe and Asia about each other.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen unprecedented Indo-Pacific cooperation in the challenges that Europe has faced since the invasion &#8212; the Russian invasion of Ukraine, more generally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think it&#8217;s a multifaceted approach.&nbsp; The President and our team will have more to say on details on the Indo-Pacific Economic Forum, some of the details of what we hope to accomplish in the Quad, a number of other initiatives that are in the works.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the sum total of the next couple of weeks is intended to send a concerted message that we are following through on the strategy of investing at home, working with top partners and allies, and laying out clearly what our goals and objectives in the Indo-Pacific are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll stop there.&nbsp; I’m happy to take a couple of questions.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s sort of the background about where we are.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; That was a really helpful laydown of what&#8217;s to come in the coming days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Operator, could you please give us the directions on how to ask the questions?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thanks a lot for doing this.&nbsp; I just wanted to &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, John.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; (inaudible) &#8212; yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Is it true the President is not going to be doing any bilateral meetings with the ASEAN leaders in town?&nbsp; You probably saw the remark from the Cambodian minister who said that the U.S. hosts “should be more generous to guests.”&nbsp; I’m just curious if you think that’s a fair criticism.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I had not seen those comments.&nbsp; I can just assure you that the United States is bending over backwards to be the best possible host.&nbsp; The President will have a quick, private time with each of the leaders.&nbsp; We put enormous effort into the program as a whole.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would also just underscore that this is really a meeting with ASEAN as an institution, and we are in many ways following the recommendation of individual countries in the region that said that the United States has to take the necessary steps to bolster our engagement with the institution, and we&#8217;re seeking to do that.</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re trying to balance opportunities for private interaction with individual countries but a larger engagement with ASEAN as a whole.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;ve done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I would simply say that we have tried very hard to send a very constructive message of how deeply we want to work with partners in the region, and we&#8217;re grateful that so many countries have decided to join us in this endeavor.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; The first one &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, Patsy.&nbsp; How are you?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m well, thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I understand that the issue of Russia and Ukraine will be brought up.&nbsp; I’m wondering if you can give us some details about how hard would the President be pushing on Russia.&nbsp; For example, will you discuss the issue of secondary sanctions?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, if you could elaborate on your statement this morning that the U.S. wants ASEAN leaders to play a more deeply engaged role in Myanmar; I think that was the term that you that used.&nbsp; Will you be urging something more towards the enforcement of the five-point consensus or something beyond that?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, just on the first question: First of all, I expect that there will be a broad discussion of Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; I think ASEAN leaders are very interested to hear the American approach, both where things stand in terms of next steps.&nbsp; And I don’t want to get ahead of what is to come in terms of anything beyond that, but I expect that there will be a fulsome discussion on Ukraine, on Myanmar &#8212; on Burma.</p>



<p>I think, obviously, we’ve had substantial consultations with countries in the region and interested parties who are deeply focused and, frankly, frustrated by what we’ve seen take place inside the country.</p>



<p>I think we saw some of the initial steps that the ASEAN had taken.&nbsp; I think some of those steps have stalled, and we&#8217;re looking for an indication that ASEAN and, perhaps, the help from other countries supportive of ASEAN will take the lead in basically determining what are the appropriate next steps for the institution with respect to its demands and expectations inside the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thanks &#8212; thanks for doing the call.&nbsp; I know that you said that you’ll release more details on the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework coming up soon, but what degree &#8212; to what degree do you expect to discuss that framework with the ASEAN leaders here?&nbsp; And maybe you could detail for us which ASEAN country you are aiming to get to join the framework, if at all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, look &#8212; and I very much appreciate the question.&nbsp; And I will say we are engaged in very substantial conversations with ASEAN countries and engaged in, you know, close deliberations on the way forward.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I indicated, we will have more to say on this.&nbsp; But this is a subject of deep conversation not only between the leaders but expert groups that are meeting around the edges of every meeting currently.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Radio Free Asia would like to know specifically, like, who is from &#8212; who is representing Myanmar, and is the National Unity Government involved in this summit in any way.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, again, we&#8217;ll have more to say on this tomorrow.&nbsp; We have had diplomatic engagement with the government in exile.&nbsp; We are in discussions about the best way to represent what has transpired in Burma and how to represent that in the meeting.</p>



<p>I think one of the discussions has been to have an empty chair to reflect our dissatisfaction with what&#8217;s taken place and our hope for a better path forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we&#8217;ll have more to say about that.&nbsp; And, clearly, Burma will be a subject of intense deliberation in all of our meetings.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the contents of the call are embargoed until the end of the call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you did not get your question in or have more questions, please feel free to reach out to me and we&#8217;ll get back to you for sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much, [senior administration official]. I really appreciate it.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>3:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
