<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 18:45:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Amends Florida Emergency Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-amends-florida-emergency-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 18:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional assistance available to the State of Florida by authorizing an increase in the level of federal funding for debris removal and emergency protective measures undertaken in the State of Florida as a result of the Surfside Building Collapse beginning on June 24, 2021, and continuing. Under the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional assistance available to the State of Florida by authorizing an increase in the level of federal funding for debris removal and emergency protective measures undertaken in the State of Florida as a result of the Surfside Building Collapse beginning on June 24, 2021, and continuing.</p>



<p>Under the emergency declaration issued for the State of Florida on June 25, 2021, the federal share was made available for the Individuals and Households Program under Section 408 of the Stafford Act and assistance for debris removal and emergency protective measures, including direct federal assistance, at 75 percent of the total eligible costs.&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under the President&#8217;s order today, the federal share for debris removal and emergency protective measures, including direct federal assistance, under the Public Assistance program has been increased to 100 percent of the total eligible costs for a continuous period of 30 days beginning June 24, 2021.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT:  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the June Jobs Report</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/02/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-june-jobs-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 17:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 10:50 A.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning, everyone.&#160; It is a good morning.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; It’s a good morning.&#160; As we get prepared to celebrate Independence Day, today’s job news brought us something else to celebrate.&#160; This morning we learned that, in June, our economy created 850,000 jobs.&#160; Eight hundred and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>10:50 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; It is a good morning.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; It’s a good morning.&nbsp; As we get prepared to celebrate Independence Day, today’s job news brought us something else to celebrate.&nbsp; This morning we learned that, in June, our economy created 850,000 jobs.&nbsp; Eight hundred and fifty thousand jobs.&nbsp; Wages went up for American workers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Since I took office, our recovery [economy] has created an average of 600,000 dollar &#8212; six- &#8212; “dollars.” &nbsp;(Laughs.) &nbsp;I wish they &#8212; they probably wish there was 600,000 jobs that paid $600,000 a year. &nbsp;But 600,000 jobs per month. &nbsp;We have now created over 3 million jobs since I took office &#8212; more jobs than have ever been created in the first five months of any presidency in modern history, thanks to the incredible work of the entire team.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is historic progress pulling our economy out of the worst crisis in 100 years, driven in part by our dramatic progress in vaccinating our nation and beating back the pandemic, as well as other elements of the American Rescue Plan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, the U.S. is the only major advanced economy where the OECD projections of future output are higher today than they were in January 2020, before the pandemic hit.&nbsp; And America was ranked first in Bloomberg’s “COVID Resilience Ranking.”&nbsp; None of this happened by accident.&nbsp; Again, it’s a direct result of the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; And at the time, people questioned whether or not we should do that, even though we didn’t have bipartisan support.&nbsp; Well, it worked.<br>&nbsp;<br>In February, the Congressional Budget Office projected 2021 economic growth would be 3.7 percent.&nbsp; Yesterday, they doubled that number to 7.4 percent, in large part thanks to the American Rescue Plan and our work to defeat the virus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The last time the economy grew at this rate was in 1984, and Ronald Reagan was telling us it’s “morning in America.”&nbsp; Well, it’s getting close to afternoon here.&nbsp; The sun is coming out.&nbsp; At the time, the CBO revised their long-run deficit projections down as a share of GDP they &#8212; just as they have done.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the American Rescue Plan is strengthening our financial position, and it grows our economy.&nbsp; It’s continuing to grow our economy.&nbsp; And the strength of our recovery is helping us flip the script.<br>&nbsp;<br>Instead of workers competing with each other for jobs that are scarce, employers are competing with each other to attract workers.&nbsp; That kind of competition in the market doesn’t just give workers more ability to earn higher wages; it also gives them the power to demand to be treated with dignity and respect in the workplace.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>More jobs, better wages &#8212; that’s a good combination.&nbsp; Put simply: Our economy is on the move, and we have COVID-19 on the run.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Yes, we have more work to do to get America vaccinated and everyone back to work.&nbsp; We are aiming for full employment, and that means keeping our pace on job growth, including for Black, Hispanic, and Asian workers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But this progress is testament to our commitment to grow this economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan provided resources to get shots in people’s arms and checks in people’s pockets.&nbsp; Schools &#8212; schools were struggling to reopen so we made vaccinating teachers a priority, getting schools much-needed support.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In March, we&#8217;ve added &#8212; just in the month of [since] March, we added 364,000 education jobs and roles. &nbsp;Small businesses and restaurants were getting crushed. &nbsp;Now we’re delivering the loans and support they need to reopen and to stay open.<br>&nbsp;<br>This morning, we’ve learned that jobs in some hard-hit sectors &#8212; such as restaurants, hotels, amusement parks &#8212; were up by 343,000 last month; over 1.5 million over the past five months.&nbsp; And more help is on the way to give families just a little bit more breathing room.<br>&nbsp;<br>Starting this month, families are going to receiving one of the largest-ever, single-year tax cuts that middle-class families have ever received, and it’s called the Child Care Tax Credit.<br>&nbsp;<br>And here’s how it works: In the past, if you paid taxes and had a good income, you could deduct $2,000 per child, and that would come off the total amount of taxes you owe.&nbsp; If you had two children, you owed $10,000; you take off $4,000.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In the American Rescue Plan, we expanded that.&nbsp; Now a parent would get $3,600 for each child under the age of six, and $3,000 for dependents they had between the ages of 6 and 17.&nbsp; So instead of just being a credit against your taxes you owe, it’s now a fully refundable credit, half of which will get paid out in monthly basis.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, what that means is: This year, middle-class families with two young children can expect to get &#8212; receive $7,200 in a rebate, in effect &#8212; a tax return &#8212; with the monthly payments of $600 a month starting this month, until it’s paid out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Eight out of every ten families who use direct deposit will get their refunds.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll be able to get a monthly payment on the 15th of every month from now until the end of the year, so they get that paid out.&nbsp; Help with families most need it &#8212; most need help to make ends meet.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I’ve said it for a long time: It’s time to give ordinary folks, ordinary Americans, middle-class and working-class Americans a tax break.&nbsp; This is the type of tax cut that can help our economy because it will go to families who are going to spend it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It will also help lead a historic reduction in child poverty &#8212; excuse me &#8212; (the President takes a drink of water) &#8212; historic reduction in child poverty, which would have long-term benefits for our economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re delivering $39 billion to help childcare providers serve more families, to help parents, particularly women, get back to work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Last month, our economy added nearly 25,000 childcare jobs.&nbsp; Again, none of this happened by accident.&nbsp; We’re providing &#8212; proving to the naysayers and the doubters that they were wrong.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>None of this is guaranteed to continue, though, unless we finish our work.&nbsp; Now is the time to accelerate the progress we’ve been making.&nbsp; Now is the time to build in a long-term foundation that we’ve laid, and build it in for a long term.&nbsp; Economists of all stripes agree that my plan will create good jobs and drastically strengthen our economy in the long run.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we have to continue to make the investments that will allow our economy to build back better and deal everyone in.&nbsp; We took a significant step in that direction last week when the bipartisan group of senators forged an agreement with me to move forward on key portions of my American Jobs Plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It was &#8212; I just in Wisconsin, where I highlighted how this agreement is going to pave the way for a generational investment to modernize our infrastructure; create millions of jobs, according to the experts; and what that will mean an ever- &#8212; and it won&#8217;t just be in the center cities.&nbsp; It will be every corner of the state and our nation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to create jobs repairing roads and bridges, replacing 100 percent of our nation’s lead water pipes, making our power grid more reliable, delivering high-speed Internet to every American home, rural and urban.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re going to put people to work building a nationwide electric vehicle charging network, transitioning from diesel school buses and transit buses to electric buses, and bringing in world-class rail service to more Americans by reducing &#8212; and, in the process, reduce our carbon footprint.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, when I was up in Wisconsin, I said &#8212; I pointed out &#8212; the governor was there.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;Gov, I know it takes…&#8221; &#8212; or I don&#8217;t know how many people &#8212; a couple hundred people, I guess, in the audience.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;It takes, they tell me, four and half hours to drive from here to Chicago.&nbsp; With the money we have in &#8212; for mass transit here, we &#8212; you&#8217;re going to be able to do that in two and half hours.&#8221;&nbsp; And all the data shows that when it&#8217;s easier to get someplace by rail than by automobile, it&#8217;s cheaper and it generates a whole lot less carbon footprint.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re going to create good-paying union jobs capping hundreds of thousands of abandoned oil and gas wells to stop methane leaks, which are devastating, and to protect the health of our communities.&nbsp; These are good jobs.<br>&nbsp;<br>Taken together, these investments are going to position America to compete with the world and win the 21st century.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, as we bring home key parts of my American Jobs Plan, I’m going to make the case for equally critical investments that we still need, including those in which I introduced at the same time: my American Families Plan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>When I was running for President, I put together a bold, aggressive plan to deliver childcare, paid leave, universal pre-K for three- and four-year-olds, free community college.&nbsp; Maybe the most important among them was extending the expanded Child Care Tax Credit I just mentioned for another five years, which will significantly benefit middle-class and working-class families.<br>&nbsp;<br>That human infrastructure is as essential as our physical infrastructure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to help us create more good jobs, ease the burden on working families, and strengthen our economy &#8212; strengthen it in the long run.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These investments are critical.&nbsp; And as the plans I put forward tackle our climate crisis, which are broad and deep, I&#8217;m going to fight to see them enacted and signed into law.&nbsp; We have a chance to seize this economic momentum of the first months of my administration, not just to build back, but as I&#8217;ve been saying, &#8220;build back better.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is much already &#8212; this much is already clear: We’re on the right track and we&#8217;re on the right track.&nbsp; Our plan is working.&nbsp; And we’re not going to let up now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I want to thank everyone.&nbsp; I wish you all a happy Fourth of July.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be able to go to ballgames.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to be able to sit in the stadiums.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to be able to be with your families in backyard barbeques, as we hoped.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to make more progress.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, God bless America.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could you talk to us about Afghanistan?&nbsp; Is the drawdown going to be done in the next few days?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, we’re on &#8212; we’re on track exactly as to where we expected to be.&nbsp; But we just &#8212; I wanted to make sure there was enough, quote, “running room” that we could get &#8212; wouldn&#8217;t be able to do it all until September.&nbsp; There will still be some forces left.&nbsp; But it’s a rational drawdown with our allies, and it’s making &#8212; so there&#8217;s nothing unusual about it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you worried that the Afghan government might fall?&nbsp; I mean, we are hearing about how the Taliban is taking more and more districts.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, we were in that war for 20 years.&nbsp; Twenty years.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; I met with the Afghan government here in the White House, in the Oval.&nbsp; I think they have the capacity to be able to sustain the government.&nbsp; There are going to have to be, down the road, more negotiations, I suspect.&nbsp; But I am &#8212; I am concerned that they deal with the internal issues that they have to be able to generate the kind of support they need nationwide to maintain the government.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow on that thought on Afghanistan &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I want to talk about happy things, man.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If there is evidence that Kabul is threatened, which some of the intelligence reports have suggested it could be in six months or thereabout, do you think you&#8217;ve got the capability to help provide any kind of air support, military support to them to keep the capital safe, even if the U.S. troops are obviously fully out by that time?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have worked out an over-the-horizon capacity that we can be value added, but the Afghans are going to have to be able to do it themselves with the Air Force they have, which we’re helping them maintain.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, on Afghanistan &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m not going to answer any more quick question on Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, it’s Fourth of July.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the economy &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned about Fourth of July gatherings &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m concerned that you guys are asking me questions that I&#8217;ll answer next week.&nbsp; But I’m &#8212; this is a holiday weekend.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to celebrate it.&nbsp; There is great things happening.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The economy is growing faster than any time in 40 years.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got a record number of new jobs.&nbsp; COVID deaths are down 90 percent.&nbsp; Wages are up faster than any time in 15 years.&nbsp; We&#8217;re bringing out &#8212; bringing our troops home.&nbsp; We have &#8212; all across America, people are going to ballgames and doing good things.&nbsp; This is good.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll be &#8212; I’ll answer all your negative questions &#8212; not negative &#8212; your legitimate question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But with the gatherings, are you concerned that there is a potential, this weekend, in places where vaccination levels are not particularly high, that there will be new COVID outbreaks in various regions of the country?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I am concerned that people who have not gotten vaccinated have the capacity to catch the variant and spread the variant to other people who have not been vaccinated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I am not concerned there is going to be a major outbreak &#8212; in other words, that we&#8217;re going to have another epidemic nationwide, but I am concerned lives will be lost.&nbsp; And I was even reading today there&#8217;s some speculation and some judgment that’s coming out that you may be able to even communicate the vaccine &#8212; the &#8212; the new variant to your pets.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I say, not &#8212; not totally facetiously, for those of you who haven&#8217;t been vaccinated because you don&#8217;t &#8212; you don&#8217;t &#8212; you don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s &#8212; you want to go through it: It doesn&#8217;t hurt, it&#8217;s accessible, it&#8217;s free, it&#8217;s available.&nbsp; And not only &#8212; don&#8217;t think about yourself; think about your family.&nbsp; Think about those around you.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we should be thinking about today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Fourth of July this year is different than the Fourth of July last year.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s going to be better next year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you all.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you think that Congress will enact your plans?&nbsp; Are you confident &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that you&#8217;re going to get it done?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Come on.<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Come on, guys.&nbsp; Am I co- &#8212; are you &#8212; have you ever been confident about anything with guarantee?&nbsp; Who wants to put money on anything that Congress is going to do?&nbsp; Look, folks, this is a process.&nbsp; This is a process.<br>&nbsp;<br>I love you guys, but it&#8217;s a process.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t &#8212; you want me to say, “Yes, I’m absolutely certain.”&nbsp; Well, are you absolutely certain this new commission is going to work, investigating what happened on the 6th?&nbsp; Are you guys confident that Republicans are going to participate?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, all I know &#8212; only thing I know what to do &#8212; and I really mean this &#8212; is do my best to lay out what I think the country has to do, try to be as persuasive as I can, and hope.&nbsp; And thus far, you know, it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, it seems to be working a little bit.&nbsp; So, thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>11:06 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/02/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-independent-review-commission-on-sexual-assault/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:19:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[5:02 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you so much for joining us.&#160; Today&#8217;s call is going to be on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&#160; And the contents of this call are embargoed until 11:00 tomorrow morning, Friday, June [July] 2nd. With that, I&#8217;m happy to turn it over to our speakers,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>5:02 P.M. EDT<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone, and thank you so much for joining us.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s call is going to be on background, attributed to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And the contents of this call are embargoed until 11:00 tomorrow morning, Friday, <s>June</s> [July] 2nd.<br><br>With that, I&#8217;m happy to turn it over to our speakers, [senior administration official], who is the [redacted], and [senior administration official], who is the [redacted].<br><br>[Senior administration official], over to you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].<br><br>Good afternoon, and thank you all for joining us to discuss the President&#8217;s announcement regarding the findings and recommendations of the Independent Review Commission on Sexual Assault in the Military.<br><br>As most of you probably know, President Biden has a longstanding and deep-seated commitment to fighting to eliminate all forms of gender-based violence.&nbsp; This has really been a central part of his life&#8217;s work, including as an original author of the Violence Against Women Act in 1994 as a senator.&nbsp;<br><br>So at the very early days of his presidency, following up on a promise he made during the campaign, he asked Secretary of Defense Austin to create this Independent Review Commission to undertake an in-depth analysis over a period of 90 days, and to provide its findings and recommendations to address sexual assault and harassment in the military.<br><br>On March 24th, the Independent Review Commission, chaired by Lynn Rosenthal and comprised of 12 independent highly qualified experts, began their work.&nbsp; They were charged with making recommendations &#8212; and [senior administration official] will talk about this more &#8212; in four key areas related to accountability, prevention, climate and culture, and survivor care and support.<br><br>The Commission has met with the Secretary on several occasions to present their findings and recommendations to him.&nbsp; Defense Secretary Austin informs the President that he is endorsing the findings of the Commission and supports the recommendation to remove cases of sexual assault, sexual harassment, and related crimes from the military chain of command, as well as recommendations in the other key areas of prevention, climate and culture, and victim care and support.&nbsp; The President spoke with Secretary Austin about these issues and fully supports his approach.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden appreciates the leadership Secretary Austin has shown in taking these bold steps necessary to remedy this persistent problem.&nbsp; The President has sought to stamp out the scourge of sexual assault in the military and believes that in advancing the IRC’s recommendations, the Department of Defense will be introducing comprehensive changes to implement his administration&#8217;s unwavering commitment to improving both the response to and prevention of sexual assault and sexual harassment in the military.<br><br>And the President would particularly like to thank the IRC chair, Lynn Rosenthal, who he has known for a very long time, and the entire Independent Review Commission for their exemplary work and dedication.&nbsp;<br><br>Most of all, the President is grateful to the hundreds of individuals across the Services, the many external stakeholders whom the IRC consulted with, and to the survivors who shared their stories and made recommendations to the IRC.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s also grateful to countless other survivors of sexual assault and sexual harassment in the military, who for decades have shared their stories and their pain, as well as their courage and their resilience to continue to speak out and advocate for these much-needed reforms and to improve the pathways to healing and justice for survivors.<br><br>Finally, the President wants to acknowledge and thank Senator Gillibrand for many years of tireless efforts to shine a light on these deep-seated problems and for her efforts to build a bipartisan consensus to work for change, and is also grateful for the leadership of Senator Joni Ernst, and others, who have amplified the voices of survivors to advocate for necessary reforms to address assault and harassment in the military.<br><br>I&#8217;m going to turn it over to [senior administration official] now to provide more information about how the IRC approach their work, as well as the findings and recommendations of the Commission.<br><br>Over to you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And I want to begin by just really appreciating the leadership of President Biden and Secretary Austin in addressing this longstanding problem.&nbsp; And I want to acknowledge the support and cooperation of the Department of Defense and the Services as a part of this process.<br><br>The Independent Review Commission established that independence by creating a body of highly qualified experts, external to the Department, as the deliberative body on our recommendations.&nbsp; We were supported in that effort, however, by senior leaders from the services and subject-matter experts across the force.&nbsp;<br><br>As a part of our process, we met with over 600 external experts, including survivors, researchers, former service members, commanders, junior and senior enlisted members, and advocates.&nbsp; And while we have some tough findings in our report, we don&#8217;t at all believe that these represent a lack of concern for this problem.&nbsp; Everyone we talked to &#8212; senior officials within DOD, senior leaders in the services, and enlisted junior and senior members &#8212; want to see change.&nbsp; Everyone we talked to wants to see that change.&nbsp; There are people working very hard to make that happen, but they often are not equipped to do so.&nbsp;<br><br>We identified that there is a troubling gap between what senior leaders say about this problem and how junior enlisted members experience the problem.&nbsp; We have heard for many years that there is no tolerance for sexual harassment and sexual assault, but we learned that, in practice, there is quite a lot of tolerance.&nbsp;<br><br>We found that the military justice system is not well equipped to handle sensitive cases like sexual assault, sexual harassment, and domestic violence.&nbsp; We note that there is a strong continuum between sexual harassment and sexual assault, and the relationship of both these problems to poor unit climates.&nbsp; We note also that the cyber domain has to be prioritized as a part of unit climates.&nbsp;<br><br>We found that there are critical deficiencies in the workforce across the services, including lack of experience and lack of specialization, which are key elements to addressing sexual assault and sexual harassment.&nbsp;<br><br>Nowhere is this problem more apparent than in the near-total lack of a prevention workforce.&nbsp; So we often hear that prevention is the key to solving this problem.&nbsp; But we learned that there aren&#8217;t actually prevention specialists working across the services to make that happen.&nbsp; There is a lack of an evidence-informed public health approach to prevention.&nbsp;<br><br>And finally, we found that victims carry a very heavy burden.&nbsp; And they carry this burden whether they report or not.&nbsp; Many whom &#8212; who did report regretted doing so because of what they experienced afterwards.&nbsp; That includes being ostracized, bullied, and having trouble accessing quality services.<br><br>I must say, and the IRC strongly believes, that leadership is the key to correcting all of these deficiencies.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made 28 recommendations and 54 sub-recommendations in those lines of effort that [senior administration official] noted, including accountability, prevention, climate and culture, and victim care and support.&nbsp;<br><br>So I just want to highlight a few.&nbsp; As you know, we&#8217;ve recommended shifting prosecution decisions to special victims prosecutors outside of the chain of command.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve also recommended improving the handling of sexual harassment cases and a series of other improvements to the UCMJ.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve recommended equipping leaders to understand prevention and the development of an actual prevention workforce to carry out these programs.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve made a series of recommendations to improve unit climate, including better methods to select, develop, and evaluate leaders; enhancements to the climate survey process; and greater transparency about disciplinary actions.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve made a series of recommendations to improve victim care and support, including shifting sexual assault response coordinators and victim advocates out of the command structure, largely eliminating part-time and collateral-duty victim advocates, and professionalizing the sexual assault response workforce across the board.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve also recommended lifting the barrier to victims of sexual harassment receiving services from sexual assault prevention and response programs, which is a problem in the services, except for the Army which handles both of these problems together.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ve recommended identifying a structure within the Department of Defense to provide greater assistance to the Services in addressing sexual harassment.&nbsp;<br><br>Our report includes four separate reports from each line of effort.&nbsp; So, depending on what you&#8217;re most interested in, when the report is released tomorrow, you&#8217;ll be able to dive into all of these recommendations in great detail in accountability, prevention, climate and culture, and victim services.&nbsp; So everything you want to know about what I just highlighted is within those four reports.&nbsp;<br><br>Finally, I want to note that we found and we believe that commanders are essential to implementing every one of these recommendations.&nbsp; Most importantly, commanders are the key to improving unit climate, to changing the culture, and to protecting victims from negative consequences related to reporting sexual assault.&nbsp; Indeed, commanders are the key to making it safe for victims to come forward at all.&nbsp;<br><br>And I want to say very clearly that we reject the notion that shifting legal decisions about prosecution from command to prosecutors diminishes the role of those commanders.&nbsp; We believe, instead, that it enhances their role and places them in the lead of taking care of their people &#8212; the number one job of commanders &#8212; and creating climates of no tolerance for sexual assault, sexual harassment, and related crimes.&nbsp;<br><br>And with that, I will turn it back over to [senior administration official].&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So I&#8217;ll just say a few more words on the process going forward, which is that the President &#8212; the Secretary, excuse me, has made it clear that he generally accepts all of these recommendations from the IRC and that now he&#8217;s going to move into the implementation process.&nbsp;<br><br>So as you have just heard and as you all know, this is a profound change for the Department of Defense and, really, a monumental pivot in how the department does its business.&nbsp;<br><br>So the Secretary has asked for the grace to, I think in his own words, “measure twice and cut once” as he thinks through implementation.&nbsp; And the President really fully supports that approach.&nbsp;<br><br>So, over the next few months, the White House and the Pentagon will be in consultation to best understand how to make these recommendations to reality, and work with Congress to amend the Uniform Code of Military Justice, as is required to make whatever legislative changes are part of these recommendations.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you all so much.&nbsp; With that, we&#8217;re happy to open the line to some press questions.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, in the recommendations that you made in terms of leadership selection and how you can do that better to make sure that a command climate doesn&#8217;t support or doesn&#8217;t tolerate sexual harassment and sexual assault, what are some of the specific recommendations that you made for that sort of selection process?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Most importantly, we recommend using narrative and qualitative data to select and evaluate commanders so that there&#8217;s a more &#8212; a fuller picture of how they&#8217;re actually addressing these climate issues.&nbsp;<br><br>And then we&#8217;ve recommended a series of improvements to the climate survey process so that they can get more on-the-ground information about the climate specifically related to sexual harassment and specific to the ability to report sexual assault.&nbsp; So those are some improvements we&#8217;ve recommended to the climate survey process.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So, I have a question for both of you.&nbsp; Does the Biden administration support the Gillibrand legislation that takes all felony crimes out of the chain of command?&nbsp; And if you don&#8217;t, then don&#8217;t you end up with two legal systems &#8212; one that deals with just sex crimes and then another that deals with felony and murder and other serious crimes?&nbsp;<br><br>And then my other question for you is: You talked about taking victim advocates out of the chain of command.&nbsp; Who would they report to?&nbsp; How would that work?&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I can jump in on the first one.&nbsp; This is [senior administration official].&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think it&#8217;s really clear that Senator Gillibrand deserved an enormous amount of credit for her tireless efforts over many, many years to address the problem of sexual assault in the military.&nbsp; And the President really shares her strong passion to take on this issue. &nbsp;That&#8217;s why he asked Secretary Austin to stand up this IRC on sexual assault and sexual harassment immediately upon taking office.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think, you know, the President &#8212; this review commission has been squarely focused and was asked just to focus only on addressing the problem of sexual assault and harassment in the military.&nbsp; And he is really pleased to see that there is a growing consensus that these crimes should be taken out of the chain of command.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to now look to Congress to work out the details for legislating that change.&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And this is [senior administration official].&nbsp; I think that there are a few different models for who the victim advocates and the sexual assault response coordinators could report to.&nbsp; So &#8212; it’s better &#8212; rather than identifying one specific component, we should talk about some of those guiding principles.&nbsp;<br><br>And we do believe in flexibility for the services because they all operate a little bit differently, but we think this requirement should be uniform, and then, within that, the services can develop implementation plans.&nbsp;<br><br>But the key is that sexual assault response coordinators and victim advocates need to be free of any sort of command influence over what kind of services a victim receives.&nbsp;<br><br>So, certainly, the commander is responsible for making sure that victims are protected from retaliation, bullying &#8212; all of that that can happen after a report &#8212; but actually what kind of services they might want to need to be developed by a professional victim advocate who can put a package together.&nbsp;<br><br>And we actually recommend a commander&#8217;s package, which will include what the victim has identified as his or her needs, the kind of support they might need throughout the process, what remedies should be available for them.&nbsp; And these could be as simple as having some time off to go to medical or legal appointments.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s really very much in the details of what victims identify that they need.&nbsp;<br><br>So you can see, as I laid that out, that those sexual assault response coordinators and victim advocates should be within a unit where they can receive some professional supervision.&nbsp; So that could be within a chain where social services are happening on an installation or a chain in which they can receive that sort of support from colleagues.&nbsp;<br><br>They also have to be able to provide these independent recommendations, but, at the same time, they have to have key relationships with commanders.&nbsp; So in no way does this sort of separate those conversations.&nbsp; What we envision is that the victim advocates are able to work closely with commanders and serve as key advisors.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I have two questions, one being if we could get a timeline or an estimated timeline for about how long you think it will take for some of these recommendations to start being implemented and maybe, you know, until all of them are implemented.<br><br>But then, also, [senior administration official], you mentioned in your remarks that you found that there was a gap between what senior leaders say is happening and what the junior enlisted service members are experiencing.&nbsp; How are these recommendations going to ensure that that gap is closed and that that won&#8217;t continue happening for years to come &#8212; where senior leaders are pointing to these recommendations as they&#8217;re being rolled out, but the junior service members are continuing to not see that play out at their level?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s really the heart of the matter.&nbsp; On the timeline, I think DOD is going to have to identify that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve recommended some key priorities for immediate action.&nbsp; We believe that because we found such critical deficiencies in victim care and support &#8212; and I might add that, to me, those were surprising findings, as somebody who&#8217;s worked on this for some time.&nbsp; But because we found those critical deficiencies, we would like to see &#8212; we recommend that manpower study be conducted on the victim advocacy workforce within three months, with additional implementation within six months.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we think those are priority for near-term actions.&nbsp; The legislative changes to the UCMJ will take &#8212; should take some time.&nbsp; So we recommend, in our report, enactment dates of 2023.&nbsp; We think that it&#8217;s important to take due care to structure this system in a way that has the best chance of success.<br><br>So, we recommend that there &#8212; this is not an area for quick wins or quick fixes, but rather a plan that will result in sustained change over time.&nbsp; And we think that investment of time is what will lead to the results.&nbsp; We think that’s what will really move the needle.<br><br>And your second question &#8212; the gap between what senior leaders say about the problem and what junior leaders actually experience?&nbsp; I mean, the key finding from junior leaders &#8212; well, from junior enlisted members &#8212; I’m sorry &#8212; is that they experience daily acts of demeaning language and sexual harassment.&nbsp; That is ubiquitous.&nbsp; In many units, that is a part of the climate, and that women in particular are told this is just what they should expect.&nbsp; We spoke with many, many survivors and also junior enlisted members who witnessed their friends experiencing sexual harassment and assault, who said that, on one hand, the leaders say there’s no tolerance, but on the other hand, they’re experiencing that daily.<br><br>So, by focusing on selecting, developing, and evaluating the right leaders, we should end up with commanders and leaders at all levels who actually practice no tolerance, which means interrupting these behaviors, which means setting that standard.&nbsp; And those things, quite frankly, while some of our package requires investment in the workforce and resources, that does not.&nbsp; That can start on day one &#8212; and that is: Interrupt these behaviors, speak out, and show and practice a real no tolerance.&nbsp; That’s how you create a positive climate.<br><br>When you take as good care of your people as you do your vehicles, that’s when we’ll start to see real change.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to clarify &#8212; thanks for the call &#8212; just to clarify: So you&#8217;re not suggesting (inaudible) until 2023 to take this out of the chain of command?&nbsp; And then also, if you could just give &#8212; just to confirm that.&nbsp;<br><br>And then also, if you just give us a sense of whether or not you think, once these recommendations are implemented, whether the kind of situation we all saw play out at Fort Hood could still repeat itself.&nbsp; Is it &#8212; or is it clear to you that once these changes are implemented, that kind of thing won&#8217;t happen again?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So we recommend that the legislation be enacted this year, but that the provisions are enacted in 2023 &#8212; that that kind of time is taken to appropriately build a structure which involves special victims prosecutors reporting outside of the chain of command &#8212; of the military chain of command &#8212; and addressing sexual assault, sexual harassment, domestic violence, and related crimes.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s our special victims bucket &#8212; the issues that we think should be addressed.&nbsp; And we believe it takes some time to establish that system.&nbsp; It involves a number of steps forward to do so.&nbsp;<br><br>And many of our recommendations parallel the Fort Hood report, particularly removing the victim advocates from the chain of command.&nbsp; So I think that we&#8217;ve identified some of those same problems.&nbsp; I think that when you have lea- &#8212; it&#8217;s all about leadership.&nbsp; It&#8217;s all about commanders stepping forward and leading and having the skills to do so.<br><br>I think, today, we heard from commanders that they don&#8217;t always know what to do to address their &#8212; these poor climates &#8212; that they&#8217;re seeking out.&nbsp; And we recommend some steps the Department can take to provide that kind of help to commanders who step forward and say, &#8220;I want to improve my climate.&#8221;<br><br>So I think careful implementation of this plan will result in leaders who are better equipped to address sexual harassment and sexual assault, and particularly the continuum between the two.&nbsp; So if commanders are aggressive, proactive in addressing sexual harassment &#8212; that means stopping the demeaning language, that means addressing those who are committing the harassment, that means working appropriately through the steps that will lead to accountability.&nbsp; When those things happen, we hope that we can prevent situations like what tragically happened at Fort Hood.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, everyone.&nbsp; That concludes our call.&nbsp; A friendly reminder that we are on background, attributed to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and that the contents of this call are embargoed until 11:00 tomorrow morning.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks all for joining.<br><br>5:27 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe Biden on the Results of the Independent Review Commission on Military Sexual Assault</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-results-of-the-independent-review-commission-on-military-sexual-assault/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 15:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23107</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I strongly support Secretary Austin’s announcement that he is accepting the core recommendations put forward by the Independent Review Commission on Military Sexual Assault (IRC), including removing the investigation and prosecution of sexual assault from the chain of command and creating highly specialized units to handle these cases and related crimes. Ending violence against women&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I strongly support Secretary Austin’s announcement that he is accepting the core recommendations put forward by the Independent Review Commission on Military Sexual Assault (IRC), including removing the investigation and prosecution of sexual assault from the chain of command and creating highly specialized units to handle these cases and related crimes. Ending violence against women and eliminating sexual assault against any person in our country has been a priority for me throughout my career in public service. Sexual assault is an abuse of power and an affront to our shared humanity. And sexual assault in the military is doubly damaging because it also shreds the unity and cohesion that is essential to the functioning of the U.S. military and to our national defense.<br><br>Yet, for as long as we have abhorred this scourge, the statistics and the stories have grown worse. We need concrete actions that fundamentally change the way we handle military sexual assault and that make it clear that these crimes will not be minimized or dismissed. They will be prosecuted under the Uniform Code of Military Justice (UCMJ) to their fullest extent. We will also prioritize effective prevention strategies; promote safe, healthy, and respectful climates; and improve services to address the trauma that sexual assault victims experience and to facilitate their healing and recovery.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank Lynn Rosenthal for her leadership of the IRC and her decades of dedicated work to end sexual assault and gender-based violence. To everyone who served on the IRC, thank you for your tireless work to deliver thoughtful, effective, actionable recommendations for how we can drive sexual assault and harassment from the ranks of the United States military.<br><br>I also want to recognize the determined leadership within Congress over the years—in particular of Senator Gillibrand, Senator Ernst, Representative Speier, and Representative Mullin, who have worked in a strong bipartisan way to support needed change and to keep this issue at the forefront of our agenda. I look forward to working with Congress to implement these necessary reforms and promote a work environment that is free from sexual assault and harassment for every one of our brave service members.<br><br>Finally, I want to recognize the experience of our service members who have survived sexual assault and the bravery of those who have shared their stories with the world and advocated for reform. This kind of violation and trauma should never occur. You have a right to be heard. You have a right to justice. And for all those in the ranks who have suffered an assault and its after effects in silence, whether because you felt that you would not receive the support you deserve, or because you feared the repercussions for yourself and your career—I hope this announcement offers some reassurance that the Department of Defense leadership stands with you, starting with your Commander in Chief.<br><br>I also want to honor the pain of those families whose loved one did not survive an assault or the struggle with PTSD that so often follows in the wake of sexual assault. The hurt of that loss is unimaginable.<br><br>Today’s announcement is the beginning, not the end of our work. This will be among the most significant reforms to our military undertaken in recent history, and I’m committed to delivering results. Keeping our country safe has to start with prioritizing the safety of those who proudly sign up to serve our country. And today’s announcement represents an important and overdue step in the right direction.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Meeting with Congressional Hispanic Caucus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/02/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-congressional-hispanic-caucus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 04:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23013</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today,&#160;National Economic Council Director&#160;Brian Deese&#160;met with the Congressional Hispanic Caucus (CHC) to discuss the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and the President’s legislative priorities. During a productive meeting, Deese and members of the CHC spoke about how elements of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, including investing in clean drinking water, public transit, and high speed internet, would directly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today,&nbsp;National Economic Council Director&nbsp;Brian Deese&nbsp;met with the Congressional Hispanic Caucus (CHC) to discuss the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and the President’s legislative priorities. During a productive meeting, Deese and members of the CHC spoke about how elements of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework, including investing in clean drinking water, public transit, and high speed internet, would directly benefit the Latino community. Deese underscored the President’s two-track strategy and commitment to the rest of his agenda being pursued in the budget resolution and a reconciliation bill, and thanked the members for being partners in the fight to advance racial equity in underserved communities.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the Surfside Condo Collapse</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/01/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-surfside-condo-collapse/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 03:54:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=23001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[St. Regis HotelSurfside, Florida 4:29 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, folks.&#160; Let me begin by saying that the degree of cooperation between local, state, and federal officials down here has been remarkable.&#160;&#160;I want to thank our FEMA Director for leading this national effort.&#160;&#160; But Governor DeSantis, Senators Rubio and Scott, Congresswoman Debbie Wasserman Schultz, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">St. Regis Hotel<br>Surfside, Florida</p>



<p>4:29 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, folks.&nbsp; Let me begin by saying that the degree of cooperation between local, state, and federal officials down here has been remarkable.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I want to thank our FEMA Director for leading this national effort.&nbsp;&nbsp; But Governor DeSantis, Senators Rubio and Scott, Congresswoman Debbie Wasserman Schultz, and Mayor Cava –- Cava &#8212; they’ve been &#8212; they’ve all cooperated in ways that I haven’t seen in a long time.&nbsp; And it’s really a testament to &#8212; to what&#8217;s &#8212; how difficult things are down here.&nbsp; And it’s what, quite frankly, we miss a lot.&nbsp; You know, we all &#8212; we&#8217;ve all been working in tandem from the moment we got the news of the collapse of the building.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think my colleagues will tell you we cut through the bureaucracy.&nbsp; The one &#8212; the one order I gave federal folks was, “No bureaucracy.&nbsp; Just cut through it.&nbsp; Get to whatever they need.”<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s why we’ve decided to cover, for example, 100 percent of the search-and-rescue costs for the first 30 days.&nbsp; Not done often but necessary here, in my view.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And FEMA is going to provide temporary housing and other urgent needs for the survivors.&nbsp; The State Department is expedi- &#8212; expediting visas for family members from other countries &#8212; and there are from Latin America, South America, Europe, Israel.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to give a special shout-out to the first responders &#8212; International Association of Firefighters, one of the best organizations in the country.&nbsp; And I particularly want to thank the president.&nbsp; Ed came down from Boston, and he&#8217;s here with the entire &#8212; with the entire group.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, these folks are &#8212; these folks are always showing up, no matter what.&nbsp; They&#8217;re risking their lives.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s that old expression.&nbsp; I know, the press that travels with me is tired of hearing me saying it, but I&#8217;m not tired of saying it.&nbsp; And that is &#8212; that old expression &#8212; “God made man.&nbsp; Then he made a few firefighters.”&nbsp; They&#8217;re remarkable, remarkable people.&nbsp; There&#8217;s always &#8212; they&#8217;re always risking their lives to save lives, as well as the police and other first responders.&nbsp; I got to meet with a whole bunch of them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are able to deploy nearly 500 personnel, including five other search-and-rescue teams on the ground today here because of &#8212; our FEMA Director ordered it.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to compliment FEMA and, I might add, all those folks who are risking their lives to save lives, but also holding out hope that others will be found.&nbsp; Hope springs eternal.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When I talked to those first responders, I pointed out that they&#8217;re under a great deal of stress and we should take advantage &#8212; they should take advantage of the mental health facilities that are going to be available.&nbsp; Because, you know, we talk about our military suffering from post-traumatic stress.&nbsp; Well, seeing what they&#8217;re seeing and doing what they&#8217;re doing, understanding how &#8212; how much trauma is involved, I just don’t want them thinking that they should walk away from help if it’s needed.&nbsp; You know, they stand together, and it’s really impressive.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there&#8217;s also the need, in addition to state and local assistance, to determine the cause of this collapse &#8212; and the adjacent buildings, how safe they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>There are two outstanding concerns.&nbsp; First, the remaining buildings may collapse &#8212; the remainder of the building may collapse.&nbsp; We need to determine if it&#8217;s safe for first responders to return to the site to continue their rescue mission.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s being done right now.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I asked the National Institute of Standards and Technology &#8212; NIST &#8212; to investigate, to see if it&#8217;s safe to go back and what caused the building to collapse in the first place.&nbsp; Because we&#8217;re committed not only to recover, but to restore the safety across the board.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the other reason I came down was to meet with the families.&nbsp; The whole nation is mourning with these families.&nbsp; They see it every day on television.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going through hell.&nbsp; And those who&#8217;ve survived the collapse, as well as those who are missing loved ones.<br>&nbsp;<br>I realize I&#8217;m a little late because I spent a lot of time with the families &#8212; a whole lot of time.&nbsp; And I apologize for taking so long to get here, because I thought it was important to speak to every single person who wanted to speak to me.&nbsp; So, after what you all covered when I opened up the &#8212; the meeting, I spent the remainder of the time, and I &#8212; and such incredible people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I sat with one woman who had just lost her &#8212; her husband and her little baby boy; didn&#8217;t know what to do.&nbsp; I sat with another family that lost almost the entire family: cousins, brothers, sisters.&nbsp; And to watch them and to &#8212; the &#8212; they&#8217;re praying and pleading that, &#8220;God, let there be a miracle.&nbsp; Let them be something happen for me that&#8217;s good.&#8221;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Because I have, like many of you do, some idea what it&#8217;s like to suffer that kind of loss so many of them are suffering.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, they had basic heart-wrenching questions: &#8220;Will I be able to recover the body of my son or daughter, my husband, my cousin, my mom and dad?&nbsp; How can I have closure without being able to bury them if I don&#8217;t get the body?&nbsp; What do I do?&#8221;<br>&nbsp;<br>Jill and I wanted them to know that we&#8217;re with them and the country is with them.&nbsp; Our message today is that we&#8217;re here for you, as one nation.&nbsp; As one nation.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the message we communicated.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ll be in touch with a lot of these families continuing through this process.&nbsp; But there is much more to be done.&nbsp; We&#8217;re ready to do it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, I thank the governor, I thank my colleagues, my &#8212; Senator Scott and Senator Rubio, I thank Debbie Wasserman Schultz for their total, complete cooperation.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no &#8212; there&#8217;s no disagreement, no bickering.&nbsp; Everybody is on the same team.&nbsp; It&#8217;s what America is all about.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about pulling together, leaving nobody behind.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what made me feel &#8212; the one thing that made me feel good about this is the &#8212; is a cohesion that exists.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no Democrat or Republican out there; they&#8217;re just people wanting to do the right thing for their fellow Americans.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, may God bless the victims and their families.&nbsp; And may God protect our first responders.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I&#8217;ll take a couple questions right now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, what were you told today about the likelihood &#8212; you said, “Hope springs eternal” &#8212; but that somebody will be able to be pulled out alive from this?&nbsp; And what were you able to convey to the families about that possibility?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, first of all, the families are very realistic.&nbsp; They know the longer it goes &#8212; and one of the things that the local FEMA personnel as well as the local first responders did is they took all of the families to the site to see &#8212; to see what it looked like up close.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re all realists.&nbsp; They all look, and they see those floors just literally feet &#8212; cement upon cement upon cement.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, I &#8212; when I talked to some of the families, some of the people who did escape, survived, and got out, they talked about watching the building collapse and watching as they were in the garage &#8212; one floor come down &#8212; literally a whole floor on top of another floor.&nbsp; They know that the chances are, as each day goes by, diminished slightly.<br>&nbsp;<br>But at a minimum &#8212; at a minimum &#8212; they want to recover the bodies.&nbsp; They want to recover the bodies.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of very religious people who are in there.&nbsp; Members of the &#8212; the rabbis in the Jewish community were talking about the need to make sure that they recover the body and be able to bury them.&nbsp; Give them &#8212; and, you know, the &#8212; anyway.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think they&#8217;re very realistic, Mike.&nbsp; But &#8212; but I don&#8217;t think that that, in any way, suggests that it’s too &#8212; that we should stop.&nbsp; I think that we should move on, continue to try to recover the bodies.<br>&nbsp;<br>In the meantime, that&#8217;s why NIST and others are determining whether or not it&#8217;s safe to send the first responders back.&nbsp; When they&#8217;d asked me about this, I&#8217;d point out that the last thing they would want and we would want is, in the process of trying to recover &#8212; and the possibility &#8212; there’s still a possibility someone could be alive, someone could still be breathing, someone could be there &#8212; that the last thing you want to have happen is have that building collapse and kill 10, 20, 30, 50 firefighters or wound them, or first responders.<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; but Mike, they&#8217;re &#8212; you know, they&#8217;re realistic.&nbsp; I &#8212; it just brought back so many &#8212; so many memories.&nbsp; It&#8217;s bad enough &#8212; it&#8217;s bad enough to lose somebody.&nbsp; But the hard part &#8212; the really hard part is to not know whether they&#8217;re surviving or not &#8212; just not have any idea.<br>&nbsp;<br>When the accident took my wife and my family, the hardest part was: Were my boys going to get out?&nbsp; Are they going to make it?&nbsp; And not knowing.&nbsp; Not knowing, when you&#8217;re flying home from Washington to get the news.&nbsp; You know, you just don’t know.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I was amazed &#8212; as you know, unfortunately, I&#8217;ve done a lot of these circumstances where I&#8217;ve met with families who have had great loss.&nbsp; And what amazed me about this group of people was the resilience and their absolute commitment, their willingness to do whatever it took to find &#8212; to find an answer.&nbsp; I walked away impressed by their strength.&nbsp; And &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>And Nancy, Bloomberg &#8212; do you have a question?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I was told.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thank you.&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; What did you learn, if anything, about the collapse of the building?&nbsp; Is there anything more you learned from investigators or the FEMA administrators (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, it’s underway.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; and the director of FEMA is with me here.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have any firm proof of what&#8217;s happened.&nbsp; There’s all kinds of rational speculation about whether or not the rebars are &#8212; were &#8212; were rusted; whether or not the cement &#8212; whether it was limestone or not; whether or not &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>But a lot of the &#8212; a lot the families who survived talked about how upset they were that, in the last years that they&#8217;ve been here, how there was one condominium complex built across the street and a road was purchased.&nbsp; And while they were living there, they would hear the drilling and they’d feel their building moving and shaking.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are all kinds of discussions about whether or not they thought that water level rising &#8212; what impact it had.&nbsp; And interesting to me &#8212; I didn&#8217;t raise it &#8212; but how many of the survivors and how many of the families talked about the impact of global warming.&nbsp; How much &#8212; and they didn’t know exactly, but they talked about sea levels rising and about how &#8212; how there were &#8212; and &#8212; and the combination of that and the concern about incoming storm &#8212; incoming tropical storms.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so &#8212; but I don&#8217;t think there is, at this point, any definitive judgment as to why it collapsed and what can be done to prevent it from happening and what other buildings may have to be inspected to determine if they have the same problems.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m supposed to head out and catch up with the governor.&nbsp; So I want to thank you all for taking the time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, can we ask you about two matters away from where we are now?&nbsp; The first is: While you’ve been speaking, a top associate of the former President has been in a New York court, pleading not guilty to various financial charges.&nbsp; Do you have a reaction to that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And secondarily, if I can, does the Supreme Court&#8217;s ruling today on an important voting rights decision add to the sense of urgency you feel about pursuing voting rights legislation at this time?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know nothing about the first circumstance because I&#8217;ve been gone.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any idea, so I&#8217;m not going to comment on that.&nbsp; And even if I did, I wouldn&#8217;t comment on an ongoing case if it&#8217;s an ongoing case.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>With regard to the second point: I think I did get a summary on the way down on the plane of the Supreme Court decision.&nbsp; It is mildly positive, in the sense that there&#8217;s a remedy available based on the particular voting decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think that it is critical that we make a distinction between voter suppression and suspension.&nbsp; The ability of a state legislative body to come along and vote &#8212; their legislature &#8212; vote to change who is declared the winner, I find to be somewhat astounding.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the Supreme Court rule did not rule that way today, to the best of my knowledge.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I&#8217;ll have much more to say about that because I plan on speaking extensively on voting rights and &#8212; as well as going on the road on this issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So thank you all very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:44 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/01/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-43/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 03:02:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22993</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 1:36 P.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good afternoon, and thank you for joining us.&#160; Today, we’re joined by Doctors Fauci and Walensky, who I’ll turn to in a few minutes. First, I want to report on the progress we are making to end the COVID-19 pandemic here at home and around the world.&#160; Here&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>1:36 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good afternoon, and thank you for joining us.&nbsp; Today, we’re joined by Doctors Fauci and Walensky, who I’ll turn to in a few minutes.<br><br>First, I want to report on the progress we are making to end the COVID-19 pandemic here at home and around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Here at home, going into the 4th of July holiday weekend, Americans have good reason to celebrate.&nbsp; Thanks to the President&#8217;s whole-of-government response and the American people stepping up, more than 180 million Americans, including 67 percent of adults &#8212; two out of three adult Americans &#8212; have now received at least one shot.&nbsp;<br><br>In cases or death &#8212; deaths are down by more than 90 percent since January 20th.&nbsp; As a result, we have exceeded our expectations for where we would be on July 4th.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re in a strong position to build on this progress going forward.&nbsp;<br><br>This weekend, millions of Americans will be able to get together &#8212; back together, not just with their families and close friends for small backyard cookouts, but with their community for larger festivals, parades, and fireworks, celebrating our country&#8217;s July 4th Independence Day and the progress we have made against the virus together.<br><br>We will celebrate this progress on July 4th.&nbsp; But, of course, our work does not stop &#8212; because as the President has said, our work to vaccinate the millions of Americans who still need protection against the virus continues across the summer months.&nbsp; And our resolve to reach those who have not yet gotten their shot is only strengthened because of the spread of the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>As we push to get more Americans vaccinated, we will also continue mobilizing and leading the effort to vaccinate the world.&nbsp; Earlier this year, the President committed that the United States will be an arsenal of vaccines for the world.<br><br>Through historic announcements and actions, we are delivering on the President&#8217;s commitment.&nbsp; Over the past several weeks, the President has committed to sharing 580 million doses of vaccine to the world, including a half billion doses of Pfizer vaccine that the United States will purchase and donate to 100 countries in need.&nbsp;<br><br>This is by far the largest-ever donation of COVID-19 vaccines by a single country.&nbsp; And this historic announcement builds on the prior commitment we made to share 80 million doses of our own surplus U.S. vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>These 80 million doses have all been shared with 46 countries, the African Union, and CARICOM through a combination of bilateral sharing and sharing through COVAX.&nbsp;<br><br>Each country has now received a specific number and type of U.S. vaccines they will be shipped.&nbsp; By the end of this week, we will have shipped out about 40 million doses, including doses to the Republic of Korea, Mexico, Canada, Brazil, Taiwan, Honduras, Colombia, Pakistan, Peru, Ecuador, Malaysia, and Bangladesh.&nbsp;<br><br>The remaining doses will be shipped in the coming weeks as countries complete their own domestic set of operational, regulatory, and legal processes that are specific to each country.&nbsp; These U.S. doses will boost vaccination efforts in these countries and save lives.&nbsp;<br><br>And just as our work to vaccinate Americans does not stop on July 4th, our work to help vaccinate the world does not stop at these 80 million doses.&nbsp; We will continue to share tens of millions more U.S. doses over the summer months as we help lead the fight to end the pandemic across the globe.&nbsp;<br><br>In a few minutes, I will discuss how the Biden administration is mobilizing to support states and communities experienced increasing cases of the Delta variant.<br>But first, let me turn to Dr. Walensky to provide us an update on the state of the pandemic, including the Delta variant, and then Dr. Fauci to discuss the essential role our vaccines are playing in curbing its spread, including the spread of the Delta variant.<br><br>With that, over to you Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp; Yesterday, CDC reported 14,875 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is about 12,600 cases per day.&nbsp; And while this is a 95 percent decrease, lower from our peak in early January, it does also reflect a 10 percent increase in the seven-day average from last week.&nbsp; The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 1,822 per day, a decrease of about 1 percent from the prior seven-day period.&nbsp; And the seven-day average of daily deaths was about 257.<br><br>Looking across the country, we have made incredible progress towards ending the pandemic.&nbsp; We continue to see overall low numbers of cases, hospitalizations, and deaths.&nbsp; However, looking state by state and county by county, it is clear that communities where people remain unvaccinated are communities that remain vulnerable.&nbsp; This is all true as we monitor the continued spread of the hyper-transmissible Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>The Delta variant is predicted to be the second most prevalent variant in the United States, and I expect that in the coming weeks it will eclipse the alpha variant.&nbsp; An estimated 25 percent of all reported SARS-CoV-2 sequences nationwide are the Delta variant.&nbsp; And in some regions of the country, nearly one in two sequences is the Delta variant.<br><br>There are communities that are vulnerable and where we are now seeing surges in cases, and indeed also hospitalizations, due to what could be the spread of the Delta variant and low vaccination rates in these communities.<br><br>Currently, approximately 1,000 counties in the United States have vaccination coverage of less than 30 percent.&nbsp; These communities, primarily in the Southeast and Midwest, are our most vulnerable.&nbsp; In some of these areas, we are already seeing increasing rates of disease.&nbsp; As the Delta variant continues to spread across the country, we expect to see increased transmissions in these communities, unless we can vaccinate more people now.<br><br>As you will hear from Dr. Fauci shortly, our authorized vaccines provide protection against the circulating variants in this country, including Delta.&nbsp; Vaccination is how we protect these individuals, families, and communities, and prevent severe disease, hospitalizations, and deaths from COVID-19.<br><br>Preliminary data from a collection of states over the last six months suggest 99.5 percent of deaths from COVID-19 in these states have occurred in unvaccinated people.&nbsp;<br><br>Any suffering or death from COVID-19 is tragic.&nbsp; With vaccines available across the country, the suffering and loss we are now seeing is nearly entirely avoidable.&nbsp; COVID-19 [vaccines] are available and free for everyone aged 12 and up, and I encourage everyone who has not been vaccinated, especially those in these vulnerable communities with low vaccine coverage, to roll up their sleeves and get vaccinated.<br><br>As we prepare to celebrate Independence Day, I want to remind those who remain unvaccinated to protect themselves by wearing a mask and avoiding crowds to prevent transmission and illness.&nbsp; If you have symptoms of COVID-19, please get tested.&nbsp; And, of course, please get vaccinated in one of the many places near you as soon as you can.<br><br>Please enjoy a safe family- and friend-filled holiday weekend.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; What I&#8217;d like to do over the next couple of minutes is to address the issue of the role of the COVID-19 vaccines that we have available to us and their ability to protect against the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>If I could have the first slide.<br><br>It is simple &#8212; simplified to think about it in three separate buckets: What is the protection against infection,&nbsp;against symptomatic disease, or against hospitalization?&nbsp; And we have data for all three.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>First, in a study published online on June 14, from Scotland, it was shown that the mRNA vaccine had about an 80 percent effectiveness against PCR-confirmed infection.&nbsp; In this situation, two doses of AZ was about 60 percent effective.<br><br>Next, with regard &#8212; next slide &#8212; to symptomatic disease: Again, in this study, in medRxiv, published on May 21st &#8212; 24th &#8212; two weeks after the second dose of Pfizer BioNTech vaccine, again, 88 percent effective against symptomatic disease from the Delta variant.<br><br>Next slide.<br><br>Next, what about hospitalization?&nbsp; Again, from Public Health England, from June 14, the Pfizer BioNTech vaccine was 96 percent effective against hospitalization from the Delta variant after two doses, and the AZ was 92 percent effective against hospitalization after two doses.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>The question then obviously arises: The direct data we have are from AZ and the mRNA vaccines; what about J&amp;J?&nbsp; A question often asked.&nbsp; There&#8217;s indirect evidence for effectiveness of J&amp;J against the SARS-CoV-2 Delta variant.&nbsp; And the reason is that the effectiveness of this vaccine is similar to a vaccine for which we do have data, namely the AZ &#8212; the data that I just showed you.&nbsp;<br><br>Since these vaccines &#8212; the AZ and the J&amp;J &#8212; are based on very similar platforms, one could anticipate and make a reasonable assumption that the results against the Delta variant would be at least similar, perhaps even better.&nbsp; We are now looking at neutralization data, and soon we will have more firm data which we will we make available to you as soon as it occurs.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>Another question commonly asked: Is the WHO concerned about the Delta variant &#8212; has urged vaccinated people to keep wearing masks?&nbsp; There&#8217;s a reason for that.&nbsp; The WHO is responsible for the planet as a whole.&nbsp; It&#8217;s different in the world in general, from here in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>As shown here, if you look at the share of the population fully vaccinated in the United States and worldwide, they&#8217;re dramatically different, as is the dynamics of infection.&nbsp; And as we&#8217;ve always said, you can make general guidelines, but you also have to be flexible enough at various levels &#8212; be it a country level, or within a country at local levels.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>Bottom line and finally, the good news we have is that we have a solution.&nbsp; The science is clear.&nbsp; The best way to protect yourself against the virus and its variants is to be fully vaccinated.&nbsp; It works.&nbsp; It&#8217;s free.&nbsp; It&#8217;s safe.&nbsp; It&#8217;s easy.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s convenient, as President Biden has said in a speech in North Carolina just several days ago.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll pass it back to Jeff.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; As both Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci just made clear, the Delta variant is a threat to unvaccinated Americans and to communities with low vaccination rates.&nbsp; And the best way for communities to protect themselves from the virus is by getting more people vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>From day one, the President&#8217;s whole-of-government response effort has been closely tracking the data on the pandemic and vaccination effort in states and counties.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve worked with governors and local public health officials to ensure they have the support they need to curb the spread of the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, given what we are seeing with the spread of Delta in some communities in the country, we&#8217;re intensifying our efforts to help states prevent, detect, and respond to hotspots among the unvaccinated by mobilizing COVID-19 surge response teams to be at the ready to deploy federal resources and, where needed, federal personnel.&nbsp;<br><br>These are dedicated teams working with communities at higher risk for or already experiencing outbreaks due to the spread of the Delta variant and their low vaccination rate.&nbsp;<br><br>Our COVID-19 surge response teams will be ready to, one, surge additional testing into communities to expand detection of the virus and allow public health authorities to do contact tracing to help contain outbreaks.&nbsp;<br><br>Two, provide therapeutics to help treat those infected with COVID.&nbsp;<br><br>Three, deploy federal personnel where needed and where requested to address gaps and augment local staff supporting vaccination, testing, and therapeutics work.<br><br>Four, leverage CDC&#8217;s technical expertise to help communities experiencing or at risk for becoming hotspots with containment, including assisting with epidemiology, data analysis, field investigations, and other public health response work.<br><br>And five, as Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky have both underscored, the most important step we can take to prevent these outbreaks is for more Americans to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the COVID-19 surge response teams will focus on increasing shots in arms in communities with low vaccination rates who are fighting outbreaks, including through targeted paid media into these areas.<br><br>To be clear: The federal government stands ready to meet the moment and work with our state partners to respond to the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br><br>And as we continue to work with communities across the country to get more shots in arms, we will also be working with governors and state and local health authorities to identify and address the needs on the ground in places with emerging outbreaks, including potential deployment of federal personnel.&nbsp;<br><br>Before we open up to questions, I want to close with this thought: Thanks to the President&#8217;s whole-of-government response, we are further in our fight against the virus than anyone anticipated.&nbsp; And importantly, in the weeks and months ahead, we will continue mobilizing the whole of government to help state and local leaders bring an end to this pandemic by doubling down to get even more Americans vaccinated and stopping the spread as soon as possible when cases do increase.&nbsp;<br><br>With that, let&#8217;s open it up for some questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks Jeff.&nbsp; And a reminder to please keep questions to one question.&nbsp; First, we&#8217;ll going to Yamiche at PBS.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for taking my question.&nbsp; What are &#8212;&nbsp; can you tell us more about whether or not Americans may be having to go back to wearing masks in light of the Delta variant?&nbsp; We saw Los Angeles County and the WHO both recommending that even vaccinated people should wear masks.&nbsp; Where does that stand?&nbsp; Should people be preparing themselves to possibly going back to wearing masks if they&#8217;re vaccinated?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, as I was alluding to in my comments, you have a broad recommendation for the country as a whole, which is the CDC recommendation, that if you are vaccinated, you have a high degree of protection so you need not wear a mask either indoor or outdoor.&nbsp;<br><br>But also, as is said and as the CDC has recommended, is that there&#8217;s a degree of flexibility.&nbsp; People at the local level, depending upon the on-ground situation, will make recommendations or not according to the local situation.&nbsp; But the broad recommendation that the CDC makes, based on the high degree of effectiveness of the vaccine, remains unchanged.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Sharon LaFraniere at the New York Times.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, I wanted to ask: Why is the data on whether J&amp;J works against the Delta variant lagging behind the data for other vaccines?&nbsp; And what do you make of reports that J&amp;J recipients are now asking for Pfizer and Moderna doses as boosters?&nbsp; Do you recommend that?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, first of all, the reason is the paucity of direct clinical trial data in the context of Delta variant.&nbsp; So you have a much, much more wider use globally of the mRNAs in situations in which you can actually make data-based statements on that.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the reason why I show that slide &#8212; that, from the standpoint of data right now, you have to make an extrapolation based on what you would predict from what it does with other variants and what it does comparable to other vaccine products such as AZ.&nbsp;<br><br>With regard to the idea of boosting: There&#8217;s a lot of talk about that, but right now I think we still need to remember that, in fact, the J&amp;J vaccine is a highly effective vaccine that has been recommended very clearly and has received an emergency use authorization.&nbsp;<br><br>The situation right now is that people, locally, will be making those kinds of decisions, but you should only be making a formal recommendation based on clinical data.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s the reason why, even though individual physicians will be doing that, from a clinical trial basis, there&#8217;s no real fundamental scientific reason to do that right now.&nbsp;<br><br>When those data become available, you will see recommendations change according to the data.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question, please.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Meg Tirrell at CNBC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: You know, some folks have pointed to the vaccines still being under emergency use authorization as perhaps one reason that people may still be on the fence about getting them.&nbsp; Do you have any guidance about when you expect potential full approval &#8212; the process to kind of come to fruition for these vaccines? &nbsp;When would &#8212; might we see that from the FDA?&nbsp;<br><br>And a quick second follow-up.&nbsp; I apologize.&nbsp; But, Dr. Walensky, are you concerned about, as people are taking their masks off and starting to circulate more, the rise of other respiratory infections other than COVID that you&#8217;re seeing right now?&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So why don&#8217;t we start with the second one, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you, Meg.&nbsp; You know, I think we saw actually a paucity of viral infections last year.&nbsp; Many of our pediatricians would say that they didn&#8217;t see a lot of people coming in with upper respiratory infections.&nbsp; I do think part of that was the distancing, the not being in school, and of course, the masking.&nbsp;<br><br>I do anticipate that in the months ahead, if people are not wearing masks &#8212; and we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; started to see some of this already &#8212; that there will likely be an increase of upper respiratory infections in places that are not wearing masks.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, in terms of the emergency use authorization and moving toward full approval, that&#8217;s at the FDA, and that&#8217;s obviously the FDA’s decision to make.&nbsp; I know that Pfizer and Moderna have provided data to the FDA, and the FDA is working on an expedited timeframe.<br><br>But, Dr. Fauci, you might want to just talk about the experience we have with the vaccines &#8212; the hundreds of millions &#8212; and what that should tell people about their safety and efficacy.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thank you, Jeff.&nbsp; You know, as always, we don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the FDA.&nbsp; You know, they have their process where they need to cross all the &#8220;T&#8217;s&#8221; and dot all the &#8220;i&#8217;s.&#8221;&nbsp; But if you look at the history of emergency use authorizations, they use for a wide range of emergency approval of interventions, often the criteria is: Does the benefit appear to be better than the risk involved?<br><br>Very infrequently do you have such an extraordinary amount of data of literally hundreds of millions of doses, and a lot of real-world effectiveness data, as well as safety, having been accumulated.&nbsp;<br><br>So, again, although it&#8217;s understandable how some people would say, “Well, we really want to wait to the full approval,” to have an emergency authorization and to have this amount of extraordinarily positive data, one would say &#8212; again, the caveat: You never want to get ahead of the FDA &#8212; but it would really be a most unusual situation not to see this get full approval.&nbsp; I believe it&#8217;s going to happen.&nbsp;<br><br>The timing is such that I hope it does not get people to hesitate from taking a potentially lifesaving vaccine that already has an extraordinary amount of data as to its real-world effectiveness and its safety.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Tamara Keith, at NPR.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; My question is &#8212; I noticed that as you talked about the next steps and the next phase, you&#8217;re talking about these surge response teams going into states.&nbsp; Is that the next phase of this push?&nbsp; Is it more focused on the states?<br><br>You talked a lot &#8212; your language talked about states asking the federal government for help.&nbsp; At this point, is this shifting from Cabinet officials barnstorming the country, begging people to get vaccinated, to, &#8220;Welp, states, you figure it out&#8221;?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Not at all.&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; This &#8212; the surge response teams are important to be ready to work with, where called upon, states and counties that are in a situation where there&#8217;s fewer people vaccinated and cases are increasing.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s capabilities that we&#8217;ve had in place that we&#8217;re amping up to deal with the Delta variant.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s an important area of focus.&nbsp;<br><br>But even as vaccinations have slowed somewhat across the last month or so, we are still vaccinating millions of people each week.&nbsp; More than 2 million people each week in June have gotten their first shot, and millions more, importantly, are getting their second shot because Dr. Fauci&#8217;s data on the effectiveness &#8212; that&#8217;s about people getting their second shot, their full regimen.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;ll double down on these efforts as we continue to vaccinate millions of people across the summer months.&nbsp; So this whole-of-government wartime response continues.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working, more and more, person by person, community by community &#8212; meeting people where they are: in places of worship, deploying pop-up clinics and mobile clinics.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue to answer people&#8217;s questions, as we&#8217;ve talked about before.&nbsp;<br><br>Doctors are critical here.&nbsp; They are trusted messengers, and we are getting vaccines more and more into doctors&#8217; offices.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll work with employers and schools to bring vaccines on site as people go back to school and back to work.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, throughout all of our efforts, equity and fairness will continue to be at the center.&nbsp; So this whole-of-federal-government, wartime-like approach &#8212; it continues.&nbsp; And the surge response teams are just another approach, given the Delta variant and the time that we find ourselves in.&nbsp;<br><br>Last question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Andrea Shalal at Reuters.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for taking my question.&nbsp; Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky, I want to ask you a question that I asked at the White House briefing recently.&nbsp; Does it send a bad signal &#8212; given what we&#8217;re seeing now, in terms of the Delta variant and these increases in certain communities &#8212; that, in Washington, the nation&#8217;s capital, there&#8217;s going to be a large party at the White House on July 4th and there&#8217;s going to be fireworks on the National Mall?&nbsp; I mean, is that a little bit of a mixed signal, on one hand, to be sending to the country at this point?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Let me go first there.&nbsp; And then, Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky, please chime in.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, the Fourth of July is a moment for us to step back and celebrate our progress.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made tremendous progress in our fight against the virus, with now two out of three adult Americans with at least one shot.&nbsp; And directly because of this work, deaths and hospitalizations have fallen 90 percent since January 20th.&nbsp;<br><br>The American people should be proud of the work that we&#8217;ve collectively done, and we want to recognize that progress and that work on July 4th.<br><br>People who are vaccinated have a high degree of protection, and those who are not vaccinated are at risk.&nbsp; And they need to continue to wear a mask and, as the doctors have said, get vaccinated as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, as we just talked about, there&#8217;s a lot more work to do.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to double down on our efforts to keep pushing more and more people to get vaccinated by making it, as Dr. Fauci said, easy.&nbsp; Lots of places to get vaccinated.&nbsp; It&#8217;s free.&nbsp; It&#8217;s convenient.&nbsp;<br><br>So we&#8217;re going to keep doing that, but, right now, it&#8217;s an appropriate time to step back and celebrate the progress we&#8217;ve made.&nbsp; At the same time, we&#8217;ve got a lot more work to do.&nbsp;<br><br>Dr. Fauci?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, Jeff, you said it very well.&nbsp; I mean, nothing has really changed in our policy.&nbsp; You&#8217;re dealing with the &#8212; a very important national holiday.&nbsp; The country, as a whole, as I&#8217;ve mentioned and we have mentioned several times, has done very well.&nbsp;<br><br>You can still celebrate at the same time as you get your message very, very clear.&nbsp; And the message for the situation in Washington is the same, and you said it very well.&nbsp; That is: If you are vaccinated, you have a high degree of protection.&nbsp; If you are not, you should wear a mask and you should think very seriously about getting vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>So, in so many respects, nothing has really changed.&nbsp; We are celebrating, as a country, at the same time as we recognize the fact that we&#8217;re in a serious situation for those who have not been vaccinated.&nbsp; And the message is: Get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s close on: Get vaccinated if you&#8217;re not vaccinated, and happy Fourth of July weekend to everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>We look forward to seeing everybody next week.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:04 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_1July2021_for-transcript.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_1July2021_for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Deputy Prime Minister Pham Binh Minh of Vietnam</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-deputy-prime-minister-pham-binh-minh-of-vietnam/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22987</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Vietnamese Deputy Prime Minister Pham Binh Minh. Mr. Sullivan emphasized the United States’ commitment to our comprehensive partnership with Vietnam, and discussed ways to deepen cooperation between the two countries in areas such as maritime security, the Mekong region, combatting climate change, and ending the COVID-19 pandemic.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Vietnamese Deputy Prime Minister Pham Binh Minh. Mr. Sullivan emphasized the United States’ commitment to our comprehensive partnership with Vietnam, and discussed ways to deepen cooperation between the two countries in areas such as maritime security, the Mekong region, combatting climate change, and ending the COVID-19 pandemic. Mr. Sullivan underscored the Biden-Harris administration’s commitment to ASEAN centrality and ASEAN’s essential role in the Indo-Pacific architecture and pledged that the administration would continue to engage at a high-level with Vietnam and partners throughout the region. Mr. Sullivan and Deputy Prime Minster Minh also discussed the South China Sea, including the United States’ support for the 2016 arbitral tribunal award. Additionally, Mr. Sullivan conveyed President Biden’s concern over the dire humanitarian and human rights situation in Ethiopia’s Tigray region and the urgent need for the UN Security Council to marshal support to address ongoing famine conditions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/u-s-covid-19-global-response-and-recovery-framework/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 23:26:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[More than&#160;600,000&#160;of our fellow Americans,&#160;and nearly 4 million people globally,&#160;have died due to COVID-19. The devastating impact of the pandemic has been felt at home and abroad, triggering health and economic crises. Globally, we are witnessing the first&#160;wide scale&#160;increase in extreme poverty in more than twenty years, the loss of decades of development progress,&#160;increases in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>More than&nbsp;600,000&nbsp;of our fellow Americans,&nbsp;and nearly 4 million people globally,&nbsp;have died due to COVID-19. The devastating impact of the pandemic has been felt at home and abroad, triggering health and economic crises. Globally, we are witnessing the first&nbsp;wide scale&nbsp;increase in extreme poverty in more than twenty years, the loss of decades of development progress,&nbsp;increases in gender-based violence,&nbsp;rising food insecurity, and increased unemployment—particularly among young people and women.&nbsp;Even as we gain confidence in&nbsp;United States (U.S.)&nbsp;domestic COVID-19 vaccination coverage, none of us are safe until all of us are safe. The risk of emergent, dangerous variants where COVID-19 transmission remains high poses a risk to us all.&nbsp; This disease knows no borders.</p>



<p>The U.S. will work with our partners to intensify the fight against COVID-19 around the world, pave the way to global recovery, and build back better national and global health security. Our first goal is to end the pandemic—at home and abroad. On January 21, 2021, President Biden released the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/National-Strategy-for-the-COVID-19-Response-and-Pandemic-Preparedness.pdf">National Strategy for the COVID-19 Response and  Pandemic Preparedness</a>, including Goal 7, which details the Biden-Harris Administration’s comprehensive plan to restore U.S. leadership globally and build better preparedness for future threats; re-engage with the World Health Organization (WHO) and seek to strengthen and reform it; urge the international COVID-19 public health and humanitarian response; restore U.S. leadership to the international COVID-19 response and advance global health security and diplomacy; and build better biopreparedness and expand resilience for biological threats.</p>



<p>In support of that strategy, the&nbsp;U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework&nbsp;provides a focused set of objectives and lines of effort under which U.S. departments of agencies are executing a whole-of-government response.&nbsp; This response&nbsp;aims to shorten the lifespan of and ultimately end the COVID-19 pandemic globally; mitigate its wider harms to people and economies and support the global recovery; and build back better to strengthen international readiness for future biological threats.&nbsp;The U.S. Government will pursue five objectives under the U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework that together constitute a comprehensive approach to managing the immediate global health crisis and ending the pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. COVID-19 Global Response and Recovery Framework<sup>&nbsp;</sup>also supports U.S. commitments to the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/11/fact-sheet-united-states-and-g7-plan-to-defeat-the-covid-19-pandemic-in-2022-and-prevent-the-next-pandemic/">G7<sup>+</sup>&nbsp;Plan to Defeat the COVID-19 Pandemic in 2022 and Prevent the Next Pandemic</a>&nbsp;by supporting vaccination of the world’s most vulnerable populations, supporting last mile vaccination and getting shots in arms, providing personal protective equipment (PPE) and medical supplies where needed, strengthening supply, improving disease surveillance and early warning, supporting recovery, building resilience, and advancing global health security.</p>



<p>Read the full framework here:&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/U.S.-COVID-19-Global-Response-and-Recovery-Framework.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/U.S.-COVID-19-Global-Response-and-Recovery-Framework.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>2021 Annual Report to Congress on White House Staff</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/01/2021-annual-report-to-congress-on-white-house-staff/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=22935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since 1995, the White House has been required to deliver a report to Congress listing the title and salary of every White House Office employee. Consistent with President Biden’s commitment to transparency, this report is being publicly disclosed on our website as it is transmitted to Congress. 2021 Annual Report to Congress on White House&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since 1995, the White House has been required to deliver a report to Congress listing the title and salary of every White House Office employee. Consistent with President Biden’s commitment to transparency, this report is being publicly disclosed on our website as it is transmitted to Congress.</p>



<p><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/July-1-2021-Report-Final.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">2021 Annual Report to Congress on White House Staff</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
