<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 15:54:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Reproductive Justice&#160;Leaders </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/21/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-reproductive-justice-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 15:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, Jennifer Klein, Director of the White House Gender Policy Council, and Rohini Kosoglu, Domestic Policy Advisor to the Vice President, hosted a meeting with reproductive justice leaders from across the country.&#160;Reproductive justice leaders shared their concerns about access to reproductive health care on the ground, describing the range of challenges that patients currently face&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, Jennifer Klein, Director of the White House Gender Policy Council, and Rohini Kosoglu, Domestic Policy Advisor to the Vice President, hosted a meeting with reproductive justice leaders from across the country.&nbsp;<br>Reproductive justice leaders shared their concerns about access to reproductive health care on the ground, describing the range of challenges that patients currently face as states pass extreme laws restricting access to critical health care. Participants also highlighted the disproportionate impact that abortion restrictions have on underserved communities, including communities of color and low-income women.<br><br>On Thursday, the Vice President&nbsp;<a href="https://twitter.com/VP/status/1527351664432525317?s=20&amp;t=-WpEoNePRl1rtAw-uqMjQw">met</a>&nbsp;with doctors and nurses to discuss the impact that overturning&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade&nbsp;</em>would have on women’s health care. Later the day, White House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre issued a&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/19/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-oklahoma-abortion-bill/">statement</a>&nbsp;on the Oklahoma legislature’s latest bill, which is one of the most extreme efforts yet to undo fundamental reproductive rights.<br><br>Reproductive justice meeting participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Marcela Howell, In Our Own Voice: National Black Women’s Reproductive Justice Agenda</li><li>Guadalupe Rodriguez, National Latina Institute for Reproductive Justice</li><li>Sung Yeon Choimorrow, National Asian Pacific Women’s Forum (NAPAWF)</li><li>Marsha Jones, The Afiya Center </li><li>Neha Gill, Apna Ghar, Inc. </li><li>Sevonna Brown, Black Women’s Blueprint</li><li>Tammy Boyd, Black Women’s Health Imperative</li><li>Laura Jimenez, California Latinas for Reproductive Justice</li><li>Dr. Nusrat Ameen, Daya Inc.</li><li>Nadiah Mohajir, HEART</li><li>Camille Kidd, In Our Own Voice: National Black Women’s Reproductive Justice Agenda</li><li>Yvonne Hsu, National Asian Pacific Women’s Forum (NAPAWF)</li><li>Megan Simmons, National Birth Equity Collaborative</li><li>Candace Gibson, National Latina Institute for Reproductive Justice</li><li>Kelly Davis, New Voices for Reproductive Justice</li><li>Dazon Dixon Diallo, SisterLove</li><li>Dr. Krystal Redman, SPARK Reproductive Justice Now!, Inc.</li><li>Corrine Sanchez, Tewa Women United</li><li>Kimberly Inez McGuire, URGE: Unite for Reproductive &amp; Gender Equity</li><li>Deon Haywood, Women with a Vision</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 7691 and ​H.R.&#160;7791</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/05/21/bills-signed-h-r-7691-and-h-r-7791/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 10:27:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53791</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On&#160;Saturday,&#160;May&#160;21, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 7691, the &#8220;Additional Ukraine Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2022,&#8221; which provides supplemental emergency appropriations for fiscal year 2022 to Federal agencies to respond to the situation in, and for assistance to, Ukraine; and  H.R. 7791, the &#8220;Access to Baby Formula Act of 2022,&#8221; which allows the waiver of certain program requirements&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On&nbsp;Saturday,&nbsp;May&nbsp;21<a></a>, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 7691, the &#8220;Additional Ukraine Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2022,&#8221; which provides supplemental emergency appropriations for fiscal year 2022 to Federal agencies to respond to the situation in, and for assistance to, Ukraine; and </p>



<p>H.R. 7791, the &#8220;Access to Baby Formula Act of 2022,&#8221; which allows the waiver of certain program requirements in the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children due to a supply chain disruption or emergency.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea During Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/21/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-yoon-suk-yeol-of-the-republic-of-korea-during-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 08:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The People&#8217;s HouseSeoul, Republic of Korea 3:09 P.M. KST PRESIDENT YOON:&#160; (As interpreted.)&#160; Mr. President, today we&#8217;re living in the era of economic security, where economy is security and vice versa.&#160; The transformation of the international trade order and the disruption of global supply chains are having a direct impact on the livelihood of our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The People&#8217;s House<br>Seoul, Republic of Korea</p>



<p>3:09 P.M. KST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Mr. President, today we&#8217;re living in the era of economic security, where economy is security and vice versa.&nbsp; The transformation of the international trade order and the disruption of global supply chains are having a direct impact on the livelihood of our people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ROK-U.S. alliance should also move forward and adapt to this new era of economic security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, Mr. President and I, together, visited what can be described as the &#8220;global epicenter&#8221; of cutting-edge semiconductor industry.&nbsp; There, I was able to feel the strength of our economic and technology alliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will continue our cooperation in strategic industries, such as microchips and EV batteries, in order to expand mutual investment and to attain our common goal, which is building a resilient supply chain.</p>



<p>And, Mr. President, our summit talks today will provide a valuable opportunity to further strengthen our cooperation and economic security, as well as to discuss ways to work together and align our policies to resolve many other pressing global challenges that we face together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you for your incredibly warm welcome.&nbsp; It’s wonderful to be back in the Republic of Korea.&nbsp; I&#8217;m honored to be making this visit less than two weeks since you’ve been inaugurated.&nbsp; And congratulations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, our alliances between our countries is built on shared sacrifice.&nbsp; And our joint commitment to the freedom of the Republic of Korea and our firm opposition to changing borders by force has flourished with decades of peace and cooperation.&nbsp; And today, with this visit, we&#8217;re taking the cooperation between our two countries to new heights.</p>



<p>For decades, our alliance has been a linchpin for regional peace and growth and prosperity, and it’s been vital to deterring attacks from the DPRK.&nbsp; And, today, our cooperation is essential to preserve the stability and global &#8212; on the global stage as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our two nations are working together to take on both the opportunities and the challenges of the moment: continuing to fight COVID-19, securing the supply chains, tackling the climate crisis, deepening our security cooperation to meet regional challenges, and writing the rules of the road to ensure the Indo-Pacific is a free and open area.</p>



<p>So, thank you again for the welcome, Mr. President.&nbsp; I’ve enjoyed our conversations and getting to spend some time with you.&nbsp; Matter of a fact, we spent so much time, we didn’t get a chance to see the rest of your people.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; And I’m looking forward to continuing the great friendship between our two nations.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>3:16 P.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United&#160;States-Republic of Korea Leaders’ Joint&#160;Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/21/united-states-republic-of-korea-leaders-joint-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 07:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53779</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Yoon Suk Yeol welcomes President Joseph R. Biden to the Republic of Korea (ROK), marking the earliest meeting in a ROK President’s term in office with the President of the United States (U.S.). Founded in our shared sacrifice and honed by our deep security ties, the Alliance between the Republic of Korea and the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Yoon Suk Yeol welcomes President Joseph R. Biden to the Republic of Korea (ROK), marking the earliest meeting in a ROK President’s term in office with the President of the United States (U.S.). Founded in our shared sacrifice and honed by our deep security ties, the Alliance between the Republic of Korea and the United States continues to evolve and expand. The linchpin for peace and prosperity in the region, the Alliance has grown far beyond the Korean peninsula, reflecting the pivotal role of our countries as global leaders in democracy, economy, and technology. Faced with existential challenges like climate change and the COVID-19 pandemic, and growing threats to the rules-based international order, foremost among which is Russia’s further aggression against Ukraine, the Republic of Korea and the United States are unified in common determination to deepen and broaden our political, economic, security, and people-to-people ties.</p>



<p>The two Presidents deeply appreciate the recent accomplishments of the Alliance and pledge to continue building off of its rock solid foundation.</p>



<p><strong>The Linchpin for Peace and Prosperity</strong></p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden reaffirm their mutual commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea and the combined defense posture under the ROK-U.S. Mutual Defense Treaty. President Biden affirms the U.S. extended deterrence commitment to the ROK using the full range of U.S. defense capabilities, including nuclear, conventional, and missile defense capabilities. The two Presidents also agree to reactivate the high-level Extended Deterrence Strategy and Consultation Group at the earliest date. Both leaders commit to further strengthen deterrence by reinforcing combined defense posture, and reiterate commitment to a conditions-based transition of wartime operational control. With this in mind, and considering the evolving threat posed by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK), both leaders agree to initiate discussions to expand the scope and scale of combined military exercises and training on and around the Korean Peninsula. Both leaders also reaffirm the commitment of the U.S. to deploy strategic U.S. military assets in a timely and coordinated manner as necessary, as well as to enhance such measures and identify new or additional steps to reinforce deterrence in the face of DPRK destabilizing activities. In this vein, the United States and ROK will significantly expand cooperation to confront a range of cyber threats from the DPRK, including but not limited to, state-sponsored cyber-attacks.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden reiterate their common goal of the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and agree to further strengthen the airtight coordination to this end. The two Presidents share the view that the DPRK’s nuclear program presents a grave threat not only to peace and stability on the Korean Peninsula but also the rest of Asia and the world. Both leaders condemn the DPRK’s escalatory ballistic missile tests this year, including multiple launches of intercontinental ballistic missiles, as clear violations of United Nations Security Council resolutions and reaffirm their joint commitment to work with the international community to urge the DPRK to abandon its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs.Both leaders urge all UN Member States to fully implement all United Nations Security Council resolutions and also call on the DPRK to abide by its obligations under UN Security Council resolutions as well as its previous commitments and agreements.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden emphasize that the path to dialogue remains open toward peaceful and diplomatic resolution with the DPRK and call on DPRK to return to negotiations. President Yoon outlined his vision to normalize inter-Korean relationship through an audacious plan aimed at a denuclearized and prosperous Korean peninsula and President Biden expresses his support for inter-Korean cooperation. Both leaders underscore the importance of ROK-U.S.-Japan trilateral cooperation for responding to the DPRK’s challenges, protecting shared security and prosperity, upholding common values, and bolstering the rules-based international order.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden express grave concern over the human rights situation in the DPRK. The two Presidents also reaffirm their commitment to facilitate the provision of humanitarian aid to the most vulnerable North Koreans. Both leaders express concern over the recent COVID-19 outbreak in the DPRK. The ROK and the U.S. are willing to work with the international community to provide assistance to the DPRK to combat the virus.</p>



<p><strong>A Strategic Economic and Technology Partnership</strong></p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden recognize that the future of the Alliance will be defined by common efforts to address 21<sup>st</sup> century challenges. In this vein, the two Presidents pledge to deepen and broaden cooperation on critical and emerging technologies, and cyber security. Both leaders also pledge to develop, use, and advance technologies in line with shared democratic principles and universal values.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden recognize the importance of deepening cooperation on economic and energy security, which are critical to safeguarding our prosperity, shared security, and collective interests. To support these initiatives, the two Presidents will direct respective National Security Councils to launch an economic security dialogue aimed to align the bureaucratic and policy approaches between the two governments.</p>



<p>Fully recognizing that scientists, researchers, and engineers of the ROK and the U.S. are among the most innovative in the world, the two Presidents agree to leverage this comparative advantage to enhance public and private cooperation to protect and promote critical and emerging technologies, including leading-edge semiconductors, eco-friendly EV batteries, Artificial Intelligence, quantum technology, biotechnology, biomanufacturing, and autonomous robotics. Moreover, the two Presidents also reaffirm their active support for people-to-people exchanges between experts in these fields. To this end, the two Presidents agree to work together to enhance partnership on these critical and emerging technologies in both countries through the promotion of investment as well as research and development cooperation. Recognizing the growing potential for ROK-U.S. cooperation in the defense industry, the two leaders agree to strengthen partnerships in areas such as defense sector supply chain, joint development and manufacturing, including beginning discussions on a Reciprocal Defense Procurement agreement.</p>



<p>Secure, sustainable, and resilient global supply chains are foundational to these efforts. Building upon international cooperation fostered by the U.S.-led Summit on Global Supply Chain Resilience, and by working closely together in the upcoming Ministerial-level summit, the two Presidents agree to continue working together to tackle immediate and long-term challenges in the supply chain ecosystem. Both leaders agree to strengthen the resiliency and diversity of these networks including by cooperating on early warning systems to detect and address potential supply chain disruptions and working together to address sourcing and processing of critical minerals. The two Presidents also agree to establish a regular ministerial-level Supply Chain and Commercial Dialogue to discuss promotion of resilient supply chains of key products, including semiconductors, batteries, and critical minerals. Both leaders also agree to enhance cooperation between our foreign investment screening and export control authorities related to critical technologies, which is necessary to prevent the use of advanced technologies to undermine our national and economic security.</p>



<p>Recognizing the importance of energy security as well as commitment to address climate change given the rapid increase of volatility in the global energy market as a result of Russia’s further aggression against Ukraine, the two Presidents will work to strengthen joint collaboration in securing energy supply chains that include fossil fuels, and enriched uranium, acknowledging that true energy security means rapidly deploying clean energy technology and working to decrease our dependence on fossil fuels.</p>



<p>The two leaders recognize the importance of nuclear energy as a critical and reliable source of carbon-free electricity, an important element to grow our clean energy economy, and an integral part of enhancing global energy security. The two leaders commit to greater nuclear energy collaboration and accelerating the development and global deployment of advanced reactors and small modular reactors by jointly using export promotion and capacity building tools, and building a more resilient nuclear supply chain. The two Presidents reaffirm that both countries will engage in global civil-nuclear cooperation in accordance with the highest standards of nuclear nonproliferation, including the IAEA Additional Protocol as the standard for both international safeguards and for nuclear supply arrangements. Acknowledging the shared goals of deepening strategic ties, while respecting each country’s intellectual investments, both leaders commit to using tools such as the ROK-U.S. Memorandum of Understanding on Nuclear Technology Transfer and Export Cooperation to provide a solid foundation for strengthened cooperation in the U.S., ROK and overseas nuclear markets and the High-Level Bilateral Commission, to further cooperation for spent fuel management, nuclear export promotion, assured fuel supply and nuclear security. The U.S. welcomes the ROK’s decision to join the U.S.-led Foundational Infrastructure for Responsible Use of Small Modular Reactor Technology (FIRST) program.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden commit to strengthening the ROK-U.S. alliance across all sectors of space cooperation. Building on the ROK’s previous commitment to participate in the Artemis program, the two Presidents agreed to foster joint research in space exploration and to support the ROK’s development of the Korean Positioning System (KPS). Both leaders agree to hold “the 3<sup>rd</sup> U.S.-ROK Civil Space Dialogue” by the end of the year, and to strengthen cooperation on the two countries space industries. They also commit to continue cooperation to ensure a safe, secure, and sustainable space environment including through the bilateral space policy dialogue and committed to strengthen defense space partnerships including through joint exercises.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden agree that the Korea-U.S. Free Trade Agreement (KORUS), which celebrated its 10<sup>th</sup> anniversary this year, remains the foundation of our economic relationship. To promote sustainable growth and financial stability, including orderly and well-functioning foreign exchange markets, the two Presidents recognize the need to consult closely on foreign exchange market developments. The two Presidents share common values and an essential interest in fair, market-based competition and commit to work together to address market distorting practices.</p>



<p><strong>Global </strong><strong>Comprehensive Strategic Alliance: Beyond the Korean Peninsula</strong></p>



<p>Faced with increasingly complex global challenges including the threats posed by climate change and the COVID-19 pandemic, President Yoon laid out the ROK’s initiative for a global pivotal state that envisions a heightened role in advancing freedom, peace, and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region and beyond. The two Presidents reaffirm their commitments to a global comprehensive strategic alliance firmly rooted in the shared values of promoting democracy and the rules-based international order, fighting corruption, and advancing human rights. President Biden appreciated President Yoon’s initiative to embrace greater regional and global responsibilities, and enthusiastically welcome the ROK taking a leadership role in <em>the Summit for Democracy </em>process.</p>



<p>Acknowledging the existential threat posed by climate change, President Yoon and President Biden reaffirm their commitments to their announced nationally determined contributions under the Paris Agreement including the 2030 greenhouse gas reduction targets and 2050 net zero emission goals with strong efforts to align policies across sectors. The two Presidents also agree to enhance cooperation to address methane emissions globally, recognizing the importance of the Global Methane Pledge and rapid global action needed to address methane. The two Presidents also decide to strengthen cooperation in clean energy fields such as hydrogen, clean shipping, accelerated deployment of zero-emissions vehicles (ZEVs) and aligning international financial flows with global net zero emissions by 2050 and deep reductions in the 2020s.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden pledge to support in strengthening multilateral efforts to prevent, prepare, and respond to infectious disease threats. President Yoon underscored President Biden’s leadership in convening the Global COVID-19 Summit in May 2022, and President Biden appreciated President Yoon’s active participation and ROK’s announced pledges, including funding for the Act-Accelerator to combat COVID-19 and support for the Financial Intermediary Fund for pandemic preparedness and global health security at the World Bank. President Biden welcomes the ROK’s decision to host a Global Health Security Agenda ministerial meeting this Fall and establish a GHS coordinating office for global and regional sustainable health security in Seoul. Our countries will also increase efforts bilaterally and in multilateral fora to promote biosafety and biosecurity norms. The U.S. and ROK will also strengthen health systems and build on successful health sector collaboration to accelerate cooperation and innovation in cancer research, cutting edge cancer treatments, mental health research, early detection, and treatment of mental health disorders.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden highlight their shared belief in the extraordinary benefits afforded by an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable, and secure Internet. To combat the rising threats posed by digital authoritarianism, they committed to defend human rights and foster an open “network of networks” that ensures the free flow of information globally. To achieve this, the ROK is ready to join the U.S. in endorsing <em>the Declaration for the Future of the Internet</em>. The two Presidents also reaffirm the need to ensure that the Internet continues to play a positive role in promoting equity, equality and safety for women and girls in both our societies. To this end, the U.S. and the ROK joined the Global Partnership for Action on Gender-Based Online Harassment and Abuse as founding members. Recognizing the importance of telecommunications security and vendor diversity, the leaders also commit to work together to develop open, transparent, and secure 5G and 6G network devices and architectures using Open-RAN approaches, both at home and abroad.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden will continue to deepen ROK-U.S. cooperation on regional and international cyber policy, including cooperation on deterring cyber adversaries, cybersecurity of critical infrastructure, combatting cybercrime and associated money laundering, securing cryptocurrency and blockchain applications, capacity building, cyber exercises, information sharing, military-to-military cyber cooperation, and other international security issues in cyberspace.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden oppose all activities that undermine, destabilize, or threaten the rules-based international order and stand together with the international community in condemning Russia’s unprovoked further aggression against Ukraine. Both countries, alongside other international partners, have responded resolutely to this clear violation of international law, by imposing their own financial sanctions and export controls against Russia and Russian entities, along with the vital provision of humanitarian aid to Ukraine. Both leaders affirm that they will ensure the effective implementation of their country’s respective measures to deter further Russian aggression and maintain our commitment to the principles of sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>



<p>The two Presidents recognize the importance of maintaining a free and open Indo-Pacific that is prosperous and peaceful, and agree to strengthen mutual cooperation across the region. In this regard, President Biden shares his support for President Yoon’s initiative to formulate ROK’s own Indo-Pacific strategy framework. President Yoon also welcomed the U.S. Indo-Pacific Strategy. The two Presidents commit to cooperate closely through the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework (IPEF), based on the principles of openness, transparency, and inclusiveness. Both leaders agree to work together to develop a comprehensive IPEF that will deepen economic engagement on priority issues, including the digital economy, resilient supply chains, clean energy, and other priorities geared toward promoting sustainable economic growth.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden also reaffirm their strong support for ASEAN centrality and the ASEAN Outlook on the Indo-Pacific. The two Presidents commit to increase cooperation with Southeast Asia and the Pacific Island Countries to promote sustainable development, energy security, and high-quality, transparent investment, including in quality infrastructure. President Biden welcomes President Yoon’s interest in the Quad, and noted complementary ROK strengths including tackling the pandemic, fighting climate change and producing critical technologies. The two leaders also agree to cooperate on infrastructure financing, including digital infrastructure, in third countries. The two Presidents emphasize the importance of ROK-U.S.- Japan trilateral cooperation to effectively address common economic challenges.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden reaffirm their commitment to maintain peace and stability, lawful unimpeded commerce, and respect for international law including freedom of navigation and overflight and other lawful use of the seas, including in the South China Sea and beyond. The two Presidents reiterate the importance of preserving peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait as an essential element in security and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific region. Sharing our mutual concerns regarding human rights situations in the Indo-Pacific region, both leaders commit to promote human rights and rule of law globally. The two Presidents resolutely condemn the coup in Myanmar and the military’s brutal attacks on civilians, and commit to press for the immediate cessation of violence, the release of those who are detained, unfettered countrywide humanitarian access, and a swift return to democracy. The two Presidents call on all nations to join us in providing safe haven to Burmese nationals and in prohibiting arms sales to Myanmar.</p>



<p>President Yoon and President Biden share the view that the Alliance has matured into a deep and comprehensive strategic relationship. Through our close ties between the two dynamic populations, extensive economic and investment links, and commitment to democracy, human rights, and the rules-based international order, the ROK and the U.S. are charting a path toward a relationship that is capable of meeting any challenge and seizing all the opportunities presented before us. President Yoon and President Biden jointly recognize the importance of our shared commitments and pledge to work tirelessly to broaden and deepen our ties to position us to succeed in a rapidly changing world.</p>



<p>President Biden expressed his gratitude for President Yoon’s warm hospitality and extended an invitation for President Yoon to visit Washington at a time of mutual convenience.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Republic of Korea President Yoon Suk&#160;Yeol</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/21/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-republic-of-korea-president-yoon-suk-yeol/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 07:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea (ROK) in Seoul. Both Leaders reaffirmed their commitment to strengthen the U.S.-ROK alliance and to broaden its focus beyond the Korean Peninsula to take on global challenges, including threats to the rules-based international order, such as Russia’s invasion&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea (ROK) in Seoul. Both Leaders reaffirmed their commitment to strengthen the U.S.-ROK alliance and to broaden its focus beyond the Korean Peninsula to take on global challenges, including threats to the rules-based international order, such as Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. The two Leaders committed to increase cooperation on a broad range of priority issues including critical technologies, economic and energy security, global health, and climate change. The Presidents also discussed their shared belief in constitutional democracy and the importance of respecting individual rights as well as strengthening the regional security environment. They committed to further strengthen deterrence and ensure close cooperation to address the threat posed by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK). Both Leaders shared concerns about the rapid spread of COVID-19 within the DPRK and expressed support for working with the international community to provide assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing President&#160;Biden’s Second Day in the Republic of&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/20/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-president-bidens-second-day-in-the-republic-of-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 03:37:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53770</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 9:12 A.M. KST MODERATOR:&#160; Good morning, everybody.&#160; I hope you all had a restful night in Seoul.&#160; Apologies for the delay. Thanks so much for joining us today on this background call.&#160; As mentioned on the invite, this call will be on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and embargoed until the call&#8217;s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>9:12 A.M. KST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good morning, everybody.&nbsp; I hope you all had a restful night in Seoul.&nbsp; Apologies for the delay.</p>



<p>Thanks so much for joining us today on this background call.&nbsp; As mentioned on the invite, this call will be on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and embargoed until the call&#8217;s conclusion.</p>



<p>Not for reporting for just for everyone&#8217;s knowledge, joining us on this call is [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>[Senior administration official] has some remarks to make off the top, and then we will take some questions before our speaker has to run into another commitment.</p>



<p>So, with that, I will turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; And thanks for joining both the trip and then joining us this morning.&nbsp; I’ll try and keep this as short as possible and take some questions.</p>



<p>So, as I&#8217;m sure all of you know, today the President has a packed day.&nbsp; But before I get into it, I do want to very quickly highlight yesterday’s tour of the Samsung Pyeongtaek facility by the President, President Yoon, and Secretary Raimondo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think as you all are aware, this is essentially the model of the facility that Samsung has &#8212; is starting to build in Taylor, Texas, that will create 3,000 new good-paying jobs.&nbsp; And it’s also an example of the strong partnership between the United States and the ROK, as well as the value of the relationship in terms of generating investment in the United States.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an example of how the Biden administration is deepening our economic ties with the region to deliver for U.S. workers, businesses, consumers, and of course for people everywhere, including in the ROK.</p>



<p>You’ll see us continue to deepen our economic ties on this trip, including with the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.&nbsp; We firmly believe that much of what happens in the coming decades will depend on how well governments harness innovation &#8212; and especially the transformations afoot in clean energy and digital and tech sectors &#8212; while fortifying our economies from a range of vulnerabilities that we&#8217;ve seen, in particular, driven home by the impacts of the pandemic.&nbsp; And this ranges from fragile supply chains, to the vulnerabilities to disruption, to corruption, to tax havens.</p>



<p>And from our view, this requires a new model that we can move on quickly, and that&#8217;s what IPEF will do.&nbsp; We are pleased to see the very strong interests in the region for IPEF and for our economic engagement in the region, which we think reflects the continuing importance of an affirmative U.S. vision for the region, which we highlight in our Indo-Pacific strategy, as well as the desire in the region for continued U.S. economic leadership.</p>



<p>So, very quickly, to walk over today’s schedule.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll start on &#8212; the first event will be: The President will participate in a wreath-laying ceremony to pay his respects to those who died to defend the Republic of Korea, many of whom died &#8212; many of those who died fought alongside U.S. forces in the Korean War.&nbsp; And I think this reflects the deep commitment to our joint security and to our alliance, and the President&#8217;s deep respect for those who paid the ultimate price to defend our freedoms.</p>



<p>I think that this also reflects what we see as one of the major things from the visit &#8212; or outcomes from the visit, which is continued collaboration in strengthening our alliance to deal with today&#8217;s challenges.</p>



<p>The President will then participate in a bilateral meeting with President Yoon Suk Yeol.  They will have extensive discussions on a range of issues, as I&#8217;m sure you&#8217;d expect.  We expect that there will be a joint statement. </p>



<p>And we expect that, you know, really, what we&#8217;re doing in this, as much as anything else, is building on the strong alliance &#8212; to expand it; to take it to deal with global issues and the issues and challenges of today; and, I think, also to take advantage of the visit, which comes so early in President Yoon&#8217;s time in office &#8212; I mean, this is unprecedented, as you all know &#8212; to really build a strong personal relationship between the two leaders that we think will help propel the relationship going forward.</p>



<p>And as you all know, the relationship between the U.S. and the ROK is something that is extraordinarily important to both countries but, we believe, is increasingly important for the region and to promote peace and stability and prosperity throughout the Indo-Pacific, as well as around the world.</p>



<p>So, you know, I think some of the key things that we expect the presidents to discuss will be the ROK&#8217;s role and the U.S.-ROK alliance&#8217;s role as a lynchpin for peace and security.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that we expect that there will be some discussions on how to deal with some of the most recent threats and developments that have occurred.</p>



<p>We also believe that there will be discussion on how we can find ways to further expand our cooperation to make sure that we&#8217;re ready and &#8212; as ready as possible to deal with the threats of today.</p>



<p>I think that, you know, as you would expect, the presidents will discuss DPRK and, you know, reaffirm the continuing commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.</p>



<p>We believe that there will be discussion on how we can manage and address the most recent threats, particularly posed by the nuclear program, as well as the ongoing missile program.&nbsp; And very confident the leaders will stress the importance and agree on the importance of all countries fully enforcing U.N. Security Council resolutions.&nbsp; And also, we&#8217;re going to call on the DPRK to abide by its obligations under the U.N. Security Council resolutions.</p>



<p>I think the will discuss ways forward in &#8212; on a variety of issues associated with DPRK.&nbsp; And, you know, I don&#8217;t want to prejudge and get ahead of the discussions, but we&#8217;re very confident it will be very thorough, it will be very wide-ranging, and very detailed.<br><br>The presidents will also recognize the future of the alliance.&nbsp; It’s not just going to be defined by security, as has been the case in the past, but it’s also going to be defined by creating a strategic economic and technology partnership that really will reflect the importance of innovation and technology to both countries and to our work in the region going forward.</p>



<p>I think that the &#8212; we expect that there will be some work on how we can better support innovation, how we can support partnership on critical emerging technologies, and, you know, find ways to strengthen cooperation on defense industry issues.&nbsp;<br><br>I think that there will be work on &#8212; there&#8217;ll be discussion of secure supply chains and their importance.&nbsp; And I think that we’re very confident that we will have a discussion about the impact on global economic iss- &#8212; on the global economy of Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; And that we know that there is great interest in both countries on how we can better make ourselves more resilient in the face of disruptions in global energy as well as other economic issues linked to Russia&#8217;s invasion.<br><br>I think that you can expect some discussion of both nuclear cooperation as well as other technology-related issues.&nbsp; And I think that you can also expect that there will be discussion of the importance of our own economic relationship bilaterally and how we can work together to bring prosperity to the region through the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.<br><br>I think that we also recognize that, you know, as I said before, part of this visit is about turning a bilateral alliance into something that was traditionally very much focused on peace and stability in the Korean Peninsula, and then immediately in Northeast Asia, to something that really looks to the region &#8212; to the Indo-Pacific region &#8212; and to the world.<br><br>I think that there&#8217;s &#8212; there&#8217;ll be discussion about the threats posed by climate change, by the COVID-19 pandemic, and the importance of promoting democracy and shared values.<br><br>I think that we recognize that we also need to better work together to deal not just with the current pandemic but prepare for future ones.&nbsp; And so, I think that we&#8217;ll be looking for ways in which we can better cooperate, and I think the presidents will discuss that.<br><br>I think that we will have some discussion on other technology issues, including the importance of a free, open, secure Internet.&nbsp; I think that there&#8217;ll be some discussion about cyber.&nbsp; And I think that we will stress the importance of all countries standing together against efforts to destabilize the &#8212; or threaten the rules-based international order and, first and foremost, Ukraine.&nbsp; And we expect some pretty extensive discussions on Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think the U.S. and the President will highlight the great U.S. appreciation for the Republic of Korea’s strong stance on Ukraine, both in terms of imposition of sanctions and taking of economic steps, and we&#8217;ll look for ways to expand that.</p>



<p>I think the ROK has been particularly strong on this, because I think they recognize that, because of their own history and our shared history together, the importance of a strong international reaction to invasions of this kind.</p>



<p>I think the presidents are going to discuss the importance of promoting a free and open Indo-Pacific, look for areas in which we can expand cooperation with both Southeast Asia as well as on the Pacific Islands, and look for ways in which we can better integrate our efforts across the entire range of Indo-Pacific issues.</p>



<p>I think that there will be some discussions about other issues involving regional security.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t want to prejudge those, but I think that you will see that there &#8212;&nbsp;there is a great commonality in terms of our vision of the importance of a strong response to threats to the international order, particularly in the Indo-Pacific.<br><br>And I think that we strongly believe that this visit will highlight both what &#8212; how strong our alliance is today.&nbsp; But really, this is about building for the future, building a much stronger bilateral alliance and one that deals with strategic and issues globally, but also building a strong personal relationship with the leaders that will propel this going forward.<br><br>So, with that, I&#8217;ll take a few questions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; If you have a question, please use the “raise hand” function of the Zoom interface.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll try to get through as many questions as we can.<br><br>Why don&#8217;t we start with Aamer Madhani from the Associated Press?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I was having trouble with the mute button there.&nbsp; But so &#8212; hopefully, you can hear me.</p>



<p>Is there going to be an explicit message to Kim Jong Un today in what the President says in his public comments?&nbsp; And I was also wondering what, if any, assurances Jake Sullivan got from Yang Jiechi about addressing the North Korean issue in their talk?</p>



<p>And finally, do you &#8212; [senior administration official], do you believe there is any connection between the rise in COVID rates inside North Korea and Kim&#8217;s seemingly increased saber-rattling?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m very sympathetic to problems with muting and unmuting.<br><br>So let me address a couple of things.&nbsp; I think, first of all, you know, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the discussions between the leaders.&nbsp; But I think you can expect that there will be extensive discussion about DPRK issues.<br><br>I think that we are very concerned about the COVID situation in the DPRK.&nbsp; We&#8217;re very sensitive to the fact that they’re &#8212; they appear to be facing a quite serious situation.&nbsp; And I think you&#8217;ve seen we are &#8212; we stand ready to work with others in the international community as needed to provide assistance.&nbsp; And that includes, obviously, the ROK, but it includes others and using the existing international mechanisms, but this is something that is of deep concern to us.</p>



<p>I think that in terms of, you know, your characterization of the increased saber-rattling, what we&#8217;ve seen is a fair amount of saber-rattling throughout the year.&nbsp; There have obviously been quite a few tests of ballistic missiles, some of which have been successful.</p>



<p>And I think that, you know, from our standpoint, we are ready.&nbsp; We &#8212; you know, we, at the same time, it is very much our desire that we find ways to have a diplomatic approach with the DPRK.&nbsp; We have made very clear we&#8217;re prepared to talk to them and with no preconditions, and we&#8217;re also prepared to take steps to address their domestic challenges, including COVID.</p>



<p>I think that in terms of the discussion with Yang Jiechi, as you&#8217;d expect, there was discussion about the challenges of the DPRK, including their domestic situation, the COVID issue.</p>



<p>I think that, you know, we&#8217;re looking for ways in which we and others in the international community can work together to provide assistance as needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think that the key thing is that we recognize that the DPRK has to make decisions about what they&#8217;re willing to do.&nbsp; It is our hope that they will make decisions that will allow for the maximum amount of support in this time of great need and great crisis.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s go to Trevor Hunnicutt with Reuters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; So, just wanted to follow up on what Aamer asked about a little bit there &#8212; was just if there was any level of commitment from China to help on the North Korea situation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, do you expect this joint statement to deal with what you&#8217;ve described as China&#8217;s destabilizing policies towards Taiwan, its human rights issues?</p>



<p>And also, if you could talk a little bit about what the President is doing this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah. &nbsp;So, you know, I think, first, with regard to the joint statement, I don&#8217;t want to prejudge the discussions, but I think that, you know, we expect extensive discussions about regional security issues.&nbsp; And the fact that, in our view, both leaders of both countries strongly support preserving peace and stability in the region.</p>



<p>I think that with re- &#8212; I don’t want to get into the specifics of the discussions between Jake Sullivan and Yang Jiechi, but just to say that, of course, we are looking for ways in which it is possible to provide assistance and support to the DPRK as they deal with this COVID outbreak.</p>



<p>I think that, in terms of the broader issues that you raised, I think that we want to find ways to work with the international community to provide support to the DPRK.&nbsp; I think we also want to make clear that the international community stands united in opposition to their violations of U.N. Security Council resolutions and their destabilizing and threatening behavior.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Next, why don&#8217;t we go to Esther Oh with NHK.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; Just two questions.&nbsp; I know previously the administration says it has no plans to share vaccines with North Korea directly, but is the President planning to discuss with President Yoon ways that the U.S. and South Korea can work together to provide any sort of direct COVID aid to North Korea?</p>



<p>And my second question is: Will the President directly address the immediate need for South Korea and Japan to improve their bilateral ties?&nbsp; Because the relationship between the two countries &#8212; it&#8217;s deteriorated significantly in the last several years.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Those are both, obviously, very good and very important questions.&nbsp; I think that you could expect that the leaders will discuss the COVID situation.&nbsp; I think that it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s very clear that we have a common interest in doing whatever we can to address this challenge and working through the international &#8212; with the international communities through whatever mechanism is appropriate.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of those discussions, but I think that you can expect that this is something that&#8217;s very topical and we recognize that this is of great importance to the DPRK&#8217;s neighbors, as well as to us.</p>



<p>I think that with regard to the ROK-Japan relations, I think, you know, we strongly support improved ROK-Japan relations.&nbsp; At the same time, we recognize this is something that both countries are &#8212; it&#8217;s sensitive and important for both countries.&nbsp; And I think the President will make clear his support while also making clear his understanding of the need for this to be done in a way that&#8217;s mutually acceptable and agreeable to both countries.</p>



<p>However, it&#8217;s very clear that from the U.S. perspective &#8212; and we&#8217;ve been clear about this in the past &#8212; it is not in our interest for the relationship between the two of our closest and most political allies to not be strong.&nbsp; And so we want &#8212; we very much hope and support efforts by either sides, by both sides to take steps to improve the relationship.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; I think we have time for just a couple more questions before our speaker has to hop.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t we go to Paris Huang with the Voice of America next.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Hi, thank you for doing this.&nbsp; So, earlier you mentioned about the &#8212; part of this visit is for us to ensure the peace and stability in East Asia.&nbsp; I just would like to clarify: Is that specifically means Taiwan?&nbsp; And what is your assessment on President Yoon&#8217;s attitude toward issues around China and Taiwan?&nbsp; And will the language be clearly written in a joint statement?&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s the first question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second, on the Quad: Is the Biden administration &#8212; on the expansion of &#8220;Quad Plus&#8221; &#8212; or is South Korea directly involved with the Quad summit on this time?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; So, let me take the first question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, when we talk about maintaining peace and stability in the Indo-Pacific region, we&#8217;re clearly talking about the entire Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp; There are a number of areas where there are challenges, and I would note that, you know, very clearly the leaders will be talking about one that is closer to where we are now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I think that it&#8217;s clear that, you know, both countries have a very strong interest in preserving peace and stability.&nbsp; I think you can expect the leaders to talk about that and to look for ways in which we can work more effectively together to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think, on the issue of the Quad, I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the discussions.&nbsp; Obviously, you know, I think that this is a topic of great interest.&nbsp; I think that we don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the discussion with the leaders, but, also, I think that we have to recognize that the Quad is still developing, and so we&#8217;re looking for ways in which we can reinforce and strengthen what we&#8217;ve done so far.&nbsp; But at the same time, I think that we welcome any support for the Quad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I think that the issue of participation is one that we will still be working on.&nbsp; I think that you can expect &#8212; you know, I am biased, but I think you can expect that a joint statement will be clear.&nbsp; And I think we look forward to being able to, you know, really highlight how much we have in common, how similar our viewpoints are on a very wide range of issues, how close the two countries are, and how much we expect them to come closer on a very wide range of issues dealing with the challenges of today, but also challenges that we have (inaudible) to working on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think one of the things that, you know, for us &#8212; and this is not just a visit in Seoul today; this is about the entire trip &#8212; this is about demonstrating the unity and resolve and strengthening the coordination between our closest allies and &#8212; or two of our closest allies, and also strengthening our alliances to deal with problems that we are all dealing with today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think that we&#8217;re very optimistic that we are &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve done a great deal of groundwork.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we have to really recognize &#8212; and I&#8217;d ask everyone to just be very sensitive to this &#8212; this is day 11 for the Yoon administration.&nbsp; This is the earliest that we&#8217;ve ever had an American President visit an ROK President in an ROK President&#8217;s time in office.&nbsp; It is normal that in &#8212; you know, in 11 days, it takes a while for an administration to come up to speed.&nbsp; We&#8217;re very impressed with what the Yoon administration has done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re very happy with the work we&#8217;ve been able to do together, but I think it&#8217;s also important to recognize that it is unrealistic to expect any administration to have fully settled in only 11 days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we think that we&#8217;ve done quite well.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re very, very impressed by what&#8217;s been done and by the spirit of partnership, the spirit of tru- &#8212; of really genuine allies who are used to being together when times are bad, as well as when times are good.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re confident that that&#8217;s going to continue, and that we&#8217;ll be able to highlight the way forward for the alliance.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;ve got time for one last question.&nbsp; So last question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to MJ Lee with CNN.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Given that this bilateral meeting comes, as you just said, 11 days into President Yoon’s presidency and particularly given that he doesn&#8217;t have much of a foreign policy background: Are there areas you can point to where you all think, you know, there are serious question marks in terms of President Yoon’s positions on major foreign policy issues and where just the President &#8212; President Biden is keen on trying to draw him out today and gain a better understanding of where he stands?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Look, I would push back very hard against the premise of that.&nbsp; I think we are very impressed with the cohesion, the coherence, and the clarity of the Yoon administration&#8217;s vision for its &#8212; for the ROK, for the ROK-U.S. relationship and the ROK role in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that what &#8212; in our discussions with them &#8212; and look, I&#8217;ve done &#8212; I&#8217;ve been doing this for a long time &#8212; I think we&#8217;ve been very, very impressed with how focused and how clear they&#8217;ve been, how decisive they&#8217;ve been.&nbsp; And I think that reflects, in our view, a great deal of potential to really strengthen the alliance going forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that, in terms of the President&#8217;s engagement with President Yoon, I think that, clearly, they’re going to &#8212; this &#8212; part of the purpose here is two leaders of countries who have a very, very vital relationship, a close alliance getting to know each other.&nbsp; I think you all know: There is no substitute for that kind of direct engagement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think we got off to a very good start last night at the Samsung plant.&nbsp; I think that their interaction was very positive.&nbsp; And I think that, you know, it went very well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know that the President was quite satisfied and quite impressed.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking forward to more of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think that part of this is obviously getting to understand each other &#8212; I think to understand each other&#8217;s worldviews.&nbsp; I think that the President has &#8212; looks forward to doing that and getting to know President Yoon.</p>



<p>But I think that this is done in the context of tremendous confidence in the Yoon administration’s commitment to the alliance and clarity of their vision on foreign policies issues.&nbsp; And I think that, you know, from our standpoint, this is about building on a very strong foundation, rather than trying to lay any groundwork.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; And thanks so much everybody for joining this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,&#8221; and embargoed until the call concludes, which will be shortly.</p>



<p>Thanks so much for joining.&nbsp; And we, of course, will be in touch throughout the rest of the trip.&nbsp;</p>



<p>9:36 A.M. KST&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces John Kirby as NSC Coordinator for Strategic&#160;Communications</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/20/president-biden-announces-john-kirby-as-nsc-coordinator-for-strategic-communications/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 23:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53760</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden announced that John Kirby, who is currently the Assistant to the Secretary of Defense for Public Affairs, will be the new National Security Council Coordinator for Strategic Communications at the White House. In&#160;this role, Kirby will coordinate interagency efforts to explain United States policy and will serve as a senior administration voice&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden announced that John Kirby, who is currently the Assistant to the Secretary of Defense for Public Affairs, will be the new National Security Council Coordinator for Strategic Communications at the White House. In&nbsp;this role, Kirby will coordinate interagency efforts to explain United States policy and will serve as a senior administration voice on related matters, including as appropriate at the White House podium. This position will be housed at the NSC and report to the National Security Advisor.</p>



<p><strong>Statement from President Biden:</strong></p>



<p>“John Kirby is uniquely qualified for this position, and I look forward to bringing his background, knowledge, and experience to the White House. From his work as the Assistant Secretary and Spokesperson at the State Department to his work at the Pentagon, most recently as Assistant to the Secretary for Public Affairs and Press Secretary, John understands the complexities of U.S. foreign and defense policy, and he will ably represent the Administration on important national security issues.”</p>



<p><strong>Statement from National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan:</strong></p>



<p>“I am proud to welcome John to the team.&nbsp; I’m excited to see him get to work on behalf of the president and the entire national security enterprise.”</p>



<p><strong>Statement from John Kirby:</strong></p>



<p>“I am incredibly honored to be given this opportunity to continue serving my country and this Administration. I am very grateful to President Biden for his confidence in me and to Secretary Austin for his tremendous support and leadership these last 18 months. Secretary Austin has been more than just my boss; he’s been a mentor and a confidante, and he has helped make me a better communicator. He has trusted me to speak for the Department, and he has trusted me to speak for him. Those are precious responsibilities, the weight of which I felt and respected every day. I thank him for that. I also thank my entire team at OSD Public Affairs. When I messed up, they fixed it. When I did well, they made it so. I’ve never known a better team of professionals. I am excited to start this next assignment very soon, but I will surely miss each and every one of them.”</p>



<p><strong>John Kirby, NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications</strong></p>



<p>John Kirby is currently the Assistant to the Secretary of Defense for Public Affairs. In this role, he advises Secretary of Defense Lloyd Austin and Deputy Secretary of Defense Kathleen Hicks and serves as the Department’s chief spokesperson. Kirby previously served at the Department of State, as the Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of Public Affairs from December 2015 to January 2017 and as the State Department’s spokesperson from May 2015 to January 2017. Prior to the State Department, Kirby served as the Pentagon Press Secretary under Secretary of Defense Chuck Hagel.</p>



<p>Kirby commissioned in the U.S. Navy in September 1986 and served in uniform for more than 28 years, before retiring in 2015 at the rank of Rear Admiral. He is a 1985 graduate of the University of South Florida and holds a Master of Science degree in International Relations from Troy State University and a Master of Arts in National Security and Strategic Studies from the Naval War College.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the District Court Ruling on Title 42&#160; </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/20/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-district-court-ruling-on-title-42/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 22:44:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Administration disagrees with the court’s ruling, and the Department of Justice has announced that it will appeal this decision. The authority to set public health policy nationally should rest with the Centers for Disease Control, not with a single district court.&#160; However, in compliance with the court’s injunction, the Biden Administration will continue to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Administration disagrees with the court’s ruling, and the Department of Justice has announced that it will appeal this decision. The authority to set public health policy nationally should rest with the Centers for Disease Control, not with a single district court.&nbsp; However, in compliance with the court’s injunction, the Biden Administration will continue to enforce the CDC’s 2020 Title 42 public health authority pending the appeal.&nbsp; This means that migrants who attempt to enter the United States unlawfully will be subject to &nbsp;expulsion under Title 42, as well as immigration consequences such as removal under Title 8.</p>



<p>As the appeal proceeds, the Department of Homeland Security will continue planning for the eventual lifting of Title 42 in light of CDC’s public health judgment, at which point anyone who attempts to enter the country unlawfully will be subject to Title 8 Expedited Removal proceedings, if they do not have grounds to remain in the United States.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/20/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-16/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53678</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration: Amy L. Solomon, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General, Office of Justice Programs, U.S. Department of Justice Milancy Harris, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Security &#38; Intelligence, U.S. Department of Defense Joey&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announces his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve as key leaders in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Amy L. Solomon, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General, Office of Justice Programs, U.S. Department of Justice</li><li>Milancy Harris, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Security &amp; Intelligence, U.S. Department of Defense</li><li>Joey R. Hood, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Tunisia</li><li>Jonathan Henick, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Uzbekistan</li><li>Richard Glick, Nominee for Member and Chair of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Amy L. Solomon, Nominee for Assistant Attorney General, Office of Justice Programs, U.S. Department of Justice</u></strong></p>



<p>Amy L. Solomon currently serves as Principal Deputy Assistant Attorney General of the U.S. Department of Justice (DOJ) Office of Justice Programs (OJP), overseeing approximately $5 billion annually in grants to support state and local justice efforts. Solomon brings to this role more than three decades of government, think tank, and philanthropy experience and a deep commitment to social justice, racial equity, and improving the criminal justice system.</p>



<p>Before returning to DOJ in 2021, Solomon spent almost four years as Vice President of Criminal Justice at Arnold Ventures where she launched portfolios on corrections reform and expanding economic opportunity for justice-impacted populations. Solomon spent seven years in the Obama-Biden Administration, serving as Director of Policy and Senior Advisor at OJP. Solomon concurrently served as Executive Director of the Federal Interagency Reentry Council, a cabinet-level body responsible for spearheading the federal Ban the Box rule, fair housing guidance, the Second Chance Pell initiative, and Medicaid guidance for the justice-involved population.</p>



<p>Solomon spent 10 years at the Urban Institute, directing projects on prisoner reentry and public safety. She also worked at the National Institute of Justice, managed a community service program, developed reentry strategies for a Department of Correction, and worked with juveniles in probation, halfway houses, and school settings. Solomon holds a Master’s Degree in Public Policy from the Harvard Kennedy School of Government and a Bachelor’s Degree from the University of Michigan.</p>



<p><strong><u>Milancy Harris, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Security &amp; Intelligence, U.S. Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Milancy Harris is currently the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for Irregular Warfare and Counterterrorism at the U.S. Department of Defense. Prior to taking this role, she served on the Intelligence Community Agency Review Team for the Biden-Harris Transition. Harris joined the Intelligence Community in 2004 as an Analyst with the Defense Intelligence Agency. Harris previously served in a variety of analytic and staff roles at the National Counterterrorism Center and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence until 2019. She also served as a Director for Counterterrorism on the National Security Council staff from 2015-2017.&nbsp; Outside of government, her work focused on technology governance issues and content moderation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Originally from Wisconsin, Harris holds a Bachelor’s Degree from Marquette University and a Master’s Degree from The George Washington University.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Joey R. Hood, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Tunisia</u></strong></p>



<p>Joey R. Hood is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor.&nbsp; Hood served as Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of State, Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs, U.S. Department of State, and was the Acting Assistant Secretary of the Bureau from January to September, 2021. Previously, Hood served in leadership positions overseas as the Chargé d’affaires and Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Baghdad, Iraq, the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Kuwait City, Kuwait, and the Principal Officer of the U.S. Consulate General in Dhahran, Saudi Arabia. Hood’s other assignments include service as the Deputy Director and the Acting Director of the Office of Iranian Affairs in the State Department’s Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs, as the Public Affairs Officer of the U.S. Embassy, Doha Qatar, and as the Political-Economic Section Chief of the U.S. Embassy in Sanaa, Yemen.&nbsp; Hood earned a B.A. Degree from Dartmouth College and an M.A. Degree from the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy at Tufts University. Hood speaks French and Arabic.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jonathan Henick, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Uzbekistan</u></strong></p>



<p>Jonathan Henick, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as the U.S. Department of State Chair at the College of Information and Cyberspace at the National Defense University. Previously, he served as the Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau for South and Central Asian Affairs, where he was responsible for the countries of Central Asia, as well as Public Diplomacy and Press for all of South and Central Asia. Earlier, he served as Acting Deputy Coordinator of the Global Engagement Center where he helped to lead and coordinate U.S. efforts to counter disinformation from Russia, China, and Iran. Henick served as the Principal Deputy Coordinator and Acting Coordinator for the Bureau for International Information Programs. His other assignments include serving as the Minister Counselor for Public Affairs in Turkey, the Deputy Chief of Mission in Timor-Leste, as well as in other positions in Azerbaijan, Turkey, Portugal, and Uzbekistan. Henick has worked as a Fellow and Visiting Professor at The George Washington University and as a Diplomat-in-Residence at the East-West Center in Honolulu, Hawaii. He has received the Public Diplomacy Alumni Association Achievement Award.&nbsp; A native of New York, he speaks Russian, Portuguese, Turkish, and Azerbaijani, and holds a Ph.D. in Political Science from the University of Hawaii, a Master’s Degree in International Affairs from Columbia University, and a Bachelor’s Degree from Columbia College, Columbia University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Richard Glick, Nominee for Member and Chair of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Chairman Richard Glick was named by President Biden to be Chairman of the Federal Regulatory Commission on January 21, 2021 and is serving a Commission term that ends June 30, 2022. Glick was nominated to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission by President Donald J. Trump in August 2017 and confirmed by the U.S. Senate on November 2, 2017. Before joining the Commission, he was General Counsel for the Democratic members on the U.S. Senate Energy and Natural Resources Committee, serving as a Senior Policy Advisor on numerous issues including electricity and renewable energy.</p>



<p>Prior to that, he was Vice President of Government Affairs for Iberdrola’s renewable energy, electric and gas utility, and natural gas storage businesses in the United States. Glick previously served as a Director of Government Affairs for PPM Energy and before that was Director of Government Affairs for PacifiCorp. Glick served as a Senior Policy Advisor to U.S. Energy Secretary Bill Richardson, and before that was Legislative Director and Chief Counsel to U.S. Senator Dale Bumpers (D-AR). From 1988-1992, Chairman Glick was an Associate with the law firm of Verner, Liipfert, Bernhard, McPherson and Hand. He is a graduate of The George Washington University and Georgetown Law.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on Record-Low State Unemployment&#160;Rates </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/20/statement-from-president-biden-on-record-low-state-unemployment-rates/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 16:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53670</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Americans across the country are back to work at a historic level. Right now, workers in Alabama, Alaska, Arizona, Georgia, Idaho, Indiana, Kansas, Kentucky, Minnesota, Mississippi, Montana, Nebraska, South Dakota, Tennessee, Utah, West Virginia, and Wisconsin are less likely to be unemployed than in any other time on record.&#160;The unemployment rate did not increase in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Americans across the country are back to work at a historic level. Right now, workers in Alabama, Alaska, Arizona, Georgia, Idaho, Indiana, Kansas, Kentucky, Minnesota, Mississippi, Montana, Nebraska, South Dakota, Tennessee, Utah, West Virginia, and Wisconsin are less likely to be unemployed than in any other time on record.&nbsp;The unemployment rate did not increase in any of our 50 states.</p>



<p>This news comes on the heels of new data showing that the number of Americans who are forced to rely on unemployment insurance programs for their support fell to its lowest level in over 52 years and that the economy has added more than 8 million jobs since I took office – more jobs on average per month than under any other President in history.</p>



<p>​This job creation is no accident – it’s the direct result of my economic plan to rebuild the economy from the bottom up and the middle out through the historic American Rescue Plan and a nationwide vaccination strategy. There is more work to do to build an economy that works for all Americans. Tackling inflation is my top priority. But we cannot lose sight of the fact that millions of workers are now able to better provide for themselves and their families and enjoy the dignity that a good-paying job provides.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
