<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 23:51:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of the Second White House Eviction Prevention Convening</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/21/readout-of-the-second-white-house-eviction-prevention-convening/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 23:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24709</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House hosted a second virtual convening to help cities quickly deliver emergency rental assistance and develop plans to prevent evictions. The convening highlighted actions taken by cities since the first summit on June 30th and is part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s broader efforts to ensure state and local governments disburse the more&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House hosted a second virtual convening to help cities quickly deliver emergency rental assistance and develop plans to prevent evictions. The convening highlighted actions taken by cities since the first summit on June 30<sup>th</sup> and is part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-initiatives-to-promote-housing-stability-by-supporting-vulnerable-tenants-and-preventing-foreclosures/">broader efforts</a> to ensure state and local governments disburse the more than $46 billion dollars in Emergency Rental Assistance (ERA) made available to them to assist households in need. Today, Treasury released <a href="https://home.treasury.gov/news/press-releases/jy0284">new data</a> on the ERA program, which showed that more than $1.5 billion in assistance was delivered to eligible households in the month of June—more than what was provided in the previous three reporting periods combined. The number of households served in June grew by about 85 percent over the previous month and nearly tripled since April.</p>



<p>White House American Rescue Plan Coordinator Gene Sperling opened today’s convening, reaffirming the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to do everything it can to make sure cities and states provide relief to renters and landlords as the CDC’s eviction moratorium comes to an end on July 31st. Sperling stressed that the Administration has provided new flexibilities to get emergency rental assistance out and that this is the time for state and local officials to step up and not hide behind being overly cautious or conservative. Officials from the Department of Treasury then shared best practices and responded to frequently asked questions about the ERA program and updated guidance. Speakers from across the country discussed case studies and best practices on topics such as culturally and linguistically relevant outreach and ways to improve the delivery of rental assistance programs. The convening also featured panels focused on how mayors, judges, and philanthropy can champion local efforts to prevent evictions, as well as strategies for community and landlord engagement.</p>



<p>Today’s convening builds upon the June 30<sup>th</sup> <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/30/readout-of-the-white-house-eviction-prevention-summit/">White House Eviction Prevention Summit</a> which brought together teams from 46 cities to commit to take swift action to prevent evictions in their jurisdictions.</p>



<p>Public officials speaking at the second convening included:</p>



<ul><li>Mayor Tom Barrett, City of Milwaukee</li><li>Mayor Greg Fischer, City of Louisville</li><li>Judge Brendan Murphy, Chief Magistrate, Cobb County (GA)</li><li>Judge Rachel L. Bell, Presiding Judge, General Sessions Court, Division VII, Davidson County (TN)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki Aboard Air Force One En Route Cincinnati, OH</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/21/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-aboard-air-force-one-en-route-cincinnati-oh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 22:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24701</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3:40 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Welcome to our trip to Cincinnati, Ohio &#8212; also known as the birthplace of my husband.&#160; So, a special place in my heart.&#160;A couple of announcements for you at the top:&#160;Today, Treasury released new data on the Emergency Rental Assistance Program, which showed that more than $1.5 billion in assistance was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>3:40 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Welcome to our trip to Cincinnati, Ohio &#8212; also known as the birthplace of my husband.&nbsp; So, a special place in my heart.<br>&nbsp;<br>A couple of announcements for you at the top:<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, Treasury released new data on the Emergency Rental Assistance Program, which showed that more than $1.5 billion in assistance was delivered to eligible households in the month of June &#8212; more than what was provided in the previous three reporting periods combined.&nbsp; The number of households served in June grew by about 85 percent over the previous month and nearly tripled since April.<br>&nbsp;<br>The data demonstrates that the administration has heard from states and localities over the past months that ERA is helping develop a new national infrastructure for rental assistance and eviction prevention that did not previously exist.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that also today, as a part of this effort, the White House is hosting a second virtual convening on eviction prevention with over 2,000 participants from cities and states across the country, including the 46 cities that were the focus of the first summit on January 30th.&nbsp; That is virtual; everyone can tune in.<br>&nbsp;<br>Also, on August 25th, the President and members of his national security team and across the administration will hold a meeting with private sector leaders to discuss how we work together to collectively improve the nation&#8217;s cybersecurity.&nbsp; So that is a continuation of his effort to work in close partnership with the private sector.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, I also wanted to note that, according to a new report from Moody&#8217;s this morning, the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and Build Back Better agenda will add almost 2 million jobs per year, on average, across the whole decade while accelerating America&#8217;s path to full employment and increasing labor force participation.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Moody&#8217;s report also confirms that the &#8212; what the President said on Monday: that these sorts of investments in making our economy more productive will keep prices stable and decrease inflationary pressure.<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, where should we start?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions off the top, on the debt limit.&nbsp; Mitch McConnell said today that Democrats should basically pass a hike in the debt limit on their own; that Republicans would not vote for that.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House response?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And does the White House believe that Democrats should pass a standalone debt limit hike and sort of leave it up to Republicans?&nbsp; Or would you be open to including it in a reconciliation bill, or eliminating the debt limit altogether?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we expect Congress to act in a timely manner to raise or suspend the debt ceiling as they did three times on a broad bipartisan basis during the last administration.<br>&nbsp;<br>As you all know, raising or suspending the debt ceiling does not authorize new spending; it merely allows Treasury to meet obligations that Congresses have already approved.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that Republicans raised the debt ceiling throughout the Trump administration, including after putting exorbitant deficit and debt &#8212; debt-hoaking [sic] tax breaks &#8212; debt-hiking &#8212; sorry &#8212; tax breaks for the wealthiest Americans and big corporations on the country&#8217;s credit card.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what we expect them to do.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;To follow up on a part that Alex just asked about at the end: Would the administration be open to, whether now or in the coming weeks and months, talking about fully eliminating the debt ceiling so that we don&#8217;t have these crises &#8212; crisis moments every so often?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not making a projection of that.&nbsp; We are fully expecting Congress will raise the debt ceiling as they have numerous times over the last couple of years.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you want it to continue to exist?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick question on travel restrictions.&nbsp; The airlines have been lobbying the administration to ease travel restrictions on European travel.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the status of those conversations?&nbsp; Are you moving closer to that point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are ongoing discussions between the working groups and, of course, updates and briefings with our health and medical experts about when it is safe to do that.&nbsp; We will be guided by the science.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have any prediction of what the timeline looks like.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President said a few days ago that he would have something more to say within a few days on the travel restrictions.&nbsp; Can you at least give us a sense of the timing for when you think there may be some easing or loosening?&nbsp; Or is it &#8212; is the upsurge in Delta variants, in cases involving Delta, pushing that off?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He gets regular updates from his COVID team; that&#8217;s what he was referring to.&nbsp; But he is going to be guided by their recommendations on when we should ease travel restrictions, which are based on a range of criteria.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on Nord Stream.&nbsp; So, today there&#8217;s been announcements about an agreement reached with Germany.&nbsp; There were lots of signals about this already last week.&nbsp; There&#8217;s widespread criticism of this among Republican lawmakers who feel that the administration isn&#8217;t actually acting on the laws that they have passed &#8212; that have been passed by Congress.<br>&nbsp;<br>Are you &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; In what way?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because of the waiving of the sanctions.&nbsp; But then there are other sanctions or other laws that haven&#8217;t &#8212; where sanctions haven&#8217;t been fully implemented.&nbsp; Are you concerned that you may be sending a wrong signal to Russia about this pipeline?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say on part of your question: We&#8217;re committed to following the law and continuing to examine entities that have engaged in potentially-sanctioning behavior, as would be abiding by the law.&nbsp; That has not changed.<br>&nbsp;<br>This announcement today follows, of course, the meeting the President had with Chancellor Merkel last week, where they said that they would be asking their teams to look at practical measures we could take together to address what our root issues are here, which we have voiced many times in the past.<br>&nbsp;<br>So even though the pipeline was 90 percent built when the President took office, what our objective is, is to prevent or reduce the geopolitical impact that it was going to have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I know these have been announced; I think a lot of you are following them.&nbsp; But for the purpose of the full context, these measures, in our view, represent a significant impact by Germany, supported by the United States, to push back against the Kremlin&#8217;s harmful activities and to advance a more secure and sustainable energy future for Ukraine and other frontline NATO and EU countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, yes, it was 90 percent built.&nbsp; We feel confident about the impact of these measures.&nbsp; And, of course, we&#8217;ll continue to abide by the law, which includes using sanction authority as needed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say how much U.S. money will flow into this billion-dollar Green Fund for Ukraine energy independence?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a great question, Andrea.&nbsp; Let me &#8212; it&#8217;s really a State Department announcement that we&#8217;re making today.&nbsp; I’ll see if there&#8217;s more details I can get back to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quickly, I have a follow-up on Nord Stream.&nbsp; Is the Zelenskyy visit a part of that deal in terms of, you know, giving them a visit as part of the concessions to Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; No.&nbsp; They&#8217;re unrelated.&nbsp; We have long been in touch with the Ukrainians about scheduling a visit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one other thing on the borders, please.&nbsp; The reports today that DHS has extended the restrictions on the Canadian and the Mexican border: Can you give any explanation as to why, especially given the recent announcement from Canada about vaccinated travelers?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We rely on the health &#8212; the guidance of our health and medical experts, not on the actions of other countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the White House &#8212; is there concern, though, about repercussions about, like, easing restrictions at one border and not the other?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We created these working groups so that we could have an open line of communication about what the criteria looked like, what measures needed to be met.&nbsp; Those are ongoing, and, of course, we are continuing to be briefed internally as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could you say something about infrastructure and, sort of, the progress on the Hill and &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; you know, the Republicans, potentially this group of 10 or 11 lawmakers, supporting a vote next week to move forward on the bill? &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, kind of related to that, on reconciliation: It seems like the Democrats in the Senate are still a far way off from a real agreement on that.&nbsp; Would you be concerned if that gets pushed later into August, into September, and this whole process continues to drag on?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, the President is enormously grateful to the work of Republican senators who have poured so much good work &#8212; and Democratic senators, of course &#8212; and vision into the bipartisan infrastructure deal; is eager to deliver these economic benefits that Americans in red states and blue states have deserved for so long.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we certainly &#8212; we were encouraged to see the comments of Senator Romney this morning, and we understand this is a legislative process, and it&#8217;s ongoing.<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the reconciliation process, of course, we&#8217;re working in close coordination with Leader Schumer.&nbsp; We are grateful to his efforts.&nbsp; He has conveyed his interest in moving this forward in July, and we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re looking forward to supporting that effort.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the infrastructure, what &#8212; to the Republicans&#8217; criticism about the shell bill vote that&#8217;s being held today: Essentially, what is the harm in waiting until Monday, like the GOP negotiators on the Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework wish to do?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first note that this is just a vote on a motion to proceed, so a motion to debate.&nbsp; This is not a vote on a final package.&nbsp; And this is the same procedure that the Senate used as it related to the AAPI Hate Crimes bill and as it related to a number of pieces of legislation already this Congress.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it is par for the course and normal operations up there on the Senate side.&nbsp; This is merely a motion to proceed, and certainly we were encouraged, again, by Senator Romney&#8217;s comments this morning.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And sticking with some Congress news here, the select committee for January 6: The White House statement that was released just before we took off &#8212; among the things that was listed in this statement was that they&#8217;re confident in Speaker Pelosi&#8217;s ability to proceed with an investigation that is full, investigative, and transparent.&nbsp; The word &#8220;bipartisan&#8221; was not included in there.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering, is the White House disappointed that Speaker Pelosi&#8217;s investigation, as it will proceed, will be technically bipartisan because of Liz Cheney&#8217;s involvement, but not truly bipartisan?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First, we stated at the time our disappointment that there wasn&#8217;t bipartisan support for a select committee when there was an opportunity to vote for that.&nbsp; And we also have long stated our support for Speaker Pelosi in getting to the bottom of what happened on January 6 &#8212; a dark day in our democracy &#8212; and we support her efforts for moving forward on that initiative.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, Jen, are you concerned that no matter what product comes from Speaker Pelosi&#8217;s investigation or Leader McCarthy&#8217;s separate investigation &#8212; that no matter what comes of it, the result is always going to be perceived as partisan, based on what happened today?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think many Americans across the country, regardless of their political affiliation, look at the events of January 6 as a dark day in our democracy.&nbsp; The President strongly supports taking steps to get to the bottom of what happened so we can prevent it from happening in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, on the visit to Ohio today, the White House put out a comprehensive list of what it says it&#8217;s going to be doing for the people of Ohio, but notable in the absence in that list was anything about fentanyl, the opioid epidemic.&nbsp; Has that been deprioritized?&nbsp; Where &#8212; is it still a priority?&nbsp; And what do you say to the people of Ohio and the country with &#8212; there&#8217;s still a plateau and tens of thousands of people dying?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely, it&#8217;s a top priority, and there&#8217;s no question it is an issue that has impacted people across Ohio and continues to.&nbsp; Any health expert will tell you that the most important thing we could do is make sure people have access to healthcare coverage.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the President has taken a number of steps to ensure more people have access to, including opening up the Special Enrollment Period, including pushing for tax cuts to incentivize more people to get access to healthcare.&nbsp; That is the best way, but certainly this remains a priority and will continue to be and he may even talk about it today in the town hall.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see what questions come up.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Another question on behalf of the radio pool: Are you encouraged by the shift in messaging by Republicans and Fox News now overtly talking positively about vaccines?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to designate it around one individual or one network or one social media platform.&nbsp; I will say that our view is that we are at war with the virus; we are not at war with a social media platform or with a network.&nbsp; And so anyone who goes out there and shares accurate information about the effectiveness of the vaccine, about the fact that it can save lives, is a positive step in our view, and hopefully it continues.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I ask you another question on inflation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The signs seem to be &#8212; there was a &#8212; there was a hope, I think, that the prices would peak over the summer months.&nbsp; Now it looks like that may continue and slip into the fall.&nbsp; Are you concerned by this sort of sustained, you know, increase in prices and this sort of &#8212; like the fact that it&#8217;s not coming down, or there are no indications yet?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we take inflation very seriously.&nbsp; Obviously, it&#8217;s the purview of the Federal Reserve, and I would point you to their projections about inflation coming down in 2022.&nbsp; That&#8217;s also in line with a number of outside economists.&nbsp; But we do take it incredibly seriously.<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note that there are a number of impacts, including the economy turning back on; steps that we&#8217;re taking in addition to getting more money in the hands of the American people, including the Child Tax Credit that just started going out a few weeks ago, to make sure they have extra assistance in this time, even as we&#8217;re seeing prices go back up, some to pre-pandemic levels.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also working to get important initiatives across the finish line.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would, again, return to where I started, which was the Moody&#8217;s analysis that conveyed that this would help address inflation in the future by providing more supply out there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A COVID question, Jen.&nbsp; If Axios hadn’t learned about the positive case at the White House, would the White House have informed the public about it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me give you a little bit of an update here.&nbsp; One moment.&nbsp; I just want to do this completely accurately.&nbsp; Sorry.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And sort of related to that, just &#8212; you know, is &#8212; are there any discussions happening within the White House about potentially, you know, direct- &#8212; or encouraging, if not requiring, mask wearing again on the White House grounds or anything like that?&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen &#8212; I think people are, on the Hill and at the White House, are wearing masks a little bit more today than they might have been a week ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say on that: We abide by public health guidance by the CDC.&nbsp; The CDC guidelines currently are: If you are vaccinated, you do not need to wear a mask.&nbsp; If you are not vaccinated, you should wear a mask.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the guidelines we continue to give to members of the White House staff.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now, if individuals decide to wear masks for whatever reason, we support that, and that&#8217;s their personal choice &#8212; and individuals do for a variety of reasons.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let me just give you a little bit of an update to some of the questions that were asked yesterday.&nbsp; There are approximately 2,000 people on the White House campus each day.&nbsp; So, statistically speaking, COVID cases among vaccinated people will occur, just like they occur across the country.&nbsp; They have occurred; they will continue to occur.&nbsp; We&#8217;re prepared for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as the instance yesterday shows, cases in vaccinated individuals are typically mild or asymptomatic.&nbsp; There&#8217;s &#8212; this is more &#8212; this is one more reminder of the efficacy of the COVID-19 vaccines against severe illness or hospitalization.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because of our commitment to transparency, what we&#8217;re going to be providing are up- &#8212; moving forward &#8212; are updates on any White House official who tests positive for COVID-19 that the White House medical unit deems as having had close contact with the President, Vice President, First Lady, or Second Gentleman.&nbsp; That will up to &#8212; be up to the White House medical unit, based on the criteria of the CDC.&nbsp; And this criteria, again, is up to the CDC.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At no point has the President been required to change his behavior or self-quarantine due to a close contact with an individual who tested positive for COVID.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that, today, an email from our COVID-19 operations protocol team has been sent to White House staff informing them of the official policy that if you are in close contact with a principal and test positive for COVID-19, your case will be disclosed to press, along with any other relevant details, and that we will share the name of the staffer if that individual agrees to do so.&nbsp; Of course, we respect their privacy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, that is our policy moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask one follow-up on that?&nbsp; For July 4th, anyone coming to the White House lawn who was not vaccinated was asked to wear a mask.&nbsp; Should we take that policy to mean that the athletes who were unmasked at the White House yesterday were all vaccinated?&nbsp; Was that confirmed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The policy that we continue to convey with public events is the CDC policy: If you are vaccinated, you don&#8217;t need to wear a mask.&nbsp; If you are not vaccinated, you should wear a mask.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that the same for outdoors, though?&nbsp; You&#8217;re saying, outdoors, if you are unvaccinated, you need to be wearing a mask if you&#8217;re at the White House?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It is &#8212; we &#8212; our guidelines are not different from what CDC guidelines are.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What guidance is the First Lady following as she heads to Tokyo for the Olympics?&nbsp; And is there still confidence that she&#8217;ll be kept safe, as we&#8217;re seeing some breakout infections?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah &#8212; so, I would say: One, we have consulted. &nbsp;The First Lady is on her way &#8212; proceeding to Tokyo &#8212; and that has been done in consultation with, of course, our White House medical unit, with staff about what protocols she and the delegation should abide by.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that while she is leading this delegation &#8212; because it was important to the President and the First Lady that we cheer on our athletes and show support for the United States at the highest level &#8212; it is a delegation of two, and usually it is a much larger delegation.&nbsp; They will have limited public interaction, and they will be taking every precaution throughout the course of their trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say another word about this cybersecurity meeting that you&#8217;re hosting &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; or that the President will host on August 25th?&nbsp; Can you say what private-sector leaders are going to be participating, and whether &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re not quite there yet.&nbsp; Yeah,<br>I mean, it&#8217;s more than a month away.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I understand.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you &#8212; you know, you&#8217;ve had a focal point on ransomware.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You&#8217;ve been having regular meetings on ransomware.&nbsp; Is that going to be a big focus for that meeting &#8212; ransomware?&nbsp; Or is it, you know, cybersecurity writ large?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re not quite there on the agenda for the meeting.&nbsp; What I would note is that the President felt it was important to use the White House as a forum for bringing together private sector leaders to have a discussion about both how we can work together and also what best practices are, which is including them taking &#8212; hardening their own cybersecurity protections and also what the U.S. government can do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, as you know, there have been ongoing considerations, from a policy perspective, of what we can stake [sic] &#8212; take &#8212; what steps we can take.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you also know from covering this closely, ransomware attacks have increased over the last 18 months.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no question it&#8217;s a big issue and factor for private sector companies.&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s no question it will be a part of the agenda at this meeting, but in terms of what the day looks like, we&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the Milwaukee Bucks come to the White House?&nbsp; Has the President invited them?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He did tweet about them today &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, I saw (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; congratulating them.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we will invite them to the White House.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a scheduled meeting quite yet.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;re celebrating on their own today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About Iraq, if I may: When the Prime Minister comes to the White House, should we expect announcements regarding U.S. troops or maybe a timeline, anything?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ah- &#8212; quite ahead of the meeting.&nbsp; Obviously, it&#8217;s an important meeting to discuss our relationship with Iraq and with the Prime Minister, and certainly our presence on the ground and their role moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the State Department officials who were briefing earlier on the Nord Stream deal made the point that getting this issue off the table with Ukraine will allow a broader discussion of security issues with Ukraine.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a lot of interest, of course, in terms of supporting Ukraine vis-à-vis Russia and its aggression.&nbsp; Are you &#8212; are there any new initiatives that you can talk about in terms of bolstering Ukraine security or the security of the Eastern Flank allies?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there&#8217;s a couple of things that were in the package that, I think, will benefit Ukraine, so let me highlight some of those.&nbsp; Germany will help to preserve gas transit revenues for Ukraine and buy time for Ukraine to eliminate its dependence on Russian gas and transit fees, as it has long sought to do, including with U.S. support.&nbsp; Germany will do this by committing to appoint a special envoy to use all its available leverage to negotiate an extension to Ukraine&#8217;s gas transit agreement with Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s no question that the impact, in what we&#8217;re trying to address here, is the impact on the Eastern Flank countries of this pipeline.&nbsp; And so that is part of our effort as we, you know, work to finalize the deal announced today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I mean, the President of Ukraine will be coming here to visit with the President &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; at the White House.&nbsp; What &#8212; you know, what is your vision at this point &#8212; I realize it&#8217;s still a month off &#8212; but for that meeting?&nbsp; I mean, what do you hope to get out of that meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re in a position to preview it quite yet.&nbsp; We will, as I &#8212; as we get closer to the meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should the Ukrainians feel a little disappointed about the Nord Stream final decision going through? &nbsp;And they’ve been kind of bracing for it since May, when the U.S. said they would waive sanctions.&nbsp; But given the announcement today of Volodymyr Zelenskyy&#8217;s visit later, based on the decision that&#8217;s coming, do they have a right to feel a little disappointed?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think, again, part of the objective here, as the President said last week, was to work to address the geopolitical impact of this pipeline &#8212; a pipeline that was 90 percent built when the President took office.&nbsp; And Ukraine and the impact on their energy security is certainly part of that, and there are initiatives in this that help to address that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just something quickly on &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the statement that came in from the bipartisan group of lawmakers working on the infrastructure deal: They say that they&#8217;ve made significant progress and are close to a final agreement.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you were aware of that before you came back here, or if there&#8217;s anything else, sort of, on the progress here beyond what you said before.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That certainly is a positive sign.&nbsp; I will check more on that and see if there&#8217;s more to report from our end.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve been encouraged and grateful &#8212; encouraged by the progress and grateful to the work of both the Democrats and Republicans involved.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there going to be ice cream in Cincinnati?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Graeter&#8217;s ice cream?&nbsp; Raspberry chip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don’t think so, but we&#8217;ll have to &#8212; I don’t know.<br>&nbsp;<br>(Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now I really want &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;s aware of it.<br>&nbsp;<br>4:03 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>White House Releases Policy for Contacts with Agencies and Departments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/21/white-house-releases-policy-for-contacts-with-agencies-and-departments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 22:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House sent the Senate and House Judiciary Committees our policy on contacts between the White House and agencies and departments, and the Department of Justice formally updated their policy on contacts with the White House. These policies reaffirm President Biden’s commitment to restoring faith in institutions of government and the independent role of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House sent the Senate and House Judiciary Committees our policy on contacts between the White House and agencies and departments, and the Department of Justice formally updated their policy on contacts with the White House. These policies reaffirm President Biden’s commitment to restoring faith in institutions of government and the independent role of the Department of Justice in law enforcement matters.</p>



<p>Read the White House’s policy here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/White-House-Policy-for-Contacts-with-Agencies-and-Departments.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/White-House-Policy-for-Contacts-with-Agencies-and-Departments.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Amends Ponca Tribe of Nebraska Disaster Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/21/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-amends-ponca-tribe-of-nebraska-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 20:28:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the Ponca Tribe of Nebraska by authorizing an increase in the level of federal funding for Public Assistance projects undertaken as a result of severe storms and flooding during the period of March 13 to April 1, 2019 Under the major disaster declaration&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the Ponca Tribe of Nebraska by authorizing an increase in the level of federal funding for Public Assistance projects undertaken as a result of severe storms and flooding during the period of March 13 to April 1, 2019</p>



<p>Under the major disaster declaration issued for the Ponca Tribe of Nebraska on June 17, 2019, federal funding was made available for Public Assistance and Hazard Mitigation at 75 percent of the total eligible costs.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under the President&#8217;s order today, the federal share for Public Assistance has been increased to 90 percent of the total eligible costs.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Four Key Foreign Policy Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/21/president-biden-announces-four-key-foreign-policy-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 20:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24665</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following four individuals to serve in key roles promoting U.S. foreign policy: John R. Bass, Nominee for Under Secretary of State (Management) David L. Cohen, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Canada Jamie L. Harpootlian, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following four individuals to serve in key roles promoting U.S. foreign policy:</p>



<ul><li>John R. Bass, Nominee for Under Secretary of State (Management)</li><li>David L. Cohen, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Canada</li><li>Jamie L. Harpootlian, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Slovenia</li><li>Victoria Reggie Kennedy, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Austria</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>John R. Bass, Nominee for Under Secretary of State for Management</u></strong></p>



<p>John R. Bass, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister, currently is a Senior Advisor at the Department of State’s Foreign Service Institute. He has served as Ambassador to the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan, Ambassador to the Republic of Turkey, and Ambassador to the Republic of Georgia.&nbsp; Previously, Bass focused, among other things, on supporting U.S. government efforts to mobilize allies and marshal resources to combat terrorism and instability in Iraq, Syria and Southwest Asia.&nbsp; He served at seven U.S. Missions overseas including as Team Leader of Provincial Reconstruction Team &#8211; Baghdad at the American Embassy in Baghdad, Iraq.&nbsp; In addition, he was the Executive Secretary of the State Department and held other senior leadership positions at the Department of State.&nbsp; Bass earned an A.B. Cum Laude from Syracuse University.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>David L. Cohen, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Canada</u></strong></p>



<p>David L. Cohen is Senior Advisor to the CEO at Comcast Corporation, having previously served as Senior Executive Vice President where he led a broad portfolio of responsibilities, including corporate communications, legal affairs, government and regulatory affairs, public affairs, corporate administration, corporate real estate and security, and community impact.&nbsp; Cohen also served as the company’s first Chief Diversity Officer.&nbsp; Before coming to Comcast, Cohen served as a partner in and Chairman of Ballard Spahr Andrews &amp; Ingersoll, LLP.&nbsp; Before that, Cohen served as Chief of Staff to the Honorable Edward G. Rendell, the Mayor of the City of Philadelphia.&nbsp; Cohen serves on many nonprofit boards, including as a member of the Trustee Board and the Executive Committee of Penn Medicine, the Board of Directors and the Executive Committee of the Greater Philadelphia Chamber of Commerce, and the national board of the National Urban League. Additionally, he is Chair of the national board of City Year and its Executive Committee.&nbsp; Cohen has received numerous awards for his civic and charitable activities.&nbsp; He was awarded Honorary Doctor of Laws degrees from Drexel University. Rider University, Rowan University, and Rohrer College of Business.&nbsp; Cohen graduated from Swarthmore College with a BA and with a JD from the University of Pennsylvania Law School summa cum laude.</p>



<p><strong><u>Jamie L. Harpootlian, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Slovenia</u></strong></p>



<p>Jamie Harpootlian, an accomplished attorney, is currently counsel to the law firm of Richard A. Harpootlian, P.A., where she advises on a broad range of federal litigation matters. Previously, Harpootlian served as a court-appointed Special Master to facilitate case resolution in complex, mass disaster class actions. The Department of Justice, Civil Division appointed Harpootlian to serve as a Hearing Officer on the 9/11 Victim Compensation Fund of 2001 on behalf of the Special Master Kenneth Feinberg. Prior to her appointments, Harpootlian served 17 years as a career judicial law clerk in the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Louisiana, New Orleans, where she provided legal advice to the Court to assist in making decisions in civil and criminal actions. Harpootlian also is a leader and patron of non-profit groups supporting the environment, the arts, and historic resources.&nbsp; Harpootlian earned a B.A. in Political Science and Art History from Mary Baldwin University, Staunton, Virginia in 1981 and a J.D. from Tulane University Law School, New Orleans, Louisiana in 1984.</p>



<p><strong><u>Victoria Reggie Kennedy, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Austria</u></strong></p>



<p>Victoria Reggie Kennedy is Senior Counsel in the corporate and securities practice group at Greenberg Traurig LLP, in Boston, Massachusetts and Washington, D.C.&nbsp; She also is the president of the board and co-founder of the Edward M. Kennedy Institute for the United States Senate, a non-partisan non-profit that educates the public about the U.S. Senate, and inspires leadership and active citizenship.&nbsp;&nbsp; She earned a B.A., magna cum laude, Phi Beta Kappa, at Newcomb College and a J.D., summa cum laude, from Tulane University School of Law, and then clerked for Hon. Robert A. Sprecher, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit in Chicago.&nbsp; She is the recipient of eight honorary degrees and numerous civic awards, including the Boston Business Journal Power 50 List, the Ellis Island Medal of Honor and the Greater Boston Chamber of Commerce Pinnacle Award for Lifetime Achievement.&nbsp; She chairs the Education Committee of the Board of Trustees of the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts in Washington, D.C. and is on the Board of other non-profit and civic organizations. An advocate for gun safety, Kennedy was a long-time member of the Board of Trustees of the Brady Center to Prevent Gun Violence in Washington, D.C., and has served on the board of Stop Handgun Violence in Boston.&nbsp; She founded an advocacy group, Common Sense about Kids and Guns, aimed at reducing guns deaths and injuries to children.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives on Fiscal Year 2022 Budget Amendments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/21/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-on-fiscal-year-2022-budget-amendments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:57:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24653</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: I ask the Congress to consider the enclosed Fiscal Year (FY) 2022 Budget amendments for the Departments of Agriculture, Defense, Education, Health and Human Services, Homeland Security, Housing and Urban Development, Justice, Labor, and State, and for the District of Columbia and the United States Agency for International Development.  These amendments are necessary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker:</p>



<p>I ask the Congress to consider the enclosed Fiscal Year (FY) 2022 Budget amendments for the Departments of Agriculture, Defense, Education, Health and Human Services, Homeland Security, Housing and Urban Development, Justice, Labor, and State, and for the District of Columbia and the United States Agency for International Development.  These amendments are necessary to correctly reflect policies assumed in my FY 2022 Budget.  The net discretionary budget authority in my FY 2022 Budget would increase by $5 million as a result of these technical corrections.<br><br>The details of these amendments are set forth in the enclosed letter from the Acting Director of the Office of Management and Budget.<br><br>                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely,<br><br>                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White House Press Secretary Jen Psaki on the Visit of President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/21/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-visit-of-president-volodymyr-zelenskyy-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 16:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden looks forward to welcoming President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine to the White House on August 30, 2021. The visit will affirm the United States’ unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russia’s ongoing aggression in the Donbas and Crimea, our close cooperation on energy security, and our backing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden looks forward to welcoming President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine to the White House on August 30, 2021. The visit will affirm the United States’ unwavering support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity in the face of Russia’s ongoing aggression in the Donbas and Crimea, our close cooperation on energy security, and our backing for President Zelenskyy’s efforts to tackle corruption and implement a reform agenda based on our shared democratic values.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister &#038; Foreign Minister Mohammed Bin Abdulrahman Al Thani</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/20/readout-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-qatari-deputy-prime-minister-foreign-minister-mohammed-bin-abdulrahman-al-thani/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 23:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister &#38; Foreign Minister Mohammed Bin Abdulrahman Al Thani to reaffirm the importance of the strategic partnership between the United States and Qatar. They discussed regional developments, including support for humanitarian efforts in Gaza and advancing the Afghanistan peace process. The two leaders agreed to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Qatari Deputy Prime Minister &amp; Foreign Minister Mohammed Bin Abdulrahman Al Thani to reaffirm the importance of the strategic partnership between the United States and Qatar. They discussed regional developments, including support for humanitarian efforts in Gaza and advancing the Afghanistan peace process. The two leaders agreed to stay in touch on the range of issues on which the United States and Qatar are cooperating.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before Cabinet Meeting to Mark Six Months in Office</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/20/remarks-by-president-biden-before-cabinet-meeting-to-mark-six-months-in-office/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 22:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24609</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cabinet Room 3:31 P.M. EDT&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, look, today &#8212; today’s Cabinet meeting, I want to give a brief progress report as to where I think we are and the job you&#8217;re doing in the first six months.&#160;First, the pandemic.&#160; I know folks are watching the number of cases rising again and wondering, quite frankly,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cabinet Room</p>



<p>3:31 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, look, today &#8212; today’s Cabinet meeting, I want to give a brief progress report as to where I think we are and the job you&#8217;re doing in the first six months.<br>&nbsp;<br>First, the pandemic.&nbsp; I know folks are watching the number of cases rising again and wondering, quite frankly, what it means to them.&nbsp; But overall &#8212; overall, COVID-19 deaths are down dramatically &#8212; dramatically.&nbsp; And these last six months, about 90 percent down due to our vaccination program.&nbsp; And I want to thank you all for the great job you did in getting that done.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we have to stay vigilant, especially with the Delta variant that’s out there.&nbsp; While COVID-19 cases are rising, virtually all of the COVID death &#8212; virtually all of the COVID deaths and hospitalizations are from unvaccinated people.&nbsp; Let me say it again: Virtually all are from unvaccinated people.<br>&nbsp;<br>And that means the safest thing to do is to get vaccinated &#8212; get vaccinated.&nbsp; And that’s why we’re focusing, on our next phase, on getting the unvaccinated vaccinated.&nbsp; I know it seems like a constant uphill climb, but it’s gradually &#8212; we’re making progress, but we&#8217;ve got a way to go yet.<br>&nbsp;<br>Secondly, the economy.&nbsp; Yesterday &#8212; that I spoke of the historic economic progress we&#8217;ve made, which starts with the American Rescue Plan: shots in arms that saved a lot of lives; checks and tax cuts to give them just a little extra breathing room &#8212; ordinary Americans; and &#8212; and lower healthcare costs, just when so many Americans needed that help.&nbsp; And it’s helped create 3 million &#8212; 3 million jobs &#8212; more than any administration has done in the first six months of being in office &#8212; again, thanks to all of you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And with our Bipartisan Infrastructure Framework and our Build Back Better plan, I think we can turn this &#8212; this great movement into a economic boom for some time to come.&nbsp; And I really mean that.&nbsp; I think we’re in a cusp &#8212; not only getting us out of the hole, but setting us on a &#8212; on a path that’s going to generate significant continued economic growth.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the American people are overwhelmingly supportive of our plans &#8212; that&#8217;s support that a lot of our friends and the other team kind of miss.&nbsp; The polling data shows that they strongly support &#8212; strongly support our effort for infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think they&#8217;re a little tired of Infrastructure Week for four years in a row.&nbsp; I think we’re on the verge of me being able to get something really done &#8212; rebuilding roads and bridges; replacing lead water pipes; delivering high-speed Internet to every American &#8212; rural and inner-city; and taking on the climate crisis with &#8212; with American jobs.<br>&nbsp;<br>And they want us to build back &#8212; to build back better.&nbsp; They don’t know the name necessarily, but they know that they support universal pre-K and two years of community college; paid leave and childcare, which is essentially a significant tax cut for working-class families; and allowing Medicare to negotiate lower drug costs, which will significantly reduce drug prices across the board for people.<br>&nbsp;<br>And they support asking the wealthiest 1 percent of Americans and corporate America not to pay more than they should; just begin to pay their fair share, just step up a little bit.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The idea that 50 of the largest corporations in America pay no tax, it’s &#8212; I &#8212; I think people should be able to be millionaires and billionaires if they have the ideas, but, Lord’s sake, the idea &#8212; let’s start paying your fair share.<br>&nbsp;<br>And third thing is, there are &#8212; and, by the way, there’s overwhelming evidence, in the polling data, they support what we’re doing &#8212; is how to pay for these programs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thirdly, restoring American leadership in the world.&nbsp; I know you all have &#8212; those of you who’ve travelled around the world &#8212; I know our Ambassador to the United Nations knows it full well &#8212; that America has &#8212; is really behind the eight-ball the last four years.&nbsp; We’ve lost a lot of our standing.&nbsp; I don’t have to tell that to my buddy sitting to my right here &#8212; the Secretary of State.&nbsp; He understands it well.<br>&nbsp;<br>And as I’ve said before, we are &#8212; we are defining &#8212; in a defining competition right now for the 21st century &#8212; for the second quarter of the 21st century &#8212; with China and many other nations.&nbsp; And many of these nations believe that autocracy is the future; that democracies cannot compete with autocracies because it’s so hard &#8212; things are moving so rapidly, technologically and otherwise, that democracies can’t get the act together enough to get a consensus on how to move.<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, I reject that most &#8212; notion completely, and I think the vast majority of American people do as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, in my conversations and meetings with world leaders &#8212; just coming back from, I guess, about eight, nine days over there, ending with a &#8212; a meeting with Putin &#8212; you know, I’m making it absolutely clear that democracy is more capable &#8212; more capable, and America is back, whether it’s helping vaccinate the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we’re not just vaccinating ourselves.&nbsp; We’re going to do &#8212; we’re going to vac- &#8212; help vaccinate the world.&nbsp; We’re building back better to create jobs and grow the middle class not just at home, everywhere.&nbsp; It&#8217;s in our interests the economic &#8212; the economies of these other nations grow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;re going to lead the fight against the climate crisis and tackling &#8212; tackling the challenges of cybersecurity.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been very clear to our &#8212; our &#8212; other nations as to what we expect in terms of their conduct.<br>&nbsp;<br>And finally, there&#8217;s much more to be done and so much more to do &#8212; tackling voting rights, which is an existential threat to democracy right now.&nbsp; The things that are being asked are just beyond the pale.&nbsp; And the Vice President has been working hard on this issue and is going to continue to &#8212; we all are &#8212; but there&#8217;s much more to do.&nbsp; We have to tackle the immigration problem, which we&#8217;re working really hard to get done in a humane and serious way.&nbsp; Police reform and crime.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the bottom line is: We&#8217;re delivering on our promises.&nbsp; We have to deliver on all of the promises we made.&nbsp; Because I think we&#8217;re in a situation where the vast majority of the public agrees with the essence of what we&#8217;re trying to do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, I just think that we&#8217;re showing there&#8217;s nothing that America is unable to do when we do it together.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, you know, I think it&#8217;s time for us to &#8212; to stop now so we can get started with our meeting.&nbsp; So, are you ready, folks, to go to work?<br>&nbsp;<br>PARTICIPANTS:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, quickly: Do you think vac- &#8212; do you think vaccinated people should start wearing masks?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Guys, we’re &#8212; we’re going to work now.&nbsp; We’re &#8212; we’ll have plenty of time to (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>3:38 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Opposition Leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/20/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-opposition-leader-svyatlana-tsikhanouskaya-of-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 22:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus. Mr. Sullivan conveyed American support for the people of Belarus and respect for the courage and determination of the opposition, including Mrs. Tsikhanouskaya, in the struggle for democracy and human rights.  The United States, together with partners and allies, will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus. Mr. Sullivan conveyed American support for the people of Belarus and respect for the courage and determination of the opposition, including Mrs. Tsikhanouskaya, in the struggle for democracy and human rights.  The United States, together with partners and allies, will continue to hold the Lukashenka regime accountable for its actions, including through the imposition of sanctions.  Mr. Sullivan reiterated the Biden Administration’s demand that the Lukashenka regime allow a credible international investigation into the events of May 23, immediately release all political prisoners, and enter into a comprehensive and genuine political dialogue with the leaders of the democratic opposition and civil society groups that leads to the conduct of free and fair Presidential elections under OSCE observation.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
