<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 22:02:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Incoming Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal&#160;Hulata</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-incoming-israeli-national-security-advisor-dr-eyal-hulata/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 22:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with incoming Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata.&#160; Mr. Sullivan congratulated Dr. Hulata on his new role and emphasized that he looks forward to working together to strengthen all aspects of the U.S.-Israel partnership.&#160; Mr. Sullivan and Dr. Hulata discussed the strategic challenges in the region, including&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with incoming Israeli National Security Advisor Dr. Eyal Hulata.&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan congratulated Dr. Hulata on his new role and emphasized that he looks forward to working together to strengthen all aspects of the U.S.-Israel partnership.&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan and Dr. Hulata discussed the strategic challenges in the region, including the threat posed by Iran, and agreed to consult closely on these issues.&nbsp; They also exchanged views about the opportunities in the region, including advancing the normalization of relations between Israel and countries in the Arab and Muslim world and recent positive developments in Israel’s relationship with Jordan.&nbsp; Mr. Sullivan also stressed the importance of pursuing positive steps related to the Palestinians, which are critical to peace, security and prosperity. &nbsp;They discussed the upcoming visit to Washington by Israeli Prime Minister Bennett, and Mr. Sullivan conveyed that President Biden looks forward to warmly welcoming Prime Minister Bennett to the White House soon.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-29/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 21:23:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25757</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Jonathan Eric Kaplan, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Singapore. &#160; &#160; &#160;Francisco O. Mora, of Florida, to be Permanent Representative of the United States of America to the Organization of American States, with the rank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Jonathan Eric Kaplan, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Singapore.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Francisco O. Mora, of Florida, to be Permanent Representative of the United States of America to the Organization of American States, with the rank of Ambassador, vice Carlos Trujillo.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Amy Elizabeth Searight, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Jonathan Nicholas Stivers.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi of&#160;Indonesia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-foreign-minister-retno-marsudi-of-indonesia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 21:03:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25751</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi of Indonesia in Washington, D.C. to discuss opportunities to deepen the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership. Mr. Sullivan informed Foreign Minister Marsudi that the United States will provide an additional $30 million in COVID-19 assistance to Indonesia, bringing the total U.S. assistance to Indonesia since&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Foreign Minister Retno Marsudi of Indonesia in Washington, D.C. to discuss opportunities to deepen the U.S.-Indonesia Strategic Partnership. Mr. Sullivan informed Foreign Minister Marsudi that the United States will provide an additional $30 million in COVID-19 assistance to Indonesia, bringing the total U.S. assistance to Indonesia since the start of the pandemic to more than $65 million.</p>



<p>Mr. Sullivan underscored the United States’ enduring commitment to Southeast Asia and reiterated our support for ASEAN centrality and ASEAN’s essential role in the Indo-Pacific’s regional architecture. He noted we will continue high-level engagement with Indonesia and the region as part of our efforts to promote a free and open Indo-Pacific. They also discussed a range of bilateral and regional issues including the climate crisis and the importance of freedom of the seas and adherence to UNCLOS principles in the South China Sea. They shared deep concerns regarding the crisis in Burma and recommitted to promoting a swift return to democracy.</p>



<p>On COVID-19, they discussed the surge of cases in Indonesia and Mr. Sullivan underscored that his thoughts are with all those affected and that the United States will continue to stand shoulder-to-shoulder with the Indonesian people and support them as they battle the pandemic. He noted that the new $30 million in U.S. assistance will support additional oxygen and medical supplies to treat COVID-19 patients and enhance Indonesia’s ability to get shots into arms by supporting cold chain vaccine distribution, facilities readiness, and other measures. They discussed U.S. efforts to serve as an arsenal of vaccines for the world and our singular focus on saving lives, and they welcomed the August 1 arrival of an additional 3.5 million U.S.-donated Moderna vaccine doses to Indonesia through COVAX, bringing the total to 8 million doses donated by the United States to Indonesia thus far. They also discussed the Defense Department’s donation of PPE to the Indonesian armed forces for distribution to the civilian medical system as part of the ongoing Garuda Shield exercise. Finally, they discussed Indonesia’s continued leadership in advancing global health security and agreed on the need to create sustainable global health partnerships to prepare for future biological threats.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on Senior Administration Official Travel to Brazil and&#160;Argentina</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-senior-administration-official-travel-to-brazil-and-argentina/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 20:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan will&#160;travel to&#160;Brazil and Argentina, joined by&#160;National Security Council Senior Director for Western Hemisphere Juan Gonzalez, Senior Director for Technology and National Security Tarun Chhabra, Senior Director for Cyber Amit Mital, and Department of State Senior Bureau Official for Western Hemisphere Ricardo Zuniga. &#160;In his first trip to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan will&nbsp;travel to&nbsp;Brazil and Argentina, joined by&nbsp;National Security Council Senior Director for Western Hemisphere Juan Gonzalez, Senior Director for Technology and National Security Tarun Chhabra, Senior Director for Cyber Amit Mital, and Department of State Senior Bureau Official for Western Hemisphere Ricardo Zuniga. &nbsp;In his first trip to the region, Mr. Sullivan will meet with leaders of the Major Non-NATO allies in the Americas. While in Brazil, the delegation will meet with leaders to discuss opportunities to&nbsp;strengthen the U.S.-Brazil strategic partnership, enhance regional stability, advance climate objectives, collaborate on digital infrastructure,&nbsp;and help forge a path on COVID-19 pandemic recovery.&nbsp;In Argentina, they will discuss&nbsp;increasing strategic ties on bilateral and regional priorities, including pandemic recovery,&nbsp;the regional climate summit, and shared economic growth and security in our hemisphere and around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Eviction Prevention&#160;Efforts</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-eviction-prevention-efforts/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 18:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25707</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden is taking further action to prevent Americans from experiencing the heartbreak of eviction. Thanks to State eviction moratoria, almost 33% of the country will be spared evictions for the rest of this month. But in the remaining States, action is needed. Thanks to the bipartisan COVID relief act Congress passed in December&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden is taking further action to prevent Americans from experiencing the heartbreak of eviction. Thanks to State eviction moratoria, almost 33% of the country will be spared evictions for the rest of this month. But in the remaining States, action is needed.</p>



<p>Thanks to the bipartisan COVID relief act Congress passed in December 2020 and the American Rescue Plan Congress and the Biden Administration enacted in March 2021, State and local governments long ago received Emergency Rental Assistance—a $46.5 billion plan to protect millions of Americans facing deep rental debt and potential eviction during the pandemic. Some cities and States have demonstrated their ability to release these funds efficiently to tenants and landlords in need. But even though funds began to be distributed in February by the Biden Administration, too many States and cities have been too slow to act.</p>



<p>As the Administration made clear last week, there is no excuse for any State or locality not to promptly deploy the resources that Congress appropriated to meet the critical need of so many Americans. This assistance provides the funding to pay landlords current and back rent so tenants can remain in their homes or apartments, not be evicted. No one in America should be evicted when Federal funds are available, in the hands of State and local government, to pay back rent due.</p>



<p>Last week the Administration also made clear that given the spread of the Delta variant among those Americans most likely to face eviction and lacking vaccinations, the President would have strongly supported a decision by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to further extend its eviction moratorium to protect renters at this moment of heightened vulnerability. Unfortunately, the Supreme Court declared on June 29<sup>th</sup> that the CDC could not grant such an extension without “clear and specific congressional authorization (via new legislation).”</p>



<p>Given the rising urgency of containing the spread of the Delta variant, on Sunday, the President asked the CDC to consider once again the possibility of executive action. He raised the prospect of a new, 30-day eviction moratorium—focused on counties with High or Substantial case rates—to protect renters. This temporary measure would spur States and localities to ramp up Emergency Rental Assistance programs to full speed this month, giving every landlord the opportunity to collect the rent they are owed and ensuring no eligible family gets evicted.</p>



<p>To date, CDC Director Rochelle Walensky and her team have been unable to find legal authority for a new, targeted eviction moratorium. Our team is redoubling efforts to identify all available legal authorities to provide necessary protections.</p>



<p>In the meantime, the President will continue to do everything in his power to help renters from eviction. The Administration has provided States and local governments with the flexibility to get funds out efficiently without burdensome documentation; to use funds to help those who are homeless or in need of new housing; and to use American Rescue Plan State and local funds to expand any effort to help those whose housing is at risk due to the pandemic.</p>



<p>Today, the President is taking these additional measures:</p>



<ul><li>Directing his White House policy, implementation, and legal teams to assemble all Federal agencies to reexamine whether there are any other authorities to take additional actions to stop evictions.</li><li>Calling on States and localities to extend or put in place evictions moratoria for at the least the next two months. Among those behind on their rent, 1 in 3 renters live in States that have already extended protections against evictions due to State eviction moratoria—which are not covered by the Supreme Court’s ruling. The rest of the States should follow course by also extending eviction moratoria.</li><li>Calling on State and local courts to heed the call of the Justice Department to pause eviction proceedings until tenants and landlords can first seek to access Emergency Rental Assistance—making evictions a last, not first—resort.</li><li>Directing his Cabinet Departments to use their powers to prevent evictions and tell landlords: If your government is backing your mortgage or providing you housing tax relief, you should not be choosing eviction over the Emergency Rental Assistance we have provided to make you whole and keep your tenants and their families safely housed.</li><li>Challenging every landlord to hold off on evictions for the next 30 days and instead seek out the Emergency Rental Assistance Congress and the Administration meant for them.</li><li>Challenging utilities providers to work with State and local governments to access Emergency Rental Assistance and other resources made available by Congress and the Administration to avoid cutting off services for those behind in payments due to the pandemic and at risk of eviction.</li><li>Directing the Treasury Department to make clear that States and localities can use emergency housing and State and local relief to support eviction prevention efforts by courts, legal aid, and housing counselors, as well as to give incentives to landlords who cooperate in these efforts by offering housing to those who have been evicted or are homeless, or by offering leases to the most hard-pressed tenants at a length that ensures true housing stability.</li><li>At the request of Congressional leadership, directing the White House, Treasury Department, and other relevant Federal agencies to continue examining why State and local governments have failed to distribute rental assistance Congress has provided, and explore any authorities the Federal government has to press the States and localities to make these distributions.</li></ul>



<p>The Administration remains deeply committed to doing everything in its power to keep people safely and securely housed, which is essential to the health, well-being, and dignity of us all.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Reopening Schools and Rebuilding With&#160;Equity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/02/fact-sheet-reopening-schools-and-rebuilding-with-equity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Administration has taken decisive action to support the safe reopening of schools for in-person instruction and to address the pandemic’s disparate impact on students of color and other underserved students. As families across the country eagerly anticipate a return to school, the Administration is determined to ensure that our schools and students not only&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Administration has taken decisive action to support the safe reopening of schools for in-person instruction and to address <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/20210608-impacts-of-covid19.pdf">the pandemic’s disparate impact on students of color and other underserved students</a>. As families across the country eagerly anticipate a return to school, the Administration is determined to ensure that our schools and students not only recover from the pandemic, but that we Build Back Better for the future.<br><br><strong><u>Prioritizing safe reopening</u></strong><br><br>The President made clear on <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/21/executive-order-supporting-the-reopening-and-continuing-operation-of-schools-and-early-childhood-education-providers/">Day One of this Administration</a> that safely reopening schools was a national priority, signing the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/21/executive-order-supporting-the-reopening-and-continuing-operation-of-schools-and-early-childhood-education-providers/">Executive Order on Supporting the Reopening and Continuing Operation of Schools and Early Childhood Education Providers,</a> which launched a comprehensive effort across the White House, Department of Education, and Department of Health and Human Services to safely reopen schools for in-person instruction. The Department released two volumes of its COVID-19 Handbook focused on safely reopening schools and meeting the needs of students, and <a href="https://bestpracticesclearinghouse.ed.gov/">launched a clearinghouse</a> of best practices for safely operating in-person and addressing the needs of students and staff. Secretary Cardona’s National Safe School Reopening Summit highlighted best practices from districts across the country to support safe in-person learning.<br><br>Vaccination is our leading strategy to end the pandemic, and—combined with the layered mitigation strategies recommended by the CDC—has the greatest potential to allow schools to reopen fully this fall and stay open for in-person learning. That’s why, in March the President prioritized teachers and school staff for access to the COVID vaccine. As a result, almost 90 percent of educators and school staff are now vaccinated. To get more of our students ages 12 and older vaccinated, the President is now calling on school districts nationwide to host at least one pop-up vaccination clinic over the coming weeks and directing pharmacies in the federal pharmacy program to prioritize this and to work with school districts across the country to host vaccination clinics at schools and colleges.<br><br>Heroic efforts from teachers, parents, and school staff, combined with the Administration’s aggressive vaccination push, has demonstrated that safe in-person learning is possible. <a href="https://ies.ed.gov/schoolsurvey/">Since January, the percentage of K-8 schools offering remote-only instruction decreased from 23 percent in January to only 2 percent in May.</a><br><br>However, there is still work to be done.&nbsp;<a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/70/wr/mm7026e2.htm">During the pandemic, students of color have been less likely to be enrolled in in-person instruction</a>. Data shows that on <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/stoken/default+domain/CIGQDAR3XPJUMKYTSTDX/full">average students in remote learning report poorer well-being than those in in-person instruction</a>. A continued reliance on remote learning threatens to further widen disparities. The Administration will continue to address the concerns of families, and provide support to states in creating safe, inclusive, and supportive learning environments.<br><br><strong><u>Investing historic resources in equitable reopening</u></strong><br><br>With the passage of the American Rescue Plan, the Biden-Harris Administration has invested a historic $130 billion to support schools safely reopening and addressing the needs of students, including $122 billion through the <a href="https://oese.ed.gov/offices/american-rescue-plan/american-rescue-plan-elementary-and-secondary-school-emergency-relief/">American Rescue Plan’s Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief Fund</a> (ARP ESSER). ARP ESSER funding supports efforts to get students back in the classroom safely for in-person learning, to safely keep schools open once students are back, and to address the social, emotional, mental health, and academic needs of all students. This funding is being used to help <a href="https://oese.ed.gov/offices/american-rescue-plan/american-rescue-plan-elementary-and-secondary-school-emergency-relief/stateplans/">schools safely operate, implement high-quality summer learning and enrichment programs, hire nurses and counselors, support the vaccination of students and staff, and invest in other measures to take care of students.</a><br><br><strong>Ensuring funds address the needs of students.</strong><em><strong> </strong></em>Districts and states must spend a combined minimum of 25 percent of the state’s total ARP ESSER funds, totaling nearly $30.5 billion, to address the impact of lost instructional time through summer learning or enrichment, extended day instruction, comprehensive afterschool programs, or other evidence-based practices. Funded strategies must also respond to students’ social and emotional needs and account for the disproportionate impact of the coronavirus on underserved students. The Administration recognizes that the communities that support our students have a critical understanding of what their students need and are key to ensuring funds have the greatest impact on students. As they put together their plans for the use of funds, states and school districts are required to engage a wide range of stakeholders during the planning process, including educators, school leaders and staff, students, families, civil rights organizations, and stakeholders representing the interests of students with disabilities, English learners, students experiencing homelessness, children in foster care, migratory students, students who are incarcerated and other underserved students.<br><br><strong>Protecting high-poverty districts from funding cuts.&nbsp;</strong>The American Rescue Plan’s ARP ESSER program includes a first-of-its-kind <a href="https://oese.ed.gov/offices/american-rescue-plan/american-rescue-plan-elementary-and-secondary-school-emergency-relief/resources/">maintenance of equity</a> requirement to ensure that high-poverty school districts and schools are protected in the event of funding cuts. These requirements will ensure that school districts and schools serving a large share of students from low-income backgrounds will not experience disproportionate budget cuts—and that the school districts with the highest poverty levels do not experience any decrease in state per-pupil funding below their pre-pandemic level.<br><br><strong>Ensuring states continue to fund education<em>.&nbsp;</em></strong>The Department has emphasized the importance of the American Rescue Plan’s <a href="https://oese.ed.gov/files/2021/04/MOE-Chart_with-waiver-FAQs_FINAL_4.21.21Update.pdf">maintenance of effort requirement</a>, which ensures that states continue to fulfill their commitments to fund their education systems, and has worked with states to ensure that they meet these requirements. The maintenance of effort requirement helps protect students by making sure that federal pandemic relief funds are used to meet the immediate needs and impacts of the pandemic on students and schools&nbsp;to the greatest extent possible, rather than to supplant general state funding for K-12 education.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting effective implementation.<em> </em></strong>The Department of Education has worked aggressively to support states and school districts in implementing education relief funding. This includes providing <a href="https://oese.ed.gov/offices/american-rescue-plan/american-rescue-plan-elementary-and-secondary-school-emergency-relief/resources/">resources on how ARP ESSER funds can be used</a>, including to <a href="https://www.ed.gov/coronavirus/improving-ventilation">support effective ventilation in schools</a>, <a href="https://oese.ed.gov/files/2021/07/FAQ-21.pdf">vaccination efforts</a>, creating and expand <a href="https://oese.ed.gov/files/2021/07/21-0138-ARP-Community-Schools-OMB-and-OS-Approved-071421-1.pdf">full-service community schools </a>, hiring nurses and counselors, and providing high-quality summer programs and high-dosage tutoring to students. With critical partners like the National Governors Association and Council of Chief State School Officers, the Department launched the <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/us-department-education-launches-national-summer-learning-enrichment-collaborative-help-students-most-impacted-pandemic">Summer Learning and Enrichment Collaborative</a> to support states providing high-quality summer learning and enrichment.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Stabilizing and ensuring access to child care.<em> </em></strong>High-quality early care and education helps ensure that children can take full advantage of education and training opportunities later in life. The pandemic <a href="https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/early-childhood/reports/2020/09/03/489900/true-cost-providing-safe-child-care-coronavirus-pandemic/">significantly disrupted</a> the child care sector, threatening access to this critical support and threatening economic security for childcare workers, who are disproportionately women of color. The American Rescue Plan invested $24 billion in stabilizing the child care sector, and is helping to provide this essential industry—which provides vital opportunities for children—with more flexible funding to help more low-income working families access high-quality care, increase compensation for early childhood workers, and help parents to work. &nbsp;&nbsp;<br><strong><em><br></em>Addressing the needs of students experiencing homelessness. </strong>The pandemic <a href="https://files.consumerfinance.gov/f/documents/cfpb_Housing_insecurity_and_the_COVID-19_pandemic.pdf">increased housing insecurity</a>, and disproportionately impacted the education of students experiencing homelessness, who were less likely to be able to successfully engage in remote learning due to lack of reliable access to the internet. The Department of Education has released all $800 million in American Rescue Plan <a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/education-department-announces-state-allocations-800-million-american-rescue-plan-funds-support-students-experiencing-homelessness">funds for identifying and addressing the needs of students experiencing homelessness</a>, including by providing wraparound services and support ranging from afterschool to mental health services.<br><em><br><strong>Supporting students with disabilities.</strong></em><strong><em> </em></strong>The pandemic created serious challenges for many students with disabilities, who struggled to access special education and related services according to their individualized services plan. The American Rescue Plan provides support to students with disabilities and infants and toddlers with disabilities through the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act. To ensure states can deliver the necessary services and supports to young children and youth with disabilities, the American Rescue Plan devotes nearly $2.6 billion in grants to states to support elementary and secondary education students with disabilities, $200 million for preschool children with disabilities, and $250 million for infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families.<br><br><strong>Bolstering Tribal education. </strong>The Bureau of Indian Education (BIE) is using $535 million in American Rescue Plan funds to support 183 BIE-funded K-12 schools, providing much-needed financial support to help Tribal communities recover more quickly from the pandemic’s wide-ranging impact.<br><br><strong>Funding COVID testing.</strong> The American Rescue Plan includes $10 billion to support COVID-19 testing in schools. This funding will help to reopen schools, including in communities of color, which have been disproportionately impacted by the pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Protecting the rights of students.</strong><em><strong>&nbsp;</strong></em>Protecting the rights of students to equal opportunity is an essential part of ensuring educational equity.&nbsp;The Department of Education has provided resources to school leaders, students, families and other stakeholders to ensure students’ rights are protected, including information about&nbsp;<a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/qa-reopening-202105.pdf">civil rights and school reopening</a> and <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/correspondence/stakeholders/educator-202105-aapi.pdf">confronting COVID-19-related harassment</a> against AAPI students. The Department of Education has moved swiftly to implement the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/03/08/executive-order-on-guaranteeing-an-educational-environment-free-from-discrimination-on-the-basis-of-sex-including-sexual-orientation-or-gender-identity/">President’s Executive Order on Guaranteeing an Educational Environment Free from Discrimination on the Basis of Sex, Including Sexual Orientation or Gender Identity</a>; implement a <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/correspondence/stakeholders/20210406-titleix-eo-14021.pdf">comprehensive plan</a> to address sexual harassment, including sexual violence, in schools; and make clear that it will enforce Title IX to <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/06/22/2021-13058/enforcement-of-title-ix-of-the-education-amendments-of-1972-with-respect-to-discrimination-based-on">prohibit discrimination based on sexual orientation and gender identity</a>, including for <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/lgbt.html">LGBTQ+ students</a>. The Department has also worked to address <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/docs/crdc-exclusionary-school-discipline.pdf">the disproportionately high rates of school discipline for students of color and students with disabilities that removes them from the classroom</a>. The Department held a <a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/conferences/brown-67yl.html">public convening on school discipline</a> in May and launched a major, <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/06/08/2021-11990/request-for-information-regarding-the-nondiscriminatory-administration-of-school-discipline">ongoing effort to address racial, disability-based and other disparities in the administration of school discipline</a>.<br><em><br><strong>Closing the digital divide.</strong> </em>The American Rescue Plan included $7.2 billion for the E-Rate program, which helps support American schools by funding programs to help ensure K-12 students and teachers have the appropriate internet connections and devices for distance learning, a particular challenge in low-income and rural communities.<br><br><strong>Supporting nutrition security.</strong> It is hard for students to learn successfully when they are experiencing hunger. Black and Latino households face food insecurity at <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC5823283">twice the rate</a> of white households. The American Rescue Plan <a href="https://www.fns.usda.gov/coronavirus">guards against food hardship</a> among students this summer by allowing states to continue the Pandemic-EBT program, which provides grocery benefits to replace meals for students who are eligible for free and reduced priced meals when schools are closed. It also increases SNAP benefits by 15 percent through September 2021, maintaining the increase through the summer, when <a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/26203095/">childhood hunger spikes</a> due to a lack of school meals. The U.S. Department of Agriculture likewise acted to offer flexibility for the 2021-2022 school year by providing waivers that allow schools to serve free meals to all students.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>For more information on how President Biden’s Build Back Better agenda builds on this work by investing historic and vitally-needed resources that unlock opportunity for millions of Americans, please see the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/23/fact-sheet-how-the-biden-harris-administration-is-advancing-educational-equity/">White House Fact Sheet on How the Biden-Harris Administration is Advancing Educational Equity</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with President Kais Saied of&#160;Tunisia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/31/readout-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-president-kais-saied-of-tunisia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 22:34:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with President Kais Saied of Tunisia. In an hour-long discussion, he conveyed President Biden’s strong support for the people of Tunisia and for Tunisian democracy based on fundamental rights, strong institutions, and a commitment to the rule of law. In this spirit, the call focused on the critical need for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with President Kais Saied of Tunisia. In an hour-long discussion, he conveyed President Biden’s strong support for the people of Tunisia and for Tunisian democracy based on fundamental rights, strong institutions, and a commitment to the rule of law. In this spirit, the call focused on the critical need for Tunisian leaders to outline a swift return to Tunisia’s democratic path. National Security Advisor Sullivan underscored that this will require rapidly forming a new government, led by a capable prime minister to stabilize Tunisia’s economy and confront the COVID-19 pandemic, as well as ensuring the timely return of the elected parliament. As Tunisia’s leaders answer the widely expressed demands of Tunisians for improved standards of living and honest governance, the United States and other friends of the Tunisian people stand ready to redouble our efforts to help Tunisia move toward a secure, prosperous, and democratic future.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Marine One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/30/remarks-by-president-biden-before-marine-one-departure-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 01:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 6:15 P.M. EDT     Q    Mr. President, do you want to open travel with Cuba again?  Do you want to open travel with Cuba, Mr. President? THE PRESIDENT:  I just had a long &#8212;   Q    Mr. President, do you have plans to invite Polish President to the White House? THE PRESIDENT:  Pardon me? Q   &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>6:15 P.M. EDT    <br><br>Q    Mr. President, do you want to open travel with Cuba again?  Do you want to open travel with Cuba, Mr. President?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I just had a long &#8212;  <br><br>Q    Mr. President, do you have plans to invite Polish President to the White House?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Pardon me?<br><br>Q    Do you have a plan to invite Polish President to the White House?  Polish President.  <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The Polish President?<br><br>Q    Yes.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  No I haven&#8217;t yet. <br><br>Q    Should Americans expect more &#8212; should Americans expect more guidelines coming up, more restrictions because of COVID?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  In all probability. And, by the way, we had a good day yesterday, almost a million people got vaccinated.  About half a million of those people for the first time &#8212; for the second shot.  And so, I&#8217;m hopeful that people are beginning to realize how essential it is to do.<br><br>Q    Mr. President, you had talks with Russia in Geneva on arms control.  Are you satisfied with those talks &#8212; how those went?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  They&#8217;re in process, and I&#8217;m hopeful.<br><br>Thank you. <br><br>6:17 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, July 30,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/30/press-briefing-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-july-30-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 23:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:35 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello.&#160; Here&#8217;s my mask from yesterday.&#160; I was wondering where that went. Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Happy Friday.&#160; I have a couple things for all of you at the top. Today, the President and the Vice President met with governors to discuss the worsening 2021&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:35 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Here&#8217;s my mask from yesterday.&nbsp; I was wondering where that went.</p>



<p>Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Happy Friday.&nbsp; I have a couple things for all of you at the top.</p>



<p>Today, the President and the Vice President met with governors to discuss the worsening 2021 wildfire season and ongoing efforts to strengthen prevention, preparedness, and response activities.</p>



<p>This was a follow-up to the meeting the President convened last month with Cabinet officials, governors from Western states, and private sector partners.</p>



<p>During today’s event, the President highlighted the heroism of our firefighters who undertake dangerous work to keep Americans safe, and he discussed the actions his administration is taking to improve emergency preparedness and keep Americans safe.</p>



<p>The President and the Vice President then received an update from the governors about the situation on the ground. They discussed what their administration can do to support state and local response efforts and ensure the federal government’s response is as quick and effective as possible.</p>



<p>Driven by extreme heat, prolonged drought, and the changing climate, as well as decades of forest management decisions, the 2021 wildfire season continues to outpace the devastating 2020 season in terms of large fires to date.</p>



<p>Already this year, FEMA has approved 20 Fire Management Assistance Grants to help states pay for the cost of fighting these fires.</p>



<p>The President has been receiving regular reports on how wildfires are impacting communities across the country, and he will continue to close &#8212; to closely monitor the severity of this situation.</p>



<p>Cuba.&nbsp; On the Cuba meeting today that the President is having: Since the historic protests we witnessed in Cuba on July 11, the President has been watching the events closely.&nbsp; As we have stated before, he’s made clear that Cuba is led by a failed and repressive regime and that communism is a universally failed ideology.&nbsp; That’s why, from the start, the President has said that addressing this moment was a priority for the administration.</p>



<p>We have said many times that Cuban-Americans are the best ambassadors for freedom and prosperity in Cuba.&nbsp; As part of that, today the President will host Cuban-American leaders at the White House to discuss the demonstrations and the administration’s response.</p>



<p>In addition, we also announced yesterday that the President is nominating Cuban American Frank Mora to be the next U.S. Ambassador to the Organization of American States, a vital forum where we have and will continue to regularly urge the countries of the hemisphere to support a fundamental freedom &#8212; the fundamental freedoms of the Cuban people.</p>



<p>And I know you love these.&nbsp; This is our vaccination update.&nbsp; They&#8217;re so great.&nbsp; We are always happy to share them with you.</p>



<p>So, today, we recorded over half a million new shots in arms, the highest number since the 1st of July.&nbsp; And the average number of people getting their first shots each day is up 30 percent over the past week alone.&nbsp; And this is the third week that states with the highest cases have the highest vaccination rates.</p>



<p>Every day, Americans are making the choice to get vaccinated.&nbsp; This is an encouraging sign, but we need everyone across the country to have the conversation with someone they know who is unvaccinated about getting the shot.&nbsp; This is how we will stop the spread of the Delta variant and, as we all know, save lives.</p>



<p>Finally, I have a quick preview of the week ahead for all of you.</p>



<p>The next week &#8212; this next coming week, the President will continue engaging with members of Congress to pass the bipartisan infrastructure deal, which will deliver historic infrastructure investments that will drive economic growth and create good-paying, middle-class jobs.</p>



<p>Also next week, the President will meet with Dr. Eric Lander, his Science Advisor and Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, about his plan for preparing for future pandemics.</p>



<p>On Tuesday, the President will deliver remarks on the administration’s progress delivering vaccines to the world to fight this pandemic globally.</p>



<p>On Friday, we will deliver remarks on the July jobs report, as you all know, it&#8217;s the first Friday of the month.</p>



<p>And, lastly, President Biden will then travel to Rehoboth Beach, Delaware, where he will remain over the weekend.</p>



<p>Alex, please take it away.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So I know we have a hard out at 3:10, so I have a couple quick questions on Congress.&nbsp; First, the eviction moratorium.&nbsp; Lawmakers are scrambling to find a legislative solution, but Speaker Pelosi said today that she&#8217;d like to see the CDC extended.</p>



<p>I know you all have cited the Supreme Court decision as the reason Congress needs to deal with.&nbsp; But why not just extend it, have that legal fight, and give Congress a little bit more room to work?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as &#8212; as we&#8217;ve stated, Alex &#8212; and to your point about Pelosi, you know, the &#8212; the Supreme Court said that it could only be extended with congressional authorization.&nbsp; That was their decision.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how they were able to strike it down, and that&#8217;s what they said needed to happen.</p>



<p>And so, this &#8212; this bill that Pelosi is asking for &#8212; this would meet that requirement if successful.&nbsp; So, this is an important &#8212; important &#8212; it&#8217;s incredibly important to &#8212; to move forward.</p>



<p>And so the administration is working &#8212; is going to work together with leaders in Congress on potential avenues to extend the eviction moratorium to protect these vulnerable renters and their families.&nbsp; We understand how critical that is, how important that is.&nbsp; It has been a lifeline to so many, so many Americans here.</p>



<p>So this is a public health concern, as you can imagine, that we think should be supported by both Republicans and Democrats.&nbsp; So we support the Speaker&#8217;s effort, and we will do everything that we can to move this forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on voting rights, can you tell us any more information about how the President&#8217;s meeting with Schumer and Pelosi on the, sort of, efforts around voting rights went?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead, Alex.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, no, no.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That was it?&nbsp; Okay, great.</p>



<p>So, as you stated. the President and the Vice President are hosting Speaker Pelosi and Leader Schumer at the White House today, later this afternoon.&nbsp; And this is &#8212; they&#8217;re doing this because they want to make sure that they continue having the conversation on protecting the sacred right to vote because it&#8217;s such incredibly &#8212; it&#8217;s an incredible priority for them.</p>



<p>The President and the Speaker, the &#8212; Leader Schumer are regularly in touch about this, but they wanted to have this meeting in person to talk about the next step.</p>



<p>This is both personal to the President, as we&#8217;ve talked about many times, having fought for voting rights his entire life.&nbsp; He spoke about it in Pennsylvania at &#8212; not too long ago, just a couple of weeks ago.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to just continue having those conversations.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one more on the CDC document that was just leaked.&nbsp; The Washington Post obtained the CDC PowerPoint that suggested the situation surrounding the Delta variant is more dire than, you know, the administration has characterized it.</p>



<p>I wanted to read a few quotes from it.&nbsp; It said, quote, &#8220;Given the higher transmissibility and current vaccine coverage, universal masking is essential to reduce transmission of the Delta variant.&#8221;&nbsp; Delta variant breakthrough infections &#8220;may be as transmissible as unvaccinated cases.&#8221;&nbsp; &#8220;Risk of infection is reduced threefold in the vaccinated population.&#8221;</p>



<p>And so, President Biden has repeated over and over that this is a pandemic of the unvaccinated, but this PowerPoint seems to raise questions about that.</p>



<p>He&#8217;s also promised to level up with the American people.&nbsp; So his comments yesterday &#8212; I mean, was he being completely upfront about the challenges of the Delta variant?&nbsp; This PowerPoint would suggest it&#8217;s a little bit more dire than he laid it out to be.&nbsp; And why wasn’t that PowerPoint made public?&nbsp; Why did it have to be (inaudible) the public?</p>



<p>And then lastly &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Wow.</p>



<p>(Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, why aren’t we seeing universal &#8212; recommendations for universal masking?&nbsp; Why is it just in areas of high transmission when the CDC seems to be suggesting universal masking is needed?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, Alex.&nbsp; That was a lot.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; No, I appreciate the question.&nbsp; It’s actually a very important question, and we need to &#8212; and I’m happy to address all of them.</p>



<p>So, since May &#8212; I just wanted to step back a little bit &#8212; since May, the CDC and the administration have been crystal clear about the increased risk of the Delta variant in our pandemic response.&nbsp; And so I just want to run through a couple of examples because this is such an important moment that we&#8217;re in, in fighting this pandemic.</p>



<p>So, in May, out of the concern of the spread of Delta, we restricted travel to India, where it was growing.&nbsp; That is something that we did in May, and so that &#8212; as you know, that was many months ago at this point &#8212; or a couple months ago at this point.</p>



<p>In the month of June, doctors from the admin blitzed local constituency and national media with over 400 media interviews with a clear message: Delta is a serious threat, and getting vaccinated is the clear solution.&nbsp; So that was in the month of June &#8212; for the month of June.</p>



<p>Throughout June, the President, Jeff Zients, and our medical experts spoke dozens of times to the threat of Delta &#8212; the threat that Delta poses.</p>



<p>On July 4th, the President made clear that COVID-19, quote, “has not been vanquished, and Delta is a powerful variant.&nbsp; This is what the President said on July 4th.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in light of recent reporting, it is worth noting that Dr. Walensky said eight days ago that the Delta variant is the most infectious respiratory disease she&#8217;s been &#8212; she has seen in the last 20 years &#8212; her 20 years of her career.</p>



<p>Our message has always been clear throughout: We need more people to get vaccinated to stop the spread of this variant, and so we have to continue to make that effort.</p>



<p>Vaccinated and unvaccinated people infected with Delta have higher viral loads, meaning more virus in their body than with previous variants.&nbsp; The last two did not have that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so this is what we&#8217;re seeing in the Delta: High viral loads mean you are more likely to spread it.&nbsp; So, in the rare occasions that vaccinated people get Delta in a breakthrough infection, they may be contagious.&nbsp; And this is what we heard from CDC this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so the most important takeaway &#8212; and I want to be really clear about this because this is critical for all of you who report about this and for those who are watching.&nbsp; We should have &#8212; the takeaway is &#8212; we should have from this guidance and any follow-up reporting &#8212; is actually pretty simple: We need more people to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the answer.&nbsp; We need more people to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s if we want to stop the spread of this variant and avoid mutations, we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we just need to get more people vaccinated.&nbsp; And the good news is that the vaccinations &#8212; the vaccines work, so we got to get out there and make sure people get vaccinated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the President said, for the early months of this administration, that those who are vaccinated and wearing masks and doing all those steps could look toward the Fourth of July as that independence opportunity.&nbsp; We now know the CDC is basing some of this new science on a Fourth of July party that happened in Massachusetts where the Delta variant was predominant; we saw that vaccinated people were passing it and so forth.</p>



<p>Does this give the President pause about making recommendations about what the public can do?&nbsp; Because he encouraged people who were vaccinated to gather on the Fourth of July.&nbsp; A group that did so is now sort of the poster example for the CDC of what can happen with this variant.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean &#8212; you know, Kelly O, his &#8212; the President has always said he&#8217;s going to follow the science and he&#8217;s going to listen to public health experts.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we do, right?&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re &#8212; we are all following the CDC guidance on masking.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s our North Star, as we &#8212; as Jen has said earlier this week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, the job of all of us in this room is to communicate the truth about where we are in the pandemic, and this is something the President has said from day one, and also highlight how we can get out of this pandemic.</p>



<p>So the vaccines work.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the truth.&nbsp; We know masks work.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the truth.&nbsp; They save lives and prevent spread of this dangerous Delta variant.&nbsp; So we need to help in communicating the actions we are telling the American people to take and getting vaccinated and wearing a mask.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re in an area where there&#8217;s lots of virus circulating, it&#8217;s more contagious.&nbsp; You have to wear a mask.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know I have one more question that I actually didn&#8217;t get to for Alex that I want to make sure that I answer, which is, will the CDC release more data publicly or this data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So just wanted to say that the CDC’s first and foremost priority is getting the American people information as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s what they did on Tuesday: They got it as quickly as they can.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be releasing this data today, as you know.&nbsp; And it was clear that the vacc- &#8212; it was clear that vaccinated people had the ability to transmit an action needed to be taken quickly.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why they did it.&nbsp; They did it ahead of releasing the data, and they&#8217;re going to do that today, as I just mentioned.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But part of this is also in terms of getting information out.&nbsp; Like, why are the doctors not here in the briefing room to take our questions?&nbsp; Why have we not had a COVID briefing?&nbsp; When we got some update from Dr. Walensky, that was a phone briefing.&nbsp; It provides information, but the public is eager to know more about what the Delta variant can do.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know what, Kelly O?&nbsp; I would &#8212; I would argue that we had the President of the United States speak to this yesterday.&nbsp; He gave a more than 30-minute speech about where we are as a country.&nbsp; I mean, he is a trusted voice; he&#8217;s the leader of our country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he’s not a scientist.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, but we heard from him, right?&nbsp; We heard from the President yesterday.&nbsp; We heard from the President about the Delta variant and vaccinations, in general, the day before yesterday, when he was in Pennsylvania, when he was supposed to talk about Buy American, which he did, but he led off talking about the vaccinations.</p>



<p>We have had our doctors on your networks, on many of the networks that are here, talking &#8212; probably all of them &#8212; talking about the Delta variant all throughout these last couple of days.&nbsp; So they have been out there.&nbsp; They have been talking about it.&nbsp; And, yeah, we heard from &#8212; directly for Dr. Walensky herself, you know?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this is something that we&#8217;re going to continue to do.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to make sure that we communicate directly with the American people and also hand &#8212; work hand in hand with local governments and state governments as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just to follow up on all of that &#8212; you mentioned the CDC’s data that was released on Tuesday.&nbsp; I think the question is: Why doesn&#8217;t that guidance match the internal memos guidance?&nbsp; Because, on Tuesday, they updated the mask guidance to say you only have to wear it in places that have high or moderate transmissibility.&nbsp; The internal memo that was leaked says, “Given higher transmissibility and current coverage” &#8212; vaccine coverage &#8212; “universal masking is essential to reduce transmission.”</p>



<p>So, one, why don&#8217;t the recommendations match?&nbsp; And, two, should the American public anticipate updated guidance that includes universal masking and also new items about large gatherings and how many people should gather, given what we are seeing from Provincetown?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, Weijia, we do not make those types of, you know, decisions from here when it comes to the science, when it comes to guidance.&nbsp; That comes from CDC.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So the questions that you just asked me, I refer you to CDC.&nbsp; About those slides and the &#8212; what you saw in the slides specifically, that comes from them, and they all have that specific, you know, kind of information for you that you&#8217;re trying to get here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will say, though, I think the most important thing &#8212; and I don’t want to get away from this because this is what&#8217;s the most critical thing here &#8212; is that people need to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the answer.&nbsp; If we want to make sure that we curb this pandemic, that we curb this &#8212; the COVID-19, that we fight &#8212; that we win this fight that we&#8217;re in, we have to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the President calls this a pandemic for the unvaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have to make sure that we take care of each other and that they take &#8212; not just take care of themselves, but take care of each other.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re talking about our kids who are 12 and under who can&#8217;t get vaccinated.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about our grandparents.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about older people in our lives that we want to make sure are taken care of.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that is &#8212; if anything, that is &#8212; should be one of the main reasons people get vaccinated: to make sure they take care of their families and their community.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the White House reviewed CDC&#8217;s internal memo and slides?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t have anything to say about that.&nbsp; I could look into that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Because the language is &#8212; the analogies are helpful to understand, like, you know, there &#8212; that the Delta variant is as contagious as chickenpox, or more contagious than the common cold or Ebola.&nbsp; Are these things that they&#8217;re going to present to the public to help us understand &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, the data is being released today, I believe, right?&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So, it&#8217;ll be &#8212; it&#8217;ll be available.&nbsp; It&#8217;s being released today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Got it.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more just follow-up on Kelly.&nbsp; Of all the weeks not to have a COVID briefing, why this week?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I know that&#8217;s the question you all are asking me, but they &#8212; the doctors have been on national television all week, speaking to this, answering the questions on your networks.&nbsp; So, they&#8217;ve been out there talking about it.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not hiding.&nbsp; They&#8217;re actually having the conversations with anchors and hosts, and answering the hard questions about the Delta variant, about the CDC masking.&nbsp; And so they&#8217;ve been out there; they&#8217;re not hiding.&nbsp; They&#8217;re actually speaking to this almost every day.</p>



<p>So, you know, and &#8212; and we heard from the President of the United States yesterday for a more than 30-minute speech that many of you were in.&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>Go ahead, Peter.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Building off of your point that vaccines work, then why is the President asking vaccinated people to mask up if there have been just 0.0035 percent of the 161 million fully vaccinated Americans who have had a breakthrough case?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let me give you the facts about the Delta variant, and maybe this will help, Peter.&nbsp; It spreads more than twice as easily from one person to another, and it&#8217;s spreading rapidly.&nbsp; It is, really, just across the country, and that is just the fact.</p>



<p>Two months ago, only 1 percent of COVID in the U.S. were Delta.&nbsp; Now, more than 80 percent are Delta.&nbsp; And so this is where we are today with this vaccine, and so it is &#8212; we are listening to the experts, the CDC guidance, and this is what they are telling us.</p>



<p>If you live in an area that has &#8212; that is highly contagious and that has high levels, you have to &#8212; they are saying &#8212; they are, you know, giving the guidance of wearing a mask to protect yourself and to protect your community and your family.&nbsp; That is the guidance that we&#8217;re getting.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And some of the preliminary stuff we&#8217;ve seen from the CDC says this new guidance for vaccinated people to mask up is based on data from people who got sick partying in Provincetown, Massachusetts.&nbsp; Has the White House seen any proof that COVID is spreading &#8212; vaccinated people are spreading COVID who are not going to big parties?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Here&#8217;s what we know, and I&#8217;m just going to repeat again: We need to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; That is really the answer here.&nbsp; That is what we&#8217;re seeing from &#8212; that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re hearing from CDC, that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re even seeing from these slides is that people need to get vaccinated.&nbsp; That is how we fight the Delta &#8212; the Delta variant.&nbsp; That is how we fight COVID.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, last one: The President said yesterday it is “still a question whether the federal government can mandate the whole country” to get vaccinated.&nbsp; He said, “I don&#8217;t know that yet.”&nbsp; Does that mean he has asked the Justice Department to see if it&#8217;s legal to make everybody get a vaccine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, when he said that across &#8212; about the mandate across the country, you know, I would encourage you to read his statement and make sure you read the contents of his remarks.</p>



<p>So, a national vaccine requirement is not under consideration at this time.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where we are with that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But has he asked the Justice Department to see if it&#8217;s even possible?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more to add to that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A lot of questions, obviously, about the super- spreader event in Provincetown.&nbsp; More than 800 cases, but 74 percent of people there fully vaccinated.&nbsp; So doesn’t that at least suggest that maybe breakthrough cases aren’t rare?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But that’s not what the &#8212; that&#8217;s not what the data shows us.&nbsp; That’s not what we&#8217;ve gotten from CDC. We&#8217;ve been told &#8212; we &#8212; we know that it is the breakthroughs that do happen with vaccinated people are rare.</p>



<p>And so, right now, what the CDC has told us is, because they do know that there are some breakthrough cases, we have to &#8212; we have to make sure we&#8217;re masked.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, again, we just have to continue to make sure people get vaccinated.&nbsp; That is the answer.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we got to move forward.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re focused on here at the White House.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So we&#8217;re supposed to see that as more of a one-off event, an outlier?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, that&#8217;s &#8212; well, I&#8217;m &#8212; what I&#8217;m saying is that what we&#8217;re focused on &#8212; our message is very, very clear &#8212; is that we want to make sure that people get vaccinated.&nbsp; That is &#8212; yes, that is one event, but what the CDC &#8212; that what the CDC guidance tells us is that the breakthroughs have been where &#8212; this is what the public health officials have said.&nbsp; Like, yes, there are breakthroughs, but they have been rare.&nbsp; But the problem is that they are &#8212; it is now contagious.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s why they&#8217;re asking us to wear a mask.</p>



<p>Where before, with the last two variants that we&#8217;ve seen, we weren&#8217;t seeing that.&nbsp; We weren&#8217;t seeing vaccinated people pass that along.&nbsp; And so, now, that has changed with the Delta variant.&nbsp; That is how serious this variant is.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why our message continues to be: Please, get vaccinated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the eviction moratorium, Speaker Pelosi, in her statement, said that only $3 billion out of an allocated $46.5 billion has actually going out the door.&nbsp; So what is the administration doing to help get more money out the door faster?</p>



<p><a>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, so that&#8217;s a good question because that shouldn&#8217;t be happening.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; We are aware that the monies are taking some time to get to the &#8212; some time from the &#8212; it&#8217;s already out in the states &#8212; some time getting to where the folks who really need it: the renters and lawmakers [landlords].</a></p>



<p>So, what we have done these past couple of days is we made an announcement last week that $1.5 billion of that ERA went out in the month of June, and that was the most that we saw in the last five months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we continue to &#8212; continue to work to make sure that people are being made aware that this is &#8212; this is in existence.</p>



<p>Look, this &#8212; this shouldn&#8217;t be happening.&nbsp; States should be making sure that these monies are getting out as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And so, we &#8212; and just yesterday &#8212; just this week, we had a Day of Action to promote the availability of the rental assistance, which reached tens of millions of Americans.</p>



<p>Last week, the Treasury released new data, which I just mentioned with the $1.5 billion.</p>



<p>And then &#8212; so what we know is that these funds can continue to be dispersed to renters and landlords until 2025. And so these Emergency Rental Assistance are so critical, they&#8217;re so important, and so we&#8217;re making sure that we continue to work with local governments to get that out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; But I think people are applying.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve heard tens of thousands of people have applied.&nbsp; They&#8217;re just waiting for the funds to be dispersed.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, I hear you.&nbsp; And that’s why we&#8217;re encouraging the states to get that out as soon as possible.&nbsp; They have it.&nbsp; They need to get that out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yeah, go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, given the seriousness of the Delta variant, are there conversations in the White House, or between the White House and scientific advisors, about more lockdowns, partial lockdowns, or anything along those lines?</p>



<p><a>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So that is something that &#8212; you know, I know this was asked to me yesterday.&nbsp; The way we see this is that we have the tools in our toolbelt to fight this &#8212; this variant, to fight this vaccine [virus].&nbsp; </a>And we &#8212; we are not &#8212; we are not going to head towards a lockdown.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We want to make sure that we&#8217;re doing everything that we can because, after passing the historic Rescue Plan, we have the resources to make sure that doesn&#8217;t happen.&nbsp; So our role, again, is to make sure that we get &#8212; that we get people vaccinated as quickly as possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, this vaccine &#8212; these vaccines are free.&nbsp; They&#8217;re easy to get.&nbsp; They’re never been easier to get vaccinated.&nbsp; So that is the number one thing that we&#8217;re trying to do is making that happen.&nbsp; We have the resources to do that.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve been able to do this past six months.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve been able to get more than 160 million people fully vaccinated.&nbsp; Eighty percent of that are &#8212; are people who are over the age of 65.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to continue to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so our goal is to make sure that we are not headed towards that.&nbsp; That is not going to be the direction that we take, because we have the tools to prevent that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said yesterday that the federal &#8212; new requirements for federal workers could be an example for other employers.&nbsp; Can you just explain: Will federal employees’ data be collected when they submit their vaccination status?&nbsp; And will the federal government be paying for the tests that they take if they do not attest to being vaccinated?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the agencies will pay for the cost of regular federal employee screening tests, so that&#8217;s how that&#8217;s going to move forward.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re going to implement &#8212; the agencies are going to be implementing this program themselves.&nbsp; So, they&#8217;ll be in charge of that &#8212; how that moves forward.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s kind of how that&#8217;s going to be dispersed &#8212; the program.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just on another topic, lastly: The New York Times is reporting, and others, that President Trump pressed the Justice Department last year to declare falsely that the election was corrupt.&nbsp; Do you have a reaction &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; to that?&nbsp;&nbsp;And would &#8212; you know, would your Justice Department, the Biden Justice Department, do anything about that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So President Biden has been clear that he believes it is absolutely vital to have a Department of Justice that is free from undue political influence, and these revelations underscore why that&#8217;s important.</p>



<p>Go ahead, Phil.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Just to follow up on MaryAlice’s question: Your number, at least percentage wise, was right, from the CDC study.&nbsp; It says about 74 percent of 346 cases had been fully vaccinated in that cluster.&nbsp; So, just to clarify, it&#8217;s still the belief of the administration and the public health officials that breakthrough cases are rare on that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, what we&#8217;ve been &#8212; what we&#8217;ve been told by CDC and what we know from our public health expert is that they are rare.&nbsp; But here&#8217;s &#8212; I mean, but here&#8217;s the thing, and this is what we keep trying to say, is that: We got to get people vaccinated.&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is what we have to focus on.&nbsp; That is why we&#8217;re seeing the Delta variant.&nbsp; And so that is what we&#8217;re working on as an administration.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s what the President talked about.&nbsp; He talked about incentives.&nbsp; He talked about ways to do this in a more robust way.&nbsp; And this is the way we&#8217;re going to be focused on, is making sure people get vaccinated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that actually &#8212; that was my follow-up, which is, you know, very clear that those who are vaccinated see fewer symptoms, hospitalizations, death; there’s no question about it when you look at the data.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How concerned are you guys that people see a headline like that about breakthrough cases or a headline from the slide about transmissibility and it undercuts your efforts to say “Vaccination is the answer.&nbsp; Vaccination is the solution”?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I just talked about what we&#8217;ve seen the last couple of days: the rise in numbers of people getting vaccinated.&nbsp; And so, if anything, we&#8217;re seeing people are &#8212; are out there, who are unvaccinated, clearly getting vaccinated.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s critical.&nbsp; That&#8217;s important.&nbsp; The numbers and the data shows that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to continue to do, is making sure that people continue to get vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, we were all being tested every single day.&nbsp; At a certain point, we were not being tested.&nbsp; I&#8217;m curious what the current status of staff &#8212; White House staff testing is,&nbsp;and whether, given this news about transmission, there are plans to ramp up that testing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to continue to follow the guidance that&#8217;s been laid out, that&#8217;s been &#8212; that&#8217;s been handed.&nbsp; And so all of that is going to be determined &#8212; our testing is going to be determined by the White House Medical Unit.</p>



<p>We continue to get tested here &#8212; the staff does; so does the President.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to &#8212; that&#8217;s what &#8212; that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s how we&#8217;re going to continue to move forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So when you say “guidance,” is that &#8212; I think the current guidance is “only if there are symptoms” if you&#8217;re vaccinated.&nbsp; Is that the current status?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, but we’ve also &#8212; we also have stated in the past, like, when we &#8212; when you’re around &#8212; when a staffer is around the President, they get tested.&nbsp; And because of &#8212; we’re around the President of the United States, we get tested pretty regularly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s something that we have shared in the past.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing new there.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to follow what the White House Medical Unit entails for us to do as staff and for the President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the eviction moratorium: Why did the White House wait until yesterday to publicly inform Congress that it was them who needed to extend it legislatively?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So let me just first say, about the eviction moratorium, because this is, I think, really important:&nbsp;We know that this has a disproportionate effect on those Americans, both most likely to face evictions and lacking vaccinations.&nbsp; And President Biden would have strongly supported a decision by the CDC to further extend this eviction moratorium to protect renters at this &#8212; at this moment of heightened vulnerability.</p>



<p>But like we&#8217;ve all said today, unfortunately, the Supreme Court has made clear that this option is no longer available.&nbsp; So, the Supreme Court&#8217;s ruling stated that clear and specific congressional authorization would be necessary for the CDC to extend the moratorium through July.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, one of the things that I do want to say that we have been doing: We have had this whole-of-government effect to get the word out about the availability of the rental assistance, and to support grantees to ramping up their efforts.&nbsp; And so that is our focus because we know that getting that funding to renters and landlords is incredibly key and important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve been doing that since day one.&nbsp; And now &#8212; what we&#8217;re saying right now, what we have been saying, is that we&#8217;re going to work with Congress to make sure that we&#8217;re able to extend it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We support Speaker Pelosi in her &#8212; in her efforts.&nbsp; And what she is trying to do actually speaks to what the Supreme Court laid out in making sure that there is a continuation of the eviction moratorium.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right, but the Supreme Court ruling was more than a month ago, and you waited until this week to tell Congress that they need to do it.&nbsp; And you effectively jammed them two days before &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve been &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the moratorium ended.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; we&#8217;ve been &#8212; we&#8217;ve been having conversations with Congress for some time about this.&nbsp; This is something that we have been working with them on some &#8212; with some time about how do we move forward.&nbsp; And so this is &#8212; so this is &#8212; we&#8217;re going to continue to do that.&nbsp; And we appreciate Speaker Pelosi’s efforts.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to work closely with her on getting that done.</p>



<p>And, again, from day one, this administration has been working to make sure that we &#8212; we really take care of the most vulnerable in this country who’s been affected by COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There was some confusion over military service members being mandated to get the vaccine.&nbsp; The President said yesterday it was all about timing and recommended the DOD study it.&nbsp; The DOD later put their own statement out.</p>



<p>What did he mean that it’s all about “timing,” when he also said that the numbers are going to get worse before it gets better?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;ll say this: The President is asking the Department of Defense to look into how and when &#8212; and when they will add COVID to the list of mandatory vaccinations for their &#8212; for our armed forces.&nbsp; Anything else, I refer you to the DOD.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For both civilian and military service members?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I just know it’s the Department of Defense.&nbsp; That&#8217;s who &#8212; that&#8217;s who he&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s been talking to about getting that done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And just on a separate note, it was reported this morning that Senator Sinema &#8212; a key Dem swing vote &#8212; said she will be &#8212; not be putting off August vacation plans to vote on your $3.5 trillion reconciliation bill.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your reaction to that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I know that this has come up, and I just want to be really clear about this and what she actually &#8212; what Sinema actually said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, I&#8217;m not going to clearly negotiate or anything like that at the podium, but it&#8217;s important to be clear about what the senator said.&nbsp; She is going to vote to proceed with the debate on the budget resolution.&nbsp; She expressed reservations about the topline, which she&#8217;s been clearly clear about, and other senators have said the same.&nbsp; But she is stand &#8212; she&#8217;s not standing in the way of moving this process forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve been clear that the position of the administration is around the importance of getting vaccinated, but I have a follow-up to Alex&#8217;s question earlier.&nbsp; Because a lot of Americans do not know if they are in an area with substantial or high levels of transmission.&nbsp; So while you are trying to get vaccination rates up, is it the position of the administration that local officials in those affected areas should bring back mask mandates?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, local officials are going to look at the vaccination rate in their area, and they have the flexibility to put that into place &#8212; to put mandates into place, as we&#8217;ve seen across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That is not our role here as the federal government.&nbsp; We are not mandating mask wearing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re following, again, CDC guidance, and we encourage &#8212; we encourage local governments and states to adhere or to take a look at the guidance and make sure that they keep people safe &#8212; right? &#8212; they keep their community safe and they keep people in their state safe.&nbsp; So that is what we encourage.</p>



<p>And at the same time &#8212; I&#8217;m going to be a broken record on this because this is true, this is the case &#8212; we have to make sure we continue to get people vaccinated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a question with respect to Cuba and the ongoing policy review.&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s a meeting today, but has there been any movement on actionable steps?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Specifically, does the President plan to lift travel restrictions between the U.S. and Cuba, and make it easier for Cuban Americans to send money to their relatives on the island, both of which are issues he campaigned on?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, no, and both important issues that we understand to the Cuban people.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not going to preview any specific actions here.&nbsp; That is not something that I&#8217;m going to do from the podium.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will say that on the remit- &#8212; remittances, this is a complex issue that requires coordination with experts that will help to inform the administration&#8217;s policy.&nbsp; So, at the President&#8217;s direction, the Department of Treasury and State will form a remittance working group to review available options to establishing those channels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, may I follow up, please, on Cuba?&nbsp; Right &#8212; right back here.&nbsp; May I follow up on Cuba, please?&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You may have noticed those protests last week across the street from the White House.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you or anybody from the White House happened to speak to those protesters, but I did.&nbsp; And it’s anecdotal, of course, but they say they see no difference between the policy of President Biden towards Cuba and the policy of former President Obama towards Cuba.&nbsp; Is the approach the same of those two Presidents &#8212; of President Biden currently and the former President, President Obama?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, I&#8217;m going to be really clear here.&nbsp; So, since day one, we have said many times &#8212; many, many times &#8212; that the Cuban Americans are the best ambassadors for freedom and prosperity in Cuba, is what I said at the beginning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, the President is going to sit down and &#8212; to meet with Cuban Americans, leaders at the White House &#8212; that&#8217;s what he&#8217;s going to do in just a few hours &#8212; to discuss the demonstrations and the administration&#8217;s response.&nbsp; And so &#8212; including applying new sanctions on Cuba &#8212; on Cuban leaders and establishing Internet access for the Cuban people.&nbsp; So, we want to lift up the Cuban people, and that is going to be our focus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On July 22nd, The Treasury &#8212; the Treasury&#8217;s Office of Foreign Assistant [Assets] Control sanctioned one of the Cuban individuals and one Cuban entity for serious human rights abuses and the repression of peaceful pro-democratic protests in Cuba that began on July 11th.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we are going to continue to lift up the Cuban American people that &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, the Cuban people &#8212; and we&#8217;re going to have a conversation.&nbsp; As I just mentioned, the President will have one today, and we&#8217;ll probably have more to read out from that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead, Jenny.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Just, really quickly, following up on someone&#8217;s question on the eviction moratorium.&nbsp; You said that you&#8217;ve been working with Congress for some time now.&nbsp; Is there anything you can share in terms of who you&#8217;ve been talking with and when that started?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because Democratic leaders, quite frankly, seem pretty surprised that it&#8217;s now their responsibility.&nbsp; Obviously, we know the Supreme Court decision has been out for a month.&nbsp; So, what can you share in terms of that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don’t have specific meetings or conversations to share.&nbsp; Look, I &#8212; what I want to be make &#8212; make really clear is that we are going to cont- &#8212; we&#8217;re going to work with Congress on &#8212; to get this done because we understand the importance of the eviction moratorium to everyday people, especially after what we have seen this past year with COVID-19.&nbsp; That is a priority for us, and we work with Congress on so many different issues and have so many different conversations, and this is going to be a priority.&nbsp; And so, we support what Speaker Pelosi is trying to do now.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any response to Congresswoman Ocasio- Cortez calling your handling of the situation “reckless and irresponsible” because you &#8212; the White House hasn’t shown leadership on this before?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I disagree with the congresswoman.&nbsp; Because, as I stated and I&#8217;ve laid out, from day one, we have been working on the Emergency Rental Assistance.&nbsp; We have been making sure, working with local &#8212; local governments to get those funds out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just last month, we saw $1.5 billion in just one month in rental assistance that &#8212; which was more than the last five months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we have been working very hard in a whole-of-government approach that we do here at this &#8212; at this White House and this administration, and we&#8217;ll continue to do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Back to Senator Sinema&#8217;s comments, which you noted, her reservations about the price tag: Do White House negotiators and the President support Senate Democrats scaling back the reconciliation deal?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, this is a process that we&#8217;re going through.&nbsp; This is a negotiation process.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to have &#8212; to engage congressional members on the Hill when it comes to reconciliation, and also, clearly, the bipartisan infrastructure deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re not going to &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to stand here and trying to negotiate from the podium; I&#8217;m going to let congressional members do that.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll work closely with them.&nbsp; We understand this is how incredibly critical this is.&nbsp; This is part of a Build Back Better plan that the President has put forward, his economic policy, for this country.&nbsp; And he is all in on this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He brought people here &#8212; right? &#8212; to work with both sides of the aisles to bring this bipartisan deal on the hard infrastructure, and we&#8217;re going to continue as well with the whole Build Back Better plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And back to COVID.&nbsp; I know you said it&#8217;s up to the CDC and health officials to lead on new recommendations.&nbsp; But has the White House or the President asked them to look at new restrictions &#8212; possible restrictions surrounding large group gatherings, given the Delta variant transmission?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We &#8212; again, we follow the science and we listen to public health officials.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we move forward with this.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212; speaking of the science, Karine &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, switching topics.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Biden administration, earlier this week, laid out their plan on addressing root causes in Central America, including combating corruption in the region.&nbsp; It comes days after Guatemala’s Special Prosecutor Against Impunity was fired.&nbsp; The State Department has suspended cooperation with Guatemala’s Attorney General.&nbsp; So, I guess, how does this affect the White House&#8217;s work in the region?&nbsp; And does this cause any setbacks?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:Yeah, thank you for the question.&nbsp; Yes, this is something that we are very aware of.&nbsp; So, the situation in Guatemala &#8212; look, it&#8217;s important to us to make sure that &#8212; you know, that &#8212; that corruption is &#8212; as we&#8217;re dealing with the Northern Triangle &#8212; is dealt with.</p>



<p>Hold on.&nbsp; Yeah, I did have something that I wanted to share with all of you if I can find it really quickly.&nbsp; Just give me a second.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have it with me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s something that we&#8217;re aware of.&nbsp; And as you can imagine, as we&#8217;re dealing with the Northern Triangle, as you just stated, it&#8217;s critical and important that when we&#8217;re dealing with these countries and talking about how we&#8217;re going to help them with the root causes; that corruption, you know, is not is &#8212; is something that doesn&#8217;t affect the process that we&#8217;re trying to make.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, when we &#8212; when we do deal with the Northern Triangle countries, it&#8217;s not giving money directly to the government, it&#8217;s working as well with the organizations on the ground.&nbsp; So that is also critical and important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;re going to keep an eye on that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to stay focused on that as well.&nbsp; And we should have more to share on the Guatemala situation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You have the person.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.&nbsp; I totally forgot.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Oh, my goodness.&nbsp; Give me one second.&nbsp; Our Fun Friday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, for our last question for our Fun Friday Zoom, a reporter hailing from Black Information Network, Vanessa. Vanessa.&nbsp; Hey, Vanessa Tyler.&nbsp; How are you?</p>



<p>(Reporter via Zoom denoted in <em>italics</em> is only heard via livestream. Audio is not played in the Press Briefing Room.)</p>



<p><em>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Karine.&nbsp; Thank you so much for taking my question.</em></p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, we cannot hear you.&nbsp;</p>



<p><em>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me?</em></p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Can&#8217;t hear you, Vanessa.</p>



<p><em>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me?&nbsp; Hello?</em></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We have questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; There are questions in the room, for sure.</p>



<p><em>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me now?</em></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, how do you test if that is the Delta variant &#8212; that COVID is the Delta variant?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t understand the question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, how do you test, when that is the dominant strain in the area &#8212; when people just test whether they&#8217;re COVID positive or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we don&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t test the &#8212; we don’t test it.&nbsp; We listen to public health and scientists, and they tell us that it&#8217;s the Delta variant.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have they explained their process on that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t even understand, why would they explain &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was saying, how do they explain their process and how they&#8217;re determining it&#8217;s the Delta variant?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, that&#8217;s what they are telling us.&nbsp; I laid out why &#8212; why they &#8212; I laid out how contagious it was and I laid out why we needed to act on the Delta variant.&nbsp; I laid out &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I get that, but a lot of what &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; what I &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the answers we get is, “Because they say so,&#8221; without a lot of (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, they&#8217;re the experts.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just “they.”&nbsp; These are scientists.&nbsp; These are experts.&nbsp; I just said that &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know, but they&#8217;ve contradicted &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hold on one second.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; themselves &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; hold on one second.&nbsp; I just said that Dr. Walensky said just recently, in her 20-year career, she had never seen a variant that was so contagious.&nbsp; So, this is 20 years of her career.&nbsp; So this is absolutely, absolutely a major, major problem that we are trying to deal with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we heard from the President yesterday.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we keep talking about people need to get vaccinated.&nbsp; So, that is &#8212; that is the &#8212; that is the way that we&#8217;re trying to move in this administration: making sure that we are protecting people here, making sure that we&#8217;re dealing with this pandemic in a way that is effective.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s how we&#8217;re going to move forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Cross-talk from reporters.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll take another question.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The question is &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Eugene.&nbsp; Go ahead, Eugene.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In April, the Chief of Staff told Playbook that the Education Department was reviewing whether the President could forgive student debt, and that review would be done in a matter of weeks, rather than a matter of months.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering where that review stands.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, this is the student &#8212; the student &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Student debt relief.&nbsp; So, the President is signing away $10,000 or $50,000, which is a big ask for (inaudible).</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I think we&#8217;ve been &#8212; you know, the President, as you know, supports Congress providing $10,000 in student relief &#8212; in debt relief, and he continues to look into what the debt relief actions can be taken administratively.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an update on that at all right now, at this moment.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, the Department of Education is working in partnership with colleagues at the Department of Justice and the White House to review options with respect to debt cancellation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, again, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any update.</p>



<p>(Cross-talk from reporters.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Afghanistan &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question on &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have to wrap up.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have to wrap up, guys.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to have to wrap up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you so much.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did she ever get to ask?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you, everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about the (inaudible) reporter?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Can we hear you now?&nbsp; We still can’t hear you?</p>



<p>(Audio does not play in the room.)</p>



<p><em>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me now?</em></p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m so sorry.&nbsp; Are you on mute?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, she&#8217;s not.</p>



<p><em>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m not on mute, no.&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, it&#8217;s something in the room.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, so we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re trying to &#8212; we&#8217;re trying to hear you and we cannot.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Vanessa, I&#8217;m so sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so sorry.&nbsp; Do you want to write a note?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Let us know what your questions is?&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; All right, Vanessa, we&#8217;ll try next Friday.</p>



<p><em>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, thank you.&nbsp; Yeah, next Friday will be fine.&nbsp; I can hear you.&nbsp; I can hear you perfectly.&nbsp; I can hear you, and I understand &#8212;&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, guys.&nbsp; Vanessa, we’ll see you &#8212; we’ll try and do it next week.&nbsp;</p>



<p>3:21 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on&#160;Cuba</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/30/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-cuba/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 23:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 2:32 P.M. EDT SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Thanks so much, and good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Thank you for joining us this afternoon.&#160; And welcome to an on-background conference call where we’ll be &#8212; we’ll be discussing Cuba.&#160; For your reference, today we are joined by [senior administration official].&#160; And from this point on, we&#8217;ll be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>2:32 P.M. EDT<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much, and good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you for joining us this afternoon.&nbsp; And welcome to an on-background conference call where we’ll be &#8212; we’ll be discussing Cuba.&nbsp;<br><br>For your reference, today we are joined by [senior administration official].&nbsp; And from this point on, we&#8217;ll be referring to them as a “senior administration official,” per the ground rules of the call.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ll start with some quick remarks, and then we&#8217;ll open it up for question-and-answer.&nbsp; The contents of today&#8217;s briefing will be embargoed until 3:45 p.m. this afternoon.&nbsp; And as always, if you have follow-up questions, feel free to email me or the NSC press team distro at <a href="mailto:DL.NSC.Press@NSC.eop.gov">DL.NSC.Press@NSC.eop.gov</a>.&nbsp;<br><br>And with that, I’ll turn the floor over to [a senior administration official].<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; It&#8217;s been a busy week at the White House and the administration in general on Latin America.&nbsp;<br><br>You all saw on Monday that Secretary Blinken &#8212; the State Department released a joint statement with 20 countries condemning the crackdown on peaceful protesters in &#8212; that came out into the streets all over Cuba on July 11th.&nbsp; We also rolled out this week, as you saw, the Central America collaborative migration and root causes strategy.<br><br>On Thursday, we met with the Mexican delegation to think really strategically about how we can look at migration management beyond the bilateral relationship and looking at a, kind of, hemispheric approach to migration management.&nbsp;<br><br>You saw that we put up the Federal Register notice on Haiti temporary protected status and it marked the date to &#8212; you know, to reflect since the assassination of President Jovenel Moïse.&nbsp; And we have rolled out the President’s intention to nominate a well-respected academic and former policymaker at the Defense Department, Frank Mora, as the U.S. ambassador to the Organization of American States.&nbsp;<br><br>What the President is doing today is &#8212; is part of what has been a very active period of engagement in response to the July 11th protests.&nbsp; And he is doing &#8212; he&#8217;s going to take the time to meet with members of the Cuban American community, as well as Senator Robert Menendez, Chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, and Greg Meeks, the Chairman of the House Foreign Affairs Committee.<br><br>And basically, the President wants to hear directly from the community on not just the goings on and &#8212; but, frankly, what the President has said, which is how to hold the Cuban regime accountable for its violations of human rights, but also, at the same time, focusing on responding to the needs of the Cuban people.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what we are &#8212; in addition to that conversation, we have Treasury Department, the Office of Foreign Assets Control, is going to have sanctions that are going to be coming out today.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t get into specifics except to say that&#8211; except that one entity and two Cuban individuals are going to be designated pursuant to the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act for their role in human rights abuses.<br><br>You know, I already mentioned Frank Mora, that we are in talks with private sector providers about the possibility of providing wireless LTE communications to the Cuban people, which we consider to be a right.&nbsp; We&#8217;re including all options, but we&#8217;re also looking at other ways to make sure that the Cuban people have the right to information, the right to communicate with each other, and the international community can really see the abuses that are taking place.&nbsp;<br><br>We are also going to be talking about humanitarian support for the Cuban people.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to have a few points to mention with regard to explaining the way forward for the remittance working group and just plans for the embassy staffing going forward.<br><br>So, but again, really the focus here is to hear from members of Congress that have been active on this issue from &#8212; from members of the Cuban American community.&nbsp; And it follows on engagements by Congressman Cedric Richmond, senior advisor to the President, meeting with a much larger group of members of the community, but also meetings that I have had, at the request of Senator Menendez, with the Cuban American National Foundation, but also Cuba Decide, to hear all points of views on Cuba and really to try to do what&#8217;s best to provide the President and the Secretary of State with our best objective analysis and recommendations on the way forward following the July 11th protests in Cuba.<br><br>So, I&#8217;ll leave it there.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to enter into any &#8212; answer any questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thank you, [senior administration official], for doing this.&nbsp; And thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; One question regarding to the team at the State Department that is studying the possibilities and measures in order to help Cubans with the remittances and Internet without helping or providing support, if I can say that in that way, to the regime: Is there any specific measure that you can advance or tell us about these two possibilities?<br><br>I mean, sending remittances without using the Cuban bank system is quite difficult.&nbsp; There is no other bank system in Cuba that is not controlled by the regime.&nbsp; And providing Internet, it seems that it would be a kind of activity that the &#8212; it would violate the Cuban sovereignty of the territory, and it could create maybe a counterproductive situation.<br><br>I mean, what are the real options besides just repeating that you are studying that and you&#8217;re studying and trying to identify technical solutions?&nbsp; Is there anything concrete that you can tell us today?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get out ahead of the President.&nbsp; I think anything that&#8217;s discussed at the meeting will &#8212; will be rolled out afterward.&nbsp; But, you know, you hit two very &#8212; two, you know, very real challenges when it comes to Internet connectivity, but also the issue of remittances.<br><br>On the latter, look, I&#8217;ll say that technology is advancing every day.&nbsp; And in the example of Venezuela, for example, we&#8217;ve actually been able to roll out licenses that have allowed, you know, the interim government to send money directly to people in Venezuela.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, what I think is really important here is we have looked at recommendations that even came out under the previous administration.&nbsp; They put together a Internet communications working group that issued a series of recommendations.&nbsp; We looked at those.&nbsp; But then, what we want to do is, we put together a U.S. government group together.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to consult with, you know, members of Congress, with the experts, and try to make some recommendations on how &#8212; on what&#8217;s the best way to go forward.<br><br>The point here is &#8212; again, is maximizing the benefit to the Cuban people, and that really has to be the focus of everything that we do in this situation.&nbsp;<br><br>With regard to Internet connectivity, there are no silver bullets.&nbsp; If it&#8217;s something that could be done easily, it would have been done already in places like Iran and in other closed regimes.&nbsp; You know, but &#8212; we see the access to &#8212; we see the censorship of information as a violation of human rights.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re going to explore every option possible to be able to guarantee that access to that information.<br><br>But also, in a &#8212; you know, in a transparent manner, what our Cuban democracy programs and our Google programs do is &#8212; is actually support, you know, civil society, artists, musicians to be able to do what they do without any sort of ideological objective, but just to do &#8212; practice their craft and &#8212; but that also includes access to information, the ability to communicate with each other, but also the importance of making sure that that the international community is not blind to the abuses and the crackdown that&#8217;s being perpetrated by the Cuban regime.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; Here at the White House, we&#8217;ve seen massive protests lately that included thousands of Cuban Americans who are asking for more action from this administration &#8212; that includes Republican legislators, as well.<br><br>I have two questions.&nbsp; The first one is: Is this administration &#8212; or the President, for that matter &#8212; meeting with any Republican legislators &#8212; not necessarily today, but maybe in the following days or in the previous days?&nbsp;<br><br>And also, can you give us full &#8212; not a full, but maybe like some &#8212; a list of the participants that are going to be taking part in this meeting with the President later on today?<br><br>And is the administration &#8212; has the administration a set plan towards Cuba?&nbsp; Or is it open to new ideas that might come out either from the participants today or from legislators in Congress?&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks for the question.&nbsp; So, look, we&#8217;ve been &#8212; we&#8217;ve been listening to the protesters, you know, when &#8212; I&#8217;m here on the weekends.&nbsp; And, you know, we&#8217;ve been listening to them and we&#8217;ve been talking to members of the community.&nbsp; And I will say that, when I say “we,” I mean the administration.<br><br>The State Department has been regularly briefing members of Congress from the House and the Senate.&nbsp; And, of course, we &#8212; I think the dialogues that Congressman Richmond, that I have engaged in, but also at the State Department&nbsp;and others have been engaging in are to he- &#8212; are to listen to Cuban Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s important to really listen to their voices and what they&#8217;re calling for, and &#8212; but also to &#8212; really to make sure that we keep the focus not on the United States or the conflict with the United States and Cuba, but rather on the Cuban people and the rights that they&#8217;re demanding.&nbsp; And the focus the international community needs to be to stand up for them, to stand up for their rights, and to make sure that we&#8217;re doing everything to support them, including, by any means, to prov- &#8212; you know, provide &#8212; efforts to provide humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know, those who are political dissidents are be &#8212; are abandoned by the government.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t have access to basic necessities.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t have access to hospital services.&nbsp; They&#8217;re cut off &#8212; they and their families are cut off.&nbsp; And so, I think it&#8217;s important for the international community to stand up for these people.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I mean, I guess &#8212; you asked if the President had already made up his mind on Cuba policy or if he&#8217;s willing to hear more from the community.&nbsp; My response to that is that that&#8217;s why he&#8217;s holding these meetings, but also why he&#8217;s receiving daily updates on the situation and why the State Department primarily has been engaging regularly with members of Congress to hear their views.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s why, for example, the remittance working group is one that is going to be engaging with members of Congress to try to get, you know, as much guidance as possible.&nbsp; I mean, I don&#8217;t know &#8212; I think that answers your question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, good afternoon.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; Just to clarify, should we expect an announcement today on Internet access or on remittances or not?&nbsp;<br><br>And secondly, on the sanctions, I know you don&#8217;t want to give information in advance of the OFAC release, but just a general question: How effective do you think that these sanctions on Cuban officials can be, since 50 years of embargo and sanctions have not succeeded in changing their (inaudible) behavior?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, no, on the second question, that&#8217;s an important question.&nbsp; Look, what we&#8217;re doing through these individual sanctions, as the President has said, is that we are focusing on individuals and entities that are involved in the crackdown and the violation of human rights by the regime.&nbsp; Part of it is to layer on sanctions, but the other one is to make sure that we are keeping these individuals in the spotlight not just on the international community, but that the Cuban people know that the United States is supporting them and is trying to defend them.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; as the President said, the sanctions are rolled out that &#8212; last week were just the beginning.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to try to keep &#8212; we&#8217;re going to do everything we can to keep Cuba on the front burner so that they can talk about &#8212; keep the conversation on the &#8212; on the rights of the Cuban people and their &#8212; and their right to manifest peacefully.<br><br>&nbsp;And so the other &#8212; sorry, what was the other question you had? &nbsp;I didn’t get the first question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you hear me?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, we can hear you.&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; My question was whether we can expect an announcement today on &#8212;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp; Yeah, yeah, yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; (inaudible) remittances.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp; So, look, we are going to be &#8212; we&#8217;re going to be announcing a series of things.&nbsp; And, you know, those include efforts to improve Internet connectivity and other means to make sure that we are supporting the ability of the Cuban people to communicate with each other.&nbsp; And we see information as something that should be treated as a human right.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; To follow up on that: Are you going to be announcing anything on remittances?&nbsp; Are you going to be announcing anything on our diplomats going back to Havana and theirs coming back to Washington?&nbsp; And if the President wanted to hear from all points of view &#8212; at least you haven&#8217;t mentioned any Republicans who are going to be present &#8212; is Senator Rubio or any other Republican members or senators going to be present?&nbsp;<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thank you, Andrea.&nbsp;<br><br>So, he is going to be making &#8212; he is going to be making announcements on both.&nbsp; Either in the meeting or afterward, I think he’s going to be &#8212; some of it he’ll mention, you know, at the camera spray at the top.&nbsp; Some of it may come up at the meeting.&nbsp;<br><br>I think the focus is going to be on hearing from members of the community.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we do have plans to provide more information on the Remittance Working Group that he directed the U.S. government to form and plans for U.S. Embassy augmentation.&nbsp;<br><br>What I&#8217;ll say is it that, look &#8212; given the protests of July 11th, it is important for U.S. diplomats to engage directly with the Cuban people.&nbsp; And if we can do that in a way that is &#8212; that ensures the safety of U.S. personnel, that is something that &#8212; that we will undertake.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll be able to say something more about that &#8212; the meeting.&nbsp;<br><br>So, what the focus of the meeting today &#8212; and the participants, and I can mention some of them &#8212; is &#8212; are members of the Cuban American community.&nbsp; They are going to be the ones that are going to be the main speakers here.&nbsp; And we invited the respective Chair of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and the Chair of the House Foreign Affairs Committee to join the conversation as well.&nbsp;<br><br>But we&#8217;re going to have individuals like Felice Gorordo, who is the CEO of eMerge Americas and has worked for Republican and Democratic administrations.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re going to also be hearing from Yotuel Romero, who is the Grammy Award winning artist and activist that wrote the song “Patria y Vida.”&nbsp;<br><br>We have, also, members of the religious community &#8212; Father Fernando Eduardo Heria, Director of the National Shrine of Our Lady of Charity of Cuba.&nbsp;<br><br>And actually, several other people have been &#8212; have been invited.&nbsp;<br><br>But again, in the conversations that we&#8217;ve been having, we&#8217;ve been meeting with people across the political spectrum and folks that have a range of views.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I think it’s going to be only the beginning of a regular engagement with the Cuban American community so that we can develop the right policies to support the Cuban people. &nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; This is Anne Gearan with the Post. &nbsp;It &#8212; following on a couple of questions about the Internet connectivity: I mean, can you give us some specifics here, please, about what might be possibilities?<br><br>I mean, one thing that&#8217;s been reported is the potential to do balloons off the island.&nbsp; Other things that have been reported have been ways for the United States to direct Internet toward Cuba.&nbsp; Are those what&#8217;s under discussion here?&nbsp; Can you help us out a little bit so that we have something that we can actually report at 3:45?&nbsp;<br><br>And secondly, on the Internet, is there anything that you all could do in terms of connectivity that could not be blocked by the regime?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I can&#8217;t offer you many details on what we&#8217;re doing or what we&#8217;re going to be announcing because I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President.&nbsp; But what I&#8217;m saying is we&#8217;ve been &#8212; we heard, you know, the &#8212; Governor Ron DeSantis wrote a letter to the President.&nbsp; Senator Marco Rubio wrote a letter.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been hearing also in our consultations with &#8212; the administration&#8217;s consultations with members of Congress, and we&#8217;ve been exploring all those options.<br><br>So, the administration, (inaudible) the Department of Commerce, Department of Treasury, the FCC have been looking at what rulemaking authorizations, licenses we can provide that would allow any of those options to work.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re looking at &#8212; when we&#8217;re talking to private sector companies and looking at all the legal and technical restrictions to doing that, it&#8217;s challenging because whether you&#8217;re looking at satellite technology or balloons or anything, a lot of those signals are fairly easy to block.&nbsp; But we have to explore any and all options to &#8212; exhaust any and all options to provide Internet connectivity.<br><br>The other point I&#8217;ll mention, just in terms of &#8212; and this is, obviously, open source information &#8212; is that the regime actually cut Internet for, I think, between 30 minutes and an hour, maybe a little bit more, and after that was involved in selective blocking of websites and areas where there were specific protests.<br><br>In that regard, there are tools and there&#8217;s technology that civil society actors are able to use to circumvent censorship.&nbsp; There&#8217;s been a dramatic increase in their use of VPN technology, (inaudible) proxies.&nbsp; And so all of those are &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s all unclassified, it&#8217;s all out there.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s really about making sure that the Cuban American people have &#8212; or the Cuban people have the training and have the technical know-how and the tools to be able to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>And obviously, the goal is to support it so that the Cuban people can communicate with each other.&nbsp; And that information about the regime’s abuses can make it out into the &#8212; and be seen by the international community.<br><br>So we have funds in the Open Technology Fund.&nbsp; There&#8217;s work that we have with international partners.&nbsp; And so there are a lot of different options, and we&#8217;re trying to exhaust all of them to make sure that we&#8217;re doing everything possible to support those Cubans that are out in the streets &#8212; that were out in the streets demanding their rights.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And this is [senior administration official], and we&#8217;re just about out of time.&nbsp; I just want to say thanks to everyone for joining, especially since I know we also have the briefing going on concurrently &#8212; the White House briefing.<br><br>As a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to “a senior administration official.”&nbsp; The contents of the call are embargoed until 3:45.&nbsp; If you have any additional questions, feel free to reach out to me, and otherwise, have a great day.<br><br>2:56 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
