<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:50:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-63/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50740</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Sharon Beth Lewis, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2022, vice Alan L. Cohen, term expired.      Sharon Beth Lewis, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sharon Beth Lewis, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2022, vice Alan L. Cohen, term expired.</p>



<p>       Sharon Beth Lewis, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2028.   (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Patricia Hart Neuman, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for a term of four years, vice Robert D. Reischauer, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Patricia Hart Neuman, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund for a term of four years, vice Robert D. Reischauer, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Patricia Hart Neuman, of the District of Columbia, to be a Member of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund for a term of four years, vice Robert D. Reischauer, term expired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Senate transmitting the Extradition Treaty between the Government of the United&#160;States of America and the Government of the Republic of&#160;Albania</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/a-message-to-the-senate-transmitting-the-extradition-treaty-between-the-government-of-the-united-states-of-america-and-the-government-of-the-republic-of-albania/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 19:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50732</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE&#160;SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES: &#160; &#160;With a view to receiving the advice and consent of the Senate to ratification, I transmit herewith the Extradition Treaty between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of Albania (the &#8220;Treaty&#8221;), signed at Tirana on December 22, 2020.&#160;&#160;I also transmit,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE&nbsp;SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>&nbsp; &nbsp;With a view to receiving the advice and consent of the Senate to ratification, I transmit herewith the Extradition Treaty between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of Albania (the &#8220;Treaty&#8221;), signed at Tirana on December 22, 2020.&nbsp;&nbsp;I also transmit, for the information of the Senate, the report of the Department of State with respect to the Treaty.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;The Treaty would replace the extradition treaty between the United States and Albania, signed at Tirana on March 1, 1933.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Treaty follows generally the form and content of other extradition treaties recently concluded by the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;It would replace an outmoded list of extraditable offenses with a modern &#8220;dual criminality&#8221; approach, which would enable extradition for such offenses as money laundering, cyber-related crimes, and other newer offenses not appearing on the list.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Treaty also contains a modernized &#8220;political offense&#8221; clause and provides that extradition shall not be refused based on the nationality of the person sought.&nbsp;&nbsp;Finally, the Treaty incorporates a series of procedural improvements to streamline and expedite the extradition process.</p>



<p>   I recommend that the Senate give early and favorable consideration to the Treaty, and give its advice and consent to ratification.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"> JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>        April 7, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden for World Health Day&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/statement-from-president-joe-biden-for-world-health-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 17:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For too many families, in too many places, worrying about health problems and access to health care is a daily reality.&#160;&#160;So today, on World Health Day, let us reaffirm our commitment to building a future that is safer, more equitable, and healthier,&#160;for families here and abroad. Since day one of my Administration, we have renewed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For too many families, in too many places, worrying about health problems and access to health care is a daily reality.&nbsp;&nbsp;So today, on World Health Day, let us reaffirm our commitment to building a future that is safer, more equitable, and healthier,&nbsp;for families here and abroad.</p>



<p>Since day one of my Administration, we have renewed U.S. leadership in global health, starting here at home. As we vaccinated 255 million Americans and fought COVID-19, we also lowered health care costs and enrolled a record breaking 14.5 million people; expanded postpartum coverage in several states; released a new Overdose Prevention Strategy; and launched a national strategy to treat mental health and physical health concerns equally. </p>



<p>On the global stage, we have led an ambitious campaign with our allies and partners to fight COVID-19, strengthen global health systems, and finance future pandemic preparedness. We have already shipped more than 516 million COVID-19 vaccines to countries around the world, with no strings attached, and we have pledged another 700 million by the end of this year. But we have to keep up the fight. More work lies ahead, and Congress must continue funding our fight against COVID-19, at home&nbsp;<em>and</em>&nbsp;abroad.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>While we focus on COVID-19, we have also reinvigorated our efforts and our investments to&nbsp;address core global health challenges. We’re doubling down on our commitment to meet our 2030 goals to end the AIDS epidemic. We’re boosting efforts to fight tuberculosis and malaria, including through our $2 billion commitment to the Global Fund and by rallying contributions from around the world. We’re working to reverse the alarming downward trend in global life expectancy and the impacts of the climate crisis by making foundational investments in childhood vaccinations, maternal and reproductive health, and basic nutrition. And it’s why the United States&nbsp;joined the Universal Health Coverage Group of Friends – a coalition of countries dedicated to strengthening health systems and expanding access to health coverage around the world.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>This pandemic has spotlighted the critical role and bravery of health and care workers. That’s why I’ve asked my Administration to develop a global health workforce plan, to accelerate our contributions to the Sustainable Development Agenda and investments in health and care workers.</p>



<p>Our&nbsp;health and security at home are irrevocably connected to the health and security of people everywhere. On this World Health Day, let us recommit to making sure that all people can access the health care they need.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration’s Commitment to Global Health in the FY 2023 President’s&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-commitment-to-global-health-in-the-fy-2023-presidents-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 17:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50715</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States Government is proud to be the largest donor for global health and supporter of research and cooperation worldwide. As we work to end the COVID-19 pandemic, we remain committed to investing in global public health, science partnerships and collaboration, strengthening health systems and institutions, advancing global health security, and accelerating efforts towards&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States Government is proud to be the largest donor for global health and supporter of research and cooperation worldwide. As we work to end the COVID-19 pandemic, we remain committed to investing in global public health, science partnerships and collaboration, strengthening health systems and institutions, advancing global health security, and accelerating efforts towards achieving universal health coverage and the objectives of the Sustainable Development Agenda. The President’s Budget for Fiscal Year (FY) 2023 requests mandatory and discretionary funding totaling over $17 billion for the Department of State (State) and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) and over $11 billion for the Department of Health and Human Services to advance U.S. leadership in global health, including health system strengthening; HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis; maternal and child health; family planning and reproductive health; nutrition; global health security, and pandemic and other biological threat preparedness, and neglected tropical diseases.</p>



<p>We continue to lead the global community toward a safer, more equitable future.&nbsp;&nbsp;Investments in global health advance U.S. foreign policy interests by protecting Americans at home and abroad, promoting economic progress and recovery, and supporting the rise of capable partners to better solve regional and global problems.<br>Over the last year, the Biden-Harris Administration has renewed U.S. leadership in global health, and the FY 2023 Budget will continue to advance global health priorities on the following:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Strengthening health systems, including the global health workforce.&nbsp;</strong>The FY 2023 Budget prioritizes sustained investment across health programs to support health system resilience and strengthening. The Budget provides $1 billion in mandatory funding for State and USAID to support and protect the global health workforce as part of the Administration’s increased prioritization and investments in human resources for health.&nbsp;&nbsp;These resources are intended to support the Administration’s launch of a new Global Health Worker Initiative, which complements the Domestic Health Worker Initiative launched by the Administration last year.&nbsp;&nbsp;In addition, the FY 2023 Request includes $10 million for USAID to establish a Health Resilience Fund (HRF) to support cross-cutting health systems strengthening in countries emerging from crisis. The HRF will provide flexible, no-year funding to ensure basic health services are accessible to those most in need and to build more resilient health services and systems in order to prevent worse outcomes from ongoing health crises. The FY 2023 Request also includes over $265 million in discretionary funding for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) for partnerships that build critical health system capacity for global immunizations and the fight against parasitic diseases and malaria.<br></li><li><strong>Supporting enhanced global leadership on addressing HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis.</strong>&nbsp;The Budget includes $4.37 billion for State to support U.S. President’s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR) bilateral programs and the global AIDS response. Funds will continue to save lives, prevent millions of HIV infections, and help countries build a strong foundation to prevent, detect, and respond to other health threats, including COVID-19. Across 55 countries, PEPFAR invests in strengthening local health systems’ ability to respond to HIV. The FY 2023 Budget also includes $2 billion to support the Global Fund’s seventh replenishment for an intended pledge of $6 billion over three years, to save lives and continue the fight against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria, as well as $780 million for the U.S. President’s Malaria Initiative to continue the fight against malaria. Finally, the FY 2023 Budget requests $350 million for USAID to support programs combatting tuberculosis around the world.<br></li><li><strong>Strengthening multilateral global health institutions:</strong>&nbsp;Funding requested in FY 2023 will support efforts to strengthen our partnerships with multilateral global health institutions, including the World Health Organization and the United Nations Children’s Fund.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Building global health security and pandemic preparedness capacities.</strong>&nbsp;The FY 2023 President’s Budget includes nearly $750 million for USAID, and over $1.5 billion in mandatory and discretionary funding for CDC, to expand global health security capacity building to additional partner countries, strengthen global disease detection, bolster our commitment to the multilateral Global Health Security Agenda, and accelerate progress toward improved prevention, detection, and response to infectious disease threats. Funding through USAID would support $250 million for Access to COVID-19 Tools (ACT) Accelerator multilateral organizations, and $590 million in discretionary and mandatory funding to replenish USAID’s Emergency Reserve Fund for Contagious Infectious Diseases (ERF).&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Financing for global health security and pandemic preparedness.&nbsp;</strong>The Budget includes $4.75 billion in mandatory and discretionary funding for State to establish a new financial intermediary fund (FIF) at the World Bank focused on global health security and pandemic preparedness. This catalytic, fit-for-purpose financing mechanism is critical to filling major gaps in the world’s ability to prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease threats and future pandemics at the national, regional and global levels.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Budget also provides $500 million over five years for the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI) to support innovations in science and technological capabilities to shorten the cycle for development of safe, effective, and globally accessible vaccines for pathogens with pandemic potential.<br></li><li><strong>Building global medical countermeasure readiness, research and development,</strong>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<strong>advancing capacity to conduct variant and strain surveillance</strong>&nbsp;through support for global innovations in vaccine and therapeutics policy development, program design, and effective monitoring of the viral strains that are circulating globally to detect the emergence of significant variants. The Budget includes $5.9 billion in mandatory funding for CDC for this effort which would expand and strengthen multi-pathogen and molecular laboratory capabilities, bioinformatics systems, and data modernization to detect and monitor respiratory and other high-consequence pathogens.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Advancing biosafety and biosecurity in the United States and globally to prevent biological incidents.&nbsp;</strong>The Budget supports applied research and innovation in biosafety and biosecurity, which will expand capabilities to identify and minimize safety and security risks in the design and development of biotechnology. It also enables CDC and USAID to expand efforts to strengthen biosafety and biosecurity practices and globally.<br></li><li><strong>Leading global threat detection innovations</strong>&nbsp;through a globally connected network of public health surveillance systems that optimizes disease prevention and health promotion as we strengthen surveillance initiatives to provide necessary actionable data before, during, and after a pandemic. The Budget includes $2.47 billion in mandatory funding for CDC to will include enhancements to domestic sentinel surveillance programs, expansion of domestic and global wastewater surveillance, and investments in global genomic surveillance approaches as well as global respiratory disease surveillance platforms. CDC will transition and sustain genomic surveillance capacities initially developed for COVID-19 to support additional priority pathogens.<br></li><li><strong>Sustaining commitments in global maternal and child health.</strong>&nbsp;As the largest donor to both maternal health and voluntary family planning programs, including the provision of life-saving health care services in crisis settings, the United States will continue its efforts to make pregnancy and childbirth safer by strengthening health systems to provide women with integral health services, including increased access to maternal health care and voluntary family planning.&nbsp;The FY 2023 Budget includes $879.5 million for USAID to continue the United States’ sustained commitment to ensure that critical health services continue to prevent child and maternal deaths globally. This includes $290 million for a contribution to Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, to reach children with cost-effective vaccines to accelerate progress towards preventing child deaths. In addition, $25 million is requested for USAID to support&nbsp;the implementation of the U.S. Government’s Strategy Advancing Protection and Care for Children in Adversity and USAID’s Child Blindness Program to reduce childhood blindness and improve eye health.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing sexual and reproductive health and rights.</strong>&nbsp; In the last year, the Administration has taken several legislative and policy steps to advance sexual and reproductive rights around the world, starting with President Biden’s issuance of a Presidential Memorandum on Protecting Women’s Health at Home and Abroad in his first days in office, which revoked the expanded Mexico City Policy and directed agencies to resume funding to the United Nations Population Fund (UNFPA) in support of its essential work to prevent maternal deaths, expand access to voluntary family planning, and prevent and respond to gender-based violence around the world.&nbsp; Under the leadership of Secretary Blinken, the Department of State has returned to reporting on sexual and reproductive health issues in its Annual Country Reports on Human Rights. The Administration continues to advance sexual and reproductive health and rights (SRHR) for all, in support of accelerating progress toward universal health coverage and gender equality. The FY 2023 Budget provides $597 million to continue support for critical SRHR programs globally, as well as a $56 million contribution to the United Nations Population Fund. As the largest bilateral donor to family planning, the United States will continue to lead globally by advancing SRHR in multilateral fora and with bilateral partners. Funds will support increased access to SRHR services.<br></li><li><strong>Continuing to demonstrate strong global leadership on nutrition.</strong>&nbsp;Given increased rates of global malnutrition, and expected further impacts on global food security from Russia’s unprovoked further invasion of Ukraine, the United States will accelerate efforts to support global nutrition, particularly for vulnerable populations. The FY 2023 Budget includes $150 million for USAID for global health nutrition programs, in addition to over $1 billion in State and USAID economic and development assistance, $1.7 billion in emergency food aid via Food for Peace Title II, and humanitarian assistance to support food security and nutrition globally.<br></li><li><strong>Supporting efforts to address neglected tropical diseases.</strong>&nbsp;The FY 2023 Budget includes $114.5 million to continue USAID’s long-standing and effective public-private partnerships with pharmaceutical companies to focus on ending the most prevalent neglected tropical diseases (NTD). Over the past 15 years, USAID has leveraged $27.6 billion in donated medicines, resulting in the delivery of more than 2.8 billion treatments to approximately 1.4 billion people. This funding will also support USAID in achieving its goal to eliminate at least one NTD as a public health problem within 5 years in 15 countries, and to expand private sector partnerships.<br></li><li><strong>Leading the global COVID-19 response.</strong>&nbsp;The Biden Administration has submitted an urgent request to Congress for $5 billion to accelerate near-term COVID-19 global response.&nbsp;&nbsp;Without additional funding to support getting shots into arms, U.S. agencies will have to cut short efforts to turn vaccines into vaccinations across the globe.&nbsp;&nbsp;Leaving large unvaccinated populations worldwide will increase the risk of new, emerging deadly variants that could evade our current vaccines and treatments.&nbsp;&nbsp;Without additional funds, the Administration would be unable to extend Global VAX surge support to 20+ additional under-vaccinated countries that will need intensive support this year to get shots in arms. This will devastate our ability to ensure those countries can effectively deploy safe and effective vaccines. U.S. agencies will also be unable to provide life-saving supplies, tests, therapeutics, oxygen, and humanitarian aid to countries still struggling to manage a continuing COVID-19 disease burden.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Unprecedented IEA Release Following President&#160;Biden’s SPR&#160;Announcement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-unprecedented-iea-release-following-president-bidens-spr-announcement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 17:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50710</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Last week, President Biden announced a historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve of 1 million barrels a day for six months and said it would be in coordination with other countries releasing tens of millions of additional barrels on the market. Today after around the clock diplomacy by the United States and our allies&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Last week, President Biden announced a historic release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve of 1 million barrels a day for six months and said it would be in coordination with other countries releasing tens of millions of additional barrels on the market. Today after around the clock diplomacy by the United States and our allies and partners, the International Energy Agency announced a historic collective release with member countries outside of the United States releasing an additional 60 million barrels.&nbsp;Together&nbsp;with the United States’ commitment, this&nbsp;will add&nbsp;a combined global amount of 240 million barrels.&nbsp;It is both the largest release from the United States and the largest release from other IEA countries in history, and will support American consumers and the global economy.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement is another result of President Biden’s unwavering focus on doing everything in his power to help American families who are paying more out of pocket as a result of Putin’s war of choice against Ukraine. Since Putin accelerated his military build-up around Ukraine this past winter, gas prices have increased by nearly a dollar per gallon because less oil is getting to market, and the reduction in supply is raising prices at the pump for Americans. We will continue to take every action we can to increase supply in the immediate term so families can pay for gas while at the same time working with the international community to achieve energy independence that reduces demand for oil and bolsters our clean energy economy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden on Unemployment Insurance&#160;Claims</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/07/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-unemployment-insurance-claims-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Americans are getting back to work at a historic pace, with fewer America is back to work. Over the last four weeks, fewer Americans filed initial claims for unemployment insurance than at any time in our nation’s recorded history. Our economy added 7.9 million jobs since I took office – more jobs created on average&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Americans are getting back to work at a historic pace, with fewer America is back to work. Over the last four weeks, fewer Americans filed initial claims for unemployment insurance than at any time in our nation’s recorded history. Our economy added 7.9 million jobs since I took office – more jobs created on average per month than under any other President in history. That’s millions of families with a little more breathing room and the dignity a job provides. This historic job growth is a direct result of the American Rescue Plan, which funded our vaccination strategy, re-opened schools, and helped grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out. While we have more work to do to combat Putin’s Price Hike and lower costs for families, today’s data demonstrate that America is on the move again and the economy is uniquely well-positioned to overcome the global challenges brought on by the pandemic and Putin’s War of Choice.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, April 6,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/06/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-april-6-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 23:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50698</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 3:15 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay.&#160; Okay, a couple of items for you at the top.&#160;&#160;On his first day in office, President Biden directed the Department of Education to pause federal student loan repayments through September of that year.&#160; He has since extended it twice, today being the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>3:15 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Okay, a couple of items for you at the top.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On his first day in office, President Biden directed the Department of Education to pause federal student loan repayments through September of that year.&nbsp; He has since extended it twice, today being the third extension.&nbsp; Millions of Americans were struggling, of course, at that time to stay afloat.&nbsp; Because of the pause in repayments, 41 million Americans were able to breathe a little easier during some of the toughest days of the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today, as America &#8212; America is stronger than we were a year ago and we will be stronger a year from now than we are today.&nbsp; However, as our administration recognized in recently extending the COVID-19 national emergency, we are still recovering from the pandemic and the unprecedented economic disruption it caused &#8212; which, of course, is the root reason for this extension.<br>&nbsp;<br>In order to enable Americans to continue to get back on their feet after two of the hardest years this nation has ever faced, we have announced, earlier today, of course, the plan to &#8212; the extension of the pause on federal student loan repayments through August 31st of this year.&nbsp; That additional time will assist borrowers in achieving greater financial security and support the Department of Education’s efforts to continue improving student loan programs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Also would note &#8212; one note on the COVID funding bill.&nbsp; We have made clear for months about our funding needs.&nbsp; And at every step of the way, we&#8217;ve provided the details that Republicans have asked for, even when they&#8217;ve asked for &#8212; has changed in real time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I have a little prop here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to call him “Vanna” over here.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; This is Kevin Munoz.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is 385 pages of information we have given to Capitol Hill and briefed them on how COVID funding has been spent, what we need, what the needs are.&nbsp; These are the kind of details we have provided and constantly briefed members on the Hill to make clear to them what the impact will be if we do not get this funding.&nbsp; You can have access to this for a prop if you would like it as well.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll make copies for you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay.&nbsp; But unfortunately, as we&#8217;ve gone through before, going back to January &#8212; while we&#8217;ve worked, going back to January, with members of Congress &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; on the funding needs, we&#8217;ve hosted dozens of briefings, we&#8217;ve held more than three dozen conference calls, we&#8217;ve shared more than a dozen funding tables &#8212; all available 385 pages.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve also given Congress a full accounting of every dollar that&#8217;s been spent on the COVID medical response and a full accounting of the entire American Rescue Plan, which, as you all know, goes well beyond the direct medical needs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve also provided all the specifics of planned additional funding: how it will be deployed against the additional purchase of monoclonals and pills and vaccine &#8212; vaccines.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And unfortunately, even after Senate leadership agreed upon a &#8212; on a pared down bipartisan bill, Senate Republicans decided to move the goalposts yet again and force amendment votes on something completely independent of our COVID response needs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And at this point, we &#8212; the question we have is whether Republicans are acting in good faith to provide the resources we need to save American lives or if they are just playing politics.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The virus is not waiting for Republicans in Congress to get their act together.&nbsp; We know BA.2 is here.&nbsp; We know that it is more transmissible.&nbsp; We know that it is leading to increased cases, and we know we&#8217;re already seeing an impact on our resources.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The program that reimbursed doct- &#8212; doctors, pharmacists, and other providers for vaccinating the uninsured had to end yesterday due to a lack of funds.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>America&#8217;s supply of monoclonal antibodies that are effective at keeping people out of the hospital will run out as soon as late May.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And our test-manufacturing capacity will begin ramping down at the end of June.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we&#8217;re going to continue to work closely with Congress to drive to a solution, because the President knows that we can&#8217;t afford inaction in this moment.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to require politicians stopping &#8212; to stop skirting their responsibility to the American people.&nbsp; COVID is not over, and we have an obligation to protect our country, the American people, and make sure we&#8217;re taking steps to prepare.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, last thing: Last night, as you may have all seen, we announced the authorization of an additional $100 million in security assistance &#8212; the Department of Defense announced &#8212; to Ukraine through presiden- &#8212; through presidential drawdown authority.&nbsp; This package will meet Ukraine&#8217;s urgent need for additional Javelin anti-armor systems, which we&#8217;ve been providing to Ukraine and they have been using effectively to defend their country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The Javelins have been one of the most effective weapons the Ukrainians have been &#8212; have deployed in combating Russian tanks and Russian armored vehicles.&nbsp; They were critical in the defense of Kyiv and other areas, and we want to ensure we continue to get them in the Ukrainians’ hands.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also continue to work with our allies and partners to provide Ukraine with additional capabilities and expect to have more to announce in the coming days.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Kevin has been out here before, so I have already embarrassed him in the past, and I will keep it short.&nbsp; But Kevin, as many of you know, is our COVID spokesperson.&nbsp; Kevin only recently turned 26, which means he can barely rent a car.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But he is &#8212; he can now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. MUNOZ:&nbsp; I can now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But he &#8212; he has become an expert.&nbsp; He is stalwart.&nbsp; He works 20 hours a day.&nbsp; And he is indispensable.&nbsp; And so, I&#8217;m very grateful to Kevin and happy he&#8217;s out here to provide the prop but also to provide all of you with many, many answers on a daily basis.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, with that, Zeke.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; You just mentioned that COVID isn&#8217;t over.&nbsp; We just saw the President give remarks to a very large crowd indoors.&nbsp; I was hoping you’d speak a little bit to how the President views, sort of, what &#8212; when it is safer to be going to such large gatherings.&nbsp; Is that the sort of thing he’s trying to model for the rest of the American public?&nbsp; That the risks for most people from COVID now are lesser than they were a year or two ago before vaccines and treatments?&nbsp; Is that sort of behavior now &#8212; it&#8217;s not something that should be stigmatized or &#8212; and should be embraced?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I think what the President is doing is he is following CDC protocols and models, and that&#8217;s exactly what we would recommend the rest of the country do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That includes getting vaccinated; getting boosted; getting an extra booster if you are eligible, as the President did just last week; and obviously taking any steps or precautions that the CDC recommends to keep yourself safe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, in Washington, D.C., we remain in a yellow zone, and the President follows those protocols as needed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just an update: He said &#8212; did he say when the last &#8212; the last time the President tested for COVID?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I suspected you would ask this.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve asked this question, and I will get you an answer to that as quickly as possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As you know, he is tested on &#8212; he has a regular testing cadence &#8212; is usually tested a couple times a week.&nbsp; We will venture to get to that as soon as possible after the briefing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And on a different topic, the U.S. today sanctioned a number of Russians, including Vladimir Putin’s daughters, as well as some other senior officials.<br>&nbsp;<br>I was hoping you’d might be able to speak a little bit about sort of the &#8212; the administration’s thinking about when are family members of Russian oligarchs and Russian government officials, sort of, fair game for sanctions and how you’ve weighed and (inaudible) distinction between minors and adults, in this case, with, sort of, you know, collective punishment or trying to prevent them from harboring assets with, you know, people who are not necessarily involved in the decision-making in Ukraine but have, sort of, maybe benefited from that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve seen a pattern over time of President Putin and Russian oligarchs stash assets and resources in the bank accounts and &#8212; of their family members.&nbsp; And so, this was an effort to get at those assets, and that&#8217;s why these individuals were sanctioned.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so there’s no &#8212; but why the distinction, then, between minors and adults?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we look at where assets may be stored and stashed and make a decision and an assessment on what&#8217;s appropriate.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The New York Times has a verified video that appears to show a group of Ukrainian soldiers killing captured Russian troops outside a village just west of Kyiv.&nbsp; Has the White House seen these videos?&nbsp; Do you have a response?&nbsp; Is this something you&#8217;re investigating?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have seen the video; I don&#8217;t have any confirmation or validation of the video or the report.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so far, the administration &#8212; or the U.S. has spent about $2 billion since the beginning of this invasion.&nbsp; Obviously, you know, you&#8217;ve said the U.S. is committed to doing everything it can to help Ukraine in this fight.&nbsp; But if General Milley is correct in what he said yesterday &#8212; that this really could go on for several years &#8212; are these numbers sustainable over the long term?&nbsp; Can you keep up at this pace?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first &#8212; just to reiterate what General Milley said and the President has also been clear &#8212; that there are tough days ahead for the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a likely scenario where there &#8212; this could go on for some time.&nbsp; And even as they have moved their forces and they&#8217;ve retreated from Kyiv &#8212; they retreated from the north and the west, and they&#8217;re consolidating forces in the east and in the Donbas.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve warned that we&#8217;re entering a new phase of the conflict that could last for some time.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t mean it will look exactly the same or the needs or the resources will be exactly the same.&nbsp; And that is something we will continue to assess in our conversations with the Ukrainians, as well as with our allies and partners around the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And right now, just to note, obviously, our focus is on amping up and providing a range of military assistance of &#8212; the $100 million for Javelins is a good example of that &#8212; as they are in an active fight every single day against the Russian military.&nbsp; Also, humanitarian and economic assistance.&nbsp; And there will be different needs that will come about over the course of time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that&#8217;s something we are, of course, committed to continuing to support: their recovery from this, their continued fight from this.&nbsp; But I can&#8217;t make an assessment about sustaining because, obviously, this war and the needs will change over the course of time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if this is a really protracted, prolonged conflict, given what the Treasury Secretary said today &#8212; sort of warning of the enormous economic repercussions of this war for the whole world &#8212; what does this mean for the economy in the U.S. for the next year or two?&nbsp; Can you just give us sort of a big picture of what Americans should be bracing for?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as we&#8217;ve made decisions about putting sanctions in place, we&#8217;ve continued to do that through the prism of maximizing the impact on Russia, on the Russian economy while minimizing the impact on the West and the United States.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, there are areas where there has been an impact, including on the price of gas.&nbsp; And you saw the Federal Reserve convey today the impact of the Russian invasion on inflation.&nbsp; And we know that to be the case.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what we&#8217;re trying to do is mitigate those impacts.&nbsp; And obviously, not just the announcement of the Strate- &#8212; release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, but the announcement by the IE &#8212; IEA today is the largest release that they have ever done in history.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And all of these are part of our collective effort to impact &#8212; to mitigate the impacts on the American people over the course of time.&nbsp; Even the length of time of the release from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve &#8212; meant to be a stopgap measure or kind of a bridge measure, to get to the point where oil companies could produce more &#8212; is intended to have a mitigation impact over the course of time.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I &#8212; what we&#8217;re doing is anticipating and trying to step &#8212; take steps to reduce the impact on the American people over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up on that IEA question: Do you have a detail or figure of how much oil has been released of the 180 million barrels to date?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to get that for you.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure that our team may have that, but I don&#8217;t have that in front of me.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask &#8212; President Biden today told union members, “Amazon, here we come.”&nbsp; Was he endorsing the efforts of union &#8212; of workers to unionize Amazon facilities?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What he was not doing is sending a message that he or the U.S. government would be directly involved in any of these efforts or take any direct action.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What he was conveying is that &#8212; is his longtime support for collective bargaining, for the rights of workers to organize, and their decision to do exactly that in this case &#8212; something that he has long supported broadly over the course of his career.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just back to the issue of the sanctions that are being imposed on Putin’s children and, obviously, sanctions against him as well.&nbsp; Does the U.S. have a rough estimate, at this moment in time, of how much of his assets are tied up versus what he still might have access to?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an assessment to offer from here on that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But we know that &#8212; we&#8217;ve seen attempts and efforts to stash assets in the accounts and resources of his children.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A senior administration official, earlier today, was raising the question of Putin’s endgame &#8212; that, at some point, he would presumably recognize that this war has been a failure for him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Given some of the scenes that we&#8217;re seeing in places like Bucha and Mariupol, does the U.S. believe that he is any closer to realizing that reality today versus a week ago, a month ago?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, remember, the scenes we&#8217;re seeing in Bucha are from events and atrocities that didn&#8217;t happen yesterday.&nbsp; They happened some time ago.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; And there will be more of those &#8212; which our Secretary of State and our National Security Advisor have also predicted, unfortunately &#8212; because there are a lot of areas of the country where Russia has invaded and committed atrocities &#8212; no doubt &#8212; which we have not yet had visual access to.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would say that I can&#8217;t make an assessment for you from here on what is in President Putin&#8217;s mind.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we do know is that because of the impact of the economic sanctions, including the ones we have taken today, and steps we&#8217;ve taken over the course of time, we have seen an unquestionable, significant impact on Russia&#8217;s economy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And that has led to this question now, as a result of the decision around whether or not they would be able to make a bond payment earlier this week, that they will have to decide whether they are going to spend down dollars and resources they have to avoid default or whether they&#8217;re going to spend that money &#8212; continue to spend that money in funding the war.&nbsp; And that is a part of our objective &#8212; is to force them into a place where they are making that decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;ve seen Russia&#8217;s economy collapse by 15 percent, wiping out the gains made in the last 15 years.&nbsp; Inflation is spiking up to 15 percent.&nbsp; Russia is set to lose its status as a major economy.&nbsp; And our objective is to implement those consequences to make it much more difficult for President Putin to fund the war &#8212; and we&#8217;re seeing the direct impacts of that already &#8212; and to make it clear that this was a strategic blunder.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re already seeing those impacts on the economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>How that impacts him and &#8212; you know, that &#8212; that is not something I can predict in terms of getting into his mind.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the administration&#8217;s current assessment of what Putin&#8217;s endgame is?&nbsp; And does the administration believe that that may have shifted since the beginning of the invasion?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we &#8212; I would say that, one, while they have moved their troops around and repositioned, we have not made &#8212; and they haven&#8217;t made many airstrikes in the last 24 hours, according to Department of Defense and their briefing, which you may have seen, or their backgrounder &#8212; we also know that, you know, their goal remains weakening Ukraine as much as possible.&nbsp; And we should be under no illusion that that objective hasn&#8217;t changed, even as their tactics have changed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The President today, as he was talking about his vow to stand by Ukrainians, added a line: “And, by the way, if I&#8217;ve got to go to war, I&#8217;m going with you guys.”&nbsp; Can you clarify what that meant?&nbsp; Is &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has no intention of sending boot &#8212; troops to the ground or fighting a war between &#8212; with the U.S. forces against Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That was a reflection of his long love for labor unions, and members of labor unions, and the building and trades workers who were there, and people that he would always love to be in the foxhole with &#8212; not an indication of a change in U.S. policy.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Got it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He also referred to that heated exchange we saw that involved Secretary Austin.&nbsp; And he said, with regard to Ukrainian troops, “We&#8217;ve trained them and we&#8217;ve given them the weapons.”&nbsp; Can you clarify what he meant by “We have trained them”?&nbsp; What training was he talking about?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there was some, some time ago &#8212; training.&nbsp; And we have provided them, obviously, a range of weapons over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What point he was making is one Secretary Austin made yesterday: Without the extensive military assistance that we have been providing the Ukrainians &#8212; the security assistance &#8212; over the course of the last several weeks and even months before that &#8212; $1.6 billion worth, maybe a little higher now after the $100 million last night &#8212; they would not have been able to effectively fight back as they have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And how it has basically worked is: They have requested a range of assistance.&nbsp; We go through and see what we are able to provide.&nbsp; We often work with partners and allies to provide assistance we don&#8217;t have access to here.&nbsp; And then we expedite the delivery of that over the course of time, whether that is Javelin, Stingers, or a range of materials that are &#8212; the U.S. military has determined they&#8217;re not only trained on but has been effective in fighting this war.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Aside from the physical resources, what training was he talking about?&nbsp; What was the latest training the U.S. troops have done?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s not new training to report out to you.&nbsp; What he was really emphasizing and the important part here is what Secretary Austin was also talking about, is the military equipment that has been provided that has allowed them to fight this war.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And one more &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on sanctions.&nbsp; You said a couple times now that, you know, the U.S. sanctioned Putin’s daughters because there&#8217;s reason to believe Putin has stashed his wealth with them.&nbsp; Does that mean that the U.S. has some information about where the billionaire daughters are stashing their wealth?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more to provide to you from here.&nbsp; We make assessments about where to implement financial sanctions to get close to not only the assets of President Putin, but those around him.&nbsp; And we have seen a long pattern of using relatives and family members to stash wealth.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; First, on immigration: Our team in Texas is that saying that you guys are starting to give smartphones to border crossers, hoping that they&#8217;ll use the phones to check in or to be tracked.&nbsp; I &#8212; which part of that is supposed to deter people from crossing illegally into the states?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think you of all people &#8212; since you&#8217;ve asked me a range of questions on this topic over time &#8212; would recognize that we need to take steps to ensure that we know where individuals are and we can track &#8212; and we can check in with them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The alternatives to detention programs &#8212; is what we utilize &#8212; has three unique forms of technology to monitor participants enrolled in the program:<br>&nbsp;<br>Telephonic, which is one of them, which is uses a participant’s voice to create a biometric voice print during the enrollment process.&nbsp; And when the participant has a check-in call, their voice is compared to the voice print.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SmartLink, which is another option, enables participant monitoring via smartphone or tablet using facial-matching technology to establish identity.<br>&nbsp;<br>And Global Positioning System monitoring is of a participant’s location and movement history, using satellite technology through an ankle bracelet.&nbsp; This is all part of our effort, as individuals come into the United States and individuals who are entering who will proceed to immigration proceedings, to monitor and track where they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With the telephonic, though, any concern by folks around here that these migrants will take the phones and just<br>toss them?&nbsp; And then &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Do you have a record of people throwing phones away?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m just asking if that&#8217;s a concern.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our concern is ensuring that individuals who irregularly migrate to the United States proceed through our process of, you know, of course, being monitored, but also participating in &#8212; in hearings to determine whether or not they will be able to stay.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that nearly 80 percent of non-citizens released at the border from DHS custody under prosecut- &#8212; prosecutorial discretion have either received a notice to appear or are still within their window to report.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, actually, the vast, vast majority of people are appearing.&nbsp; In part, we have these monitors and monitoring systems in order to do that effectively.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; On another topic, was it common for President Biden to do favors for Hunter Biden&#8217;s international business partners like writing college recommendations for their kids?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have &#8212; I&#8217;ve seen the report.&nbsp; I have no confirmation or comments on a report about whether or not the President, when he was a private citizen, wrote a college recommendation letter for an individual.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A college recommendation letter, though, from, at the time, a former Vice President would be a big deal.&nbsp; So, do we know what the President might have gotten in return for doing a favor like that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Again, I have no confirmation of any recommendation letter the President wrote when he was a private citizen &#8212; by the way, not serving in public office.&nbsp; That&#8217;s even in the report.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But he&#8217;s the President now, and you&#8217;re his spokesperson.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; And he was not the President at the time of this report.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, there&#8217;s evidence that the President, at one point, was officemates with Hunter and his brother Jim here in D.C.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not accurate.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That is not accurate?&nbsp; So, when Hunter Biden is emailing a landlord, “Please have keys made available for new officemates &#8212; Joe Biden, Jill Biden, Jim Biden,” that &#8212; you&#8217;re disputing it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They were not officemates, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They were not officemates.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Great.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; On student loans, briefly &#8212; and you were sort of asked about this yesterday, but I just wanted to come back to it.&nbsp; So, as people plan for the future, should borrowers expect that after August 31st, they&#8217;ll have to repay their loans?&nbsp; Or is there another &#8212; is there a chance that it could be further extended after August 31st?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue to assess.&nbsp; And what we look at &#8212; while, of course, the economy is in a better state than it is &#8212; than it was a year ago, and it&#8217;s &#8212; we have a strong recovery, we also understand that there are a range of impacts that are still longer lasting because of the pandemic, including the impacts on costs and inflation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And this is part of the President&#8217;s effort to help alleviate that, as was fix &#8212; as was the “family glitch” announcement of yesterday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we&#8217;ll make an evaluation.&nbsp; The Department of Education will look at that and a range of factors as we get closer to that timeline.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And has the President, at this point, ruled out a possible executive-level cancellation on a widescale of student debt?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He has not ruled out, but I don’t have any update on that.&nbsp; And I would note that, again, he would encourage Congress to send him a bill cancelling $10,000 in student debt, something that he talked about looking forward to signing on the campaign trail.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just really briefly, on the G20 &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; Secretary Yellen said today that they may not &#8212; that the U.S. might not attend meetings if Russians are there.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is she implying that these would just be individual meetings, or would it be a kind of broader-scale boycott of the G20 in Bali?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; She &#8212; I think they have later clarified she was referencing at the ministerial level and, more specific, meetings.&nbsp; I would point you to them of the more specifics.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President has also said &#8212; he said on the trip that he did not think Russia should be a part of the G20, you know, meeting.&nbsp; And I would note it&#8217;s seven months away, which is a lifetime in our &#8212; in our lives.&nbsp; But it wasn&#8217;t an indication of plans for us to boycott or not attend.&nbsp; It was just, “It shouldn&#8217;t be business as usual,” which is something the President has also said.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, is it a priority of the President to try to identify the Russian units that carried out the atrocities in Bucha?&nbsp; Is that something that the U.S. may be able to do?&nbsp; And is it something the President wants to have happen?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will continue to assist in every way possible with these efforts to track down data, additional information, and contribute to the international effort to do exactly that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; May I ask, if I can, a couple of other questions that made news today?&nbsp; A judge has just issued the first outright acquittal of a defendant charged in the January 6th Capitol riot.&nbsp; This was a New Mexico man, Matthew Martin.&nbsp; He was acquitted on some misdemeanor charges by the judge.&nbsp; This man had claimed that he thought police allowed him into an entrance near the Capitol Rotunda.&nbsp; Does the White House have any view now that that case has been adjudicated?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any specific comment on that case.&nbsp; We continue to support the efforts of the January 6th commission and all of the members in trying to get to the bottom of what happened that day to prevent it from happening in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me go back to one last question as it relates to what&#8217;s happening in Russia.&nbsp; The U.S. still doesn&#8217;t have an ambassador to India, but it appears increasingly clear that Los Angeles Mayor Garcetti doesn&#8217;t have the votes right now to be confirmed.&nbsp; How does the lack of an ambassador to India impact our ability &#8212; America&#8217;s ability to pressure India not to work with Russia in providing any aid or assistance?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, while our preference is always to have a confirmed ambassador on the ground &#8212; it’s an incredibly important diplomatic position &#8212; we also engage with countries through a range of channels.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, our Deputy National Security Advisor was just in India recently in the last few weeks conveying clearly what the consequences of violating sanctions would be and what the mechanisms are; and also making clear that we do not think India should accelerate or increase imports of Russian energy and other commodities, even as obviously those decisions are made by individual countries; and also making clear that we stand ready to support India as &#8212; in any efforts to diversify its imports and serve as a reliable supplier, even as they&#8217;re only importing about 1 to 2 percent of their oil from India.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we have a range of ways to communicate and engage. &nbsp;And obviously, sending our Deputy National Security Advisor is an example of that.&nbsp; But clearly our preference would be to have a confirmed ambassador.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President still support that nomination?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He does.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Russian ruble has been on the rise.&nbsp; Viktor Orbán in Hungary said today that he&#8217;d be happy to pay for Russian gas in rubles and that he&#8217;s happy to buy more Russian gas.&nbsp; Is there anything the U.S. can do about this?&nbsp; Are you engaging Hungary on this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would &#8212; I would first say, in terms of the ruble, the reason &#8212; it&#8217;s important to note that the Russian Central Bank is making extreme policy decisions to artificially prop up the ruble.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s not actually on the rise.&nbsp; It is being artificially propped up by limitations that they are putting in place, including barring banks from selling dollars to customers; Russian brokerages are not allowing foreign clients to sell securities; exporters are being forced to sell 80 percent of their dollar revenues and buy rubles.&nbsp; So, they are essentially manipulating it on their end.<br>&nbsp;<br>As it relates to Hungary &#8212; I mean, slightly a different question, but our &#8212; you know, obviously, there was the recent election, as you noted, of Viktor Orbán.&nbsp; I would note that our &#8212; Hungary is a NATO Ally, continues to be. &nbsp;We continue to cooperate on a range of bilateral and shared global interests, including on NATO defense and on humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; They&#8217;re currently hosting forces from an Army Stryker infantry troop as part of a NATO battle group.&nbsp; We regularly conduct joint training exercises with them, and we will continue to work to strengthen our partnership with Hungary.<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, reliance on the ruble is a decision individual countries will make, and we&#8217;ve obviously made our views clear on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you have engaged Hungary on this question?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is not what I conveyed.&nbsp; I just conveyed they’re a NATO Ally.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we go back to the sanctions?&nbsp; As they were announced this morning, the Sberbank and the Alfa Bank sanctions, I believe, exclude energy.&nbsp; They’re full blocking sanctions excluding energy.&nbsp; Similarly, the SOE sanctions coming tomorrow also will not affect the energy sector.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you speak to that balancing act?&nbsp; Is that because you&#8217;re worried about the domestic impact here in the U.S. on the price of natural gas, price of gasoline? &nbsp;Or is that because the Europeans asked you to sort of carve that out?&nbsp; Why &#8212; or why is that still sort of a bridge too far for the U.S. on these sanctions?&nbsp; They&#8217;re not really full blocking sanctions if they’re excluding energy.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I mean, I would say they’re quite extensive, given Sberbank is the largest bank in Russia and Alfa Bank is the largest private bank in Russia.&nbsp; So, in total, we’ve now fully blocked more than two thirds of Russia’s banking sector.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These conversations and discussions, obviously, are done in coordination with our European allies and partners.&nbsp; And we continue to assess how we can maximize the impact while minimizing the impact on other economies, including, of course, the gloi- &#8212; the global oil marketplace.<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve taken steps, of course, banning oil imports.&nbsp; A number of countries, including Poland, in Europe have announced their intention to take steps, but that&#8217;s up to individual countries to make.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s part coordination, assessment with other countries and our allies about the impacts.&nbsp; But I would still say it&#8217;s quite a significant step, given they&#8217;re the largest bank in Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is it accurate then to say that this was done because of the Europeans saying, “Hey, you know, this would be too (inaudible)?”<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, this is &#8212; but we do update them and brief them on the steps we take and why.&nbsp; And we look at the impacts on &#8212; on how things will impact the United States, how they will impact a range of our allies as we make decisions about sanctions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And very quickly on the central bank actions propping up the ruble &#8212; do you have any sense of how long they&#8217;re able to keep that up?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have an assessment from here at this point in time on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; On immigration: With the lifting of Section 42, there are a lot of Democrats, particularly Democratic senators, up for reelection who worry that you don&#8217;t have a plan to either stop the spring surge of undocumented immigrants or handle it.&nbsp; What do you say to those Democrats?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that Title 42 is not an immigration measure, it&#8217;s a public health measure and one that Congress has given the CDC authority to make a decision about.&nbsp; And we respect that and think that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s absolutely right.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the President proposed an immigration bill in his first day in office.&nbsp; And we would certainly welcome efforts of anybody to work with us on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>But as we&#8217;re implementing this over the course of the next five weeks, if I&#8217;m doing my math correctly, we&#8217;ve also surged resources from the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; And we will continue to take additional steps to implement and make clear that this is not the time to come, that there are &#8212; there will still be significant measures put in place for anyone who tries to irregularly migrate to the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you feel that you &#8212; I mean, what&#8217;s your goal, and what do you expect &#8212; what impact do you expect to have on the spring surge with those kinds of measures?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point you to the Department of Homeland Security to make any projections of that, because we have not made any projections of what it will mean in terms of the ending of Title 42 either.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I know that you&#8217;ve talked about the stringent measures you&#8217;ve taken to keep the President safe from COVID that go beyond the CDC guidelines, but that&#8217;s such a visual contrast between that and the President showing up maskless in front of people at some of these events.&nbsp; So how do you make sure that you keep that protection bubble around him?&nbsp; I’m sure you feel like you’re asked to explain this ad nauseum.&nbsp; But &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, it’s okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the bubble is looking pretty porous lately.&nbsp; So how do you keep that, sort of, enforced?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, that we continue to<br>take measures that go beyond what the CDC protocols are.&nbsp; That includes ensuring that everybody who&#8217;s going to see the President in a meeting is tested in advance &#8212; or if you&#8217;re traveling with the President, you&#8217;re tested in advance.<br>&nbsp;<br>When possible, we take steps to socially distance in circumstances, which certainly the Oval Office and other meeting spaces in the White House allow for.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If an individual in the White House is a close contact, they are asked to or required to, I guess you could say, wear a mask for 10 days after that exposure.&nbsp; And they are also tested regularly following.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I would say we take additional measures that go beyond what the CDC protocols and requirements are to ensure that we&#8217;re doing everything we can to keep principals safe &#8212; the President, the Vice President, and others, of course, in the building.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Was everyone tested before the East Room event tomorrow &#8212; everyone who was there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not at public events.&nbsp; I&#8217;m talking about at meetings.&nbsp; But again, I can check on the protocols for public events.&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you changed any protocol surrounding him in recent days as more people are &#8212; in the administration contract this virus?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve continued to implement stringent and strict protocols.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note that even as we&#8217;re looking at, with BA.2 &#8212; a very transmissible variant, as we all know, and our public health officials have told us.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen an increase in cases &#8212; right? &#8212; in the country, in the region, among the press corps, and certainly in the White House.&nbsp; And &#8212; but it is not, at this point, what we saw during Omicron.<br>&nbsp;<br>And what &#8212; the steps we have taken here, including policy put in place to ensure that “return to work” was part of our policies in the federal government, are meant to ensure that can continue to be the case.&nbsp; And even while we have individuals who are out with COVID, everyone here is required to be tested, highly recommended to be boosted.&nbsp; People who are out because of that &#8212; the vast, vast majority have mild cases and are continuing to work from home.<br>&nbsp;<br>And obviously, we are continuing to implement the “return to work” policy and feel we have the measures necessary to do that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So what&#8217;s the clearest version of the message that you&#8217;re trying to send to Americans about living with this virus, even as infection rates rise &#8212; I mean, that it&#8217;s not the end of the world if you get it if you&#8217;re boosted?&nbsp; I mean, is that the message you send through the President, who&#8217;s maskless in front of hundreds of people &#8212; that this isn&#8217;t the end, that we have to live this way?&nbsp; Is that the clear version of the message?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, our recommend- &#8212; well, the message we&#8217;re sending is to follow the CDC protocols and guidance for where you live.&nbsp; The President does that.&nbsp; He did an event in Washington, D.C., today where it does not require mask wearing.&nbsp; There are other parts of the country, as you know, where he&#8217;s traveled and he has worn a mask where that has been the recommendation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our protocols also here &#8212; and we would certainly project this to the American people &#8212; are that getting vaccinated and getting boosted &#8212; and if you are immunocompromised or you’re over certain age, getting your next booster &#8212; is certainly a way to help protect yourself.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something the President has done and every member of the senior staff and White House staff has done and will continue to do, although some of us are teasing the people who are over 50 that were not old enough yet.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s a si- &#8212; that&#8217;s a sidebar.&nbsp; When we are, we will be doing that as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it is &#8212; it is to follow the protocols and to recognize that the statistics show you are significantly more likely to be hospitalized and even to die if you are not vaccinated, if you are not boosted.<br>&nbsp;<br>And, yes, we are living with COVID-19.&nbsp; We are continuing to fight it.&nbsp; And our biggest message right now is that we need the resources from Congress to continue to have the &#8212; to ensure we have programs for the uninsured, that we can provide treatments for immunocompromised, that we can make sure that we have testing mechanisms and booster mechanisms.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re at serious risk of those programs not being able to continue.&nbsp; Some haven&#8217;t, obviously.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Karen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, just to follow up on something you said to Mara on the Title 42 question.&nbsp; You said that the administration will be taking additional steps to make clear this is not the time to come.&nbsp; That was, of course, a pretty explicit message from the President and others last year: “Do not come.”&nbsp; Is that still the message on May 24th?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, a follow-up to that: As the U.S. moves to end Title 42 in May, are there discussions now or is there any update you can give us on ending the testing requirement for reentry into the U.S. for people traveling here?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update on that at this point in time.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something we will continue to evaluate.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; I have a follow-up on sanctions and energy.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The European Union said yesterday that they are paying Russia, every day, a little more than $1 billion for gas and oil.&nbsp; How long can this go on, in the President&#8217;s view, without undermining the collective effort to punish Russia?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that we continue to believe that it&#8217;s up to individual countries to make assessments about what additional measures they will be put in place.&nbsp; While we are focused on continuing unity with our NATO Allies and partners and our European partners, it does not mean that it is always identical, and different countries have to make their own assessments.<br>&nbsp;<br>What we&#8217;ve also tried to do is take steps to ensure there are other options to reduce dependence, even if it&#8217;s a small percentage.&nbsp; And if there&#8217;s a vari- &#8212; varying, as you all know, degree of reliance for these countries you&#8217;re referencing on Russian oil.&nbsp; And some of them have taken steps to convey they want to reduce or end their dependence or import of Russian oil, and that&#8217;s something certainly we&#8217;d support and play any constructive role in helping &#8212; to helping expedite.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, a follow-up &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll come around to you in a second.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow up on the question about Hungary, are there any plans to engage with them about this particular topic of paying in rubles at any level in the coming days or weeks?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with the State Department to see if there&#8217;s any plans for engagement about it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, Jen.&nbsp; Again, an American Catho- &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; You talked about the increasing picture of Russia&#8217;s economy.&nbsp; Over the years, public reporting has shown that white supremacists and other domestic extremists have developed an affinity for Russia.&nbsp; Is there any concern that as the Russian economy continues to degrade, that Russia might try and inspire domestic extremists, domestic terrorists to commit acts of violence on American soil in retaliation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s an interesting and scary question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any prediction or assessment of that, nor have I heard a prediction or assessment of that from our national security experts or the Department of Homeland Security.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with them and see if there&#8217;s anything on that front.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, again &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right, Jen.&nbsp; So, an American Catholic nun has been abducted &#8212; it happened Monday night &#8212; by gunmen in Burkina Faso, in Western Africa.&nbsp; Her name is Sister Suellen Tennyson.&nbsp; She was doing missionary work there.&nbsp; Is the White House aware of that, by any chance &#8212; her abduction?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check with our national security team and the State Department.&nbsp; Obviously, they would have purview over any steps to bring Sister &#8212; tell me her name again.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sister Suellen Tennyson.&nbsp; And she was working in Burkina Faso, in Western Africa.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sister Tennyson back, who clearly was doing incredible work &#8212; humanitarian work, it sounds like &#8212; on behalf of the people in Burkina Faso.<br>&nbsp;<br>I will check with the State Department and see if there&#8217;s any updates on this specific case.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Okay, go ahead, Patsy.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I want to follow up on what you said yesterday about the lack of global COVID funding.&nbsp; And you explained it essentially means that the U.S. cannot turn the doses that you already have into shots in arms.&nbsp; And I believe that the U.S. has already purchased 1.2 billion doses that it’s pledged.&nbsp; And out of that, there is about 680 million that haven&#8217;t been delivered.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my question, then, is: What will happen to those doses?&nbsp; I know, like, possibly you already have funding for delivery &#8212; the cold chain storage, training people, and so on.&nbsp; But what happens to the rest of it when you are unable to turn those vaccines into vaccinations?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re not quite there yet.&nbsp; And our hope is that we will be able to turn them &#8212; vaccines into vaccinations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But as you know, it&#8217;s not just an issue of vaccine doses.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the know-how, it&#8217;s the capacity, it&#8217;s the tools and mechanisms to be able to store, deliver, implement getting shots into arms in a number of these countries, which is why a number of countries haven&#8217;t even been able to accept the doses that we&#8217;ve been able to offer &#8212; because of that know-how.&nbsp; And that is part of the program that is so essential to fund through USAID and other of our international bodies to do exactly that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we&#8217;re not quite at that point.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to press for international funding, just like we are going to continue to press for domestic funding, because we feel it&#8217;s important and imperative that we continue to be the arsenal of vaccines around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us a sense on how you want to do that?&nbsp; Is the goal to push for a separate package on global COVID funding?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of where we are.&nbsp; Obviously, it was disappointing, to say the least, that the package did not move forward despite an agreement on that yesterday afternoon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But what I&#8217;m here to convey is that this funding, domestically and internationally, is imperative, it&#8217;s urgent, and we&#8217;re going to continue to press for all of it.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I have one more question on Daleep Singh’s visit to India &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; which was also partly to go on a listening tour for the Build Back Better World that was actually scheduled to be formally launched early this year.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So if you can give us an update on that.&nbsp; Why has it not launched yet?&nbsp; And at this point, do you feel that it is &#8212; with the projects &#8212; with the listening tours, with the pilot projects that are being planned, is it robust enough to be introduced to the world as a viable alternative to China&#8217;s Belt and Road Initiative?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As you know, the President has used his own time to talk about Build Back Better World and how important it is to our efforts to rebuild infrastructure without the strings attached around the world.&nbsp; And that speaks to our commitment to it.&nbsp; And obviously, our Nat- &#8212; Deputy National Security Advisor taking a trip himself, having a discussion about it is a reflection of our commitment to that and our efforts.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you a follow-up question on COVID-19?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The WHO Director-General is in D.C. &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Earlier this morning at the Monitor Breakfast, NEC Director Brian Deese mentioned a classified briefing that took place earlier today between lawmakers, Jake Sullivan, and others about, quote, “escalating vulnerabilities” around semiconductors.&nbsp; Can you tell us more about this meeting?&nbsp; And was it an effort to get Congress to hurry up on the reconciliation of the two related bills?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t speak to the specifics of a classified briefing.&nbsp; What I can tell you is that we can &#8212; remain committed to supporting efforts to get you USICA passed, which includes significant funding for chips manufacturing and production, which, as we know, is a big hindrance to our ability to manufacture a range of &#8212; a range of items in the United States, including cars and others, that rely on chips.&nbsp; And this bill has a great deal of funding for it.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think it was a reminder &#8212; and more details that I can&#8217;t get into from here on &#8212; on how important addressing that shortage and being able to produce them at home are, moving forward.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, as the administration sort of collects this evidence for potential war crimes trials against Russian officials, does the U.S., does the administration have a preferred venue for where that type of trial might take place?&nbsp; That &#8212; there are obviously a few avenues available to the international community.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are.&nbsp; And there &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of precedent and &#8212; that has used different venues.&nbsp; So at this point, that determination has not been made.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we are doing &#8212; and I think I would point you first to our Attorney General&#8217;s comments earlier today about the role of the Department of Justice in this effort moving forward.&nbsp; But we have supported a range of efforts, including the efforts by the Ukrainian Special Prosecutor to gather information and the work of the war crimes unit under the Ukrainian Prosecutor General &#8212; sorry, Prosecutor General, not Special Prosecutor &#8212; and a team of international prosecutors who are working with them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also &#8212; in the last few weeks, we helped establish investigations for the U.N. Human Rights Council and the OSCE of possible violations by Russia.&nbsp; And we welcome the investigation opened by the ICC Prosecutor.<br>&nbsp;<br>So there has been different ways that war crimes &#8211;unfortunately, there are past instances and examples &#8212; have been investigated and tried in the past.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to support all of these efforts, but there hasn&#8217;t been a determination yet about what mechanism it will take.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has this effort changed at all the thinking of the administration as it relates to the relationship between the U.S. and the ICC?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we are not a member of the ICC, as you know.&nbsp; That hasn&#8217;t changed.&nbsp; We have supported and contributed data and information to ICC investigations in the past.&nbsp; There was &#8212; we supported the U.N. Security Council&#8217;s referral of Libya to the ICC back in 2011.&nbsp; And if you look back to 2004, we also provided data and information to the ICC investigation of Darfur.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there is past precedent, even as we have not been members of the ICC.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; A couple of follow ups. &nbsp;When the President said that the U.S. was training Ukrainians, was he talking about training that had occurred during his administration?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any other additional details.&nbsp; What he was really making a point about is what Secretary Austin said yesterday, which is that without the extensive and robust military assistance we have provided, the Ukrainians would not have been able to as effectively fight and push back on the Russian invasion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then he said, “Amazon, here we come.”&nbsp; You said that he was generally expressing his support for the right to unionize.&nbsp; Moments later, though, news broke that the SEC was beginning an investigation of Amazon.&nbsp; Was that a coincidence?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No relation.&nbsp; SEC is an independent agency.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gotcha.&nbsp; Was he aware that there was an investigation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not that I&#8217;m aware of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one final one.&nbsp; This administration has sent everything from medical supplies to laser-guided rockets to the Ukrainians right now.&nbsp; While this administration is making them more lethal, is the thought that we are bolstering their defensive capabilities?&nbsp; Or is the administration confident that we are bolstering their offensive capability to, in fact, you know, expel Russia from their borders?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, their country is being invaded, so it&#8217;s all defensive.&nbsp; They&#8217;re defending their sovereign country and the territorial integrity of Ukraine using these weapons systems that the Department of Defense has long categorized as defensive systems.<br>&nbsp;<br>You wouldn&#8217;t go invade another country with a lot of these systems &#8212; the vast majority of these systems.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not how you would go about it.&nbsp; And obviously, that is not what they&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; They&#8217;re trying to protect their own people, their own cities, their own innocent civilians who are being invaded by a foreign power.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let me do one more in the back because I never get to the Huffington Post, and I &#8212; today is the day.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; There was a recent report that the President had expressed some frustration that the former President had not been charged.&nbsp; Without getting into the details of that, there are lots of people being charged with obstructing an official proceeding, meaning the January 6th certification.<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, the former President was doing that openly and his administration was doing it.&nbsp; Why wouldn&#8217;t you charge him?&nbsp; And why hasn&#8217;t the President come out and said that if that&#8217;s the case?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; first, I&#8217;ve never heard the President say those words &#8212; or say that phrase that was reported.&nbsp; And I know Ron Klain said something similarly, so I don&#8217;t know &#8212; we each spend a lot of time with him.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would say that the President, from the beginning, has felt strongly that the Justice Department and the Attorney General must operate independently, and any decisions about prosecution need to be made independently.&nbsp; And that is the strength of our system, even as the former guy ignored that and former-President Nixon ignored it as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President does not want to be in that category of how you approach the separation of the White House and the Department of Justice.&nbsp; And &#8212; and he thinks that will even strengthen our systems as they&#8217;ve been weakened over the last few years.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, thanks so much.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>(Cross-talk by reporters.)<br>&nbsp;<br>All right, everybody.&nbsp; See you tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>4:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Signing of H.R. 3076, the “Postal Service Reform Act of&#160;2022”</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/06/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-h-r-3076-the-postal-service-reform-act-of-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 22:21:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50695</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 4:28 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; You know, Annette, as you were speaking, I looked down at &#8212; Senator Carper used to be chairman of this committee.&#160; How many years, Tommy, you’ve been working on this? SENATOR CARPER:&#160; Four hundred.&#160; (Laughter.) THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; I tell you what &#8212; your service both in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>4:28 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You know, Annette, as you were speaking, I looked down at &#8212; Senator Carper used to be chairman of this committee.&nbsp; How many years, Tommy, you’ve been working on this?</p>



<p>SENATOR CARPER:&nbsp; Four hundred.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I tell you what &#8212; your service both in the Air Force as a letter carrier is real, and it&#8217;s all about serving your community, and I appreciate it very much.</p>



<p>Matter of fact, when I said, “It&#8217;s good to meet you,” she said, “I know you.&nbsp; We’ve met before.”&nbsp; And I said, “I apologize.”&nbsp; She said, “You used to show up every &#8212; in Wilmington” &#8212; how often?</p>



<p>MS. TAYLOR:&nbsp; In D.C.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, in D.C.</p>



<p>MS. TAYLOR:&nbsp; Every year.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Every year, I&#8217;d show up to the letter carriers’ breakfast or lunch or dinner &#8212; I can’t remember which.&nbsp; But it reminded me why I &#8212; I think foreign policy is easier.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; “War and Peace” goes down easier, Gerry, I think.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Senator Peters, Senator Portman, Senator Carper, Senator Tillis; Representatives Maloney, Comer, Connolly, and Virginia Foxx and Stephen Lynch &#8212; Stephen, good to see you, pal.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t do &#8212; I didn&#8217;t know you did post offices.</p>



<p>REPRESENTATIVE LYNCH:&nbsp; Oh, yeah.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And &#8212; and Brenda Lawrence, who served the U.S. Postal Service for 30 years before being elected to Congress.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Which was harder?&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Well, look, some of you know, before I became President &#8212; I&#8217;m sure you all know this &#8212; I was the Ben Franklin Professor of Practice at the University of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; Professor, Jim.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And everybody walks in and they wonder why Ben Franklin&#8217;s picture is hanging in my &#8212; portrait is hanging in my office.&nbsp; Because if I didn&#8217;t put that up, there&#8217;d be no &#8212; nobody I knew would get into University of Pennsylvania again. (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m only kidding.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But Ben Franklin, one of our Founding Fathers, was our first postmaster general.&nbsp; And he saw the Postal Service in a way to connect the colonies and to build together as one nation.&nbsp; I mean, literally, that&#8217;s what it was seen as: It was to connect the colonies and build one nation &#8212; connect everything.</p>



<p>He saw the power of the Postal Service to deliver more than the mail, but some of our most basic freedoms and basic rights were delivered by the Post Office.&nbsp; Freedom of speech by allowing citizens the voice and to &#8212; their voices to be amplified all across the country.&nbsp; Freedom of the press by offering discounted rates for newspapers.&nbsp; The right to privacy by expressly prohibiting &#8212; this sounds silly &#8212; but expressly prohibiting the opening of mail that belonged to somebody else.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And beyond those rights and freedoms, our oldest postal roads helped give rise to some of our nation’s most essential infrastructure.&nbsp; There were postal highways.&nbsp; That’s why a lot of these roads were built: to provide post.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, we used to serve with a guy who was from West Virginia, Jennings Randolph.&nbsp; And he &#8212; the thing he &#8212; he started an airline.&nbsp; But the way the airlines used to work was there’d be a great &#8212; Tommy, they’d put up two big poles like goal posts, and they would put a wire between it and they’d hang whatever the Postal Service &#8212; the post mail used to be collected.&nbsp; And the airplane would come down with a hook on it and pick it up and take it off.&nbsp; So, you know &#8212; I’m not going to say &#8212; if Jennings were here, he’d say there’d be no Post Office out there.&nbsp; But anyway, I’m only kidding.&nbsp; But &#8212;</p>



<p>But today, more than 670,000 &#8212; -75,000 dedicated men and women of the U.S. Postal Service continue to deliver for the American people.</p>



<p>They help keep us healthy by shipping 4 million prescriptions per day.&nbsp; Four million per day.&nbsp; And when we’re dedicated &#8212; and when we dedicated to send and committed we would send to &#8212; free &#8212; to &#8212; COVID-19 tests directly to people’s homes, the Postal Service stepped up to make that happen as well.</p>



<p>And now they delivered over two hundred and &#8212; three hundred &#8212; excuse me &#8212; 320 million COVID test 19 kits so far, in every state, territory, and U.S. military base in the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>An impressive turnaround for an unprecedented task.&nbsp; And it’s continuing the truly heroic service that they provided throughout this pandemic.</p>



<p>When everyone was worried about &#8212; that supply chain delays would ruin the holidays, the Post Office delivered the packages that were &#8212; that &#8212; more than any other shipper in the world, and they got the gifts to our homes and our loved ones on time.</p>



<p>And the Postal Service is central to our economy and is central to rural America, delivering mail and packages between small businesses and customers every single, solitary day.</p>



<p>And the deliveries &#8212; you know, and delivering seeds and even live animals, often, to parts of the country that private carriers can&#8217;t or won&#8217;t or aren&#8217;t required to reach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is another essential thing the Postal Service delivers: your vote.&nbsp; In 2020, 43 percent of the votes cast by ballot were cast by mail.&nbsp; And on average, it took those ballots &#8212; (applause) &#8212; on average, it took those ballots less than two days to get from the voter to the election office, faster than the average delivery time for first-class mail.</p>



<p>So it&#8217;s no exaggeration to say that the Postal Service delivers democracy.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s no exaggeration to say the Postal Service is as essential as it ever was, as it’s ever been &#8212; today.</p>



<p>In 2006, the law required the Postal Service to prepay &#8212; prepay retirement benefits 50 years into the future.&nbsp; No other &#8212; no other company or federal agency has to do anything like that.&nbsp; And the requirement of that law stretched the Postal Service&#8217;s finances almost to the breaking point, with real consequences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are stories of people across the country getting hit with late fees because their credit card bill arrived a week late, if it arrived at all.&nbsp; Small businesses on the verge of collapse because payments they were counting on were &#8212; were severely delayed.&nbsp; Elderly Americans suffering because they had to go weeks without their medication.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I, like many of you, made a campaign promise to fix this. And today we are.&nbsp; You all &#8212; the members in front of me did all the work.&nbsp; I made the promise; you did all the work.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I&#8217;m glad that strong, bipartisan majorities in the House and Senate have come together to deliver on this needed reform.</p>



<p>With this bill, we&#8217;re repealing the pre-funding mandate and setting the Postal Service on a more sustainable and stable financial footing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re guaranteeing that the mail will continue to be delivered six days a week.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the bill increases transparency by requiring the Postal Service to develop online &#8212; an online public dashboard updated weekly with local and national service performance data.</p>



<p>You&#8217;ll be able to see in real-time how well the Postal Service is delivering for you and for your community.&nbsp; And this bill streamlines healthcare for Postal workers as well.&nbsp; They deliver for us, so &#8212; through rain and snow and sleet, and we&#8217;re making sure the healthcare they need will be there for them as well.</p>



<p>And finally, this bill will allow the Postal Service to partner with state, local, and Tribal governments to offer valuable and helpful non-postal services to the public.&nbsp; Imagine a trip to the Post Office where you can pick up your bus pass or your hunting license or your fishing license.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, there are more areas where we want to see the Postal Service leading.&nbsp; For example, it needs to do more to modernize and electrify its fleet of vehicles to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and to save money.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we’re going to do that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll continue to fight for these commonsense improvements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But today, we enshrine in law our recognition that the Postal Service is fundamental to our economy, to our democracy, to our health, and the very sense of who we are as a nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this bill &#8212; this bill recognizes the Postal Service is a public service, and we&#8217;re ensuring that it can continue to serve all Americans for generations to come.</p>



<p>Now, I’ll now go over and sign that postal bill.&nbsp; And those of you who are going to come up while I sign it, I&#8217;m not going to read out your names; they told me who you are.&nbsp; Everybody but Steny can come.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’m only kidding, Steny.</p>



<p>And we’ll get this reform bill finally signed.&nbsp; And, Thom, it only took what?&nbsp; Eleven years?</p>



<p>SENATOR TILLIS:&nbsp; (Inaudible).</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Twelve.&nbsp; Twelve.&nbsp; Twelve years.</p>



<p>SENATOR TILLIS:&nbsp; It seems like more.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Rob, now that’s pretty fast, right?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anyway, all kidding aside, thank you for the hard work you’ve done.&nbsp; You’ve done a good job.&nbsp; Let me walk over here.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>(The bill is signed.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right, it’s official.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:38 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Congressional Briefing on National Security Impact of Semiconductor Supply Chain and Importance of Passing Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/06/readout-of-congressional-briefing-on-national-security-impact-of-semiconductor-supply-chain-and-importance-of-passing-bipartisan-innovation-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon, senior Administration officials including Commerce Secretary Raimondo, Deputy Defense Secretary Hicks, National Security Advisor Sullivan, and National Science Foundation Director Panchanathan held a briefing with a bipartisan and bicameral group of Members of Congress to discuss the urgent need to invest in made-in-America semiconductors as well as research and development that will protect&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This afternoon, senior Administration officials including Commerce Secretary Raimondo, Deputy Defense Secretary Hicks, National Security Advisor Sullivan, and National Science Foundation Director Panchanathan held a briefing with a bipartisan and bicameral group of Members of Congress to discuss the urgent need to invest in made-in-America semiconductors as well as research and development that will protect our economic and national security.</p>



<p>During the briefing, the Administration officials underscored how decades of disinvestment in domestic semiconductor manufacturing capacity have left America producing only 12% of global semiconductor output and vulnerable to the sort of supply chain disruptions we’ve seen in recent years, like the pandemic and Russia’s war of aggression against Ukraine. A significant interruption to our supply of semiconductors could cause historic damage to the U.S. economy – damage far greater than the impact of chips shortages on the American auto industry right now – and would undercut our technological competitiveness and military advantages over adversaries globally.</p>



<p>The House and Senate have each passed bills to make historic investments in research, domestic manufacturing and America’s capacity to make semiconductors – including with $52 billion in new funding authorized in the CHIPS Act. This support would help spur further private sector investments in America’s semiconductor industry after nearly $80 billion in new investments in President Biden’s first year in office, including Intel’s $20 billion fabrication facility in Ohio.&nbsp;</p>



<p>These investments in semiconductors are crucial and must be complemented by investment in other advanced technologies as well, including the research and development leading to the next generation of these technologies, and related workforce development. These investments are critical to making our economy stronger and more resilient, and to protect our national security. That’s why the Administration officials urged Congress to move quickly to get legislation to the President’s desk for his signature, including through action to formally go to conference and name conferees this week.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at North America’s Building Trades Unions Legislative&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/06/remarks-by-president-biden-at-north-americas-building-trades-unions-legislative-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 21:40:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=50690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington HiltonWashington, D.C. 12:58 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; It’s good to be home!&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Whoa.&#160;&#160; AUDIENCE:&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe! THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you. AUDIENCE:&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe! THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; You better stop; I’ll start believing it.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Washington Hilton<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>12:58 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s good to be home!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; You better stop; I’ll start believing it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Please, have a seat if you have one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s good to be home!&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You know, I look out there and I see an awful lot of you who &#8212; as they say in Claymont, Delaware &#8212; “who brung me to the dance.”&nbsp; And I &#8212; no, I really mean it.&nbsp; There is no exaggeration: I’d not be standing here without labor, without union &#8212; union labor.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, as we used to say when I was a senator, “If you’d excuse the point of personal privilege” &#8212; before I turn to my main remarks, I’d like to &#8212; I have to briefly address the horrifying reports of the atrocities taking place in Ukraine and the steps the United States is taking to respond in close coordination with our Allies and our partners.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I’m sure you’ve seen the pictures from Bucha and out &#8212; just outside of Kyiv: bodies left in streets as Russian troops withdrew, some shot in the back of the head with their hands tied behind their backs; civilians executed in cold blood; bodies dumped into mass graves.&nbsp; The sense of brutality and inhumanity left for all the world to see unapologetically.&nbsp; There’s nothing less happening than major war crimes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Responsible nations have to come together to hold these perpetrators accountable.&nbsp;&nbsp;And together with our Allies and our partners, we’re going to keep raising the economic cost and ratchet up the pain for Putin and further increase Russia’s economic isolation.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, the steps we’ve already taken are predicted to shrink Russia’s gross domestic product by double digits this year alone.&nbsp; Just in one year, our sanctions are likely to wipe out the last 15 years of Russia’s economic gains.&nbsp; And because we’ve cut Russia off from importing technologies like semiconductors and encryption security and critical components of quantum technology that they need to compete in the 21st century, we’re going to stifle Russia’s ability and its economy to grow for years to come.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Folks, this is the United States, and we’re taking additional steps in lockstep with our Allies and partners to raise the economic pressure on Putin.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, the United States will impose full blocking sanctions on Sberbank, by far the largest financial institution in Russia, and Alfa Bank, its largest private bank.&nbsp; We’re locking down any accounts, any funds that those banks hold in the United States.&nbsp; They’ll not be able to touch any of their money.&nbsp; They’ll not be able to do any business here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, second, I’m going to sign an executive order that’s going to ban any new U.S. investment in Russia &#8212; more than 600 private sector companies.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, corporate America is stepping up, a change.&nbsp; From McDonalds to Exxon, they’ve left the Russian market on their own accord &#8212; 600 of them.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; The private businesses choosing to leave Russia rather than risk being associated with Putin’s brutal war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this ban on investment is going to make sure that new money cannot come in to Russia to replace what’s left so that the Russian economy doesn’t feel the loss &#8212; and the loss of these businesses for the long term.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, we’re adding more critical state-owned enterprises&nbsp;to the list of fully blocked Russian companies.&nbsp; These companies are major revenue generators owned by Russia and the government, which Putin uses to fund himself and enable his war in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’ll also be cut off from doing any business with the United States.&nbsp; They will not be able to access or use any assets they have in the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, fourth, we, along with our European allies, are adding the names to the list of Russian elites and their families that we are sanctioning.&nbsp; Did you see these yachts we’re &#8212; that are being picked up?&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yeah!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No &#8212; no, think about it.&nbsp; Think about the &#8212; the incredible amounts of money these oligarchs have stolen.&nbsp; These yachts are a hundred &#8212; millions and millions of dollars.</p>



<p>Look, these oligarchs and their family members are not allowed to hold on to their wealth in Europe and the United States and keep these yachts worth hundreds of millions of dollars, their luxury vacation homes, while children in Ukraine are being killed, displaced from their homes every single day.</p>



<p>And, finally, we’re continuing to supply Ukraine with the weapons and resources to defend their country.&nbsp; Last Friday &#8212; (applause) &#8212; last Friday, we announced millions in funding to procure new equipment for Ukraine &#8212; advanced drones, laser-guided rocket systems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, I signed another package to send more Javelins missiles &#8212; those shoulder-mounted missiles&nbsp;that can take out tanks and armored vehicles &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to keep getting an uninterrupted supply&nbsp;to the Ukrainian military.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we won’t be able to advertise every piece of security we give because our Allies and partners are supplying to Ukraine through us, but advanced weapons and ammunition are flowing in every single day.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as you may have seen yesterday on television, when the Secretary of Defense was being cross-examined by one of our &#8212; how can I say it? &#8212; our congresspersons &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; saying, “What have you done?”&nbsp; And he basically looked at him and said, “What the hell do you think we’ve done?&nbsp; Why do you think they’re able to fight?&nbsp; We’ve trained them and we’ve given them the weapons.”&nbsp; That’s what’s happening.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, thanks to the bravery, the grit, and the fight- &#8212; the fighting spirit of the Ukrainian people, Russia has already failed in its initial war aims.&nbsp; Russia wanted to take Ukraine’s capital city of Kyiv and topple its democracy and elected government.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, Kyiv still stands, and that government still presides.&nbsp; This fight is far from over.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And here’s the point: This war could continue for a long time, but the United States will continue to stand with Ukraine and the Ukrainian people in the fight for freedom.&nbsp; And I just want you to know that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, if I got to go to war, I’m going with you guys.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I’ll tell you.&nbsp; (Inaudible.) I mean it.</p>



<p>I want to talk about &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I want to talk about what I’m here today to talk about: You women or men in the American union movement remember, you know, when the Fair Labor Standards Act was first passed, everybody said you “can” have unions.&nbsp; It didn’t say that.&nbsp; It says we “should” have more unions.&nbsp; We should.&nbsp; American labor of the Building Trades Unions.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>President McGarvey.&nbsp; And, by the way, Dad, Jack &#8212; where are you, Jack?</p>



<p>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; Right in front there.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ll tell you what, Dad, as they say in southern Delaware, “You done good with this boy.”&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)</p>



<p>And, you know, I just know Jack is a Philadelphia guy.&nbsp; You know why?&nbsp; He &#8212; I just asked Sean.&nbsp; I said, “Where is…”&nbsp; He said, “Well, he’s down the shore.”&nbsp; Now, if you’re from Philadelphia or Jersey, you go to “the shore.”&nbsp; If you’re from northern Delaware, you go to “the shore.”&nbsp; A little bit further south, you go to “the beach.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You go to the beach.&nbsp;&nbsp; You can always tell where someone is from.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Dad, I asked whether or not &#8212; whether or not you &#8212; like my wife Jill, who is from Philly &#8212; still talks about “Broad Street.”&nbsp; The Broad Street Run, you know?&nbsp; And &#8212; and, you know, “Jeet, yet?”&nbsp; You know?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; I had to learn to speak Philadelphian when I got married.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But, Dad, it’s an honor to meet you from a distance here.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MR. JACK MCGARVEY:&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look &#8212; it’s good to be with you all, and I mean that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, there’s an old expression, as I said earlier: “You go home with them that brung you to the dance.”&nbsp; And you all &#8212; you folks brought me to the dance.&nbsp; And the people that brought me to the dance were union workers &#8212; not just workers, union workers: IBEW, Ironworkers, Boilermakers, Teamsters, Laborers, Bricklayers, Masons, Plumbers and Pipefitters, Painters, Plasterers, Roofers, Operating Engineers, Steel Metal Workers.&nbsp; You’re all represented in this room &#8212; and so many more who are not in the building trades that are union members across the country.</p>



<p>I want to thank you for what you did to support my election this last time out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I remember going to a guy sitting down here a little further to the right when I refused to &#8212; I wasn’t going to introduce my &#8212; my climate plan until I decided I was going to speak a guy from the IBEW because I wanted to make sure you all knew what I was doing and why it not only was good for the environment, but good for labor.&nbsp; And I sat down with that guy right there.&nbsp; And he thought about it, and he went out and he talked to other people, and you all stepped up.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I mean it sincerely: You’re probably the biggest reason why I’m standing here today.&nbsp; I’ve never forgotten not only what you’ve done for me but, more importantly, what you’ve done for this country.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’re the ones who literally built this country, and that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; And you heard it a thousand times when I was running for office, that we’re going to build this economy not from the top down anymore, but from the middle up and out.&nbsp; That’s how you build America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because we know that when the middle class does well, the poor have a way up and the wealthy are just fine.&nbsp; And that’s exactly what we’re doing.</p>



<p>And, by the way, the reason there is a middle class is because of unions.&nbsp; Unions.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Fact.&nbsp; Unions.&nbsp; That’s a fact.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s true.&nbsp; And look, it’s not only to provide a good living but what you do more than anything else &#8212; what my dad used to say &#8212; you allow people to have dignity &#8212; the dignity of their work, to be treated with respect.</p>



<p>When it comes time to rebuild the economy &#8212; before I did anything, as I said, I talked to you.&nbsp; I laid out my plan for economic growth.&nbsp; I talked with a lot of the folks sitting behind me here and others in the union movement.&nbsp; And with your help, it was a darn good plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And look at the results: Our economy created 431,000 jobs in March &#8212; (applause) &#8212; 7.9 million since I became President.&nbsp; More jobs in 14 months than any President in the history of America has ever created because of you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unemployment is down to 3, 6 &#8212; 3.6 percent from 6.4 when I took office &#8212; the fastest decline in unemployment from the start of a term of a President ever recorded because of you.&nbsp; And the economy grew 5.7 percent last year &#8212; the fastest growth in 40 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know people are still hurting.&nbsp; I’m not &#8212; I’m not unaware of it.&nbsp; As my dad would say, every time that price of gas went up at the pump, guess what?&nbsp; It was a conversation at our kitchen table that mattered.&nbsp; It’d affect outcomes.&nbsp; It affected what we did.</p>



<p>But in the process, we were able to cut the deficit by $360 billion last year.&nbsp; And it’s been a long, tough stretch, but Americans are back to work.&nbsp; Our economy has gone from being on the mend to being on the move.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It started with the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; When I took office in the midst of the worst economic crisis since the Great Depression, you all remember the lines of cars stretching for miles, waiting for a box of food to be put in their trunk &#8212; not just poor folks, folks across the board waiting for that box of food.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because of the American Rescue Plan &#8212; helped 41 million Americans put food on their table.&nbsp; Because of the American Rescue Plan, we helped keep a roof over the heads of 4 million people.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>When you helped get that plan passed, 4 million people were on the verge of being evicted from their homes and apartments.&nbsp; That’s a fact, not a joke.&nbsp; Four million.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Rescue Plan put money in the pockets of hardworking Americans who, through no fault of their own, were in trouble, giving families what my dad used to call “just a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; “Just a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because of the Rescue Plan, we had the best year of state and local job growth in 20 years, adding back 467,000 jobs; and the educators, firefighters, police officers who were laid off got back on the job.&nbsp; We made a &#8212; you made a gigantic difference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In addition, because of the Rescue Plan, 320,000 construction jobs last year.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; 320,000.&nbsp; You’re building America again!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I meant what I said.&nbsp; We’re the only nation in the world that’s come out of every serious problem we’ve had stronger than when we went in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there are now more construction jobs today than we had before the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A leading financial firm, Moody’s, from Wall Street, estimates that because of the Rescue Plan, 4 million more jobs were created and unemployment is 2 percent lower than it would have been had we failed to act.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, look, that wasn’t all we did to the Rescue Plan.&nbsp; We also included the law called the Butch Lewis Act &#8212; (applause) &#8212; you know what it is; most people don’t &#8212; to ensure that as we rebuilt America, we upheld a promise &#8212; a promise to secure a dignified retirement for millions of workers and retirees all across America, protecting pensions you all worked so damn hard for, you sacrificed to secure.</p>



<p>And it didn’t stop there.&nbsp; Because we can’t compete for the jobs of the 21st century if we don’t fix our infrastructure.&nbsp; That’s why it was so important to pass the&nbsp;Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; You know, and now not only is it &#8220;Infrastructure Week&#8221; finally arrived, it’s infrastructure decade.&nbsp; Infrastructure decade.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, for real.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>Already &#8212; already, as all of you know, we’ve announced nearly $5 billion to improve 3,000 airports across 50 states this year.&nbsp; We’ve announced $5 billion, including $615 million this year alone so Lonnie Stephenson and the IBEW can get to work building a national network of electric vehicle charging stations &#8212; 500,000 across the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve announced $4.7 billion to cap and plug hundreds of thousands of orphaned wells and gas wells spewing methane into the air, creating jobs as good as the jobs the folks who dug those wells got paid in the first place.&nbsp; Same folks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, nearly $17 billion for ports, waterways, and dams; 700 projects already announced across 50 states; $52.5 billion for highways and road repairs this year; $5.4 billion for bridges this year.&nbsp; The I-5 Bridge over the Columbia River in Washington State.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; The I-95 Bridge in West Haven, Connecticut.&nbsp; The Jefferson Highway, U.S. 61&nbsp;in East Baton Rouge Parish in Louisiana.&nbsp; The list goes on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And not only that.&nbsp; We’re getting rid of poisonous lead pipes in 10 million homes and 400,000 schools and childcare centers &#8212; (applause) &#8212; so kids and families can have drinking water that doesn’t poison them.</p>



<p>Look, folks, this is America &#8212; the United States of America.&nbsp; We’re investing $65 billion to deliver affordable high-speed Internet everywhere in America &#8212;&nbsp;urban, rural, suburban, and Tribal communities.&nbsp; You can’t be a country where a mother has to pull, with her child, up in her car to a McDonald’s parking lot to connect to an Internet so the kid can do their homework.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, think about that.&nbsp; It’s the United States of America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, this law puts an end to that and creates thousands of jobs doing it &#8212; good-paying jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, look, what this means for all of you is jobs &#8212; good-paying union jobs; jobs you can raise a family on; jobs you &#8212; can’t be outsourced.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is about more than rebuilding our infrastructure.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about rebuilding our middle class.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so sick and tired.&nbsp; I was raised by a dad &#8212; not a joke &#8212; who, when things would go bad &#8212; I remember we lived in a &#8212; we weren&#8217;t poor, but we lived in a three-bedroom, split-level house with four kids and a grandpop living with us.&nbsp; And I &#8212; looking back on it, we thought it was great, but I wonder how my mom and dad thought about it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Because &#8212; and I remember one night &#8212; true story &#8212; I remember on my &#8212; my headboard with a bunk bed I was in.&nbsp; We had two sets of bunks in my &#8212; in our room.&nbsp; And one was up against the wall that divided between my mom&#8217;s bedroom and ours.&nbsp; And I could tell my dad was restless; I could hear him.&nbsp; And I asked my mom the next morning what was the matter.&nbsp; She said, “He just found out he lost insu- &#8212; we lost our insurance, honey.&nbsp; We lost our insurance.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; You &#8212; you are the ones who keep millions of people from losing their insurance.&nbsp; Unions built the middle class.&nbsp; We have to rebuild the middle class.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why we made sure that the Infrastructure Law included significant labor protections.&nbsp; For example, overwhelming &#8212; the overwhelming majority of the funds included in this law are subject to Davis-Bacon requirements.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, by the way, as you may remember, when I &#8212; the &#8212; President Obama asked me to do the Recovery Act back in our administration, the previous one, we didn&#8217;t do anything you guys didn&#8217;t do.&nbsp; If they wanted the money, they had to show me that they were doing it and prevaying [sic] &#8212; paying a prevailing wage.</p>



<p>As you know, that means folks who are rebuilding the country are going to earn a prevailing wage now.&nbsp; And, by the way, the Labor Department, led by a proud former president of the Laborers’ Union 223, Marty Walsh &#8212; (applause) &#8212; good man.&nbsp; If I&#8217;m in a foxhole &#8212; if I&#8217;m in a foxhole, I want Marty next to me.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Look, he recently proposed a new regulation to strengthen prevailing wage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Another thing the law does is help expand registered apprenticeships.  Wasn&#8217;t it wonderful when businesses said, “Don’t worry, we’ll do the apprenticeships”?  Wasn’t that a great, generous thing for them to do early on?  Well, come on, man &#8212; union partnerships that allow workers to earn while they learn, that matters. </p>



<p>Because laying a strong foundation for the future of this country is about more than having strong roads and bridges, ports and airports that can compete with any in the world.&nbsp; It’s also about making sure that here, in America, folks who work hard and live their lives, they have an opportunity to live it with dignity and respect.&nbsp; That’s what unions are about, in my view &#8212; about providing dignity and respect for people who bust their neck.</p>



<p>That’s why I created the White House Task Force on Worker Organization and Empowerment to make sure the choice to join a union belongs to workers alone.&nbsp; And, by the way &#8212; (applause) &#8212; by the way: Amazon, here we come.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Watch.&nbsp; Watch.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, it’s why I’ve called on Congress to finally pass the PRO Act and send it to my desk.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And that’s why we’re strongly encouraging grantees who get infrastructure funding to use &#8212; use what we know as the project labor agreements &#8212; you know what they are; the vast majority listening to this won&#8217;t know &#8212; which helps ensure that people building major projects are well-trained, highly-skilled workers who have a voice on the work site.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, you all know why this matters.&nbsp; Union members get higher wages and benefits like healthcare and insurance and paid leave; protections against discrimination and harassment; safer, healthier workplaces.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there’s another reason &#8212; the basic American reason: Workers who join a union gain power &#8212; the power over the decisions that affect their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When you’ve got a union, workers’ voices are heard and heeded.&nbsp; Unions provide, in one word, democracy in the workplace.&nbsp; Organizing, joining a union &#8212; that’s a democratic and democracy action &#8212; in action.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Unions aren’t just good for the workers who join them.&nbsp;&nbsp; Rebuilding America with union labor is smart for business and the American public and for our entire country.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Union workers &#8212; and I&#8217;m not just saying because you&#8217;re sitting there, but giving you my word &#8212; you&#8217;re the best in the world at what you do &#8212; highly skilled, highly trained.&nbsp; You’ve got a voice in the workplace, a sense of ownership in the project.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When union workers are on the job, projects are completed efficiently and they&#8217;re completed professionally.&nbsp; That’s good for the American taxpayer.&nbsp; It’s good for families in every neighborhood where infrastructure projects are underway, and &#8212;</p>



<p>So we’re going to keep investing in you and your families.&nbsp; We can and we must do more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, there are nearly 1.2 million extremely qualified women who haven’t returned to the workforce.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a simple reason: There’s no affordable childcare for them.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Many families pay up to &#8212; in this city and other major cities, they pay up to $14,000 a year for one child.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I got to the Senate, as some of you know, right after I got elected in November 17 &#8212; in December 18th, after that election, I got a phone call saying my wife and daughter had just been killed.&nbsp; A tractor trailer broadsided them, and my two boys weren’t al- &#8212; weren&#8217;t supposed to make it.&nbsp; My boys did make, thank God.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the point was, everybody thinks I commuted every day because I was this good</p>



<p>father wanting to go home.&nbsp; That&#8217;s true.&nbsp; But &#8212; but I couldn&#8217;t afford daycare.&nbsp; So I had my mom and my sister and my brother &#8212; I had to do it from home.&nbsp; I had no choice.&nbsp; And I was making a good salary.&nbsp; I think, at the time, we were making $42,000 a year, which was a fair amount of money.&nbsp; I couldn&#8217;t afford childcare.&nbsp; And these women can&#8217;t afford it either.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you capped childcare, as I have proposed, at 7 percent of a family’s income making less than 125 grand a year, it could cut co- &#8212; in half the costs of childcare, saving thousands of dollars and freeing so many people to be able to go back to work, particularly these women who are totally qualified but have no alternative but to stay home.</p>



<p>Or take prescription drugs, like insulin.&nbsp; Many of you know people who have Type 1 diabetes &#8212; another reason for insulin.&nbsp; Do you know how much it costs to make that vial of insulin?&nbsp; Ten dollars &#8212; T-E-N.&nbsp; Ten dollars.</p>



<p>But you see families paying, on average, over $641 a month for that insu- &#8212; up to $1,000 a month.&nbsp; Think about those 200,000 kids out there &#8212; maybe some of your children &#8212; who have Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; Two hundred thousand.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And think about what it does to a parent who looks at their child, doesn&#8217;t have insurance, doesn&#8217;t have the cash, and wonders, &#8220;My God, what am I going to do?&nbsp; I have no idea how we&#8217;re going to pay for what we need so desperately.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It not only puts the child&#8217;s life in jeopardy, it strips you of your dignity.&nbsp; How can you look at your child, knowing they need this but there&#8217;s no way?&nbsp; You don&#8217;t qualify for it because you&#8217;re making some money, but you don&#8217;t have enough money to pay for that monthly bill.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s easy.&nbsp; We can cap insulin at $35 a month.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll still make 350 percent profit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, there’s so much more we can do if we let Medicaid be able to do what they do.&nbsp; Those of you who are veterans, they negotiate &#8212; Veterans Administration negotiates with Medicare for the pri- &#8212; for the price they charge.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a big deal.&nbsp; They still make a lot of money.</p>



<p>But what&#8217;s going on now &#8212; we can do it all without adding to inflation.&nbsp; You don’t have to believe me that &#8212; about that.&nbsp; Seventeen Nobel laureates in economics within the last six months wrote to me independently and said, &#8220;Guess what?&nbsp; If you do what you&#8217;re talking about, it will not only not increase inflation, it will reduce the impact on inflation.&#8221;</p>



<p>We can do this without raising a penny in taxes on anyone making under $400,000.&nbsp; We have to do it.&nbsp; All we have to do is ask the wealthiest Americans among us and major corporations to pay their fair share &#8212; just a little bit more.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Really.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a joke.</p>



<p>I made a commitment: No one making less than $400,000 in my administra- &#8212; while I&#8217;m President will pay a many &#8212; a penny more in taxes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I held up the passage of the &#8212; of the Infrastructure Bill.&nbsp; They wanted to add a fee for highways.&nbsp; I said, &#8220;No.&nbsp; People &#8212; ordinary people are going to be paying for that.&nbsp; I’m not for that.&#8221;&nbsp; We got to have everybody chip in and pay their fair share.</p>



<p>Look, folks, there&#8217;s no reason why someone making $10 million a year should pay a lower tax rate than a married couple who are a firefighter and a schoolteacher.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s how it works.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I mean, for real, there&#8217;s no reason why, in 2020, the 55 of the companies &#8212; Fortune 500 companies paid zero in federal income tax and they made $40 billion.&nbsp; Zero.&nbsp; Zero.</p>



<p>Look, I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; If you can go out and make a million or a billion dollars, go at it.&nbsp; But for God&#8217;s sake, chip in and pay your fair share.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I think &#8212; you know, a lot of my friends are registered Republicans living out there.&nbsp; They think that too.&nbsp; I mean, it&#8217;s just so outrageous.&nbsp; That $2 trillion tax cut, the last guy &#8212; what was his name?&nbsp; Anyway, the last guy.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I forgot it.&nbsp; He never showed up for the inauguration, but anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside &#8212; I shouldn’t kid.&nbsp; But that tax cut basically went to the top one tenth of 1 percent of the American public.&nbsp; And it didn&#8217;t grow the economy.</p>



<p>Look, the bottom line is this: The United States is in a position to outcompete the world once again.&nbsp; If we can keep coming together to invest in the backbone of America, there&#8217;s no limit to what we can achieve.</p>



<p>When I &#8212; I wasn&#8217;t going to run again, as some of you know. Some of you are my friends.&nbsp; But when I finally decided to run &#8212; and my kids encouraged it because &#8212; anyway, I won&#8217;t go into that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I finally decided to run.&nbsp; And the fact of the matter is I made a judgment that we just had to &#8212; there&#8217;s no reason why we have to keep it the way it&#8217;s been.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When&#8217;s the last time trickle-down economy has trickled anybody you know?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.</p>



<p>So, look, I said I was running for three reasons back then.&nbsp;&nbsp; One, to restore the soul of this country.&nbsp; And by that, I meant decency and honor and honesty and what we&#8217;re going to do to.&nbsp; And two, to rebuild the backbone of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; To rebuild the backbone of America, which is the middle class and working people.&nbsp; And two &#8212; and three, to try to unify the country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been the hardest thing so far.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to get there, because you can&#8217;t have a democracy function unless you can generate consensus.&nbsp; You ultimately have to unify it, as angry as I sometimes get.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, look, America &#8212; this is a fact: America has always counted on union workers.&nbsp; And given just half a chance, you have never, ever, ever &#8212; not a &#8212; you&#8217;ve never let the country down.&nbsp; We&#8217;re counting on you again.&nbsp; And you can count on me to keep fighting for you, I promise you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, folks, let&#8217;s continue giving working families a fighting chance.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s face the challenge ahead.&nbsp; And let&#8217;s keep building a better America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And one last thing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re announcing today an investment through the Infrastructure Law &#8212; the largest investment in public transit in American history: $20.5 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s going to accomplish two big things: create more good union jobs using products made in America and reduce pollution at the same time, while making it safer and easier for folks to get to work.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let&#8217;s keep going.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s keep building.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s keep it on the way.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; May God bless you. And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>1:30 P.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
