<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 07:00:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Japan-U.S. Joint Leaders’ Statement: Strengthening the Free and Open International&#160;Order </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/japan-u-s-joint-leaders-statement-strengthening-the-free-and-open-international-order/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53860</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Japan and the United States affirm a partnership that is stronger and deeper than at any time in its history. Guided by our shared values; anchored by our common commitment to democracy and the rule of law; inspired by the innovation and technological dynamism of our economies; and rooted in the deep people-to-people ties&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Japan and the United States affirm a partnership that is stronger and deeper than at any time in its history. Guided by our shared values; anchored by our common commitment to democracy and the rule of law; inspired by the innovation and technological dynamism of our economies; and rooted in the deep people-to-people ties between our countries, the Japan-U.S relationship is the cornerstone of a free and open Indo-Pacific region.<br>&nbsp;<br>It is in this spirit that Prime Minister&nbsp;of Japan KISHIDA Fumio welcomed Joseph R. Biden, Jr to Japan in his first visit as President of the United States. President Biden commended Prime Minister Kishida’s global leadership, including in&nbsp;the Japan-Australia-India-U.S.&nbsp;(Quad)&nbsp;Summit meeting.<br>&nbsp;<br>As global partners, Japan and the United States affirm that the rules- based international order is indivisible; threats to international law and the free and fair economic order anywhere constitute a challenge to our values and interests everywhere. Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden shared the view that the greatest immediate challenge to this order is Russia’s brutal, unprovoked, and unjustified aggression against Ukraine.&nbsp;The two leaders&nbsp;condemned Russia&#8217;s actions, and called for Russia to be held accountable for its atrocities. They reaffirmed their support for Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.&nbsp;The Prime Minister and the President underscored the importance of the international community’s unity, and expressed solidarity with the Ukrainian people in responding to Russia’s aggression through sanctions, including financial sanctions, export controls, and other steps, taken with like-minded countries to impose long-lasting economic costs on Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>The two leaders shared the view that the United&nbsp;Nations&nbsp;(U.N.) forms the foundation of the rules-based international order, grounded in shared principles and universal values articulated in the U.N. Charter, including respect for human rights. Both commended the unprecedented global unity demonstrated by U.N. Member States in condemning Russia’s aggression against Ukraine and suspending it from the U.N. Human Rights Council. Recognizing that the U.N. Security Council (UNSC) has primary responsibility for&nbsp;the&nbsp;maintenance&nbsp;of&nbsp;international peace and security on behalf of the Member States, the two leaders expressed deep concern about Russia’s irresponsible behavior as a Permanent Member and its abuse of the veto, particularly Russia’s attempt to shield itself from accountability for its aggression against another Member State. The two leaders expressed a determination to strengthen the United Nations and to encourage all Member States to recommit to the vision and values enshrined in the U.N. Charter. Both expressed the need to strengthen and modernize the multilateral system to better enable it to meet&nbsp;the challenges of the 21st century.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden reiterated support for Japan’s permanent membership on a reformed Security Council, and for other countries who are important champions of multilateral cooperation and aspire to permanent seats. The two leaders also stressed the importance of strengthening coordination among democracies and like-minded partners to effectively address the challenges they face.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Advancing a “Free and Open Indo-Pacific”<br></u></strong><br>Notwithstanding the ongoing crisis in Europe, the two leaders reaffirmed that the Indo-Pacific is a region of vital importance to global peace, security, and prosperity &#8211; and one that faces mounting strategic challenges to the rules-based international order. From this standpoint, Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden committed to action to advance their shared vision of a free and open Indo-Pacific region. Prime Minister Kishida welcomed&nbsp;the U.S.&nbsp;“Indo-Pacific Strategy.” President Biden emphasized unwavering U.S.&nbsp;commitment to the region, and underscored that his strategy will be matched with resources and steady implementation. The two leaders welcomed the increasingly vibrant, multilayered, and interconnected architecture in the region that supports our common vision; they affirmed the importance of ASEAN unity and centrality, and highlighted the important work of the Quad, AUKUS, and other multilateral fora. They also underscored the importance of cooperation with like-minded partners in other regions, such as Europe and Canada.&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Regional Issues: Responding to an Increasingly Challenging Regional Security Environment<br></span><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden called on China to stand with the international community and unequivocally condemn Russia’s actions in Ukraine. They discussed continuing actions by China that are inconsistent with the international rules-based order, including coercion by economic and other means. Noting China&#8217;s ongoing increase in its nuclear capabilities, the two leaders requested China to contribute to arrangements that reduce nuclear risks, increase transparency, and advance nuclear disarmament. They also concurred to work together to strengthen deterrence to maintain peace and stability in the region. The two leaders strongly opposed any unilateral attempts to change the status quo in the East China Sea, and reiterated their strong opposition to China’s&nbsp;unlawful maritime claims, militarization of reclaimed features, and coercive activities in the South China Sea; they emphasized&nbsp;their firm commitment to the rule of law, including the freedom of navigation and overflight,&nbsp;consistent with the UN Convention on the Law of the Sea&nbsp;(UNCLOS). Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden stated that their basic positions on Taiwan remain unchanged, and reiterated the importance of peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait as an indispensable element in security and prosperity in the international community. They encouraged the peaceful resolution of cross-Strait issues. Both leaders voiced concern over the recent PRC-Solomon Islands security agreement, which was concluded in a non-transparent manner without addressing regional voices of concern. Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden also shared serious and ongoing concerns&nbsp;regarding&nbsp;developments in Hong Kong and human rights issues in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region. They underscored the importance of candid communication&nbsp;with China, including at the leader level, and&nbsp;expressed the intent to work with China&nbsp;where possible on areas of common interest.&nbsp;Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden welcomed the inauguration of the new government of the Republic of Korea (ROK), and stressed the critical importance of close ties and cooperation among Japan,&nbsp;the United States, and&nbsp;the ROK, including&nbsp;security ties. The two leaders condemned North Korea&#8217;s advancing&nbsp;nuclear and missile development activities, including its recent ICBM launches. They reaffirmed their commitment to the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula in accordance with UNSC resolutions,&nbsp;and urged&nbsp;North Korea to&nbsp;abide by&nbsp;its obligations under these resolutions. The two leaders reaffirmed U.S. commitment to&nbsp;the&nbsp;immediate resolution of the abductions&nbsp;issue. Both leaders expressed support for a calibrated diplomatic approach to North Korea, and called for its engagement in serious and sustained dialogue.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden condemned the coup in Myanmar and the Myanmar military’s brutal attacks on civilians, and committed to continue taking action to press for the immediate cessation of violence, the release of all those who are wrongfully detained, unfettered countrywide humanitarian access, and a swift return to democracy.<br><br>The two leaders&nbsp;expressed&nbsp;concern about the increasing activities of Russian military forces around Japan, and committed to remain attentive to cooperation between China and Russia in military affairs.<br></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">The Japan-U.S. Alliance: Strengthening Deterrence and Response Capabilities</span></p>



<p>The&nbsp;two&nbsp;leaders renewed their commitment to strengthening the deterrence and response capabilities of the Alliance. Prime Minister Kishida&nbsp;expressed&nbsp;his&nbsp;resolve&nbsp;to&nbsp;examine all options necessary for national defense, including capabilities to counter missile threats. Prime Minister Kishida stated his determination to fundamentally&nbsp;reinforce&nbsp;Japan’s&nbsp;defense capabilities&nbsp;and secure substantial increase of its defense budget needed to effect it. President Biden strongly supported Prime Minister Kishida’s determination.<br><br>President Biden&nbsp;reiterated&nbsp;the U.S. commitment to&nbsp;the defense of&nbsp;Japan under the&nbsp;Treaty&nbsp;of Mutual Cooperation and Security,&nbsp;backed by the full range of capabilities, including&nbsp;nuclear; the leaders reaffirmed their intent to ensure full bilateral coordination through the Alliance Coordination Mechanism throughout every phase of a developing situation. The two leaders affirmed the critical importance of ensuring that U.S. extended deterrence remains credible and resilient. They reiterated the significance of enhancing bilateral discussions on extended deterrence, including through the Security Consultative Committee (SCC) and the Extended Deterrence Dialogue. The President reaffirmed&nbsp;that Article V of the&nbsp;Treaty&nbsp;applies to the Senkaku&nbsp;Islands, and the two leaders reiterated their opposition to any unilateral action that seeks to undermine Japan’s longstanding administration of the Senkaku Islands.&nbsp;The two leaders decided to accelerate cooperation in the cyber and space domains as well as in the field of emerging technologies. They shared the view that cyber security and information security form the foundation of close alliance cooperation, and will remain a continuous focus of our collaboration. The two leaders expressed their determination to continually modernize the Alliance, evolve bilateral roles and missions, and strengthen joint capabilities including by aligning strategies and prioritizing goals together.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden affirmed their intent to deepen cooperation on joint training and capacity building&nbsp;in third countries, including through cooperation by the&nbsp;Japan and U.S.&nbsp;Coast Guards; the two leaders welcomed the signing of annexes to the Memorandum of Cooperation between the U.S. Coast Guard and the Japan Coast Guard.<br><br>The two leaders confirmed the steady implementation of the realignment of U.S. forces in Japan, including the construction of the Futenma Replacement Facility at Henoko as the only solution that avoids the continued use of MCAS Futenma,&nbsp;development of the Field Carrier Landing Practice Facility at Mageshima, and the relocation of U.S. Marine Corps units from Okinawa to Guam.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Achieving More Resilient, Sustainable and Inclusive Economic Growth</span></p>



<p>The two leaders discussed opportunities to further secure our shared prosperity. They exchanged perspectives on the importance of bold economic policies, including Prime Minister Kishida’s “new form of capitalism” and President Biden’s plan to build from the bottom up and the middle out, that promote technological advances while recognizing that the benefits of such progress must accrue to all communities, reduce inequality, and strengthen the middle-class in both nations. The two leaders also expressed their determination that Japan and the United States play an active role in addressing the challenges most salient for the global community &#8211; whether the emergence of new technologies, the impact of climate change, or&nbsp;transnational threats such as infectious disease.<br><br>The two leaders confirmed that Japan and the United States will collaborate in protecting and promoting critical technologies, including through the use of export controls, supporting their respective competitive advantages and ensuring&nbsp;supply chain resilience. They concurred on establishing a joint task force to explore the development of next generation semiconductors, based on “the Basic Principles on Semiconductor Cooperation” adopted in the Japan-U.S. Commercial and Industrial Partnership (JUCIP). President Biden noted the Japanese Diet’s approval of the Economic Security Promotion Bill, with its focus on supply chain resilience, essential infrastructure protection, technology development and the protection of patent applications. The two leaders concurred in exploring further cooperation to strengthen economic security.<br><br>The two leaders applauded the work to date under the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/fact-sheet-the-u-s-japan-competitiveness-and-resilience-core-partnership/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Competitiveness and Resilience (CoRe) Partnership </a>announced last year, and expressed their intention to hold the Japan-U.S. Economic Policy Consultative Committee (the Economic &#8220;2+2&#8221;) at the Ministerial level in July 2022.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida expressed his support for President Biden’s Indo-Pacific Economic Framework (IPEF), and the two leaders welcomed the launch of discussions among IPEF partners toward future negotiations.<br><br>The two leaders recognized&nbsp;the importance of a multilateral trading system based on free and fair economic rules, and&nbsp;confirmed that they will work closely together, through&nbsp;international frameworks such as&nbsp;the G7, G20, WTO, and OECD, to&nbsp;address non-market policies and practices as well as economic coercion, that are incompatible with the&nbsp;multilateral trading system. They also welcomed the recent progress made on bilateral and multilateral trade issues as well as in advancing close cooperation in such areas as digital trade and combatting forced labor. Both leaders reaffirmed the moral and economic imperative of ending the use of forced labor and concurred in working together, recognizing the importance of enhancing predictability and fostering an enabling environment for businesses that respect human rights in their supply chains.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden reaffirmed the importance of implementing the&nbsp;“G20 Principles&nbsp;for&nbsp;Quality Infrastructure Investment” and confirmed that they will further promote efforts to meet global infrastructure needs, in cooperation with the G7 and regional partners. They reiterated the importance of promoting debt sustainability and transparency under the G20 Common Framework. The two leaders also stressed the importance of fair and open lending practices. They reiterated the importance of internationally recognized rules and standards for major creditor countries.<br><br>The two leaders welcomed recent efforts by the international community to secure stable energy and food supplies, which are threatened by the impact of Russia’s aggression against Ukraine. Prime Minister Kishida emphasized the significant role U.S. Liquid Natural Gas plays in alleviating global supply constraints and welcomed investment by U.S. industry to increase oil and natural gas production. The two leaders also welcomed the establishment of Japan-U.S. Clean Energy and Energy Security Initiative (CEESI) to achieve both energy security and net-zero emissions. They confirmed their commitment to work bilaterally and multilaterally on energy and food security, and to cooperate with international organizations such as the International Energy Agency to promote clean energy and mitigate the impact of the disruption in energy supplies, especially on developing countries. Building on the G7 countries’ commitment to reduce dependence on Russian energy, the two leaders shared their intention to explore an initiative to provide Asian partners with support for strengthening their energy security<em>.</em><br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden welcomed Japan’s commitment to take all available measures to double demand for bioethanol, including for sustainable aviation fuel and on-road fuel, by 2030 to reduce dependence on imported petroleum.<br><br>They also shared the need to strengthen resilient and diverse supply chains of critical minerals and to elevate environmental, social, and governance standards in the sector.<br><br>The two leaders celebrated the deep tradition of space cooperation between Japan and the United States. They announced progress in collaboration on the Artemis program, including reaffirming our shared intention to include a Japanese astronaut on Gateway and on human and robotic lunar surface missions. Both leaders committed to conclude negotiations on the Framework Agreement and the Implementing Arrangement for Gateway cooperation in 2022.<br></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Global Challenges: Realizing Human Security in a New Era</span></p>



<p>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden confirmed that they will continue cooperating to overcome&nbsp;the&nbsp;COVID-19&nbsp;crisis and strengthen health security to prevent, prepare&nbsp;for, and respond to future pandemics, including through frameworks such as the&nbsp;Quad,&nbsp;the COVID-19&nbsp;Global Action Plan, and the G20 Finance and Health fora.&nbsp;The two leaders&nbsp;confirmed&nbsp;support through COVAX, as well as for “last&nbsp;one&nbsp;mile support” programs to increase equitable access to vaccines,&nbsp;while working together on therapeutics, testing, and strengthening health systems. They also confirmed the need to strengthen the global health architecture, including&nbsp;by reforming&nbsp;the WHO, establishing a new pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank, strengthening coordination arrangements between finance and health authorities,&nbsp;with a view to achieving universal health coverage.<br><br>The two leaders welcomed further progress in&nbsp;Japan-U.S.&nbsp;joint research on cancer cures and treatment, and welcomed the renewal of the Memoranda of Understanding enabling this cooperation. President Biden highlighted the role of the National Cancer Center of Japan in promoting international collaborations under the Cancer Moonshot program since 2017, and underscored that U.S. commitment to growing that initiative.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden recognized the existential threat of the climate crisis, and committed to making the 2020s the decisive decade for climate action. They affirmed their intent to meet today’s energy demands while working toward long-term energy security by implementing ambitious 2030 nationally determined contributions under the Paris Agreement and 2050 net zero emission goals. In service of these goals, the two leaders affirmed their intent to enhance cooperation under the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/u-s-japan-climate-partnership-fact-sheet/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Japan US Climate Partnership</a>.<br><br>The two leaders recognized the importance of nuclear energy as a critical and reliable source of carbon-free electricity and process heat. To this end, they committed to greater nuclear energy collaboration and to accelerating the development and global deployment of advanced and small modular reactors by jointly using export promotion and capacity building tools. The two leaders also concurred to work together to create more resilient nuclear supply chains, including uranium fuel, for both existing and new reactors.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden reaffirmed their intent to work together toward a world without nuclear weapons. In particular, they affirmed their commitment to strengthen the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons as the cornerstone of the international nuclear non-proliferation and disarmament regime. Prime Minister Kishida noted the importance of advancing realistic measures on nuclear disarmament, while addressing&nbsp;security challenges, and President Biden agreed. The two leaders&nbsp;welcomed recent progress in cooperation on nuclear security, including the removal of&nbsp;all highly enriched uranium (HEU) fuel from the University of Tokyo research reactor “Yayoi” and other Japanese research reactors to the United States, furthering&nbsp;their mutual goal of&nbsp;minimizing worldwide&nbsp;stocks of HEU.<br><br>Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden, recognizing that the pandemic has made promoting gender equity more important than ever, concurred that ensuring that all people, regardless of gender identity, can achieve their full potential is both a moral and strategic imperative, critical to every aspect of society and the economy. The two leaders also emphasized the importance of preventing and addressing gender-based violence, including conflict-related sexual violence.<br></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">People-to-People Exchange: Creating Diverse and Inclusive Networks that Support a “Free and Open Indo-Pacific”</span></p>



<p>The two leaders underscored the importance of mutual exchange and collaboration, to foster the next generation of leaders that will advance a “free and open Indo-Pacific.” They concurred to resume and boost various exchanges, including&nbsp;through study abroad programs;&nbsp;the JET Programme; the Kakehashi Project and the Tomodachi Initiative;&nbsp;and fellowships and collaborative projects among researchers and practitioners such as the Mansfield Fellowship&nbsp;Program and those of the Japan Foundation. Prime Minister Kishida expressed his intention to boost exchanges among professionals and practitioners in areas such as advanced technologies, climate change and disaster management and implement Kakehashi with an emphasis on Okinawa, Hiroshima and Nagasaki. The two leaders also paid tribute to the history, contributions and cultural heritage of Japanese Americans and concurred to engage next generation Japanese American leaders in the future Japan-U.S. cooperation. The two leaders also reaffirmed the role of the U.S.-Japan Conference on Cultural and Educational Interchange in people-to-people exchange.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Toward&nbsp;Building a Future-Oriented Japan-U.S.&nbsp;Relationship</u></strong><br>As the two largest democratic economies, Japan and the United States have a unique obligation to support democratic values, norms, and principles, and to advance a vision for the future in which peace, prosperity, and freedom are ensured. Prime Minister Kishida and President Biden together embraced this responsibility. They affirmed the importance of building a coalition of likeminded partners to advance this shared vision, noting that Japan will chair the G7 and the United States will host APEC in 2023.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: U.S.- Japan Climate&#160;Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/u-s-japan-climate-partnership-fact-sheet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recognizing that the path to energy security runs through clean energy, the United States and Japan intend to build on their cooperation to increase climate ambition, including through decarbonization and clean energy, and continue to lead on their respective domestic climate efforts and on accelerating international climate action. The two sides intend to reinforce bilateral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Recognizing that the path to energy security runs through clean energy, the United States and Japan intend to build on their cooperation to increase climate ambition, including through decarbonization and clean energy, and continue to lead on their respective domestic climate efforts and on accelerating international climate action. The two sides intend to reinforce bilateral cooperation in the priority areas below to achieve their 2050 net zero goals and their aligned 2030 nationally determined contributions (NDCs) under the Paris Agreement, alongside promoting a global trajectory consistent with keeping global temperature increase to 1.5 degrees Celsius within reach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two sides intend to further cooperate and accelerate respective action by:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Exchanging views regarding respective domestic planning for, and implementation of, policies to achieve their respective 2030 NDCs under the Paris Agreement and 2050 net zero emission goals;</li><li>&nbsp;Working to, in line with their respective climate finance pledges, continue contributing to fully delivering on the goal of developed countries to jointly mobilize $100 billion in climate finance as soon as possible, in line with the Climate Finance Delivery Plan, including enhancing action on the ten principles for collective actions identified therein;</li><li>Advancing efforts to make financial flows consistent with the global achievement of net zero greenhouse gas emissions no later than 2050, with deep emission reductions in the 2020s and climate-resilient development;</li><li>Working to ensure there is no new direct government support for unabated international coal-fired power generation and to rapidly scale-up technologies and policies that further accelerate the transition away from unabated coal capacity to an overwhelmingly decarbonized power system in the 2030s, consistent with our 2030 NDCs and net zero commitments, while ensuring stable energy supply;</li><li>Advancing rapid decarbonization of on-road transport, including by working to achieve a significant market share for zero-emission vehicles in the light duty sector by 2030, by reducing emissions from medium and heavy-duty vehicles and by promoting innovation for various technologies;</li><li>Enhancing cooperation bilaterally and through multilateral fora to address climate-related financial risks and opportunities, including by promoting consistent and comparable mandatory disclosure of climate-related information that is decision-useful for investors;</li><li>Continuing to enhance efforts and cooperation in innovation and advanced technology deployment, including in such areas as renewable energy, energy storage (such as batteries and long-duration energy storage technologies), smart grids, building electrification, energy efficiency, clean hydrogen, clean ammonia, carbon capture utilization and storage/carbon recycling, industrial decarbonization, and advanced nuclear power, including small modular reactors;&nbsp;and advancing collaboration under the U.S.-Japan Clean Energy and Energy Security Initiative (CEESI), including several new bilateral task forces for accelerating offshore wind, geothermal energy technologies and nuclear power;&nbsp;</li><li>Collaborating in the First Movers Coalition (FMC), where the United States welcomes Japan as a government partner and steering board member, and recognizing that Japan’s participation in the First Movers Coalition, a flagship initiative launched at COP26 to drive demand for green innovation across hard-to-abate sectors, will help elevate the role of Japanese companies in these efforts, align public investment and demand with green innovation in FMC sectors, and provide supportive policies to help scale up supply to meet FMC demand signals;</li><li>Collaborating to accelerate the deployment of heat pumps in our respective domestic markets and globally to displace fuel burned in buildings and advance energy security and climate goals through electrification of space and water heating in buildings, for example through support for manufacturing, training, and promotion;</li><li>Advancing collaboration to accelerate subnational action including under the Global Subnational Zero Carbon Promotion Initiative by continuing the Zero Carbon City International Forum, sharing best practices and considering opportunities for collaborative actions in third countries;</li><li>Coordinating closely on our diplomatic efforts toward all major economies’ taking bold actions in the 2020s to keep a 1.5 degree Celsius limit on warming within reach, including through the Major Economies Forum and the G20;&nbsp;</li><li>Enhancing collaboration on the implementation of Article 6 of the Paris Agreement, including through capacity building activities on high integrity carbon markets by sharing best practices and lessons learned;</li><li>Pursuing opportunities to cooperate on&nbsp;fully utilizing existing nuclear power, and to advance innovative nuclear power technologies, including&nbsp;strengthening industrial partnerships and deepening successful capacity building cooperation in third countries under the Foundational Infrastructure for the Responsible Use of Small Modular Reactor Technology (FIRST) program;</li><li>Enhancing cooperation to address methane emissions globally, recognizing the importance of the Global Methane Pledge and rapid global action to address methane; and by implementing domestic methane emission reduction based on respective national plans, and encouraging those countries that do not have such plans to develop them, and to pursue opportunities to provide financial and technical assistance to assist third countries to meet their methane reduction targets; and the U.S., as one of the largest producers and Japan, as one of the largest consumers, intend to take action to reduce methane emissions from production and consumption. Japan intends to share knowledge and information on technology to reduce methane emission through a Quad roundtable event focused on the oil and gas sector;</li><li>Working to accelerate deployment of offshore wind installations, both at home and in third countries, and seeking partnerships to scale financing, improve policy conditions, and undertake relevant technical work, recognizing the U.S. goal to deploy 30 gigawatts (GW) of offshore wind by 2030, and Japan’s goal to deploy 10 GW of offshore wind by 2030;</li><li>Securing resilient and diverse supply chains of critical minerals to support energy security and the clean energy transition;</li><li>Collaborating on greening government initiatives with the aim of using the procurement power of our respective national governments to achieve ambitious goals, including procuring carbon-free electricity, acquiring zero-emission light-duty vehicles, constructing net-zero emission buildings, and upgrading lighting to high-efficiency lighting, contributing to net-zero emissions by 2050 through greening overall national government operations;</li><li>Building on established deep cooperation on the decarbonization of the&nbsp;shipping sector&nbsp;to promote&nbsp;the demonstration, deployment, and adoption of low- and zero- emission lifecycle fuels and technologies for shipping, recognizing that decarbonizing the shipping sector is essential to transitioning to a clean energy economy; advancing ocean-based climate actions such as green shipping corridors and supply for zero-emission shipping;</li><li>Cooperating to accelerate the transition to decarbonized and lower-methane economies in third countries, particularly in the Indo-Pacific, including through:&nbsp;<br><br>The Japan-U.S. Clean Energy Partnership (JUCEP), which advances the deployment of renewable energy and decarbonization technologies in the Indo-Pacific through partnerships with the private sector, and; The Japan-U.S. Mekong Power Partnership, or JUMPP, which supports the Mekong’s energy security while encouraging greater regional power trade, renewable energy integration, and power market development.&nbsp; &nbsp;</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  The U.S.-Japan Competitiveness and Resilience (CoRe)&#160;Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/fact-sheet-the-u-s-japan-competitiveness-and-resilience-core-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53882</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and Japan, as the world’s two largest democratic economies, resolve to promote prosperity and to strengthen the rules-based economic order in the Indo-Pacific region and the world.&#160; Together, the two countries recognize the progress made under the U.S.-Japan Competitiveness and Resilience (CoRe) Partnership announced in April 2021 and commit to broaden and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States and Japan, as the world’s two largest democratic economies, resolve to promote prosperity and to strengthen the rules-based economic order in the Indo-Pacific region and the world.&nbsp; Together, the two countries recognize the progress made under the U.S.-Japan Competitiveness and Resilience (CoRe) Partnership announced in April 2021 and commit to broaden and deepen bilateral economic cooperation including through the Economic Policy Consultative Committee announced in January 2022.&nbsp;<br><br><strong><u>Competitiveness&nbsp;and Innovation</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Digital Economy</strong>:<ul><li>The United States and Japan launched the Global Digital Connectivity Partnership in May 2021 to further promote secure connectivity and a vibrant global digital economy.</li><li>The United States and Japan promoted an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable, and secure Internet at the 12th U.S.-Japan Policy Cooperation Dialogue on the Internet Economy, and endorsed the Declaration for the Future of the Internet.</li><li>The United States and Japan continued to promote sustainable smart cities, including through the Integrated Urban Services Program Launch Workshop in August 2021 and the APEC conference in September 2021.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Open Radio Access Networks (Open RAN)</strong><strong>:&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan strengthened collaboration on 5G supplier diversification and Open RAN, both bilaterally and through the Quad.</li><li>The United States and Japan supported industry-led efforts to promote a diverse and competitive telecommunications marketplace with trusted suppliers through the launch of the Prague Proposals on Telecommunications Supplier Diversity.&nbsp;</li><li>The United States, in collaboration with Japan, will launch in 2022 an Open RAN training academy in Southeast Asia to improve access to skilled workers needed to deploy Open RAN, drive workforce development, and promote supplier diversity.</li><li>Japan funded&nbsp;an R&amp;D lab in Texas to help telecommunications companies to evaluate and verify interoperability of 5G mobile base stations compliant with Open RAN.</li><li>U.S. and Japanese officials and private sector representatives engaged Latin American officials through visits, workshops and seminars to advance secure 5G networks and open and interoperable technologies, including Open RAN.</li><li>Japan held the Beyond 5G International Conference with high-level U.S. representation and aligned visions for the development and deployment of next generation network technologies. &nbsp;Our countries&nbsp;intend to fund new&nbsp;joint research and development projects on 5G and Beyond 5G,&nbsp;including those using Open RAN (including v-RAN) technologies, in addition to projects funded under the&nbsp;Japan-U.S. Network Opportunity&nbsp;(JUNO) program.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Cybersecurity/Critical Infrastructure Resilience</strong><strong>:&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan concurred on the urgent need to take a collective approach to enhancing cybersecurity in an increasingly digital world with sophisticated cyber threats.</li><li>The United States and Japan, together with the EU, will organize the flagship Industrial Control Systems Cybersecurity Week to provide training in the Indo-Pacific Region.</li><li>The United States plans to provide cybersecurity training resources for the ASEAN-Japan Cybersecurity Capacity Building Centre funded and supported by Japan.</li><li>The United States and Japan commit to improving the defense of our nations’ critical infrastructure by sharing threat information.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Collaboration in the Indo-Pacific</strong>: &nbsp;<ul><li>The United States and Japan, together with Australia, are partnering with the Federated States of Micronesia (FSM), Kiribati, and Nauru to improve internet connectivity through a new undersea telecommunications cable.</li><li>The United States and Japan, together with Australia, will promote designing certification frameworks for quality infrastructure projects under the Blue Dot Network with support of the OECD, and in alignment with the G20 Principles for Quality Infrastructure Investment and the G20 Operational Guidelines for Sustainable Financing.</li><li>The United States and Japan will cooperate on supporting quality infrastructure development in emerging markets and encouraging the U.S. and Japanese private sectors to support infrastructure projects that advance global goals in such key areas as climate, digital economy and sustainable development including through the Memorandum of Cooperation between U.S. Trade and Development Agency and Japan Bank for International Cooperation.</li><li>The United States and Japan, along with Australia and New Zealand, are collaborating on the Papua New Guinea Electrification Partnership (PEP), which supports PNG’s ambitious goal of increasing the electrification rate from 13 percent to 70 percent by 2030.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Science and Technology Cooperation:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan held the 16th Japan-U.S. Joint Working-Level Committee (JWLC) Meeting on Science and Technology Cooperation in June 2021 to discuss the full range of science and technology cooperation between our countries, such as quantum technologies, artificial intelligence (AI), biotechnology, and climate change technology.&nbsp;</li><li>The United States and Japan&nbsp;signed the Project Arrangement on quantum information science, which will promote research and development on quantum communication, computing, sensors, and materials.</li><li>The United States and Japan intend to conduct joint research and development projects of critical and emerging technologies for respective economic security interests, foreseeing the potential future acquisition and utilization of such technologies, not only between the two countries but also together with other like-minded countries.</li><li>The United States and Japan acknowledged the progress of collaboration on Privacy Enhancing Technologies and welcomed the planned workshop towards future implementation of the technology.</li><li>The United States and Japan seek to accelerate innovation and startup collaboration to enhance competitiveness, possibly through Japan’s concept to establish a “Startup Campus.”<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Civil Space Cooperation</strong><strong>:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan intend to complete the negotiation on the Framework Agreement in 2022 and conclude it in 2023, which will expand bilateral cooperation for decades to come across a wide variety of space exploration, scientific, and research activities.</li><li>The United States and Japan announced that they are committed to a Japanese astronaut opportunity on the Gateway, a human outpost in the lunar vicinity, as part of expanding Artemis collaboration.</li><li>The United States and Japan also announced continued progress on our Artemis collaboration for human and robotic lunar surface missions, including a shared ambition to see a future Japanese astronaut on the lunar surface.&nbsp;</li><li>To advance the return to the lunar surface, the United States and Japan are working to sign an Implementing Arrangement for Gateway cooperation in 2022.</li><li>Japan provided the United States with an asteroid sample collected by Hayabusa2 in November 2021 and the United States intends to provide Japan with a sample from the asteroid Bennu in 2023, as part of ongoing collaboration on a variety of space science missions.</li><li>The United States and Japan are cooperating to use Earth observation data to improve our capability to predict how our climate is changing.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Cooperation for Creating International Standards:&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan intend to further enhance cooperation in the international standardization organizations through cooperation frameworks such as the new International Standards Cooperation Network.</li><li>The United States and Japan strengthened collaboration on international technical standards development, both bilaterally and through the Quad Critical and Emerging Technology Working Group. The United States and Japan&nbsp;have collaborated in the United Nations fora to&nbsp;develop international guidelines and technical requirements&nbsp;for safe and secured&nbsp;advanced autonomous driving technology. The United States and Japan have collaborated to develop international safety standards for electric and hydrogen fuel cell vehicle technologies.</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Enhanced Cooperation on Export Controls:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan discussed a joint effort to enhance U.S.-Japan cooperation on more effective and agile export controls on critical technologies, including microelectronics and cyber surveillance systems, to address the misuse of critical technologies by malicious actors and inappropriate transfers of emerging technologies through research activities<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Supply Chain Resilience</strong><strong>:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan are working together to advance&nbsp;resilient supply chains for critical commodities in order&nbsp;to minimize supply disruption and inflation concerns, a threat to middle-class prosperity.</li><li>The two countries intend to cooperate with like-minded partners in areas such as:</li></ul></li><li>Semiconductor manufacturing capacity, diversification, next-generation semiconductor research and development, and responding to supply shortages.</li><li>Information sharing and collaboration on advanced battery supply chains; and</li><li>Cooperation to build stable and resilient supply chains for critical minerals, including midstream materials processing.<ul><li>The United States and Japan reaffirmed the importance of respecting human rights in supply chains and reinvigorated our cooperation to enhance predictability and foster an enabling environment for businesses to actively engage in efforts to respect human rights, including through the Economic Policy Consultative Committee.</li><li>The United States and Japan are committed to diversifying and strengthening the resilience of supply chains in the Indo-Pacific region, including through promoting trade facilitation and streamlined customs procedures.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>COVID-19 Response, Global Health, and Health Security</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>COVID-19 Response</strong><strong>:</strong><ul><li>Japan has committed to playing a leadership role under the U.S.-launched COVID-19 Global Action Plan under line of effort 1, “Get Shots in Arms” and to contributing to line of effort 6, “Strengthen Global Health Architecture.” The United States has provided more than $19 billion&nbsp;globally in&nbsp;COVID-19 funding for life-saving health and humanitarian assistance, with $580 million announced in December 2021 to support the work of multilateral partners to help fight the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; Japan has been providing approximately $5 billion in comprehensive support globally since the COVID-19 outbreak, with the recent pledge of up to $500 million that was made as the largest contribution at the COVAX AMC Summit in April 2022.</li><li>Bilaterally and in partnership with COVAX, the United States has shared more than 540 million doses of safe and effective COVID-19 vaccine with more than 115 countries and economies.&nbsp;</li><li>Japan has delivered approximately 44 million doses of COVID-19 vaccine donations to 32 countries and regions bilaterally or through the COVAX Facility and more than $160 million of &#8220;Last One Mile Support&#8221; to 77 countries and regions.</li><li>In April 2021, the United States co-hosted with Gavi, the Vaccine Alliance, the launch of the Investment Opportunity for the COVAX AMC to ensure the world’s poorest countries will get access to COVID-19 vaccines, regardless of their ability to pay. &nbsp;Building upon the initial progress by the United States, Japan hosted the COVAX AMC Summit in June 2021, which resulted in securing $9.6 billion in funding commitments excessing the AMC’s commitment goal.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Global Health Architecture including Global Health Security:</strong><ul><li>At the Global Pandemic Preparedness Summit, the United States pledged $150 million over three years, subject to Congressional appropriations, while Japan recently pledged $300 million to the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations through 2026.</li><li>The United States and Japan acknowledge the importance to further strengthen the global health architecture with a view to achieving universal health coverage (UHC), and to enhance prevention, preparedness and response, including through the pandemic preparedness and global health security fund at the World Bank, supporting the work of the G20 Joint Finance-Health Task Force, and ongoing negotiation on a WHO international instrument.&nbsp;</li><li>The United States and Japan committed to further strengthen the IHR (2005), including through implementation, compliance, and targeted amendments.</li><li>The United States and Japan reaffirmed commitments to support the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Malaria, and Tuberculosis.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Scientific Cooperation</strong><strong>:</strong><ul><li>The United States&nbsp;and Japan co-funded&nbsp;joint research projects&nbsp;on the “COVID-19 Research in Non-Medical Sciences,”&nbsp;on “Digital Science for post-COVID-19 Society,” and through the U.S.-Japan Cooperative Medical Science Program, including projects on “Countermeasures for COVID-19 in Medical Research.”</li><li>The United States and Japan supported an industry-led Healthcare Innovation Roundtable to enhance industry support for a pharmaceutical innovation ecosystem.</li><li>Under the Quad Vaccine Partnership, the United States and Japan have tirelessly promoted Quad science and technology cooperation, including on clinical trials, genomic surveillance, and pandemic preparedness joint exercise and the Quad Vaccine Confidence event, contributing to building back better health security.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Cancer:&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>The U.S. National Cancer Institute and the Japanese National Cancer Center extended a Memorandum of Cooperation on research collaboration, and signed a Memorandum of Understanding on cooperation in cancer research in May 2022.</li><li>Japan launched a moonshot research and development program on cancer to foster bilateral U.S.-Japan cancer research through Japan’s Cancer Moonshot program. The United States intends to foster research collaboration through the U.S. research programs including the United States Cancer Moonshot.&nbsp;</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Universal Health Coverage:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan committed, as members of the Group of Friends of UHC to take global leadership on promoting UHC towards the UN High-Level Meeting on UHC to be held in 2023 as well as the target year of achieving the SDGs (2030).</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Climate Change, Clean Energy, and Green Growth</u></strong><strong><u> and Recovery</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Global Subnational Zero Carbon Promotion Initiative:&nbsp;</strong><ul><li>During COP 26, Japan&nbsp;and&nbsp;the United States&nbsp;launched&nbsp;the Global Subnational Zero Carbon Promotion Initiative and subsequently co-hosted the Zero Carbon City International Forum to share subnational commitments, policies, and actions to mitigate climate change and adapt its impacts.&nbsp;<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Sustainable and Climate-Smart Agriculture:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan have been working together to identify opportunities on sustainable and climate-smart agriculture and intend to conduct research collaborations to mitigate methane emissions generated from rice paddies and livestock from 2022.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Clean Energy&nbsp;Cooperation:</strong><ul><li>The Japan-U.S.-Mekong Power Partnership (JUMPP) is providing technical assistance and capacity building to support energy security through regional power trade and renewable integration in the Mekong region.&nbsp;</li><li>Japan and&nbsp;the United States launched the Japan-U.S. Clean Energy Partnership (JUCEP)&nbsp;in April 2021&nbsp;to&nbsp;support&nbsp;countries in the Indo-Pacific&nbsp;and around the world to accelerate the transition to clean, affordable, and secure energy sources.&nbsp; In cooperation with the Government of Indonesia, Japan and the United States utilized financial, technical and business matchmaking tools to increase interest in renewables investment, and to conduct clean energy capacity building activities, including for Small Modular Reactor nuclear energy.</li><li>Japan&nbsp;and&nbsp;United States&nbsp;established&nbsp;the Clean Energy and Energy Security Initiative (CEESI) to&nbsp;strengthen energy security through stable and sufficient energy supply, including LNG, and accelerate innovation and marketization of clean energy technologies&nbsp;including renewable energy, hydrogen and fuel ammonia, CCUS/Carbon Recycling and nuclear power. CEESI will work toward achieving&nbsp;both global energy security and 2050 net zero&nbsp;goals.&nbsp;</li><li>The United States and Japan held the Carbon Neutral Port (CNP) Workshop, and concurred to further strengthen the collaboration and identified the ports of Los Angeles and Yokohama and Kobe as pilot cases.</li><li>The United States and Japan pursue opportunities to cooperate on fully utilizing existing nuclear power, to include collaboration on extending reactor life and ensuring security of fuel supply.</li><li>The United States and Japan committed to cooperate on advanced nuclear power technologies such as small modular reactors and fast reactors, including supporting their global deployment with capacity building and financial tools, and cooperating to develop resilient supply chains.</li><li>Japan will join the U.S.-led First Movers Coalition as a strategic government partner to accelerate the maturation and deployment of breakthrough clean technologies in hard-to-abate sectors.</li><li>The United States and Japan will strengthen cooperation on methane reductions across the fossil energy, agricultural, and waste sectors to support implementation of the Global Methane Pledge. &nbsp;This includes supporting methane emissions reductions in third countries.<br></li></ul></li><li><strong>Transparency for Investors on Climate Risks:</strong><ul><li>The United States and Japan will continue to collaborate to address climate-related financial risks and facilitate investors’ ability to evaluate climate-aligned opportunities. This includes by working in international forums to promote best practices on disclosure of climate-related information.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong>Expanding and Renewing our Partnership<br></strong>The United States and Japan committed to strengthen further our vibrant people-to-people ties by expanding collaboration and participation in research projects and international exchange programs. Our exchange programs will continue to distribute the benefits of the CoRe Partnership inclusively and equitably, to empower women in our societies.&nbsp; Exchange programs have engaged civil society, and the public and private sectors to encourage women’s role in the business sector, government, and STEM fields.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Kishida of&#160;Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/23/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-kishida-of-japan-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 04:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53893</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Prime Minister Kishida Fumio of Japan today, to advance cooperation on a range of bilateral, regional, and global issues. The President commended Prime Minister Kishida’s leadership in responding to Russia’s war against Ukraine, and his determination to strengthen Japan’s defense capabilities, noting that a strong U.S.-Japan alliance is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Prime Minister Kishida Fumio of Japan today, to advance cooperation on a range of bilateral, regional, and global issues. The President commended Prime Minister Kishida’s leadership in responding to Russia’s war against Ukraine, and his determination to strengthen Japan’s defense capabilities, noting that a strong U.S.-Japan alliance is the cornerstone of peace and stability in Indo-Pacific region. The two leaders committed to work closely together to address security challenges, including the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s (DPRK) nuclear and ballistic missile programs and China’s increasingly coercive behavior that runs counter to international law. They agreed to deepen cooperation in areas such as emerging technologies, supply chain security, and clean energy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###<br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces First Two Infant Formula Defense Production Act&#160;Authorizations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/22/president-biden-announces-first-two-infant-formula-defense-production-act-authorizations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 22:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53852</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Secretary Becerra Authorized Priority Orders of Input for Infant Formula The President is announcing the first two Defense Production Act (DPA) authorizations for infant formula. U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Secretary Xavier Becerra authorized the first two infant formula priority orders today. The two infant formula manufacturers can now begin to add legally&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>Secretary Becerra Authorized Priority Orders of Input for Infant Formula</em></strong></p>



<p>The President is announcing the first two Defense Production Act (DPA) authorizations for infant formula. U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Secretary Xavier Becerra authorized the first two infant formula priority orders today. The two infant formula manufacturers can now begin to add legally binding language to their orders with suppliers that will give them priority over other customers. Last week, the President invoked the DPA to ensure that manufacturers have the necessary ingredients to make safe, health infant formula here at home.</p>



<p>Earlier today, the President announced the second Operation Fly Formula flight had been sourced for later this week. The flight will transport 114 pallets of Gerber Good Start® Extensive HA infant formula. This is the remainder of the equivalent of up to 1.5 million 8-ounce bottles of three formulas—Alfamino® Infant, Alfamino® Junior, and Gerber Good Start® Extensive HA—all of which are hypoallergenic formulas for children with cow’s milk protein allergy. The first tranche of this shipment arrived in the United States on DOD aircraft earlier today. These formulas have been prioritized because they serve a critical medical purpose and are in short supply in the United States because of the Abbott Sturgis plant closure.</p>



<p>Today’s infant formula priority orders are:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Abbott Nutrition </strong>can now receive priority orders of raw materials like sugar and corn syrup for infant formula. Constraints in global&nbsp; supply chain for these materials mean that Abbott’s allotment/allocation of these materials have been limited to 75 percent of its normal amount. By allowing Abbott to receive its full allotment of needed raw materials, it will be able to quickly increase production by one third over where it stands today.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Reckitt </strong>(which owns Mead-Johnson) can now receive priority orders of consumables like single-use products like filters necessary to generate certain oils needed to produce infant formula. This will also allow Reckitt facilities to operate at maximum capacity.</li></ul>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration will continue to identify opportunities to invoke the Defense Production Act and further increase infant formula production to maximum capacity. The Biden-Harris Administration has been working around the clock to increase production of infant formula and keep store shelves stocked during the Abbott Nutrition voluntary recall.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden Administration Announces Second Operation Fly Formula&#160;Flight</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/22/biden-administration-announces-second-operation-fly-formula-flight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 20:54:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53850</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the Department of Defense (DOD) has sourced a second flight to fulfill the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)’s request for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé S.A. formula from Ramstein Air Base in Germany to Washington Dulles International Airport. From there, the formula will be transported to a Nestlé facility in Pennsylvania. DOD is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the Department of Defense (DOD) has sourced a second flight to fulfill the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA)’s request for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé S.A. formula from Ramstein Air Base in Germany to Washington Dulles International Airport. From there, the formula will be transported to a Nestlé facility in Pennsylvania. DOD is contracting with FedEx Express to transport the shipment via its integrated air and ground network. The flight and trucking will take place in the coming days. More details on timing will be announced when available.</p>



<p>The Operation Fly Formula shipments will transport 114 pallets of Gerber Good Start® Extensive HA infant formula. This is the remainder of the equivalent of up to 1.5 million 8-ounce bottles of three formulas—Alfamino® Infant, Alfamino® Junior, and Gerber Good Start® Extensive HA—all of which are hypoallergenic formulas for children with cow’s milk protein allergy. The first tranche of this shipment, announced on May 19, arrived in the United States via DOD aircraft on Sunday, May 22. These formulas have been prioritized because they serve a critical medical purpose and are in short supply in the United States because of the Abbott Sturgis plant closure.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, USDA and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) are authorized to use DOD-contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. In addition, President Biden has directed his Administration to take a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) to reopen Abbott Nutrition’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance to allow major formula manufacturers to safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Tokyo,&#160;Japan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/22/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-tokyo-japan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53841</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Tokyo, Japan 4:33 P.M. JST MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Okay, I just have a quick topper, and then we’ll have Jake Sullivan for you guys. Okay, just wanted to give a quick update on our administration’s work to speed up the import of infant formula and get more formula to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Tokyo, Japan</p>



<p>4:33 P.M. JST<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Okay, I just have a quick topper, and then we’ll have Jake Sullivan for you guys.</p>



<p>Okay, just wanted to give a quick update on our administration’s work to speed up the import of infant formula and get more formula to stores.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under Operation Fly Formula, the Departments of Agriculture and Health and Human Services are authorized to use Department of Defense contracted commercial aircraft to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards so it can get to stores &#8212; store shelves faster.</p>



<p>On Sunday morning &#8212; or later today &#8212; a military plane will arrive in Indiana with 78,000 pounds of specialty infant formula, enough for over half a million bottles.&nbsp; This formula was manufactured in an FDA-approved facility and will be inspected on arrival like all food imports.</p>



<p>We prioritize this for the first shipment because this formula types &#8212; type serves a critical medical purpose and is in short supply in the United States as the result of the Abbott Sturgis plant closure.</p>



<p>We are working with USDA and HHS to ensure this formula goes to those who need it the most.&nbsp; Due to the urgency of the situation, the Secretary of Defense approved U.S. military aircraft for this mission on Friday evening.</p>



<p>Typically, the process to transport this product from Europe to U.S. would take two weeks.&nbsp; Thanks to Operation Fly Formula, we cut that down to approximately three days.</p>



<p>This is a testament of the President&#8217;s commitment to pulling every lever to get more infant formula onto the market.&nbsp; And Operation Fly Formula is one tool that we are using to do so.</p>



<p>Okay, I have Jake Sullivan, as you all can see &#8212; National Security Advisor.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, can we have you step in just a little bit?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Hey, guys, just very briefly, you all know we&#8217;re on our way to Tokyo.&nbsp; And the President will spend tomorrow with Prime Minister Kishida and will also join a number of other leaders, some in person but largely virtually, to launch the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.</p>



<p>And then, of course, on Tuesday, he&#8217;ll join the Quad leaders for the second Quad Summit and also have the opportunity to meet with Prime Minister Modi and to meet with a Prime Minister who will then &#8212; right now, Prime Minister-Designate; as of tomorrow, actual Prime Minister Albanese, who is flying up tomorrow to be able to join in person for the Quad on Tuesday, which we think is a real testament to Australia&#8217;s investment in the Quad as a critical vehicle for the Indo-Pacific and this new Prime Minister&#8217;s investment in hitting the ground running as a leader in the region and a close ally of the United States.</p>



<p>So, I’m happy to get into details on any and all things, but why don&#8217;t I just stop there and let you guys fire away.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are those meetings with Modi and Albanese one on one?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; What do you mean by “one on one”?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is he meeting with them separately?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I mean, there’ll be other people in the room &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m talking about like &#8212; other than the Quad is what I meant.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Will have disti- &#8212; in addition to the Quad, he’ll have a distinct bilateral meeting with Prime Minister Modi and a distinct bilateral meeting with Prime Minister Albanese.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question about the Quad meeting.&nbsp; On Taiwan: To what extent do you think that you guys will be talking with the Quad and other allies in Asia about a concrete action plan on how to respond if China were to invade Taiwan?&nbsp; And do you think that that action plan could include both military response and an economic response?&nbsp; So can you share a little bit about how much he&#8217;ll talk about that with the &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It won&#8217;t be part of the formal agenda of the Quad.&nbsp; But, of course, significant security issues in the Indo-Pacific will come up, and all of the Quad members share an interest in peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait.&nbsp;</p>



<p>More broadly, the Biden administration is invested in working with allies and partners to send a clear message of deterrence and to support the basic policy of the Biden administration, which is a One China policy, the Three Joint Communiqués, and the Taiwan Relations Act, that we do not want to see unilateral changes to the status quo and we certainly don&#8217;t want to see military aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we do want that message coming not just from us, but from a range of allies and partners, both in the region and beyond.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working with allies and partners accordingly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, just to follow up on Taiwan, two questions.&nbsp; One, do you think it will appear in the Quad statement?&nbsp; And two, why is it not in the IPEF, given how important it is to global supply chains?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the Quad statement.&nbsp; So, when we do the backgrounder tomorrow laying down the main components of Quad outcomes, you can pose that question at that point.</p>



<p>And then, in terms of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, I don&#8217;t think we have yet actually announced who is in and who is not in.&nbsp; That will be unveiled hopefully in a very dramatic fashion.&nbsp; No, I’m just kidding.&nbsp; That will be unveiled tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the list finalized?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The list is finalized.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is Taiwan invited?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Taiwan won&#8217;t be part of the launch &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said will or will not?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It will not be part of the launch of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework.</p>



<p>Ambassador Tai met with her counterpart from Taiwan just a couple of days ago.&nbsp; You can find a readout of that conversation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we are looking to deepen our economic partnership with Taiwan, including on high-technology issues, including on semiconductors and supply chains.</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re pursuing that, in the first instance, on a bilateral basis while we work with a range of other countries through the framework.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one more follow-up on IPEF: China was out with some statements of Liu, the gentleman who is &#8212; deals with their policy on the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp; Said it&#8217;s basically closed &#8212; a closed club; there&#8217;s no reason to be doing that; things should be open and allow everybody in the Asia Pacific, including China, to join. &nbsp;What would you say in response to that?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a surprise to me that China has concerns about the number of countries, the diversity of countries who have expressed interest in and enthusiasm for IPEF.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, it&#8217;s natural that they&#8217;re going to try to find ways to raise questions.&nbsp; In this particular case, it&#8217;s just flatly untrue to call IPEF closed.&nbsp; It is by design and definition an open platform.&nbsp; And we do expect, in addition to the countries that join for the launch tomorrow, others will come along in the months and years ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That being said, the breadth of participation tomorrow was such that it will very much show that it&#8217;s anything but a closed club.&nbsp; It is a &#8212; it is a very wide-ranging membership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will South Korea be one of those countries?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, now you&#8217;re putting me in a funny spot, because I directly answered on Taiwan.&nbsp; If we start going down country by country, then I&#8217;ll be announcing the membership of the Quad just stan- &#8212; I mean, of the &#8212; of IPEF standing here right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I&#8217;m going to leave the announcement of the participation to whatever Karine and the press team want to &#8212; want to do with that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But anyway &#8212; yeah, so I&#8217;ll leave it there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is IPEF strictly just mostly economic policies at this point?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Or does it also include addressing maritime security, when you talk about countering China’s &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No, it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not a security arrangement.&nbsp; It is an economic arrangement focused around the further integration of Indo-Pacific economies, setting of standards and rules, particularly in new areas like the digital economy, and also trying to ensure that there are secure and resilient supply chains.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In that sense, maritime security is a relevant issue.&nbsp; But IPEF will not be negotiating out maritime security arrangements.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, a quick follow, too.&nbsp; So, the administration &#8212; you, as well &#8212; have often framed foreign policy strategy as a global battle between autocra- &#8212; democracies and autocracies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m wondering how you balance trying to engage economically with someone like Prime Minister Modi, who himself has been accused, under the guise of democracy, of human rights abuses and maligning Muslim minorities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>How do you balance accountability, approaching a bilateral like that, while also the desire to have an economic collaboration?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; President Biden has been clear from the beginning of this administration that we&#8217;ll speak out when we see any form of departure from or deviation from basic principles, fundamental freedoms, human rights, the values of democratic institutions, and the rule of law.&nbsp; That&#8217;s true for a range of countries.&nbsp; And, you know, we don&#8217;t single India out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we have found a way both to pursue practical cooperation with countries that are democratic and non-democratic, while at the same time being clear and consistent of where our values lie.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to push him on wheat exports?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to push Modi &#8212; is the President going to push Modi on wheat exports?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just say that food security will be a topic of conversation at the Quad.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about Russia?&nbsp; What about Russia and the invasion at large?&nbsp; What is he going to say to Modi about that?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, they&#8217;ve already had the opportunity to engage on that.&nbsp; And the President had an extended discussion with Prime Minister Modi when they did a virtual Quad Summit back in April.&nbsp; I think it was back in April, maybe even March.&nbsp; I think it was in March.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they also got to speak about it when they had a short video bilateral meeting at the top of the 2+2 when the Indian ministers came to Washington.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So it won&#8217;t be a new conversation.&nbsp; It will be a continuation of the conversation they&#8217;ve already had about how we see the picture in Ukraine and the impacts of Russia&#8217;s brutal invasion of Ukraine on a wider set of concerns in the world, including this food security concern.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, they&#8217;ll talk all of that through.&nbsp; And I will leave the specifics of it to what has been a set of private and constructive exchanges, and I expect that this will similarly be constructive and straightforward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, you&#8217;ve written a lot and talked a lot about there being a domestic angle to foreign policy.&nbsp; This weekend, you guys sent $40 billion to Ukraine.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to announce IPEF.&nbsp; How does this fit into the domestic angle?&nbsp; What&#8217;s your message to people who are struggling with inflation back home about why these things are important to them?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, also this weekend, the President announced and held up major &#8212; or lifted up major new investments in the United States, job-creating investments that will help power the industries of the future, help the communities where those investments take place, employ thousands of workers.&nbsp; And that was true when he went to Samsung on Friday night, and it was true with the announcement with Hyundai this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>So this trip has, in part, been about not just talking the talk when it comes to delivering for American workers and American families when the President is engaged in foreign policy, but actually walking the walk and backing it up with real numbers that begin with a “B.”</p>



<p>Now, when it comes to the war in Ukraine, the President has been very straightforward that if &#8212; that if we, the United States, do not work with likeminded allies to stand up to aggression, we will pay a greater cost tomorrow.&nbsp; So he actually believes that this investment in the Ukrainian people&#8217;s fight to defend their country and in support of our allies who live under the shadow of Russian aggression is a worthy investment in terms of the long-term contribution it makes to peace, security, and stability.<br><br>That will benefit American families and American workers.&nbsp; And we actually think that the American people understand that and, more than understand that, they very much support it.&nbsp; And we see that on a bipartisan basis with the overwhelming votes in both the House and the Senate for that funding.<br><br>With IPEF, IPEF is designed to put workers at the center &#8212; American workers.&nbsp; It&#8217;s designed to create the kinds of high-standard approaches to the digital economy, to the clean energy transition, to diverse and resilient supply chains, to open and transparent economic governance that will ultimately benefit American workers, American families.&nbsp; And you&#8217;ll hear that from the President tomorrow.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, Jake, I want to take a step back.&nbsp; The President, on this trip, has highlighted China&#8217;s economic slowdown.</p>



<p>In the past, building alliances like IPEF sometimes had been frustrated by China&#8217;s economic ascendancy and its rising power.&nbsp; What impact do you think the slowdown is having on the U.S.’s ability to build alliances in Asia?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think that, also taking a step back, that all of the traditional expectations about trajectories of countries that have been baked in over the course of several years in the press narrative and, you know, in the public conversation, including in this region, are due for review and reconsideration.&nbsp; And the fact that the United States will grow faster than China this year, for the first time since 1976, is a quite striking example of how countries in this region should be looking at the question of trends and trajectories.<br><br>And &#8212; and so, what the President said yesterday in his remarks at the press conference was something he said repeatedly over the course of his career, which is: It&#8217;s never a good bet to bet against the United States.&nbsp; And actually, we think a lot of countries in this region are recognizing that fact.<br><br>And when you see the breadth of participation in IPEF tomorrow, we believe that that will be strong evidence that countries do want to bet on the United States, do want to be part of an economic arrangement with the United States where we&#8217;re setting rules together, we&#8217;re building diverse and resilient supply chains together, that American innovation is at the heart and American infrastructure investment is at the heart of the economic strategy of a lot of these countries.<br><br>So our view is that this is not about a zero-sum game with China.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about forcing countries to choose.&nbsp; But it is about offering a value proposition that we think countries are taking extremely seriously.&nbsp; And we think that&#8217;ll be on display tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, on &#8212; I was going to say, on China tariffs, is the administration close to deciding whether you&#8217;re going to ease those tariffs that the last administration put in place?<br><br>And then on inflation, do you think that lowering or easing some of those tariffs really would help with the inflation problem by helping reduce some prices for U.S. consumers?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So the President has asked his international economic team to run the analysis on the relationship between tariffs and inflation, both top-line inflation and, just frankly, the way that families experience inflation, which is: When they go to the store to buy everyday products, are the prices higher?&nbsp; Would removing tariffs lead price &#8212; those &#8212; those prices on those goods to be lower?<br><br>So he&#8217;s asked for that analysis, and he has also asked for the perspectives of the range of voices in his economic team for how to proceed when it comes to the overall approach to China trade.&nbsp; And he will make a decision, you know, as soon as he feels that he&#8217;s got the inputs he needs to do so.<br><br>So I won&#8217;t put a timetable on it.&nbsp; But, you know, he&#8217;s considering his options when it comes to moving beyond the Trump trade strategy as we look to chart a new way forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Jake, how long &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he &#8212; sorry, just to follow up &#8212; has he gotten the analysis back from those teams yet, or is he still waiting on that?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; He has gotten analysis.&nbsp; He’s received detailed written work on this question, but he&#8217;s asked further questions and is looking for more input.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What can you tell us about the President&#8217;s briefing so far on monkeypox?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s your current understanding of whether there is a national stockpile of vaccine the President referred to?<br><br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So there &#8212; there is a vaccine that is relevant to treating monkeypox.&nbsp; We have vaccine available to be deployed for that purpose.</p>



<p>The &#8212; your question was about him being briefed?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; And how often and by whom.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, he has been briefed.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been out on the road, giving him updates based on the written inputs we are getting from our health and medical team and, you know, walking through with him what the &#8212; what the current state of play looks like and, as we learn about cases both in the United States and elsewhere, making sure that he&#8217;s tracking the picture.</p>



<p>So he&#8217;s being apprised on this on a very regular basis and getting inputs from the key members of his health team.</p>



<p>On Korea, you&#8217;ve talked about the risk of a ballistic missile test, or something like that, during the President&#8217;s visit.&nbsp; What does it say that, so far, such an incident hasn&#8217;t occurred?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s hard to speculate, honestly.&nbsp; And anytime people start speculating on what North Korea might or might not do, they tend to have their expectations confounded one way or another.</p>



<p>So, all we can do is control our policy and our approach.&nbsp; So, we were prepared for any contingency while we were in Korea, we&#8217;re prepared for any contingency while we&#8217;re in Japan, and we will stay very closely lashed up with the ROK and Japan on this.</p>



<p>And if North Korea acts, we’ll be prepared to respond.&nbsp; If North Korea doesn&#8217;t act, North Korea has the opportunity, as we&#8217;ve said repeatedly, to come to the table and start negotiating (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick follow-up on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;(Inaudible) still saying that they could do a test?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Oh, yes.&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So how are you going to measure the seriousness, the sincerity that the President talked about yesterday?&nbsp; How are you &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the intelligence still say that there could still be a test?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There could be a test.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So how are you going to measure the seriousness and sincerity?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The first step would be for North Korea to come forward and be prepared to actually engage in a dialogue.&nbsp; And thus far, they&#8217;ve not shown that they&#8217;re willing to do so.</p>



<p>From there, it &#8212; you can determine through the substance of those initial conversations whether you&#8217;re on a serious pathway or not.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re not even at step one yet.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why do you think they haven’t?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there preconditions for them getting vaccines from you?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I’m sorry?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are there preconditions for them getting vaccines from you?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why do you think they haven&#8217;t engaged while they were engaged so much with the Trump administration?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; They go through cycles where they respond and cycles where they don&#8217;t.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a cycle where they&#8217;re not.&nbsp; That&#8217;s been true across multiple administrations.&nbsp; And I just can&#8217;t speculate as to the rationale for them not (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s about this president versus that president?&nbsp; You think it&#8217;s just sort of a cycle that&#8217;s outside of that?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I mean, every previous president going back to Bush &#8212; so Bush, Obama, Trump &#8212; faced a nuclear test.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t yet.&nbsp; We anticipate we may.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Each one of them faced missile tests; each one of them worked on a diplomatic approach.&nbsp; And at various points during each of those presidencies, the North Koreans were forthcoming, and at various points during each of those presidencies, they weren&#8217;t.</p>



<p>And so you could ask the question: Why hasn&#8217;t there been a nuclear te- &#8212; why wasn&#8217;t there a nuclear test in the first year when there was for these other presidents?&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t think it has so much to do with who&#8217;s in the Oval Office as their own rhythms and cadences.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I just violated my own rule and started speculating about their motives &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; so I&#8217;ll stop.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine, can you talk about when the first shipments of weapons from this new package will arrive, or when you&#8217;re expecting them to go out?&nbsp; What&#8217;s going to be in there?&nbsp; Anything new?&nbsp; And do you have anything on these &#8212;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; When you’re saying “this new package,” do you mean the next &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The one he just signed yesterday.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Oh, the $40 billion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The 40.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So we expect him &#8212; so the way that it works is a portion of that $40 billion is drawdown authority.&nbsp; So Secretary of Defense and Secretary of State have to make a recommendation to the President of a drawdown package.&nbsp; They are actively working through that now.&nbsp; We expect it&#8217;ll come up to the President in the next couple of days for him to then be able to move out on.&nbsp; But we are on the receiving end of that based on the law and the process.&nbsp; So I would also go to the Pentagon and State to ask them, okay, you know, when &#8212; when are they going to push it forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what’s the latest, you guys believe, on what&#8217;s happening on the ground in Ukraine?&nbsp; And do you have anything on the high-ranking commanders being fired in the Russian forces?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; No.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then what about that allegation from the Russian Defense Ministry that they destroyed a large batch of Western weapons from the U.S. and &#8212; and the Europeans?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that true?&nbsp; Do we think that they really did destroy a lot of weapons?&nbsp; I saw Ukraine was confirming it, but anything you can share?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I have nothing to validate it and haven&#8217;t had the opportunity to consult with the Ukrainians on it.&nbsp; What I can say is that, you know, we have what we believe to be a diverse and resilient supply chain for these weapons into Ukraine.&nbsp; So even if there is a circumstance where the Russians are able to target and hit some shipment on the ground in Ukraine, that&#8217;s not going to fundamentally, from a strategic perspective, disrupt the military assistance we&#8217;re providing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What can you tell us about how John Kirby is coming over?&nbsp; How did that all come together?&nbsp; And can you describe what his role will be and how often we&#8217;ll see him in the briefing room?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, John Kirby, as you all know, is a very effective national security voice and advocate for the President&#8217;s policies.&nbsp; Actually, you know, I think a good partner to you all.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re excited to have him at the White House.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m particularly excited to have him at the NSC, because having a senior voice who can come do these gaggles instead of me will just be awesome.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m joking.&nbsp; I&#8217;m joking.</p>



<p>No, but &#8212; but otherwise, we&#8217;ll work out how it&#8217;s all going to play out in practice.&nbsp; The key thing is that John, at a moment when we&#8217;re dealing with a series of really critical national security issues, is just going to bring a great wealth of experience.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to be fun to work with for me; he’ll be fun to work with for the entire press team as well.</p>



<p>Q    There was reporting that he would basically fill the same role that Ben Rhodes did near the end of the Obama administration.  Is that sort of how you guys are seeing the role, or is it going to be different?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The thing about describing models like that &#8212; the “Ben Rhodes model” &#8212; they tend to be unique to an individual.&nbsp; And Ben, who is a very good friend of mine, is a unique individual and served in a unique capacity to President Obama.<br><br>John Kirby will have the &#8220;John Kirby model&#8221; of the role of Coordinator for Strategic Communications at the NSC.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll shape it based on his own, kind of, capabilities, the relationship he builds with the President and the rest of the team.&nbsp; And so I &#8212; I think the comparisons tend &#8212; tend not to illuminate.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We&#8217;re landing, guys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp; Thanks, guys.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, is there a reason why Biden didn’t sign the aid bill on camera &#8212; the Ukraine aid package?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I think he just wanted to sign it very quickly.&nbsp; And that was the &#8212; that was just the &#8212; we&#8217;ve always said: Once he got the bills, he would sign it quickly.&nbsp; And once the &#8212; once he was done with his event yesterday, he was able to do that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There&#8217;s been some questions about whether or not it had to be flown over.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your understanding of why it was flown over to sign?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, so that we can actually have the &#8211;the original copy for him to sign it.&nbsp; So, what happened was &#8212; and I think we&#8217;ve shared this with all of you &#8212; there was a &#8212; a staffer who was already scheduled to be here.&nbsp; And so, it came &#8212; it came with that staffer and was delivered to the President to sign.&nbsp; Yeah, there&#8217;s nothing &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s nothing really more to it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, now that the DPA has been invoked and the actions that you listed at the top for baby formula, can you say when parents in the U.S. who are trying to get baby formula will be able to readily, you know, get baby formula?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, you know, the President &#8212; you know, you&#8217;ve heard us say this: The President understands the struggle of moms and dads and parents and caregivers and making sure that &#8212; you know, making sure that we get &#8212; a child has, you know, a healthy &#8212; a healthy &#8212; a healthy way of eating.&nbsp; A healthy formula is &#8212; and safe &#8212; and safe formula &#8212; is our number one priority, which is why we&#8217;re &#8212; you know, which is why we have been very, very acutely aware of &#8212; of the process that we&#8217;ve initiated with the flyover and also the DPA.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have a timeline for you yet.&nbsp; We want to exp- &#8212; you know, make sure it goes very quickly, because it&#8217;s so critical.&nbsp; And we know what &#8212; what families are going through.&nbsp; I &#8212; but I don&#8217;t have an exact timeline.&nbsp; Clear- &#8212; clearly, we want this to happen as fast as possible, as quickly as possible.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a reason, also, that the administration isn&#8217;t seeking a stay in the Title 42 case?&nbsp; I know that you&#8217;re appealing.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We’re appealing.&nbsp; I mean, I don&#8217;t have much more than &#8212; than what the DOJ is doing is appealing Title 42.<br><br>You know, we continue to believe Title 42 is a health authority.&nbsp; It is an authority that CDC is &#8212; has that was given to them by Congress.&nbsp; And so that is kind of what we also agree with, which is the authority that Congress gave them.<br><br>Yep.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let’s let you get to your seat.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; Thanks a lot.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>5:02 P.M. JST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Yoon Suk Yeol of the Republic of Korea at the Air Operations Center’s Combat Operations Floor on Osan Air&#160;Base</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/22/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-yoon-suk-yeol-of-the-republic-of-korea-at-the-air-operations-centers-combat-operations-floor-on-osan-air-base/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53838</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Osan Air BasePyeongtaek, Republic of Korea 1:52 P.M. KST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; First of all, I want to say thank you.&#160; And I wish you’d work on your biceps a little bit.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And you too, pal.&#160; It’s about as big as my thighs.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And I was a pretty good athlete.&#160; And I &#8212; I’m&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Osan Air Base<br>Pyeongtaek, Republic of Korea</p>



<p>1:52 P.M. KST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; First of all, I want to say thank you.&nbsp; And I wish you’d work on your biceps a little bit.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And you too, pal.&nbsp; It’s about as big as my thighs.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I was a pretty good athlete.&nbsp; And I &#8212; I’m worried about you, Captain.&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I &#8212; first of all, it’s great to be here with the President.&nbsp; We had a &#8212; we’ve had great meetings thus far.&nbsp; We had a great state dinner last night as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and I want to say what I’m sure the President thinks as well: Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you to all of you &#8212; every one of you.&nbsp; You are &#8212; you are the frontline of everything we’re concerned about.&nbsp; You represent the commitment of our two countries made to each other and the strength of the U.S.-ROK alliance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And our alliance &#8212; our alliance was formed through shared sacrifice of the Korean War.&nbsp; And now, seven decades later, thanks to you, the Republic of Korea is a strong, thriving, and innovating democracy.&nbsp; And our alliance grows stronger every single day because of you all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And today, Korean and American forces stand sentinel still to &#8212; the integration and coordination between our forces is essential as it was yesterday and 10 years ago and 20 years ago and 40 years ago, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact is that deterring threats and underwriting stability is as vital today for not only the Peninsula but for the world &#8212; for the world.&nbsp; That’s what the President and I spent the last couple of days talking about.&nbsp; It’s not just the Korean Peninsula, it’s the world.&nbsp; And so &#8212;</p>



<p>Should I stop and have that translated?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>(A translation is provided.)</p>



<p>The connections that you form serving together &#8212; not just as fellow service members, but as friends &#8212; helps knit our two nations together.</p>



<p>To all the American troops that are here and your families: Thank you for what you do to defend our country and our ally, and for representing our country so very well.</p>



<p>And to the Korean forces: Thank you as well for your service, for having our backs just as we have yours.&nbsp; I won’t attempt the Korean, but we &#8212; we &#8212; we’re &#8212; we go together, and we go together well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve been impressed.&nbsp; Thank you so very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, we go together.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>PRESIDENT YOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; It is an honor and pleasure to visit Osan Air Base with President Biden today.&nbsp; In particular, as the President of the Republic of Korea, I am deeply grateful to all U.S. airmen, airwomen, and also Korean Air Force soldiers for their service and devotion to defend the peace and prosperity on the Korean Peninsula, and also to your families who are waiting for you across the Pacific Ocean.</p>



<p>I believe that friendship between the U.S. soldiers and officers and also with the Korean soldiers and officer is the real strength and power of ROK-U.S. alliance.<br><br>Since the outbreak of the Korean War, President Truman ordered to deploy U.S. forces to Korea just five days after the war.&nbsp; And the place near Osan Air Base was the very first place to be deployed, which the Smith Task Force was deployed and engaged for the first time with the DPRK forces at the Battle of Osan.<br><br>After the Korean War, the U.S. forces started to run air base in Osan.&nbsp; And also, soon after, Korea also made its command.<br><br>I believe that KAOC is the center &#8212; critical center to together respond to the DPRK’s increasing nuclear and missile threat, and also a symbol of the robust ROK-U.S. alliance.<br><br>I believe that I would like to show my deepest respect and extend my gratitude to all of you for your service protecting world peace and freedom and for your patriotism.<br><br>Thank you very much.</p>



<p>And I would like to note, with appreciation, that KAOC as the center of Korea&#8217;s three-pillar system to defend the North Korean missile threat.&nbsp; And I would like to mention the importance of your role and responsibility to defend the security of this Peninsula.<br><br>And today, I&#8217;m really &#8212; I am delighted to be here with President Biden.&nbsp; And I really feel assured, seeing you today, as the center of our defense.&nbsp; I would like to once again extend my deepest gratitude to you.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>2:10 P.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Air Force One Departure &#124; Pyeongtaek, Republic of&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/22/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-pyeongtaek-republic-of-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 09:39:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Osan Air BasePyeongtaek, Republic of Korea 3:26 P.M. KST Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, quick question: What have your health advisors told you your level of concern should be about monkeypox and the cases that are in the United States and around the world? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, they haven’t told me the level of exposure yet, but&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Osan Air Base<br>Pyeongtaek, Republic of Korea</p>



<p>3:26 P.M. KST</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, quick question: What have your health advisors told you your level of concern should be about monkeypox and the cases that are in the United States and around the world?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, they haven’t told me the level of exposure yet, but it is something that everybody should be concerned about.&nbsp; We’re working on it hard to figure out what we do and what vaccine, if any, may be available for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it is a concern in the sense that if it were to spread, it’s consequential.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all they have told me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any message for the new Australian leader &#8212; the new prime minister that you&#8217;ll be visiting with in Tokyo?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking forward to seeing him, and the Quad matters.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you spoken to him yet?&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’ve called him and congratulated him, but that’s it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>3:27 P.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Hyundai&#8217;s Investments in Savannah,&#160;Georgia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/22/remarks-by-president-biden-on-hyundais-investments-in-savannah-georgia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2022 09:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53831</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Grand Hyatt SeoulSeoul, Republic of Korea 11:22 A.M. KST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Thank you, Mr. Chairman. CHAIRMAN CHUNG:&#160; Thank you. PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, thank you, Mr. Chairman.&#160; It&#8217;s &#8212; I think the last time we were together, we were at a university.&#160; Was it two thousand and &#8212; CHAIRMAN CHUNG:&#160; Yeah, Yonsei University.&#160; 2013. PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Grand Hyatt Seoul<br>Seoul, Republic of Korea</p>



<p>11:22 A.M. KST</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. Chairman.</p>



<p>CHAIRMAN CHUNG:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Mr. Chairman.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; I think the last time we were together, we were at a university.&nbsp; Was it two thousand and &#8212;</p>



<p>CHAIRMAN CHUNG:&nbsp; Yeah, Yonsei University.&nbsp; 2013.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; 2013.&nbsp; He showed me a picture.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t have a lot more hair then either.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>It&#8217;s great to be here to announce the more than $10 billion in new investment in American manufacturing.&nbsp; This new commitment of $5 billion for advanced automotive technology and $5.5 billion investment to open a new factory near Savannah, Georgia, is going to create more than 8,000 new American jobs.</p>



<p>The plan is to break ground as soon as January of 2023.&nbsp; And the new facility should be rolling out the latest electric vehicles and batteries to power them by 2025.</p>



<p>And the workers in Georgia who will build these pla- &#8212; these plants and manufacture this new electric battery technology, it means economic opportunity for an awful lot of Americans.</p>



<p>And I want to commend my friends and the two senators in Georgia, Rafael Warnock and Jon Ossoff, for how they&#8217;ve been fighting for Georgia to be the magnet for this clean energy investment.</p>



<p>And these investments are part of a trend my administration &#8212; in my administration.&nbsp; Manufacturing jobs are coming back to America.</p>



<p>Even before these new investments, my administration, since coming to office, created 545,000 new manufacturing jobs since we took office.</p>



<p>And thanks to Hyundai, we are being part of this transformative automobile sector and accelerating us on the road where we’re going to be <s>handling </s>[heading] to &#8212; the United States &#8212; an all-electric future.  And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re shooting for.</p>



<p>Our administration is setting ambitious standards to cut pollution in cars and trucks and boost &#8212; boost fuel economy standards for those continuing to operate on gasoline.</p>



<p>And last year, standing together with the CEOs of major American manufacturers, along with the CEO and the head of the United Auto Workers, I signed an executive order setting a goal of having 50 percent of all new vehicles sold by the year 2030 be electric.&nbsp; And it’s an ambitious target, I know, but I believe we can meet it.</p>



<p>But we’re all committed to making it happen &#8212; auto companies, American UAW, and the &#8212; and the federal government as well &#8212; because all understand the same basic thing: Electric vehicles are good for our climate goals, but they’re also good for jobs, and they’re good for business.</p>



<p>Hyundai and any company investing in the United States would benefit greatly from entering into partnerships with some of the most highly skilled, dedicated, and engaged workers in the world, anywhere you can find.&nbsp; And that is American union members.</p>



<p>And again, every venture to manufacture electric vehicles and electric vehicle batteries would be made stronger by a collective bargaining relationship with our unions.</p>



<p>Investing aggressively in electric vehicles and battery production now &#8212; now, not tomorrow &#8212; now &#8212; is also important for strengthening our long-term economic security and accelerating progress toward a clean-energy future.</p>



<p>You know, because of Putin’s war, we’ve been sort of knocked off slightly, a little bit, because of the impact of the &#8212; impact of Russian oil on Europe.<br><br>But batteries &#8212; batteries that will be made at this new facility in Georgia are going to power cars without one drop of gasoline and increase security of our battery supply chains as well.</p>



<p>That’s going to serve &#8212; save families money at the pump because they can skip the pump altogether.  And instead, families will be able to stop at one of 500,000 new electric vehicle stations &#8212; part of the network we’re going to be building across America with the $7.5 billion in funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law. </p>



<p>And the Chairman told me walking out here that they’re also going to be investing in battery techno- &#8212; in charging stations as well.</p>



<p>My administration &#8212; and, by the way, when you invest in a charging station along a highway, it’s a little bit like years and years ago, when we were starting to build automobiles in America and you’re investing in a gas station.&nbsp; Other things pop up around it.&nbsp; It has &#8212; it has an effect of generating economic growth just by putting in the station.&nbsp; And I think you’re going to see that as well in the United States.</p>



<p>My administration is supercharging efforts to lead the electric future.</p>



<p>We’re also making historic investments in battery &#8212; battery manufacturing, clean transit, and light rail.</p>



<p>For example, we’re going to be investing $5 billion to transform our fleet of nearly 500,000 polluting, diesel school buses into clean, all-electric vehicles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And my climate and jobs agenda is making the United States a premier destination for savvy private firms looking to invest in the electric vehicle future.</p>



<p>In fact, today’s welcome announcement by Hyundai comes on top of an additional $100 billion of investments in the last year from companies in America &#8212; in American manufacturing to build electric vehicles and electric batteries.</p>



<p>And so, folks, the administration is going to stay laser-focused on innovation and batteries and EVs, building out our infrastructure and increasing the market demand.</p>



<p>So, Chairman Chung, thank you again for choosing the United States.&nbsp; We will not let you down.</p>



<p>And over these last two days, I’ve been focusing all my &#8212; all the ways in which the Republic of Korea and the United States can work closely together to shape the direction of our world for the better.</p>



<p>This deal is another prime example of how that partnership &#8212; and innovation, expertise, and values that drive both the Korean and American people &#8212; are delivering for the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I thank you all for being part of this very integral clean, electric vehicle future, not only here but in my country, and for deepening the ties between our two great democracies.</p>



<p>Thank you all so very much.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, are you concerned about a North Korean missile test while you’re here in Asia?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We are prepared for anything North Korea does.&nbsp; We’ve had &#8212; we’ve thought through how we would respond to whatever they do.&nbsp; And so, I am not concerned, if that’s what you’re suggesting.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a message for Kim Jong Un while you&#8217;re here?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; “Hello.”&nbsp; Period.</p>



<p>Thank you.<br><br>11:29 A.M. KST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
