<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 20:32:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Welcoming the 2020 and 2021 Stanley Cup Champions Tampa Bay&#160;Lightning</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/25/remarks-by-president-biden-welcoming-the-2020-and-2021-stanley-cup-champions-tampa-bay-lightning/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 20:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51756</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Lawn 2:16 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Clapping for you guys.&#160; (Removes sunglasses.)&#160; I’m going to put them back on.&#160; (Puts sunglasses back on.)&#160; (Laughs.)&#160;&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Welcome.&#160; Welcome to the White House.&#160; I see a couple of future All-Americans right there in the front row.&#160;&#160; You know, if there’s a little extra excitement&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Lawn</p>



<p>2:16 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Clapping for you guys.&nbsp; (Removes sunglasses.)&nbsp; I’m going to put them back on.&nbsp; (Puts sunglasses back on.)&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Welcome.&nbsp; Welcome to the White House.&nbsp; I see a couple of future All-Americans right there in the front row.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, if there’s a little extra excitement around the White House today, it’s probably because the Cup is in the building.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’re here today to congratulate and welcome to the White House the Stanley Cup Champion, Tampa Bay Lightning.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>To the players and coaches; and to the owner, Jeff; everyone involved in this team: It’s an honor to have you all here.&nbsp; And it’s great to see Congresswoman Castor.&nbsp; There she is.&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; She’s holding &#8212; you think I didn’t see you holding up that sign?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You know, and Mayor Jane Castor.&nbsp; And they’re not related.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I tell you.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anyway, I want to thank Commissioner Gary Bettman and &#8212; for being here as well.</p>



<p>And at the risk of stating the obvious here, it’s a pretty good time to be a sports fan in Tampa.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know what the hell you have in the water down there &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but, over the last &#8212; please, have a seat.&nbsp; Don’t stand because of me.&nbsp; I am so sorry.&nbsp; See, the congresswoman knew to sit down immediately.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, the Buccaneers won the Super Bowl, the Rays won the pennant, and these guys behind me became back-to-back Stanley Cup Champions.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And they may be here next year.&nbsp; Who knows?</p>



<p>Well, I don’t know &#8212; I don&#8217;t know why they keep moving everything so quickly here, but with your &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; you all saw that, right?&nbsp;</p>



<p>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; We can’t keep up either.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; They’re seeing if I’m on my toes (inaudible).&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But I really did worry about whether you got something in the water down there.&nbsp; It’s &#8212; with your victory last season, this team joined rare company.&nbsp; One of only eight teams over the last century to win two Stanley Cups in a row.&nbsp; In the last century.&nbsp; And I know that those two championships were very different.</p>



<p>In 2020, your fans watched you win from thousands of miles away as you competed in “The Bubble” in Edmonton due to the pandemic.</p>



<p>But this past season, you got to deliver something truly special: hosting the Cup in your &#8212; on your home ice in front of the Tampa faithful.</p>



<p>And don’t underestimate what that feeling meant to so many fans, especially kids, and lifelong memories you created for countless families.</p>



<p>Folks, the victory capped off an incredible run by one of the most well-rounded teams in recent memory, with outstanding players at every level, led by your captain, the Lightning stalwart of 14 seasons.&nbsp; Steve, 14 seasons?<br><br>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Yep.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You’re getting old, man.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>I &#8212; I got to get some advice from Steve about this.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Of course &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; you accomplished this victory not as an individual, but as a team &#8212; pulling together when it mattered most.&nbsp; And now the names of every single one of you will be engraved on the Stanley Cup for all time.&nbsp; And that is a big deal where I come from.</p>



<p>And this team didn’t just step up on the ice, you stepped up in the community as well.</p>



<p>You know, through your Lightning Community Hero program, you’ve delivered more than $25 million in critical causes to the reg- &#8212; for critical causes in the region.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Provided food and clothing for the families in need.&nbsp; Supported early education for youth mentorship programs.&nbsp; Lifting up local non-profits.&nbsp; Donating to veterans’ hospitals, community colleges, and other vital institutions all across Western Florida, along with hundreds of other initiatives you engaged in.</p>



<p>And last year, your home arena also became a lifeline for families in Tampa.<br><br><a>The First Lady &#8212; and I am Jill’s husband &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; came down with Dr. Fauci during the Stanley Cup semifinals to encourage hockey fans to get vaccinated at your arena through a program called &#8212; called “Shots on Ice,” helping save lives, helping bring us back to our lives and loved ones, and helping the country and our &#8212; and our economy go from being on the mend to on the move.</a></p>



<p>Look, I’m not saying that the First Lady being there at your arena during the playoffs is why you won &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but just saying that she was there during the election season as well.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She seems to show up when people win.&nbsp; And just something to think about.</p>



<p>So thank you all for the great work you&#8217;re doing in the community.&nbsp; And congratulations again for all the great work you&#8217;ve done on the ice.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to wish you good luck in the upcoming playoffs.&nbsp; Who knows, as I said, you may be here next year if you&#8217;re willing to come back.&nbsp; But &#8212; but for now, let&#8217;s bring up Jeff to say a few words.</p>



<p>Jeff, the podium is yours.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>There you are.&nbsp; I got to find my blue dot.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. VINIK:&nbsp; Yeah, you do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s right over here.&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>MR. VINIK:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. &#8212; thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; Now, we don&#8217;t get to hear &#8212; to be here very often, so you can stand up for me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I told you I’d use one joke.&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>So, Mr. President, on behalf of myself, the Tampa Bay Lightning players, coaches, staff, and all at Bolts Natsi- &#8212; Nation watching across &#8212; in Tampa, across North America, and around the world, we would like to thank you for hosting us today.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a tremendous honor to be here &#8212; tremendous &#8212; at the White House celebrating our back-to-back Stanley Cups.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s been a long time coming for the lighthouse &#8212; the “lighthouse” &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; the Lightning after three championships.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s how I felt.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. VINIK:&nbsp; And, by the way, our playoffs start in a week.&nbsp; The First Lady is welcome back.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve already told us she’s good luck.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know about you, yet, but we’re happy to have her come back.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>So after the three championships, the first one of which was about 18 years ago, we&#8217;re extremely excited to finally make our first appearance here on Pennsylvania Avenue after missing out in previous years due to a bunch of different circumstances.</p>



<p>The Lightning&#8217;s 2020 Stanley Cup championship was one defined by the extraordinary time of sacrifice &#8212; on and off the ice &#8212; with many of these gentlemen behind me spending 65 days isolated in a bubble, away from their family and friends, in order to capture the ultimate prize.&nbsp; It was a true test of both physical and mental endurance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This last season, we&#8217;re proud to say we returned to home ice.&nbsp; And after starting the season with no fans, we capped it off with our second consecutive Stanley Cup championship in front of a roaring capacity crowd at AMALIE Arena.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>As we head back in the playoffs &#8212; exactly one week from now, we expect to start &#8212; we know exactly why the Stanley Cup is the hardest trophy to win in sports.&nbsp; Hopefully, we&#8217;ll get &#8212; hopefully, we&#8217;ll be back here again.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already been invited.&nbsp; So, hopefully, we&#8217;ll be back here next season.&nbsp; Maybe we can get &#8212; well, I did write down here we could get you down to Tampa.&nbsp; Oh, so the First Lady is invited for the games. You&#8217;re invited, though.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MR. VINIK:&nbsp; You&#8217;re invited, Mr. President, for one of &#8212; for one of our one-of-a-kind championship boat parades, and they are fun.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp; They&#8217;re fun to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can come for the games, too.&nbsp; You&#8217;re welcome.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know what?&nbsp; We have a no talking rule in our suite. &nbsp;When the puck is in play, nobody is allowed to talk.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll make an exception for you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>In closing, thank you for your hospitality and the honor of coming here to be part of this storied tradition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s now my pleasure to introduce our defenseman &#8212; our defenseman and two-time Stanley Cup champion, a native of St. Paul, Minnesota, Alternate Captain Ryan McDonagh.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MCDONAGH:&nbsp; Thanks, Mr. Vinik.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. President, on behalf of all the players, coaches, and staff from the Tampa Bay Lightning, we&#8217;d like to extend a huge thank you for the invitation and hospitality here today.</p>



<p>This is a huge honor to come here to the White House.&nbsp; Like it&#8217;s been talked about, it&#8217;s been an incredible two years for everybody down there in Tampa Bay.&nbsp; I&#8217;m so proud to be standing up here beside all these guys and everything we&#8217;ve accomplished, and also to the guys that couldn&#8217;t make it here today, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s been a historic run.&nbsp; Like it&#8217;s been said, it&#8217;s only been done twice in this century: back-to-back Stanley Cup champions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Both came in very different fashions.&nbsp; The first one coming in a bubble in Canada for 65 days, isolated away from our family, playing in arenas with no fans, and having to deal with strict restrictions and daily COVID testing.&nbsp; But our group embraced it.&nbsp; We embraced the challenge and, boy, did it pay off.</p>



<p>For almost all of us, it was the first time we got to hoist the Stanley Cup &#8212; an unbelievable feeling that no one can take away from us.</p>



<p>The second championship run also had its challenges.&nbsp; We still had to abide by some restrictions while traveling from city to city playing and also started the year with no fans in the buildings.</p>



<p><a></a><a></a><a></a>But at the very end, we found ourselves at Amalie Arena with a chance to win the Stanley Cup not only in front of family friends, but in front of a packed arena filled with Bolts Nation fans &#8212; an unbelievable memory that&#8217;s something you can only dream about as a young kid learning and playing the sport of hockey.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like Mr. Vinik said, in a week from now, we’ll get to start another journey and, hopefully, chase down a third consecutive Stanley Cup.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although we know the difficulties ahead of us, we feel we have a great group intact that&#8217;s going to battle hard for one another and leave it all on the ice.&nbsp; The quest for a third cup is not out of reach.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll do whatever we can, Bolts Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like I said, Mr. President, it&#8217;s an honor to be here.&nbsp; As an American and someone who hails from St. Paul, Minnesota, I never thought I&#8217;d be standing here at the White House next to you.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s been a surreal experience and something I think all of us will remember for a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you for having us.&nbsp; And appreciate it again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thanks, pal.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. MCDONAGH:&nbsp; I think Victor and Steven have some gifts for you now.&nbsp; We all like gifts, right?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; I got to report every one.&nbsp; But &#8212; (laughter).</p>



<p>(The President is presented with a jersey and hockey stick.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.</p>



<p>MR. HEDMAN:&nbsp; Now you’ve got this nice stick.</p>



<p>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Walk over to the Cup a little bit so you can &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Walk over to the Cup a little bit.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Yeah, so you can &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Yeah, let&#8217;s to do that.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. HEDMAN:&nbsp; Here you go.&nbsp; The stick.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. STAMKOS:&nbsp; Want to hold the stick?&nbsp; It’s heavy.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Whoa.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No wonder you guys win. (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, thank you very, very much.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:29 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-64/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 20:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51754</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: John Z. Lee, of Illinois, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Seventh Circuit, vice Diane P. Wood, retiring. Salvador Mendoza, Jr., of Washington, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Ninth Circuit, vice M. Margaret McKeown, retiring. Stephen Henley Locher, of Iowa, to be United States District&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>John Z. Lee, of Illinois, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Seventh Circuit, vice Diane P. Wood, retiring.</p>



<p>Salvador Mendoza, Jr., of Washington, to be United States Circuit Judge for the Ninth Circuit, vice M. Margaret McKeown, retiring.</p>



<p>Stephen Henley Locher, of Iowa, to be United States District Judge for the Southern District of Iowa, vice John Alfred Jarvey, retired.</p>



<p>Nancy L. Maldonado, of Illinois, to be United States District Judge for the Northern District of Illinois, vice Matthew F. Kennelly, retired.</p>



<p>Gregory Brian Williams, of Delaware, to be United States District Judge for the District of Delaware, vice Leonard Philip Stark, elevated.</p>



<p>Rachelle L. Crowe, of Illinois, to be United States Attorney for the Southern District of Illinois for the term of four years, vice Stephen R. Wigginton, resigned.</p>



<p>Joshua D. Hurwit, of Idaho, to be United States Attorney for the District of Idaho for the term of four years, vice Bart M. Davis, resigned.</p>



<p>Gerard M. Karam, of Pennsylvania, to be United States Attorney for the Middle District of Pennsylvania for the term of four years, vice David J. Freed, resigned.</p>



<p>Jacqueline C. Romero, of Pennsylvania, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania for the term of four years, vice William M. McSwain, resigned.</p>



<p>Phillip A. Talbert, of California, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of California for the term of four years, vice McGregor W. Scott, resigned.</p>



<p>Jaime Areizaga-Soto, of Virginia, to be Chairman of the Board of Veterans&#8217; Appeals for a term of six years, vice Cheryl L. Mason, resigning.</p>



<p>Carol Spahn, of Maryland, to be Director of the Peace Corps, vice Josephine Olsen.</p>



<p>Steven M. Dettelbach, of Ohio, to be Director, Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, vice B. Todd Jones, resigned.</p>



<p>Cynthia Dyer, of Virginia, to be Director of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking, with the rank of Ambassador at Large, vice John Cotton Richmond.</p>



<p>Rachna Sachdeva Korhonen, of New Jersey, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Mali.</p>



<p>Richard Lee Buangan, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Mongolia.</p>



<p>Michael Alan Ratney, of Massachusetts, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>Michael C. Gonzales, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Zambia.</p>



<p>Geoffrey R. Pyatt, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Energy Resources), vice Francis R. Fannon.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>Susan Harthill, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission for a term expiring April 27, 2027, vice James J. Sullivan, Jr., term expired, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>



<p>Amanda Howe, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, vice Craig Hooks, resigned, which was sent to the Senate on June 15, 2021.</p>



<p>James Arthur Jemison II, of Michigan, to be an Assistant Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, vice Robert Hunter Kurtz, which was sent to the Senate on January 4, 2022.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Air Force One&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/25/remarks-by-president-biden-after-air-force-one-arrival-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51739</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George’s County, Maryland Q&#160;&#160;&#160; (Inaudible) the French election, sir? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, we feel good about the French election, number one.&#160; Number two, I tried to talk to him last night.&#160; We spoke with his staff, but he was at the Eiffel Tower having a good time.&#160; So I’m going to be&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews<br>Prince George’s County, Maryland</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) the French election, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, we feel good about the French election, number one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Number two, I tried to talk to him last night.&nbsp; We spoke with his staff, but he was at the Eiffel Tower having a good time.&nbsp; So I’m going to be talking to him today.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And did you speak with Secretary Blinken or Secretary Aus- &#8212; Austin after their trip to Ukraine?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We’re going to be doing that now.&nbsp; I haven’t spoke &#8212; I’ve spoken to them before and on the way, but I haven’t to them (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what did you think of their trip?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How do you think it went, sir?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It went good.</p>



<p>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Macron of&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-macron-of-france-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 17:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France to congratulate him on his re-election.  He underscored the close and enduring relations between the United States and France, our oldest ally, based on shared democratic values, economic ties, and security cooperation. President Biden conveyed his readiness to continue working closely with President Macron on our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France to congratulate him on his re-election.  He underscored the close and enduring relations between the United States and France, our oldest ally, based on shared democratic values, economic ties, and security cooperation. President Biden conveyed his readiness to continue working closely with President Macron on our shared global priorities. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with His Majesty King Abdullah II of&#160;Jordan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-his-majesty-king-abdullah-ii-of-jordan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 17:35:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51727</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden spoke today with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan to consult on a range of regional and global issues.  The two leaders discussed in detail recent efforts to stem violence in Israel and the West Bank, including at the Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount complex in Jerusalem.  The President welcomed recent steps&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden spoke today with His Majesty King Abdullah II of Jordan to consult on a range of regional and global issues.  The two leaders discussed in detail recent efforts to stem violence in Israel and the West Bank, including at the Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount complex in Jerusalem.  The President welcomed recent steps to reduce tensions and expressed his hope that the final week of Ramadan will pass peacefully.  He underscored the need to preserve the historic status quo at the Haram al-Sharif/Temple Mount, and recognized the Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan’s role as the custodian of Muslim holy places in Jerusalem.  The King briefed the President on his recent engagements in the region and the President emphasized the U.S. commitment to the Middle East and regional stability.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on World Malaria&#160;Day</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-world-malaria-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 17:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51724</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[No one should die from a mosquito bite. Seventy years ago, the United States eliminated malaria in our country. And, thanks to strong bipartisan leadership in Congress, and the enormous generosity of the American people, we lead the fight to end malaria worldwide. As the largest donor in the battle to end malaria, the United&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>No one should die from a mosquito bite. Seventy years ago, the United States eliminated malaria in our country. And, thanks to strong bipartisan leadership in Congress, and the enormous generosity of the American people, we lead the fight to end malaria worldwide.</p>



<p>As the largest donor in the battle to end malaria, the United States has helped save more than 10.6 million lives and prevent 1.7 billion malaria infections in partner countries around the world. Together with our partners, we have developed the knowledge and toolset – including the promising new malaria vaccine &#8211; to end malaria illness and death in our lifetime. We have worked together to bolster health systems and invest in health workers. We will continue to invest in research and expand our partnerships with regional and multilateral institutions to ensure science is driving our response.</p>



<p>Tragically, a child still dies every two minutes from malaria. We must step up and do more to finish this fight. We risk losing valuable progress as the disease develops resistance to drugs and mosquitoes develop resistance to insecticides. And, as climate change causes warmer, wetter, and more extreme weather, malaria-carrying mosquitoes will be able to breed and spread their disease more easily. That’s why I am proud to host the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria’s Replenishment Conference later this year. Working with allies and partners around the world, we can accelerate the fight against malaria and advance progress towards the Sustainable Development Agenda.</p>



<p>My Administration is committed to making the vision of a malaria-free future a reality. Together, we can build a safer, more prosperous, and more equitable world for everyone.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Domestic Counter-Unmanned Aircraft Systems National Action&#160;Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/fact-sheet-the-domestic-counter-unmanned-aircraft-systems-national-action-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51705</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the last decade, unmanned aircraft systems (UAS or “drones”) have become a regular feature of American life. We use them for recreation, for research, and for commerce. But the proliferation of this new technology has also introduced new risks to public safety, privacy, and homeland security.&#160; Malicious actors have increasingly used UAS domestically to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Over the last decade, unmanned aircraft systems (UAS or “drones”) have become a regular feature of American life. We use them for recreation, for research, and for commerce. But the proliferation of this new technology has also introduced new risks to public safety, privacy, and homeland security.&nbsp; Malicious actors have increasingly used UAS domestically to commit crimes, conduct illegal surveillance and industrial espionage, and thwart law enforcement efforts at the local, state and Federal level.<br><br>Today, the Biden Administration is releasing the first whole-of-government plan to address UAS threats in the Homeland. Through the <strong>Domestic Counter-Unmanned Aircraft Systems National Action Plan</strong>, the Administration is working to expand <em>where</em> we can protect against nefarious UAS activity, <em>who</em> is authorized to take action, and <em>how </em>it can be accomplished lawfully. The Plan seeks to achieve this legitimate expansion while safeguarding the airspace, communications spectrums, individual privacy, civil liberties and civil rights. To achieve this balance, the Administration is calling on Congress to adopt legislation to close critical gaps in existing law and policy that currently impede government and law enforcement from protecting the American people and our vital security interests.<br><br>UAS serve many beneficial commercial and recreational purposes.&nbsp; As has been the case with many technological advances, they can also be exploited for pernicious purposes.&nbsp; To protect our Homeland and prevent their growing use from threatening the safety and security of our people, our communities, and our institutions, this Counter-UAS National Action Plan will set new ground rules for the expanding uses of UAS and improve our defenses against the exploitation of UAS for inappropriate or dangerous purposes.<br><br><strong><em>Recommendations</em></strong><br>The Plan provides eight key recommendations for action:</p>



<ol><li>Work with Congress to enact a new legislative proposal to expand the set of tools and actors who can protect against UAS by reauthorizing and expanding existing counter‑UAS authorities for the Departments of Homeland Security, Justice, Defense, State, as well as the Central Intelligence Agency and NASA in limited situations. The proposal also seeks to expand UAS detection authorities for state, local, territorial and Tribal (SLTT) law enforcement agencies and critical infrastructure owners and operators.  The proposal would also create a Federally-sponsored pilot program for selected SLTT law enforcement agency participants to perform UAS mitigation activities and permit critical infrastructure owners and operators to purchase authorized equipment to be used by appropriate Federal or SLTT law enforcement agencies to protect their facilities;<br></li><li>Establish a list of U.S. Government authorized detection equipment, approved by Federal security and regulatory agencies, to guide authorized entities in purchasing UAS detection systems in order to avoid the risks of inadvertent disruption to airspace or the communications spectrum; <br></li><li>Establish oversight and enablement mechanisms to support critical infrastructure owners and operators in purchasing counter-UAS equipment for use by authorized Federal entities or SLTT law enforcement agencies;<br></li><li>Establish a National Counter-UAS Training Center to increase training accessibility and promote interagency cross-training and collaboration;<br></li><li>Create a Federal UAS incident tracking database as a government-wide repository for departments and agencies to have a better understanding of the overall domestic threat;<br></li><li>Establish a mechanism to coordinate research, development, testing, and evaluation on UAS detection and mitigation technology across the Federal government;<br></li><li>Work with Congress to enact a comprehensive criminal statute that sets clear standards for legal and illegal uses, closes loopholes in existing Federal law, and establishes adequate penalties to deter the most serious UAS-related crimes; and <br></li><li>Enhance cooperation with the international community on counter‑UAS technologies, as well as the systems designed to defeat them.<br><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/eo13985-vision-for-equitable-data.pdf"></a></li></ol>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Keeping our Promise to Veterans Suffering from Toxic Environmental&#160;Exposures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-keeping-our-promise-to-veterans-suffering-from-toxic-environmental-exposures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51690</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America’s veterans are the best of us. I’ve always believed that we have a sacred obligation to equip all those we send into harm’s way and to care for them and their families when they come home. That’s especially true for veterans suffering the visible and invisible wounds of war, whether they were injured in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America’s veterans are the best of us. I’ve always believed that we have a sacred obligation to equip all those we send into harm’s way and to care for them and their families when they come home. That’s especially true for veterans suffering the visible and invisible wounds of war, whether they were injured in combat or breathed in toxic smoke from burn pits on base. We can and must do more to address the harms that come from hazardous exposures, which have gone unaddressed for far too long.</p>



<p>We learned a horrible lesson after Vietnam, when the harmful effects of exposure to Agent Orange sometimes took years to manifest, and too many veterans were left unable to access the care they needed. I refuse to repeat that mistake when it comes to the veterans of our wars in Iraq and Afghanistan.</p>



<p>In my State of the Union address, I announced that we would propose expanding disability and health benefits to veterans suffering from nine rare respiratory cancers. Today, the Department of Veterans Affairs is delivering on that promise and upholding that sacred obligation to the women and men who have worn the uniform of our country. This new action is guided by science and driven by a desire to ensure that our nation’s veterans receive timely access to the benefits and services they deserve.</p>



<p>Supporting our veterans is a critical part of the Unity Agenda I proposed for our nation. No matter where we live or who we voted for in the last election, we all agree that we should serve our veterans as well as they have served us. My Administration will continue to do everything in its power to support our nation’s veterans, and I urge Congress to pass bipartisan legislation to comprehensively address toxic exposures and further deliver the vital benefits our veterans have earned. I will sign it immediately.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Nominee for Ambassador to&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/25/president-biden-announces-nominee-for-ambassador-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intention to nominate veteran U.S. diplomat Bridget A. Brink to serve as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ukraine. Bridget A. Brink, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ukraine Bridget A. Brink, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, currently serves as the U.S. Ambassador to the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intention to nominate veteran U.S. diplomat Bridget A. Brink to serve as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ukraine.</p>



<p><strong>Bridget A. Brink, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Ukraine</strong></p>



<p>Bridget A. Brink, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, currently serves as the U.S. Ambassador to the Slovak Republic.&nbsp;Prior to that, she served as Senior Advisor and Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs at the U.S. Department of State, with responsibility for issues related to Eastern Europe and the Caucasus.&nbsp;She also served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassies in Tashkent, Uzbekistan, and Tbilisi, Georgia. Brink spent her twenty-five-year career in the Foreign Service focused on advancing U.S. policy in Europe and Eurasia.&nbsp;She was the Director for the Aegean and the South Caucasus at the National Security Council and served in the State Department as the Deputy Director for Southern European Affairs, Special Assistant to the Under Secretary for Political Affairs, and Cyprus Desk Officer.&nbsp;She began her career in Belgrade, Serbia.</p>



<p>Originally from Michigan, Brink is the recipient of numerous performance awards. She holds Master’s degrees in International Relations and Political Theory from the London School of Economics and Political Science, as well as a Bachelor’s degree in Political Science from Kenyon College. She speaks Russian and has studied Slovak, Serbian, Georgian, and French.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of&#160;Israel</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/24/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-prime-minister-naftali-bennett-of-israel-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 17:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51686</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of Israel to discuss shared regional and global security challenges, including the threat posed by Iran and its proxies. The two leaders emphasized the strong personal bond they have developed since the Prime Minister’s visit to Washington last summer. This personal relationship has animated&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Prime Minister Naftali Bennett of Israel to discuss shared regional and global security challenges, including the threat posed by Iran and its proxies. The two leaders emphasized the strong personal bond they have developed since the Prime Minister’s visit to Washington last summer. This personal relationship has animated the work of our diplomatic and national security teams, enabling both countries to arrive at common positions on difficult matters. The President welcomed the visit to Washington this week by the Prime Minister’s National Security Advisor. The President also accepted an invitation to visit Israel in the coming months. The President took note of ongoing efforts between Israeli and Palestinian officials to lower tensions and ensure a peaceful conclusion to the holy season of Ramadan. He affirmed his unwavering support for Israel and its defense needs, and welcomed the historic $1 billion allocation to replenish Israel’s Iron Dome system. The two leaders committed to stay in regular contact to follow up on the important work of the U.S-Israel Strategic Consultative Group, chaired by their respective National Security Advisors.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
