<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 13:32:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with National Security Advisor Moeed Yusuf of Pakistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-national-security-advisor-moeed-yusuf-of-pakistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 13:32:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The National Security Advisors of the United States and Pakistan met in Geneva yesterday. Both sides discussed a range of bilateral, regional, and global issues of mutual interest and discussed ways to advance practical cooperation. Both sides agreed to continue to the conversation. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The National Security Advisors of the United States and Pakistan met in Geneva yesterday. Both sides discussed a range of bilateral, regional, and global issues of mutual interest and discussed ways to advance practical cooperation. Both sides agreed to continue to the conversation.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on Secretary of State Antony Blinken&#8217;s Visit to the Middle East</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/24/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-secretary-of-state-antony-blinkens-visit-to-the-middle-east/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18233</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following up on our quiet, intensive diplomacy to bring about a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, I have asked my Secretary of State, Tony Blinken, to travel to the Middle East this week. During his trip, Secretary Blinken will meet with Israeli leaders about our ironclad commitment to Israel’s security. He will continue our Administration’s efforts&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Following up on our quiet, intensive diplomacy to bring about a ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, I have asked my Secretary of State, Tony Blinken, to travel to the Middle East this week. During his trip, Secretary Blinken will meet with Israeli leaders about our ironclad commitment to Israel’s security. He will continue our Administration’s efforts to rebuild ties to, and support for, the Palestinian people and leaders, after years of neglect. And he will engage other key partners in the region, including on the coordinated international effort to ensure immediate assistance reaches Gaza in a way that benefits the people there and not Hamas, and on reducing the risk of further conflict in the coming months.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United States – Republic of Korea Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/21/fact-sheet-united-states-republic-of-korea-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and the Republic of Korea (ROK) pledge to strengthen our alliance and to broaden its focus to address issues of critical importance to the Indo-Pacific region and the world. We will deepen our cooperation on advanced technologies, increase global vaccinations and protect the world from future pandemics, combat the climate crisis, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States and the Republic of Korea (ROK) pledge to strengthen our alliance and to broaden its focus to address issues of critical importance to the Indo-Pacific region and the world. We will deepen our cooperation on advanced technologies, increase global vaccinations and protect the world from future pandemics, combat the climate crisis, and enhance economic cooperation and our people-to-people ties. Through these concrete initiatives, the United States and the Republic of Korea will demonstrate that our alliance is prepared to lead the region towards a prosperous, secure, dynamic, and bright future.<br><br><br><strong><u>Technology and Innovation</u></strong><br><br>As global leaders in technology and innovation, the United States and the ROK are committed to fostering strong and resilient supply chains, deepening our cooperation across space and new digital frontiers, and safeguarding a trusted, values-driven digital and technological ecosystem, in line with our shared democratic values. As we work together to foster post-pandemic recovery and build back a stronger more resilient global economy, we seek to leverage the collective strengths of our two countries – our open and competitive market systems, our shared democratic values and commitments to human rights, our mutual commitment to intellectual property protection and scientific and research integrity, and the shared spirit of innovation that animates our scientific and business communities &nbsp;– to address the critical challenges of the 21st century to the benefit of our citizens and the global community.<br><br>The United States and the Republic of Korea welcome:</p>



<ul><li>The announcements of significant investments in the United States and the Republic of Korea by our leading companies. These investments, totaling more than $25 billion, reflect the longstanding close economic ties between the United States and the ROK.</li></ul>



<p>Together, the United States and the Republic of Korea will:</p>



<ul><li>Facilitate mutual and complementary investments in semiconductors, including for advanced and auto-grade chips, and high-capacity batteries and commit to mutual and complementary investments across the entire supply chain of materials, parts, and equipment to expand the production capacity of these key products.<br></li><li>Encourage joint R&amp;D on critical and emerging technologies through programs nurturing AI, next-generation mobile network (6G), data, quantum technology, and biotechnology. Regarding quantum technology in particular, we welcome joint research and expert exchanges in quantum computing, communications, and sensing.<br></li><li>Recognize the importance of secure 5G and 6G networks, commit to supporting diverse and resilient supply chains, including innovative network architectures such as open-RAN technology, and commit to work together on open-RAN technology development and standardization issues.&nbsp;<br></li><li>Strengthen competitiveness in advanced information communications technologies, including 5G and next-generation mobile networks (&#8220;6G&#8221; or &#8220;Beyond 5G&#8221;), by encouraging investments in research, development, testing, and deployment of secure networks. The United States has committed $2.5 billion to this effort, and the ROK has committed $1 billion.<br></li><li>Explore the creation of a U.S.-ROK Supply Chain Task Force between the U.S. White House and the ROK Office of the President, to implement and review bilateral cooperation in the high-tech manufacturing and supply chains.<br></li><li>Establish a bilateral investment screening cooperation working group, led by the U.S. Departments of Treasury and State and their ROK counterparts at the technical level, to collaborate on ways to safeguard investments and strengthen investment screening mechanism.&nbsp;<br></li><li>Expand cooperation on space exploration facilitated by the Republic of Korea’s decision to sign the Artemis Accords, joining nine other nations focused on returning to the moon by 2024 and ultimately expand and deepen space exploration.<br></li><li>Support for the ROK’s development of its own satellite navigation system, the Korean Positioning System, and enhance its compatibility and interoperability with the Global Positioning System.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Deepening Cooperation on</u> <span style="text-decoration: underline">COVID-19 Response, Global Health, and Health Security</span></strong><br><br>The United States and the Republic of Korea recognize the suffering that COVID-19 has caused around the world and share a commitment to multilateral cooperation to end the pandemic and address future global health threats.  We pledge to expand coordination under the Global Health Security Agenda and to bolster pandemic prevention and response. We are also committed to partnering with each other, and with the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovation and COVAX, to expand vaccine production and related supplies and manufacturing innovations to meet this pressing global need. Through active leadership, the U.S. and the ROK will implement measures to improve our collective global health security, bolster COVID-19 response efforts, and build capacity to prevent the next pandemic.</p>



<p>Together, the United States and the Republic of Korea will:</p>



<ul><li>Support the Global Health Security Agenda, as steering group members, to improve global capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease threats. To facilitate this the ROK has committed $200 million in new funding over five years to help address future health threats.<br></li><li>To prepare for and mitigate the damage of the next biological threat, the United States and the ROK will work together in a new partnership with other likeminded partners to establish a multilateral, sustainable and catalytic health security financing mechanism this year and an associated governance structure.<br></li><li>Work together to renew its bilateral health memorandum of understanding between the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services and the Korean Ministry of Health and Welfare to ensure continued close cooperation on pandemic response and future global health issues.<br></li><li>Establish a comprehensive KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership to strengthen joint response capabilities for infectious disease through international vaccine cooperation.&nbsp; Based on the partnership, we will actively cooperate on greatly scaling up global COVID-19 vaccine supply, including through COVAX and in coordination with CEPI, to countries around the world. Drawing on each of our strengths, we will undertake the following work:<br></li><li>The United States and Korea will work collaboratively to expand manufacturing capacity for vaccines and related raw materials and promote science and technology cooperation for global benefit; &nbsp;<br></li><li>The United States and Korea will work to expand the production of vaccines that have been demonstrated safe and effective, as assessed by Stringent Regulatory Authorities and/or the World Health Organization;<br></li><li>Korea will provide expanded production capacity at manufacturing facilities in Korea to meet increasing demand of safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines in a timely manner; &nbsp;<br></li><li>The United States will discuss production constraints and launch expert cooperation aimed at global expansion of the raw materials and other components needed to make vaccines.<br></li><li>The United States and Korea will foster R&amp;D and scientific collaboration with a focus on global health security and pandemic preparedness. Korea and the United States each have gold standard biomedical research institutions in the area of infectious diseases and globally will promote the importance of voluntary technology transfer for vaccine production. By fostering collaborative work on COVID-19 and research to combat epidemics and pandemics of the future, we can jointly realize a world that prevents future outbreaks from becoming epidemics.<br></li><li>Launch a senior-level KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership Experts Group to implement the partnership to expand global COVID-19 vaccine manufacturing, comprised of scientists, experts and officials from our governments.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Advancing Shared Goals on Climate and Clean Energy</u></strong></p>



<p>The United States and the Republic of Korea will work together on areas of shared commitment, including climate ambition, sectoral decarbonization and clean energy deployment. To achieve these goals, the United States and the Republic of Korea will cooperate on our efforts to limit the global average temperature increase to 1.5 degrees Celsius and achieve net zero emissions no later than 2050.&nbsp;<br><br>Together, the United States and the Republic of Korea will undertake the following work:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The ROK will release early in October its provisional enhanced 2030 target, and by COP26 its final enhanced 2030 target, aligned with efforts to limit the global average temperature&nbsp;increase to 1.5 degrees Celsius and with the global goal to achieve net zero greenhouse gas emissions no later than 2050.&nbsp;<br></li><li>The United&nbsp;States&nbsp;and the ROK will enhance technical&nbsp;exchanges and cooperate to enhance our efforts to achieve our 2030 targets and 2050 goals, including&nbsp;long-term strategies.&nbsp;<br></li><li>The&nbsp;United&nbsp;States&nbsp;and the ROK will seek economy-wide decarbonization aligned with achieving net zero emissions by 2050, including working together to decarbonize our respective power sectors and facilitate clean and zero-emissions vehicle development for our respective government fleets.&nbsp;<br></li><li>The United&nbsp;States&nbsp;and the ROK will align official international financing with the global achievement of net zero greenhouse gas emissions no later than 2050 and deep emission reductions in the 2020s, and work to support developing countries and promote the flow of public and private capital toward climate-aligned investments and&nbsp;away from high-carbon investments.&nbsp;The ROK and the United States will work together at the&nbsp;OECD and in other international venues to end all forms of new public financing for overseas unabated coal-fired power plants.&nbsp;The ROK looks forward to joining with the United States and other countries in contributing climate finance towards the new post-2025 mobilization goal under the Paris Agreement.<br></li><li>The United&nbsp;States&nbsp;and the ROK will collaborate and exchange information on nature-based solutions,&nbsp;to conserve and enhance natural carbon sinks including forests, oceans and coastal ecosystems, recognizing their role in combatting the climate crisis.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li>The&nbsp;United&nbsp;States&nbsp;and the ROK will cooperate on the issue of marine debris and plastic pollution at the global level. In this regard, the Republic of Korea would like to highlight the significance of hosting of the 7th International Marine Debris Conference in cooperation with the U.S. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the United Nations Environment&nbsp;Programme. For the success of the 2022 Conference in Busan, the Republic of Korea looks forward to the United States support and active participation.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li>The United&nbsp;States&nbsp;and the ROK will elevate to the Ministerial level and expand the existing Energy Policy Dialogue to focus on enhancing clean energy deployment and areas of mutual interest. We will expand clean energy and decarbonization cooperation to include: R&amp;D on hydrogen storage, collaboration on&nbsp;electric vehicle&nbsp;battery manufacturing in the United States, lithium-ion battery recycling, grid-scale energy storage, and potential renewable energy deployment (e.g., offshore wind).&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Expanding our partnership</u></strong><br><br>The unbreakable U.S.-ROK alliance is grounded in our shared democratic values, is comprehensive in nature, and poised to tackle the most urgent issues of the 21st Century. &nbsp;We pledge to continue to work together to create a free, safe, prosperous, and dynamic Indo-Pacific region and reinforce the ASEAN-led regional architecture through cooperation between the ROK’s New Southern Policy and the United States’ priorities in the region. &nbsp;The United States and the ROK commit to expanding our partnership in cybersecurity, development assistance, human rights and democracy promotion, health, and climate change. &nbsp;People-to-people ties between our two countries are a central pillar of the enduring friendship of our people, which has spanned generations and will continue for generations to come.<br><br>Together, the United States and the Republic of Korea will:</p>



<ul><li>Recognizing that the Indo-Pacific is a key region for the peace and prosperity of the two countries, advance cooperation on projects in the region in connection with the ROK&#8217;s New Southern Policy and the United States’ vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific.<br></li><li>Establish a cyber-working group focused on enhancing cooperation among law enforcement and homeland security agencies, to learn from past cybercrime events and combat ransomware attacks against our two countries.<br></li><li>Further cooperation in civil nuclear industry in overseas nuclear markets, and strengthen our cooperation in non-proliferation in the course of such collaboration. As part of our earnest effort to ensure supply of nuclear power, the ROK and the United States commit to co-participate in overseas nuclear markets by promoting coordination in the supply chain, and the ROK will adopt a common policy with the United States to require recipient countries have an IAEA safeguard agreement Additional Protocol in place as a condition of supply of nuclear power plants. In this regard, we agree to hold the High Level Bilateral Commission meeting at a mutually agreeable time.<br></li><li>Continue our shared commitment to Afghanistan including its security and the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces through the NATO Afghan National Army Trust Fund.<br></li><li>Announce the U.S.-ROK Democracy and Governance Consultations (DGC), which will serve as a mechanism for coordination on human rights and democracy promotion efforts at home and abroad.&nbsp; The DGC will be an opportunity for both sides to share best practices and cooperate to promote and strengthen democratic resilience, good governance, and democratic institutions.<br></li><li>Initiate the two-way exchange of young environmental leaders between the United States and the ROK. U.S. Embassy Seoul will partner with the ROK Embassy in Washington to recruit American participants and organize the exchange program itinerary in Seoul, and U.S. Embassy Seoul would organize Korean participants going to the United States. U.S. Embassy Seoul is looking at 10 participants from each side with the ability to expand as necessary.<br></li><li>Create a public-private Domestic Violence and Cyber-Exploitation Working Group dedicated to ending the abuse of women online and offline in our two countries. It will 1) develop a statement of principles on addressing cyber-exploitation; 2) launch a bilateral dialogue between our governments on domestic violence and cyber-exploitation legislation; 3) establish a bilateral law-enforcement dialogue on domestic violence and cyber-exploitation, encouraging cooperation domestically and transnationally; and 4) design educational programs to address root causes of domestic violence and cyber-exploitation.<br></li><li>Expand exchange programs between graduate students of both nations to facilitate training and exchange of professionals in the fields of science, technology and information communications technologies.<br></li><li>Promote ASEAN centrality and advance new development cooperation between USAID and the Korea International Cooperation Agency in Southeast Asia to enhance public health cooperation; expand cooperation on connectivity, build digital capacity and cyber-security; strengthen the resilience of cities to address growing climate threats and vulnerability; and improve solid waste management and mitigate the impacts of ocean plastic pollution.<br></li><li>Explore further opportunities to jointly contribute to advancing technical and vocational education and training and seek possible areas of cooperation in linking the youth leadership development programs of the U.S., such as the Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative, and the ROK’s ASEAN youth projects.<br></li><li>Assist countries in the Indo-Pacific region to eradicate illegal, unreported and unregulated (IUU) fishing by providing IUU response capacity building and sharing information on IUU issues.</li></ul>



<p>Increase the interconnectedness between our two countries through a first of its kind baggage screening pilot program between the U.S. Department of Homeland Security and the ROK Ministry of Land, Infrastructure and Transport. The objective is to leverage transit time to screen and adjudicate checked baggage prior to arrival in the U.S., which will maximize resources, limit person-to-person contact, and result in a more efficient process for travelers. This pilot builds on the deep trust between our governments and is intended to increase security, while decreasing traveler-processing times at U.S. ports of entry.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S.-ROK Leaders’ Joint Statement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/21/u-s-rok-leaders-joint-statement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18203</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over seventy years ago, the alliance between the United States and the Republic of Korea was forged on the battlefield, as we stood shoulder-to-shoulder in war. Bonded in common sacrifice, our partnership has helped to keep the peace in the decades since, allowing both of our countries and our peoples to thrive. The linchpin for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Over seventy years ago, the alliance between the United States and the Republic of Korea was forged on the battlefield, as we stood shoulder-to-shoulder in war. Bonded in common sacrifice, our partnership has helped to keep the peace in the decades since, allowing both of our countries and our peoples to thrive. The linchpin for stability and prosperity, our alliance has continued to evolve as the world around us has changed. Now, as the regional security environment in the Indo-Pacific grows more complex, and existential issues, from the COVID-19 pandemic to the threat of climate change, reshape the globe, we recommit ourselves to an ironclad alliance.</p>



<p>The United States and the Republic of Korea share a vision for a region governed by democratic norms, human rights, and the rule of law at home and abroad. We seek a partnership that continues to provide peace and prosperity for our peoples, while serving as a linchpin for the regional and global order. Above all, we are united in our determination to reinvigorate and modernize our ties for a new era.&nbsp; President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. is honored to welcome President Moon Jae-in of the Republic of Korea to Washington to begin a new chapter in our partnership.<br><br><strong><em>The Alliance: Opening a New Chapter</em></strong></p>



<p>President Biden and President Moon reaffirm their mutual commitment to the defense of the Republic of Korea and their combined defense posture under the ROK-U.S. Mutual Defense Treaty, and President Biden affirms the U.S. commitment to provide extended deterrence using its full range of capabilities. We commit to strengthening the alliance deterrence posture, share the importance of&nbsp;maintaining joint military readiness, and reiterate our firm commitment to a conditions-based transition of wartime operational control. We also agree to deepen cooperation in other domains, including cyber and space, to ensure an effective joint response against emerging threats. We welcome the signing of a multi-year Special Measures Agreement, which enhances our combined defense posture and represents our dedication to the alliance.</p>



<p>The two sides reaffirm that close coordination on all matters related to global nonproliferation and safe, secure, and safeguarded uses of nuclear technology remain key characteristics of the alliance, and the United States recognizes the ROK’s global role in promoting nonproliferation efforts.&nbsp; Following consultations with the United States, the ROK announces the termination of its Revised Missile Guidelines, and the Presidents acknowledged the decision.</p>



<p>President Biden and President Moon emphasize their shared commitment to&nbsp;the complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula and their intent to address the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea’s&nbsp;(DPRK’s) nuclear&nbsp;and&nbsp;ballistic missile&nbsp;programs.&nbsp; We call for the full implementation of relevant UN Security Council resolutions by the international community, including the DPRK. President Moon welcomes the conclusion of the United States’ DPRK policy review, which takes a calibrated and practical approach that is open to and will explore diplomacy with the DPRK to make tangible progress that increases the security of the United States and the Republic of Korea. We also reaffirm our common belief that diplomacy and dialogue, based on previous inter-Korean and U.S.-DPRK commitments such as the 2018 Panmunjom Declaration and Singapore Joint Statement, are essential to achieve the complete denuclearization and establishment of permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula. President Biden also expresses his support for inter-Korean dialogue, engagement, and cooperation. We agree to work together to improve the human rights situation in the DPRK and commit to continue facilitating the provision of humanitarian aid to the neediest North Koreans. We also share our willingness to help facilitate the reunion of separated families of the two Koreas. We also agree to coordinate our approaches to the DPRK in lockstep. We underscore the fundamental importance of U.S.-ROK-Japan trilateral cooperation for addressing the DPRK, protecting our shared security and prosperity, upholding common values, and bolstering the rules-based order.</p>



<p>The significance of the U.S.-ROK&nbsp;relationship extends far beyond the Korean Peninsula: it is grounded in our shared values&nbsp;and anchors our respective approaches to the Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp;We agree we will work to align the ROK’s New Southern Policy and the United States’ vision for a free and open Indo-Pacific and that our countries will cooperate to create a safe, prosperous, and dynamic region. The United States and the ROK reaffirm support for&nbsp;ASEAN centrality and the ASEAN-led regional architecture.&nbsp;We agree to expand regional coordination on law enforcement, cybersecurity, public health and promoting a green recovery.&nbsp;We agree to work closely together to promote greater connectivity and foster digital innovation within ASEAN, while developing deeper people-to-people ties among Americans, Koreans, and the people of Southeast Asia. We will also consider opportunities for joint efforts to promote sustainable development, energy security, and responsible water management in the Mekong sub-region. The United States and the ROK&nbsp;also&nbsp;reaffirm support for&nbsp;enhanced cooperation with Pacific Island Countries&nbsp;and acknowledge the importance of open, transparent, and inclusive regional multilateralism including the Quad.</p>



<p>The United States and the Republic of Korea oppose all activities that undermine, destabilize, or threaten the rules-based international order and commit to maintaining an inclusive, free, and open Indo-Pacific. We pledge&nbsp;to maintain peace and stability, lawful unimpeded commerce, and respect for international law, including freedom of navigation and overflight in the South China Sea and beyond. President Biden and President Moon emphasize the importance of preserving peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait. As democracies that value pluralism and individual liberty, we share our intent to promote human rights and rule of law issues, both at home and abroad.</p>



<p>We resolutely condemn violence by the Myanmar military and police against civilians, and commit to continuing to press for the immediate cessation of violence, the release of those who are detained, and a swift return to democracy. We call on all nations to join us in providing safe haven to Burmese nationals and in prohibiting arms sales to Myanmar.<br><br><strong><em>The Way Forward: Comprehensive Partnership for a Better Future</em></strong></p>



<p>President Biden and President Moon acknowledge that contemporary threats and challenges require us to deepen our partnership in new areas. We commit to forging new ties on climate, global health, emerging technologies, including 5G and 6G technology and semi-conductors, supply chain resilience, migration and development, and in our people-to-people relationship.<br><br>President Moon&nbsp;welcomes U.S. leadership to enhance global climate ambitions through its hosting of the Leaders’ Summit on Climate on April 22, 2021. President Biden looks forward to&nbsp;the&nbsp;Republic of Korea’s contributions to achieve inclusive, international green recovery and net zero greenhouse gas emissions by hosting the P4G Seoul Summit on May 30-31.&nbsp;The United States has submitted an ambitious Nationally Determined Contribution, and welcomes the Republic of Korea’s plan to release early in October its provisional enhanced 2030 target, and by COP 26 its final enhanced 2030 target, aligned with efforts to limit the global average temperature increase to 1.5 degrees Celsius and with the global goal to achieve net zero greenhouse gas emissions no later than 2050.&nbsp;We will cooperate to enhance our efforts to achieve our 2030 targets and 2050 goals, including&nbsp;long-term strategies, set examples among the world leaders in reducing carbon emissions, conserve and enhance natural carbon sinks such as oceans and forests,&nbsp;and expand much-needed collaboration on technology and innovation to help achieve our long-term goals.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Building on President Moon’s declaration to end public financing for new overseas coal fired power plants and President Biden&#8217;s Executive Order on Tackling the Climate Crisis,&nbsp;the Republic of Korea and United States will work together at the OECD and in other international venues to end all forms of new public financing for&nbsp;unabated overseas coal-fired power plants.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Republic of Korea and the United States will&nbsp;align official international financing with the global achievement of net zero greenhouse gas emissions no later than 2050 and deep emission reductions in the 2020s.&nbsp;The Republic of Korea looks forward to joining with the United States and other countries in contributing climate finance towards the new post-2025 mobilization goal under the Paris Agreement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States and the Republic of Korea have been critical allies in the COVID-19 pandemic and on longstanding global health challenges, and President Biden expresses his gratitude for the ROK’s donation of critical medical supplies to the United States at its time of dire need. Against this backdrop, we agree to establish a comprehensive KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership to strengthen joint response capabilities for infectious disease through international vaccine cooperation, including focus areas on global expansion of production and related materials, as well as scientific and technological cooperation. Drawing on each of our strengths, Korea and the United States will work collaboratively to expand manufacturing of vaccines that have been demonstrated safe and effective, as assessed by Stringent Regulatory Authorities and/or the World Health Organization, for global benefit.&nbsp; The United States and Korea will partner to meet increasing demand for safe and effective COVID-19 vaccines in a timely manner.&nbsp; Based on the partnership, we will actively cooperate on greatly scaling up global COVID-19 vaccine supply, including through COVAX and in coordination with CEPI, to countries around the world toward ending the pandemic in the nearest future and preparing for the next biological threat. To this end, we will launch a senior-level experts group, the KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership Experts Group, to implement the partnership, comprised of scientists, experts and officials from our governments. Both countries will actively work together to ensure the success of COVAX, and the ROK commends the United States on its bold $4 billion contribution this year.&nbsp; To this end, and in recognition that we are both leaders in this fight, the ROK will increase its pledge to COVAX AMC substantially this year.</p>



<p>We agree to work together to strengthen and reform the World Health Organization by strengthening its ability to prevent pandemics through early and effective prevention, detection, and response to potential health emergencies, and by increasing its transparency and ensuring its independence. We will also support a transparent and independent evaluation and analysis of the origins of the COVID-19 outbreak and for investigating outbreaks of unknown origin in the future. We resolve to take decisive action to help the Indo-Pacific build better regional pandemic preparedness, and will work together and multilaterally to build the capacity of all countries to prevent, detect, and respond to infectious disease outbreaks. To move towards this goal, the ROK commits to increase its engagement in the Global Health Security Agenda Steering Group and Action Package Working Groups, and the ROK pledges a new $200M commitment for 2021-2025 period to support the GHSA target and help partner countries fill their gaps.&nbsp; The United States and the ROK will also work together with likeminded countries to create a new sustainable, catalytic health security financing mechanism.</p>



<p>The United States and the ROK are among each other’s largest trading and investment partners, and these strong economic ties, particularly the U.S.- Korea Free Trade Agreement (KORUS FTA), are a bedrock. The Presidents agreed to cooperate closely on the reform of the WTO and expressed their shared commitment to oppose unfair trade practices.</p>



<p>With the technological landscape rapidly changing, we agree to strengthen our partnership on critical and emerging technologies to promote our shared security and prosperity. We agree on the importance of careful screening of foreign investments and cooperation on export controls on critical technologies. Recognizing the importance of telecommunications security and vendor diversity, President Biden and President Moon commit to work together to develop open, transparent, and efficient 5G and 6G network architectures using Open-RAN technology. To this end, we agree to cooperate to increase resiliency in our supply chains, including in priority sectors such as semiconductors, eco-friendly EV batteries, strategic and critical materials, and pharmaceuticals. We also agree to work together to increase the global supply of legacy chips for automobiles, and to support leading-edge semiconductor manufacturing in both countries through the promotion of increased mutual investments as well as research and development cooperation. President Biden and President Moon commit to work together to develop a future-oriented partnership by leading innovation in the areas of clean energy, such as next generation batteries, hydrogen, and carbon capture and storage, and in the emerging technologies including Artificial Intelligence (AI), 5G, next generation communications network (6G), open-RAN technology, quantum technology, and bio-technology.</p>



<p>President Biden and President Moon also commit to strengthening their partnership in civil space exploration, science, and aeronautics research and will cooperate towards the ROK signing the Artemis Accords. Moreover, we commit to develop cooperation in overseas nuclear markets, including joint participation in nuclear power plant projects, while ensuring the highest standards of international nuclear safety, security, and nonproliferation are maintained.</p>



<p>President Biden and President Moon welcome the chance to strengthen development ties between the United States and the ROK. We are pleased to expand our partnership to facilitate closer collaboration between the U.S. Agency for International Development and the Korea International Cooperation Agency. We also recognize the importance of addressing the root causes of migration from Central America’s Northern Triangle countries to the United States. To this end, the ROK pledges to increase its financial commitment to development cooperation in the Northern Triangle countries to $220 million for the 2021-2024 period. The United States also welcomes the ROK’s initiatives to increase cooperation with the countries in Latin America and the Caribbean region, including digital and green cooperation.<br><br>The enduring friendship between the United States and the Republic of Korea is fed by our vibrant people-to-people ties. Over 1.7 million Korean students have enrolled in United States educational institutions since 1955. More than two million ROK citizens visit, work, or live in the United States, and over 200,000 U.S. citizens reside in the ROK. More than 10,000 U.S. and ROK citizens have participated in sponsored exchange programs, including ROK political leaders. We take great pride in celebrating the 60th anniversary of the first Korean and American Fulbright grantees to visit each other’s countries, which demonstrates the depth and strength of the longstanding ties between the people of the United States and the ROK. Our extensive exchange programs promote common purpose between our countries; we agree to increase two-way exchanges of young environmental leaders to strengthen our ability to cooperate in this critical area. Moving forward, we place particular emphasis on supporting greater interaction between experts in science, technology, engineering and mathematics and empowering women and girls in these fields, to build a solid foundation for secure and sustainable innovation and economic resilience in both countries.</p>



<p>President Biden and President Moon also agree to redouble their commitment to democratic values, and the promotion of human rights at home and abroad. The strength of our democracies depends on women&#8217;s full participation in them. Together we will strive to end the abuse of women and girls, including domestic violence and cyber-exploitation, and to exchange best practices to close the gender wage gap&#8211;a challenge both our countries share. We agree to expand cooperation to combat corruption, and ensure the freedoms of expression and religion and belief. Finally, we join voices in condemning violence against the Asian-American and Pacific Islander community, and pledge to work together to ensure that all Americans, including Korean-Americans, are treated with dignity and respect.</p>



<p>At a time of considerable international hardship and rapid global change, President Biden and President Moon are cognizant of the hurdles facing the United States, the ROK, and the world. We recognize that, with our cooperation, the U.S.-ROK alliance will play an increasingly global role, allowing us to rise to these defining challenges. For over seven decades, and thanks to its reciprocity and dynamism, our alliance has been a source of steadfast national strength; we look forward to working closely together to ensure it remains one for decades to come. President Moon expresses his gratitude to President Biden for the warm hospitality and extends an invitation for President Biden to visit the ROK.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, May 21, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/05/21/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-may-21-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 23:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 2:02 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Happy Friday.&#160; Okay, I only have one item for you all at the top: a brief preview of the President&#8217;s schedule for next week.&#160; On Monday, he will visit FEMA headquarters in D.C. to receive a briefing on the Atlantic hurricane outlook and preparedness&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>2:02 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Happy Friday.&nbsp; Okay, I only have one item for you all at the top: a brief preview of the President&#8217;s schedule for next week.&nbsp;<br><br>On Monday, he will visit FEMA headquarters in D.C. to receive a briefing on the Atlantic hurricane outlook and preparedness efforts.<br><br>On Tuesday, he will mark the anniversary of the death of George Floyd.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have more details on what the plans are for that day soon &#8212; maybe later today, maybe &#8212; maybe later this weekend.&nbsp;<br><br>On Thursday, the President will travel to Cleveland, Ohio to deliver remarks on the economy.<br><br>And on Friday, his budget will be released and he will also travel to Wilmington, where he will remain over the Memorial Day weekend.<br><br>With that, Darlene, why don’t you kick us off?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I wanted to start with Israel.&nbsp; Does the President or the White House have any concerns that the extent to which the Israeli Prime Minister continued the war will affect the President&#8217;s own ability to continue to defend Israel&#8217;s right to defend itself?&nbsp; I know that&#8217;s a little circular, but &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean domestically here or &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that the President has set a clear objective from the beginning, which was to end the war &#8212; play any role we can ending the war and bringing it to a conclusion as quickly as possible.&nbsp; And at the beginning, that seemed highly unlikely, given there were thousands of rockets falling on Tel Aviv and the Israelis were on a war footing and preparing for &#8212; by many reports &#8212; a ground invasion.&nbsp;<br><br>So I would say: What&#8217;s important to look at and reflect on here is historic precedent and the fact that the conflict in 2014 &#8212; many more lives were lost; also it went on for 51 days.&nbsp;<br><br>So the President&#8217;s view is that &#8212; and his view from the beginning &#8212; was that through disciplined, intensive, and qui&#8211;&nbsp; in a disciplined, intensive, and quiet campaign of diplomacy, and one where we would lead coordination in the region, we could bring an end to the conflict more quickly than it was intended to be.<br><br>And it&#8217;s also important to remember that Hamas is a terrorist organization, that Israel, of course, continues to have the right to defend itself.&nbsp; But what&#8217;s most important from now forward, in his view, is to &#8212; to contemplate where we go from here, Darlene.<br><br>And, certainly, he talked yesterday about replenishing support for the Iron Dome.&nbsp; And our view is that saved hundreds of lives, maybe more than that, given the effectiveness.&nbsp; Also, to support &#8212; through the United Nations &#8212; continued additional assistance in rebuilding Gaza.<br><br>We&#8217;ve already, of course, restarted our assistance that was ended in 2018 through UNRWA through the United States, but we&#8217;ll work through the &#8212; through the U.N. and we also will remain engaged deeply with diplomatic conversations with leaders in the region.&nbsp;<br><br>So, you know, obviously anyone here domestically will have to make their own decisions, but I would say that, you know, it&#8217;s important to convey what our intention was, what we feel &#8212; that we feel this was concluded as a result of the President&#8217;s engagement and &#8212; and, frankly, discipline from the beginning, much faster than these conflicts have been in the past.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp; Darlene, go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We also heard this week a lot of Democrats shifting their tone on Israel.&nbsp; So, is it time for the President or the White House or the United States to also perhaps start thinking about shifting the approach &#8212; its approach to Israel?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Shifting &#8212; what are &#8212; shifting in what way?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You had a lot of Democrats who were frustrated that the President didn&#8217;t call for a ceasefire immediately &#8212; that was one thing that a lot of people were upset about.&nbsp;<br><br>So &#8212; and the, sort of, I don&#8217;t want to say knee-jerk, but the U.S. position is that Israel has a right to defend itself.&nbsp; And there are a lot of Democrats who, I think &#8212; from what we heard them say this week &#8212; they don&#8217;t necessarily buy into that.&nbsp; And so the thinking is, is there some shift in the approach to Israel (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Darlene, I think the reason I answered it the way I did is because obviously we all shared an objective of bringing an end to the conflict.&nbsp;<br><br>The President&#8217;s view and his strategic approach and that of his team was that the best way to do that was not to call out our allies and partners, but was to remain closely coordinated and to work in lockstep and, at the right moment, to convey it was time to wind it down.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what he did.&nbsp;<br><br>And now the conflict is concluded in 11 days.&nbsp; And frankly, he resisted calls to take an alternative approach that, in his view, would have had an alternative outcome.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s why I answered it the way I did.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, one &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have one final question.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, we had a ceremony here &#8212; the bill signing &#8212; a large group of lawmakers &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; came.&nbsp; We had the Medal of Honor ceremony &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; today &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re back.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the meeting with the Kennedy Center Honors that we were told the President and First Lady had.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve seen handshakes, hugging, kissing.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the White House open again?&nbsp; Can you talk about some of the considerations that went into these events over the past couple of days?&nbsp; And is this the norm &#8212; the new norm?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The new “new” norm going forward?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can confirm we are a warm and fuzzy crew, and we like to hug around here.&nbsp; But we were waiting for that to be allowed by CDC guidelines, which we certainly abide by.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we are &#8212; as many organizations and companies are &#8212; working to implement these guidelines here at the White House.&nbsp; And so what you&#8217;ve seen over the last coveral [sic] &#8212; couple of days is efforts to do exactly that, and that includes welcoming back and having a full briefing room very soon.&nbsp;<br><br>It includes having more events with more people and, certainly, continuing to open the White House up &#8212; the People&#8217;s House &#8212; up to the American public.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Back to Israel for a moment: One of the other examples I think that would fit into Darlene&#8217;s question is this pressure from lawmakers over the $735 million pending sale of precision-guided missiles to Israel.&nbsp;<br><br>I know the President said yesterday he&#8217;s committed to replenishing the Iron Dome.&nbsp; But is he also committed to making sure that sale goes through?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have no plans to change our security assistance that we&#8217;re providing to Israel.&nbsp; But I will say that the President&#8217;s view is through &#8212; is that we need to do &#8212; we need to move forward on a couple of fronts.&nbsp; Certainly, supporting the security of Israel is one of them.&nbsp;<br><br>But another front is rebuilding &#8212; playing a constructive role in rebuilding Gaza; providing assistance and funding through the U.N. efforts to do exactly that; ensuring that it is not Hamas, but is the Palestinian people who benefit from that assistance.&nbsp; And doing that through the U.N. is, in our view, the best way to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>It also includes continuing to have engaged diplomacy with leaders in the region, continuing discussions with officials across the Middle East &#8212; Egyptians, Israelis, Palestinian leaders, Qataris, others &#8212; about how we move forward from here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, one on police reform: It looks like this, sort of, soft Memorial Day deadline is going to slip without legislation being passed.&nbsp; Is the White House losing some confidence in the bipartisan talks that are going on on Capitol Hill?&nbsp; And also, how does President Biden plan to address that issue on Tuesday when he speaks about the anniversary of George Floyd&#8217;s death?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, that the President used the occasion of his joint address &#8212; one of the highest-profile moments any President has &#8212; to speak about, reiterate his view that police reform is long overdue, that the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act is exactly the right forum and bill that could help get that done, rebuild trust in communities.<br><br>What we&#8217;ve seen from the negotiators &#8212; and we&#8217;ve been in close touch with the negotiators as well &#8212; is that they still feel there is progress being made.&nbsp;<br><br>Yes, it&#8217;s unlikely, as they&#8217;ve conveyed as well, we&#8217;re going to meet the timeline that the President outlined in his speech, which he did because he felt it was important to lift it up, to be gold [sic] &#8212; bold and ambitious in how we&#8217;re talking about such an important piece of legislation.<br><br>But we have confidence in the negotiators, and we&#8217;ve seen them convey publicly that they feel the vibes are good and they&#8217;re continuing to make progress.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Is the President confident that this ceasefire will hold?&nbsp; And if so, can you explain a bit why?&nbsp; Did he receive any kinds of assurances from Prime Minister Netanyahu?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we have strong assurancens [sic] &#8212; assurances &#8212; sorry, I don&#8217;t know why that was a hard word.&nbsp; Let me try again: We have strong assurances from the relevant parties that they are committed to the ceasefire.&nbsp; And obviously, this is something we will be watching extremely closely in the coming days.<br><br>And I think what&#8217;s important to note is: In the final 24 hours leading up to the ceasefire &#8212; obviously, the President was deeply engaged before that, but he was very &#8212; he was especially deeply engaged in that period of time, as were high-level senior officials here.&nbsp; And they were back and forth on the phone between many different parties &#8212; the Israelis; the Egyptians, who were in touch with Hamas; and others &#8212; about the importance of not violating, even pre-violating the ceasefire in the hours leading up to it, as we see did not happen.&nbsp;<br><br>So we will be in close touch with all parties.&nbsp; We clearly will be watching it.&nbsp; But we do have assurances from the relevant parties that they are committed.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And yesterday, before this was announced, you said you expected Israel to start winding down their operations because they had achieved significant military objectives.&nbsp; So how much of the timing of this do you think is because of the President&#8217;s diplomatic approach?&nbsp; And how much of this is simply because the Israelis had exhausted much of their targets in Gaza?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think what&#8217;s, again, important to remember is to point back to how these conflicts have worked in the past.&nbsp; And we have seen these conflicts last for weeks and weeks &#8212; many, many more lives lost.&nbsp;<br><br>Now we certainly know there were lives lost in this 11-day conflict; every one is a tragedy.&nbsp; But certainly, because of the President&#8217;s deep engagement; his long relationships; the fact that he set a clear objective from the beginning that we were going to put out the noise and focus on our strategy of deep, intensive, quiet diplomacy; have conversations, not call out our partners and allies and do that &#8212; do it &#8212; do our engagements through &#8212; through one-on-one conversations, we certainly think that had an impact.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, of course, we also were watching closely where &#8212; and were in touch with them closely &#8212; about &#8212; about their military successes.&nbsp; And certainly, that was a part &#8212; a factor, but a part of the discussion as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, sort of, a scheduling question here: There had been an expectation that there was going to be a conversation of some kind today between Republicans on the Hill, some officials here at the White House about the status of infrastructure and the Republican counterproposal.&nbsp; Is that meeting still happening today?&nbsp; And can you give us, kind of, an update on where things stand, and any movement that may or may not be happening?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, it is happening.&nbsp; It may be ongoing as we speak, but it started shortly before one o&#8217;clock over video conference this afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>Our team, including Steve Ricchetti, Louisa Terrell, Brian Deese, Secretary Raimondo, and Secretary Buttigieg, put forward a reasonable counteroffer that reduces the size of the package from $2.25 trillion in additional investment to $1.7 trillion.&nbsp;<br><br>And, in our view, this is the act &#8212; the art, I should say, of seeking common ground.&nbsp; This proposal exhibits a willingness to come down in size, giving on some areas that are important to the President &#8212; otherwise they wouldn&#8217;t have been in the proposal &#8212; while also staying firm in areas that are most vital to rebuilding our infrastructure and industries of the future, making our workforce and our country more competitive with China.<br><br>We actually have every intention to share the complete totality of the counterproposal with you all.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll just wait for the meeting to conclude to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Until then, can you say any more about what was taken out to lower that price tag?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, let me give you, kind of, some topline details.&nbsp; And then, again, what &#8212; the counterproposal that we’ll put out is very detailed, so you’ll see all of the specifics for yourself.&nbsp; But, again, I noted the topline number that offered.&nbsp;<br><br>It &#8212; our proposal also involved a shifting &#8212; shifting investments in research and development, supply chains, manufacturing, and small business out of the negotiation and into other efforts, such as the Endless Frontier Act and the CHIPS Act &#8212; which, as you know, there&#8217;s ongoing discussions and negotiations on a bipartisan level about those, as well.<br><br>The President &#8212; the proposal also agreed to reduce the funding request for broadband to match the Republican offer and to reduce the proposed investment in roads, bridges, and major projects to come closer to the number proposed by the senators.&nbsp; This is all in the spirit of finding common ground.<br><br>Now, at the same time, as I alluded to, we also &#8212; the counteroffer also reflects our view that the Republican offer excludes entirely some proposals that are key to our competitiveness &#8212; key to investments in clean energy and in industries of the future, in rebuilding our workforce, including critical investments in our power sector, building and construction, workforce training, veterans hospital construction, and the care economy.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we push for increased funding levels for critical transportation infrastructure, like rail, especially considering China&#8217;s level of investment in such projects, as well as the elimination of lead pipes that poison drinking water, and resilience projects as extreme weather events &#8212; as we&#8217;ve seen around the country &#8212; continue to become more common as a result of climate change.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And lastly, any changes to how you would like to pay for all of this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We also reiterated &#8212; or the intention is to reiterate the fact that the President is not willing to raise taxes on Americans earning under $400,000 a year through a gas tax or through user fees.&nbsp; He believes that the extraordinarily wealthy, the companies that, many of whom have not paid taxes in recent years, can afford a modest increase to pay for middle-class jobs.<br><br>Go- &#8212; did you have another question, or are you good?&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just heard you describe the infrastructure negotiations as the “art of seeking common ground.”&nbsp; At some point, does that become the “The Art of the Deal”?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t know.&nbsp; You’re the professional, here, Peter.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was a joke.&nbsp; That was a joke.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You’re the TV star &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; you know?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Um &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; What’s the FOX chyron going to be?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; “Art of Seeking Common Ground” does take a lot of characters &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It does.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ll check with the control room.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; “The Art of the Deal” &#8212; we’d be okay with that.&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With “The Art of the Deal”?&nbsp; I think that’s a headline.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there you go.&nbsp; An art of a different kind of deal &#8212; a deal for the working people.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Got it.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, on &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Glad we could work that out.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.<br><br>On Israel, how much credit does President Biden think he deserves for this ceasefire that was negotiated by the President of Egypt?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, the President’s focus was on one objective, which was bringing an end to the conflict as quickly as possible.&nbsp; As you know &#8212; and as our briefing day-in-and-day-out was evidence of, there was criticism &#8212; and as Darlene’s question was evidence of &#8212; there was criticism coming from many sides.&nbsp;<br><br>We kept our head down, focused on our strategic objective, focused on intensive, quiet diplomacy to bring an end to the conflict as quickly as possible.<br><br>Our engagements with the leaders of Egypt were &#8212; was &#8212; the leader of Egypt was a key part of that discussion and a key part of bringing an end to the conflict, given their important relationships with Hamas.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I &#8212; because we are just trying to understand all these &#8212; the dozens of calls and who played what role &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the President extended his “sincere gratitude to President Al Sisi and the other senior Egyptian officials who played a critical role in the diplomacy.”&nbsp; So, if their role was critical, how does the White House describe President Biden&#8217;s role?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, Peter, I think what I can do here &#8212; what the President was conveying is that this was an effort &#8212; much of it coordinated by the United States, much of which he was involved in personally &#8212; engagements on the phone, engagements with his team, a commitment and a driving desire to keep the strategy aligned with what we knew would help bring an end to the conflict as quickly as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>He&#8217;s also someone who wants to give credit where credit is due, and that includes the role the Egyptians played, and the role many countries in the region played in &#8212; in working to bring an end to the conflict.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, quickly &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And also his team.&nbsp; I mean, he called out Secretary of State, Tony Blinken.&nbsp; He called out his National Security Advisor, and also our UN Ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, who played an important role here as well.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quickly on immigration: The governor of Tennessee says that he was asked and he declined a Biden administration request to house unaccompanied minors.&nbsp; And in coming days &#8212; or in recent days, there have been some reports that at least four planes filled with unaccompanied minors landed in his state, some in the middle of the night.&nbsp; Can you explain what&#8217;s going on there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as we have been very clear about: Children &#8212; our objective is to unite these unaccompanied children &#8212; children under the age of 18 &#8212; with families, with sponsor families.&nbsp; So children traveling &#8212; were traveling through &#8212; have been traveling through Tennessee.&nbsp;<br><br>They&#8217;re simply on their way to unite with relatives and sponsors &#8212; to meet sponsors in the state, or just traveling through Tennessee until they reach another destination to unite with family members or legal sponsors.&nbsp;<br><br>As you know, geographically, it&#8217;s right in a place where it &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a lot of states around it, so it&#8217;s a place where some flights have gone through as children are moving to other destinations.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And since this was something that the governor of the state said he didn&#8217;t want, this is not a case of federal officials trying to sneak something past the state-level officials.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;m confirming here that Tennessee is a state that is right near in the middle of the country and some kids have to travel through there to get <s>through</s> [to] their destination.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve been very clear that our objective is to treat these kids humanely, get them to safe homes, especially homes of loved ones and sponsored families.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A point of clarification: You mentioned &#8212; detailed some of the cuts to the counterproposal.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did I hear you right &#8212; you said they&#8217;re going to find a home in other Senate legislation that&#8217;s currently through now, like the (inaudible) bills are &#8212; while they&#8217;re coming out of your counterproposal, they are going to find a home somewhere?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are some components, yeah, where there is some overlap in the Frontiers bill, in the CHIPS bill, where there is opportunity to still move forward on some of the President&#8217;s ideas.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gotcha.<br><br>Republican governors in some 22 states have rolled back those expanded unemployment benefits.&nbsp; What is the White House or the Biden administration doing to &#8212; to preserve those benefits, if anything, at the state level?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Jarrett, it is up to, of course, these governors to make a decision about what assistance they want to provide to the people of their states.<br><br>Our view continues to be that unemployment insurance, of course, at a federal level &#8212; which is something we advocate for and would work to pass through Congress, or have worked to pass through Congress &#8212; is something that can help people &#8212; during a time where there are still more than 8 million people out of work &#8212; make ends meet.&nbsp; And that &#8212; there is not overwhelming data that suggests that it is a driving factor in people not reentering the workforce, especially at a time where we&#8217;re continuing to recover from the pandemic.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s ultimately up to governors to make those decisions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And there&#8217;s nothing the federal government can do, just to be clear?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We can continue to convey what we see in the data, what we advocate for, in terms of what we think will help get people back on their feet, and we use every opportunity to do that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>The Washington Post just reported some details on the upcoming budget, specifically that the &#8212; the public option to create a government run health insurance program and a pledge to cut prescription drug costs are not going to be in that budget proposal.&nbsp; Anything you can comment on that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ll be announcing and rolling out the President&#8217;s proposed budget a week from today.&nbsp; Buckle up.&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s a big day for Reuters those days.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to get too far ahead of that.<br><br>But what I will tell you is that what it will outline is how we&#8217;re proposing to pay for a range of the proposals the President has put forward.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s clearly talked about and remains committed to his campaign pledge of pushing for a public option to doing something to address the rising cost of prescription drugs &#8212; something he talked about in his joint session address.&nbsp; But every entity may not be reflected in this budget.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Back to the Middle East: Prime Minister Netanyahu seemed to ignore President Biden&#8217;s requests for a de-escalation of the violence over several days, and then a truce was struck once Egypt stepped in.&nbsp; So, I guess, the question is: Why should people have confidence that President Biden will be able to work with him for a de-escalation should there be another flare up?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Through &#8212; with Prime Minister Netanyahu?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Prime Minister Netanyahu.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just have to say, Kristen, that I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s how any of the parties involved &#8212; the Prime Minister, the Egyptian President, or this President &#8212; would characterize what happened over the last 11 days.&nbsp; And obviously, some of this is going to remain &#8212; continue to be &#8212; remain behind the d- &#8212; behind the scenes through what &#8212; what was quiet diplomacy over the course of 11 days.<br><br>But there&#8217;s no question that the President&#8217;s engagement, both with the Israeli Prime Minister, both with the &#8212; with the President of Egypt, with leaders in the region, our commitment to staying disciplined and remaining focused on our overarching objective of bringing an end to the conflict as quickly as possible, was contributed to &#8212; to the ceasefire we saw last night.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I guess what I’m asking about is, based on your own readouts from the White House, President Biden pressed Prime Minister Netanyahu to de-escalate the violence.&nbsp; And then, in later phone calls, urged a ceasefire, and that didn&#8217;t happen until recently.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And there was a ceasefire last night, and he urged for a ceasefire about two days in advance of that.&nbsp; And, again, I would say that the President&#8217;s objective from the beginning was to have these conversations quietly, to work in close coordination with the Prime Minister about how we could bring an end to the conflict, recognizing fully that at the same time there were thousands of rockets coming into cities in Israel from Hamas.&nbsp; And that was something the Prime Minister was going to work to defend.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the President said yesterday that he told Prime Minister Netanyahu he would replenish the Iron Dome system.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did he offer that as a promise in order to reach the ceasefire?&nbsp; And were there any concessions made a as part of this deal?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First of all, the President did that because &#8212; conveyed that because he felt that the effectiveness of the Iron Dome helped save hundreds of lives.&nbsp; And it remains &#8212; the President remains steadfast, of course, in his support of Israel&#8217;s right to defend itself, but also believes that the effectiveness of the Iron Dome is something that we should continue to support, and we will continue to support as United States.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any concessions made &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; By the United States?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; in order to broker this deal &#8212; by the United States in order &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp;&nbsp; No.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>Let me ask you, domestically: You just said it&#8217;s unlikely they will reach a deal on the George Floyd Policing Act by next Tuesday.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the negotiators have conveyed that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Yes, they have conveyed that.&nbsp; What will the pressure point be if not this one-year anniversary?&nbsp; How does President Biden make sure this gets done?&nbsp; And if you speak to civil rights groups, interest groups &#8212; they want it done this summer.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, with the &#8212; all of the negotiators are continuing to press forward on working to find common grand &#8212; ground to get this done.&nbsp; The President wants to sign it into law.<br><br>And, of course, the anniversary of George Floyd’s death &#8212; something that impacted the President personally and deeply, as it impacted millions of Americans, was a moment to call for action, to call for forward movement.&nbsp; But the negotiators, by all accounts, are continuing to make progress.&nbsp; They&#8217;re continuing to have good discussions, and that is a positive sign.<br><br>So, you know, we are not going to slow our &#8212; slow our efforts to get this done, but we can also be transparent about the fact that it&#8217;s going to take a little bit more time &#8212; that sometimes that happens and that&#8217;s okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By the summer &#8212; does the President want this done by the summer?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President wants to sign it into law as quickly as possible.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow up on something that Mary was asking you &#8212; this counterproposal.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you tell us, specifically, about the corporate tax rate?&nbsp; Has there been any change to the corporate tax rate?&nbsp; Has it come down to 25 percent &#8212; something that Democrats were asking for?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, our counterproposal was primarily focused on the areas of investment, as you&#8217;ll see when we provide the specific details.&nbsp; And what I reiterated to &#8212; which is the President&#8217;s bottom line, about not raising taxes on people making less than $400,000 a year &#8212; encouraging the Republican ranking members and leaders to take a fresh look at the fact that many corporations can afford to pay a little bit more in taxes and so can many in the highest income, that was really what was in our counterproposal.&nbsp; In terms of what was discussed in the meeting, I don&#8217;t have a readout of that quite yet.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No change yet to the corporate tax rate, that you&#8217;re aware of?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I mean &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; From the proposal of the corporate tax rate?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not a mathematician &#8212; otherwise, I wouldn&#8217;t be here &#8212; but, obviously, we proposed a package that was $500 billion less expensive, so it needs less payfors.&nbsp; But what that looks like will have to be a part of the negotiation.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I&#8217;m hoping you can give us an update on international inbound travel.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if the administration &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I wish I could.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a very popular question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I was going to ask if the administration feels any urgency, ahead of the summer high season, to make any new policy moves.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we certainly understand the desire of many Europeans to come travel to the United States and vice versa.&nbsp; And people &#8212; that&#8217;s part of returning to normal and part of what will make people feel good about the efforts to fight the pandemic.<br><br>But we can&#8217;t respond to public pressure or even emotion; we have to rely on the health and guidance &#8212; the guidance of our health and medical experts, which is exactly what we&#8217;ll do.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But in terms of that guidance, at this point, the CDC is saying, for vaccinated individuals, they can go in and outside &#8212; large crowds, small crowds.&nbsp; You know, they said that vaccinated individuals can travel internationally.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, and &#8212; and they&#8217;re still required to wear masks, and airline travel is a little different.&nbsp; And, again, I&#8217;m not a doctor, but we rely on their advice, and they obviously are continuing to consider and update guidance as information becomes available.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And in terms of possibly requiring, you know, proof of vaccination for non-U.S. citizens, is there any further consideration of that that you could share?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; A vaccine passport?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t use that term.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, yeah, you mean the same basic thing: the federal government requiring vaccines &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; vaccine &#8212; proof of vaccination.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Proof of vaccination.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That is not in our intended plan.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just &#8212; on a different topic, on Colonel Puckett, Jr.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why was &#8212; maybe you could take us a little bit &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; into the decision to have him be the first recipient of a Medal of Honor from the President.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, clearly, he has an incredible personal story and is part of what the President feels is one of the greatest generations in history.&nbsp; And he also has a great deal of support for the sacrifices he made and the incredible story we just heard the President tell at that event.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, it&#8217;s &#8212; and the President, I think, felt it was important to honor him, recognize him, you know, as one of the first people, given the service that he paid to the country and, you know, the fact that he is still a young man, but someone we want to recognize while his family can celebrate with him.<br><br>Go ahead, Anne.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Let me try a different version of Kristen&#8217;s question on Israel.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, on Wednesday, the readout of the President&#8217;s call with the Prime Minister was pretty blunt in saying that the President had told the Prime Minister he expected to see a significant de-escalation that day &#8212; Wednesday.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The ceasefire didn&#8217;t come until more &#8212; well more than 24 hours later to &#8212; well, 36 hours later &#8212; 2:00 a.m., Friday, local time.&nbsp; Was the President concerned?&nbsp; And was there a &#8212; at a cert- &#8212; was there any consternation around here as the day wore on on Wednesday and moved into Thursday that the Prime Minister was blowing him off, not listening to him, not doing what the President had asked him to do?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; And that is not a reflection of what happened behind the scenes either.&nbsp; Clearly, the President felt it was important to convey, even in a public readout, that his view and the view of the United States was it was time to move toward a ceasefire.&nbsp; And just over 24 hours later, there was an agreed ceasefire, and that required additional conversations behind the scenes, many of which the President was involved in himself, as you well know because we did readouts of them.&nbsp;<br><br>It required also an agreement, as you know &#8212; and from the other side &#8212; and required an agreement from Hamas that they also would engage in the ceasefire.&nbsp; Hence, the conversation the President had with President Al Sisi on Thursday &#8212; just yesterday morning &#8212; that was an &#8212; a factor that led to that agreement on that side.<br><br>So it was the moment in the discussions and negotiations where the President felt it was important to convey that publicly.&nbsp; Obviously, he was careful about what he conveyed publicly, what he said publicly, what we said in readouts publicly, but it was a reflection of that.&nbsp; But over &#8212; the last 24 to 36 hours were clearly pivotal in bringing an end to the conflict.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it&#8217;s unusual for a President to throw a flag like that and to say to a foreign leader, effectively, &#8220;The U.S. President is setting a deadline for a specific action.&#8221;&nbsp; If that specific action isn&#8217;t met in the deadline the President sets &#8212; even though I completely take your point that there was a ton of other stuff happening, and it wasn&#8217;t a terribly long &#8212; much longer time period than the one that President has set &#8212; is there a risk that the President looks, in any way, weak or ineffective in having set the deadline to begin with?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first of all, there was a ceasefire in 11 days.&nbsp; That was one fifth of the length of time of the 2014 conflict, with far fewer lives lost.&nbsp;<br><br>This was accomplished, in part, because of intensive, quiet diplomacy where we did not make him or leaders in the United States the centerpieces of this effort because we felt that was not &#8212; that the most important thing we could do was play a role behind the scenes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what we did.&nbsp; The conflict has now ended.&nbsp; There is a ceasefire just over 24 hours after that call was made, and that was an important point to convey publicly.<br><br>But, no, that is not our view from here.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On one other topic.&nbsp; This month, the Justice Department had informed Washington Post reporters &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and then this week, a CNN reporter, that the previous administration had obtained their &#8212; their phone records as part of investigations into presumed leaks that lead to news stories.&nbsp; What is this administration&#8217;s view of the appropriateness of seeking reporters&#8217; phone records?&nbsp; And do you plan to continue those investigations?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I will say that I learned of this issue for the first time after CNN&#8217;s report yesterday.&nbsp; And I know similar sentiments have been expressed from many parts of this government.<br><br>As I understand it, the records sought and the legal process to obtain them began, as you noted, during the prior administration.&nbsp; We, of course &#8212; this President is committed, strongly, to the rights of the freedom of press, as you have seen for decades, and to standing up for the rights of journalists.<br><br>And the Justice Department conveyed yesterday that they intend to meet with reporters to hear their concerns about recent notices.&nbsp; And they, certainly, intend to use the &#8220;Holder model&#8221; as their model &#8212; not the model of the last several years.<br><br>But, really, these decisions would be up to the Justice Department.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, the Holder model included pretty significantly aggressive leak investigations.&nbsp; The specific question, though, is the appropriateness of seizing &#8212; seeking and seizing personal phone records from journalists.&nbsp; Do you &#8212; does this administration believe that&#8217;s an appropriate tactic?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, it was done by the prior Department of Justice; I would send you to the Department of Justice for any comment on what their intentions are moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There was a Marist Poll that came out earlier weighing race relations in the U.S., with 17 percent of people saying that they did not believe that things had &#8212; sorry, 17 percent believing &#8212; only 17 percent &#8212; things had changed.&nbsp;<br><br>Earlier, you talked about police reform and what the administration is doing.&nbsp; You mentioned building trust in communities.&nbsp; But what does that actually mean?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; the reason I referenced that is because, obviously, passing &#8212; or our view, I should say, is passing the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act into law, ensuring that there is more accountability, more requirements and restrictions in place for departments across the country.&nbsp; And also, it would be a contribution to rebuilding trust in communities.&nbsp; Obviously, there&#8217;s more that needs to be done beyond that; that&#8217;s not the only step &#8212; far from it.<br><br>But I think our view and the President&#8217;s view is that signing this bill into law would make a contribution.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Also, what concerns &#8212; with concerns among parents about potential long-term effects on children associated &#8212; if they&#8217;ve gotten the vaccine &#8212; what type of &#8212; any type of surveillance, outside of the two-year plan that&#8217;s been described by Pfizer, has the administration considered to help kind of quell the concerns of parents?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Just so I understand your question, you mean surveillance of the impacts on kids?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that the most important thing we can say &#8212; message we can convey from this administration is: It&#8217;s okay to have questions and concerns, and your primary care physicians and doctors are the &#8212; absolutely the right people to answer these questions now and a year from now and three years from now.&nbsp;<br><br>And, certainly, there has been a great deal the &#8212; the process of approving vaccines in the United States is the gold standard.&nbsp; We have the highest standards in the world.&nbsp; And our health and medical experts are confident in that.<br><br>But we also know &#8212; I&#8217;m a parent, many of us are parents &#8212; parents have questions about what this means for their kids.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s okay; that&#8217;s valid.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one of the reasons why we are trying to fund and empower local leaders, civic leaders, medical experts, partnering with primary care physicians so that parents feel like they can ask these questions to people they trust &#8212; right? &#8212; who they&#8217;ve been taking their kids to for years.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lastly, the Department of Agriculture, today, published the first notices of the funding available.&nbsp; And so, for Black farmers who&#8217;ve been talking about &#8212; they have felt like there&#8217;s a lot of racism within that system.&nbsp; We know that the banks had sent a letter to Secretary Vilsack earlier, pushing back on those funds being available, and many farmers took it as a threat.&nbsp; What is the administration prepared to do if we start to see that then banks don&#8217;t offer any loans to Black farmers because of that decision?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I know this is very much on the mind of Secretary Vilsack, in terms of ensuring equity and how these funds are being distributed and delivered around the country.&nbsp; I&#8217;d probably have to check with the Department of Agriculture on, kind of, the status of this letter; I haven&#8217;t been following this as closely.<br><br>Go ahead, in the back.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On infrastructure, you mentioned some of the items removed in this newest counteroffer kind of migrating to other proposals that are pending legislation.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could some of those then be included in the Families Plan?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, I think the reason I referenced the &#8212; the CHIPS proposal and, of course, the Frontiers proposals is because, as you know, those are negotiating and working their way through in a bipartisan fashion at this point in time.<br><br>But as I&#8217;ve also said from here, but I&#8217;ll restate: What the President&#8217;s put forward is a &#8212; is a bunch of large, bold ideas.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; The mechanisms and the mechanics of how they move forward, we&#8217;re very open to working with Congress on what that looks like.<br><br>So, there is some overlap in some of the pieces proposed in the Jobs Plan with some of the components in the CHIPS plan and the Frontiers plan, hence, there&#8217;s an opportunity to move those ideas forward.&nbsp; But beyond that, you know, obviously, he&#8217;ll continue to press for these in the months ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the original proposal had pretty ambitious plans for electric vehicles.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You referenced this a little bit before, but &#8212; a lot of GOP skepticism about some of those plans.&nbsp; So, any counterproposal?&nbsp; Or are you guys ratcheting back on those at all?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, absolutely.&nbsp; And again, you&#8217;ll see the specifics when we put out the &#8212; our entire counterproposal.&nbsp; But certainly, investments in the electric vehicle industry, charging stations, industries of the future &#8212; which, in our view, are going to be the backbone of communities around the country; including communities like Dearborn, where the President was earlier this week &#8212; are areas where we feel we need to continue to invest to be competitive with China and boost our workforce.<br><br>Go ahead, in the back.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The administration has said that it wants to work with Japan and South Korea to stand up to China&#8217;s aggression.&nbsp; But, as you know, South Korea and China, they&#8217;re heavily dependent on &#8212; South Korea and Japan economies are heavily dependent on China.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s also been some reports about the South Korean side being reluctant to add any language that might upset the Chinese in today&#8217;s joint statement.&nbsp;<br><br>So, how is the administration going to work with South Korea and Japan when it comes to standing up to Beijing when their economies are so closely tied to China?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, let me say that it is &#8212; should send a clear message about the importance of these partnerships and alliances that the first two bilateral meetings the President had &#8212; has had, after today, are with Japan and South Korea.&nbsp;<br><br>And, obviously, there are a range of means we can (inaudible) coordinate and communicate with both of those countries, including through our trilateral discussions that we&#8217;ve already participated in, in a very high level from the federal government, with our National Security Advisor and our Secretary of State.<br><br>We certainly recognize that, fundamentally, our two countries &#8212; the United States and South Korea &#8212; may look at aspects of our relationship with China similarly and some aspects differently, and that will be a part of our discussion and a part of what we understand, going into these discussions that are ongoing now.<br><br>But, you know, at the end of the day, we feel there&#8217;s areas of cooperation and partnership with South Korea.&nbsp; As you know, there was a big announcement that was made today which we welcomed, which is significant investments in the United States by South Korean companies totaling more than $25 billion &#8212; which that reflects the longstanding close economic ties between the United States and South Korea.&nbsp; And we expect there to be continued opportunities for those type of economic engagements and cooperation.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more.&nbsp; There&#8217;s &#8212; as you know, there&#8217;s ongoing tension between South Korea and Japan.&nbsp; Will the President &#8212; will he urge President Moon Jae-in today to improve its relationship with Japan?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, we continue to promote expanded trilateral U.S-South Korea-Japan cooperation.&nbsp; Again, you&#8217;ve seen that through the trilateral meetings that we&#8217;ve had at a very high level.&nbsp; We not only want to strengthen America&#8217;s relationship with our allies, but also between our allies.&nbsp; And nowhere is that more important than between South Korea and Japan.&nbsp;<br><br>So, certainly, there&#8217;s a range of topics they&#8217;ll discuss, and they&#8217;ll have a press conference to talk about all of it.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I want &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go right to you next.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll go right &#8212; I will not forget you.&nbsp; Sorry, I was jumping around.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about President Biden&#8217;s conversation with Rashida Tlaib on the tarmac in Michigan.&nbsp; What was his reaction to what she said, which was reported to be that she told him, &#8220;The U.S. can&#8217;t continue to give the right-wing Netanyahu government billions of dollars to commit crimes against the Palestinians&#8221;?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President spoke about how impressed he was by Congresswoman Tlaib at the event he had after he had the conversation with her.&nbsp; So I think he spoke to that already.<br><br>And, certainly, he understands that there are a range of viewpoints as it relates to the conflict in the Middle East, which we were in the heat of over the last several days.&nbsp; And he felt it was important to have a discussion with her on the tarmac so he could convey his point of view, certainly hear hers, and &#8212; you know, he&#8217;ll look forward to continuing to engage moving forward.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; I&#8217;m following up on Darlene&#8217;s question about the White House being open.&nbsp; Of course, now we&#8217;re all masks off, at least in the press.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I &#8212; you know, I can only speak to our experience here: It seems to be on the honor system if we&#8217;re vaccinated or not.&nbsp; So, now that the White House is having these events &#8212; maskless hugging today and yesterday and, I assume, you know, kind of, forthright from here &#8212; how is the White House tracking vaccinations beyond the folks who got vaccinated &#8212; (someone sneezes) &#8212; God bless you &#8212; on TV, like Pelosi?&nbsp; For the folks who we haven&#8217;t seen vaccinated on TV, how is the White House tracking who is vaccinated and who is not vaccinated?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, what the guidance provided was information so people could take steps to protect themselves: either to get vaccinated &#8212; which every American is eligible who&#8217;s over the age of 12, at this point in time &#8212; or to mask up if they&#8217;re not yet vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the steps we&#8217;re taking here &#8212; so that means every individual in the White House, members of the press corps, can do exactly that: either get vaccinated or wear a mask.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the honor system is really about &#8212; I don&#8217;t actually even like that term because I think it&#8217;s confusing.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not saying you&#8217;re intending to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>But the real question is: How will people who are not yet vaccinated protect themselves?&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; Because people who are vaccinated &#8212; what the CDC guidance is saying is that, &#8220;You&#8217;re protected.&#8221;&nbsp; So, people who are not vaccinated &#8212; the guidance is, &#8220;You should wear a mask.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; But the White House is not going to go out of its way to necessarily verify this individual &#8212; or, like, &#8220;I&#8217;ve been vaccinated or not, so she&#8217;s cleared to wear a mask.&#8221;&nbsp; That&#8217;s not the plan.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s not the role we&#8217;re going to play.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, awesome.&nbsp; Just wanted to clarify.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then a quick follow-up on the budget proposal coming out next week.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of things that were not included were very progressive ideas, like prescription drug reform and student debt relief.&nbsp; And you touched on this a little bit earlier &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but I just want to get clarification.&nbsp; A message to progressives who might feel a little bit gypped or let down that, you know, they voted for Biden to get these specific things through in the first 100 days of the first year, and they feel like, well, maybe that&#8217;s not going to be accomplished for them.&nbsp; Is there any message directly to those people?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say &#8212; again, we&#8217;ll roll out the totality of the budget.&nbsp; You&#8217;ll have more paper and factsheets than you know what to do with a week from today. And so I don&#8217;t want to get too far ahead of that.&nbsp;<br><br>But what is important for people to remember is that the President talked about his commitment to lowering the cost of prescription drugs in his joint session address.&nbsp; He remains committed to continuing to make healthcare more affordable and more accessible for Americans.<br><br>Is the totality of everything he wants to accomplish in his presidency done in the first 100 days?&nbsp; Clearly not, because we&#8217;ve passed that period of time.<br><br>And will every single thing he wants to get done in his presidency be reflected in the budget?&nbsp; It won&#8217;t.&nbsp; But that doesn&#8217;t mean he&#8217;s not committed to it, and it doesn&#8217;t mean that he do- &#8212; doesn&#8217;t have a desire to move all of these agenda items forward that he talked about in his joint session address, and that he talked about when he was running for President.<br><br>Go ahead, in the back.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; House Speaker Nancy Pelosi has called for a diplomatic boycott of the 2022 Beijing Olympics.&nbsp; Does President Biden agree with that urging?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Our position hasn&#8217;t changed.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; At all?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Nope.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Human rights and all &#8212; and as much as this administration forcefully defends human rights, and treating people (inaudible) &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are quite outspoken on human rights, the values of the United States in our conversations with the Chinese government and leaders, and any country where we have concerns &#8212; as was clear in the readout that &#8212; from the President&#8217;s call with President Xi, and as has been clear in every engagement we&#8217;ve had with the Chinese leaders.&nbsp; But our position on the Beijing Olympics has not changed.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And a follow-up, if I can.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In light of the Israeli-Palestinian fighting, genocide against the Uyghurs, the plight of the Rohingya, persecution of Christians across the globe &#8212; this is the big question here: Going forward, how is the Biden &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a lot wrapped up.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; administration going to foster international religious freedom?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, there was a lot wrapped up in there.&nbsp; What I will tell you is that, broadly speaking, the President and the administration and the Secretary of State will continue to advocate for freedom of religion, freedom of expression, freedom of media around the world when they have engagements diplomatically, when we have bilateral meetings, through public and private conversations.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And closer to home, finally, we&#8217;ve seen gas prices rising &#8212; this a much different topic, here &#8212; gas prices rising significantly, and we all know that they&#8217;ve hurt poor people &#8212; they hit them the hardest.&nbsp; I mean, every &#8212; every dollar that comes in &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Which is why it&#8217;s so perplexing that some are proposing user fees, but that&#8217;s another topic.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Well, do you want to continue on your &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; you had a question.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; Well, my question is, is: Has the Biden administration considered &#8212; does it have any plan or any sort of action it can take to try to bring down prices or at least somehow make the cost less &#8212; whether it&#8217;s a tax or something to help impoverished people?&nbsp; Otherwise, the money that&#8217;s going to them &#8212; in the form of the Rescue Plan and the other money &#8212; is really money going back out the door to pay for higher gas, isn&#8217;t it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that the President&#8217;s plans, his proposals &#8212; whether it was the American Rescue Plan, his American Jobs Plan, his American Families Plan &#8212; have all been proposed through the prism of what he can do to help working people, help people trying to make ends meet, help people trying to put food on the table.&nbsp; His proposals have helped cut childhood poverty in half by this &#8212; this year.&nbsp; It&#8217;s helped bring &#8212; put 1.5 million people back to work; has helped ensure that families and parents have a little bit of extra assistance so they can cover the cost of childcare.<br><br>So that has been the prism through which he&#8217;s made all of his proposals.<br><br>I have to wrap this up in a minute here.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a quick point of clarification?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did you mean when you said that this &#8212; when it comes to spying on journalists, this DOJ is going to follow the &#8220;Holder model&#8221;?&nbsp; Because Eric Holder was the attorney general when the DOJ was spying on the Associated Press and was obtaining phone records for bureaus and individual journalists.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the question that was asked, which was a good question, was about the &#8212; the records that were taken or seized or whatever &#8212; however you want to characterize it &#8211;during the last administration.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re not going to follow the &#8220;Barr model.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>And I would say our &#8212; I would point you at our Department of Justice to how they will approach that issue.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you said the &#8220;Holder model,&#8221; and Eric Holder did monitor the phone records of journalists.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I would point to the Department of Justice here.&nbsp; This &#8212; all these decisions would be made by our attorney general and the Department of Justice.&nbsp;<br><br>And again, they are going to be meeting with journalists to hear their concerns.&nbsp; And certainly, we will continue to advocate for freedom of press, freedom of expression in the United States, of course, but also around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You got to get the &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; I always &#8212; I don&#8217;t intend &#8212; I unintentionally forget.&nbsp; It&#8217;s my favorite part of the week.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; How are you?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m good.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen, for the opportunity.&nbsp; My name is Andrew Peng.&nbsp; I&#8217;m with the Yappie, a publication, dedicated to tracking Asian American and Pacific Islander activism.&nbsp;<br><br>I have two questions.&nbsp; The first one is on anti-Asian hate.&nbsp; In addition to the COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act that the President signed yesterday, the administration also announced plans back in March to re-establish the White House Initiative on Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders.&nbsp; The White House also said that the President would appoint a permanent director to lead that initiative.<br><br>Do we have any announcements or can we expect an update on an executive order reauthorizing the initiative?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s very nice to meet you.&nbsp; Thanks for all the reporting you do.&nbsp;<br><br>I will first say that reinstating and expanding the White House Initiative on Asian American and Pacific Islanders and ensuring that it is successful is a top priority for the President.&nbsp;<br><br>He is committed to reestablishing the initiative, as he talked about early on in his presidency.&nbsp; We hope to have more on that soon.&nbsp; So, &#8220;soon&#8221; &#8212; coming weeks &#8212; on more specifics and an update.<br><br>As you noted, he signed into law a bipartisan bill &#8212; the COVID Hate Crimes Bill legislation yesterday.&nbsp; First big event here at the White House with bipartisan support.&nbsp; Welcomed people to the White House.&nbsp; That just conveys how important that legislation was to him.&nbsp;<br><br>And he also committed to appointing a senior member of his White House team &#8212; which he has done &#8212; who has a seat at the table both on policy and personnel, to speak to the &#8212; the initiatives that are important to the AAPI community.<br><br>But, hopefully, we&#8217;ll have more soon.&nbsp; Maybe if we we&#8217;re having this conversation next week I&#8217;d have more of an update, but it could be that soon.&nbsp; But it’s very nice &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Awesome.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; to meet you.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us in the briefing room.&nbsp;<br><br>Thanks, everyone, so much.&nbsp; And have a wonderful weekend.&nbsp;<br><br>2:51 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and H.E. Moon Jae-in, President of the Republic of Korea at Press Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/21/remarks-by-president-biden-and-h-e-moon-jae-in-president-of-the-republic-of-korea-at-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 5:55 P.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Please.&#160; Please be seated.&#160; Today, I&#8217;ve been honored to welcome to the White House President Moon.&#160; And I got an opportunity to spend some private time with him, as well as with our delegations.&#160; This is only the second person &#8212; head of state &#8212; second&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>5:55 P.M. EDT<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Please.&nbsp; Please be seated.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I&#8217;ve been honored to welcome to the White House President Moon.&nbsp; And I got an opportunity to spend some private time with him, as well as with our delegations.&nbsp; This is only the second person &#8212; head of state &#8212; second head of state to visit the White House since I&#8217;ve been President.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s been a real joy.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s a reflection of how much we value the 70-year alliance with the Republic of Korea and how essential we know the relationship is &#8212; is to the United States, the future the Indo-Pacific region, and, quite frankly, to the world.<br><br>Today has been particularly special because this afternoon, in addition to our bilateral meetings, President Moon participated in a ceremony, right in this room, that &#8212; awarding the Medal of Honor to a veteran of the Korean War &#8212; a true American hero, Colonel Ralph Puckett, Jr.&nbsp;<br><br>And I want to thank you again, Mr. President, for joining us.&nbsp; It was special.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know that there&#8217;s ever been an award of a Medal of Honor with the head of state of the country where the award was won.&nbsp; It meant a great deal to me and to the family and to our country.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but today has not only been an affirmation of our shared history of sacrifice that binds the Republic of Korea and North &#8212; and the North &#8212; excuse me, and the United States together; it&#8217;s a commitment to expanding cooperation and shaping our shared future in accordance with our democratic values that have made our nations strong and agile and highly competitive in the 21st century economies.<br><br>The Republic of Korea and the United States are both nations built on innovation, and we must both meet the challenges facing us today and look to what is possible for tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>Our partnership is grounded in our ironclad commitment to shared security.&nbsp; Our alliance has long been the linchpin of peace, security, prosperity, and the region growing more prominent and us being together.&nbsp;<br><br>I was grateful that our two nations were able to quickly conclude a new cost-sharing agreement for forces in Korea in March which will benefit both our peoples.&nbsp; And I thank, again, the President for that agreement.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we made important progress on a range of issues.&nbsp; We spoke about the shared approach of the Democratic &#8212; shared approach to the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic in Korea and continuing threat of the DPRK’s nuclear and missile programs.&nbsp;<br><br>My team consulted closely with President Moon’s team throughout the process of our DPRK review, and we both are deeply concerned about the situation.&nbsp;<br><br>Our two nations also share a willingness to engage diplomatically with the DPRK to take pragmatic steps that will reduce tensions as we move toward our ultimate goal of denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I affirm to President Moon that the United States will proceed in close consultation with the Republic of Korea and our strategy and our approach.&nbsp; And to help drive all these efforts, I&#8217;m pleased to announce that Ambassador Sung Kim, a career diplomat and with deep policy expertise, will serve as a U.S. Special Envoy for the DPRK.<br><br>Ambassador Kim &#8212; you&#8217;re here somewhere today &#8212; stand up, will you?&nbsp; Thank you for being willing to do this.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you for taking on this important role.&nbsp; We appreciate it very much.&nbsp;<br><br>The U.S.-ROK partnership also extends beyond the goals of the Peninsula.&nbsp; The address &#8212; they address issues of regional and global concern through stronger cooperation with partners in the region, including the ASEAN, the Quad, and trilateral cooperation with Japan.<br><br>The multilateral cooperation is particularly important to coordinate in the approach to the situation that exists in Burma as we work to pressure the junta to restore democracy for the people of Burma &#8212; and to address issues critical to regional stability, such as maintaining freedom of navigation in the South China Sea and preserving peace and stability across the Taiwan Straits.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, we also discussed ways that the Republic of Korea and the United States will work together to address the challenges of our time, beginning with our efforts to end the COVID-19 pandemic globally.&nbsp;<br><br>We agreed to establish a comprehensive vaccine partnership to expand the manufacture of vaccines that have been approved safe and effective.&nbsp; And we can scale up glo- &#8212; and so we can scale up global vaccine &#8212; vaccine supplies.&nbsp;<br><br>We’ll strengthen our ability to fight the pandemic and respond to future biological threats.&nbsp; When it comes to fighting climate change, the Republic of Korea and the United States are committed to making ambitious 2030 targets aligned with the effort to achieve net-zero greenhouse gas emissions no later than 2050.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;re going to work together both to mobilize climate finance for developing countries and to make sure that international financing is aligned to promote our climate goals.&nbsp;<br><br>We also talked about how to harness our nation&#8217;s technological advantages to ensure the Republic of Korea and the United States are cooperating to shape &#8212; to shape emerging technologies around our shared value system.&nbsp;<br><br>This includes everything from strengthening our cybersecurity to deepening our cooperation to build out an open secure G5 network &#8212; 5G network, I should say.&nbsp; I&#8217;m talking about the G5, that’s another organization.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m thinking organization, Mr. President &#8212; to secure the 5G networks.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;m particularly gratified that so many leading South Korean companies see the benefits of investing in the United States, including this morning&#8217;s announcement of more than $25 billion in new investments from Samsung, Hyundai, SK, and LG.&nbsp;<br><br>I understand the executives of those companies are here.&nbsp; Would you please stand up?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; And I think we&#8217;ll do great work together.&nbsp;<br><br>These new investments are going to create thousands of good-paying jobs and jobs of the future right here in the United States.&nbsp; And they’re going to help fortify and secure the supply chains for things like semiconductors and electric batteries.<br><br>I know, as I said, that the CEOs made the effort not only to do this, but to be here today.&nbsp; And again, I thank them for being here.&nbsp; I thank you for making the investments in our future and yours.<br><br>Finally, I want to note that yesterday I had the honor of signing into law the COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act to help Americans of Asian descent from having to live in fear just walking down the streets of the United States.&nbsp; Quite frankly, I’ve been ashamed &#8212; ashamed at the way some Americans have responded.&nbsp;<br><br>And there’s a long history in this country of contributions of Asian Americans being overlooked, forgotten, and ignored.&nbsp;<br><br>And I affirmed to President Moon today what I said yesterday: that we&#8217;re committing and we’re going to stay committed to stopping the hatred based on this bias.&nbsp; I promise you.<br><br>Our peoples share a long history.&nbsp; Our soldiers have fought alongside one another.&nbsp; Our scientists work side by side in both our countries.&nbsp; Our students study together, share ideas, and seed new opportunities for future collaboration.&nbsp;<br><br>And our people &#8212; our people-to-people and cultural connections are only growing.&nbsp; And K-Pop fans are universal.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I can tell those who laughed know what I’m talking about.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Well, anyway, I’ll get back to that later.&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>A Korean actress took home an Oscar for Supporting Actress this year, following up on the four Oscar wins for the movie “Parasite” last year.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And so, our two countries &#8212; our two nations have the tools<br>and the deep connections that we need to make even stronger alliances with stronger cooperation.&nbsp;<br><br>And I want to thank you again for the meetings today, Mr. President, particularly our long, private meeting.&nbsp; I appreciated that a great deal.&nbsp;<br><br>And I’m looking forward to working closely with you and your team as we expand and strengthen our efforts to shape the future together.&nbsp; And I mean that literally &#8212; to shape the future together.&nbsp; So, thank you.<br><br>Mr. President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT MOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Honorable President Biden, Madam Vice President, I extend my deepest gratitude to you for your special hospitality and welcome.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, leaders and delegates of Korea and the United States met each other&#8217;s eye and had a dialogue.&nbsp; For the peoples of our two nations, this will give them hope for recovery from COVID-19, as well as a meaningful gift for celebrating the 139th anniversary of our diplomatic relations.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden and I had an awarding ceremony for the Medal of Honor to the Korean War veteran, a one-on-one meeting, as well as an expanded summit.&nbsp; For many hours together, we&#8217;ve had a very frank dialogue like old friends.&nbsp;<br><br>As regards to the promotion of democracy, inclusive growth, the strengthening of the middle class, climate change response, as well as many other areas &#8212; two of us were able to see for ourselves that we had common interests and commitments.&nbsp; In particular, we reaffirmed the strength of the ROK-U.S. alliance and confirmed the common vision for developing it into an even stronger one.<br><br>During my visit this time, the trust that has been built up between President Biden and I will foster a deeper friendship between our two peoples and lay a firm foundation that will undergird the sustainable development of the ROK-U.S. alliance, and I say this with confidence.&nbsp;<br><br>The most urgent common task that our two countries must undertake is achieving complete denuclearization and permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp;<br><br>Recently, the Biden administration concluded its DPRK policy review.&nbsp; Building on past agreements, including the Singapore joint statement, while taking a calibrated and practical approach to seeking diplomacy with North Korea is indeed a welcome direction of the Biden administration&#8217;s North Korea policy.&nbsp; During the course of the review, our two countries closely coordinated with each other in lockstep, which I note with much appreciation.<br><br>Moreover, I welcome President Biden&#8217;s appointment of Ambassador Sung Kim as Special Representative for North Korea Policy.&nbsp; This reflects the firm commitment of the U.S. for exploring diplomacy and its readiness for dialogue with North Korea.&nbsp; I have high expectations, all the more, as such a man of high caliber with expertise in the Korean Peninsula issues has been appointed.<br><br>President Biden and I discussed the dialogues based on commitments made between the two Koreas and between the U.S. and North Korea are essential for making a peaceful Korean Peninsula.&nbsp; This is the belief that we were able to reaffirm.<br><br>Moreover, President Biden also expressed his support for the inter-Korean dialogue and cooperation.&nbsp; Under close cooperation with the U.S., we will work to facilitate progress in inter-Korean relations so as to achieve a virtuous cycle with U.S.-DPRK dialogue.&nbsp;<br><br>Moving forward as well, Korea and the United States will continue close communication while exploring our North Korea approach through dialogue and diplomacy.&nbsp; On that, I expect a positive response from North Korea.<br><br>When strong security is firmly in place, we can preserve and make peace.&nbsp; Two of us agreed to further reinforce our combined defense posture and reaffirmed our commitment to a conditions-based transition to wartime operational control.&nbsp;<br><br>It is also with pleasure that I deliver the news on the termination of the revised missile guidelines.&nbsp; The signing of ROK-U.S. Special Measures Agreement on burden sharing in the early days of the Biden administration displays for the world the robustness of our alliance as a symbolic and practical measure.<br><br>Today at the summit, President Biden and I decided to expand our cooperation in new emerging areas that are relevant for the changing times and landscape.&nbsp;<br><br>First, to surmount COVID-19, our most urgent task, we pledged to pull our strength together.&nbsp; America&#8217;s advanced technologies and Korea&#8217;s production capabilities will be married to establish a comprehensive KORUS Global Vaccine Partnership.&nbsp; Collaboration between our two countries will boost global vaccine supply and contribute to accelerating a complete ending of COVID-19 through the Global Health Security Agenda, which aims to enhance infectious disease response capability.&nbsp; Multilateral cooperation will be pursued as well.<br><br>Under this broad framework of vaccine cooperation, illustrating the robust ROK-U.S. alliance, an important announcement was made: President Biden pledged to supply vaccines to Korean servicemen.&nbsp; I thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; This announcement of the U.S., I believe, extends the ROK-U.S. alliance to the field of health in a meaningful measure.&nbsp;<br><br>Second, from semiconductors to EV batteries, pharmaceuticals to other cutting-edge manufacturing technology sectors, in an effort to build a secure supply chains, we&#8217;ve committed to work in close concert.&nbsp; Digital transformation is accelerating and the areas of cutting-edge emerging technologies are gaining greater importance.&nbsp;<br><br>Korea and the U.S., in response to a post-COVID-19 era, plan to strengthen our cooperation in civil space exploring &#8212; exploration, 6G, and green energy to secure global competitiveness.&nbsp;<br><br>Furthermore, to join the advance into overseas nuclear power plant markets, we decided to bolster our partnership.&nbsp;<br><br>Third, in a bid to address climate change, we will further solidify coordination between our two countries.&nbsp; Our two nations are already spearheading global cooperation in climate change response.<br><br>Last April, the U.S. hosted a Leaders Summit on Climate successfully.&nbsp; Korea, for its part, next week, is hosting P4G Seoul Summit, once again trying to build the international community&#8217;s collective will for climate change response.<br><br>President Biden will participate in the P4G Seoul Summit next week virtually.&nbsp; I welcome his participation, which will certainly help us catalyze the international community to come together.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden and I participated in the ceremony for awarding a Medal of Honor to a Korean War veteran, Colonel Ralph Puckett, Jr.&nbsp; Based on the ROK-U.S. alliance, rooted in the noble sacrifices of our heroes, our two nations will usher in a new future together without a doubt.<br><br>Today&#8217;s meetings between President Biden and myself, and between the U.S. and Korea, will mark another milestone for bilateral cooperation towards a new era.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden has extended such warm hosp- &#8212; hospitality and I express my deepest gratitude once again.&nbsp; I look forward to our frequent communication and continued close coord- &#8212; consultation.&nbsp;<br><br>Last but not least, yesterday Israel and Hamas agreed on a ceasefire, which is indeed a relief.&nbsp; I appreciate President Biden&#8217;s hard work and leadership in this regard.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Well, first question, I&#8217;m told, is MaryAlice <s>Parker</s> [Parks] of ABC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp; What is your message to Democrats who want you to be more confrontational with Israel, and &#8212; and, specifically, to those that are saying that there should be an end to arm sales?&nbsp; I mean, do you recognize that there&#8217;s been a shift, an evolution in your party, Mr. President, in the last 20 years on this issue?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; There &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I have a question for President Moon, but I can wait, or I can ask that now.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; There is no shift in my commitment and the commitment to the security of Israel, period.&nbsp; No shift.&nbsp; Not at all.&nbsp;<br><br>But I’ll tell you what there is a shift in: The shift is that we have to &#8212; we still need a two-state solution.&nbsp; It is the only answer.&nbsp; The only answer.&nbsp;<br><br>And what I am convinced of, is that we can now move &#8212; as I had &#8212; did even before, when I was able to negotiate &#8212; well, I shouldn&#8217;t &#8212; before the ceasefire was negotiated, that I made it clear that &#8212; and I spoke with President Abbas &#8212; we were &#8212; we&#8217;re going to make sure that we are going to provide for security in the West Bank.&nbsp; And we &#8212; we renewed the security commitment as well as economic commitment to the people on the West Bank.&nbsp;<br><br>I also indicated to the Israelis that I thought it was very important that they stop, in Jerusalem, this inner-communal fighting that has extremes on both sides.&nbsp; It has to end.&nbsp; It has to end.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;m prepared to put together &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to attempt to put together a major package, with other nations who share our view, to rebuild the homes and &#8212; without reengaging &#8212; without providing Hamas the opportunity to rebuild their weapon systems &#8212; rebuild the Gaza &#8212; rebuild Gaza.&nbsp; And they need the help, and I&#8217;m committed to get that done.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, I don&#8217;t &#8212; and I think that, you know, my party still supports Israel.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s get something straight here: Until the region says, unequivocally, they acknowledge the right of Israel to exist as an independent Jewish state, there will be no peace.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a question to President Moon?&nbsp; I &#8212; I&#8217;m curious if the two of you have offered any assurances, behind the scenes, to Taiwan, and if President Biden has &#8212; has pushed you to take a tougher stance when it comes to China&#8217;s posture towards Taiwa- &#8212; Taiwan.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Good luck.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>PRESIDENT MOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Well, fortunately, there wasn&#8217;t such pressure.&nbsp; But, as for peace and stability in the Taiwan Strait, we agreed how important that region is, especially considering the special characteristics between China and Taiwan.&nbsp; We decided to work more closely on this matter going forward.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; You can (inaudible).<br><br>PRESIDENT MOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; So, we have a question from a Korean journalist this over here.&nbsp; Yes, two from the left.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you for giving me this opportunity.&nbsp; I am&nbsp;Kang from Yonhap News&nbsp;&#8212; Yonhap News.<br><br>I have a question to both of the Presidents here.&nbsp; As was mentioned by the former journalist, I understand that the Israel and Palestine issues are very important, but North Korea’s nuclear issues is equally important.&nbsp; On your to-do list, what&#8217;s the number that&#8217;s given to the North Korean nuclear issue on your priority list, Mr. &#8212; President Biden?<br><br>And also, to M- &#8212; President Moon, in terms of your roadmap for resolving the nuclear issue in North Korea, I want to &#8212; I want to understand whether your time schedule actually matches and is equal to one another in terms of resolving the nuclear issues on the Korean Peninsula.<br><br>PRESIDENT MOON:&nbsp; So, to begin, under the new Biden administration, the DPRK policy review has been completed in a rather fast period of time. That means that the Biden administration puts priority on its North Korea policy among its diplomatic tasks.<br><br>And also, in terms of reviewing its DPRK policy, there was a very close coordination, as well as consultations, between the United States and the Republic of Korea.&nbsp; So the principle of the negotiations towards North Korea has already been announced by the U.S. government.&nbsp; A very calibrated, practical, gradual, step-by-step manner, and very flexible &#8212; that is the approach that the current administration is aiming to adopt.&nbsp; So that is the common understanding that we have with the United States and that we&#8217;re going to continue to work forward on this.&nbsp;<br><br>And in terms of the timeline for the denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula, there aren&#8217;t any differences in terms of how we think about this &#8212; no differences in terms of our opinions.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I agree with what the President just said.&nbsp; Our goal is and remains complete denuclearization of the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp; We want to make practical progress and increase security in the United States &#8212; for the United States and our allies.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, we closely studied what others have tried, and &#8212; what worked and what hasn&#8217;t worked.&nbsp; And, you know, under &#8212; we&#8217;re under no illusions how difficult this is &#8212; none whatsoever.&nbsp; And the past four administrations have not achieved the objective.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an incredibly difficult objective.<br><br>As we move forward, we&#8217;re going to stay in very close coordination with our friends and our partners in the region, including President Moon.&nbsp; And we fully recognize that this is about our collective security in the Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp; And so &#8212; but total denuclearization is our objective and remains so.<br><br>Well, I get the next question, huh?&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to ask the press a question, if I may.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Nancy Cordes, CBS.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you very much, Mr. President.&nbsp; I have one question about North Korea and one question about Israel.&nbsp;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; We&#8217;ve changed this “one question” thing, haven’t we?&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two foreign policy questions.&nbsp;<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Okay.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You have said in the past that you would not meet with Kim Jong Un, the leader of North Korea, without certain preconditions.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What are those preconditions?&nbsp; And do you believe he would ever be able to meet them?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, what I never do is I never make a judgment what a man or woman is going to do or not do based on what they said.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see.&nbsp; If he made any commitment, then I would meet with him.&nbsp; And if there was a commitment on which we met &#8212; and the commitment has to be that there&#8217;s discussion about his nuclear arsenal, and if it&#8217;s merely an &#8212; a means by which how do we deescalate what they&#8217;re doing.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, if that was the case, I would not meet unless there was some outline made that my Secretary of State and others would have negotiated as to how we would proceed.&nbsp;<br><br>But what I would not do is I would not do what had been done in the recent past.&nbsp; I would not give him all that he&#8217;s looking for is: national &#8212; international recognition as legitimate and &#8212; and say &#8212; and give them what allowed him to move in the direction of appearing to be more &#8212; how can I say it? &#8212; more serious about what he wasn&#8217;t at all serious about.<br><br>I&#8217;d have to know specifics.&nbsp; But the idea of never meeting with North Korea &#8212; I would make sure that my team had met with his count- &#8212; my &#8212; their counterparts and I know exactly what we&#8217;re meeting on.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, in the wake of all of your conversations this week, what is your relationship like now with Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu?&nbsp; Do you have certain expectations that he will bolster the rights of the Palestinian people in some way?&nbsp; And if so, did you convey that to him in your conversations?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; One of the reasons why we were able to get the ceasefire in 11 days, they didn&#8217;t do what other people have done: I don&#8217;t talk about what I tell people in private.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t talk about what we negotiate in private.&nbsp;<br><br>What I can assure you, though, is that, the last time, it took 56 days and then 6 months to get a ceasefire.&nbsp; I&#8217;m praying the ceasefire will hold.&nbsp; I take Bibi Netanyahu &#8212; when he gives me his word, I take him at his word.&nbsp; He&#8217;s never broken his word to me.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but what I&#8217;ve made clear is that it’s essential &#8212; it&#8217;s essential that the Palestinians in &#8212; on the West Bank be secured, that Abbas be recognized as a leader of the Palestinian people, which he is.&nbsp; Hamas is a terrorist organization; we&#8217;ve recognized that.&nbsp; But that doesn&#8217;t mean we should not be in Gaza, rebuilding Gaza for all those innocent people who in fact have been hurt and &#8212; and had been collateral damage, including loss of homes and a whole range of other things &#8212; as well as insisting that Israeli citizens, whether they be Arab or Jew, are treated equally as Israeli citizens.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what was going on in &#8212; in Jerusalem.&nbsp;<br><br>And so that has to come to an end.&nbsp; And Bibi know &#8212; the Prime Minister knows my views and &#8212; but the commitment that was given had &#8212; was immediately kept.&nbsp; I &#8212; from the very beginning, I told him what our objective was: that there needed to be a ceasefire.&nbsp; And he, in fact, kept his commitment in the timeframe in which he said he would do it.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, I wasn&#8217;t the only one that spoke to him.&nbsp; We had &#8212; I look down here &#8212; every major player on my team &#8212; from the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, all the way down the line, and our national security guys were in constant contact with their counterparts in Israel, in Egypt, and throughout the Middle East.&nbsp;<br><br>This was not something that was just done with a casual conversation between myself and Bibi.&nbsp; I have &#8212; presumptuous of me to say this but, Mr. President &#8212; but I think I&#8217;ve got a great team.&nbsp;<br><br>And the res- &#8212; and I spent a lot of time with Al Sisi on the phone in &#8212; in Egypt.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve done a commendable job of bringing Hamas to the table and getting them to agree to a ceasefire as well.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Is that it?&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s one more question over here.<br><br>PRESIDENT MOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; A lady?&nbsp; Our ladies do not raise their hands?&nbsp; Do we not have female journalists from Korea?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; I&#8217;m from Korea Herald.&nbsp; My name is Lee Ji-yoon.&nbsp; The Korean people are very curious about vaccines, and they&#8217;re waiting for the good news regarding vaccine.&nbsp; I understand that you&#8217;ve had a lot of discussions with President Biden regarding vaccine, and I wonder whether you have any good news to deliver to the people of Korea.&nbsp; And has there been any meaningful achievement that you want to go into the details of?<br><br>PRESIDENT MOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Regarding vaccine cooperation, you can read the joint statements and also the remarks that were issued as press release today.&nbsp;<br><br>But to emphasize it once again, between the U.S. and Korea for vaccine cooperation, there will be a comprehensive partnership to be established between our two nations, and there has been an agreement between our two sides on that.&nbsp;<br><br>The U.S. has the ability to develop vaccines and Korean companies have the capacity to produce biomedicine.&nbsp; And we are going to combine those capabilities so that we can boost vaccine supply, so that we can accelerate the rollout of vaccines to the entire world, especially in the Indo-Pacific region.&nbsp; For supplying vaccines to that region, I believe that we&#8217;ll be able to make a contribution in that regard.&nbsp;<br><br>And in that process, Korea, in my opinion, will get some help in stabilizing our vaccine supply.&nbsp; And at the same time, for the sake of the ROK-U.S. alliance, President Biden decided to provide vaccines to the servicemen in Korea as soon as the U.S. is ready.&nbsp; I understand there will be an announcement to be made by the U.S. side.<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; By the way, I &#8212; I can just prematurely make that.&nbsp; And we’re going &#8212; there are 550,000 Korean soldiers, sailors, airmen who work in close contact with American forces in Korea.&nbsp; We’ll provide full vaccinations for all 550,000 of those Korean forces engaging with American forces on a regular basis &#8212; both for their sake, as well as the sake of the American forces.<br><br>In addition to that, we&#8217;ve talked about the ability to have vaccines produced with our &#8212; working with &#8212; and this is in the offing &#8212; working with one of the major vaccine producers in the United States and to &#8212; where Korea is incredibly sophisticated.&nbsp; And with the help of that particular &#8212; that &#8212; that particular company, we’ll be able to make significant numbers of vaccines for themselves.<br><br>And lastly, it is my hope and expectation &#8212; I cannot commit to it because we don&#8217;t know for certain &#8212; but we think that, over the remainder of 2021, we&#8217;re &#8212; we’re going to be able to vaccinate every American.&nbsp; We have enough &#8212; we have enough vaccine to vaccinate every American &#8212; period &#8212; right now.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to be able to do that by the mid-summer, and we&#8217;re going to continue to get more people to engage in seeking the vaccine.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe &#8212; I never have believed that there&#8217;s a large percentage of Americans who will not take the vaccine.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re doing very imaginative things, and the states are, to get people to show up and have the vaccine.<br><br>But we believe &#8212; we believe that, between the second half of 2021 and going in through 2022, we can produce as many as another billion doses of vaccine.&nbsp; Because it&#8217;s not just &#8212; and this is what I like about this President &#8212; he&#8217;s not just talking about it, any more than I&#8217;m just talking about the United States or just Korea; he&#8217;s talking about the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; He&#8217;s talking about the world.&nbsp;<br><br>We, with advanced capabilities, have an obligation to do everything we can to provide for protection of the entire world.&nbsp;&nbsp; I know that is an awfully, awfully, awfully ambitious proposal, but I think the nations that have that capacity are going to be continuing to work toward getting that done.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Time for one more, Mr. President?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; If you&#8217;re not asking me a mean one like you usually do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s something interesting, I think, that has not come up.&nbsp; President Obama says that there is footage and records of objects in the skies &#8212; these unidentified aerial phenomenon &#8212; and he says we don&#8217;t know exactly what they are.&nbsp; What do you think that it is?<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I would ask him again.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Come on, (inaudible), let&#8217;s go.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 6:29 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and President Moon Jae-in of the Republic of Korea Before Bilateral Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/21/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-moon-jae-in-of-the-republic-of-korea-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18195</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 3:55 P.M. EDT PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; I am honored to have President Moon here at the White House today for the second foreign leader visit, head-of-state visit in my presidency.&#160; The United States and the Republic of Korea are allies with a long history of shared sacrifice.&#160; And in a personal note, I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>3:55 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I am honored to have President Moon here at the White House today for the second foreign leader visit, head-of-state visit in my presidency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States and the Republic of Korea are allies with a long history of shared sacrifice.&nbsp; And in a personal note, I want to thank the President for being with me today as I had the great honor of presenting the Congressional Medal of Honor to a Ranger in his mid-90s who was &#8212; showed incredible acts of valor and bravery in Korea during the Korean War.&nbsp; The President was kind enough to come spend the entire time there and personally congratulate our honoree.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I also want to point out that our history of shared sacrifice and our cooperation is vital to maintaining peace and stability in a critical region of the world.&nbsp; President Moon and I and our teams have had good meetings addressing our shared agenda.&nbsp; We had a private meeting in which my staff kept coming out and saying, “You&#8217;re over time.&nbsp; You&#8217;re over time.”&nbsp; But I enjoyed our meeting so much that we caused us to move everything back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I look forward to continuing our discussion today here and in growing the U.S.-ROK relationship further as we take on new challenges and we take them on together.</p>



<p>Mr. President, the floor is yours.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT MOON:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; I’d like to express my deep gratitude to President Biden and the American people for extending such a warm hospitality to me and my delegation.&nbsp; And my congratulations on how the U.S. is becoming an example of the &#8212; for the world as it succeeds in overcoming COVID-19, achieving economic recovery, and uniting the nation under President Biden&#8217;s leadership.</p>



<p><a>Korea and the U.S. are strong allies, forged more than 70 years ago.&nbsp; America is our everlasting friend who helped us and led us in our times of direst need.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>And I&#8217;m very pleased to visit the U.S. as my first overseas trip destination since the spread of COVID-19 and meet President Biden and his new team.</p>



<p>Even in the midst of COVID-19 crisis, our two countries left the door open to each other, helped with each other&#8217;s fight against the virus, and kept our people and goods flow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we are seeing increasing cases of successful cooperation between our two countries&#8217; businesses and industries that will shape the post-COVID-19 era, such as semiconductors, batteries, and communication.&nbsp; An expanding cooperation between the U.S. &#8212; a center of global business &#8212; and Korea &#8212; a rising economic hub of East Asia &#8212; will be a breakthrough in economic recovery for not only the two countries, but the entire world.</p>



<p><a>In previous meetings with President Biden, we affirmed our joint commitment to strengthening the ROK-U.S. alliance and bringing peace on the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp; I believe our peoples will be delighted to hear this a day shy of our 139th anniversary of our diplomatic relations.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>And Korea will closely work with the U.S. to achieve complete denuclearization and establish permanent peace on the Korean Peninsula.</p>



<p>The world is welcoming America&#8217;s return and keeping their hopes high for America&#8217;s leaders to do more than ever before.&nbsp; President Biden, himself, also underscored the importance of building back better and expressed his willingness to resolve common challenges of humanity with the power of example.</p>



<p>Although tricky challenges lie ahead of us, as allies that share core values, our two countries will actively work together to address global challenges such as COVID-19, economic recovery, and climate change.&nbsp; And we will usher in a new era.</p>



<p>Following our meeting today, I look forward to welcoming President Biden again in Seoul, the Republic of Korea, in not-too-distant future.&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you think the ceasefire will hold in Israel?</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll have time to answer your questions later.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>4:03 P.M. EDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Maritime Day, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/21/a-proclamation-on-national-maritime-day-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:18:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18183</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the first days of our Republic, America has been a proud maritime Nation. &#160;To this day, the United States Merchant Marine is a pillar of our country&#8217;s prosperity, playing a vital role in the maintenance of our economic and national security. &#160;Through every period of peace and war, our merchant mariners have been dedicated&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Since the first days of our Republic, America has been a proud maritime Nation. &nbsp;To this day, the United States Merchant Marine is a pillar of our country&#8217;s prosperity, playing a vital role in the maintenance of our economic and national security. &nbsp;Through every period of peace and war, our merchant mariners have been dedicated to protecting our freedom and promoting commerce. &nbsp;On National Maritime Day, we honor the steadfast commitment and sacrifices of the men and women who serve in the United States Merchant Marine, and recognize their essential role in safeguarding and strengthening our Nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Called the &#8220;fourth arm of defense&#8221; by President Franklin D. Roosevelt during World War II, the Merchant Marine established itself as a cornerstone of sealift support for our Armed Forces, sailing through theaters of war to deliver troops and supplies while keeping vital ocean supply lines operating. &nbsp;The perseverance and dedication of the Merchant Marine contributed to the Allied victory even as they suffered one of the highest casualty rates of any of our military services.</p>



<p>Our merchant mariners also play a critical role in times of peace.&nbsp; They ensure our economic security by keeping our coastal and inland waterways open to trade, while United States-flagged ships operated by American merchant mariners transport goods across our country and all over the world. &nbsp;United States maritime freight operations helped support $5.4&nbsp;trillion of economic activity among the many non-maritime industries that depend on the Merchant Marine for access to world markets. &nbsp;This movement of goods domestically and internationally continues to ensure America&#8217;s economic competitiveness throughout the world &#8212; growing jobs and supporting businesses of all sizes here at home.</p>



<p>Our merchant mariners are also critical to extending United States support and assistance to foreign nations and local communities hit hard by natural disasters and devastating crises. &nbsp;Even in the midst of a worldwide pandemic, these brave men and women have overcome seemingly insurmountable obstacles to fulfill their mission while keeping our Nation&#8217;s supply chains running. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The operation of the United States-flagged fleet is essential in contributing to the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions and landside congestion, helping provide current and future generations with a more sustainable means of freight transportation. &nbsp;The industry is also working to develop and implement new technologies to continue reducing emissions &#8212; an effort my Administration is supporting through new international partnerships.</p>



<p>The maritime industry has long provided opportunity for Americans of all backgrounds &#8212; and the Merchant Marine continues to advance a more equitable industry in which barriers to entry and advancement are eliminated.</p>



<p>On this National Maritime Day, we honor the brave merchant mariners who provide critical support to our troops stationed in&nbsp;warzones, and who are essential to our Nation&#8217;s economic success. &nbsp;Recognizing the contributions of our merchant mariners, my Administration strongly supports protecting the Jones Act &#8212; the cornerstone of our domestic maritime industry. &nbsp;We must protect those who protect our country.</p>



<p>The Congress, by a joint resolution approved May 20, 1933, has designated May 22 of each year as &#8220;National Maritime Day&#8221; to commemorate the first transoceanic voyage by a steamship in 1819 by the S.S. Savannah.&nbsp; By this resolution, the Congress has authorized and requested the President to issue annually a proclamation calling for its appropriate observance.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR<em>.</em>,&nbsp;President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 22, 2021, as National Maritime Day.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to observe this day and to celebrate with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/05/21/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-38/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18165</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  11:03 A.M. EDT ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&#160; Good morning.&#160; Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Fauci will provide an update on the latest science, and Dr. Murthy will provide an update on our efforts to build vaccine confidence.&#160; Here’s how I want to start though: I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference </p>



<p>11:03 A.M. EDT<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Fauci will provide an update on the latest science, and Dr. Murthy will provide an update on our efforts to build vaccine confidence.&nbsp;<br><br>Here’s how I want to start though: I want to discuss what some businesses who cater to young people are doing to assist with the vaccination efforts.<br><br>Scores of businesses and organizations have responded to the President&#8217;s call to action to volunteer their services and help the American people to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Over the next few weeks, we&#8217;ll be highlighting a number of outside initiatives to provide incentives for people to get vaccinated.&nbsp; We believe that it&#8217;s particularly important to reach young people where they are in the effort to get them vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>We do know that in addition to schooling, financial loss, stress levels, the pandemic has also had a negative impact on young people&#8217;s social lives.&nbsp;<br><br>Social distancing and dating were always a bit of a challenging combination.&nbsp; So today, dating sites like Bumble, Tinder, Hinge, Match, OkCupid, BLK, Chispa, Plenty of Fish, and Badoo are announcing a series of features to encourage vaccinations and help people with that univer- &#8212; help people meet people who have that universally attractive quality: They&#8217;ve been vaccinated against COVID-19.<br><br>These sites cater to over 50 million people in the U.S. and are some of the world&#8217;s biggest nongaming apps.<br><br>Here&#8217;s one for you: According to one of the sites, OKCupid, the people who display their vaccination status are 14 percent more likely to get a match.&nbsp; We have finally found the one thing that makes us all more attractive: a vaccination.<br><br>These dating apps will now allow vaccinated people to display badges which show their vaccination status, filter specifically to see only people who are vaccinated, and offer premium content &#8212; details of which I cannot get into, but apparently, they include things like boosts and super swipes.&nbsp; The apps will also help people locate places to get vaccinated.<br><br>Alright, got through that.&nbsp;<br><br>Today also happens to be our &#8220;Digital Day of Action.&#8221;&nbsp; The White House and others, including Michelle Obama, will be highlighting the Vaccines.gov website and 438829 text line throughout the day.<br><br>Now it&#8217;s been four months since President Biden&#8217;s first full day of office.&nbsp; Things are substantially better than they were four months ago when we were losing thousands of Americans each day and people were waiting weeks or more to get vaccinated, usually not even knowing where or when it would happen.<br><br>Today, more than 125 million Americans are fully vaccinated.&nbsp; Those Americans who have been vaccinated are at much lower risk and have more of their lives back.&nbsp; They&#8217;re able to do most things mask free and with less reason to socially distance.&nbsp; Tens of millions more, adding up to more than 60 percent of the adult population, are at least partially vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>The impact has been everything we could have hoped for, given the power of vaccines.&nbsp; Across the country, cases of COVID-19, serious illness, and loss of life are all down dramatically from when we arrived.&nbsp; And they can be brought down even further, and the risk of a future wave in your community significantly reduced, if we keep up the pace of vaccinations.<br><br>Many Americans have still not gotten vaccinated &#8212; most of them younger, many of them not opposed to vaccination; they simply haven&#8217;t prioritized it.&nbsp; It has never been easier.&nbsp;<br><br>Starting Monday, when you text to 438829, not only will you instantly see where vaccines near you are available, you will also be offered a free ride there and back, more employers are offering paid time off to get vaccinated, and, as we discussed today, there are clear benefits to your social life.&nbsp;<br><br>Most importantly, you&#8217;ll be protected from a virus which is still racing around the world.<br><br>I will now hand it over to Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; I&#8217;m pleased to be back with you today.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.&nbsp;<br><br>Yesterday, CDC reported a little over 27,850 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is about 27,700 cases per day.&nbsp; This represents yet another decrease of more than 19 percent from the prior seven-day average and also marks the second day in a row where our seven-day average is less than 30,000 cases per day.&nbsp; The last time the seven-day average of cases per day was this low was June 18th, 2020.&nbsp;<br><br>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is slightly over 3,400, a decrease of almost 15 percent from the previous seven-day period and another positive trend.<br><br>And the seven-day average of daily deaths has also declined to a new low of 498 per day.<br><br>At the start of each briefing over the past few weeks, I&#8217;ve shared with you a snapshot of the data and, more recently, the encouraging decreases in cases, hospitalizations, and deaths.&nbsp; As each week passes and as we continue to see progress, these data give me hope.&nbsp;<br><br>I also know that these snapshots are hard to put into the context after 16 months of reviewing them.&nbsp; In isolation, each data point does not tell the full story of what we are seeing across the country.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I&#8217;d like to give you a bit of a deeper dive into the data and to share with you ways you can understand the progress your community is making.<br><br>Each day, CDC, in collaboration with partners across the government, releases a Community Profile Report, and updates our county-level data on COVID Data Tracker.&nbsp;<br><br>When we look at COVID case incidents at county level, we see major decreases.&nbsp; As I mentioned at the start of my remarks, we have seen a 20 percent decrease in the seven-day average of cases across the country, and we have seen some counties across the country have had an even greater decrease, including decreases of 25 percent in more &#8212; or more in just the past week.&nbsp;<br><br>Each week, we also see a release of an assessment of county-level transmission risk, taking into account rate &#8212; COVID rates and COVID-19 test characteristics.&nbsp; And we have used this transmission risk for many of our CDC guidance materials &#8212; for example, our school guidance.&nbsp;<br><br>Importantly, over the past month, there has been a steady decline in the number of counties in the United States with a high risk of community transmission.&nbsp; And more and more counties are moving to low or moderate transmission categories.&nbsp;<br><br>We now have 307 counties, or 10 percent of the entire U.S., in which we would characterize having low transmission.&nbsp; And there are 1,183 counties, or 37 percent of all U.S. counties, in the moderate transmission category, which we define as less than 50 cases per 100,000 in the last seven days.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, if you look at this new slide up, I want to show you two maps of our country: one from January and one from this week.<br><br>CDC uses data on cases and county transmission to help us understand areas across the country where we may have concern for emerging or sustained outbreaks and where things have markedly improved, and also to understand the burden of infection at the local level, because we recognize that these decisions have to be made locally.&nbsp;<br><br>When we look across the country, our areas of high or moderate burden &#8212; indicated by red and pink respectively &#8212; are shrinking.&nbsp; And areas with low burden of disease &#8212; indicated by light green &#8212; are markedly increasing.&nbsp; Many of the areas where previous high and moderate burden are now resolving and are highlighted on blue in this map.&nbsp;<br><br>The map on the right demonstrates our national landscape that things are improving.&nbsp; And we are seeing this week after week and with more and more green over time.&nbsp;<br><br>These data are telling us a story: As more and more people roll up their sleeves and get vaccinated, the number of cases and the level of community risk is decreasing.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank everyone who has done their part to bring us where we are today, with more than 60 percent of Americans 18 and older having received at least one dose and being on their way to full vaccination, and 126.6 million Americans who are fully vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>The progress in these data are so encouraging to me and, I hope, encouraging to you.&nbsp;<br><br>And I know our work here is not done.&nbsp; We still have many more people to get vaccinated.&nbsp; I encourage everyone who is not yet fully vaccinated to visit Vaccine.gov and find a location to get your first or second shot.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to spend the next couple of minutes just underscoring and emphasizing the reasons why Dr. Walensky was able to show you such promising data, and that is the real-world effectiveness of the COVID-19 vaccine.&nbsp; And bringing you up to date on some of the data that confirms the things that we&#8217;ve been telling you over the last several press briefings.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>This is an MMWR from the CDC, which is looking both at the Pfizer-BioNTech and the Moderna vaccine among healthcare personnel at 33 sites in the United States.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, if you look at the effectiveness in the real-world setting &#8212; again, right at the point that we saw with the clinical trials &#8212; usually real-world settings have less of an efficacy than in the trials, as I’ve mentioned many times.&nbsp; Not so here &#8212; 94 percent against symptomatic disease.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>If you look at a very interesting study that came out two days ago in the New England Journal of Medicine looking at the incidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in nursing home residents in those who are either vaccinated or unvaccinated, we see a very interesting phenomenon.<br><br>Among the 13,000 residents who were vaccinated who received two doses, there was a 1 percent infection within 0 to 14 days of the second dose, and practically no infections &#8212; namely, 0.3 percent &#8212; after 14 days.&nbsp;<br><br>Note that 80 percent of the cases were asymptomatic among vaccinated individuals &#8212; something that we have seen in other situations.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>On the other side of the coin are those in the same study who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; If you look at the infection rate of those individuals within 0 to 14 days after the first clinic, they were 4.3 percent compared to the very small 1 percent in the previous slide, and they&#8217;re 0.3 percent if you waited more than 42 days.&nbsp; This is a reflection of what is likely a mini version, within the nursing home setting, of herd immunity.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>And then another multi-state Mayo Clinic Health System study where you look at adenovirus vector, namely the J&amp;J.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been speaking to you up to now about the mRNAs.&nbsp; So, after at least two weeks of follow-up, the vaccine effectiveness, again, was even greater in the United States here than we originally reported, with the 72 percent.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, more data.&nbsp; This was a J&amp;J paper that I showed to this group a few weeks ago, looking at the safety and the efficacy of the single-dose Ad26.&nbsp; As you can see, the efficacy was 74 percent in the United States.<br><br>But now take a look at this a little bit more closely.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>If you look at the hospitalizations and compare the placebo, in red, with the J&amp;J, in blue, 14 days postvaccination, you see there’s 93 percent vaccine efficacy.&nbsp; But if you wait at least 28 days postvaccination, it&#8217;s 100 percent with regard to hospitalizations.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>And then when you look at deaths, there were no COVID-19 related deaths in the vaccine group, and five COVID-related deaths in the placebo group.&nbsp;<br><br>And on the final slide, what does this tell us?&nbsp; That vaccines protect you.&nbsp; They protect your family.&nbsp; And they interrupt the chain of transmission of the virus.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the bottom line, as we&#8217;re all saying: Get vaccinated.<br><br>Passing it over to you, Dr. Murthy.<br><br>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Well, thank you so much, Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s good to be with all of you again this morning.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like, today, to share some numbers with you concerning people who are vaccinated and unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>The recent data from the CDC, involving a survey of over 14,000 people, showed that more than 70 percent of Americans are vaccinated, planning to get vaccinated, or likely to vaccinated.<br><br>And while a portion of the unvaccinated population do have questions about the vaccine, and while we are going to continue to mobilize trusted messengers through our COVID-19 Community Corps to help answer these questions, the truth is that, overall, vaccine confidence in the country remains high.&nbsp; That is good news.<br><br>The data continues to point, though, to access barriers being an important additional concern among people who are unvaccinated.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a recent Kaiser Family Foundation survey which looked at pe- &#8212; those who are unvaccinated, but who wanted to get vaccinated as soon as possible.&nbsp;<br><br>What it found was that more than a third of people in this group said that they have not gotten vaccinated because they didn&#8217;t have enough time due to work hours or other schedule conflicts or because they just hadn&#8217;t gotten around to it.&nbsp; About 7 percent of people said that they didn&#8217;t have information about how to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Eight percent said they weren&#8217;t sure if they were eligible or had the right documentation.<br><br>These numbers may seem small, but they actually represent millions of people, and they are crucial to reach with vaccines if you want cases to come down and stay down.<br><br>Now, when we look at another part of the unvaccinated population &#8212; those who do not want to get vaccinated as soon as possible &#8212; it turns out here, too, access is an issue.&nbsp; Among those who are employed, 28 percent say that they would be more likely to get vaccinated if they receive time off to receive and recover from the vaccine.&nbsp; Another 20 percent say they would be more likely if their shot was administered in their workplace.<br><br>So, employers not only have an opportunity to increase vaccination rates, but if you look at one more piece of data, it turns out that they can also help to close the equity gap in vaccinations.&nbsp; This is so important because we&#8217;ve said from the beginning that success is not just determined by how many people we get vaccinated, but by how equitably and fairly we vaccinate our population.&nbsp; And workplaces, it turns out, can play a role in that.&nbsp;<br><br>Because among the unvaccinated, 64 percent of Hispanic adults and 55 percent of Black adults have concerns about missing work to recover from vaccinations compared to 41 percent of white adults.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s why the recently announced tax credits for businesses and nonprofit organizations with fewer than 500 employees are so important &#8212; because they provide financial support for businesses providing time off for employees to actually get the vaccine and recover from temporary side effects.&nbsp; We want people to know about this.&nbsp; We want businesses to take advantage of it.<br><br>This next phase of the vaccination campaign was &#8212; will be driven, more than anything, by the people and organizations and communities who help to vaccinate their families, their friends, and others in their neighborhoods.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve been saying that addressing access, motivation, and vaccine confidence requires an all-hands-on-deck approach.&nbsp;<br><br>But, thankfully, people all across America are stepping up to meet this moment.&nbsp; Businesses like Joe&#8217;s Kansas City Bar-B-Que are giving workers time off if they get vaccinated, and The Feeding Zoo is administering vaccines on site to visitors, volunteers, and employees.&nbsp; Young Invincibles &#8212; a young adult advocacy group and a member of our COVID-19 Community Corps &#8212; recently launched “Don&#8217;t miss out, LA,” a campaign that trains young people to spread the word about the vaccine on all fronts: peer-to-peer texting, phone banking, social media, QR code stickers placed in popular LA spots, and, of course, the good old-fashioned, in-person conversation.<br><br>And ParentsTogether &#8212; another one of our COVID-19 Community Corps members, which is a parent-led and parent-powered organization which provides trusted information to families &#8212; they have engaged hundreds of thousands of patients &#8212; of parents online about their questions about vaccines, any concerns they may have, and stories about their vaccinations.<br><br>So, today, we are asking everyone to help spread the word about getting vaccinated as part of our “Digital Day of Action.”&nbsp;&nbsp; And we are encouraging communities to visit Vaccine.gov; to text their ZIP Code to 438829, which spells get “GETVAX,” or to 882862, which spells “VACUNA,” and you can find available vaccines near you.<br><br>So please reach out to your family and friends.&nbsp; Please share this with the members of your organization, whether it&#8217;s your employees or your volunteers.&nbsp; Remind people the vaccine is free of charge.&nbsp; It&#8217;s now easier to get than ever before.&nbsp; And remind people also that the vaccine remains our single-best pathway out of the COVID-19 pandemic.<br><br>Thank you so much, and I&#8217;ll turn it back to Andy.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Murthy.<br><br>Okay, we&#8217;ll take some questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Andy, and happy Friday.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Victoria Knight at Kaiser.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; My question is for Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; Will the CDC be updating their dashboard daily with state-by-state race and ethnicity data?&nbsp; And also, what is the CDC planning to do about the high percentage of missing data on race and ethnicity, which is close to about 40 percent?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Thank you for that question, Victoria.&nbsp; We have been updating our website.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t say that it&#8217;s daily; I believe that it&#8217;s weekly.&nbsp; And we actually have a new &#8212; new feature, just in the last week, looking at how we are doing for vaccine distribution in a two-week rolling basis.&nbsp;<br><br>We are working actively with states’ public health and localities to try and get more access to race and ethnicity data and have actually made some progress in that regard, and we&#8217;re continuing to do so.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Steve Portnoy, CBS.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; All of the data that the doctors have laid out this morning is extremely encouraging, but some people saw the crowd of close to 70 &#8212; presumably, fully vaccinated &#8212; people in the East Room at the White House yesterday.&nbsp; And some said on social media that the sight made them nervous.&nbsp;<br><br>So, to the doctors, what do you say to those people who may have spent the last 15 months following your advice to strictly avoid crowds, who might not be psychologically ready to do what you now know to be safe if they&#8217;ve been vaccinated?&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, are these lingering fears irrational?&nbsp; And to Dr. Walensky, what does it say about the response to the CDC’s communications over the last week if people do continue to have that fear?<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, do you want to begin?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, I would say that fears like that are not irrational.&nbsp; I mean &#8212; I mean, people &#8212; it&#8217;s understandable when you&#8217;re used to a certain type of behavior, and then, when the science says that you can actually turn around, that &#8212; as we&#8217;ve said with the recent CDC guidelines that say we can feel comfortable; that if you&#8217;re fully vaccinated, that you are safe from being infected, be it outdoors or indoors &#8212; you can understand that when people have been following a certain trend for a considerable period of time, that it may take time for them to adjust.&nbsp; So I would not say that that&#8217;s irrational; I&#8217;d say that&#8217;s understandable.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp;&nbsp; And I would &#8212; thank you.&nbsp; I would echo much of what Dr. Fauci had said.&nbsp; You know, when we released our guidelines and the &#8212; and the science said it was safe to do so, we also acknowledge that not everybody is going to feel like it&#8217;s time to rip off their masks.&nbsp; For 16 months, we&#8217;ve been saying that it&#8217;s important to wear these masks to protect yourselves.&nbsp; And now, what we&#8217;re saying is &#8212; it&#8217;s going to be hard to get back to, you know, life as we knew it without these masks, and we&#8217;re going to do so tipping our &#8212; dipping our toe in the water and having everybody move at their own pace.<br><br>We specifically have acknowledged that if you are vaccinated, there is no shame, no problem in continuing to wear your mask.&nbsp; And just like it has been hard to have everybody get masked, I think this is going to take some time for us all to get used to.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Peter Sullivan, The Hill.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the vaccine lottery incentive programs some states have been doing.&nbsp; Ohio, New York, and Maryland all have, you know, lotteries or prize money you can be entered in if you vaccinate.&nbsp; I wonder if you, kind of, think that&#8217;s a good idea.&nbsp; And have you been talking to states about that?&nbsp; Are you going to encourage more states to have these kind of lottery incentives?<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Well, from the data we&#8217;ve seen, they appear to be working.&nbsp; And I think the reason they work is because the vast number of people who are not yet vaccinated are actually not opposed to getting vaccinated; they&#8217;re just not prioritizing it very high.&nbsp; There are other things going on in their lives.<br><br>And so things that draw attention to it, like the lotteries in those states you mentioned, are &#8212; not surprisingly &#8212; very effective, and so we&#8217;re enthusiastic.<br><br>Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Jeremy Diamond, CNN.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks for taking the question.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering: How do you all anticipate that declining deaths and cases will affect people&#8217;s decision to get vaccinated, especially for those who are still on the fence?&nbsp; And then, secondly, I&#8217;m wondering if you guys have an update on the doses that you plan to send abroad, what the timing for that is, and if you&#8217;ve settled on a process for deciding which countries will get doses and how many.&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; So why don&#8217;t we start with the first question, which is the impact of &#8212; the improving outlook of the pandemic on people&#8217;s willingness and interest in getting vaccinated.<br><br>Dr. Murthy, do you want to start with that?<br><br>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Thanks, Andy.&nbsp; And, Jeremy, I appreciate the question.&nbsp; I think it’s a good one.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, it can be easy to look at the circumstances right now with all of the improvements Dr. Walensky laid out &#8212; cases, hospitalizations, deaths &#8212; and think, “We&#8217;re out of this pandemic.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have to get vaccinated or take precautions anymore.”&nbsp; But that would not be the right lesson to take.&nbsp;<br><br>The right message, we believe, is that we are seeing improvements because people have in fact gotten vaccinated.&nbsp; And if we continue on this path &#8212; get more people vaccinated &#8212; we can sustain that decline in cases that we&#8217;ve seen in the decline of deaths and hospitalizations.&nbsp; But if we stop where we are right now &#8212; if people do not get fully vaccinated; the millions who are out there who still need to &#8212; then we will still be at risk, potentially, for more infections in the future.<br><br>And we want to protect everybody in our country from this virus, so that&#8217;s why we will continue to emphasize that we should keep moving forward with vaccinations.&nbsp; Do not let your guard down.&nbsp;&nbsp; But be &#8212;&nbsp; be encouraged and cautiously optimistic that we are absolutely heading in the right direction.&nbsp; We just can&#8217;t &#8212; you know, we can&#8217;t take our foot off the accelerator.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Yeah. There&#8217;s good evidence &#8212; if people don&#8217;t feel at risk of dying of the measles, yet they still get their vaccination.&nbsp; So, I think we just have a much more continued education with the public to do, and many, many more people will get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Jeremy, your other question, which I think you ask frequently, is about the status of doses to other countries.&nbsp; To confirm that, we have committed that before the Fourth of July &#8212; and we are waiting on FDA approval &#8212; 80 million doses of &#8212; which is 13 percent of all of the doses that have been procured in the U.S. &#8212; are going to be sent overseas.&nbsp; That&#8217;s in addition to the $4 billion commitment that we&#8217;ve led with COVAX.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; so, we are &#8212; we don&#8217;t have a status yet on either the FDA approval of the AstraZeneca doses, and nor do we have news to report today about where those doses are going.&nbsp;<br><br>But I will reiterate something the President said, which is that those decisions are being made on two factors: science and public health, and equity &#8212; and no other factors.<br><br>Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Maureen Groppe, USA Today.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you talk a little bit about how the dating app initiative came about, and also whether this is a first for the White House to get involved in dating sites?<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; I suppose I have to take that question, huh?<br><br>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; (Laughs.) &nbsp;Well, all you, Andy.<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You know, as we were talking about earlier, in all seriousness, people are interested in other things in life besides their vaccine.&nbsp; But the vaccine enables people to get back to the things that they enjoy in life.&nbsp;<br><br>And, you know, Dr. Murthy has written extensively, in all seriousness, about the concept of loneliness and about social contact and so forth.&nbsp; And so, while it is, kind of, a funny thing to talk about, the truth of the matter is people do want to get back to their normal lives, they do have questions about making sure that they can do that safely, and that&#8217;s great.&nbsp; So, we are &#8212; we&#8217;re obviously pleased with that.&nbsp; And the fact that this reaches that &#8212; those many people.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, I think &#8212; I applaud the initiative on these companies’ parts.&nbsp; I think it&#8217;s their effort.&nbsp; And, you know, we &#8212; and we have conversations with them, but this is things that they were &#8212; that they&#8217;re &#8212; that they were doing because they saw a need in their audience base.&nbsp; So, I think that&#8217;s &#8212; I think that&#8217;s the gist of it.<br><br>Next question.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Tommy Christopher.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, I &#8212; I have trouble with this unmute button.<br><br>Okay, well, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; And, you know, I &#8212; I have a question, and I kind of hate to bring this up, but I really have &#8212; feel like I have to.&nbsp;<br><br>I don&#8217;t know if you guys saw this viral video from Ricky Schroder earlier in the week, yelling at some poor guy at Costco.&nbsp; But I also &#8212; I live in New Jersey, another state that hasn&#8217;t dropped the mask mandates.&nbsp; And, you know, it&#8217;s been bad all along, but it has gotten even worse since the new vaccination &#8212; the guidelines for vaccinated people.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, people come down here on the weekends and in the summertime, and they scream at our restaurant workers because they have to wear a mask to go from the door to their table.&nbsp; And, you know, I just &#8212; I&#8217;m wondering what you guys have to say about all that.<br><br>And, I mean, I know Governor Phil Murphy says that, you know, it&#8217;s not fair to ask a frontline worker to decide whether or not someone presenting themselves at a business is vaccinated or not.&nbsp; And so, I mean, what do you think about all that?<br><br>I mean, there&#8217;s &#8212; a friend of mine told me that a customer threatened to get her fired because she asked him to wear a mask.&nbsp;<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; Look, the last year and a half has been one of the most intense periods in our lives.&nbsp; People are feeling a lot of stress.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re feeling, as Dr. Fauci said earlier, very, you know, normal feelings adjusting.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s just treat each other with respect.&nbsp;<br><br>Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question, let&#8217;s go to Meg Tirrell at CNBC.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I was intrigued by what Dr. Murthy said about how employers could play a bigger role in helping people get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>What would you like to see in terms of them offering on-site vaccination clinics?&nbsp; And what do you see as the barriers for employers to be able to do that?<br><br>And if I can add just a second question for Dr. Fauci or Dr Walensky.&nbsp; You know, there&#8217;s been a lot of focus on immunocompromised folks and the fact that vaccines may not provide the same protection for them.&nbsp; Do you see monoclonal antibodies potentially being used for those folks preventively?&nbsp; Is that a potential good option for people who don&#8217;t get so much protection from the vaccines?<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Let me &#8212; let me start because I do have &#8212; we&#8217;ve been tracking very closely here how employers &#8212; and hi, Meg, thanks for the question &#8212; how employers are, in fact, creating near-site and on-site clinics.&nbsp; They&#8217;re creating &#8212; they&#8217;re either doing this on their own, through the states, or they&#8217;re creating partnerships with some of the pharmaceutical companies, and &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, not pharmaceutical companies &#8212; pharmacies who are &#8212; who are capable of providing that capability.&nbsp;<br><br>We have begun a process which we might talk about at some point where we are helping to match up employers who have lots of employees on their sites with people who provide those services, and we think it&#8217;s fairly commonplace.<br><br>I&#8217;m not sure we have any data on this, but &#8212; but it&#8217;s a great thing for an employer to do and if you&#8217;re an employer out there, I would strongly encourage you to do this, as well as giving your employees time off.<br><br>Dr. Murthy, did you have anything you wanted to add about that before I turn to Dr. Fauci?<br><br>DR. MURTHY:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, thanks Andy.&nbsp; And, Meg, thanks for the question.&nbsp; I would just say, look, we really think employers can play a powerful role here.&nbsp; The goal here is to bring vaccines closer to where people are.&nbsp;<br><br>Workplaces are obviously a place where people spend a lot of time.&nbsp; And workplaces can help in three ways: by helping build vaccine confidence by sharing information, by motivating people to get vaccines both by encouraging them and also enabling other people to share their vaccination story, and also by improving access.&nbsp; These are three concrete ways.<br><br>The barriers, though, that we often see is: Number one, employers may not always know that &#8212; about just how important a role they can play and what they can do.&nbsp; They may wonder about logistically how to arrange it &#8212; whether it&#8217;s a partnership with the pharmacy &#8212; or what materials to share.&nbsp; And they also may wonder if it&#8217;s actually working.<br><br>And this is one of the reasons why not only we set up the tax credit program and other, you know &#8212; other tools, but we built the COVID-19 Community Corps to provide a community where people can share best practices, support one another, and take these sort of innovative measures and steps that will help bring vaccines closer to where people are.&nbsp;<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci, I believe the second question Meg asked was about the use of monoclonals as prophylactics.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yeah, well, certainly it is an issue that we are concerned about is people who are immunosuppressed, particularly profoundly immunosuppressed &#8212; such as some of the solid organ transplant patients, but also others who might have autoimmune diseases who are receiving a variety of immunosuppressive agents.&nbsp;<br><br>We are doing a major study here at NIAID on just those individuals to determine what the best approach is &#8212; whether an additional boost.<br><br>The idea of monoclonal antibodies is a reasonable idea.&nbsp; It has not been studied in that context where you give people monoclonal antibody because, again, given the half-life of these antibodies, you would have to give them over a period of time &#8212; whether or not it would be feasible to have people who in fact don&#8217;t have a good immune response to be given monoclonal antibody every several months.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s certainly something worth addressing and worth studying.&nbsp;<br><br>One of the other ways of approaching it, which is in the arena of therapy, is to try and get some therapies, particularly direct-acting antiviral agents, so that when people who are in that category of immunosuppressed actually do get infected, you can treat them immediately so that they don&#8217;t progress.&nbsp; Or even &#8212; the way we&#8217;ve done with HIV &#8212; to give, actually, prophylactics.<br><br>So there are a lot of different options, Meg, that are being pursued because we do really feel that this is a substantial problem that we need to address.&nbsp;<br><br>ACTING ADMINISTRATOR SLAVITT:&nbsp; And maybe in an upcoming session, we&#8217;ll highlight the status of the trials of the antivirals at the right time.&nbsp;<br><br>Anyway, thank you all. &nbsp;Have a very happy Friday and a great weekend.<br><br>11:37 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/COVID-Press-Briefing_21May2021-for-transcript.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/COVID-Press-Briefing_21May2021-for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Safe Boating Week, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/05/21/a-proclamation-on-national-safe-boating-week-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 21:00:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every year, millions of Americans take time to enjoy our&#160;Nation&#8217;s waterways &#8212; one of our great natural treasures.&#160; As&#160;more Americans get vaccinated against COVID-19, and as warmer weather draws families to our Nation&#8217;s lakes, rivers, and beaches, this week serves as a critical reminder of the importance of staying safe on the water.&#160; Each year&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every year, millions of Americans take time to enjoy our&nbsp;Nation&#8217;s waterways &#8212; one of our great natural treasures.&nbsp; As&nbsp;more Americans get vaccinated against COVID-19, and as warmer weather draws families to our Nation&#8217;s lakes, rivers, and beaches, this week serves as a critical reminder of the importance of staying safe on the water.&nbsp; Each year during National Safe Boating Week, the Coast Guard and an array of Federal, State, and local partners help save lives and guard against accidents by highlighting safe boating practices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This year, we celebrate the 50th anniversary of the Federal Boat Safety Act of 1971.&nbsp; The Act created a partnership between the Federal Government and the States to improve the safety of recreational boating. &nbsp;It also established the National Recreational Boating Safety Program and gave the Coast Guard the&nbsp;authority to establish mandatory boat manufacturing and safety standards.&nbsp; The Coast Guard estimates that these efforts have saved nearly 100,000 lives over the last half century.</p>



<p>While most boating trips are enjoyable and safe, tragedy still strikes with alarming frequency.&nbsp; Since 2000, there have been over 13,000 boating-related deaths and over 64,000 boating-related injuries, many of which could have been prevented if proper safety precautions were taken. &nbsp;Whether you are fishing, sailing, or out on the water with family or friends, it is essential to follow safe boating practices for your own protection and the protection of those around you.</p>



<p>Safe boating begins with education and planning.&nbsp; Human&nbsp;error contributes to the vast majority of boating accidents, which can be minimized by taking an &#8220;on-water&#8221; boating safety course.&nbsp; Learning and improving your boating skills help increase the odds of an enjoyable and safe boating experience.&nbsp; Every American can ensure that their boat is ready for the water by obtaining a free vessel safety check offered through the U.S. Coast Guard Auxiliary.</p>



<p>I call upon all Americans to follow safe boating practices. &nbsp;By following basic boating safety procedures &#8212; wearing life jackets, carrying lifesaving emergency distress and communications equipment, judiciously using the engine cut-off switch, and staying sober when boating &#8212; we can prevent the vast majority of boating fatalities and help ensure boaters on&nbsp;America&#8217;s coastal, inland, and offshore waters stay safe throughout the season.</p>



<p>In recognition of the importance of safe boating practices, the Congress, by joint resolution approved June 4, 1958 (36&nbsp;U.S.C. 131), as amended, has authorized and requested the President to proclaim annually the 7-day period before Memorial Day weekend as &#8220;National Safe Boating Week.&#8221;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United&nbsp;States of America, do hereby proclaim May 22 through May&nbsp;28, 2021, as National Safe Boating Week. &nbsp;I encourage all Americans who participate in boating activities to observe this&nbsp;occasion by learning and practicing safe boating behaviors. &nbsp;I&nbsp;also encourage the Governors of the States and Territories, and appropriate officials of all units of government, to join me&nbsp;in encouraging boating safety through events and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-first day of May, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
