<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 15:58:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration’s Historic Investment in Pandemic Preparedness and Biodefense in the FY 2023 President’s&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/28/fact-sheet-the-biden-administrations-historic-investment-in-pandemic-preparedness-and-biodefense-in-the-fy-2023-presidents-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[COVID-19 has exacted an unfathomable toll on our nation and the world, causing millions of deaths and trillions of dollars in economic losses globally, and highlighting the inter-dependency between our nation’s health security and that of the world. Throughout the pandemic, Americans and people around the world have personally experienced the health, social, and economic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>COVID-19 has exacted an unfathomable toll on our nation and the world, causing millions of deaths and trillions of dollars in economic losses globally, and highlighting the inter-dependency between our nation’s health security and that of the world. Throughout the pandemic, Americans and people around the world have personally experienced the health, social, and economic impacts caused by infectious diseases. The COVID-19 response has illuminated both longstanding and newly discovered limitations in our local, national, and international health systems and health security capabilities. It has also resulted in an unparalleled, multisectoral, whole-of-society response, which has galvanized breakthrough innovation. The Biden-Harris administration has made great progress in combatting COVID-19 and building better health security to protect against future pandemics and other health emergencies. However, much more is needed to prevent future biological catastrophes. In America and around the world, people want to know: what can we do to stop future pandemics? We must increase and sustain our investments across the U.S. Government to better prevent, detect, and respond to pandemics, and to build a world safe and secure from biological threats.</p>



<p>The FY23 President’s Budget includes a historic $88.2 billion request for mandatory funding, available over five years, across the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response (ASPR) the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), the Department of State, and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to prepare for future biological threats in support of objectives within U.S. national and global biodefense and pandemic preparedness strategies and plans. This investment will fund transformative improvements in our capabilities to prevent, detect, and respond to emerging biological catastrophes.&nbsp; If we want to create a world free of pandemics and other biological catastrophes, the time to act is now. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The Budget will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Transform our capability to rapidly produce and deliver countermeasures against pandemics and other biological threats. </strong>The Budget includes $40 billion for theHHSASPR to invest in advanced development and manufacturing of countermeasures for high priority threats and viral families, including vaccines, therapeutics, diagnostics, and personal protective equipment (PPE). This funding would support development of novel technologies, including rapidly scalable vaccine production technologies; technologies to simplify the administration of vaccines; effective and broadly-acting therapeutics; next-generation PPE; rapidly scalable, affordable, and effective diagnostics; pathogen-agnostic detection technologies; and tools to suppress pathogen transmission in the built environment, including ventilation, sterilization, and antimicrobial and antiviral surfaces. This funding will also support manufacturing capacity to surge countermeasure production in response to future biological threats, whether from COVID-19 variants or another emergent biological threat. These investments build towards the ambitious goals of developing effective vaccines and therapeutics within 100 days of identifying a biological threat, producing sufficient quantities to vaccinate the United States population within 130 days, and supporting surge production to rapidly meet global needs.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Strengthen our public health infrastructure and early warning capabilities. </strong>The Budget provides $28 billion for the CDC to enhance public health system infrastructure, domestic and global threat surveillance, public health workforce development, public health laboratory capacity, and global health security. These efforts will ensure the nation is prepared to effectively contain and mitigate future biological threats and will enable States, localities, tribal nations, and Territories to mount a rapid and robust response to future outbreaks. These investments will complement discretionary funding to modernize public health data collection and increase capacity for disease early warning forecasting and analyzing future outbreaks, including at the Center for Forecasting and Outbreak Analytics. Funding will also promote health equity in pandemic response infrastructure through initiatives to support marginalized and underserved communities through community-based public health services and support state-based and international efforts to control antibiotic resistance.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in basic research to enable an effective response to novel pandemics and biological threats. </strong>The Budget provides $12.1 billion to NIH for research and development of vaccines, diagnostics, and therapeutics against high priority biological threats, including safe and secure laboratory capacity and clinical trial infrastructure. Developing a vaccine against COVID-19 built on twenty years of prior federally funded scientific research on coronaviruses. Accordingly, the Budget supports preclinical and clinical research and development of prototype vaccines and therapeutics against priority viral families. These investments will provide essential foundational knowledge to meet the goal of developing vaccines and therapeutics against novel biological threats within 100 days.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Modernize and streamline our regulatory infrastructure.</strong> The Budget provides $1.6 billion for the FDA to expand and modernize regulatory capacity, information technology, and laboratory infrastructure to support the evaluation of medical countermeasures.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Advance biosafety and biosecurity in the United States and globally to prevent biological incidents.&nbsp;</strong>The Budget&nbsp;provides $1.8 billion within the total $88.2 billion request to&nbsp;enable the CDC and NIH to expand efforts to strengthen biosafety and biosecurity practices domestically and globally. This includes applied research and innovation in biosafety and biosecurity, which will expand capabilities to identify and minimize safety and security risks in the design and development of biotechnology.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Transform global health security and pandemic preparedness for COVID-19 variants and future biological threats.</strong> A biological threat anywhere can turn into a health emergency everywhere.&nbsp; The most effective way to respond to biological threats is to respond to it at its source. The Budget includes $6.5 billion in mandatory funding for the Department of State and USAID to make transformative investments in pandemic and biological threat preparedness globally, which complements ongoing U.S. investments to also strengthen health systems. This includes $4.5 billion in seed funding to establish global, regional, and local capacity through a new financial intermediary fund at the World Bank focused on global health security and pandemic preparedness. This effort will build on U.S. global health security investments and provide a more structured platform to account for and measure international gaps and gains.&nbsp; It will also accelerate U.S. leadership to bring other donors to the table and will provide $500 million over five years to the Coalition for Epidemic Preparedness Innovations (CEPI) to support innovating science and technological capabilities to shorten the cycle for development of safe, effective, and affordable vaccines.</li></ul>



<p>These investments will build on and accelerate innovations to prepare for future COVID-19 variants, and ensure the capabilities we are building to combat COVID-19 are sustained for future pandemics.Acknowledging the possibility that future COVID-19 variants could have severe consequences for U.S. health and livelihoods, the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, HHS, and the White House COVID-19 team launched the Pandemic Innovation Task Force, which assembled science and technology leaders across the executive branch to accelerate pandemic innovations with the potential to have a major impact on our ability to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic and future biological threats.</p>



<p>Collectively, these activities will build capabilities the nation urgently needs to respond to future pandemics and biological threats from any source, strengthen international systems so that we can detect threats early and respond rapidly, and enable the nation to decisively act on the lessons from COVID-19.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On-the-Record Press Call by OMB Director Shalanda Young and CEA Chair Cecilia Rouse on the President&#8217;s FY23&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/28/on-the-record-press-call-by-omb-director-shalanda-young-and-cea-chair-cecilia-rouse-on-the-presidents-fy23-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 15:32:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[8:37 A.M. EDT MR. FRIEDLANDER:&#160;&#160;Good morning, everyone.&#160; Thanks for joining us for this on-the-record call about the President&#8217;s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget.&#160; We&#8217;re joined by OMB Director Shalanda Young and Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers Cecilia Rouse.&#160; They will each offer a few brief comments at the top, and then we&#8217;ll hold time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>8:37 A.M. EDT<br><br>MR. FRIEDLANDER:&nbsp;&nbsp;Good morning, everyone.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us for this on-the-record call about the President&#8217;s Fiscal Year 2023 Budget.&nbsp; We&#8217;re joined by OMB Director Shalanda Young and Chair of the Council of Economic Advisers Cecilia Rouse.&nbsp; They will each offer a few brief comments at the top, and then we&#8217;ll hold time for some questions at the end.<br><br>Again, this call will be on the record, and it&#8217;s embargoed until 11:00 a.m. Eastern time today.<br><br>You all should have received embargoed materials from our team a short while ago.&nbsp; If, for some reason, you haven&#8217;t, please reach out to us and we&#8217;ll make sure you get what you need.<br><br>With that, I will turn it over to Director Young.<br><br>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; Thank you, Rob.&nbsp; Thank you all for joining.&nbsp; And Happy Budget Day, as I like to call today.&nbsp;<br><br>You&#8217;ve heard the President say that budgets are about values, and his budget for fiscal year 2023 makes our values clear in three important ways.&nbsp;<br><br>First, this budget is fiscally responsible.&nbsp; It shows that we&#8217;re on track to reduce the deficit by more than $1.3 trillion this year.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the largest-ever one-year decline and less than half of the 2020 deficit the President inherited.&nbsp;<br><br>This progress was not an accident.&nbsp; It was a direct result of the President&#8217;s strategy to combat the pandemic and grow our economy from the bottom up and the middle out &#8212; a strategy that was built on smart, fiscally prudent investments that helped jumpstart our recovery.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;ve seen that strategy pay off.&nbsp; In 2021, we created more than 6.5 million jobs &#8212; the most our country has ever recorded in a single year.&nbsp; Our economy grew at 5.7 percent &#8212; the strongest growth in nearly 40 years.&nbsp; And the unemployment rate has fallen to 3.8 percent &#8212; the fastest decline in recorded history.&nbsp;<br><br>The budget outlines the President&#8217;s vision to expand this progress.&nbsp; Its investments are more than fully paid for through the tax reforms that ensure corporations and the wealthiest Americans pay their fair share, including a new billionaire minimum income tax.&nbsp; It achieves significant deficit reduction over the next decade, and it ensures that no one earning less than $400,000 a year will pay an additional penny in new taxes.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Second, the budget invests in security both at home and abroad.&nbsp; Here at home, it includes critical investments to keep our communities safe, fund crime prevention and community violence intervention, put more cops on the beat for community policing, fight gun violence, and advance criminal justice reform.&nbsp;<br><br>And during what will be a decisive decade for the world, the budget makes one of the largest investments in national security in U.S. history, strengthening our military and leveraging our renewed strength at home to meet pressing global challenges.&nbsp;<br><br>And third, the budget delivers on the agenda the President laid out in his State of the Union Address to help build a better America.&nbsp; It advances a bipartisan Unity Agenda through proposals to take on the mental health crisis, combat the opioid epidemic, support our veterans, and accelerate progress against cancer.&nbsp;<br><br>And it makes other key investments in the American people, building a stronger economy and promoting job creation, improving our country&#8217;s public health infrastructure, combating the climate crisis, and advancing equity and opportunity across our economy and our country.&nbsp;<br><br>As the President made clear in his State of the Union, he&#8217;s also committed to working with Congress to pass legislation that reduces the deficit; cuts healthcare, energy, childcare, and other costs for families; and reforms the tax system.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Because those discussions with Congress are ongoing, the budget does not include specific line items for the investments associated with that future legislation, nor does it count any of the savings from the prescription drugs or tax reforms that the House advanced as part of its Build Back Better Act.&nbsp;<br><br>Instead, the budget incorporates a reserve for the legislation and lays out the President&#8217;s three principles:&nbsp; Legislation must cut costs for families, cut the deficit, and expand the productive capacity of the economy.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ve been clear that the President wants to sign legislation that cuts costs for families and reduces the deficit.&nbsp; But to be conservative, the budget reflects this reserve fund as deficit neutral.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>So, stepping back, what this budget shows is that we can grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out, and invest in the American people, and that we can do it in a smart, fiscally responsible way.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>With that, let me turn it over to Chair Rouse to talk about the budget&#8217;s economic outlook and forecast.<br><br>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Thank you, Director Young.&nbsp; And thank you for your time today.&nbsp; I want to use this opportunity to cover two important elements of the budget: the economic motivation and the economic forecast behind this policy.&nbsp; This budget builds on the solid economic gains of the first year of this administration.&nbsp;<br><br>Remember where we were when President Biden took office.&nbsp; The pandemic still had a strong grip on the economy, and recovery was uneven and anemic.&nbsp; We actually lost 115,000 jobs in December of 2020 alone, and roughly 4 million workers had been unemployed for more than six months.&nbsp; Unemployment was forecast to come down but slowly.<br><br>Today, the country looks very different.&nbsp; The recovery over the last year has been extraordinary; quicker than independent forecasters projected.&nbsp; With over three quarters of the adult population fully vaccinated, the economy has been able to reopen and rebound.<br><br>Over 2021, real output grew by 5.6 percent &#8212; the fastest since 1984.&nbsp; The unemployment rate fell at its fastest pace since modern data began in 1948.&nbsp; The labor force participation rates of Americans 25 to 54 years old grew by the most since 1979.<br><br>This robust recovery has put us in a strong position today.&nbsp; The U.S. economy is more than 3 percent larger in inflation-adjusted terms than it was before the pandemic &#8212; the fastest recovery in the G7.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Healthy household balance sheets and a strong labor market make us more resilient to external shocks.<br><br>The strong recovery has also put us in a better fiscal position as faster growth helps lower the deficit.&nbsp;<br><br>The Fiscal Year ‘23 budget builds on this solid economic growth.&nbsp; It is a continuation of President Biden&#8217;s commitment to address longstanding issues in the economy and make investments that will ensure strong, sustainable growth that benefits all Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>First, the budget is fiscally responsible.&nbsp; Thanks to the American Rescue Plan, the economy recovered faster in 2021 than expected.&nbsp; Revenues are up, and the pandemic relief (inaudible).&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The result is that the expected deficit in Fiscal Year 2022 is $1.3 trillion smaller than it was in Fiscal Year ‘21.&nbsp; And we believe the policies in this budget will further reduce the deficit by another trillion over the next decade.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>A lower deficit will help ease long-term inflationary pressures and make our fiscal trajectory more sustainable.<br><br>Second, the budget bolsters domestic and foreign security.&nbsp; Increased security here and abroad not only protects lives, but it also reduces uncertainty, which allows economic activity the room it needs to renormalize and grow as the pandemic eases.&nbsp;<br><br>Third, the budget makes important investments in the American people.&nbsp; A healthy, cared-for workforce is a productive workforce.&nbsp; Moreover, the budget lowers costs for families such as healthcare, childcare, and energy &#8212; measures that will ease price pressures over the longer term.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;d like to close with a word about our forecast.&nbsp; In many ways, the economy looks healthier today than it did when we locked our forecast all the way back in last November.&nbsp; The economy has created an average of 600,000 jobs per month since then, including through the Omicron wave.&nbsp; And the unemployment rate has fallen an additional 0.8 percentage points since then.<br><br>Indeed, private forecasters now project the unemployment rate to be lower than the 3.9 and 3.6 percent we projected for 2022 and 2023, respectively.<br><br>But challenges have arisen since last November as well.&nbsp; The most obvious is the Russian invasion of Ukraine, which will have ramifications that are not reflected in our forecast.&nbsp;&nbsp;For example, the inflation [sic] will li- &#8212; the invasion will likely put upward pressure on energy and food prices.&nbsp;&nbsp;That, in turn, could reinforce inflation that was already an issue prior to the invasion due to the pandemic, supply chain constraints, and a strong demand for goods.&nbsp;<br><br>Independent forecasters therefore expect somewhat slower GDP growth but still anticipate that inflation will come down.&nbsp;<br><br>As I said earlier, the strength of our recovery has put us on solid ground to weather economic shocks.&nbsp; Americans are back to work, and the economy is stronger than anyone, including the federal government and private forecasters, imagined when President Biden took office.&nbsp;<br><br>The President&#8217;s 2023 budget presents a fiscally fair and responsible approach to build on the progress we&#8217;ve made so far to invest in America and meet our future challenges.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. FRIEDLANDER:&nbsp; Great. Thank you very much.&nbsp; Moderator, we&#8217;ll take a few questions now.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Happy Monday to everyone.&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I was hoping to get more sense of how you&#8217;re looking at inflation, given that from 2023 onward there&#8217;s the expectation that CPI goes to 2.3 percent.&nbsp; Is the idea that we just need another year of adjustment?&nbsp; Or what’s kind of&nbsp;underlying that forecast?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; I’m sorry, the question about the forecast itself?&nbsp; Or is it &#8212; is the question about how we’re seeing inflation now, going forward?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The economic assumptions have inflation CPI at 2.3 percent in table S-9.&nbsp; And I’m curious for &#8212; is the implication there that &#8212; that, in a sense, like, we just have another year of rough inflation in that assumption, or kind of what you’re forward thinking on that is?</p>



<p>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So we an- &#8212; so the &#8212; first of all, let’s remember that the forecast was locked on November 10th of 2021.&nbsp; So that was quite a while ago.&nbsp; So this &#8212; this economic forecast, if we were updating today, we would look at it somewhat differently.</p>



<p>But let’s understand where the inflation forecast comes from.&nbsp; We were living through a pandemic where we supported households, as we needed to do, to get through this health crisis, and at the same time, the supply chains crumbled beneath us.</p>



<p>As a result, we had a mismatch between supply and demand, which generated some inflation.&nbsp; We are not alone.&nbsp; This &#8212; we see this inflation across the developed world with other countries that were supporting their households, their workers, their businesses through the pandemic.</p>



<p>Nonetheless, we expected, back in November, that inflationary pressures would ease as the economy started to renormalize; as we learned to keep our economic activity going, supporting us through the pandemic, and as supply chain challenges started to renormalize.&nbsp; And as the extraordinary support both by the monetary policy &#8212; so, in our case, the Federal Reserve &#8212; and fiscal policy, which was no longer needed, could be eased, we expected these inflationary pressures to ease over the coming year.</p>



<p>Then Russia invaded Ukraine.&nbsp; That has created additional upward pressure on prices.&nbsp; That happened in February, well after our forecast was already completed.&nbsp; We do expect that that is going to create additional price pressures over the coming year.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, the fundamentals are that we expect that as we learn to keep economic activity going through additional waves of the pandemic &#8212; we hope there won’t be many &#8212; but as we continue to work through the challenge of the pandemic, that we will keep economic activity going, supply chain pressures will ease, the extraordinary measures will start to roll off as well, and we expect the economy to normalize.</p>



<p>But there&#8217;s tremendous uncertainty.&nbsp; But we and other external forecasters expect that inflation will ease over the coming year (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; I have a couple of questions.&nbsp; The first is: If you could explain the Reserve fund a little bit more, because it looks like, from the &#8212; from the S-2 table, that the deficit reduction is including the tax proposals that you guys are putting forward.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m trying to understand how the reserve fund would work but also not impede the deficit reduction you guys are hoping to achieve over the next decade.</p>



<p>And then, just quickly, I was wondering if there are any changes to the top individual income rate in this and then also the provision on stock buyback.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t see that listed here just yet.<br><br>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; So, let me be clear &#8212; and thank you for the question and the opportunity to explain.&nbsp; The tax proposals we’re holding for the deficit-neutral reserve fund are different than the tax proposals we are accounting for our deficit reduction proposals.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re paying for our investments on top of what we&#8217;re holding in the deficit-neutral reserve fund.&nbsp; We felt it was the responsible thing to do to not double-count those savings, so those things &#8212; those are two separate proposals.&nbsp; So you don&#8217;t see a line item of those tax proposals in the deficit-neutral reserve fund, but they are separate and apart from the line items you do see included, as far as tax reforms in the budget.</p>



<p>As far as the individual rate, the top rate goes to 39.6 percent &#8212; the same as under President Obama and Biden administration.&nbsp; And so those are, I believe, the two major questions you had.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing &#8212; thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I’m hearing a weird echo, but we&#8217;ll try anyway.</p>



<p>Basically, my core question is: A lot of the budget experts are saying, you know, look, the reason the deficit is falling is because the expiration of inherently temporary economic programs, and it&#8217;s kind of absurd for the administration to be taking credit&nbsp;for the decline from inherently temporary economic programs.&nbsp; Can I get a response to that?&nbsp; Is that (inaudible), or do you think that (inaudible)?<br><br>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; Three letters: ARP.&nbsp; This was not by accident.&nbsp; And had the President not had the wisdom and the fortitude, as some people were saying it was time to retract and stop doing pandemic spending, I don’t believe and many experts don’t believe we’d be here.&nbsp; The growth we saw last year, the highest in 40 years, that added more jobs than ever recorded last year, we don&#8217;t believe was by accident.&nbsp; And without the American Rescue Plan, we don&#8217;t believe we would be here.&nbsp;<br><br>The scarring we&#8217;ve seen after past recessionary (inaudible) and after the last economic failure after Wall Street, we saw significant scarring that took years for the economy to come through.&nbsp; So, we believe that was the right medicine at the time.&nbsp; And everything that the President is rightfully taking credit for, you can find right back to the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Hi, this is Cecilia Rouse.&nbsp; And I would just add that if we go back to the Great Recession, it took about four years for us to return to this normal fiscal posture, and we&#8217;re doing it in two.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this question.&nbsp; One question on the inflation assumption.&nbsp; So, 2.3 percent this year and next year, and stable, is not realistic.&nbsp; Under a more realistic inflation assumption, can you still claim $1 trillion in deficit reduction?&nbsp; Would you still stand by that number?&nbsp;<br><br>And then, also the fact that you have a placeholder for Build Back Better, does that mean that the talks are close?&nbsp; Can you tell us how hopeful you are coming to a deal?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>DIRECTOR YOUNG:&nbsp; Eric, I&#8217;ll take the first one, the &#8212; your second question first, before turning it over to Chair Rouse on inflation.&nbsp;<br><br>What we&#8217;re not going to do &#8212; and I think I mentioned in the opening remarks &#8212; is get ahead of congressional negotiations.&nbsp; The deficit-neutral reserve fund is meant to leave the space, the revenue specifically, to allow congressional negotiators the room to do what President Biden has asked.&nbsp; He has asked for legislation that reduce costs for Americans and reduces the deficit.&nbsp; So that is what the budget is putting forth.&nbsp;<br><br>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; And regarding the inflation: So, as I noted earlier, this budget was locked and our forecasts were locked before various factors, which have led forecasters, including the Fed, to raise their inflation expectations.&nbsp; Of course, the most recent example is the Russian invasion of Ukraine and its impact on energy and food prices.&nbsp;<br><br>We will have a chance to update our forecast for the next budget.&nbsp; And those will &#8212; and that update will reflect recent events that were unknown at the time of the forecast.&nbsp;<br><br>But regarding the impact of this inflation on deficit impacts, so what you see is that &#8212; this shows we have actually done analysis of the impact of unexpected changes in inflation on our budget.&nbsp; And based on that analysis, inflation above the forecast raises both expenditures and revenues by similar amounts, such that it will have little impact on the deficit overall.<br><br>MR. FRIEDLANDER:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, Moderator.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;ve got time for one more.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; This question is for Chair Rouse and it also relates to the inflation forecasts.&nbsp; You also have a very low interest rate forecast, which I &#8212; you locked in last November.&nbsp; But as we&#8217;ve all seen, the Federal Reserve has accelerated its plans to tighten (inaudible), and it&#8217;s already set in plans to get the funds rate to 2.8 percent next year, and now it&#8217;s assumed that it will get there this year &#8212; perhaps as soon as this year and perhaps even further.&nbsp;<br><br>That&#8217;s quite a lot higher than the Treasury yield forecasts in your economic assumptions.&nbsp; Can you tell me how a more up-to-date interest rate assumption might affect the budget outlook, the deficits and debts, et cetera?&nbsp;<br><br>CHAIR ROUSE:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, it&#8217;s important to remember that our debt service line in our summary tables is based on real debt service and real interest rates.&nbsp; So even as nominal rates have been rising, real rates remain negative and will very likely remain negative in the near term.<br><br>In the longer term, our interest rate assumptions remain in sync with the market and other forecasters’ expectations, leaving to the fact that under the President&#8217;s budget, real interest rate payments remain below their historical average throughout the coming decade.<br><br>MR. FRIEDLANDER:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; And thank you all again for joining.&nbsp; A reminder this call is on the record and embargoed until 11:00 a.m. Eastern time today, as are the materials that we provided to you earlier.&nbsp;<br><br>If you have additional questions, feel free to be in touch with us by email or phone, and we will be happy to follow up.&nbsp; Hope everyone has a great day.&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp;<br><br>8:57 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taking on Gun Crime and Violence with a Whole-of-Government&#160;Approach</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2022/03/28/taking-on-gun-crime-and-violence-with-a-whole-of-government-approach/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 15:12:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49876</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In his State of the Union address earlier this month, President Biden highlighted his comprehensive strategy to reduce gun violence. He emphasized the $350 billion in American Rescue Plan funds that we’ve made available for cities, counties, and states that enable them to hire more police and invest in proven strategies like community violence intervention.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In his State of the Union <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/02/remarks-by-president-biden-in-state-of-the-union-address/">address</a> earlier this month, President Biden highlighted his comprehensive strategy to reduce gun violence. He emphasized the $350 billion in American Rescue Plan funds that we’ve made available for cities, counties, and states that enable them to hire more police and invest in proven strategies like community violence intervention. He talked about our efforts to crack down on difficult-to-trace “ghost guns,” part of an aggressive array of executive actions to reduce gun violence, taking more steps than any other Administration in its first year. And he repeated his call for Congress to take further action tackle the gun violence epidemic that continues to take more than 100 lives each day.</p>



<p>We have made strong progress by rolling out and executing on the President’s comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy. This strategy contains five key components:</p>



<ul><li>Stemming the flow of firearms used to commit violence,</li><li>Supporting local law enforcement with federal tools and resources to put more cops on the beat and address violent crime</li><li>Investing in evidence-based community violence interventions</li><li>Expanding summer programming, employment opportunities, and other services and supports for teenagers and young adults to give them pathways away from crime</li><li>Helping formerly incarcerated individuals successfully reenter their communities instead of re-offending.</li></ul>



<p>You can read a full summary of the progress we’ve made <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-bidens-historic-actions-to-make-our-communities-safer-by-reducing-gun-crime/">here</a>. We are pulling all of the levers of the federal government to address this crisis. For example:</p>



<ul><li>The President secured a bipartisan investment in fighting gun crime, including a new $50 million initiative to expand community violence interventions, additional funding for community policing, and the resources the Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco and Firearms (ATF) needs to continue to enforce our existing gun laws.</li><li>The Administration made American Rescue Plan funds available for fighting gun crime, and cities and states across the country have taken up this opportunity.</li><li>The Justice Department is taking regulatory action to rein in the proliferation of “ghost guns”—unserialized, homemade firearms that are difficult for law enforcement to trace.</li><li>The Justice Department launched five new law enforcement strike forces focused on addressing firearms trafficking, including on the “Iron Pipeline” – the illegal flow of guns sold in the south, transported up the East Coast, and found at crime scenes from Baltimore to New York City.</li><li>In part due to action by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services, Connecticut and Illinois enacted legislation that allows Medicaid to reimburse providers for hospital-based gun violence prevention services.</li></ul>



<p>That progress is made possible by the dedicated gun violence prevention team we have at the White House, working to combat gun violence—every day, from every angle. Under the leadership of Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, I coordinate the White House’s gun violence work. The solutions to gun violence are interdisciplinary, which is why we have built a multi-faceted, 12-person team of experts here in the heart of the Domestic Policy Council who have teamed up to drive forward our gun violence reduction agenda.</p>



<p><strong>Chiraag Bains </strong>(Deputy Assistant to the President for Racial Justice and Equity), <strong>Vanessa Chen </strong>(Special Assistant to the President for Criminal Justice and Guns), and <strong>Stephonn Alcorn </strong>(Associate Director for Racial Justice and Equity) all bring their expertise in criminal justice reform and racial justice to help guide our work to expand community violence interventions. I work side by side with this team, along with <strong>Erin Murphy</strong> (Senior Policy Advisor for Criminal Justice), on broader issues related to public safety that often intersect with gun violence.</p>



<p>Vanessa leads our interagency policy council on school safety, working closely with <strong>Mo-Tracey Mooney</strong>, Special Assistant to the President for Education and the Domestic Policy Council’s expert on K-12 education.</p>



<p>We’re also fortunate to have <strong>Terri Tanielian</strong> (Special Assistant to the President for Veterans Affairs), who specializes in veteran issues, mental health, and suicide prevention, supporting our work on reducing access to lethal means through methods such as safe storage.</p>



<p>And, <strong>Pronita Gupta</strong> (Special Assistant to the President for Labor and Workers), ensures that job training and job opportunities for young adults and formerly incarcerated individuals are a core component of our comprehensive approach to reducing gun crime.</p>



<p><strong>Jessica Schubel</strong>, Director for the Affordable Care Act and Health Care, contributes her expertise in utilizing Medicaid and private insurance to support violence intervention programs.</p>



<p><strong>Priya Singh, </strong>Deputy Chief of Staff and Senior Policy Analyst, and<strong> Clarence Wardell</strong>, Senior Advisor for Delivery, specialize in bridging the gap between policy and people, including making sure that our investments in community violence intervention are having an impact on the ground.</p>



<p>Last but not least, <strong>Erin Pelton</strong>, Special Assistant to the President and Chief of Staff for the Domestic Policy Council, helps shape our legislative, public engagement, and intergovernmental affairs strategies.</p>



<p>All of us on the Domestic Policy Council work closely with our colleagues in the <strong>White House Counsel’s Office</strong>, the <strong>Office of Public Engagement</strong>, the <strong>Office of Legislative Affairs</strong>, and the <strong>Office of Intergovernmental Affairs</strong>. And each of us coordinates with our counterparts in key agencies across government, from the Department of Justice to the Department of Education to the Department of Veterans Affairs. Together, we convene multi-agency meetings to coordinate on a specific goal, hold one-on-one meetings to drive the work of a particular agency, and meet with gun violence survivors and experts, as well as state and local policymakers.</p>



<p>The strength of this integrated approach is that it enables us to see <em>across</em> issue areas, and avoid the silos that too often stymie progress. When the President’s top advisors were hammering out the details of his Build Back Better Agenda, our team ensured that it included a historic $5 billion across the Department of Justice and Department of Health and Human Services to invest in community violence intervention. When workforce training was on the agenda, we were able to work with the Department of Labor to prioritize employment for formerly incarcerated individuals to reduce recidivism. After Medicaid policy advisors at the White House and the Department of Health and Human Services briefed states on how Medicaid funds could be used to reimburse CVI programs, Connecticut and Illinois became the first two states to adopt this promising approach. Policymakers often talk about taking a “whole-of-government” approach to an issue. This is what a whole-of-government effort truly looks like in practice.</p>



<p>Driven by President Biden’s career-long commitment to combating gun violence, and guided every day by the President’s top advisor on domestic policy, our team is able to combine a deep focus on this issue with the ability to deliver on it across the White House and the Administration as a whole. That’s how we’ve been able to carry out a comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy that’s done more through executive action than any President in their first year in history, and how we’ve backed it up with historic amounts of funding for cities and states to make their communities safer. And that’s also how we’ve continued to amplify the voices of survivors and advocates and elevate them with the President’s bully pulpit – from the halls of Congress to the Rose Garden – the vital need for Congress to act on common sense gun violence prevention measures.</p>



<p>As the President acknowledged in his State of the Union remarks, there is much more to do, which is why this team wakes up every day eager to advance this essential work. The President will continue to implement his comprehensive gun crime reduction strategy. Just as he did in his State of the Union Address, he will continue to call on Congress to takes steps that cannot be achieved through executive action and do not violate the Second Amendment – like universal background checks, a ban on assault weapons with high-capacity magazines, and repeal of the liability shield for gun manufacturers and dealers. He will continue to increase investments in community policing and community violence interventions. And we will help him get the job done in order to save lives.</p>



<p><em>Stefanie Feldman is Deputy Assistant to the President and Senior Advisor to the Domestic Policy Advisor</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on the FY 2023&#160;Budget</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/28/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-fy-2023-budget/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Budgets are statements of values, and the budget I am releasing today sends a clear message that we value fiscal responsibility, safety and security at home and around the world, and the investments needed to&#160;continue our equitable growth and&#160;build a better America. My&#160;Administration is on track to&#160;reduce the&#160;federal&#160;deficit by&#160;more than $1.3 trillion&#160;this year, cutting in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Budgets are statements of values, and the budget I am releasing today sends a clear message that we value fiscal responsibility, safety and security at home and around the world, and the investments needed to&nbsp;continue our equitable growth and&nbsp;build a better America.</p>



<p>My&nbsp;Administration is on track to&nbsp;reduce the&nbsp;federal&nbsp;deficit by&nbsp;more than $1.3 trillion&nbsp;this year, cutting in half the deficit from the last year of the previous&nbsp;Administration and delivering&nbsp;the largest&nbsp;one-year&nbsp;reduction in the deficit in U.S. history.&nbsp;That’s the direct result of&nbsp;my Administration’s&nbsp;<a></a>strategy to get the pandemic under control and grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out. We spent less money than the last Administration and got better results:&nbsp;strong economic growth, which&nbsp;has increased&nbsp;revenues and&nbsp;allowed&nbsp;us to responsibly scale back emergency spending.&nbsp;My budget will continue that progress, further reducing the deficit&nbsp;by continuing to support the economic growth that has increased&nbsp;revenues&nbsp;and&nbsp;ensuring that billionaires and&nbsp;large&nbsp;corporations pay their fair share.</p>



<p>At the same time, my budget will&nbsp;make investments in securing our nation and building a better America. We willsecure our communities by putting&nbsp;more police on the street&nbsp;to engage in&nbsp;accountable&nbsp;community policing,&nbsp;hiringthe agents&nbsp;needed&nbsp;to help fight gun crime, and investing in&nbsp;crime prevention and community violence intervention.</p>



<p>I’m calling for&nbsp;one of the largest investments in our national security in history, with the funds needed to ensure that our military remains the best-prepared, best-trained, best-equipped military in the world. &nbsp;In addition, I’m calling for continued investment&nbsp;to forcefully respond to Putin’s aggression against Ukraine&nbsp;with US support for Ukraine’s&nbsp;economic,&nbsp;humanitarian,&nbsp;and security&nbsp;needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My&nbsp;budget&nbsp;also&nbsp;makes&nbsp;the investments needed&nbsp;to&nbsp;reducecosts for families&nbsp;and make progress on my Unity Agenda – including investments to&nbsp;cut the costs of child care and health care; help families pay for other essentials;&nbsp;endcancer&nbsp;as we know it;&nbsp;support our veterans;&nbsp;and&nbsp;get all Americans the mental health services they need.</p>



<p>All told, it is a budget that&nbsp;includes&nbsp;historic deficit reduction, historic investments in our security at home and abroad, and an unprecedented commitment to building an economy where everyone has a chance to succeed.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine&#160;Jean-Pierre</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/27/statement-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 00:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49788</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This afternoon, after returning from the President’s trip to Europe, I took a PCR test. That test came back positive.&#160; I last saw the President during a socially distanced meeting yesterday, and the President is not considered a close contact as defined by CDC guidance. I am sharing the news of my positive test today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This afternoon, after returning from the President’s trip to Europe, I took a PCR test. That test came back positive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I last saw the President during a socially distanced meeting yesterday, and the President is not considered a close contact as defined by CDC guidance. I am sharing the news of my positive test today out of an abundance of transparency. <br> <br>Thanks to being fully vaccinated and boosted, I have only experienced mild symptoms. In alignment with White House COVID-19 protocols, I will work from home and plan to return to work in person at the conclusion of a five-day isolation period and a negative test.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the United Efforts of the Free World to Support the People of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/26/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-united-efforts-of-the-free-world-to-support-the-people-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 21:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49775</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Royal Castle in WarsawWarsaw, Poland 6:16 P.M. CET THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; Please, if you have a seat, be seated.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; If you don’t, come up on stage. Thank you very much.&#160; It’s a great honor to be here.&#160; Mr. President, they tell me you’re over there somewhere.&#160; There you&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The Royal Castle in Warsaw<br>Warsaw, Poland</p>



<p>6:16 P.M. CET<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Please, if you have a seat, be seated.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; If you don’t, come up on stage.<br><br>Thank you very much.&nbsp; It’s a great honor to be here.&nbsp; Mr. President, they tell me you’re over there somewhere.&nbsp; There you are.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp;<br><br>“Be not afraid.”&nbsp; They were the first words at the first public address of the first Polish Pope after his election on October of 1978.&nbsp; They were words that would come to define Pope John Paul II.&nbsp; Words that would change the world.<br><br>John Paul brought the message here to Warsaw in his first trip back home as Pope in June of 1979.&nbsp; It was a message about the power &#8212; the power of faith, the power of resilience, and the power of the people.&nbsp;<br><br>In the face of a cruel and brutal system of government, it was a message that helped end the Soviet repression in the Central land and Eastern Europe 30 years ago.&nbsp; It was a message that will overcome the cruelty and brutality of this unjust war.&nbsp;<br><br>When Pope John Paul brought that message in 1979, the Soviet Union ruled with an iron fist behind an Iron Curtain.<br><br>Then a year later, the Solidarity movement took hold in Poland.&nbsp; And while I know he couldn’t be here tonight, we’re all grateful in America and around the world for Lech Wałęsa.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>It reminds me of that phrase of philosopher Kierkegaard: “[F]aith sees best in the dark.”&nbsp; And there were dark moments.<br><br>Ten years later, the Soviet Union collapsed, and Poland and Central and Eastern Europe would soon be free.&nbsp; Nothing about that battle for freedom was simple or easy.&nbsp; It was a long, painful slog fought over not days and months, but years and decades.<br><br>But we emerged anew in the great battle for freedom: a battle between democracy and autocracy, between liberty and repression, between a rules-based order and one governed by brute force.<br><br>In this battle, we need to be clear-eyed.&nbsp; This battle will not be won in days or months either.&nbsp; We need to steel ourselves for the long fight ahead.<br><br>Mr. President, Mr. Prime Minister, Mr. Mayor, members of the Parliament, distinguished guests, and the people of Poland, and I suspect some people of Ukraine that are here: We’re &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we are gathered here at the Royal Castle in this city that holds a sacred place in the history of not only of Europe, but humankind’s unending search for freedom.<br><br>For generations, Warsaw has stood where liberty has been challenged and liberty has prevailed.<br><br>In fact, it was here in Warsaw when a young refugee, who fled her home country from Czechoslovakia was under&nbsp;Soviet domination, came back to speak and stand in solidarity with dissidents.<br><br>Her name was Madeleine Korbel Albright.&nbsp; She became &#8212; (applause) &#8212; one of the most ardent supporters of democracy in the world.&nbsp; She was a friend with whom I served.&nbsp; America’s first woman Secretary of State.&nbsp; She passed away three days ago.<br><br>She fought her whole life for essential democratic principles.&nbsp; And now, in the perennial struggle for democracy and freedom, Ukraine and its people are on the frontlines fighting to save their nation.<br><br>And their brave resistance is part of a larger fight for an essential democratic principles that unite all free people: the rule of law; free and fair elections; the freedom to speak, to write, and to assemble; the freedom to worship as one chooses; freedom of the press.<br><br>These principles are essential in a free society.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But they have always &#8212; they have always been under siege.&nbsp; They’ve always been embattled.&nbsp; Every generation has had to defeat democracy’s mortal foes.&nbsp; That’s the way of the world &#8212; for the world is imperfect, as we know.&nbsp; Where the appetites and ambitions of a few forever seek to dominate the lives and liberties of many.<br><br>My message to the people of Ukraine is the message I delivered today to Ukraine’s Foreign Minister and Defense Minister, who I believe are here tonight: We stand with you.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Today’s fighting in Kyiv and Mariupol and Kharkiv are the latest battle in a long struggle: Hungary, 1956; Poland, 1956 then again 1981; Czechoslovakia, 1968.&nbsp;<br><br>Soviet tanks crushed democratic uprisings, but the resistance continued until finally, in 1989, the Berlin Wall and all of the walls of Soviet domination &#8212; they fell.&nbsp; They fell.&nbsp; And the people prevailed.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>But the battle for democracy could not conclude and did not conclude with the end of the Cold War.<br><br>Over the last 30 years, the forces of autocracy have revived all across the globe.&nbsp; Its hallmarks are familiar ones: contempt for the rule of law, contempt for democratic freedom, contempt for the truth itself.<br><br>Today, Russia has strangled democracy &#8212; has sought to do so elsewhere, not only in its homeland.&nbsp; Under false claims of ethnic solidarity, it has&nbsp;<s>invalidated</s>&nbsp;[invaded] neighboring nations.<br><br>Putin has the gall to say he’s “de-Nazifying” Ukraine.&nbsp; It’s a lie.&nbsp; It’s just cynical.&nbsp; He knows that.&nbsp; And it’s also obscene.<br><br>President Zelenskyy was democratically elected.&nbsp; He’s Jewish.&nbsp; His father’s family was wiped out in the Nazi Holocaust.&nbsp; And Putin has the audacity, like all autocrats before him, to believe that might will make right.<br><br>In my own country, a former president named Abraham Lincoln voiced the opposing spirit to save our Union in the midst of a civil war.&nbsp; He said, “Let us have faith that right makes might.”&nbsp; “Right makes might.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Today, let us now have that faith again.&nbsp; Let us resolve to put the strength of democracies into action to thwart the denigns [sic] of our &#8212; the designs of autocracy.&nbsp; Let us remember that the test of this moment is the test of all time.<br><br>The Kremlin wants to portray NATO enlargement as an imperial project aimed at destabilizing Russia.&nbsp; Nothing is further from the truth.&nbsp; NATO is a defensive alliance.&nbsp;&nbsp;It has never sought the demise of Russia.<br><br>In the lead-up to the current crisis, the United States and NATO worked for months to engage Russia to avert a war.&nbsp; I met with him in person and talked to him many times on the phone.&nbsp;<br><br>Time and again, we offered real diplomacy and concrete proposals to strengthen European security, enhance transparency, and build confidence on all sides.<br><br>But Putin and Russia met each of the proposals with disinterest in any negotiation, with lies and ultimatums.&nbsp; Russia was bent on violence from the start.<br><br>I know not all of you believed me and us when we kept saying, “They are going to cross the border.&nbsp; They are going to attack.”&nbsp;<br><br>Repeatedly, he asserted, “We have no interest in war.”&nbsp; Guaranteed he would not move.&nbsp;<br><br>Repeatedly saying he would not invade Ukraine.<br><br>Repeatedly saying Russian troops along the border were there for “training” &#8212; all 180,000 of them.&nbsp;<br><br>There is simply no justification or provocation for Russia’s choice of war.&nbsp; It’s an example of one of the oldest of human impulses: using brute force and disinformation to satisfy a craving for absolute power and control.<br><br>It’s nothing less than a direct challenge to the rule-based international order established since the end of World War Two.<br><br>And it threatens to return to decades of war that ravaged Europe before the international rule-based order was put in place.&nbsp; We cannot go back to that.&nbsp; We cannot.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The gravity of the threat is why the response of the West has been so swift and so powerful and so unified, unprecedented, and overwhelming.<br><br>Swift and punishing costs are the only things that are going to get Russia to change its course.&nbsp;<br><br>Within days of its invasion, the West had moved jointly with sanctions to damage Russia’s economy.<br><br>Russia’s Central Bank is now blocked from the global financial systems, denying Kremlin’s access to the war fund it stashed around the globe.<br><br>We’ve aimed at the heart of Russia’s economy by stopping the imports of Russian energy to the United States.<br><br>To date, the United States has sanctioned 140 Russian oligarchs and their family members, seizing their ill-begotten gains: their yachts, their luxury apartments, their mansions.<br><br>We’ve sanctioned more than 400 Russian government officials, including key architects of this war.<br><br>These officials and oligarchs have reaped enormous benefit from the corruption connected to the Kremlin, and now they have to share in the pain.&nbsp;<br><br>The private sector is acting as well.&nbsp; Over 400 private multinational companies have pulled out of doing business in Russia &#8212; left Russia completely &#8212; from oil companies to McDonald’s.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>As a result of these unprecedented sanctions, the ruble almost is immediately reduced to rubble.&nbsp; The Russian economy &#8212; (applause) &#8212; that’s true, by the way.&nbsp; It takes about 200 rubles to equal one dollar.&nbsp;<br><br>The economy is on track to be cut in half in the coming years.&nbsp; It was ranked &#8212; Russia’s economy was ranked the 11th biggest economy in the world before this evasion [sic] &#8212; invasion.&nbsp; It will soon not even rank among the top 20 in the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Taken together, these economic sanctions are a new kind of economic statecraft with the power to inflict damage that rivals military might.<br><br>These international sanctions are sapping Russian strength, its ability to replenish its military, and its ability &#8212; its ability to project power.&nbsp;&nbsp;And it is Putin &#8212; it is Vladimir Putin who is to blame, period.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, alongside these economic sanctions, the Western world has come together to provide for the people of Ukraine with incredible levels of military, economic, and humanitarian assistance.<br><br>In the years before the invasion, we, America, had sent over $650 million, before they crossed the border, in weapons to Ukraine, including anti-air and anti-armor equipment.<br><br>Since the invasion, America has committed another $1.35 billion in weapons and ammunition.<br><br>And thanks to the courage and bravery of the Ukrainian people &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the equipment we&#8217;ve sent and our colleagues have sent have been used to devastating effect to defend Ukrainian land and airspace.&nbsp; Our Allies and partners have stepped up as well.<br><br>But as I’ve made clear: American forces are in Europe &#8212; not in Europe to engage in conflict with Russian forces.&nbsp; American forces are here to defend NATO Allies.<br><br>Yesterday, I met with the troops that are serving alongside our Polish allies to bolster NATO’s frontline defenses.&nbsp; The reason we wanted to make clear is their movement on Ukraine: Don’t even think about moving on one single inch of NATO territory.<br><br>We have a sacred obligation &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we have a sacred obligation under Article 5 to defend each and every inch of NATO territory with the full force of our collective power.<br><br>And earlier today, I visited your National Stadium, where thousands of Ukrainian refugees are now trying to answer the toughest questions a human can ask: “My God, what’s going to happen to me?&nbsp; What’s going to happen to my family?”<br><br>I saw tears in many of the mothers’ eyes as I embraced them; their young children &#8212; their young children not sure whether to smile or cry.&nbsp; One little girl said, “Mr. President” &#8212; she spoke a little English &#8212; “is my brother and my daddy &#8212; are they going to be okay?&nbsp; Will I see them again?”&nbsp; Without their husbands, their fathers, in many cases, their brothers or sisters who stayed back to fight for their country.<br><br>I didn’t have to speak the language or understand the language to feel the emotion in their eyes, the way they gripped my hand, and little kids hung on to my leg, praying with a desperate hope that all this is temporary; apprehension that they may be perhaps forever away from their homes, almost with debilitating sadness that this is happening all over again.<br><br>But I was also struck by the generosity of the people of Warsaw &#8212; for that matter, all the Polish people &#8212; for the depths of their compassion, their willingness to reach out &#8212; (applause) &#8212; opening their hearts.<br><br>I was saying to the Mayor they’re preparing to open their hearts and their homes simply to help.&nbsp; I also want to thank my friend, the great American chef, José Andrés, and his team who helped feeling [sic] those &#8212; (applause) &#8212; feeding those who are yearning to be free.&nbsp;<br><br>But helping these refugees is not something Poland or any other nation should carry alone.&nbsp; All the world democracies have a responsibility to help.&nbsp; All of them.&nbsp; And the people of Ukraine can count on the United States to meet its responsibility.<br><br>I&#8217;ve announced, two days ago, we will welcome 100,000 Ukrainian refugees.&nbsp; We already have 8,000 a week coming to the United States of other nat- &#8212; nationalities.<br><br>We’ll provide nearly $300 million of humanitarian assistance, providing tens of thousands of tons of food, water, medicine, and other basic supplies.<br><br>In Brussels, I announced the United States is prepared to provide more than $1 billion, in addition, in humanitarian aid.<br><br>The World Food Programme told us that despite significant obstacles, at least some relief is getting to major cities in Ukraine, but not Metropol [sic] &#8212; no, excuse me, Mar- &#8212; not Mariupol, because Russian forces are blocking relief supplies.<br><br>But we’ll not cease our efforts to get humanitarian relief wherever it is needed in Ukraine and for the people who’ve made it out of Ukraine.<br><br>Notwithstanding the brutality of Vladimir Putin, let there be no doubt that this war has already been a strategic failure for Russia already.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Having lost children myself &#8212; I know that’s no solace to the people who’ve lost family.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But he, Putin, thought Ukrainians would roll over and not fight.&nbsp; Not much of a student of history.&nbsp; Instead, Russian forces have met their match with brave and stiff Ukrainian resistance.<br><br>Rather than breaking Ukrainian resolve, Russia’s brutal tactics have strengthened the resolve.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Rather than driving NATO apart, the West is now stronger and more united than it has ever been.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Russia wanted less of a NATO presence on its border, but now&nbsp;<s>he has</s>&nbsp;[we have] a stronger presence, a larger presence, with over a hundred thousand American troops here, along with all the other members of NATO.<br><br>In fact &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Russia has managed to cause something I’m sure he never intended: The democracies of the world are revitalized with purpose and unity found in months that we’d once taken years to accomplish.<br><br>It’s not only Russia’s actions in Ukraine that are reminding us of democracy’s blessing.&nbsp; It’s our own country &#8212; his own country, the Kremlin, is jailing protestors.&nbsp; Two hundred thousand people have allegedly already left.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a brain drain &#8212; leaving Russia.&nbsp; Shutting down independent news.&nbsp; State media is all propaganda, blocking the image of civilian targets, mass graves, starvation tactics of the Russian forces in Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Is it any wonder, as I said, that 200,000 Russians have all left their country in one month?&nbsp; A remarkable brain drain in such a short period of time, which brings me to my message to the Russian people:<br><br>I&#8217;ve worked with Russian leaders for decades.&nbsp; I sat across the negotiating table going all the way back to Soviet Premier Alexei Kosygin to talk arms control at the height of the Cold War.<br><br>I&#8217;ve always spoken directly and honestly to you, the Russian people.&nbsp;<br><br>Let me say this, if you&#8217;re able to listen: You, the Russian people, are not our enemy.&nbsp;<br><br>I refuse to believe that you welcome the killing of innocent children and grandparents or that you accept hospitals, schools, maternity wards that, for God’s sake, are being pummeled with Russian missiles and bombs; or cities being surrounded so that civilians cannot flee; supplies cut off and attempting to starve Ukrainians into submission.&nbsp;<br><br>Millions of families are being driven from their homes, including half of all Ukraine’s children.&nbsp; These are not the actions of a great nation.&nbsp;<br><br>Of all people, you, the Russian people, as well as all people across Europe, still have the memory of being in a similar situation in the late thirties and forties &#8212; the situation of World War Two &#8212; still fresh in the minds of many grandparents in the region.<br><br>What &#8212; whatever your generation experienced &#8212; whether it experienced the Siege of Leningrad or heard about it from your parents and grandparents &#8212; train stations overflowing with terrified families fleeing their homes; nights sheltering in basements and cellars; mornings sitting through the rubble in your homes &#8212; these are not memories of the past.&nbsp; Not anymore.&nbsp; Because it’s exactly what the Russian army is doing in Ukraine right now.&nbsp;<br><br>March 26, 2022.&nbsp; Just days before &#8212; we’re at the twenty-fir- &#8212; you were a 21st century nation with hopes and dreams that people all over the world have for themselves and their family.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, Vladimir Putin’s aggression have cut you, the Russian people, off from the rest of the world, and it’s taking Russia back to the 19th century.<br><br>This is not who you are.&nbsp; This is not the future reserve &#8212; you deserve for your families and your children.&nbsp; I’m telling you the truth: This war is not worthy of you, the Russian people.<br><br>Putin can and must end this war.&nbsp; The American people stand with you and the brave citizens of Ukraine who want peace.<br><br>And my message to the rest of Europe: This new battle for freedom has already made a few things crystal clear.&nbsp;<br><br>First, Europe must end its dependence on Russian fossil fuels.&nbsp; And we, the United States, will help.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That’s why just yesterday, in Brussels, I announced a plan with the President of the European Commission to get Europe through the immediate energy crisis.<br><br>Over the long term, as a matter of economic security and national security and for the survivability of the planet, we all need to move as quickly as possible to clean, renewable energy.&nbsp; And we’ll work together to help get that done so that the days of any nation being subject to the whims of a tyrant for its energy needs are over.&nbsp; They must end.&nbsp; They must end.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And second, we have to fight the corruption coming from the Kremlin to give the Russian people a fair chance.<br><br>And finally, and most urgently, we maintain absolute unity &#8212; we must &#8212; among the world’s democracies.<br><br>It’s not enough to speak with rhetorical flourish, of ennobling words of democracy, of freedom, equality, and liberty.&nbsp; All of us, including here in Poland, must do the hard work of democracy each and every day.&nbsp; My country as well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why &#8212; (applause) &#8212; that’s why I came to Europe again this week with a clear and determined message for NATO, for the G7, for the European Union, for all freedom-loving nations: We must commit now to be in this fight for the long haul.&nbsp; We must remain unified today and tomorrow and the day after and for the years and decades to come.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>It will not be easy.&nbsp; There will be costs.&nbsp; But it’s a price we have to pay.&nbsp; Because the darkness that drives autocracy is ultimately no match for the flame of liberty that lights the souls of free people everywhere.<br><br>Time and again, history shows that it’s from the darkest moments that the greatest progress follows.&nbsp; And history shows this is the task of our time, the task of this generation.<br><br>Let&#8217;s remember: The hammer blow that brought down the Berlin Wall, the might that lifted the Iron Curtain were not the words of a single leader; it was the people of Europe who, for decades, fought to free themselves.<br><br>Their sheer bravery opened the border between Austria and Hungary for the Pan-European Picnic.&nbsp; They joined hands for the Baltic Way.&nbsp; They stood for Solidarity here in Poland.&nbsp; And together, it was an unmistakable and undeniable force of the people that the Soviet Union could not withstand.<br><br>And we’re seeing it once again today with the brave Ukrainian people, showing that their power of many is greater than the will of any one dictator.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>So, in this hour, let the words of Pope John Paul burn as brightly today: “Never, ever give up hope, never doubt, never tire, never become discouraged.&nbsp; Be not afraid.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>A dictator bent on rebuilding an empire will never erase a people’s love for liberty.&nbsp; Brutality will never grind down their will to be free.&nbsp; Ukraine will never be a victory for Russia &#8212; for free people refuse to live in a world of hopelessness and darkness.<br><br>We will have a different future &#8212; a brighter future rooted in democracy and principle, hope and light, of decency and dignity, of freedom and possibilities.&nbsp;<br><br>For God’s sake, this man cannot remain in power.&nbsp;<br><br>God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God defend our freedom.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for your patience.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>6:43 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden Call with Opposition Leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of&#160;Belarus</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/26/readout-of-president-biden-call-with-opposition-leader-svyatlana-tsikhanouskaya-of-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 19:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49771</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., spoke with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus from Air Force One. He thanked her for attending his speech in Warsaw tonight. The President underscored the continued support of the United States for the Belarusian people in defending and advancing human rights, including freedom of expression, and free and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., spoke with democratic opposition leader Svyatlana Tsikhanouskaya of Belarus from Air Force One. He thanked her for attending his speech in Warsaw tonight. The President underscored the continued support of the United States for the Belarusian people in defending and advancing human rights, including freedom of expression, and free and fair elections.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden After Meeting With Ukrainian&#160;Refugees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/26/remarks-by-president-biden-after-meeting-with-ukrainian-refugees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49768</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[PGE Narodowy StadiumWarsaw, Poland 3:28 P.M. CET Q    Mr. President, what do you think about Russia changing its strategy? THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m not sure they have. Q    And what&#8217;s the impact of this on you, Mr. President?  Tell us about what you saw. THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ve been to an awful lot of places like this with a lot of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">PGE Narodowy Stadium<br>Warsaw, Poland</p>



<p>3:28 P.M. CET<br> <br>Q    Mr. President, what do you think about Russia changing its strategy?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m not sure they have.<br> <br>Q    And what&#8217;s the impact of this on you, Mr. President?  Tell us about what you saw.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ve been to an awful lot of places like this with a lot of refugee camps in my life.  And what I &#8212; what I never &#8212; I&#8217;m always surprised by is the depth and strength of the human spirit.  I mean it sincerely.  And it’s incredible.  It’s incredible.<br> <br>You see all those little children?  Just wanted to &#8212; just want a hug.  They just want to say thanks.  I mean, they&#8217;re &#8212; I mean, it’s &#8212; it just makes you so damn proud.  And they&#8217;re wonderful, wonderful, wonderful. <br> <br>And, you know, the Ukrainian people are &#8212; each one of those children said something to the effect, “Say a prayer for my dad, for my grandfather, for my brother who’s back there fighting.”  And I remember what it’s like when you have someone in a war zone.  Every morning you get up and you wonder.  You just wonder.  You pray you don’t get that phone call.  And they&#8217;re an amazing group of people.<br> <br>Q    How does this make you think of &#8212;<br> <br>Q    How do you get into some of these cities like Mariupol that’s got &#8212; you know, that’s got nothing?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Oh, they’ve got nothing.  I met two people from Mariupol.  It’s &#8212; it’s astounding.<br> <br>Q    What were the commitments with Ukraine?<br> <br>Q    What is this &#8212; I mean, you see this in your &#8212; you know, you&#8217;re dealing every day with Vladimir Putin.  I mean, look at what he&#8217;s done to these people.  What does it make you think?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  He&#8217;s a butcher.  That’s what it makes me think. <br> <br>3:29 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with President Andrzej Duda of&#160;Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/26/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 15:01:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49765</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., met today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland in Warsaw. The leaders discussed ongoing international efforts to impose powerful sanctions on Russia for its unjustified and unprovoked attack on Ukraine. They also discussed their shared commitment to continue supporting the government and people of Ukraine. President Biden thanked President Duda&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr., met today with President Andrzej Duda of Poland in Warsaw. The leaders discussed ongoing international efforts to impose powerful sanctions on Russia for its unjustified and unprovoked attack on Ukraine. They also discussed their shared commitment to continue supporting the government and people of Ukraine. President Biden thanked President Duda and the people of Poland for opening their homes and hearts to their neighbors in need, and he pledged continued U.S. support to these humanitarian assistance efforts. President Biden underscored the United States’ unwavering commitment to Article 5 and to the security of all our NATO allies. In addition, the leaders discussed our robust bilateral defense cooperation, US support for Europe’s efforts to reduce its reliance on Russian energy and to meet our climate goals, and the democratic values on which the transatlantic relationship is based.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Andrzej Duda of Poland Before Expanded Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/26/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-before-expanded-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2022 14:58:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49762</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential PalaceWarsaw, Poland 1:44 P.M. CET PRESIDENT DUDA:&#160; Excellency Mr. President, distinguished members of the American delegation: I am delighted, and it is an immensely important moment to us to host you here, Mr. President, the President of the United States of America, along with the members of your delegation &#8212; to host you here&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Presidential Palace<br>Warsaw, Poland</p>



<p>1:44 P.M. CET</p>



<p>PRESIDENT DUDA:&nbsp; Excellency Mr. President, distinguished members of the American delegation: I am delighted, and it is an immensely important moment to us to host you here, Mr. President, the President of the United States of America, along with the members of your delegation &#8212; to host you here in Poland, in Warsaw, in this time so immensely important for the whole world.&nbsp; Thank you so much.</p>



<p>That &#8212; this presence shows in such an excellent way, but also strengthens the fact of extremely strong Euro-Atlantic ties.&nbsp; It also demonstrates the unity of the North Atlantic Alliance and the traditional cooperation in the military sphere, in the economic sphere, and also in the political sphere between the United States of America and Poland.</p>



<p>Thank you, Mr. President.&nbsp; We are grateful for your yesterday’s visit to Rzeszów, which is of extremely symbolic character to all of us.&nbsp; But it is also of key importance for all of those who are helping and assisting refugees from Ukraine on a daily basis.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Poles, guests from other countries, our volunteers, foreign volunteers &#8212; they are dedicating themselves; they are sacrificing their time, offering all the means and measures in order to help people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you, Mr. President, so much for paying that visit yesterday.&nbsp; It is hugely important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, thank you for all the help and assistance provided by the United States.&nbsp; Thank you for the contribution of the First Lady of the United States, Mrs. Jill Biden.&nbsp; Thank you for her consultations with my wife, for the assistance, and for an excellent atmosphere that you, Mr. President, and your wife create for all our matters in the United States.&nbsp; My wife recently visited New York, and she felt that great atmosphere.&nbsp; So, thank you so much.</p>



<p>But let me stress &#8212; and very strongly, Mr. President &#8212; that although times are very difficult, today, Polish-American relations are flourishing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are the first, the biggest customer buying American LNG gas.&nbsp; We have received LNG gas for many years.&nbsp; Our gas terminal in Świnoujście, it helps us to diversify our gas resources in Poland.&nbsp; It is hugely important, given today’s Russia’s aggression Ukraine, given this energy blackmail which Russia has pursued for many years right now.&nbsp; We have built that LNG terminal in Świnoujście precisely to fight this blackmail, to avoid this blackmail.&nbsp; And we are thankful for U.S. support in this respect.</p>



<p>Furthermore, we are grateful for continuing on this path.&nbsp; We started a program on civil nuclear energy &#8212; the construction of U.S. nuclear power plants in Poland, which are indispensable to us to protect the climate and to develop a modern energy sector in our country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I strongly believe that this partnership that we have between the United States and Poland in the development of nuclear energy in our country, in close cooperation between our two states, will be implemented and finalized.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I have here with me Minister Piotr Naimski who is responsible on the Polish side for this program.&nbsp; And I do believe that along with American companies, but under a strong patronage of the White House, we will be able to successfully implement in the near future, because Poland badly needs it.</p>



<p>Mr. President, we have very good economic relations.&nbsp; We have got &#8212; in 2021, according to our estimates, we had more than 18 billion U.S. dollars of trade volume, despite the coronavirus pandemic, despite other obstacles that were in the way.&nbsp; This, it makes us really pleased.&nbsp; We&#8217;re happy with all the U.S. investments in Poland.&nbsp; We are happy to welcome them here, just as we are happy to welcome U.S. soldiers who are coming up to us in order to strengthen the eastern flank.&nbsp; We are grateful for this help.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let me also stress, Mr. President: We are a serious partner.&nbsp; We are a credible ally.&nbsp; We do everything we can in order to live up to the task of defending our country ourselves.&nbsp; That is why we adopted a new bill, the Act on Defense of the Republic of Poland, and that is why as early as next year we will start to allocate 3 percent of our GDP on defense.&nbsp; That is why I want to, and we want to, increase those spendings also in the years to come.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We want to equip our armed forces with modern equipment, and that is why, in the future, we want &#8212; we intend to buy well-tested and modern military equipment that is produced in the United States of America.</p>



<p>But, of course, we would be very much interested in establishing a cooperation with the United States in this respect.&nbsp; And we are delighted with every element of this cooperation that is developing, such as the possibility to co-produce, in Poland, Black Hawks.&nbsp; And right now, we would like to have more forms of such cooperation also in the military sphere.</p>



<p>So, Mr. President, all the bonds that I mentioned, all of that is strengthened immensely by your visit, Mr. President, and we&#8217;re so much grateful for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is also important for the representatives of the U.S. business circles.&nbsp; Wherever you can, Mr. President, they feel that this place is safe and secure.&nbsp; So, Mr. President, we are so much grateful for your visit.</p>



<p>But let me stress one thing, sir: This is a very difficult situation, what is happening in Ukraine right now &#8212; this Russian aggression and this huge tragedy of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; All of us, together, are experiencing it with them.&nbsp; And this also creates a great sense of threat for my compatriots, for the Polish people, because we know what Russian imperialism stands for, and we know what it means to be attacked by Russian armed forces, because our grandfathers and great-grandfathers experienced that; sometimes even our parents experienced that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you for your presence.&nbsp; And thank you, first and foremost, for your incredible leadership, strong leadership.&nbsp; Thank you for this very strong voice of the United States which leads us and which very resolutely calls on Russia to stop its aggression against Ukraine.</p>



<p>We stand with the United States.&nbsp; And along with the United States, we want to pursue this policy.&nbsp; And we very much hope for decisive and strong leadership of the United States across the entire NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, we hope that we will further strengthen the Euro-Atlantic bond.&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President, once again for your presence.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Mr. President, thank you very much.&nbsp; Twenty-five years ago, when I spoke at a university here in Warsaw, after having led the effort for Poland to join NATO, I used the phrase &#8212; and my Ambassador reminded me of this &#8212; I said &#8212; started off by saying, “For your freedom and for ours.”&nbsp; “For your freedom and for ours.”&nbsp; I meant it then, and I mean it now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, Mr. President, we have &#8212; the most important thing that binds us together are our values: freedom &#8212; freedom of the press; making sure that people are &#8212; that government is transparent; making sure people have the right to vote, et cetera.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; we had a very &#8212; and I hope we haven&#8217;t kept you waiting.&nbsp; It’s good to be back in this room again, but I hope we didn’t keep you waiting too long.&nbsp; But we were discussing a lot of things in private, not the least of which was that, as I pointed out &#8212; and my colleagues, I&#8217;m confident, agree with me &#8212; is that America&#8217;s ability to meet its role in other parts of the world rests upon a united Europe and a secure Europe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have learned from sad experience in two world wars: When we&#8217;ve stayed out of and not been involved in stability in Europe, it always comes back to haunt us, the United States.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I&#8217;ve been saying for a long time &#8212; as a senator who visited here and a member the Foreign Relations Committee, as Vice President for eight years, now as President &#8212; that stability in Europe is critically important to the United States in terms of our interest not only in Europe, but around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, what we talked about is the need for us to stay in constant contact and know what one another are doing.&nbsp; The United States and my colleagues on this side of the table heard me say it many, many times: We take Article 5 as a sacred commitment, not a throwaway &#8212; a sacred commitment that relates to every member of NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the things that I thanked the President for downstairs was the fact that the single-most important criterion in this time of a changing world &#8212; so much has changed, and not just here but in other parts of the world &#8212; is that NATO stay absolutely, completely, thoroughly united; that there be no separation in our points of view; that whatever we do, we do in unison; and everyone &#8212; everyone comes along.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m confident that Vladimir Putin was counting on being able to divide NATO, to be able to separate the eastern flank from the West, be able to separate nations based on past histories.&nbsp; But he hasn&#8217;t been able to do it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve all stayed together.&nbsp; And &#8212; and so, I just think it&#8217;s so important that we &#8212; Poland and the United States &#8212; keep in lockstep in how we&#8217;re proceeding.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, we do acknowledge that Poland is taking on a significant responsibility that I don&#8217;t think should just be Poland, it should be the whole world &#8212; all of NATO’s responsibility.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fact that you have so many &#8212; so many Ukrainians seeking refuge in the &#8212; in this country of Poland, we understand that because we have, in our southern border, thousands of people a day &#8212; literally, not figuratively &#8212; trying to get into the United States.&nbsp; But we believe that we, the United States, should do our part, relative to Ukraine as well, by opening our borders to another hundred thousand people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; but that’s &#8212; and in addition to that, I think it&#8217;s important that we are in constant contact as about how we each wish to proceed, relative to what Russia is doing, and how to proceed.</p>



<p>And so, I &#8212; I just want to thank you, Mr. President, for being available, for being so cooperative, for being &#8212; and letting us know exactly what&#8217;s on your mind.&nbsp; It&#8217;s on the mind of the Polish people &#8212; what their concerns are and what they think our responsibilities are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I&#8217;ll end where I began, and that is: We take as a sacred obligation Article 5 &#8212; a sacred obligation, Article 5. &nbsp;And you can count on that.&nbsp; And not just &#8212; I’ll end where I began: for your freedom is ours.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, thank you very much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:57 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
