<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 16:34:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Announces the Americas Partnership for Economic&#160;Prosperity</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/fact-sheet-president-biden-announces-the-americas-partnership-for-economic-prosperity/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55101</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At the opening ceremony of the Summit of the Americas, President Biden will announce the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity, a historic new agreement to drive our hemisphere’s economy recovery and growth, and deliver for our working people. Accounting for 31.9 % of global GDP, the Western Hemisphere is one of the most dynamic economic&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>At the opening ceremony of the Summit of the Americas, President Biden will announce the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity, a historic new agreement to drive our hemisphere’s economy recovery and growth, and deliver for our working people. Accounting for 31.9 % of global GDP, the Western Hemisphere is one of the most dynamic economic regions in the world, and the United States’ ties with the rest of the hemisphere are broad and deep. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Still reeling from the disproportionate impact of the COVID-19 pandemic, Latin America and the Caribbean has seen the deepest economic contraction of any region in the world. Income inequality is widening, millions of people are being cast back into poverty, and global inflation – made worse by Putin’s war in Ukraine – is straining families’ budgets.&nbsp; The Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity will rebuild our economies from the bottom up and middle out.</p>



<p>Together with partners, we deepen our economic cooperation, focusing on the largest drivers of middle-out growth, and shaping new tools for the challenges facing us today and, in the decades, to come. We will strengthen our supply chains to be more resilient against unexpected shocks. We will foster innovation in both the public and private sectors, so governments can better address society’s most pressing challenges, and businesses can enhance their productivity. And we will tackle the climate crisis by growing climate-related industries that will give rise to high-quality jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a high-standards approach that is built on shared values, this partnership will support U.S. business and workers and support hemispheric recovery, resilience, and stability across the Americas. Following the conclusion of the Summit of the Americas, the United States will hold initial consultations with partners in the hemisphere and stakeholders on the following areas of focus: &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Reinvigorating Regional Economic Institutions and Mobilizing Investment</strong>. To deliver on our aspirations, we will work to pivot our public institutions and financing mechanisms to leverage far greater levels of private investment.&nbsp; We will together reinvigorate the hemisphere’s regional economic institutions, such as the Inter-American Development Bank, including through reforms to drive climate ambition, social inclusion and private sector development with the possibility of future capital for IDB Invest, and ensure international financial and economic institutions adequately prioritize the region. We will also work to support countries that are host to large numbers of migrants or refugees, or who want to make ambitious reforms in line with the Partnership’s goals.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Making More Resilient Supply Chains.</strong> Our economic security rests on supply chains that are diverse, secure, transparent, and sustainable. We recognize the importance of diversifying and rebalancing our supply chains to minimize disruption risks.&nbsp; As we work to create resilient supply chains, we will prioritize development of our workforce and take steps to ensure supply chains are transparent and free of exploitative labor conditions.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Updating the Basic Bargain. </strong>Public investments and innovations in public administration can make life better and fairer for our respective citizens.&nbsp; We will explore how to broaden participation in the formal economy, including tax and anti-corruption measures, as well as cooperation and infrastructure investments in areas such as migration, education, health, unemployment and retirement, childcare, and women’s economic empowerment.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Creating Clean Energy Jobs and Advancing</strong>&nbsp;<strong>Decarbonization and Biodiversity</strong>. In line with our climate goals and to support good jobs, we will work together to accelerate clean energy technology, more sustainable forest conservation and management, and low emission and resilient agricultural practices. We will work to decarbonize our economies, enhance biodiversity, and build resilience to climate impacts.&nbsp; We will deepen cooperation on technologies and best practices, mechanisms to increase public and private investment, and explore technical assistance to advance quality infrastructure and programming.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ensuring Sustainable and Inclusive Trade.</strong> The pandemic has only underscored the importance of secure and resilient regional trade flows, as well as the growing role that digital technologies and services play in our economies. We will focus on how to better cooperate on customs facilitation, advance transparency and good regulatory practices, pursue high standards on the digital economy, responsibly support emerging technologies, build resilience in our energy and food supply chains, advance strong labor and environment standards, and incentivize corporate accountability and a race to the top to foster regional economic development.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Celebrates World Ocean Day with Actions to Conserve America’s Deepest Atlantic Canyon, Cut Plastic Pollution, and Create America’s First-Ever Ocean Climate Action&#160;Plan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-celebrates-world-ocean-day-with-actions-to-conserve-americas-deepest-atlantic-canyon-cut-plastic-pollution-and-create-americas-first-ever-o/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55098</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden: “During National Ocean Month, we celebrate the beauty and bounty of our ocean and reaffirm our commitment to protecting and conserving our marine environments for a sustainable future.” Following President Biden’s proclamation of June to be National Ocean Month, and in recognition of June 8 as World Ocean Day, the White House today&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><em>President Biden: “During National Ocean Month, we celebrate the beauty and bounty of our ocean and reaffirm our commitment to protecting and conserving our marine environments for a sustainable future.”</em><strong><em></em></strong></p>



<p>Following President Biden’s proclamation of June to be <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/31/a-proclamation-on-national-ocean-month-2022/">National Ocean Month</a>, and in recognition of June 8 as World Ocean Day, the White House today announced a series of new steps the Administration is taking to conserve and restore the health and productivity of the ocean for the benefit of all Americans.</p>



<p>Today’s actions include initiating the designation process for a new national marine sanctuary to conserve Hudson Canyon in the Atlantic Ocean, a phase out of single-use plastics in national parks and public lands, and the launch of efforts to create America’s first-ever Ocean Climate Action Plan and to center environmental justice in ocean science and technology activities and investments.</p>



<p>Over the course of June, Federal agencies will be making additional announcements that showcase the scale and pace of the Biden-Harris Administration’s ocean agenda, including through the President’s America the Beautiful conservation initiative, unprecedented investments in coastal resilience and restoration through the President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the rapid deployment and construction of offshore wind farms, U.S. engagement with the international Ocean Panel to spur sustainable ocean economic development, and the use of science to guide ocean planning and management.</p>



<p>The specific steps that the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing today in recognition of World Ocean Day are:</p>



<ul><li><strong></strong>Hudson Canyon, which is located approximately 100 miles off the coast of New York and New Jersey <a>and reaches depths of 2-2.5 miles, is an ecological </a>hotspot, providing habitat for endangered, protected, and sensitive species including sperm whale, sea turtles, and unique and diverse seep communities. The canyon boasts deep sea, cold-water coral communities, and contains various shipwrecks, including freighters and United States military radar platforms, dating back to the mid-19th Century. In proposing to conserve the area as a national marine sanctuary, NOAA will seek public comment on the potential boundaries for the sanctuary and other factors related to its future management.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of the Interior will reduce and eventually phase out the sale of single-use plastic products in national parks, wildlife refuges, and other public lands.</strong> As part of World Ocean Day, Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland will <a>issue Secretary’s Order</a> 3407, which aims to reduce the procurement, sale, and distribution of single-use plastic products and packaging with a goal of phasing out single-use plastic products on Department-managed lands by 2032. The Order is part of the implementation of President Biden’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/12/08/executive-order-on-catalyzing-clean-energy-industries-and-jobs-through-federal-sustainability/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Executive Order 14057</a>, which calls for Federal agencies to minimize waste and support markets for recycled products. The Order also directs the Department to identify nonhazardous, environmentally preferable alternatives to single-use plastic products, such as compostable or biodegradable materials, or 100 percent recycled materials, in an effort to reduce the more than 14 million tons of plastic ending up in the ocean every year.  <strong> </strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The Federal government and Tribes in the Bering Sea are beginning nation-to-nation coordination on the stewardship of the Northern Bering Sea Climate Resilience Area. </strong>In response to direction from President Biden when he reinstated the <a href="https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/the-press-office/2016/12/09/executive-order-northern-bering-sea-climate-resilience">Northern Bering Sea Climate Resilience Area</a>, the Bering Intergovernmental Tribal Advisory Council (which includes membership from 11 Tribes representing more than 70 Tribes in the Northern Bering Sea region) and the Bering Sea Federal Task Force (co-chaired by the Department of the Interior, NOAA, and the U.S. Coast Guard) <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/06-2022-Readout-of-the-NBSCRA-JOINT-BFTF-BITAC-Meeting.pdf">convened a historic first</a> meeting on June 3 to identify the ways they will work together to implement the Northern Bering Sea Climate Resilience Area. The two bodies, coordinated by the Office of Science and Technology Policy, represent a new model for nation-to-nation coordination for a large ocean area.<strong>  </strong></li></ul>



<ul><li><a></a>The Office of Science and Technology Policy and the Council on Environmental Quality, Co-Chairs of the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2021/10/29/readout-of-the-first-ocean-policy-committee-meeting/">Ocean Policy Committee,</a> announced that the Committee will work in coordination with the White House Climate Policy Office to develop a whole-of-government Ocean Climate Action Plan that will guide significant ocean-based climate mitigation and adaptation actions, including green shipping, ocean-based renewable energy, blue carbon, and other ocean-related solutions. The Committee will <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/sites/default/files/2022-05/OPCPublicReadout_20220512_Meeting.pdf">also develop</a> a National Sustainable Ocean Plan that will help guide sustainable economic development of U.S. ocean and coastal waters.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>The interagency Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology, which is led by the Office of Science and Technology Policy, today released an <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2022/06/07/ocean-agencies-commit-to-environmental-justice-outcomes-for-ocean-science-and-technology/">Environmental Justice Position Statement</a>, which commits the Federal government to advancing environmental justice across Federal ocean science and technology activities and investments and identifying immediate opportunities for action and investment to meet environmental justice goals across Federal agencies.<strong></strong></li></ul>



<ul><li>On June 3, the United States became the newest member in the UN Environment Program&#8217;s Clean Seas Campaign.&nbsp; Launched in 2017, the Clean Seas Campaign serves as a voluntary, multi-stakeholder platform for individuals, civil society groups, industry and governments to promote policies, standards, and practices to reduce marine litter. The United States joins 64 countries, covering more than 60 percent of the world’s coastlines. Earlier this year, the United States also joined more than 90 other countries in signing on to the High Ambition Coalition for Nature and People and its goal to conserve or protect at least 30 percent of the global ocean by 2030. And since&nbsp;we&nbsp;cannot reach that global target without equally ambitious action within&nbsp;national waters, the United States announced the Ocean Conservation Pledge,&nbsp;by which countries commit to take voluntary actions to conserve, protect, and restore at least 30% of waters under their national jurisdiction. The pledge is non-binding, but aims to catalyze political action to significantly enhance ocean conservation efforts.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration’s ongoing work to harness the clean energy potential of the ocean, conserve and restore its health and productivity, and lead the world toward sustainable ocean policies is informed and motivated by an understanding that a healthy ocean is indispensable to our economy, our health, and to our climate.</p>



<p>A <a href="https://www.noaa.gov/news-release/carbon-dioxide-now-more-than-50-higher-than-pre-industrial-levels">report</a> issued last week by scientists at NOAA and the Scripps Institution of Oceanography at the University of California San Diego, for example, found that carbon dioxide levels in the atmosphere are now more than 50% higher than pre-industrial levels. The effects of climate change on weather systems are widely known, but these rising levels of greenhouse gas pollution are also deeply disruptive to ocean systems, leading to increasing sea surface temperatures, rising sea levels, and an increased absorption of carbon, which makes sea water more acidic, leads to ocean deoxygenation, and makes it more difficult for some marine organisms to survive.</p>



<p>In addition, tomorrow, NOAA and the Bureau of Economic Analysis will release the latest update to the Marine Economy Satellite Account (MESA), a report that provides statistics on some of the contributions to the U.S. economy from the nation’s oceans, seaports, Great Lakes, and other major water bodies (e.g., Puget Sound, Chesapeake Bay). Many of the activities covered by the MESA, including commercial fishing, coastal tourism, and recreation, rely on the ecological health of the marine environment. The U.S. Natural Capital Accounts, announced on Earth Day, will align with the MESA to make these dependencies explicit, expand the accounts to include other economic values; and enable further development of a sustainable ocean economy. This year’s report will show the impact to the marine economy caused by the coronavirus pandemic in terms of employment, sales, and GDP contribution. The report identifies industries and activities most affected by the 2020 downturn, but also areas of growth and innovation in several marine sectors. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on President&#160;Biden’s Travel to G7 and NATO&#160;Summits</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/statement-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-president-bidens-travel-to-g7-and-nato-summits/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to Schloss Elmau in southern Germany on June 25 to attend the G7 Leaders’ Summit.  The President and G7 leaders will discuss a range of the most pressing global issues, including the G7’s unwavering support for a democratic, sovereign, and prosperous Ukraine, economic and democratic resilience, tackling the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. will travel to Schloss Elmau in southern Germany on June 25 to attend the G7 Leaders’ Summit.  The President and G7 leaders will discuss a range of the most pressing global issues, including the G7’s unwavering support for a democratic, sovereign, and prosperous Ukraine, economic and democratic resilience, tackling the climate crisis, development infrastructure, global health security, and the food and energy crisis caused by Russia’s war of aggression. On June 28, the President will travel to Madrid, Spain for the 2022 NATO Summit. Allied leaders will endorse a new Strategic Concept to guide NATO’s transformation over the next decade, from strengthening deterrence and defense, to building resilience against transnational threats including cyber and climate, to deepening partnerships with democratic partners in Europe and Asia in order to strengthen the rules-based international order.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Announces Action on COVID-&#8288;19 Pandemic Response and Improving Health Systems and Health Security in the&#160;Americas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/08/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-action-on-covid-19-pandemic-response-and-improving-health-systems-and-health-security-in-the-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55064</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The COVID-19 pandemic took a devastating human toll on Latin America and the Caribbean, taking the lives of more than 2.7 million people across our hemisphere — accounting for more than 40 percent of global reported deaths.  It showed us the many cracks in our global health systems and underscored the importance of strong and resilient&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The COVID-19 pandemic took a devastating human toll on Latin America and the Caribbean, taking the lives of more than 2.7 million people across our hemisphere — accounting for more than 40 percent of global reported deaths.  It showed us the many cracks in our global health systems and underscored the importance of strong and resilient health systems for the entire population, health security, and pandemic preparedness and response, starting with a strong foundation based on cooperation, transparency, and accountability. </p>



<p>Today President Biden led leaders of the Americas in adopting an “<strong>Action Plan on Health and Resilience in the Americas.”</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;The Action Plan will help our partners prevent, prepare for, and respond to future pandemic threats and other public health emergencies while also expanding the equitable delivery of healthcare and public health services to remote, vulnerable, and marginalized populations.&nbsp;&nbsp;As implementing this Action Plan will require additional investments in our health systems, the Administration is proud to announce the&nbsp;<strong>Americas Health Corps</strong>, a new initiative aligned with the recently announced&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-global-health-worker-initiative/">Global Health Worker Initiative</a>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Administration remains committed to advancing pandemic response and global health security and has prioritized additional activities in the Americas for this year and into the future.&nbsp;These activities will help the region better respond to the current COVID-19 pandemic and prepare for future pandemics by building the capability to prevent outbreaks, detect infectious disease threats, and respond effectively when outbreaks occur.</p>



<p><strong><u>Action Plan on Health and Resilience in the Americas:</u></strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;Leaders committed that&nbsp;this Action Plan — which will strengthen our health systems and coordination, preparing us for future health emergencies and improving regional coordination, transparency, and accountability — will be fully in effect by 2030.&nbsp;&nbsp;This work requires close coordination among governments and engagement with the private sector and civil society.&nbsp;&nbsp;With this in mind, the Administration is poised to launch the Economy and Health Dialogue of the Americas, and looks forward to working with health and economy ministries to create and implement the Action Plan in coordination with the private sector and civil society.&nbsp;&nbsp;Their efforts will strengthen public health and health care systems, consider how to make access to public health services and health care more equitable, and enhance pandemic prevention, preparedness, and response while increasing economic resilience in the region.</p>



<p><strong><u>Strengthening the Health Workforce:</u></strong><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>The U.S. Government intends to continue and expand investments in the health workforce, which is central to strengthening the resilience of health systems. The U.S. Government and Pan American Health Organization (PAHO) launched Americas Health Corps — Fuerza de Salud de las Americas — which will provide basic and specialized training to 500,000 public health, health science, and medical professionals throughout the region within five years.&nbsp;&nbsp;In line with the Biden-Harris Administration’s Global Health Worker Initiative, the Americas Health Corps will&nbsp;support the expansion and training of a robust, resilient, and highly skilled workforce capable of providing health services to all segments of society. The Americas Health Corps will function as a consortium and partner with academic institutions in the United States and throughout the Americas region to leverage and expand existing U.S. Government and PAHO training programs. It will serve as&nbsp;an opportunity to work together on promoting the next generation of global health workforce leaders by identifying, mentoring, and empowering professionals and community health workers, which will strengthen and expand health system capacity and equitable access to health systems in the region.&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong><u></u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>United States COVID-19 Response in the Americas:</u></strong><strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong>As the Americas face a resurgence of COVID-19 cases and the threat of new variants, the U.S. Government remains committed to ending the acute phase of the COVID-19 pandemic and promoting recovery in the region. During the Second Global COVID-19 Summit on May 12, 2022, the U.S. Government reiterated its commitment to get shots into arms, enhance access to testing and treatment, protect the health workforce, and finance and build health security for future pandemics and other health crises. The Summit raised more than $3.2 billion in new commitments, yet significant gaps remain.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Vaccinating the Americas</strong>: In support of the global effort to vaccinate 70 percent of the population in all countries, the U.S. Government has donated more than 65 million doses of COVID-19 vaccines to countries across Latin America and the Caribbean and invested more than $94 million in complementary assistance to expand access to COVID-19 vaccinations and ensure safe delivery, distribution, and administration of these vaccines.&nbsp;&nbsp;As part of the whole-of-government Initiative for Global Vaccine Access (Global VAX), the United States will continue to help ensure vaccination of eligible populations, with an emphasis on countries where coverage remains well below the regional average, by:<ul><li>Leveraging long-standing U.S. Government health investments, such as the United States President’s Emergency Plan For AIDS Relief (PEPFAR), to strengthen systems needed for vaccine delivery and to get shots in arms;</li></ul><ul><li>Establishing vaccination sites, including mobile units, to expand access to vaccines;</li></ul><ul><li>Fighting misinformation and disinformation to increase vaccine confidence and demand — including amongst rural, indigenous, migrant, and health worker groups where hesitancy may remain high; and&nbsp;</li></ul><ul><li>Evaluating the effectiveness of vaccines and vaccination programs.&nbsp;</li></ul></li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Saving Lives Now</strong>: COVID-19 continues to take a toll on the Latin American and Caribbean region. The region has been one of the hardest-hit by the virus, with over 40 percent of total COVID-19 deaths reported globally, despite making up only 8 percent of the world’s population. The U.S. Government is building off decades of investments in the region’s health systems. This includes:<ul><li>Continuing efforts to detect and characterize new variants of the virus that causes COVID-19; and&nbsp;</li></ul><ul><li>Fostering closer ties with other partners in the Americas, including PAHO, the Caribbean Public Health Agency, and countries’ Chief Medical Officers.</li></ul></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Strengthening Global Health Security in the Americas</u></strong><strong>:&nbsp;</strong>The Biden-Harris Administration understands that the health of one is directly connected to the health of all. That is why the United States is committed to continuing to engage with partners throughout the Americas to strengthen our global health security by:</p>



<ul><li>Expanding the number of U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) experts on the ground at the CDC South America Regional Office and through a new CDC Central America and Caribbean Regional Office in Panama, and increasing engagement with regional organizations including detailing staff to the Caribbean Public Health Agency (CARPHA);</li><li>Expanding USAID’s global health security programs and staffing to seven countries in South America, Central America, and the Caribbean, as requested in the President’s Budget;</li><li>Expanding the U.S. Government commitment to the Global Health Security Agenda (GHSA) by adding Guatemala as an intensive support country, a group of countries that the U.S. Government has pledged to help meet the GHSA 2024 overarching target; and</li><li>Diversifying public health supply chains through bilateral and regional engagements and supporting regulatory capacity for a faster and more agile response to future biothreats.</li></ul>



<p>These collective efforts will be complemented by expansion of health security programs including:</p>



<ul><li>Strengthening surveillance networks, laboratories, and data modernization in South and Central America through development and improvement of National Public Health Institutes;</li><li>Improving detection and response to infectious diseases by supporting acute febrile illness surveillance and increasing capacity for genomic surveillance in Central and South America;</li><li>Building partnerships in Costa Rica and beyond to implement a climate-based dengue early warning system through State’s regional science hub and Embassy Science Fellows;</li><li>Strengthening partnerships with private, non-governmental, and international organizations to improve global health security in intensive support countries and throughout the region;</li><li>Identifying and engaging new partners to join the GHSA Legal Preparedness Action Package to build capabilities in countries to map, develop, refine, and utilize legal frameworks and authorities to prepare for and respond to health emergencies; and </li><li>Exploring the development of a South America One Health University Network through State’s regional science hub for South America and its Embassy Science Fellows program.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Roundtable with Business Executives as Part of the Call to Action for Northern Central&#160;America</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-roundtable-with-business-executives-as-part-of-the-call-to-action-for-northern-central-america/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 02:41:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris today hosted a roundtable with business executives as part of the Call to Action for Northern Central America, the initiative she launched in May 2021 to bring together the private sector and civil society to invest in and support the long-term development of the region. The Vice President and the business&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris today hosted a roundtable with business executives as part of the Call to Action for Northern Central America, the initiative she launched in May 2021 to bring together the private sector and civil society to invest in and support the long-term development of the region. The Vice President and the business executives welcomed the announcement that the Call to Action has generated more than $3.2 billion of investments in the region from 40 companies and organizations. They discussed progress made on previous investments and next steps to continue to provide economic opportunities for people in northern Central America. They discussed the innovative public-private partnership that has been developed, and how companies and organizations can collaborate to reinforce each other’s work across multiple sectors.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Roundtable with Women&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-roundtable-with-women-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 02:38:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris today hosted a roundtable with women business executives, entrepreneurs, and civil society leaders to discuss women’s economic empowerment in northern Central America. The Vice President underscored that when women succeed, all of society benefits. They discussed ways to advance US.-led efforts to empower women economically and to reduce gender based violence&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris today hosted a roundtable with women business executives, entrepreneurs, and civil society leaders to discuss women’s economic empowerment in northern Central America. The Vice President underscored that when women succeed, all of society benefits. They discussed ways to advance US.-led efforts to empower women economically and to reduce gender based violence in the region, as part of the Biden-Harris Administration’s Strategy to Address the Root Causes of Migration from Central America. The Vice President and the women leaders welcomed new public and private sector initiatives launched today on the margins of the Summit of the Americas which, when taken together, will create an ecosystem of opportunity for women. They also discussed the $3.2 billion of commitments that the Vice President’s Call to Action has generated in the past year and the Vice President heard directly from women who have benefited from Call to Action initiatives. The Vice President and women leaders also discussed increasing women’s participation in the work force, expanding women’s financial and digital inclusion, and promoting diverse and inclusive workforce cultures. The Vice President reaffirmed that supporting women will remain a central pillar of her work to address the root causes of migration.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at Los Angeles City College&#8217;s 2022&#160;Commencement</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/07/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-los-angeles-city-colleges-2022-commencement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 02:12:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles, CA Thank you, Mayor Garcetti. It’s wonderful to be with you again. In 2016, the mayor and I visited LACC. The energy was incredible that day. And it’s because the city of Los Angeles was making a commitment to invest in community college students—in all of you—through the College Promise program. As all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles, CA</p>



<p>Thank you, Mayor Garcetti. It’s wonderful to be with you again.</p>



<p>In 2016, the mayor and I visited LACC. The energy was incredible that day. And it’s because the city of Los Angeles was making a commitment to invest in community college students—in all of you—through the College Promise program.</p>



<p>As all of you know, when we make community college affordable, it opens up a world of possibilities. And it tells students the same thing I said that day: “We believe in you.”</p>



<p>So, I’m excited to be back with you, Eric—six years later—to see that promise fulfilled in so many students here.</p>



<p>Thank you to Dr. Gallagher and your entire leadership for allowing me to be a part of this celebration. And I want to say a special hello to all of my colleagues and fellow educators here today.</p>



<p>So, where are you from? When we ask that, we’re not really asking about cities or states or countries, are we?</p>



<p>What we really mean is, what’s your story? Tell me about the journey that brought you to this moment.</p>



<p>As many of you may know, I’m a community college professor. I teach English, and for my first lesson of the year, I use the poem, “Where I’m From,” by George Ella Lyon.</p>



<p>Its verses tell the story of the author’s hometown, not in locations, but in sensations and experiences and memories. Then I ask my students to think about their own lives: Where does their inner strength come from? What made them who they are?</p>



<p>So, here’s who I am: I grew up the oldest of five girls in a quiet neighborhood of Willow Grove, Pennsylvania—just outside of Philadelphia and across the river from my Italian grandparents.</p>



<p>Yes, I’m from Philly. But where I’m really from is ribbons of pasta, drying on the linoleum counter in my grandfather’s Italian kitchen, tomato sauce bubbling on the stove.</p>



<p>I’m from five sisters, glued together—messy rooms and borrowed jeans and standing up to bullies who lived on our block.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’m from running through the yellow streetlights on hot July nights, feeling like summer would never end. That’s what made me who I am today.</p>



<p>For the rest of your life, people will ask you to define yourself. You’ll write a resume that lists the black and white details of your past—including LACC—in neat, bulleted lines.</p>



<p>But your story is so much more than a place you grew up, or your degree.</p>



<p>Those things don’t define you—and neither does your hometown. But it is a part of your story.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And my message to you today is this: Never forget where you come from.</p>



<p>So, where is that? To answer, let me tell you the stories I’ve heard about you and your classmates.</p>



<p>I just met Ilya Monroe. Ilya, where are you sitting?</p>



<p>Ilya wanted to be a teacher when she was little, but life took her on a different path. She worked for 25 years as a graphic designer, until she lost her job during the pandemic.</p>



<p>That’s when Ilya realized that she had an opportunity to reach for a dream that was still inside of her.</p>



<p>So, she enrolled in the early childhood education program here to become a teacher.</p>



<p>And though it hasn’t been easy, she said her love for this work makes every challenge worth it.</p>



<p>Today, when she walks across this stage at the age of 46, she will start a new chapter and bring an old dream to life.</p>



<p>And, Ilya, let me say: I will be proud to call you my colleague.</p>



<p>Are there any other future educators in the audience?</p>



<p>I also met Marie Angee Ahoba. Marie, where are you?</p>



<p>Marie came from the Ivory Coast five years ago, and built a life here with her husband and two children. But during the pandemic, they had to spend their entire life savings supporting their family. Marie wanted to be able to help financially rebuild, so she enrolled here at LACC.</p>



<p>In her last semester, pregnant with her third child, she went into labor—during her final exam.</p>



<p>Now, we all know students who would ask to be excused from a test for a runny nose. But not Marie.</p>



<p>Through her contractions—praying that her baby would stay put just a little bit longer—she finished her test and then later, delivered a healthy baby boy.</p>



<p>That’s how much finishing her degree mattered to her.</p>



<p>How many of you graduates are moms or dads—balancing parenting with school?</p>



<p>There are so many times in our lives—especially when we’re trying to reinvent ourselves or create something new—when we just have to push through the pain. Though it’s not usually so literal. And when we get to the other side, we realize that we are stronger than we ever knew.</p>



<p>Marie, congratulations on both the birth of your son and the new life you’re starting today.</p>



<p>And finally, I met Steve Kim.</p>



<p>Steve grew up in Chicago. In high school he felt like he didn’t have direction, and he wanted to give back to the country that had welcomed his family from Korea—so he joined the Marines, serving for five years.</p>



<p>After a deployment in Afghanistan, he was diagnosed with PTSD. But he didn’t let that define him.</p>



<p>And, Steve didn’t give up either. He found treatment, enrolled here at LACC, and connected with the Veteran Resource Center. The center helped him find the right classes and encouraged him when he was struggling.</p>



<p>Steve, as you graduate today, I hope you know that we are all cheering you on.</p>



<p>Do we have any other veterans or military graduates here today? And, where are your families?</p>



<p>Thank you for your service and your sacrifice.</p>



<p>These stories—your stories—of perseverance and resilience are inspiring. &nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re the journey that brought you here today. They are all the lessons that you need to face the challenges ahead. They give you strength to find joy, and fulfillment, and a sense of purpose in the future you are about to create.</p>



<p>So where are you from?</p>



<p>Well, I thought I’d give it a try: You’re from the smell of bacon-wrapped hotdogs under an orange night sky—from the cool, smooth taste of fruit-vendor mango in the hot September sun.</p>



<p>You’re from the swirling, dry dust of the Santa Anas, reminding you that everything changes, that you are changing too.</p>



<p>You’re from trying to talk over too many people in the kitchen—or from sitting alone in your bedroom, wishing there was a way to feel the warmth of your mom’s hug through the phone.</p>



<p>You’re from sitting on the 101 with your AC broken and your windows down.</p>



<p>From fitting your whole life into a few bags and praying that the thing you’re looking for is at the end of this journey.</p>



<p>You’re from catching up on chapters in line at the grocery store, from flash cards on the bus across town, from the burn of blue light after too many hours on zoom.</p>



<p>You’re from working late into the night and setting your alarm early so you can pour cereal for the kids.</p>



<p>You’re from laughing when it hurts too much and crying when joy takes you by surprise.</p>



<p>You’re from the strength you’ve found to start all over—to fail and get back up.</p>



<p>You’re from the bravery it takes to believe in yourself when it seemed like no one else did.</p>



<p>You’re from a community that carries you when you feel weak, that sees not just the best of who you are, but the beauty of who you are becoming.</p>



<p>Today, you are a college graduate.</p>



<p>I know who you are—and you astonish me with your grit and determination. This is why I love teaching community college.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I know that you will go on from here—to find great jobs or attend another school, to explore the world and all it has in store for you.</p>



<p>There will be no shortage of incredible opportunities in your future—as well as challenges that will test you once again.</p>



<p>My charge to you is this: Never forget your path, the people who brought you here, or the lessons you’ve realized along the way.</p>



<p>Never forget where you came from. It doesn’t have to define you, but it will always have something to teach you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Never forget what made you who you are—and then, you will be ready for wherever you choose to go next.</p>



<p>On behalf of my husband, the President, and me: Congratulations, graduates!</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REMARKS BY VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS AT A CALL TO ACTION ROUNDTABLE WITH&#160;CEOs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/07/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-a-call-to-action-roundtable-with-ceos/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 01:51:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55074</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[InterContinental Los Angeles DowntownLos Angeles, California 4:43 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&#160; We have convened, as part of our ongoing conversation about what we are committed to do, together as partners to focus on the northern area of Central America in what I think is an extraordinary public-private partnership that is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>InterContinental Los Angeles Downtown<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>4:43 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; We have convened, as part of our ongoing conversation about what we are committed to do, together as partners to focus on the northern area of Central America in what I think is an extraordinary public-private partnership that is focused on a number of issues that are about empowerment of people in a region in which we live &#8212; the Western Hemisphere.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it is about doing what we know is possible to maximize the capacity of the people in that region &#8212; doing it in a way that really understands the power of ecosystems, of considering the issues holistically both in terms of the issues of the region, but the issues of the individuals that will be impacted.</p>



<p>And as I said earlier, we are motivated by many things that are about uplifting and empowering the people of the region, but also based on &#8212; on a premise, which is that most people really don&#8217;t want to leave home.&nbsp; And when they do, it&#8217;s because they&#8217;re fleeing some harm or because there simply are not the opportunities at home to be able to satisfy their basic needs and the needs of their family.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the work that we are doing is motivated by creating opportunity then, investing in that region to allow opportunity for people to reach their capacity.</p>



<p>The way that we are approaching it, in terms of the work that we are doing with the call to action and our administration&#8217;s focus, is &#8212; is also with an understanding that government cannot do this work alone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if we are to actually have impact in a way that is lasting &#8212; and that is about the work that we are doing, that is about depth, but also about longevity &#8212; to do that successfully, we must engage with the private sector and our friends who are leading in that sector to work with us, to think about how we will maximize our collective capacity in terms of our focus.</p>



<p>And our focus is, yes, about improving the economic condition of the individuals in that region, but it is also a focus that includes an understanding of the connection between that and prioritizing the need to combat corruption, the need to reduce violence, the need to empower women, the need to respect and uphold rule of law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, these are some of the priorities for us in terms of our call to action and the work that we are doing together.&nbsp; I particularly want to thank Ajay Banga for your leadership as a Chair; along with Blanca, who was in a previous meeting with me; and then Vice Chair Ray Chambers.</p>



<p>But we have 40 companies and organizations that are a part of this effort thus far &#8212; an effort that only began a year ago.&nbsp; And as we announced earlier, we have seen the success already when we announced that, together, we have brought together $3.2 billion to focus on this region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when we look at the data about the numbers, in terms of the size of the population and the &#8212; the benefit and the return on investment, we know that already we can have a great impact, much less because of the work that we will do as part of our commitment going forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, I thank all the leaders who are here.&nbsp; Ajay, I thank you, and I look forward to our discussion.&nbsp; And I thank the press for &#8212; for joining this part of the discussion.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll see you later.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 4:47 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the &#8220;In Her Hands&#8221;&#160;Launch</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/07/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-in-her-hands-launch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 01:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[InterContinental Los Angeles DowntownLos Angeles, California 3:46 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; Please have a seat.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160;Laurene, thank you for that introduction and all of the work that you and Emerson have been doing over so many years that is about addressing root causes and doing it in a way that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">InterContinental Los Angeles Downtown<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>3:46 P.M. PDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; Please have a seat.&nbsp; Good afternoon.<br>&nbsp;<br>Laurene, thank you for that introduction and all of the work that you and Emerson have been doing over so many years that is about addressing root causes and doing it in a way that is informed by a sense of humanity and a collective sense of purpose.&nbsp; Thank you for that.<br>&nbsp;<br>And I also want to thank Christy Turlington Burns.&nbsp;And I am grateful to you both and to the Partnership for Central America, the Chamber of Commerce, and everyone here today for all of your efforts.&nbsp; And I see the Ambassador who is here.&nbsp; I want to thank him as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>When I began work on the root causes of migration from northern Central America, I approached the task with a few basic principles: one, my belief &#8212; I think our shared belief &#8212; that people don’t want to leave home.&nbsp; And when they do, it is usually for one of two reasons: They are fleeing harm, or they cannot address the basic needs of themselves or their family.<br><br>Two, I know, as a devout public servant, that to address this issue, government cannot do it alone.&nbsp; We must partner with the private sector and civil society to address what we know can be addressed through collaboration and coordination.&nbsp; So, that is the spirit and the foundation of the work that we are doing in the Call to Action.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Together, our collective expertise, resources, and vision can and already has begun to create an echo system of opportunity.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Three, in terms of our approach, we believe that to have a meaningful impact, we must also, in addition to addressing the economic status and condition of the region, we must also address corruption, we must promote the rule of law, we must focus with a priority on reducing violence, and we must empower women.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These are the guiding principles that inform our administration’s Root Causes Strategy and our engagement with our neighbors &#8212; with our neighbors &#8212; in the Western Hemisphere &#8212; a hemisphere, a region which is more interconnected and more independent than ever before.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, a year ago, I issued the Call to Action and encouraged companies and civil society to work with us to deepen a commitment in Northern Central America and to expand collaboration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This Call to Action is creating new jobs and opportunities for the people within those countries.&nbsp; These investments are also a good example of what our policies beyond our shore can do to benefit the people within the United States.&nbsp; Because we know the American people will benefit from stable and prosperous neighbors.&nbsp; And when we provide economic opportunity for people in Central America, we address an important driver of migration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Which brings me to today: I am pleased to announce that since the launch of our Call to Action last year, we, together, have generated more than $3.2 billion dollars of investment in the region.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you applaud because we all know that is a substantial sum as the beginning of this approach.&nbsp; This investment is on track to generate, as a result of what we have done so far,&nbsp; tens of thousands of jobs, investments in sectors such as agriculture and textiles.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This investment also means that more than 10 million people will have access to banking services and credit within that region, which is important if we are to fuel the capacity, the entrepreneurial vision, and desires of the people in that region.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to all of this work, 2 million people so far have already been connected to the Internet, with millions more to follow &#8212; all part of a holistic approach to what are the needs and the needs that can be met in that region.<br>&nbsp;<br>In context, when we put that $3.2 billion dollars in context, consider that El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras have a total population size of about 30 million people.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;A $3.2 billion investment will then have a direct impact on the quality of life for people throughout that region.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, earlier today &#8212; and I see them here &#8212; I met with a group of women leaders and women entrepreneurs who have been leading in some of this work and some of whom have already benefitted from our Call to Action initiatives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And their stories &#8212; I wish you all could’ve been in the room &#8212; incredible stories.&nbsp; Incredible stories of self-determination, of vision, of passion and commitment and courage.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, today, to build on that success, we are announcing the next phase of the Call to Action, which includes prioritizing women &#8212; a forward-looking vision for the region requires understanding that women are drivers of economic growth, wherever they are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, today, with that spirit, we are announcing an initiative that has been named “In Her Hands” &#8212; an initiative within our Call to Action that will empower, protect, and train women in Northern Central America.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think we all agree and I strongly believe: When women succeed, all of society benefits.&nbsp; And that is the work that we have done, guided by that principle, with our Root Causes Strategy.<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of this, the companies and organizations who are present today have made new commitments to digitize women-owned businesses in the region, to connect women to the banking system, to help more women participate in the agriculture industry, to train women for coding and cybersecurity, and to elevate women within companies.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, our administration’s strategy includes partnering with civil society to reduce gender-based violence in the region.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>These two priorities must go hand in hand.&nbsp; Because we know empowering women economically is not only about giving them a job; it’s about improving their quality of life.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact &#8212; and a lot of folks here know: When women don’t have financial stability &#8212; if they don’t have financial stability, the data shows us that they are more likely to stay in abusive relationships.&nbsp; A lack of opportunity continues a cycle of violence.&nbsp; However, when women have economic opportunity, we see a reduction in domestic violence, a reduction in sexual violence, a reduction in gender-based violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, today, in addition to announcing the next phase of the Call to Action, we will bring together <a><u>the private sector, the non-profit community, and the public sector to coordinate our strategy to reinforce one another’s work and to ensure that collectively we are creating an ecosystem of opportunity for women in the region.</u></a><br>&nbsp;<br>In discussions over the course of this afternoon, you will hear from panelists who will speak to all of these topics.&nbsp; And what it all comes down to is this: When you lift up the economic status of women, you lift up the economic status of families, of her community, and of our entire hemisphere.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you all again for being here and for contributing to this effort.&nbsp; We have achieved a lot, but it is only the beginning.&nbsp; And we are committed to seeing this through with all of you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thank you very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 3:56 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials Previewing the 9th Summit of Americas: Health Systems and Health&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/07/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-previewing-the-9th-summit-of-americas-health-systems-and-health-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 23:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55109</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[Via Teleconference] 7:05 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Hello, everyone.&#160; Thank you so much for joining us today.&#160; I just wanted to start by setting some ground rules as a reminder that this call is currently under a 5:00 a.m. embargo and you may attribute the contents of the call to a “senior administration official.”&#160; We really&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">[Via Teleconference]</p>



<p>7:05 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hello, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you so much for joining us today.&nbsp; I just wanted to start by setting some ground rules as a reminder that this call is currently under a 5:00 a.m. embargo and you may attribute the contents of the call to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>We really &#8212; we’ll kick off with a topper and then hopefully just answer some of the questions you might have.&nbsp; We will have a factsheet for you hopefully soon that we’ll share out to this list of everyone who has joined.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And with that, I’ll kick it over to my colleagues to outline the administration’s efforts to invest in the region’s health and prosperity.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official], and thank you all for joining us tonight.&nbsp; My name is [senior administration official].&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, President Biden will lead the effort in adapting an “Action Plan on Health and Resilience in the Americas.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Action Plan on Health and Resilience in the Americas, which will be fully implemented by 2030, will address the effects of the COVID-19 pandemic by assessing and identifying gaps and strengthening the capacity and resilience of health systems and health value chains to include the full range of activities that health systems and the people who work at part of those systems help workers do at both national and regional levels.</p>



<p>The plan has a very people-centered approach at the core, given that that’s also in line with the core of our health and resilience policies, and it’s intended to impact and further improve the ability for systems to provide both physical and mental healthcare and also account for the disproportionate impact and &#8212; on certain populations that are often vulnerable and marginalized, to include women, youth, the elderly, people of a different gender identities, and people with different disabilities, among others.</p>



<p>Secondly, the U.S. government will work with our partners to strengthen the health workforce by investing in something that’s called the health &#8212; the Americas Health Corps.&nbsp;&nbsp; The Americas Health Corps directly complements the administration’s recently launched Global Health Worker Initiative.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Global Health Worker Initiative, as noted at its launch in mid-May, is intended to serve the framework to guide both the U.S. government’s investments in the health workforce and broader contributions to health systems, as well as provide a frame for the international community.</p>



<p>And the Americas Health Corps is a key example of how those concepts and priorities are being regionalized.&nbsp; The Americas Health Corps will specifically include training for 500,000 health workers in the Latin America and Caribbean region within the next five years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it will do this in two main ways.&nbsp; One, is leveraging and expanding existing training programs, which includes decades of investments from the U.S. government, such as through the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&#8217;s Field Epidemiology Training program, and also efforts such as the U.S. Agency for International Development’s strengthening midwifery in the Latin America and Caribbean training programs, or what we do through the Peace Corps in training of community health workers.</p>



<p>And secondly, it will support and strengthen PAHO &#8212; the Pan American Health Organization&#8217;s &#8212; training platform as well.&nbsp; So, it really is a way to build off of what we&#8217;ve already been doing and bolster the capacity and investments that are done in partnership with PAHO.</p>



<p>Third, the administration, as you hopefully know, remains committed to ending the acute phase of COVID-19 in the region and globally, and to promote recovery in the region, given the devastating human toll that the pandemic has had on our hemisphere specifically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On May 12th, during the Second Global COVID-19 Summit, hosted by President Biden at the White House, there was over $3.2 billion in new commitments that were received.&nbsp; However, in spite of that, there are still &#8212; there&#8217;s still a gap in getting 70 percent of the Americas vaccinated and also expanding equitable access to testing and treatments throughout the region.</p>



<p>We, therefore, will continue to work with partners to detect and characterize new variants of COVID-19, including through closer ties with our partners in the region such as PAHO, the Caribbean Public Health Agency, and chief medical officers of countries in the region with the goal of saving lives.</p>



<p>And then, lastly, I wanted to note that the United States will look to strengthen global health security throughout the Americas.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking to expand the number of CDC experts at the CDC’s regional office, as well as expand USAID’s Global Health Security programs to seven countries, as requested by &#8212; in the President&#8217;s budget.&nbsp; And also to diversify public health supply chains in the region through both bilateral and regional engagements.</p>



<p>We, as the administration, remain committed to advancing pandemic response and global health security while, in parallel, looking to bolster the resilience of health systems that serve as the backbone.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s intended to be reflected in the additional activities that we&#8217;re planning for the Americas this year and into the future &#8212; again, as reflected in the President&#8217;s budget.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Lastly, I&#8217;ll just note that all of these activities are intended to both support the acute response to the current phase of COVID, as well as other health needs, but also better prepare health systems to &#8212; in the region &#8212; to withstand shocks that might come, which could include preventing and detecting outbreaks earlier, but also ensuring continuity of health services for all components of countries on all populations.</p>



<p>With that, we&#8217;ll be happy to take questions.&nbsp; But before doing so, I want to turn it over to my colleague, [senior administration official], who will talk a little bit more about Secretary Becerra’s engagements tomorrow as well and the next couple days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, [senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks a lot, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And good evening, everyone.&nbsp; [Senior administration official] really covered a lot of ground in her opening remarks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will just say that the Secretary will be announcing these initiatives as part of the Americas Summit, starting tomorrow at a CEO panel here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as has been mentioned, this is all under embargo until that time, but you will be hearing more from him related to the various events taking place this week.</p>



<p>In addition to the Americas Health Corps announcement &#8212; or Fuerza de Salud &#8212; we&#8217;re also going to announce a new partnership with Confederación Sudamericana de Fútbol.&nbsp; It’s a FIFA partnership around building confidence mainly around vaccine confidence, but, even broadly, it’s meant to, again, partner with our partners in the region on such public health initiatives so that we can continue to build on, as [senior administration official] was saying, the decades of programs and outreach that we have had on the ground.</p>



<p>Just for awareness, the CDC has been operating in the region for decades, and this includes both Latin America and the Caribbean.&nbsp; And so, it&#8217;s really quite encouraging to see that we&#8217;re able to build on not just that longstanding outreach but, as [senior administration official] was saying, ongoing work in epidemiology and also just frontline health services.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But in addition to our CDC, we also have offices of our FDA, as well as staff from our NIH, also in region.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re really covering the ground, from research through programs and health services, as she mentioned.</p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s also important to highlight a couple of other areas.&nbsp; One is our emphasis as well on partnerships between health ministers and finance ministers.&nbsp; This is something that we have been focused on across the U.S. government at a global level.&nbsp; But regionally, we recognize the importance of solidifying those relationships as well, particularly in light of the COVID pandemic and recognizing the need to work across various sectors if we are to be successful in ending the acute phase of the pandemic.&nbsp; And we can&#8217;t forget that we are still in a pandemic and &#8212; across the Americas region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, as [senior administration official] was saying, these programs will work towards that end but also be designed so that these health systems can sort of live beyond the current crisis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, I will say that beyond COVID, the Secretary will be speaking to a couple of other priorities for us and for the region.&nbsp; One is around the intersection of climate and health, recognizing that it&#8217;s critically important to target, again, not just what we might narrowly define as traditional health priorities but broadly look at the sort of intersection of these issues &#8212; whether we&#8217;re talking about one health, or the intersection of human health and environmental health and animal health, or even looking at issues like noncommunicable diseases, which can be greatly affected by climate change.</p>



<p>And then, finally, he also will be speaking to the importance of equity and using an equity lens as part of our work and work across the region &#8212; whether we&#8217;re talking about Indigenous communities or looking at, as [senior administration official] I believe also mentioned, the gender lens and gender equity explicitly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, with that, I&#8217;m happy to turn it back to our moderator again to take a few questions on what we are covering this week.&nbsp; But thanks again for your time this evening.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Could you talk about exactly when and where this is going to be announced tomorrow by the President? What &#8212; what&#8217;s the setting going to be for that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, I just want to make sure I understood.&nbsp; You said there&#8217;s going to be &#8212; the goal is to have 500,000 new health workers across Latin America in five years?&nbsp; Did I get that right?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; It is 500,000 health workers over the next five years.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll let [senior administration official] and colleagues from our press team confirm the announcement details.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Then just one last question then.&nbsp; Where does the money come for this training for these health workers?&nbsp; It this new money or just existing programs?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, sorry, I was on mute. I apologize for that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s okay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry about that.&nbsp; So this looks at &#8212; this is leveraging existing programs and then &#8212; and in addition to a new investment with PAHO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And, [senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if you can outline Secretary Becerra’s event tomorrow where this will be outlined.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Yeah, no problem.&nbsp; That &#8212; he will be speaking at the CE- &#8212; (sirens are heard in the background) &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, there&#8217;s, of course, background noise here in Los Angeles.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He will be speaking at the CEO summit plenary session here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an event happening on the margins of the Summit of the Americas, and it&#8217;s a panel discussion explicitly on sort of creating thriving economies and using the health lens to do so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;ll be joined by a couple of other panelists, but that is his opportunity &#8212; his first speaking engagement and an opportunity for him to further outline, as [senior administration official] has already mentioned, the new Americas Health Corps program, as well as some of the other areas that I mentioned, such as how we&#8217;re looking to strengthen partnerships between health ministries and finance ministers.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; My question is also about money.&nbsp; Do you have &#8212; are you able to attach a dollar figure to any of these programs &#8212; both the first thing that you mentioned with regard to the Action Plan and then, secondly, for the training?&nbsp; I know you answered the previous question by saying you&#8217;re leveraging existing programs in addition to some additional funds.&nbsp; Can you just tell us what the &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what the dollar figure is for these?&nbsp; Thanks very much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to.&nbsp; And as I mentioned, it&#8217;s a &#8212; it&#8217;s a partnership.&nbsp; So the Americas Health Corps, which is what I&#8217;ll detail, is intended to be a collaborative investment that would, in total, be around $100 million directly focused on, as I mentioned, 500,000 health workers over the course of five years.</p>



<p>So, one note is that the 500,000 health workers would include medical professionals and clinicians, community health workers, public health professionals, and health science professionals.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s intended to be a robust definition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. government, PAHO, and then countries that &#8212; from the region that are participating are essentially kind of working in partnership to leverage together the collaborative investment of $100,000 [sic].&nbsp; So that does not mean &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, $100 million.&nbsp; So that does not mean $100 million is solely from the U.S. government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we would have to come back to you with the specific breakdown of kind of how much each (inaudible) is putting together, but it&#8217;s intended to be a way of bringing together different investments to leverage towards some common goals.</p>



<p>If helpful, I can also talk about what some of the trainings would focus on.&nbsp; But I did want to underscore the multidisciplinary aspect of how we&#8217;re defining health workers for the investments.&nbsp; And that intention (inaudible) look at all aspects of the health system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And as far as the other partnerships, look, the Fútbol partnership, for example, is really meant to work through our existing platforms and partnerships.&nbsp; So, we are not dedicating additional funding for that currently; it&#8217;s more a matter of kind of realigning that work and leveraging the existing relationships with some of these institutions to amplify and further advance those efforts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When it comes to the policy-level work, that really is happening in those policy forums or circles &#8212; again, sort of the regional bodies that exist for those dialogues, as well as some of the ongoing global discussions around how to find better synergy across sectors when it comes to responding to global health emergencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hopefully, that answers your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for having this call.&nbsp; I was just wondering if there any concrete plans for building out these health systems outside of the 500,000 health workers that have been mentioned.&nbsp; I know that there&#8217;s a framing as of this “one health” and including these environmental aspects.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m just wondering: Outside of the health workers, what else is included in concrete plans at this point?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to take that, so &#8212; and then we&#8217;ll pass to [senior administration official] for additional.</p>



<p>So, as [senior administration official] and I have both mentioned, you know, we have a strong interest of leveraging and building off of existing investments from the U.S. government.&nbsp; And that includes through the President&#8217;s fiscal year request &#8212; budget request &#8212; requested increased resources for the U.S. CDC, as well as for USAID, which would be intended to expand a couple of things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One would be to expand what we do in terms of The Field Epidemiology Training program, which directly supports some of our health security in particular.</p>



<p>The second would be to expand regional offices, which would allow for more of a multidisciplinary approach &#8212; which we do in our health programs, but essentially, to expand the scope of different areas of health as well as the geographic ways &#8212; locations that we, as the U.S. government, partner with those governments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then lastly, potentially supporting, through &#8212; if Congress were to meet the President&#8217;s budget request, expansion at the community-health level &#8212; which would be intended to, again, be multidisciplinary, particularly gets into maternal and child care services, through agencies such as USAID and the Peace Corps.</p>



<p>[Senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if you want to comment further on some of the scope of what we would be looking at.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, absolutely.&nbsp; In addition to building on the &#8212; or utilizing the Field Epidemiology Training program, we&#8217;re also building on the Global Laboratory Leadership program, which is also a partnership with CDC and other agencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;re hopeful that between those two, those will sort of help build out the workforce, again, beyond frontline health workers or community health workers, but really looking at even those who are &#8212; were more behind the scenes but really critical to outbreak response and other public health needs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think it&#8217;s also important to highlight that these initiatives also leave room to engage with industry or the private sector.&nbsp; It&#8217;s one of the reasons why the Secretary is making this announcement at the CEO Summit.&nbsp; And given the engagement of private sector in the region, it behooves us to really think about these public-private partnerships or these opportunities to work across sectors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then finally, I&#8217;ll just say that there are active or ongoing initiatives most recently tied to COVID, such as the Global VAX Initiative and other efforts to ensure we&#8217;re getting shots in arms and otherwise reaching people with essential innovations that are that are sort of concrete programs that are ongoing and that can be expanded or extended as a result of these partnerships and additional work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this.&nbsp; Just a quick programming note.&nbsp; If you &#8212; this is the third call in a row that is going at the same time as the Vice President&#8217;s events here in LA.&nbsp; And so, to the extent that you could help those of us out in the pool with the VP by not scheduling the calls at the same time as the highest-ranking principal currently at with Summit, that would be really helpful to us in terms of covering it.</p>



<p>That said, about the 500,000 workers: Are these 500,000 existing workers who are being trained in new skills?&nbsp; Or are these 500,000 people who are currently not health workers who will be?&nbsp; And can you tell us a little bit more about what kind of health workers?&nbsp; Are these primary care?&nbsp; What breakdown are they?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, the primary focus is on upskill &#8212; so kind of giving more advanced skills to existing health workers, which, again, are intended to reflect both on the research side, the service provision side, as well as, to some degree, public health administration.&nbsp; So looking at all components of the health system.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s possible that some of the health workers are new, but the vast majority would be looking at directly supporting advanced or accelerated pathways to (inaudible) what we would call “upskill.”</p>



<p>And then in terms of the model for how it works &#8212; so I had mentioned, you know, it’s envisioned to kind of have topline investment that we would look in a phased incremental approach in working with countries and with PAHO, as well as other donors, to support and build out the vision of the Health Corps.</p>



<p>So, for the starting point, PAHO would contribute I believe it&#8217;s up to $2 million for the first year to spearhead some initial collaboration with the United States, looking at the framing and governance body and components that would help strategically guide the way that the additional components of the funding requirements would come together to support an expanded health workforce.</p>



<p>So, it really is &#8212; is looking at kind of helping propel existing health workers in all aspects of the health workforce to have more tailored skills that allow them to not just, frankly, contribute to the health system, but also can really, we believe, support economic recovery of the region, given that healthier communities result in people who can and individuals who can contribute more to their communities.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you so much, everyone.</p>



<p>This is [Moderator], with White House Comms.&nbsp; Noted on scheduling.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we will be sure to send out the embargoed factsheet shortly after we wrap this call and just wanted to send a reminder to everyone that the materials of this call is under embargo until 5:00 a.m. tomorrow morning.</p>



<p>Talk soon.&nbsp; Thanks so much.</p>



<p>7:28 P.M EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
