<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 23:44:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of the White&#160;House’s First Stakeholder Convening on Mining&#160;Reform</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/readout-of-the-white-houses-first-stakeholder-convening-on-mining-reform/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52976</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On 150th Anniversary Of 1872 Mining Law, Biden-Harris Administration Convenes Representatives from States, Tribes, The Mining Industry, Environmental Groups, Legal Experts to Discuss Much Needed Reform to Outdated Law Yesterday, the White House convened over 20 representatives from states, Tribes, the mining industry, environmental groups, labor unions, automakers, legal experts, and other stakeholders on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>On 150<sup>th</sup> Anniversary Of 1872 Mining Law, Biden-Harris Administration Convenes Representatives from States, Tribes, The Mining Industry, Environmental Groups, Legal Experts to Discuss Much Needed Reform to Outdated Law</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left"><br>Yesterday, the White House convened over 20 representatives from states, Tribes, the mining industry, environmental groups, labor unions, automakers, legal experts, and other stakeholders on the 150th anniversary of the signing of the Mining Law of 1872 to discuss the need for reforms and improvements to establish strong, 21st Century environmental and engagement standards that would allow for the responsible and sustainable development of domestic hardrock minerals.<br><br>This meeting was the first external engagement of the Department of Interior-led Interagency Working Group on Mining Regulations, Laws, and Permitting, which is charged with providing recommendations to Congress on how to reform the mining law to ensure new production meets strong environmental standards throughout the lifecycle of the project, ensure meaningful community consultation and consultation with Tribal nations, and reduce the time, cost, and risk of mine permitting.&nbsp; Additional stakeholder meetings will be held over the coming months, and comments can also be submitted in response to the Request for Information that was issued by the Department of the Interior on March 31. Comments can be made through July 31, 2022 at <a href="https://www.regulations.gov/document/DOI-2022-0003-0001">Regulations.gov</a>.<br><br>Participants discussed the shared benefits, challenges, and opportunities of reforming the current system. The General Mining Law of 1872 governs the extraction of critical and valuable minerals on federal lands across the country, and has remained fundamentally unchanged since Ulysses S. Grant signed it to promote westward expansion. The law does not require royalties to be paid to the taxpayers for the extraction and sale of valuable minerals, does not include any environmental, reclamation or financial assurance provisions, and fails to have a single department in charge of mining, leaving stakeholders and companies to navigate a morass of systems and laws. As we grow the clean energy economy, critical minerals for electric vehicles, large capacity batteries, wind turbines, and other clean energy technologies, such as lithium, cobalt, and nickel, are projected to increase in demand by 400-600% in the coming decades. The current global supply chains for these minerals too often fail to adhere to strong social and environmental standards, despite the demands of the end customers and companies. Creating a modern legal framework for the socially and environmentally responsible and sustainable mining and production of these minerals is essential to the Biden-Harris Administration’s efforts to strengthen our critical supply chains; the administration <a href="https://www.doi.gov/sites/doi.gov/files/biden-harris-administration-fundamental-principles-for-domestic-mining-reform.pdf">issued</a> principles for mining reform in February to guide this effort.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br><br>After participating in the convening, participants ranging from companies, Tribes, environmental groups, trade groups, experts, and labor unions all highlighted the importance of the discussion and common goals to improve the current system:<br><br><strong>Tom Palmer, President and CEO, Newmont Corporation</strong>: “Newmont Corporation was honored to be a part of today’s discussion with the White House on modernizing the General Mining Law. This historic gathering of diverse stakeholders, including federal and state government agencies and representatives, Native American leaders, Labor, NGOs, Academia, and consumers provided a rare opportunity to discuss updates to the Federal regulatory system to incentivize responsible domestic metals and minerals mining in a challenging global environment. We appreciate the Administration convening this productive session and initiating the discussion on the future of mining in the United States. We look forward to Newmont&#8217;s continued participation and collaboration.”&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Jennifer Krill, Executive Director, Earthworks</strong>: “Meeting the President’s climate and environmental justice goals depends on a shift in the way we source and use minerals. To ensure that our emerging clean energy system is not built on dirty mining, we must reform the rules of the road for mining and invest in creating a sustainable minerals economy. On this 150th anniversary of the 1872 Mining Law, Earthworks looks forward to working with the Biden-Harris administration and a broad group of stakeholders to promote a rapid, just, and equitable renewable energy transition using responsibly sourced materials.”<br><br><strong>Joe Britton, Executive Director, Zero Emission Transportation Association</strong>: &#8220;We had a great conversation today with a diverse array of federal, tribal, electric vehicle and critical mineral stakeholders committed to climate action, sustainable economies, and conservation. There was strong consensus on the need to both encourage community consultation and take action that reflects the urgency of responsibly procuring the critical minerals needed for climate solution technologies. ZETA thanks the Biden-Harris Administration for leading these tough discussions and looks forward to making progress on the decarbonization needed to make us all better off.”<br><br><strong>Rich Nolan, President and CEO, National Mining Association</strong>: “The NMA was pleased today to join the Biden administration’s Interagency Working Group on mining law reform at the White House. The strength of the U.S. economy depends on mining, and industry stands ready to work with the government to find a productive path forward that will help reshore essential supply chains, reduce our mineral import overreliance and build the materials industrial base needed to underpin the energy transition and the EV revolution. We look forward to continuing to contribute to the work of this important group.”<br><br><strong>Sam Penney, Chairman, Nez Perce: “</strong>The Nez Perce Tribe appreciates the White House convening the mining reform meeting today. Listening to the various perspectives of states, Tribes, and stakeholders is an important initial step. Protection of treaty reserved rights and upholding federal trust responsibility are critical aspects of mining reform.<strong>”</strong><br><br><strong>Collin O’Mara, President and CEO, National Wildlife Federation</strong>: “Responsibly mined critical minerals are essential for our clean energy future and our national security — and it’s time that we finally move our 19<sup>th</sup>&nbsp;century laws into the 21<sup>st&nbsp;</sup>century. President Biden and his administration have made it clear that they are serious about responsibly producing a secure domestic supply of critical minerals through reclamation, recycling, and new mining, while fully supporting communities and workers, remediating abandoned mines, and addressing the impacts on clean drinking water, lands, and wildlife and people alike.”<br><br><strong>Mark Bristow, President &amp; CEO, Barrick: </strong>“Barrick and Nevada Gold Mines value being part of the discussions today and look forward to continued collaboration with the federal government and other stakeholders. We support the initiative to improve the permitting process and regulatory regime with the objective of ensuring responsible mining of minerals and metals in the United States of America.”<br><br><strong>John Ruple, Professor of Law (Research) &amp; Wallace Stegner Center Fellow, S.J. Quinney College of Law, University of Utah</strong>: “The 150-year-old General Mining Law is like driving a stagecoach, and it’s time to trade in the stagecoach for an electric vehicle. Today’s meeting included a broad representation of mining stakeholders—from multinational mining corporations, to Tribes and environmentalists, to organized labor and academia—universally, we agree on the value in updating the 150-year-old general mining law to increase the supply of strategic minerals and an opportunity to improve environmental stewardship and collaboration with Native Nations. I am honored to work with the Biden-Harris Administration on efforts to bring mining law into the 21st century and to secure for America the critical minerals that we need for a transition to renewable energy in an environmentally responsible manner.”<br><br><strong>Yvette Pena-O&#8217;Sullivan, Executive Director of the Office of the President, Laborers&#8217; International Union of North America (LIUNA)</strong>: “I was pleased to be a part of the White House&#8217;s convening of stakeholders from labor, industry, environment, and tribal communities to discuss mining reform and remediation.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s meeting was an important step forward to securing a safe and domestic supply chain for critical minerals.&nbsp; The hard-working men and women of LIUNA who work on mineral mining projects too often have their livelihoods put on hold as permits are stalled due to outdated policies and a legal framework that dates to the 1870s. LIUNA commends the Biden-Harris Administration’s leadership in charting a new strategy on critical minerals that can help our nation build a vibrant clean energy economy responsibly.”&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Jason Walsh, Executive Director, BlueGreen Allilance:</strong> “As we work to grow the clean economy, demand for mined materials—such as copper, lithium, and nickel, as well as other minerals, metals, and rare earths—is only going to increase. We need&nbsp;a new national commitment to responsible mining and the reclamation and recycling of these minerals and materials. And we have to do this&nbsp;in ways that uphold our obligations to workers, communities, and the environment. We appreciate the administration convening this&nbsp;important&nbsp;conversation and we&nbsp;look forward&nbsp;to&nbsp;continuing to&nbsp;discuss and advance&nbsp;this issue with our partners.”<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After the Senate Vote on the Women&#8217;s Health Protection&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/11/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-the-senate-vote-on-the-womens-health-protection-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 21:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Q Madam Vice President, what does this vote mean? And what is your message to women and childbearing people in America about what’s next? THE VICE PRESIDENT: Yeah, so, I just presided over the Women&#8217;s Health Protective Act vote. And sadly, the Senate failed to stand in defense of a woman&#8217;s right to make decisions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Q Madam Vice President, what does this vote mean? And what is your message to women and childbearing people in America about what’s next?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT: Yeah, so, I just presided over the Women&#8217;s Health Protective Act vote. And sadly, the Senate failed to stand in defense of a woman&#8217;s right to make decisions about her own body.</p>



<p>And let&#8217;s be clear, the majority of the American people believe in defending a woman&#8217;s right, her choice to decide what happens to her own body. And this vote clearly suggests that the Senate is not where the majority of Americans are on this issue.</p>



<p>It also makes clear that a priority for all who care about this issue &#8212; a priority should be to elect pro-choice leaders at the local, the state, and the federal level, because what we are seeing around this country are extremist Republican leaders who are seeking to criminalize and punish women for making decisions about their own body.</p>



<p>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Meeting with Partnership for Central America to Drive Progress on Vice President Harris’s Call to&#160;Action</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/readout-of-meeting-with-partnership-for-central-america-to-drive-progress-on-vice-president-harriss-call-to-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 20:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52983</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Vice President Kamala Harris joined a meeting with National Security Advisor to the Vice President Dr. Phil Gordon, Chief Economic Advisor to the Vice President Michael Pyle, and business leaders who have invested in northern Central America under the Vice President’s Call to Action.  Launched in May 2021, the Vice President’s initiative has mobilized&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Vice President Kamala Harris joined a meeting with National Security Advisor to the Vice President Dr. Phil Gordon, Chief Economic Advisor to the Vice President Michael Pyle, and business leaders who have invested in northern Central America under the Vice President’s Call to Action.  Launched in May 2021, the Vice President’s initiative has mobilized over $1.2 billion in private sector investment for northern Central America and is a key pillar of the U.S. government’s comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of migration from the region.  Vice President Harris expressed her gratitude to the group for their leadership and for the success of the public-private partnership. She highlighted U.S. government efforts to support their investments in the region and address the drivers of migration, including by combatting corruption and improving governance and security. The Vice President and other attendees agreed to continue to work to deepen investments in the region.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on the U.S.-ASEAN Special&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/11/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-the-u-s-asean-special-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 20:35:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 3:04 P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&#160; So this call is on background.&#160; It is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&#160; And the contents of the call are embargoed until the end of the call.&#160; For your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker on the call today is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>3:04 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; So this call is on background.&nbsp; It is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And the contents of the call are embargoed until the end of the call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, our speaker on the call today is [senior administration official].&nbsp; So I&#8217;m going to turn it over to you to give some remarks and we can take some questions.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, guys.&nbsp; And thank you all for joining.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sorry to be a couple of minutes late.&nbsp; We&#8217;re trying to balance, you know, 10 delegations here in Washington, so it&#8217;s substantial.&nbsp; And I’m grateful to [moderator] and her team for arranging this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I&#8217;d like to do a couple of things today.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to explain and give you some background for the ASEAN Special Summit, which will be taking place here in Washington, D.C. &#8212; at the White House, at the Willard, and at the State Department &#8212; on Thursday and Friday.&nbsp; And then just preview quickly &#8212; and we&#8217;ll do more of this next week &#8212; the upcoming travel of the President to South Korea and Japan.</p>



<p>So, just quickly, I think as you know, President Biden very much looks forward to welcoming the leaders of ASEAN to Washington, D.C. &#8212; again, on Thursday or Friday &#8212; for full days of discussions the 12th and 13th for what we are calling a U.S.-ASEAN Special Summit.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is the first time in its 45-year history that ASEAN leaders will be welcomed together to Washington, D.C.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had summit meetings before in the region, and also during the Obama administration, there was a meeting in Sunnylands.&nbsp; But this is the first time they&#8217;ve gathered together in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>So just by way of background, guys: So, you know, we think this is important for obvious reasons.&nbsp; You know, there is a daily urgent set of demands as the West, the transatlantic community is engaging deeply on what&#8217;s going on on the battlefield in Ukraine.&nbsp; And that obviously takes an enormous amount of time, focus, energy, and resources currently of the senior leadership.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it is also the case there is a deep recognition that fundamental long-term challenges are playing out in the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp; And the United States is committed and determining to ensuring that our engagement in the region is broad, is broad-based, and is sustained.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So part of that will be the hosting of the summit.&nbsp; Part of it will be the trip to South Korea and Japan.&nbsp; And as part of each of those stops, there&#8217;ll be a range of engagements, including the fourth Quad meeting at the leader level in just over a year.&nbsp; That will be hosted by Prime Minister Kishida in Tokyo on the 24th of May, next week or the week after next.</p>



<p>So for the U.S.-ASEAN Summit, the program is as follows:</p>



<p>On Thursday, tomorrow, Speaker Pelosi and other senior leaders from Capitol Hill will welcome the ASEAN leaders to the Capitol for a bipartisan working lunch.&nbsp; And, obviously, this is important because, for many years, one of the most important areas of engagement for Capitol Hill was in Southeast Asia, and that continues.</p>



<p>And so, it&#8217;s important that the leaders from the region see the bipartisan commitment to the Indo-Pacific that we certainly have seen over the course of the last year and half.</p>



<p>After that, the ASEAN leaders will move to the Willard, where they will meet senior American business leaders and CEOs to discuss ways of strengthening economic cooperation between one of the most dynamic regions on the planet and the United States.</p>



<p>They will be joined by a variety of folks, including Secretary of Commerce Raimondo and U.S. Trade Representative Ambassador Tai.&nbsp; There will be discussions at this session about key challenges ahead in technology, post-COVID recovery, issues associated with climate and energy.&nbsp; The desire is to have these senior &#8212; these senior business leaders from across the United States engage and think about how to engage more directly going forward, given the dynamism in the region as a whole.</p>



<p>After that, President Biden will be hosting the ASEAN Leaders for an intimate dinner in the White House, for an opportunity to listen to the leaders about their aspirations for where they want to take ASEAN and how the United States can help in that in the period ahead.</p>



<p>Day two: Vice President Harris and Secretary of State Blinken will host ASEAN leaders for a working lunch at the State Department, and it&#8217;s focused primarily on &#8212; the lunch &#8212; on maritime cooperation, pandemic recovery, and health security.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vice President Harris will also host a discussion with ASEAN leaders and other Cabinet officials from across the interagency regarding climate action, clean energy, and sustainable infrastructure.</p>



<p>Let me just take a moment here that &#8212; I think part of the ambition of this summit is to broaden and deepen not only the level of engagement in the U.S. government but in certain key parts of the government like the State Department, the White House, and DOD, but to broaden it across every element of our government.</p>



<p>So we are seeking discussions and programs on education, on maritime domain awareness, on forestry across the board.&nbsp; So the idea here is to make sure that the ASEAN leaders see the breadth and depth, again, of the U.S. commitment to ASEAN as a whole.</p>



<p>And as you know, this is building on an area of expertise for &#8212; and interest for Vice President Harris.&nbsp; She traveled to the region at the end of last year, and she&#8217;s interested and excited to engage with the leaders about opportunities for U.S. &#8212; enhancing U.S. ties with Southeast Asia going forward.</p>



<p>And then, later in the afternoon, President Biden will host a discussion with ASEAN leaders on how to deliver directly for people in the region and beyond.</p>



<p>So, you know, I think the desire here is to have an intense set of discussions with, again, all our senior officials who will all be present and business leaders to indicate how seriously we take the relationship between the United States and ASEAN.</p>



<p>And I think you can expect to see the United States taking steps to deepen our longstanding cooperation in a whole host of areas.&nbsp; We’ve got some ideas for how to pursue new avenues of dialogue.&nbsp; I think we&#8217;re going to be thinking about how to invest in our countries and work on driving inclusive prosperity.</p>



<p>And I think it is also clear that the United States will also focus on efforts to promote respect for human rights, the rule of law, and good governance.&nbsp; And we will together address the ongoing crisis and challenges in Burma.</p>



<p>On the President&#8217;s &#8212; so I’ll just take a minute, [senior administration official], really quickly &#8212; the President&#8217;s travel.&nbsp; He will be going &#8212; he will be going to South Korea to meet the new President who has just been sworn in.&nbsp; And he will then be proceeding to Japan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll have more details on the travels as we get closer, but I just want to understand that &#8212; you know, I want you to understand that, really, since the President&#8217;s inauguration, we&#8217;ve done a lot in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll just give you a couple of examples for background in your stories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re the first administration that has taken the Quad &#8212; that&#8217;s the United States, Australia, India, and Japan &#8212; to the leader level.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had a number of meetings, and they all &#8212; again, as I’ve indicated &#8212; they will meet in Tokyo on the President&#8217;s travel.</p>



<p>We have decided for the first time in seven decades to share sensitive nuclear submarine technology with another country.&nbsp; We launched AUKUS that binds and bonds Australia, Great Britain, and the United States in a fundamental endeavor to deliver on the promise of nuclear-powered submarines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this partnership will also include more areas of technology cooperation with other countries.&nbsp; We’ll have more to report on that as we go forward.</p>



<p>I think what we have also seen is substantial engagement in the Pacific.&nbsp; It&#8217;s &#8212; clearly, the Indo-Pacific is a broad region, and too often we speak a lot about Southeast Asia, Northeast Asia, India.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s equally important to focus on the Pacific, and you will be seeing indications of that going forward.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve also broadened and deepened our discussion with Europe and Asia about each other.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen unprecedented Indo-Pacific cooperation in the challenges that Europe has faced since the invasion &#8212; the Russian invasion of Ukraine, more generally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I think it&#8217;s a multifaceted approach.&nbsp; The President and our team will have more to say on details on the Indo-Pacific Economic Forum, some of the details of what we hope to accomplish in the Quad, a number of other initiatives that are in the works.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think the sum total of the next couple of weeks is intended to send a concerted message that we are following through on the strategy of investing at home, working with top partners and allies, and laying out clearly what our goals and objectives in the Indo-Pacific are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll stop there.&nbsp; I’m happy to take a couple of questions.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s sort of the background about where we are.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; That was a really helpful laydown of what&#8217;s to come in the coming days.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, Operator, could you please give us the directions on how to ask the questions?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thanks a lot for doing this.&nbsp; I just wanted to &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, John.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; (inaudible) &#8212; yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Is it true the President is not going to be doing any bilateral meetings with the ASEAN leaders in town?&nbsp; You probably saw the remark from the Cambodian minister who said that the U.S. hosts “should be more generous to guests.”&nbsp; I’m just curious if you think that’s a fair criticism.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I had not seen those comments.&nbsp; I can just assure you that the United States is bending over backwards to be the best possible host.&nbsp; The President will have a quick, private time with each of the leaders.&nbsp; We put enormous effort into the program as a whole.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I would also just underscore that this is really a meeting with ASEAN as an institution, and we are in many ways following the recommendation of individual countries in the region that said that the United States has to take the necessary steps to bolster our engagement with the institution, and we&#8217;re seeking to do that.</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re trying to balance opportunities for private interaction with individual countries but a larger engagement with ASEAN as a whole.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;ve done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I would simply say that we have tried very hard to send a very constructive message of how deeply we want to work with partners in the region, and we&#8217;re grateful that so many countries have decided to join us in this endeavor.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I have two questions.&nbsp; The first one &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, Patsy.&nbsp; How are you?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m well, thank you.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I understand that the issue of Russia and Ukraine will be brought up.&nbsp; I’m wondering if you can give us some details about how hard would the President be pushing on Russia.&nbsp; For example, will you discuss the issue of secondary sanctions?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, if you could elaborate on your statement this morning that the U.S. wants ASEAN leaders to play a more deeply engaged role in Myanmar; I think that was the term that you that used.&nbsp; Will you be urging something more towards the enforcement of the five-point consensus or something beyond that?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, just on the first question: First of all, I expect that there will be a broad discussion of Ukraine and Russia.&nbsp; I think ASEAN leaders are very interested to hear the American approach, both where things stand in terms of next steps.&nbsp; And I don’t want to get ahead of what is to come in terms of anything beyond that, but I expect that there will be a fulsome discussion on Ukraine, on Myanmar &#8212; on Burma.</p>



<p>I think, obviously, we’ve had substantial consultations with countries in the region and interested parties who are deeply focused and, frankly, frustrated by what we’ve seen take place inside the country.</p>



<p>I think we saw some of the initial steps that the ASEAN had taken.&nbsp; I think some of those steps have stalled, and we&#8217;re looking for an indication that ASEAN and, perhaps, the help from other countries supportive of ASEAN will take the lead in basically determining what are the appropriate next steps for the institution with respect to its demands and expectations inside the country.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thanks &#8212; thanks for doing the call.&nbsp; I know that you said that you’ll release more details on the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework coming up soon, but what degree &#8212; to what degree do you expect to discuss that framework with the ASEAN leaders here?&nbsp; And maybe you could detail for us which ASEAN country you are aiming to get to join the framework, if at all.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, look &#8212; and I very much appreciate the question.&nbsp; And I will say we are engaged in very substantial conversations with ASEAN countries and engaged in, you know, close deliberations on the way forward.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I indicated, we will have more to say on this.&nbsp; But this is a subject of deep conversation not only between the leaders but expert groups that are meeting around the edges of every meeting currently.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Radio Free Asia would like to know specifically, like, who is from &#8212; who is representing Myanmar, and is the National Unity Government involved in this summit in any way.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, again, we&#8217;ll have more to say on this tomorrow.&nbsp; We have had diplomatic engagement with the government in exile.&nbsp; We are in discussions about the best way to represent what has transpired in Burma and how to represent that in the meeting.</p>



<p>I think one of the discussions has been to have an empty chair to reflect our dissatisfaction with what&#8217;s taken place and our hope for a better path forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we&#8217;ll have more to say about that.&nbsp; And, clearly, Burma will be a subject of intense deliberation in all of our meetings.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official,” and the contents of the call are embargoed until the end of the call.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you did not get your question in or have more questions, please feel free to reach out to me and we&#8217;ll get back to you for sure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you so much, [senior administration official]. I really appreciate it.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>3:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on the Senate Vote on the Women’s Health Protection&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/statement-from-president-biden-on-the-senate-vote-on-the-womens-health-protection-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 20:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52961</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Once again – as fundamental rights are at risk at the Supreme Court – Senate Republicans have blocked passage of the Women’s Health Protection Act, a bill that affirmatively protects access to reproductive health care. This failure to act comes at a time when women’s constitutional rights are under unprecedented attack – and it runs&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Once again – as fundamental rights are at risk at the Supreme Court – Senate Republicans have blocked passage of the Women’s Health Protection Act, a bill that affirmatively protects access to reproductive health care. This failure to act comes at a time when women’s constitutional rights are under unprecedented attack – and it runs counter to the will of the majority of American people.<br><br>Republicans in Congress – not one of whom voted for this bill – have chosen to stand in the way of Americans’ rights to make the most personal decisions about their own bodies, families and lives.   <br><br>To protect the right to choose, voters need to elect more pro-choice senators this November, and return a pro-choice majority to the House. If they do, Congress can pass this bill in January, and put it on my desk, so I can sign it into law.<br><br>The protections that the Women’s Health Protection Act would ensure are essential to the health, safety, and progress of our nation.  While this legislation did not pass today, my Administration will not stop fighting to protect access to women’s reproductive care. We will continue to defend women’s constitutional rights to make private reproductive choices as recognized in <em>Roe v. Wade</em> nearly half a century ago, and my Administration will continue to explore the measures and tools at our disposal to do just that.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Supporting Farmers and American&#160;Families</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/11/remarks-by-president-biden-on-supporting-farmers-and-american-families/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 20:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52969</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[O’Connor FarmKankakee, Illinois 1:15 P.M. CDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, hello, hello.&#160; Is this one working?&#160; There you go.&#160; Please, sit down.&#160; One of the things I want to put to rest &#8212; everybody looks at me and says, “Have you ever been on a farm?”&#160; And I remind them that that no- &#8212; what nobody&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">O’Connor Farm<br>Kankakee, Illinois</p>



<p>1:15 P.M. CDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, hello, hello.&nbsp; Is this one working?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Please, sit down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the things I want to put to rest &#8212; everybody looks at me and says, “Have you ever been on a farm?”&nbsp; And I remind them that that no- &#8212; what nobody knows: I come from the state of Delaware; I represented Delaware for 36 years in the United States Senate before I became Vice President.&nbsp; The single-largest industry in Delaware and the Delmarva &#8212; Delaware, Maryland, Virginia peninsula; that peninsula that goes down &#8212; is agriculture.&nbsp; It’s a $4 billion industry.&nbsp; Four billion dollars &#8212; that whole peninsula.</p>



<p>And we have more chickens than there are Americans.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; More broilers.&nbsp; And so, you know, I’ve been very &#8212; let me put it this way: If I didn’t know something about farms, I’d have been a United States senator for 6 years, not 36 years.</p>



<p>But every part of the country is different.&nbsp; Every part of the country is different.</p>



<p>But before I go on, I want to pay a little bit of a tribute to this guy right here.&nbsp; I’m going to embarrass you a little bit.&nbsp; This is the man who happens to be the son of the owners of this farm.&nbsp; And this guy is doing &#8212; you know, there’s an old expression: God made man and then he made a few firefighters.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Firefighters are incredible.&nbsp; Who else runs &#8212; who else is crazy enough to run into flames, you know?</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, what you’re doing in terms of helping conservation as well out in Wyoming is astounding.&nbsp; It really is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve been to &#8212; I don’t want to make you stand.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; The &#8212; but the whole point of my raising this is &#8212; and we’re not going to be able to talk much about it today &#8212; but conservation is also pretty darn important and climate is pretty important.</p>



<p>I’ve been to every major fire but two this year, because FEMA is working again.&nbsp; We show up; we don’t wait.&nbsp; We don’t have to wonder.&nbsp; Governors only have to call me once.</p>



<p>And here’s the deal: More timber, more land, more buildings, more territory has been burned to the ground this year than the entire state of New Jersey, from New York all the way down to Virginia.&nbsp; The entire state of New Jersey.</p>



<p>And so, what this young man does is &#8212; amazing what they do, trying to &#8212; and it relates to lack of water in most of the places I’ve flown over &#8212; those reservoirs that were 200 feet deep that are now two inches deep.&nbsp; Literally, not figuratively.</p>



<p>So one of these days, I want to come back and talk to you all about conservation as well and climate.</p>



<p>But thank you for what you’re doing, man.&nbsp; You’re &#8212; I really mean it.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Folks, I know it’s hot in here, so I’m not going to talk more than an hour and a half.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Look, I want to make a few I think are fairly important points.</p>



<p>First of all, I want to thank Jeff for that introduction and &#8212; and you, Gina, for your hospitality you’ve extended today.</p>



<p>I joined Congresswoman Robin Kelly here &#8212; the real champion of working families and farmers &#8212; who represents this area, and I just do what she says.&nbsp; She sends a note to the White House, and I get it done.&nbsp; No, but she’s a key player on infrastructure &#8212; getting high-speed Internet, clean water to every person across this district.</p>



<p>And I know we &#8212; wanted to be here also was Dick Durbin and Tammy Duckworth, but they &#8212; and I mean they were going to come, but there’s a vote today in the United States and they’re unable to be here.&nbsp; They’re one of the &#8212; they&#8217;re two of the most genuine, reliable people that I’ve ever worked with, and I’ve been doing this for a few days.</p>



<p>And I want to thank Tom Vilsack.&nbsp; Tom and I became friends when Tom was governor in Iowa.&nbsp; We traveled the state.&nbsp; And Tom has forgotten more about farming than most people will ever learn.&nbsp; I’m sure this rooms knows as much, but the idea &#8212; Tom talks about how critically important that agriculture is to the United States in every single, solitary way.</p>



<p>But the real reason I’m here is to thank the American farmers &#8212; thank farmers.&nbsp; You feed America.&nbsp; You get us through &#8212; you got us through a pandemic.&nbsp; And you’re literally the backbone of our country.&nbsp; It’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; But you also feed the world.&nbsp; And we’re seeing with Putin’s war in Ukraine, you’re like the backbone of freedom.</p>



<p>You know, I was at factory not long ago, a couple &#8212; eight days ago, down in Alabama.&nbsp; And they make Javelin missiles to help the Ukrainians stave off the Russians, beat them back in their aggression.&nbsp; And I pointed out that &#8212; the proof point that America is the arsenal of democracy.&nbsp; That’s what they are.&nbsp; We always have been.&nbsp; We’ve been the arsenal of democracy.</p>



<p>And I stand here today to thank American farmers who are the &#8212; who are the breadbasket of democracy.&nbsp; You really are.</p>



<p>You know, we talk about &#8212; you know, every investment banker could leave their job.&nbsp; If every farmer left, we&#8217;d all starve to death.&nbsp; You know, let&#8217;s talk about what&#8217;s important to us.&nbsp; Everybo- &#8212; all these jobs are important.</p>



<p>But I &#8212; just think about it: Right now, America is fighting on two fronts.&nbsp; At home, it’s inflation and rising prices.&nbsp; Abroad, it’s helping Ukrainians defend their democracy and feeding those who are left hungry around the world because Russian atrocities exist.</p>



<p>And Jeff and the American farmers understand Putin’s war has &#8212; has cut off critical sources of food.&nbsp; Ukraine was the world’s largest producer of wheat and corn and cooking oil &#8212; but wheat, the largest.</p>



<p>For example, Ukraine says they have 20 million tons of grain in their silos right now &#8212; 20 million tons.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; If those tons don&#8217;t get to market, an awful lot of people in Africa are going to starve to death because they are the sole &#8212; sole supplier of a number of African countries.&nbsp; Somalia &#8212; I won&#8217;t go through them all.</p>



<p>But the point is this: that because of what the Russians are doing in the Black Sea, Putin has warships &#8212; battleships preventing the access to Ukrainian ports to get this &#8212; this grain out, to get this wheat out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The brutal war launched on Ukrainian soil has prevented Ukrainian farmers from planting next year’s crop and next year&#8217;s harvest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they&#8217;re not doing too damn &#8212; darn well in Russia either.&nbsp; Russia is the second-largest producer.</p>



<p>And &#8212; but we’re doing something about it.&nbsp; And our farmers are helping both &#8212; on both fronts, reducing the food &#8212; cost of &#8212; price of food at home and expanding production and feeding the world in need.</p>



<p>You know, I just toured Jeff’s beautiful family farm &#8212; 800 acres of soybeans, corn, and wheat.&nbsp; We talked about farmers all across America &#8212; what they&#8217;re experiencing today.</p>



<p>In addition to Putin’s war in Ukraine, it’s been cold and wet this spring, like it is cold today.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; We waited for 90-degree weather until I showed up here.</p>



<p>But, look, many farmers in the Midwest have been put behind the eight ball because of that.&nbsp; But it kept them from getting into their fields and planting crops.</p>



<p>But as Jeff just shared, American farmers always find a way.&nbsp; They always feel something extra &#8212; a spark of patriotism.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s not hyperbole.&nbsp; A spark of patriotism.&nbsp; A sense of never giving up, of always finding a solution.</p>



<p>To all of our farmers, I want you to know: Your congresswoman, me, the Secretaries of my Cabinet &#8212; we have your back.&nbsp; Robin has your back.&nbsp; She’s always looking at what’s going on in the agricultural world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, we’re reducing the red tape so it’s easier for farmers to conserve inputs and double crop.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For folks at home who don’t know what “double cropping” means: harvesting two different crops from the same field in the same year.&nbsp; And that’s what Jeff does with wheat and soybeans, which America is a top producer of &#8212; soybeans.</p>



<p>And wheat will be harvested around July 4th, if all goes well, God willing, and “the crick not rising,” as my grandfather would say.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, look, then you plant soybeans on the same acreage.&nbsp; And he’ll tell you, double cropping comes with some real risks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The growing season for wheat is short, and if the weather conditions aren’t ideal or aren’t at least good, or there are other disruptions, then the timing of everything is thrown off.&nbsp; But it’s a risk we need to take.</p>



<p>That’s why my administration is looking at how to extend crop insurance coverage to give financial security to farmers like Jeff who practice double cropping.</p>



<p>Secondly, I want to also &#8212; farmers are worried about raising fer- &#8212; rising fertilizer costs and what is the content of the fertilizer.&nbsp; That’s why, earlier this year, the U.S. Department of Agriculture announced it would invest $250 million to boost fertilizer production.</p>



<p>Literally on the plane out here, on Air Force One, I turned to Tom and I said, “Tom, double that.&nbsp; Make it $500 million.&nbsp; It’s so desperately needed.&nbsp; We can’t take chances.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>It’s critical to get this done.&nbsp; Now, when we &#8212; when we leave here today, I’m heading up to Chicago.&nbsp; You know where Tom is going?&nbsp; He’s getting &#8212; he’s heading to the airport &#8212; when we get to Air Force One &#8212; he’s heading to Germany, to the G7.&nbsp; That is all the democracies in Europe getting together and their agricultural teams getting together.&nbsp; North America, Europe, and Asia &#8212; they’re all part of it.&nbsp; And what &#8212; to solve some really big problems.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They’re going to see what actions we can take to increase fertilizer suppliers globally and identify how we can work together to prevent export restrictions on food and agricultural inputs and bring more global production to market, which will stabilize prices and bring more certainty to our farmers and keep people from dying of hunger.</p>



<p>You know, this builds in other ways as well.&nbsp; My administration has been working to drive down the costs to farmers &#8212; and Tom mentioned it a little bit &#8212; and prices to consumers.</p>



<p>To reduce gas prices last month, I was in Iowa &#8212; a biofuel processing plant &#8212; at a biofuel processing plant.&nbsp; And I announced an emergency waiver to allow E15 gasoline to be sold across America during the summer.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an extraordinary effort, but it had to be done for this summer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>E15 uses more ethanol on crops grown here in Illinois and elsewhere around the country.&nbsp; And it can reduce the cost of a gallon of gasoline at the pump by 10 cents per gallon.&nbsp; Every little bit matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know it&#8217;s a big deal.&nbsp; And Robin is a big supporter of this, and she&#8217;s pushing it in the House as well.&nbsp; Only four big companies, by the way, control more than half the markets for beef, pork, and poultry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without meaningful competition, our farmers and ranchers have to pay whatever the four big re- &#8212; retailers are saying they&#8217;ll pay for their chickens, their hogs, and their cattle.&nbsp; These big companies can use their position as middlemen to overcharge grocery stores and, ultimately, families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just consider this: Fifty years ago, ranchers got over 60 cents on every dollar spent to produce the beef they raised.&nbsp; Today, they get 39 cents.</p>



<p>Fifty years ago, hog farmers got 40 to 60 cents for each dollar the family spent raising that hog.&nbsp; Today, it&#8217;s about 19 cents.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as big companies made massive profits, the prices you see at the grocery stores have gone up and the prices farmers receive has gone down.&nbsp; This reflects a market distorted by the lack of competition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So last year, I signed &#8212; one of the first executive orders I signed was the &#8212; the competition on a &#8212; to make competition more available and level the playing field.&nbsp; And though the American Res- &#8212; through the American Rescue Plan, we’re investing about $1 billion to help smaller meat processors expand their capacity; give farmers, ranchers, and consumers more options and be- &#8212; better prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; But capitalism without competition is not capitalism.&nbsp; It&#8217;s exploitation.&nbsp; It&#8217;s exploitation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, we can make sure that American agricultural exports will make up for the gap in Ukrainian supplies.&nbsp; In fact, during my first year in office, American agriculture exports shattered all previous records: $177 billion last year alone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I remind people: My predecessor did not come close.</p>



<p>By traveling in our &#8212; you know, by &#8212; we can&#8217;t &#8212; we have to keep investing in our farmers to reduce the costs, to reduce prices to consumers, and have the most productive, most efficient farmers in the world here in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve always combined generations of know-how with cutting-edge technology to feed us and the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m going to keep fighting for family farmers like Jeff so they can do what they do best.&nbsp; I hope Congress is going to join me &#8212; I know Robin is going to fight like hell to have it happen &#8212; in working hard to invest in farmers like Jeff and feed America and the world.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we have to do.</p>



<p>Let me close with this: Look at the family farms like this one as a reminder of the bounty, beauty, and generosity of this nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know this &#8212; and you’re tired of hearing me say this for the last two years.&nbsp; It’s never, ever &#8212; I always &#8212;</p>



<p>I was on the Tibetan Plateau with Xi Jinping.&nbsp; I’ve traveled with him and spent more time with him than any other world leader has in China.</p>



<p>And he said &#8212; he was talking about why America is a diminishing power.&nbsp; And I said, “Mr. President, it’s never been a good bet to bet against the American people.&nbsp; No one has ever won betting against the American people.”</p>



<p>And I said, “And, by the way, you asked me…”&nbsp; He went on and he said, “Can you define America for me?”&nbsp; Just me and a translator, and him and a translator.&nbsp; Simultaneous translation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, I turned all my notes over to the State Department.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It matters.</p>



<p>But, you know, what happened was, he said, “Can you define America for me?”&nbsp; And this is the God’s truth because &#8212; been quoted a thousand times now.&nbsp; I said, “Yes, one word: possibilities.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re the only nation in the world &#8212; the only nation in the world that has come out of every crisis stronger than we went in it, every single time, regardless of what it was.&nbsp; No other nation has done that.</p>



<p>It’s one of the reasons why in some places we’re called the “ugly Americans.”&nbsp; We think we can do anything.&nbsp; We know we can do anything.&nbsp; We know.</p>



<p>This nation leads the world.&nbsp; We stand up for freedom.&nbsp; We’re the United States of America.&nbsp; And when we are united, there’s not a damn thing we can’t do.&nbsp; That’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; It’s a fact.&nbsp; As a student of history, it’s a fact.&nbsp; There’s nothing beyond our capacity when we work together.&nbsp; Nothing.</p>



<p>So, I’m here to say: God bless our farmers.&nbsp; And I mean this sincerely.&nbsp; God protect our firefighters.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you for what you do.&nbsp; America owes you.&nbsp; They owe you big.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:30 P.M. CDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre En Route Kankakee,&#160;Il</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/11/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-en-route-kankakee-il/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 19:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52960</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:51 A.M. EDT&#160;MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hey, guys.&#160;&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Hello.&#160;MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hello.&#160; Hello.&#160; Good morning. &#160;Okay.&#160; Just two things for you at the top. &#160;And I&#8217;ll try and speak as loud as I can.&#160;All right.&#160; Good morning.&#160; Thanks for joining us for President Biden’s trip to Illinois.&#160; As you know, our first stop is to Kankakee, where the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:51 A.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Good morning. &nbsp;Okay.&nbsp; Just two things for you at the top. &nbsp;And I&#8217;ll try and speak as loud as I can.<br>&nbsp;<br>All right.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Thanks for joining us for President Biden’s trip to Illinois.&nbsp; As you know, our first stop is to Kankakee, where the President will visit O’Connor Farms, a family farm owned by Jeff and Gina O’Connor.&nbsp; The farm is 800 acres and grows wheat, corn, and soybeans.<br>&nbsp;<br>The O’Connors use double cropping of wheat and soybeans on their farm, which, for those unfamiliar, means harvesting two crops from the same field in a given year.&nbsp; They are currently growing wheat that we will be &#8212; that will be harvested in July and then will double crop with soybeans on those same acres. They al- &#8212; they are also in the process of planting corn on their other acres.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden will be joined by Secretary of Agriculture Tom Vilsack.&nbsp; The President will highlight the impact of Putin’s invasion of Ukraine on our domestic and global food supply and the war’s contribution to the rise in food prices at home and abroad.<br>&nbsp;<br>Fighting inflation and lowering costs for Americans is the President’s top priority, and he will deliver remarks on the effect of Putin’s price hike on the cost of food and energy.&nbsp; He will describe his administration’s action to support farmers and food processors &#8212; (clears throat) &#8212; excuse me &#8212; lower their cost and lower prices for families.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Later in the day, the President will address the IBEW’s &#8212; International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers &#8212; 40th Convention, where he will discuss his support for union jobs in the infrastructure and energy industries; increasing the number of countries eligible for double cropping insurance so that we can boost food production; increasing technical assistance for precision agriculture, allowing farmers to use less fertilizer without reducing yields; and doubling our investment for domestic fertilizer production to $500 million.<br>&nbsp;<br>Later in the day, the President will address the IBEW’s 40th Convention where he will discuss his support for union jobs in the infrastructure and energy industries.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Throughout the day, the President will be joined by Governor J. B. Pritzker; Congresswoman Robin Kelly &#8212; we’ll be in her district; and one &#8212; of course, many IBEW labor leaders at their convention.&nbsp; And we’ll be in her district at the farm, just to be clear there.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One last thing I just want to note is that, yesterday, the Senate confirmed Lisa Cook to be the first Black woman to ever serve on the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; Not only does Dr. Cook make history with this confirmation, but she is eminently qualified for this position at a critical moment of our economic process.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We call on the Senate to swiftly confirm Jerome Powell and Philip Jefferson this week as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, Zeke, you want to kick us off?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Does the White House, does the President have any response to the killing of Al Jazeera journalist and American citizen Shireen Abu Akleh?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And will that affect the President&#8217;s trip &#8212; planned trip to Israel next month?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, we strongly condemn the killing of Al Jazeera journalist and American citizen Shireen Abu Akleh in Jenin today, and we extend our deepest condolences to her family.&nbsp; We call for a thorough investigation to determine the circumstances of her death.&nbsp; Investigating attacks on independent media and prosecuting those responsible are of paramount importance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will continue to promote media freedom and protect journalists’ ability to do their jobs without fear of violence, threats to their lives or safety, or unjust detention.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don&#8217;t have anything else to preview about his trip.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And does the President plan to make any calls to Israeli officials about this or her family, or anything of that sort?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I&#8217;m happy to check, but I don&#8217;t have anything right now to preview on any calls that he&#8217;ll be making.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a question about the ASEAN Summit that&#8217;s coming up?&nbsp; Can you give me a broad sense of what the President hopes to achieve from that, please?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, today, at around two o&#8217;clock &#8212; I think 2:45 &#8212; we&#8217;ll have a preview call.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;ll have the full schedule and also, clearly, take questions from your colleagues since you guys are here with us heading to Illinois.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ll have more on deliverables tomorrow, so we&#8217;ll probably do a backgrounder on that &#8212; a preview call on that.&nbsp; But you can expect to see us deepen our longstanding cooperation by investing in our countries and driving inclusive prosperity in this critical region.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>At the end of last year, President Biden announced $102 million in new initiatives to expand our engagement with ASEAN on COVID-19 recovery and health security, fighting the climate crisis, stimulating broad-based economic growth, and deepening people-to-people ties.&nbsp; We will keep building on this.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, I would push back on any of the characterizations that are out there that the U.S. hasn&#8217;t done much in the region since TPP, which never went into effect in the first place.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We have long, strong &#8212; we have strong trade and investment relationships in the region; for example, the ASEAN countries &#8212; collectively, the United States’ fourth-largest goods trading partner.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We saw U.S. exports of goods to the Asia-Pacific increase in 2021 by 25 percent from 2020, U.S. imports increase in 2021 by 19 percent from 2020.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen also &#8212; we&#8217;ve also seen increased foreign direct investment between the U.S. and the Asia-Pacific.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as you all know, we&#8217;ve also been developing an Indo-Pacific Economic Framework to deepen our economic presence in the region.&nbsp; We’ll have more to say on this soon and are encouraged to see the int- &#8212; the interests of partners in the region.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on ASEAN, can I ask you about &#8212; you talked about trade and economic issues.&nbsp; What about human rights?&nbsp; How does that fit into the ASEAN (inaudible)?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, that is something that clearly we &#8212; we are monitoring, and that is &#8212; it’s something that&#8217;s important to this administration.<br>&nbsp;<br>Clearly, that is &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s &#8212; it is something that, when you think about Cambodia, that&#8217;s the question that we tend to get.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, the President and our administration has been clear about human rights concern and promoting human rights in Cambodia, just as an example.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President will, of course, not hold back from expressing his views and his priorities to promote human rights in that region.<br>&nbsp;<br>The summit is a &#8212; is a U.S.-ASEAN Summit, and Cambodia is the chair of the ASEAN, as you know.&nbsp; So, the leaders &#8212; so the leaders of that &#8212; of that summit as well &#8212; as well &#8212; the ASEAN General &#8212; Secretary General were invited; the different countries: Cambodia, Indonesia, Laos, Malaysia, Philippines, Singapore, Thailand, and Vietnam.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, it&#8217;s &#8212; a nonpolitical represent- &#8212; representative of Burma was invited to the summit in accordance of ASEAN&#8217;s 2021 decision to restrict Burma&#8217;s participation in high-level ASEAN meetings due to the military regime&#8217;s failure to implement the ASEAN five-point consensus.<br>&nbsp;<br>We understand that Burma has declined that option, but that is something that, clearly, we will &#8212; the President will (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, have you or the Pre- &#8212; have you seen or has the President seen the situation with the women&#8217;s team at the Delaware State University, where they got pulled over in Georgia?&nbsp; They claimed they were subject to an unfair and unlawful search looking for drugs and whatnot.&nbsp; Do you know about that?&nbsp; Does he know about that?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I actually don&#8217;t.&nbsp; This is the first I&#8217;m hearing of that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to look into that and get back to you, but I actually don’t &#8212; have not heard that one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I wanted to see if you guys have a quick comment on the arrest of the Catholic cardinal in Hong Kong and the other activists there.&nbsp; Did you have anything on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, I do.&nbsp; Give me one second.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, freedom of expression are critical to prosperous and secure societies. &nbsp;We call on PC- &#8212; PRC and Hong Kong authorities to cease targeting Hong Kong’s advocates and to immediately release who have been unjustly detained and charged, like the Cardinal Joseph Zen Ze-kiun and others arrested today.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, Senator Joe Manchin just said that he would be opposing the legislation today on the abortion vote.&nbsp; What message does it send to the country and to the nine justices that you’re going to have a bipartisan majority voting against this legislation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So &#8212; and you’re talking about the Women’s Health Protection Act?<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we put a statement of administration policy out, and so this is the message that we have. &nbsp;And, clearly, the urgency to protect women’s health, their fundamental right to control their reproductive choices, and the freedom of all people to build their own future has never been greater.<br>&nbsp;<br>The position of the Biden administration has been clear since day one: We will defend women’s constitutional rights recognized in Roe v. Wade &#8212; rights that have been under attack for decades and are under unprecedented threat now despite strong support from the American people.</p>



<p>It is evident that the constitutional rights protected for nearly 50 years, as Roe v. Wade, are now in severe jeopardy.&nbsp;&nbsp;It is imperative for Congress to act to adap- &#8212; to adopt statutory protections for women’s access to healthcare services and productive [reproductive] choices &#8212; productive [reproductive] choice, regardless of where they live.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Congress must further act to protect healthcare providers’ ability to provide such critical services free from unwarranted, inappropriate restrictions, and to eliminate unjustified burdens of commerce that prevent women and their families from participating fully and equally in the economic and social life of the &#8212; social life of the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The protec- &#8212; the protections that Women’s Health Protection Act would ensure are essential to the health, safety, and progress of our nation.&nbsp; So that is what we put out there in support of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, just on inflation, as we’re about to land.&nbsp; I know the new numbers today show that inflation slowed somewhat, but core inflation actually jumped up about 0.6 percent.&nbsp; Are you guys concerned that even though prices may start trending down that, at the root of it all, inflation is still a real problem?<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, we’re been clear-eyed in talking about the challenges driving inflation around the globe.&nbsp; As the President said yesterday, the first cause was the pandemic &#8212; the bottlenecks that has caused around &#8212; that has caused around the globe.&nbsp; And there’s no doubt that Putin’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine has also led to high &#8212; higher commodity prices and pain for Americans at the pump.<br>&nbsp;<br>But we know prices are too high on too many Am- &#8212; things for &#8212; on too many things for Amer- &#8212; working Americans.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s why the President is using every tool we have to drive down the costs.&nbsp; That includes historic release of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, announcement this week on lowering the prices of Internet access of millions of Americans, and the President’s travel today to Illinois to speak with farmers about how we can do to lower their costs and help them produce more.&nbsp; And you’ll hear more about that from him later today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you know, we’re starting to see, on the back of the report today, private market forecasts that are suggesting that we won&#8217;t see a significant deceleration of inflation until early next year, including all of the steps you&#8217;re taking, including the predicted path of Fed policy.&nbsp; Is that consistent with your estimates at this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp;Look, you know &#8212; I mean, I guess, more top- &#8212; topically, I would say that: You know, it&#8217;s heartening that the annual inflation cooled in April, which is what we saw. But as the President said yesterday, inflation is unacceptably high and bringing down prices is his top priority.&nbsp;&nbsp;That&#8217;s going to be our main focus.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I leave the prediction to the Fed &#8212; Federal Reserve and other experts, but his plan is focused on lowering the cost that families face and reducing the federal &#8212; the federal deficit.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s going to be &#8212; that&#8217;s going to be our focus for moving forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President’s executive order on cryptocurrency a few months ago &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; set out some research.&nbsp; Agencies were going to spend a few months looking at it, come back with proposals.&nbsp; That market is in significant movement right now.&nbsp; Bitcoin has lost something like more than half its value.&nbsp; So I guess the question is: Should regulators move quicker in light of the, you know, recent movement on crypto now that there are signs of, you know, systemic problems or at least a sharp plunge in the sector?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, just like the stock market, as you know, we don&#8217;t judge the economy by the daily movement of crypto.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But as you know, all &#8212; as well, crypto is a highly volatile asset.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why the President signed an EO outlining the first ever whole-of-government approach to addressing the risks and opportunities of digital assets.&nbsp; Reviews of digital assets, including crypto, is underway across agencies.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I don&#8217;t have anything right now to preview, but that is something that we&#8217;re looking at that’s being reviewed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re not planning on &#8212; for speeding it up or changing course, given the movements we&#8217;ve seen in the last couple of &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I don’t &#8212; I mean, I just don’t have anything more than what I just stated.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Can I ask &#8212; on baby formula, there&#8217;s been severe shortages throughout much of the country over many weeks and months, but particularly the last couple of weeks.&nbsp; What is the administration doing?&nbsp; What can you do?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp;&nbsp;Yeah, that’s something certainly we&#8217;ve been tracking.&nbsp;&nbsp;Ensuring that &#8212; so ensuring that infant form- &#8212; formula is safe and available for families across the country is a top priority to the White House and this administration.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We know that Abbott&#8217;s voluntary recall of infant formula products has led to some Americans being unable to access infant formula and other critical medical food supply.&nbsp; This is an urgent issue that the FDA, as you all know, and the White House is working 24/7 to address.&nbsp; They are committed to pulling every lever and are ready to making progress and getting more supply onto the market.<br>&nbsp;<br>In fact, in April, sales were about 10 percent greater than in March.&nbsp; Right now, consumers should be able to find general powdered infant formulas in stores, but we are focused on doing everything we can to ensure formula is more easily available.<br>&nbsp;<br>Just a couple of things I&#8217;ll read out really quickly &#8212; what FDA is doing.&nbsp;&nbsp;They&#8217;re working closely with industry to maximize their production capabilities by opening new lines for products in high demand, expediting FDA reviews to mo- &#8212; to more efficiently get supply out, and expanding hours of operation for manufacturers; expediting the importance [importation] of products produced aboard [abroad]; calling on retailer groups to consider placing purchase limits on some products to avoid the possibility of hoarding that could further constraint the market.<br>&nbsp;<br>And anyone who needs certain speci- &#8212; specific and metabolic formulas should consult their healthcare providers for guidance and alternatives to their current formula.<br>&nbsp;<br>I can take one right now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; who’s running point on the formula issue at the White House?&nbsp; You mentioned the White House is involved.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I &#8212; at the White House, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don’t know.&nbsp; I can find out for you and get you a person who&#8217;s running point.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have a (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You got time for one on Putin?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on the DNI’s testimony.&nbsp; She said Putin might take drastic means, escalatory optio- &#8212; military options and might view losing as an existential threat.&nbsp; How does that assessment change how you guys are dealing with the situation over there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean &#8212; so, look, it’s clear that Putin has not been able to accomplish the objectives he’s laid out before Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; Russia has failed to overthrow the Ukrainian government.&nbsp; They lost the Battle of &#8212; for Kyiv and were forced to retreat and re- &#8212; refocus elsewhere.&nbsp; And they have failed to divide the West.<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, the &#8212; you know, when it comes to &#8212; you know, you hear the question about diplomacy.&nbsp; Diplomacy is the only way to end this conflict, but Russia has shown no signs that they are willing to seriously engage in negotiations.&nbsp; So, we are focused on strengthening Ukraine’s hand as possible on the battlefields so that when the time comes, they have as much leverage as possible at the negotiation table.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, again, as we’ve said over and over again, this is &#8212; this is Russia’s war.&nbsp; They &#8212; they created this war.&nbsp; They invaded Ukraine in a brutal way.&nbsp; And so, what Ukraine is doing is they are defending themselves and their democracy.&nbsp; So, this is for Russia to end this war.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.<br>&nbsp;<br>12:08 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on NSA Jake Sullivan’s visit to&#160;Egypt</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-nsa-jake-sullivans-visit-to-egypt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 17:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52953</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and National Security Council Coordinator for the Middle East and North Africa Brett McGurk traveled to Cairo, Egypt on May 10-11 to consult on a broad range of global and regional security challenges. National Security Advisor Sullivan discussed with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi and senior Egyptian officials the global consequences of Russia’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan and National Security Council Coordinator for the Middle East and North Africa Brett McGurk traveled to Cairo, Egypt on May 10-11 to consult on a broad range of global and regional security challenges. National Security Advisor Sullivan discussed with President Abdel Fattah Al Sisi and senior Egyptian officials the global consequences of Russia’s unprovoked war against Ukraine, and Washington’s support for Egypt’s security, food, and fuel needs.  The delegations also discussed coordination on regional issues, as well as the importance of tangible and lasting human rights progress in Egypt. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Global Health Worker&#160;Initiative</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/fact-sheet-the-biden-harris-administration-global-health-worker-initiative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 16:13:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This pandemic has spotlighted the critical role and bravery of health and care workers. That’s why I’ve asked my Administration to develop a global health workforce plan, to accelerate our contributions to the Sustainable Development Agenda and investments in health and care workers. President Joseph R. Biden, April 7, 2022 Strategic and sustained investments in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>This pandemic has spotlighted the critical role and bravery of health and care workers. That’s why I’ve asked my Administration to develop a global health workforce plan, to accelerate our contributions to the Sustainable Development Agenda and investments in health and care workers.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>President Joseph R. Biden, April 7, 2022</em></p>



<p>Strategic and sustained investments in the global health workforce are key to catalyzing the U.S. Government’s efforts to achieve the 2030 Sustainable Development Agenda. The COVID-19 pandemic has further exacerbated the estimated global shortage of 18 million health workers by 2030.  With growing health demands from new and emerging pathogens, aging populations, climate shocks, and increasing conflict and migration, the ever-increasing demand for health workers needs greater coordinated attention and action. A comprehensive, trained, protected, well-equipped, and supported workforce is foundational to expanding equitable access to public health services and health care across the globe.  Investments in health workers not only improve health outcomes, they create jobs and career pathways and economic development by strengthening human capital as part of the care economy.  Funding advancements for the health workforce will accelerate ending the COVID-19 pandemic, stimulate economic recovery, and support critical components of President Biden’s values-driven global infrastructure initiative announced at the 2021 G7 Summit by strengthening global health systems, expanding national and regional capacity, including manufacturing of essential medical products.  These investments will also build on commitments made by global partners at the 2nd Global COVID-19 Summit co-hosted by the United States to accelerate combatting COVID-19 and advancing future preparedness.<br><br>Currently, U.S. Government programs such as the U.S. President&#8217;s Emergency Plan for AIDS Relief (PEPFAR), the U.S. President’s Malaria Initiative (PMI), and U.S. bilateral global health security partnerships in support of the Global Health Security Agenda, contribute approximately $1.56 billion annually to support the health workforce across the globe. Further, the President’s Fiscal Year (FY) 2023 Budget prioritizes advancing investments across health programs to strengthen health systems and the global health workforce and support. Notably, the President’s Budget includes an additional $1 billion for this new Global Health Worker Initiative to support and protect the global health workforce as part of the Administration’s increased prioritization and investments in health workforce. This funding, if provided by Congress, would be directed through the U.S. Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and coordinated with others in the U.S. government. <br><br>The Global Health Worker Initiative expands and defines &#8220;health workers&#8221; broadly to include a multidisciplinary workforce including clinicians, community health and care workers, and public health professionals. It provides a framework to guide and organize the U.S. Government’s investments and strengthen coordination with key partners including G7 and G20 countries, multilateral and regional organizations, and the private sector. While global in focus, this effort complements President Biden’s efforts to support the domestic health workforce.<br><br>From the beginning of the Biden-Harris Administration, the United States has demonstrated renewed leadership in global health through action and smart, targeted investments. The United States will continue to advance global health priorities and build upon existing efforts aligned to the following four pillars of focus under the Global Health Worker Initiative:<br><br><strong>PROTECTING HEALTH WORKERS</strong><br><br>Through global health programs, the U.S Government will advance work to ensure health workers across facilities and communities have prioritized access to vaccinations [and treatment], personal protective equipment (PPE), and services to support their physical and mental health and well-being and better protection and safeguards from violence and attacks on health facilities, including in conflict and humanitarian settings.   </p>



<ul><li><strong>Accelerate coordinated efforts to protect health workers fighting COVID-19.</strong>&nbsp;The COVID-19 Global Action Plan (GAP), announced by Secretary Blinken on February 14, 2022, has six lines of effort to help end the acute phase of the pandemic, including a dedicated effort specifically to support health workers. The GAP aims to galvanize partner countries and international organizations to decrease risks posed by COVID-19 by increasing vaccine and treatment availability, encouraging vaccine uptake, addressing workplace safety, and health worker training.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Provide tools and resources for health workers responding to COVID-19 while ensuring delivery of primary health services.</strong>&nbsp;Ongoing U.S. Government programming is adapting to account for the pandemic. For example, PMI trains health workers to efficiently and effectively diagnose and treat malaria in the context of COVID-19, including educating patients to avoid risk of transmission and where to access COVID-19 and malaria treatment services.&nbsp;&nbsp;PEPFAR-funded health workers have ensured delivery of essential HIV prevention and treatment services while responding to the pandemic, by leveraging over 100,000 health workers to support COVID-19 needs across more than 40 countries. PEPFAR is also focused on reducing the risk of health worker burnout and longer-term mental health effects by providing support, including time off for self-care, recuperation, and family’s needs; and advancing access to mental health services. Additionally, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), at the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), is working to improve local and regional healthcare personnel safety and infection prevention and control in more than 15 countries across four continents. These efforts involve healthcare worker surveillance to quickly detect infections; facility-based comprehensive safety assessments and quality improvement initiatives; infectious disease detection and response; training, supervision, and regional communities of practice; and technical engagement with Ministries of Health to ensure implementation consistent with global norms.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Supporting health workers in conflict settings.</strong>&nbsp;In Ukraine, USAID is supporting the Ministry of Health and National Health Service of Ukraine to develop an incentive system to attract, retain, and equitably distribute health care workers in war-impacted regions, using both financial and non-financial incentives so that local authorities will be better able to hire health care workers to fill critical shortages.&nbsp;&nbsp;To address the significant mental health strains of COVID-19 and the subsequent Russian invasion, USAID is also supporting the scale-up of mental health counseling services for conflict-affected populations, including health workers.</li></ul>



<p><strong><br>EXPAND THE GLOBAL HEALTH WORKFORCE AND ACCELERATE ECONOMIC DEVELOPMENT</strong><br><br>The U.S Government will continue efforts to create career pathways and expand paid employment opportunities for a more diverse and gender equitable workforce in the public and private health sectors, better equipping healthcare and community health workers, to meet local population health needs including provision of patient-centered services at the primary health care level. These efforts will further build local and regional institutional capacity to manage and support a global health workforce that is adequately prepared and aligned to respond to routine and emergency surge capacity needs.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Promote fair and timely pay for all health workers.</strong>&nbsp;Through our global health programs, including PEPFAR and PMI, we will continue to promote fair and timely compensation for health workers.&nbsp;&nbsp;PEPFAR will continue to align its financial support for over 330,000 health workers, a $1 billion annual investment, helping achieve HIV epidemic control in over 40 countries. Similarly, PMI recently updated their policies to allow the use of PMI funds to provide salaries or stipends to community health workers in settings where payment to them is in line with government policy.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Develop a multidisciplinary Global Health Security workforce.</strong>&nbsp;Achieving global health security requires a multi-sectoral approach that incorporates an understanding of the linkages among human, animal, and environmental health– a “One Health” approach. As part of the U.S. Government’s Global Health Security programs, USAID is investing up to $85 million over five years to create a “next generation” health workforce. In 2021, USAID worked with more than 110 universities in 17 countries across Africa and Southeast Asia to train more than 18,000 current and future health workers for more effective disease surveillance and control. CDC has partnered with five leading international organizations to develop the Global Laboratory Leadership Programme (GLLP).&nbsp;&nbsp;The GLLP is a comprehensive One Health-based training program for human and animal health laboratories. The GLLP is currently implemented in over 20 countries in the Americas, Africa, Asia, and the Middle East. In addition, the CDC Field Epidemiology Training Program (FETP) is recognized worldwide as an effective means to strengthen countries’ capacity to prevent, detect, and respond to public health threats through enhanced surveillance, epidemiology, and outbreak response functions. CDC works with partner countries to establish FETPs and to train epidemiologists across all levels of a country’s health system. To date, FETP has been implemented in more than 80 countries around the globe with more than 20,000 graduates with many FETP graduates becoming leaders and managers in&nbsp;&nbsp;Ministries of Health or national public health institutes.&nbsp;&nbsp;These activities accelerate progress of the United States Global Health Security Strategy, and will continue to help our partners build country-level capacities in line with their World Health Organization&nbsp;&nbsp;Joint External Evaluations, National Action Plans for Health Security, and other tools the strengthen compliance with the International Health Regulations (IHR 2005).<br></li><li><strong>Collaborate with local partners and country governments to build a sustainable health workforce.</strong>&nbsp;As part of localization efforts, USAID is advancing work with local partners to strengthen human resources planning, management, and oversight to overcome health worker shortfalls. Increasing direct partnerships with host country government entities is essential to improving sustainability of health systems. For example, USAID, through a $10 million Government-to-Government (G2G) investment, is working with the Government of Malawi to fill critical health workforce financing gaps and strengthen health systems.&nbsp;&nbsp;Part of the Malawi G2G programming agreement includes a phased transition of these health workforces to Malawi Government financing, with immediate provision of critical health services while building systems to sustain those health workers beyond USAID funding.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Optimize the health workers to support global COVID-19 vaccination efforts.</strong>&nbsp;The Initiative for Global Vaccine Access (Global VAX), a whole-of-government effort to turn vaccines in vials into vaccinations in arms around the world, builds on existing U.S. Government efforts with total cumulative commitments of more than $1.7 billion, helping over 100 countries prepare to receive and administer COVID-19 vaccines with surge funding and support to 11 countries (Angola, Côte d’Ivoire, Eswatini, Ghana, Lesotho, Nigeria, Senegal, South Africa, Tanzania, Uganda and Zambia). Through Global VAX, the U.S. Government is providing financial and technical assistance to engage and train additional health workers for vaccination efforts, including vaccine delivery, community engagement, record keeping, local micro-planning, and cold chain maintenance.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>ADVANCE EQUITY AND INCLUSION</strong><br><br>President Biden’s commitment to advancing equity and inclusion goes beyond our borders. The U.S Government will carry forward his commitment globally to address numerous barriers, including gender, ethnic/racial, geographic, age, and others, particularly among the community health workforce, to build a more diverse cohort of health worker graduates and leaders that reflects inclusivity, is better-equipped to serve local populations and provide patient-centered care including at the primary health care level.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Addressing the gender gap.</strong>&nbsp;Recognizing that women represent 70 percent of the global health workforce, the U.S. Government is increasing waged employment opportunities and leadership opportunities for women in the health workforce in alignment with the U.S. Government’s first-ever National Strategy on Gender Equity and Equality with commitment to advance the full participation of all people- including women and girls- in the United States and around the world,&nbsp;&nbsp;focus on building the global care economy and care infrastructure, and improve economic security and accelerate economic growth. This includes USAID’s development of recruitment strategies for employment of at-risk, vulnerable youth and women; partnership with the private sector; and supporting the professionalization of community health workers.&nbsp;&nbsp;PEPFAR has invested more than $1.3 billion supporting nearly 2.5 million adolescent girls and young women through the Determined, Resilient, Empowered, AIDS-free, Mentored and Safe (DREAMS) program in the last five years. The partnership supports adolescent girls and young women with socioeconomic opportunities, including employment in the health sector, as part of efforts aimed at reducing rates of HIV among adolescent girls and young women in the highest HIV burden countries.<br></li><li><strong>Health workers reflect the populations they serve</strong>. It is critical that countries recruit and retain a diverse health workforce to help meet the needs of those populations.&nbsp;&nbsp;PEPFAR has partnered with Historically Black Colleges and Universities through Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), at HHS, to provide opportunities for adolescent girls and young women, who are at high risk for early sexual debut and HIV, to receive training as community health workers and be employed to provide essential health services to their home communities in areas where there are critical shortages of health care workers. This work has started in Malawi.<br></li><li><strong>Diversifying the global health research workforce.</strong>&nbsp;The National Institutes of Health (NIH), part of HHS, is the largest funder of health research in the world, and is building an inclusive, diverse, and global scientific workforce conducting research in Federal government laboratories. In addition, the NIH Fogarty International Center (FIC) has an exclusive international mission and responsibility for foreign research coordination that includes a focus on building research capacity in low- and middle-income countries (LMICs) by providing training and research support through a variety of programs to address emerging global health needs. Much of FIC’s resources are dedicated to building research capacity in LMICs.&nbsp;&nbsp;Since 1989, more than 7,500 individuals from over 130 countries have trained through FIC programs.<br></li><li><strong>Reaching rural and remote populations</strong>. Across the globe, Peace Corps staff and Volunteers continue to work alongside existing health service providers and community health workers in difficult to reach rural and “last mile” communities and provide training of health workers to support vaccination, community engagement, disease prevention measures, surveillance activities, referral facilitation, and social and behavioral change to promote delivery of improved quality health services delivery.<br></li></ul>



<p><strong>DRIVE AND INVEST IN TECHNOLOGICAL ADVANCEMENTS AND INNOVATION</strong><br><br>The U.S Government will further harness innovation and expand digital technologies that equip health workers with the ability to provide more efficient, quality-integrated service delivery, including telehealth services that can extend the reach of health services from facilities and into communities, including the most marginalized populations. The use of digital platforms will be expanded to improve the availability and routine use of quality health workforce data to inform decisions about workforce planning and operations, including performance management and consistent remuneration, and also expand the use of digital tools.&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Digital health as a tool to advance primary health care.</strong>&nbsp;USAID’s Vision for Action in Digital Health and Vision for Health System Strengthening 2030 together lay out a plan for how USAID can increase the responsible use of digital technologies to accelerate programming in the health sector in strategic coordination with partner countries. USAID is investing in integrated digital platforms to advance patient-centered care and support front-line health workers. Current investments include working to advance broad-based functionality and guide improvement of standardized digital health tools and systems used to support health workers in providing a set of essential patient-centered primary health care services.&nbsp;<br></li><li><strong>Digital systems provide real time data to health workers.&nbsp;</strong>PMI supports digital tools in partner countries to equip health workers with real-time data. PMI improves evidence-based decision making by strengthening data collection, management, analysis, and utilization at all levels of the health care delivery system. PMI has invested $8.5 million in Rwanda, Senegal, and Burkina Faso to strengthen integrated and equitable care by equipping community health workers with tools needed to be better-connected to other health workers, bring care to unreached populations, and improve access to near real-time data.<br></li><li><strong>Technology to support data for decision making.&nbsp;</strong>&nbsp;PEPFAR invests nearly $22 million annually to support the development and use of human resource information systems and digital health platforms. These investments provide data for better understanding of the available health workforce and health worker utilization and an additional modality to ensure continuity of safe provision of services. These investments proved invaluable during the COVID-19 pandemic with the employment of modified service delivery models including telehealth service.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Nominates Bipartisan Slate for the United&#160;States Sentencing&#160;Commission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/11/president-biden-nominates-bipartisan-slate-for-the-united-states-sentencing-commission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 14:27:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52928</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is announcing seven experienced and qualified nominees for the U.S. Sentencing Commission, a bipartisan independent agency created during the Reagan Administration.&#160; The Commission was created to reduce sentencing disparities and promote transparency and proportionality in criminal sentencing. The Commission has lacked a quorum since 2019, which has prevented it from doing critical business.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is announcing seven experienced and qualified nominees for the U.S. Sentencing Commission, a bipartisan independent agency created during the Reagan Administration.&nbsp; The Commission was created to reduce sentencing disparities and promote transparency and proportionality in criminal sentencing.</p>



<p>The Commission has lacked a quorum since 2019, which has prevented it from doing critical business. &nbsp;Today, President Biden is pleased to announce the nominations of these individuals – a bipartisan slate including the first Black chair of the organization – whose confirmations would allow the Commission to conduct its important work.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge Carlton W. Reeves</u></strong><strong><u>: Nominee for Commissioner and Chair of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Carlton W. Reeves&nbsp;has served as a United States District Court Judge for the Southern District of Mississippi since 2010. Judge Reeves was previously a partner at Pigott Reeves Johnson &amp; Minor, P.A. from 2001 to 2010. From 1995 to 2001, Judge Reeves served as Chief of the Civil Division for the United States Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of Mississippi. From 1991 to 1995, Judge Reeves was an associate at Phelps Dunbar LLP. In 1991, Judge Reeves was a staff attorney for the Supreme Court of Mississippi. Judge Reeves served as a law clerk for Justice&nbsp;Reuben V. Anderson on the Mississippi Supreme Court&nbsp;from 1989 to 1990.</p>



<p>Judge Reeves received his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1989 and his B.A.&nbsp;from&nbsp;Jackson State University&nbsp;in 1986.</p>



<p><strong><u>Laura Mate: Nominee for Commissioner and Vice Chair of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Laura Mate has served as the Director of Sentencing Resource Counsel, a project of the Federal Public and Community Defenders in the Office of the Federal Public Defender for the District of Arizona, since 2021 and from 2010 to 2021 was a member of Sentencing Resource Counsel. From 2001 to 2010, Ms. Mate served in the Office of the Federal Public Defender for the Western District of Washington in various roles, including as Assistant Federal Public Defender. Ms. Mate was an associate at Perkins Coie LLP from 1998 to 2001.</p>



<p>Ms. Mate received her J.D. from the University of Michigan Law School in 1998 and her B.A. from Kenyon College in 1992.</p>



<p><strong><u>Claire McCusker Murray: Nominee for Commissioner and Vice Chair of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Claire McCusker Murray served as the Principal Deputy Associate Attorney General of the United States Department of Justice from 2019 to 2021. She also served as Acting Associate Attorney General in 2021 and as Counselor to the Attorney General in 2019. From 2017 to 2019, Ms. Murray served in the White House Counsel’s Office as Special Assistant and Associate Counsel to the President. From 2013 to 2017, Ms. Murray worked at Kirkland &amp; Ellis as an associate until she was elevated to partner in 2015. From 2010 to 2012, Ms. Murray served as a trial attorney in the Criminal Division of the United States&nbsp;Department of Justice as part of the Attorney General’s Honors Program and as a Special Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Virginia in 2011.&nbsp;She served as a law clerk for Justice Samuel Alito on the Supreme Court of the United States from 2012 to 2013 and for then-Judge Brett Kavanaugh on the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit from 2009 to 2010.</p>



<p>Ms. Murray received her J.D. from Yale Law School in 2009 and her A.B.,&nbsp;<em>magna cum laude</em>, from Harvard College in 2004. She also received an M.Phil. from the University of Cambridge in 2008 and a d.e.a. from l’Ecole des Hautes Etudes en Sciences Sociales in Paris in 2005.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge Luis Felipe Restrepo: Nominee for Commissioner and Vice Chair of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Luis Felipe Restrepo has served as a&nbsp;United States Court of Appeals Judge for&nbsp;the Third Circuit since 2016. Judge Restrepo previously served as a United States District Court Judge for the&nbsp;Eastern District of Pennsylvania&nbsp;from 2013 to 2016. Judge Restrepo served as a&nbsp;United States Magistrate Judge&nbsp;for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania from 2006 to 2013. Judge Restrepo was a partner at Krasner &amp; Restrepo from 1993 to 2006.&nbsp;From 1990 to 1993, he served as an Assistant Federal Defender in the Eastern District of Pennsylvania, and from 1987 to 1990 as an Assistant Defender with the&nbsp;Defender Association of Philadelphia.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Judge Restrepo received his&nbsp;J.D.&nbsp;from Tulane Law School&nbsp;in 1986&nbsp;and his B.A from the&nbsp;University of Pennsylvania in 1981.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge Claria Horn Boom: Nominee for Commissioner of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Claria Horn Boom has served as a&nbsp;United States District Court Judge for the Eastern and Western Districts of Kentucky since 2018. Judge Boom was previously a partner at&nbsp;Frost Brown Todd LLC. Judge Boom served as an&nbsp;Assistant United States Attorney for the United States Attorney’s Office in the Eastern District of Kentucky from 2001 to 2002 and for the Western District of Kentucky from 1998 to 2001. From 1995 to 1998, Judge Boom was as an associate at King &amp; SpaldingLLP.&nbsp;Judge Boom served as a law clerk for Judge&nbsp;Pierce Lively&nbsp;on the&nbsp;United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit&nbsp;from 1994 to 1995.</p>



<p>Judge Boom received her&nbsp;J.D.&nbsp;from Vanderbilt University Law Schooland her B.A.&nbsp;from&nbsp;Transylvania University,&nbsp;<em>summa cum laude</em>.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge John Gleeson: Nominee for Commissioner of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge John Gleeson is a partner at Debevoise and Plimpton LLP in New York, where he has practiced since 2016. From 1994 to 2016 Judge Gleeson served as a United States District Court Judge for the Eastern District of New York. From 1985 to 1994, Judge Gleeson served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of New York. Judge Gleeson served as a law clerk for Judge Boyce Martin on the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit.</p>



<p>Judge Gleeson received his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 1980 and his B.A. from Georgetown University in 1975.</p>



<p><strong><u>Candice C. Wong: Nominee for Commissioner of the United States Sentencing Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Candice C. Wong serves as an Assistant United States Attorney and Chief of the Violence Reduction and Trafficking Offenses Section in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia. Ms. Wong joined the United States Attorney’s Office in 2015, and from 2017 to 2021, was detailed to the Criminal Division of the United States Department of Justice. There, she served in various roles, including as Acting Deputy Assistant Attorney General and Acting Chief of Staff in the Criminal Division. From 2020 to 2021, Ms. Wong also served as the Department of Justice’s ex officio member on the United States Sentencing Commission. Ms. Wong was previously an associate at Bancroft PLLC from 2013 to 2015 and at King &amp; Spalding LLP from 2009 to 2011. Ms. Wong served as a law clerk for Justice Sandra Day O’Connor and Justice Sonia M. Sotomayor on the Supreme Court of the United States from 2011 to 2012, and for then-Judge Brett M. Kavanaugh on the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit from 2008 to 2009.</p>



<p>Ms. Wong received her J.D. in 2008 from Harvard Law School and her A.B. in 2004 from Harvard College.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
