<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 23:34:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official on Russia&#160;Sanctions</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/22/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-russia-sanctions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 23:34:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  3:34 P.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining today.&#160; So, as a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official,&#8221; and the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; For your awareness but not for reporting, the speaker on&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Via Teleconference</em><strong> </strong></p>



<p>3:34 P.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining today.&nbsp; So, as a reminder, this call is on background, attributable to a &#8220;senior administration official,&#8221; and the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For your awareness but not for reporting, the speaker on the call is [senior administration official].&nbsp; And I think they&#8217;re going to have some remarks to start at the top, and then we can take some questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Yes, I&#8217;ll make a few comments at the top and then happy to answer any of your questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, Russia’s long-previewed invasion of Ukraine has now begun, and our response has also begun.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Today, we responded swiftly and in a united fashion with our Allies and partners.&nbsp; The speed and coordination of the response was historic.&nbsp; We announced our first tranche of sanctions in less than a day with Allies and partners from the European Union, from the United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, and Australia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This response was taken much faster and goes much further than what we did in 2014.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me say a few words about the details of the package.&nbsp; First, after consultations overnight with Germany, Russia&#8217;s Nord Stream 2 natural gas pipeline will not become operational.&nbsp; That&#8217;s an $11 billion investment and a prized gas pipeline controlled by Russia that will now go to waste, and it sacrifices what would have been a cash cow for Russia&#8217;s financial coffers.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it&#8217;s not just about the money.&nbsp; This decision will relieve Russia&#8217;s geostrategic chokehold over Europe through its supply of natural gas, and it&#8217;s a major turning point in the world&#8217;s energy independence from Russia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, we&#8217;ve made a demonstration of the power of our financial sanctions.&nbsp; And make no mistake, this is only the sharp edge of the pain we can inflict.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, again, in lockstep with our Allies, we&#8217;re fully blocking from the U.S. and European financial systems the fifth-largest Russian financial firm, which is V.E.B. &#8212; a glorified piggy bank for the Kremlin that holds more than $50 billion in assets.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also fully blocking a $35 billion bank, Promsvyazbank, that finances the activities of the Russian military.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In plain English, the full block of these banks means they can no longer make any transactions with the U.S. or Europe, and their assets in our respective financial systems are frozen.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And let me be totally clear: No Russian financial institution is safe if this invasion proceeds.&nbsp; We are ready to press a button to take further action on the very largest Russian financial institutions, including Sperbank and VTB, which collectively hold almost $750 billion in assets &#8212; or more than half the total in Russia as a whole.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Third, together with our Allies, we&#8217;ve also cut off the Russian government, the Russian Central Bank, and its sovereign wealth funds from U.S. financing.&nbsp; Europe has taken a very similar measure.&nbsp; That means the Kremlin can no longer raise money from the U.S. and Europe, and its new debt can no longer trade in U.S. or European markets.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Fourth, we have fully sanctioned a group of Russian elites and their family members.&nbsp; These individuals have shared in the corrupt gains of the Kremlin, and they will now share in the pain.&nbsp; Other Russian elites and their family members are now on notice that additional actions could be taken on them as well.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me also just take a minute to address a key part of the President&#8217;s speech on energy.&nbsp; We were quite deliberate to make sure that the pain of our sanctions is targeted at the Russian economy, not ours.&nbsp; So none of the measures are designed to disrupt the flow of energy to global markets, and we are now executing a plan in coordination with major oil consumers and oil producers towards our collective interest to secure the stability of global energy supplies.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me just stop there and take your questions.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; So, I just want to &#8212; you know, throughout the last couple of months, there’s been talk from administration officials about the idea of starting high and staying high.&nbsp; This appears, perhaps, more as starting medium.&nbsp; And I was wondering how does this square with the bigger idea of starting high and staying high, not having things like SWIFT in this first tranche of sanctions.&nbsp; And what was the thinking on not including some sort of levy to reinforce the German’s move on Nord Stream 2?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, sure.&nbsp; So, first of all, these are &#8212; we are starting high.&nbsp; These are severe costs that we’re imposing.&nbsp; Nord Stream 2, for example, is Putin&#8217;s prized pipeline.&nbsp; He poured $11 billion into building the pipeline.&nbsp; It would have provided billions of dollars each year in revenues.&nbsp; That is now shut down after very close consultations overnight with Germany.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Second, you know, we made a demonstration out of two very significant Russian financial institutions, both of which have close ties to the Kremlin and the Russian military.&nbsp; They control over $80 billion in assets.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re clearly &#8212; I&#8217;m clearly signaling and the President has signaled we&#8217;re prepared to take action on other Russian banks, including the very largest ones.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then I think it is very significant that the U.S. and Europe have fully cut off the Russian government, its central bank, and its sovereign wealth funds from financing &#8212; from receiving financing from the U.S. and Europe.&nbsp; Over time, that&#8217;s going to mean higher borrowing costs, less capacity to invest, lower growth, lower productive capacity, and less overall ability for Putin to exert leverage on the world stage.&nbsp; So these costs are severe.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The second point I would make is: Look, this is the beginning of an invasion and this is the beginning of our response.&nbsp; If Putin escalates further, we will escalate further, using both financial sanctions and export controls, which we&#8217;ve yet to unveil.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to also underline: Our response goes well beyond sanctions.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to fortify NATO&#8217;s eastern flank to reinforce our sacred commitment to defend every inch of Allied territory.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You heard the President say that additional troops and equipment are going to be shifted within Europe to the Baltics.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to provide defensive military assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; Already, we’ve provided $650 billion in the past year &#8212; the most ever.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to work with Allies and partners to prepare for economic assistance that can help Ukraine become a successful alternative to Russian-style kleptocracy, which may be Putin&#8217;s greatest fear of all.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [Senior administration official], did you ha- &#8212; were you saying something?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; I think &#8212; [senior administration official], I think you were done, so I think we&#8217;re good for a second question, please.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, please.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, who are the Russian elites that are being sanctioned?&nbsp; Do they include Vladimir Putin?&nbsp; And if Putin is not included, why not?</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so I&#8217;ll name the Russian elites, which also includes their family members &#8212; and I apologize for the mispronunciation:&nbsp; Aleksandr Bortnikov and his son, Denis; Sergei Kiriyenko and his son, Vladimir; and Petr Fradkov, who is the CEO of Promsvyazbank.&nbsp; So these individuals and their relatives are all now fully blocked.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With respect to President Putin, I’ll just repeat what the President has said is: And all options remain on the table.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, guys, thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I guess I just wanted to ask: You know, if we’re not going with the maximum sanctions right now, is there a fear that this sort of concedes the breakaway territories to the Ukrainian control &#8212; or to Russian control, rather?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Would you have gone bigger if not for &#8212; you know, we know that there was some reluctance in Europe heading into to this.&nbsp; And so, if you could at all talk about how this package came together and how European concerns weighed on what you went forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, I was also wondering if you had an update on the &#8212; the summits, both with Lavrov and Putin, that had been sort of floated &#8212; the Lavrov one later this week &#8212; in light of what&#8217;s happened.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Hi, Justin.&nbsp; So, again, I mean, these &#8212; these are severe costs that we’re imposing today: shutting down Nord Stream, fully blocking two major financial institutions, cutting off the Russian government from Western financing.&nbsp; They’re severe actions, but this was the beginning of an invasion, and therefore this is the beginning of our response.</p>



<p>And I think, more fundamentally, just to get your question directly: No one should think that our ultimate goal is to max out on sanctions.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not an end to themselves.&nbsp; Sanctions are meant to serve a higher purpose, which is to deter and prevent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we want to prevent a large-scale invasion of Ukraine that involves the seizure of major cities, including Kyiv.&nbsp; We want to prevent large-scale human suffering, possibly tens of thousands of lives that could be lost in a full-scale conflict.&nbsp; And we want to prevent Putin from installing a puppet government that bends to his wishes and denies Ukraine the freedom to set its own course and choose its own destiny.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what this is all about.</p>



<p>With respect to the potential discussions between Secretary Blinken and Minister Lavrov, I would just refer you to the State Department.&nbsp; Secretary Blinken is about to give remarks, and I think he&#8217;ll have more to say on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; I wanted to ask, regarding SWIFT: At what point in the &#8212; and, I guess, the steps that Putin can take &#8212; perhaps, you know, taking a wider swath, going beyond these republics &#8212; is SWIFT going to be used or pulled from?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And second of all, should Americans expect for some higher gas prices in the coming weeks or months?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Hi, Franco.&nbsp; So, with respect to SWIFT, as I mentioned last Friday and as you&#8217;ve seen today, SWIFT is not part of the first package of sanctions that we&#8217;ve rolled out.</p>



<p>And look, we think there are other severe measures that have comparable impact on Russia that we can take in lockstep with Europe and that don&#8217;t have the broader spillover costs.&nbsp; But I &#8212; we are not taking SWIFT off the table.&nbsp; It will remain an option that we can deploy, depending on &#8212; depending on how Russia makes its next move.</p>



<p>With respect to gas prices, energy prices, you know, I&#8217;ll just &#8212; I know there&#8217;s been some talk about whether energy prices are moving higher because of the Nord Stream 2 decision, and I would just emphasize: They are not moving higher because Nord Stream 2 is halted.&nbsp; They&#8217;re moving higher because they&#8217;re worried that Putin will weaponize energy supply and hold the world hostage.</p>



<p>So, the right response is to reduce Europe&#8217;s addiction to Russian gas, and that&#8217;s what today&#8217;s action does.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in the meantime, we&#8217;ll continue to work with Europe to surge natural gas supplies from all over the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as I mentioned at the outset of this call, with respect to oil, we have an ongoing effort right now to execute on a plan that&#8217;s in coordination with oil producers and oil consumers to make sure the world knows we&#8217;re going to have stable energy supplies.  And I think &#8212; I expect you&#8217;ll be hearing more from other countries very soon about that coordination effort.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; (Inaudible) anyone have that sanctions deter Vladimir Putin, whether they&#8217;ve been small or large.&nbsp; Is there anything else in your toolkit beside sanctions?&nbsp; Because he doesn&#8217;t seem to be responding to these.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And was there any thinking that, given what President Zelenskyy said in Munich this weekend, you should start big &#8212; bigger &#8212; with SWIFT and other things that might get his attention rather than escalating slowly?</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Thanks, Andrea.&nbsp; Well, you know, sanctions &#8212; they work over time.&nbsp; And the pain is mounting in Russia.&nbsp; The stock market &#8212; if you look at its performance since November, it&#8217;s down more than 30 percent.&nbsp; The currency over the same time period is &#8212; has lost over 10 percent of its value.&nbsp; The interest rate that the markets are charging the Russian government to borrow has now spiked well above 10 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, if you look back to 2014 when we imposed sanctions, the comments coming out of the leadership of the Russian government suggest that were it not for the costs that we imposed then, which are similar to what we&#8217;re imposing now, Putin may have gone much further, perhaps all the way to Kyiv.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, sanctions are not the only tool in our toolkit.&nbsp; As I mentioned, export controls are a key component of our potential sanctions response.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re similar in concept to financial sanctions.&nbsp; In both cases, we’re denying something to Russia that they need and they can&#8217;t replace from anywhere else or produce at home.</p>



<p>And so, export controls are really potent because we&#8217;re talking about critical technology inputs that Russia needs to diversify its economy, modernize its economy.&nbsp; And we are fully prepared with a very large number of countries across the world to implement those export control measures if the invasion proceeds.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; I think &#8212; could we do our last question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you mentioned the sanctions would hit new issues of sovereign debt.&nbsp; Are there any &#8212; is there any impact on existing issues trading in the secondary market?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s your assessment of the ability or the willingness of Chinese financial institutions to fill the void left by the U.S. and Europe?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; David, so this &#8212; we&#8217;ve designed these sanctions so that Russia cannot raise money from U.S. investors.&nbsp; And Europe has implemented a very similar measure.&nbsp; And so, it&#8217;s the primary market that matters in terms of raising money.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;ve directed our sanction towards that portion of the market.</p>



<p>Whether &#8212; as to whether China can replace U.S. and European investors: I mean, I think the numbers speak for themselves in terms of the percentage of the total that Dollars and Euro represent as a &#8212; as a source of borrowing.&nbsp; Also, just as currencies that are used to make payments, to receive payments, and also to store wealth, store value.&nbsp;</p>



<p>China&#8217;s share on all those metrics I just mentioned are in the low single digits.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s &#8212; it is &#8212; it is nowhere close to a substitute for the Western financial system.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining today.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to “senior administration official.”&nbsp; The embargo lifts officially now.&nbsp; If you have any questions, please feel free to reach out to me, and we&#8217;ll make sure to get back to you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>3:52 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Libya</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-the-president-of-the-senate-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-libya/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 23:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47660</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.  In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to Libya declared in Executive Order 13566 of February 25, 2011, and expanded in Executive Order 13726 of April 19, 2016, is to continue in effect beyond February 25, 2022.<br><br>Libyans confront ongoing instability originating from actions Colonel Muammar Qadhafi, his government, and close associates took against the people of Libya in 2011.  Civil conflict in Libya will continue until Libyans resolve their political divisions and foreign military intervention ends.  Because many of these divisions relate to access to resources, a serious risk remains that, if not protected, Libyan state assets will be misappropriated by parties determined to undermine the ongoing United Nations peace process, including former members of the Qadhafi government, members of the Qadhafi family, or Qadhafi&#8217;s close associates.  The diversion of these resources could prolong and deepen the current instability in Libya, which benefits ISIS and other terrorist groups that pose a serious threat to the national security of the United States and the security of regional partners.  We run the risk of military escalation if sanctions do not remain in effect, particularly since those who reject dialogue and obstruct and undermine Libya&#8217;s democratic transition remain interested in exploiting the wealth of the Libyan people to advance their narrow self-interest and perpetuate conflict in the country.<br><br>The situation in Libya continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States, and we need to protect against the diversion of assets or other abuse by persons hindering Libyan national reconciliation, including Qadhafi&#8217;s family and associates.<br><br>Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13566 with respect to Libya.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Sincerely, <br><br>                               JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to&#160;Libya</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-libya-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 23:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 25, 2011, by Executive Order 13566, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions of Colonel Muammar Qadhafi, his government, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On February 25, 2011, by Executive Order 13566, the President declared a national emergency pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701-1706) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions of Colonel Muammar Qadhafi, his government, and close associates, which took extreme measures against the people of Libya, including by using weapons of war, mercenaries, and wanton violence against unarmed civilians.&nbsp; In addition, there was a serious risk that Libyan state assets would be misappropriated by Qadhafi, members of his government, members of his family, or his close associates if those assets were not protected.&nbsp; The foregoing circumstances, the prolonged attacks, and the increased numbers of Libyans seeking refuge in other countries from the attacks caused a deterioration in the security of Libya and posed a serious risk to its stability.</p>



<p>On April 19, 2016, the President signed Executive Order 13726, which expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13566.&nbsp; The President found that the&nbsp;ongoing violence in Libya, including attacks by armed groups against Libyan state facilities, foreign missions in Libya, and&nbsp;critical infrastructure, as well as human rights abuses, violations of the arms embargo imposed by United Nations Security Council Resolution 1970 (2011), and misappropriation of&nbsp;Libya&#8217;s natural resources threaten the peace, security, stability, sovereignty, democratic transition, and territorial integrity of Libya, and thereby constitute an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.</p>



<p>The situation in Libya continues to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States, and measures are needed to protect against the diversion of assets or other abuses by members of Qadhafi&#8217;s family, their associates, and other persons hindering Libyan national reconciliation.</p>



<p>For this reason, the national emergency declared on February 25, 2011, and expanded on April 19, 2016, must continue in effect beyond February 25, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13566.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.<br>                              </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>February 22, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Parents to Discuss Efforts to Invest in Children and Cut the Cost of Child&#160;Care</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-parents-to-discuss-efforts-to-invest-in-children-and-cut-the-cost-of-child-care/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 22:01:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47655</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Secretary Xavier Becerra, Gender Policy Council Director Jen Klein, and Deputy Assistant to the President for Economic Mobility Carmel Martin hosted a conversation with parents and their children at the White House to discuss the need to cut the crushing child care costs families face and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) Secretary Xavier Becerra, Gender Policy Council Director Jen Klein, and Deputy Assistant to the President for Economic Mobility Carmel Martin hosted a conversation with parents and their children at the White House to discuss the need to cut the crushing child care costs families face and increase the supply of high-quality child care.</p>



<p><br>The Administration officials highlighted President Biden’s plans to make the largest investment in child care and preschool in the nation’s history, saving most working families more than half of their spending on child care and expanding the number of high-quality child care providers. The President’s plan would also enable states to deliver two years of free pre-school for every 3- and 4-year old in a setting of their parents’ choice – from public schools and child care providers to Head Start. They reiterated that early learning experiences help children succeed later in life; research shows that every $1 invested in high-quality early childhood care and education can yield $3 to $7 over the long-run, as children do better in school, are more likely to graduate high-school and college, and earn more as adults.</p>



<p><br>The parents attending the event shared that the high costs of child care and the difficulty of finding quality, affordable child care near their homes made it challenging for them to provide for their families and remain in the workforce. One family member noted spending more than $2,000 a month in child care expense and the immense strain that put on their family’s expenses. The families discussed how the pandemic exacerbated many of the challenges they were already facing when it comes to child care and emphasized how the President’s plans will help families access high-quality early childhood care and education.</p>



<p>You can watch a recording of today’s event by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pQ0dVUiApBU">clicking here</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: United&#160;States Imposes First Tranche of Swift and Severe Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/fact-sheet-united-states-imposes-first-tranche-of-swift-and-severe-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 21:31:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47650</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, Russian President Vladimir Putin of Russia recognized two regions of Ukraine as independent states and today claimed that recognition to include all of the Donbas region. The Russian Parliament also authorized the deployment of additional Russian forces into this Ukrainian territory.&#160; As President Biden and our Allies and partners have made clear, we will&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, Russian President Vladimir Putin of Russia recognized two regions of Ukraine as independent states and today claimed that recognition to include all of the Donbas region. The Russian Parliament also authorized the deployment of additional Russian forces into this Ukrainian territory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As President Biden and our Allies and partners have made clear, we will impose significant costs on Russia for Russia’s actions. Today, the Administration is implementing the first tranche of sanctions that go far beyond 2014, in coordination with allies and partners in the European Union, United Kingdom, Canada, Japan, and Australia. And as President Biden promised, we worked with Germany to ensure the Nord Stream 2 pipeline will not move forward.</p>



<p>The President has directed the following measures:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Full blocking sanctions on two significant Russian financial institutions.</strong> The Secretary of the Treasury will impose full blocking sanctions on two large state-owned Russian financial institutions that provide key services crucial to financing the Kremlin and the Russian military: Vnesheconombank and Promsvyazbank and their subsidiaries. Collectively, these institutions hold more than $80 billion in assets and finance the Russian defense sector and economic development. These measures will freeze their assets in the United States, prohibit U.S. individuals and businesses from doing any transactions with them, shut them out of the global financial system, and foreclose access to the U.S. dollar.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanded sovereign debt prohibitions restricting U.S. individuals and firms from participation in secondary markets for new debt issued by the Central Bank of the Russian Federation, the National Wealth Fund of the Russian Federation, and the Ministry of Finance of the Russian Federation.</strong>  These prohibitions will cut off the Russian government from a key avenue by which it raises capital to fund its priorities and will increase future financing costs. It denies Russia access to key U.S. markets and investors.</li><li><strong>Full blocking sanctions on five Russian elites and their family members: Aleksandr Bortnikov (and his son, Denis), Sergei Kiriyenko (and his son, Vladimir), and Promsvyazbank CEO Petr Fradkov.</strong> These individuals and their relatives directly benefit from their connections with the Kremlin. Other Russian elites and their family members are on notice that additional actions could be taken against them.</li><li><strong>Today,</strong> <strong>the Secretary of the Treasury will determine that any institution in the financial services sector of the Russian Federation economy is a target for further sanctions.</strong> Over 80% of Russia’s daily foreign exchange transactions globally are in U.S. dollars and roughly half of Russia’s international trade is conducted in dollars. With this action,no Russian financial institution is safe from our measures, including the largest banks. </li></ul>



<p>These actions come in addition to steps being taken by our Allies and partners and represent our first response to Russia’s actions. As President Biden made clear, Russia will pay an even steeper price if it continues its aggression.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Announcing Response to Russian Actions in&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/02/22/remarks-by-president-biden-announcing-response-to-russian-actions-in-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 21:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:22 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Trying to make up your mind, huh?&#160; (Laughter.) Well, good afternoon.&#160; Yesterday, Vladimir Putin recognized two regions of Ukraine as independent states and he bizarrely asserted that these regions are no longer part of Ukraine and their sovereign territory.&#160; To put it simply, Russia just announced that it&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>2:22 P.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Trying to make up your mind, huh?&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Well, good afternoon.&nbsp; Yesterday, Vladimir Putin recognized two regions of Ukraine as independent states and he bizarrely asserted that these regions are no longer part of Ukraine and their sovereign territory.&nbsp; To put it simply, Russia just announced that it is carving out a big chunk of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Last night, Putin authorized Russian forces to deploy into the region &#8212; these regions.&nbsp; Today, he asserted that these regions are &#8212; actually extend deeper than the two areas he recognized, claiming large areas currently under the jurisdiction of the Ukraine government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He&#8217;s setting up a rationale to take more territory by force, in my view.&nbsp; And if we listen to his speech last night &#8212; and many of you did, I know &#8212; he&#8217;s &#8212; he&#8217;s setting up a rationale to go much further.</p>



<p>This is the beginning of a Russian invasion of Ukraine, as he indicated and asked permission to be able to do from his Duma.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s begin to &#8212; so, I&#8217;m going to begin to impose sanctions in response, far beyond the steps we and our Allies and partners implemented in 2014.&nbsp; And if Russia goes further with this invasion, we stand prepared to go further as &#8212; with sanction.</p>



<p>Who in the Lord&#8217;s name does Putin think gives him the right to declare new so-called countries on territory that belonged to his neighbors?&nbsp; This is a flagrant violation of international law, and it demands a firm response from the international community.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the last few months, we have coordinated closely with our NATO Allies and partners in Europe and around the world to prepare that response.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve said all along and I&#8217;ve told Putin to his face a mon- &#8212; a month a- &#8212; more than a month ago that we would act together and the moment Russia moved against Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russia has now undeniably moved against Ukraine by declaring these independent states.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, today, I&#8217;m announcing the first tranche of sanctions to impose costs on Russia in response to their actions yesterday.&nbsp; These have been closely coordinated with our Allies and partners, and we&#8217;ll continue to escalate sanctions if Russia escalates.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re implementing full blocking sanctions on two large Russian financial institutions: V.E.B. and their military bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re implementing comprehensive sanctions on Russian sovereign debt.&nbsp; That means we’ve cut off Russia&#8217;s government from Western financing.&nbsp; It can no longer raise money from the West and cannot trade in its new debt on our markets or European markets either.</p>



<p>Starting <s>tomorrow</s> [today] and continuing in the days ahead, we will also impose sanctions on Russia&#8217;s elites and their family members.  They share in the corrupt gains of the Kremlin policies and should share in the pain as well. </p>



<p>And because of Russia’s actions, we’ve worked with Germany to ensure Nord Stream 2 will not &#8212; as I promised &#8212; will not move forward.</p>



<p>As Russia contemplates its next move, we have our next move prepared as well.&nbsp; Russia will pay an even steeper price if it continues its aggression, including additional sanctions.</p>



<p>The United States will continue to provide defensive assistance to Ukraine in the meantime.&nbsp; And we’ll continue to reinforce and reassure our NATO Allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, in response to Russia’s admission that it will not withdraw its forces from Belarus, I have authorized additional movements of U.S. forces and equipment already stationed in Europe to strengthen our Baltic Allies &#8212; Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania.</p>



<p>Let me be clear: These are totally defensive moves on our part.&nbsp; We have no intention of fighting Russia.&nbsp; We want to send an unmistakable message, though, that the United States, together with our Allies, will defend every inch of NATO territory and abide by the commitments we made to NATO.</p>



<p>We still believe that Russia is poised to go much further in launching a massive military attack against Ukraine.&nbsp; I hope I’m wrong about that &#8212; hope we’re wrong about that.&nbsp; But Russia has only escalated its threat against the rest of Ukrainian territory, including major cities and including the capital city of Kyiv.</p>



<p>There are &#8212; there are still well over 150,000 Russian troops surrounding Ukraine.&nbsp; And as I said, Russian forces remain positioned in Belarus to attack Ukraine from the north, including war planes and offensive missile systems.</p>



<p>Russia has moved troops closer to Ukraine’s border with Russia.&nbsp; Russia’s naval vessels are maneuvering in the Black Sea to Ukraine’s south, including amphibious assault ships, missile cruisers, and submarines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russia has moved supplies of blood and medical equipment into position on their border.&nbsp; You don’t need blood unless you plan on starting a war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And over the last few days, we’ve seen much of the playbook that Secretary Blinken laid out last week at the United Nations Security Council come to pass: a major increase in military provocations and false-flag events along the line of contact in the Donbas; dramatically staged, conveniently on-camera meeting of Putin’s Security Council to grandstand for the Russian public; and now political provocation of recognizing sovereign Ukrainian territory as so-called independent republics in clear violation, again, of international law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Putin has sought authorization from the Russian parliament to use military force outside of Russian territory.&nbsp; And this set the stage for further pretexts and further provocations by Russia to try to justify further military action.</p>



<p>None of us &#8212; none of us should be fooled.&nbsp; None of us will be fooled.&nbsp; There is no justification.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Further Russian assault into Ukraine remains a severe threat in the days ahead.&nbsp; And if Russia proceeds, it is Russia, and Russia alone, that bears the responsibility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As we respond, my administration is using every tool at our disposal to protect American businesses and consumers from rising prices at the pump.&nbsp; As I said last week, defending freedom will have costs for us as well, here at home.&nbsp; We need to be honest about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as we will do &#8212; but as we do this, I’m going to take robust action and make sure the pain of our sanctions is targeted at the Russian economy, not ours.</p>



<p>We are closely monitoring energy supplies for any disruption.&nbsp; We’re executing a plan in coordination with major oil-producing consumers and producers toward a collective investment to secure stability and global energy supplies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This will be &#8212; this will blunt gas prices.&nbsp; I want to limit the pain the American people are feeling at the gas pump.&nbsp; This is critical to me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In the last few days, I have been in constant contact with European leaders, including with Ukrainian President Zelenskyy.&nbsp;&nbsp;Vice President Harris met in person with leaders in Germany over the weekend at the Munich Conference, including President Zelenskyy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At every step, we have shown that the United States and our Allies and partners are working in unison &#8212; which he hasn’t been counting on &#8212; Mr. Putin.&nbsp; We’re united in our support of Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;re united in our opposition to Russian aggression.&nbsp;&nbsp;And we’re united in our resolve to defend our NATO Alliance.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re united in our understanding of the urgency and seriousness of the threat Russia is making to global peace and stability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, the world heard clearly the full extent of Vladimir Putin’s twisted rewrite of history, going back more than a century, as he waxed eloquently, noting that &#8212; well, I’m not going to go into it, but nothing in Putin’s lengthy remarks indicated any interest in pursuing real dialogue on European security in the year 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He directly attacked Ukraine’s right to exist.&nbsp; He indirectly threatened territory formerly held by Russia, including nations that today are thriving democracies and members of NATO.&nbsp; He explicitly threatened war unless his extreme demands were met.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there is no question that Russia is the aggressor.&nbsp; So we’re clear-eyed about the challenges we&#8217;re facing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nonetheless, there is still time to avert the worst-case scenario that will bring untold suffering to millions of people if they move as suggested.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States and our Allies and partners remain open to diplomacy if it is serious.&nbsp; When all is said and done, we’re going to judge Russia by its actions, not its words.</p>



<p>And whatever Russia does next, we&#8217;re ready to respond with unity, clarity, and conviction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ll probably have more to say about this as we &#8212; if it moves on.&nbsp; I’m hoping diplomacy is still available.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you all very much.</p>



<p>2:32 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Foreign Minister Kuleba of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-foreign-minister-kuleba-of-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 20:10:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47643</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba of Ukraine to reaffirm the United States’ commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. President Biden updated Foreign Minister Kuleba on the United States’ response to Russia’s decision to recognize the purported “independence” of the so-called DNR and LNR regions of Ukraine, including&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met with Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba of Ukraine to reaffirm the United States’ commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. President Biden updated Foreign Minister Kuleba on the United States’ response to Russia’s decision to recognize the purported “independence” of the so-called DNR and LNR regions of Ukraine, including the Executive Order issued last night and new sanctions announced today. He also affirmed that the United States would continue providing security assistance and macroeconomic support to Ukraine. President Biden reiterated the readiness of the United States, in close cooperation with our Allies and partners, to respond swiftly and decisively to any further Russian aggression against Ukraine. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Securing a Made in America Supply Chain for Critical&#160;Minerals</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/22/fact-sheet-securing-a-made-in-america-supply-chain-for-critical-minerals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration, Companies Announce Major Investments to Expand Domestic Critical Minerals Supply Chain, Breaking Dependence on China and Boosting Sustainable Practices Critical minerals provide the building blocks for many modern technologies and are essential to our national security and economic prosperity. These minerals—such as rare earth elements, lithium, and cobalt—can be found in products from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration, Companies Announce Major Investments to Expand Domestic Critical Minerals Supply Chain, Breaking Dependence on China and Boosting Sustainable Practices</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">Critical minerals provide the building blocks for many modern technologies and are essential to our national security and economic prosperity. These minerals—such as rare earth elements, lithium, and cobalt—can be found in products from computers to household appliances. They are also key inputs in clean energy technologies like batteries, electric vehicles, wind turbines, and solar panels. As the world transitions to a clean energy economy, global demand for these critical minerals is set to skyrocket by 400-600 percent over the next several decades, and, for minerals such as lithium and graphite used in electric vehicle (EV) batteries, demand will increase by even more—as much as 4,000 percent. The U.S. is increasingly dependent on foreign sources for many of the processed versions of these minerals. Globally, China controls most of the market for processing and refining for cobalt, lithium, rare earths and other critical minerals.</p>



<p>Executive Order 14017 (E.O.)<em>, </em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/24/executive-order-on-americas-supply-chains/"><em>America’s Supply Chains</em></a>, signed one year ago this week, ordered a review of vulnerabilities in our critical mineral and material supply chains within 100 days. In June, the Biden-Harris Administration released a first-of-its-kind <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/100-day-supply-chain-review-report.pdf">supply chain assessment</a> that found our over-reliance on foreign sources and adversarial nations for critical minerals and materials posed national and economic security threats.</p>



<p>In addition to working with partners and allies to diversify sustainable sources, the reports recommended expanding domestic mining, production, processing, and recycling of critical minerals and materials—all with a laser focus on boosting strong labor, environmental and environmental justice, community engagement, and Tribal consultation standards.</p>



<p><strong>Today, President Biden will meet with Administration and state partners, industry executives, community representatives, labor leaders, and California Governor Gavin Newsom to announce major investments in domestic production of key critical minerals and materials, ensuring these resources benefit the community, and creating good-paying, union jobs in sustainable production.</strong></p>



<ul><li>President Biden will announce that the Department of Defense’s Industrial Base Analysis and Sustainment program has awarded MP Materials <strong>$35 million</strong> to separate and process heavy rare earth elements at its facility in Mountain Pass, California, establishing a full end-to-end domestic permanent magnet supply chain. Paired with this catalytic public funding announcement, MP Materials will announce it will invest another <strong>$700 million </strong>and create more than 350 jobs in the magnet supply chain by 2024. Currently, China controls 87 percent of the global permanent magnet market, which are used in EV motors, defense systems, electronics, and wind turbines.<br></li><li>Berkshire Hathaway Energy Renewables (BHE Renewables) will announce that this spring, they will break ground on a new demonstration facility in Imperial County, California, to test the commercial viability of their sustainable lithium extraction process from geothermal brine as part of a <strong>multibillion-dollar</strong> investment in sustainable lithium production over the next five years. If successful, this sets the company a path towards commercial scale production of battery grade lithium hydroxide and lithium carbonate by 2026. Imperial Valley contains some of the largest deposits of lithium in the world. Once at scale, BHE Renewables facilities could produce 90,000 metric tons of lithium per year.<br></li><li>Redwood Materials will discuss a pilot, in partnership with Ford and Volvo, for collection and recycling of end-of-life lithium-ion batteries at its Nevada based facilities to extract lithium, cobalt, nickel, and graphite. This builds upon Redwood’s recent announcements including a joint venture with Ford to build a recycling facility in Tennessee and its intention to begin construction on a new cathode manufacturing facility in Nevada in 2022.<br></li><li>Secretary Granholm will discuss DOE’s first-of-its-kind<strong> $140 million</strong> <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/doe-launches-140-million-program-develop-americas-first-kind-critical-minerals-refinery" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">demonstration project</a> funded by the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law (BIL) to recover rare earth elements and critical minerals from coal ash and other mine waste, reducing the need for new mining. This project will deliver on the work of the Interagency Working Group on Coal and Power Plant Communities and Economic Revitalization by creating good-paying manufacturing jobs in legacy coal communities.<br></li><li>She will also discuss <strong>$3 billion</strong> in <a href="https://www.energy.gov/articles/biden-administration-doe-invest-3-billion-strengthen-us-supply-chain-advanced-batteries">BIL funding</a> to invest in refining battery materials such as lithium, cobalt, nickel, and graphite, and battery recycling facilities, creating good-paying clean energy manufacturing jobs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>These are only the latest in announcements by major companies committing to domestic sourcing of critical minerals and materials:</strong></p>



<ul><li>MP Materials <a href="https://mpmaterials.com/articles/mp-materials-to-build-us-magnet-factory-enters-long-term-supply-agreement-with-general-motors/">recently announced</a> construction of a rare earth metal, alloy and magnet manufacturing facility in Texas and a long-term supply agreement with General Motors to power the motors in more than a dozen of GM’s EV models. Production will begin next year, with capacity to produce enough magnets to power 500,000 EV motors annually.<br></li><li>In addition to BHE Renewables, Controlled Thermal Resources (CTR) and EnergySource Minerals have established operations in Imperial County to extract lithium from geothermal brine. GM will source lithium for EV batteries from CTR. The companies are also working with the state-authorized Lithium Valley Commission to develop a royalty structure that would invest profits from their operations in infrastructure, health, and educational investments for the residents of the surrounding region.<br></li><li>Tesla intends to source high-grade nickel for EV batteries from Talon Metals’ Tamarack nickel project under development in Minnesota. Talon Metals and the United Steelworkers (USW) have established a <a href="https://talonmetals.com/talon-metals-and-steelworkers-union-partner-to-advance-the-tamarack-nickel-project-for-us-ev-battery-supply-chain/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">workforce development partnership</a> for the project to train workers on next-generation technologies in the local community and from mining regions in the U.S. facing declining demand. As part of this partnership, Talon has agreed to remain neutral in any union organizing efforts by USW.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ahead of the one-year anniversary of E.O. 14017 this Thursday, the Administration has taken action across the Federal government to secure reliable and sustainable supplies of critical minerals and materials, while also upholding the Administration’s labor, environmental and environmental justice, and equity priorities:</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Updating outdated mining laws and regulations.</strong> This year, the Mining Law of 1872 turns 150. This law still governs mining of most critical minerals on federal public lands. Today, the Department of Interior (DOI) <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-launches-interagency-working-group-mining-reform">announced</a> it has established an Interagency Working Group (IWG) that will lead an Administration effort on legislative and regulatory reform of mine permitting and oversight. The IWG released a list of Biden-Harris Administration <a href="https://www.doi.gov/sites/doi.gov/files/biden-harris-administration-fundamental-principles-for-domestic-mining-reform.pdf">fundamental principles for mining reform</a> to promote responsible mining under strong social, environmental, and labor standards that avoids the historic injustice that too many mining operations have left behind. The IWG will deliver recommendations to Congress by November. They will also host extensive public input and comment sessions to ensure an inclusive process, and will work with the relevant agencies to initiate updates to mining regulations by the end of the calendar year.<br></li><li><strong>Updating and prioritizing the Federal list of critical minerals. </strong>Today, pursuant to the Energy Act of 2020, DOI will update its Federal list of critical minerals, listing minerals essential to economic or national security and vulnerable to disruption. To focus the work of Federal agencies on sourcing critical minerals, the Administration will direct agencies to prioritize the production and processing of minerals necessary to produce key products like batteries, semiconductors, and permanent magnets, consistent with our strong environmental, social and labor principles.<br></li><li><strong>Strengthening critical mineral stockpiling. </strong>DOE, DOD, and the Department of State signed a memorandum of agreement (MOA) to better coordinate stockpiling activities to support the U.S. transition to clean energy and national security needs. In October, President Biden streamlined the National Defense Stockpile by signing <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/10/31/executive-order-on-the-designation-to-exercise-authority-over-the-national-defense-stockpile/#:~:text=This%20order%20confers%20authority%20related,stockpiling%20for%20national%20defense%20purposes." target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">E.O. 14051</a> to delegate authority release of strategic and critical materials to the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on Russia and&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/21/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-russia-and-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 01:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47605</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  5:24 P.M. EST MODERATOR:&#160; Good evening, everyone.&#160; And thanks for joining.&#160; Tonight’s call is going to be on background, attributed to a “senior administration official,” and contents will be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&#160; Our speaker tonight is [senior administration official].&#160; [Senior administration official], over to you. SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&#160; Great,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Via Teleconference</em><strong> </strong></p>



<p>5:24 P.M. EST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; And thanks for joining.&nbsp; Tonight’s call is going to be on background, attributed to a “senior administration official,” and contents will be embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&nbsp; Our speaker tonight is [senior administration official].&nbsp; [Senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thanks.&nbsp; And thanks, everybody.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I want to start out by discussing Russia’s recognition of the so-called DNR and LNR regions of Ukraine today.&nbsp; We have long anticipated that Russia might take this action, and as you saw, we were ready to respond immediately.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden has issued, today, an executive order that will prohibit new investment, trade, and financing by U.S. persons to, from, or in the so-called DNR and LNR regions.&nbsp; This EO will also provide authority to impose sanctions on any person determined to operate in those areas of Ukraine.</p>



<p>We will take further measures tomorrow to hold Russia accountable for this clear violation of international law and Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, as well as of Russia’s own international commitments.</p>



<p>To be clear: These measures respond to Russia’s recognition gambit; they are not the swift and severe economic measures we have been preparing in coordination with Allies and partners should Russia further invade Ukraine.&nbsp; We are pleased with the historic coordination we have had with our Allies and partners on developing these measures and will continue to stay closely coordinated in the days ahead.</p>



<p>But I also want to address the speech President Putin made today, because we believe it made clear his true designs.&nbsp; This wasn’t a speech just about Russia’s security, it was an attack on the very idea of a sovereign and independent Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He made clear that he views Ukraine historically as part of Russia, and he made a number of false claims about Ukraine’s intentions that seemed designed to excuse possible military action.&nbsp; This was a speech to the Russian people to justify a war.&nbsp; In fact, he once again explicitly threatened one.</p>



<p>Unfortunately, the sequence of events that Secretary Blinken laid out at the U.N. Security Council appears to be proceeding exactly as we predicted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russia has increased the number of false-flag events and provocations over the past few days.&nbsp; Today, it called a dramatic Security Council meeting.&nbsp; That was followed by the recognition of sovereign Ukrainian territory as independent republics, with whom Russia immediately signed so-called friendship and mutual aid agreements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>No one should mistake these theatrics as legitimate statecraft.&nbsp; This is Potemkin politics &#8212; President Putin accelerating the very conflict he has created.</p>



<p>Today’s speech from President Putin follows several days of heightened tensions and escalations by Russia in and around Ukraine.&nbsp; Russian troops have continued to move closer to the border in what looks like plans for an invasion at any moment, most likely in response to attacks Russia falsely claims are occurring in the Donbas.</p>



<p>Indeed, just in the last hour, we’ve seen Russia order troops to deploy into the DPR and LPR for so-called peacekeeping functions.&nbsp; We have seen a number of actions that are clear Russian-backed pretexts for further invasion, like explosions at eastern &#8212; at eastern Ukraine that just happen to have Russian state media covering them in the middle of the night, or videos of alleged emergency evacuation calls or so-called saboteurs whose metadata show clearly that they were created days before their release.&nbsp; These attempts at disinformation aren’t fooling anyone.</p>



<p>But the human costs of these actions are already accruing.&nbsp; Russian-backed forces are forcing civilians in eastern Ukraine to leave their homes and conscripting men and boys in those regions against their will.&nbsp; The human costs of a further Russian invasion and occupation will be devastating.</p>



<p>Today after President Putin’s speech, President Biden both spoke with President Zelenskyy and held a joint call with President Macron and Chancellor Scholz.&nbsp; In all these calls, the President strongly condemned President Putin’s decision to recognize the so-called Donetsk and Luhansk People’s Republics. &nbsp;We will continue to consult with our Allies and partners about both diplomatic solutions and the consequences we will impose on Russia should it further invade Ukraine.</p>



<p>Russia continues to escalate this crisis that it created in the first place.&nbsp; We’ll continue to pursue diplomacy until the tanks roll, but we are under no illusions about what is likely to come next.&nbsp; And we are prepared to respond decisively when it does.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And with that, happy to take any questions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; I have a question that I’ve been asked on television which is relevant, which is: If the so-call- &#8212; if the letter to the U.N. that Ambassador Crocker wrote is correct and based on the intelligence is correct, and if there are lists of people in these categories that might be arrested, even killed, you know, sent to prisons or camps &#8212; if we see this happening, if we see Americans at risk as well, will we stand on our &#8212; what the President said and has repeatedly said and (inaudible) have said about not sending American troops into Ukraine on rescue missions, about standing on this not being an Article 5/NATO situation.&nbsp; How is that sustainable for President Biden if these dire consequences are, you know, visible to the world?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Andrea.&nbsp; So if what was described in our letter transpires, those would be horrific crimes &#8212; war crimes, even.&nbsp; We have been warning individuals and groups who we think could be targeted based on our understanding and our knowledge of Russian plans to try to enable them to protect themselves or move to places where they might be safer.&nbsp; But I have nothing to amend in what the President has already said, which is that he has no intention of sending American forces to fight inside Ukraine.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official].&nbsp; You know, in the last hour, obviously, you noted that the Russian government&#8217;s decree, Putin decree, sending the troops in, there&#8217;s lots of suggestions that there might be, you know, so-called boots on the ground for Russia in parts of Ukraine, that they may cross that border tonight, perhaps tomorrow.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You know, is this not the time?&nbsp; Or are you &#8212; are you not under pressure at this point to go ahead and impose the actual sanctions &#8212; the full-blown package of sanctions?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, if not now, I mean, is there a &#8212; you know, are you literally going to wait until the first, you know, truck rolls across a particular line?&nbsp; Or how do you guys, you know &#8212; I mean, could that be three in the morning?&nbsp; Or what &#8212; how will you guys roll that out?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, thanks for the question, Mike.&nbsp; Look, as has been the case throughout this crisis, we are going to assess what Russia does and not focus on what Russia says.&nbsp; The actions that we take are very much focused on response to Russian actions, of which there have been some taken up till now and we have calibrated our responses accordingly.</p>



<p>But I want to take a step back here and point out something that may be lost on people who have not been paying attention to this conflict throughout most of the last eight years, which is that Russia has occupied these regions since 2014.&nbsp; It has been Russia&#8217;s position that there are not Russian forces present in this part of the Donbas.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The reality, as we pointed out on a number of occasions over these past years, has been quite different.&nbsp; There have been Russian forces present in these areas throughout.&nbsp; And so we&#8217;re going to be looking very closely at what they do over the coming hours and days, and our response will be measured according, again, to their &#8212; to their actions.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve taken a number of actions today, including the President&#8217;s executive order.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve indicated that we have further actions to take tomorrow.&nbsp; Beyond that, I&#8217;m not going to get into any more details.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Interfax says that armored columns already are entering Donbas, and there’s reports on the ground of that as well just on social media.&nbsp; Has the U.S. verified that there are additional troops &#8212; have moved into Donbas?&nbsp; Does it believe that forces are rolling out now?&nbsp; And will the new &#8212; will the U.S. not react if this is limited to Donbas?&nbsp; I mean, these would be armed forces entering this area.&nbsp; Is that okay and, you know, something else has to happen to trigger the sanctions package?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Ellen.&nbsp; So I have no other information to provide on the troop movements that you described.&nbsp; As I said, we&#8217;ll be watching very closely the actual actions that Russia takes, including the type of action that you just mentioned and that is apparently in these reports.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In terms of your question of whether we will not react if Russia take steps in the Donbas, that&#8217;s sort of the opposite of what I said; I said we would react based on actions that Russia takes.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already said, including in our statement that we put out today in response to the action that President Putin took, that we would have additional steps to roll out tomorrow.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of those announcements, but we will be taking additional action.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, certainly, to your question about whether it is okay, the answer is absolutely not.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, [senior administration official].&nbsp; I have a follow-up to the series of questions that are being asked about this.&nbsp; Well, first of all, to &#8212; just to make sure I understand what &#8212; the steps, the measures you&#8217;ve imposed today are basically a ban on investment and trade with the two regions &#8212; right? &#8212; Donetsk and Luhansk, and then the authority to impose economic sanctions on people in that &#8212; in those two regions, correct?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, that&#8217;s correct.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; But you&#8217;re saying you will &#8212; you will impose additional steps tomorrow?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s also correct.&nbsp; (Inaudible) and our statement said &#8212; that we’ve already published, under Jen Psaki’s name, that we will take additional steps as soon as tomorrow and going forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And those will be sanctions &#8212; economic sanctions?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think the statement specifies that, but there will be, I strongly suspect, sanctions activity related to this.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Strongly suspect sanctions activity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It looks like &#8212; very much like that Russian troops are moving, if not already, in Donbas, according to Interfax, armored columns.&nbsp; Would Russian troops moving into Donbas consist of a &#8212; of an invasion &#8212; in your words, in your view &#8212; such that it would trigger the sanctions?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Again, I think you’re just citing the same report that the previous question asked about.&nbsp;&nbsp; And I said I don’t have anything to, sort of, verify or confirm.&nbsp; But I did say that we are going to be carefully observing and assessing Russian actions and responding accordingly.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I do also want to remind you and everyone on the call that the Russian troops moving into Donbas would not itself be a new step.&nbsp; Russia has had forces in the Donbas region for the past eight years.&nbsp; Their narrative has been that they do not; our, you know, certain knowledge has been that they have.&nbsp; And they are now &#8212; they&#8217;re apparently now making a decision to do this in a more overt and open way.&nbsp; But this has been the state of affairs in that region and a big part of why it has been so unstable since 2014.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; It’s actually Cecilia Vega with ABC.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; [Senior administration official], can you say anything more about the proposed Biden-Putin summit in the wake of what&#8217;s happening right now and/or today?&nbsp; Does this &#8212; does this make it not happen?&nbsp; Or does it &#8212; what&#8217;s the effect on that?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve said a few things about this all along that I think remain true.&nbsp; One is that we were open to further engagements between the two leaders if we thought it made sense and could have a beneficial impact on the crisis, but there were a number of predicates to a meeting like that.&nbsp; One being &#8212; one critical one being that Russia does not take further military action inside Ukraine.&nbsp; And so, we are going to &#8212; again, as I said in response to previous questions &#8212; have to continue to assess what Russia is doing.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our strong sense based on everything that we are seeing on the ground in the areas around the Ukraine &#8212; to the north, to the east, to the south &#8212; is that Russia is continuing to prepare for military action that could take place in the coming hours or days.&nbsp; And so, certainly can&#8217;t commit to a meeting that has as a predicate that Russia won&#8217;t take military action when it looks as imminently like they will.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I want to double check on something.&nbsp; So, were you saying because Russian troops have been in the Donbas for eight years that if Russian troops were to enter there anew, that would not necessarily trigger sanctions or you would not consider it a renewed invasion?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then two is: There&#8217;s now calls for having a U.N. Security Council meeting.&nbsp; But of course, you&#8217;re well aware that Russia has a veto, so what would the utility of that meeting actually be?&nbsp; Thanks.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I was not saying that, Alex, in response to your first question.&nbsp; What I was saying &#8212; and I&#8217;ll &#8212; I said it a couple times, but I&#8217;ll say it again &#8212; is that we will observe and assess what actions Russia actually takes and respond accordingly.&nbsp; We have already said we&#8217;re going to take additional sanctions actions tomorrow.&nbsp; And if Russia takes further actions, I suspect there will be further responses to those actions.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how we&#8217;ve handled this up until now, and that is how we will continue to handle things going forward.&nbsp; We have a number of options at our disposal.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the U.N. Security Council session of &#8212; you know, I would say a few things.&nbsp; Russia cannot necessarily veto the holding of a meeting; they can veto a Security Council resolution.&nbsp; We see value in the U.N. Security Council, which is the sort of foremost international body charged with maintaining peace and stability in the world confronting what is, right now, the most significant challenge to peace and stability anywhere, which is what Russia is doing on the border of Ukraine and making Russia answer for the actions they took today and that it looks very likely to take additionally in the hours and days ahead.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We&#8217;ve done that a number of times during the course of this crisis.&nbsp; And given the steps that took place today, we think it would be appropriate for that to happen again.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thanks for doing this call.&nbsp; Sorry to beat a dead horse here, but I just want to go back to this question over what constitutes a new invasion, because you said at one point that Russian troops moving into the Donbas would not be a new step.&nbsp; So would Russian troops have to move past the Donbas, or what&#8217;s the exact line that they would have to cross in eastern Ukraine to constitute a new invasion from that angle that you guys would consider a new invasion?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then my second question is: Will Secretary Blinken still be meeting with Foreign Minister Lavrov on Thursday as of now?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, again, Kylie, I&#8217;ll repeat what I&#8217;ve said up until now, which is: We are going to observe and assess what Russia does in the hours ahead and overnight, that we are going to respond to any actions that Russia takes in a way that we believe is appropriate to the action.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve already said that there will be additional steps taken tomorrow &#8212; again, I said earlier on this call will likely to be sanction steps.&nbsp; And if Russia takes further actions, I suspect we would take further actions in response to that.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so, I think that&#8217;s basically how we see it.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to leave it there.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I also reminded people, separate from that consideration, that there have been Russian troops in the Donbas for eight years now and that, you know, Russia has denied this.&nbsp; Now Russia looks like its going to be operating openly in that region, and our &#8212; and we are going to be responding accordingly.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll have more steps to announce tomorrow.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Remind me of your second question though, Kylie?&nbsp; Sorry.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, just the Secretary Blinken &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Secretary Blinken/Lavrov.&nbsp; So I would refer you to the State Department on that question.&nbsp; I think they&#8217;re going to have more say about that than I will on this call.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; That&#8217;s all the questions that we have time for.&nbsp; With that, the embargo is lifted.&nbsp; And friendly reminder that we are on background, attributed to the “senior administration official.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.<br><br>5:43 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Executive Order to Impose Costs for President Putin’s Action to Recognize So-Called Donetsk and Luhansk People’s&#160;Republics</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/21/fact-sheet-executive-order-to-impose-costs-for-president-putins-action-to-recognize-so-called-donetsk-and-luhansk-peoples-republics/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 23:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47599</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to respond to President Putin’s action to purportedly recognize the so-called Donetsk and Luhansk People’s Republics (DNR and LNR) as “independent” states. President Putin’s action contradicts Russia’s commitments under the Minsk agreements, refutes Russia’s claimed commitment to diplomacy, and undermines Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. This E.O.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden signed an Executive Order (E.O.) to respond to President Putin’s action to purportedly recognize the so-called Donetsk and Luhansk People’s Republics (DNR and LNR) as “independent” states. President Putin’s action contradicts Russia’s commitments under the Minsk agreements, refutes Russia’s claimed commitment to diplomacy, and undermines Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity.</p>



<p>This E.O. is distinct from the swift and severe economic measures we are prepared to issue with Allies and partners in response to a further Russian invasion of Ukraine. We are continuing to closely consult with Ukraine and with Allies and partners on next steps and urge Russia to immediately deescalate.</p>



<p><strong>Today’s E.O. prohibits:</strong></p>



<ul><li>New investment in the so-called DNR or LNR regions of Ukraine by a United States person, wherever located;</li><li>The importation into the United States, directly or indirectly, of any goods, services, or technology from the so-called DNR or LNR regions of Ukraine;</li><li>The exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United States person, wherever located, of any goods, services, or technology to the so-called DNR or LNR regions of Ukraine;</li><li>And any approval, financing, facilitation, or guarantee by a United States person, wherever located, of a transaction by a foreign person where the transaction by that foreign person would be covered by these prohibitions if performed by a United States person or within the United States.</li></ul>



<p><strong>The E.O. also provides authority to impose sanctions on persons determined:</strong></p>



<ul><li>To operate or have operated since the date of the order in the so-called DNR or LNR regions of Ukraine;</li><li>To be or have been since the date of the order a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of an entity operating in the so-called DNR or LNR regions of Ukraine;</li><li>To be owned or controlled by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order;</li><li>Or to have materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, any person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this order.</li></ul>



<p><strong>The Department of the Treasury is issuing six General Licenses to ensure that humanitarian and other related activity can continue in these regions:</strong></p>



<ul><li>The purpose of this E.O. is to deny Russia the chance to profit from its blatant violations of international law. These actions are not directed at the people of Ukraine or the Ukrainian government.</li><li>Treasury’s General Licenses are designed to support the innocent people who live in the so-called DNR and LNR regions who did not have a choice in Russia’s destabilizing and illegitimate actions today.</li><li>The licenses allow a short-term wind down of activities, as well as for the export to the regions of food, medicine and medical devices, and ensure personal remittances can continue to flow.</li><li>The licenses also allow telecommunications and internet services to remain operational, and mail services to continue.</li><li>The licenses allow international organizations to be able to provide aid to the people in these two regions.</li></ul>



<p>The United States will not hesitate to use its authorities to target those supporting efforts to undermine Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity. This authority provides the United States with the flexibility to impose similar restrictions on any other regions of Ukraine as appropriate.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
