<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 04:56:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the Democratic National Committee’s Winter&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/10/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-democratic-national-committees-winter-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 04:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48896</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Washington HiltonWashington, D.C. 7:27 P.M. EST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, hello, hello.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Great to see you all. AUDIENCE:&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe!&#160; Joe! THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Please, sit down.&#160; Thank you so much. Jaime just gave my speech, so thank you.&#160; (Laughter.) Thank you, Jaime, for that introduction and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Washington Hilton<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>7:27 P.M. EST</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, hello, hello.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Great to see you all.<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!&nbsp; Joe!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Please, sit down.&nbsp; Thank you so much.<br><br>Jaime just gave my speech, so thank you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Thank you, Jaime, for that introduction and for all you’ve done for the party.&nbsp; And thank all of the leaders of the DNC and the staff.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, to all of you today, there are so, so many friends here tonight.&nbsp; And if I mentioned every one by name, we’d be here all night.&nbsp; But let me start by saying thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>And excuse me, as we used to say in the Senate, a point of personal privilege, I want to say thank you to the Delaware delegation.&nbsp; They brung me to the &#8212; (applause) &#8212; stand up.&nbsp; The Delaware folks, stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Betsy Maron, Chair of the Party.&nbsp; Coby Owens, Vice Chair.&nbsp; Sean Finnigan, staff for the House of Representatives.&nbsp; And my good friend to Beau, Sarah McBride, who used to work for Beau.&nbsp; And Molly Magarik as well.&nbsp; And a great friend &#8212; Brian McGlinchey, who’s basically family.&nbsp; And Bonnie Wu, a Director of Tom Carper’s office; most importantly, she helped my son Beau get elected to Attorney General, so she has a place in the heart of every Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, coming out of the State of the Union, we are in the strongest position we’ve been in in months.&nbsp; We have a record &#8212; a record to be proud of; an agenda that addresses the biggest concerns here in America, in people’s lives; the message that resonates.</p>



<p>And now &#8212; now what we have to do is we have to sell it with confidence, clarity, conviction, and repetition.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Folks, on Ukraine, Putin was counting on a divided NATO, a divided West, and, quite frankly, a divided America.&nbsp; But he got none of that.</p>



<p>In fact, he’s now facing a more united, energized, resolute NATO and the West than he ever, ever imagined.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And he’s failed to divide Democrats and Republicans.</p>



<p>But we need to be honest with the American people: The battle for freedom has its costs here at home, as well.&nbsp; People already &#8212; already feeling Putin’s price hikes at the pump.</p>



<p>I think the American people know how important this fight is.&nbsp; I think they know that as painful as the price is today, the costs are going to be higher if we do not act now to deal with this tyrant.</p>



<p>So let me be clear on the facts: We are increasing oil production with a record productivity.&nbsp; By the end of the year, we will have produced more oil than any time in the last number of years.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Look, I just want to run &#8212; the Republicans are playing a game here.&nbsp; They’re talking about the Democrats having raised prices; they all voted for the same thing.<br><br>The CEOs of major oil companies have said they’ll increase investment and production.&nbsp; They have the capacity to do it.&nbsp; They have over 4,000 opportunities.&nbsp; They say there’s nothing the U.S. government needs to do to incentivize them.</p>



<p>My message is: It’s time &#8212; in this time of war, it’s not a time of profit.&nbsp; It’s time for reinvesting in America.&nbsp; And they hear it.</p>



<p>You know, there’s a &#8212; there’s an impediment to production in the United States, and it’s called “the bankers on Wall Street.”&nbsp; And this crisis is another indication of why we need to get off dependency on fossil fuels.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>That is not &#8212; (applause) &#8212; this is not a solution to today’s crisis; it’s about the future.&nbsp; That’s why we need to build a better America.</p>



<p>Now, let’s talk about our record.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; People were hurting.&nbsp; We had to act, and we did.&nbsp; We did it as Democrats, without a single, solitary Republican vote.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And the one-year anniversary of the passage of that act is tomorrow.</p>



<p>We should be proud of it.&nbsp; We did so much people don’t even know we did it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Without exaggeration, few pieces of legislation in our history have done more to lift the country out of crisis.</p>



<p>When I took office, only 2 million Americans had been fully vaccinated.&nbsp; Today, we’ve vaccinated the nation &#8212; more than 215 million people fully vaccinated.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And all remember &#8212; you all remember the lines of cars that lined up for miles &#8212; miles, waiting for someone to put a box of food in their trunk.&nbsp; Because of the law &#8212; this law we passed, 41 million Americans put food on the table today.</p>



<p>Because of this law, we helped keep a roof over the heads of 4 million people who were being evicted.</p>



<p>We gave families what my father called “a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; And it worked.</p>



<p>Twenty million people were out of work just months before I took office.&nbsp; Job growth was anemic, 60,000 jobs a month leading up to January ’21 &#8212; 2021.&nbsp; But because we took action, we created 6.5 million jobs just last year &#8212; (applause) &#8212; more jobs than ever created in one year in the United States of America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; More jobs.&nbsp; And people got pay increases.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And it hasn’t stopped.&nbsp; We’re now well over 7 million new jobs &#8212; 678,000 jobs last month alone.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Unemployment &#8212; down to 3.8 percent.&nbsp; And the economy grew last year at 5.7 percent &#8212; the best economic growth in four decades.</p>



<p>Leading financial firm of Moody’s on Wall Street estimates that our record plan created four million more jobs, and unemployment is 2 percent lower because of what we did.<br><br>And here’s one thing that I’m proudest of: Our recovery has lifted everyone.&nbsp; Black unemployment at an all-time low; Hispanic unemployment, youth unemployment, long-term unemployment &#8212; all have farrel [sic] &#8212; fallen by historic amounts.&nbsp; We have more to do, but they’ve fallen by historic amounts.</p>



<p>Poverty for all children &#8212; including Black children, Hispanic children &#8212; are at the lowest levels ever recorded in our first year &#8212; ever recorded.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And that just didn’t happen; it was a direct result of how we designed the American Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>It was very different from how previous administrations designed their $2 trillion tax cut.&nbsp; Pretty much all of that $2 trillion went to the top 1 percent.&nbsp; And we took &#8212; we took the exact opposite approach with the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;<br><br>We decided we were going to build America from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; Because when the middle does well, everybody does well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Everybody does well.&nbsp; And our plan didn’t leave a single working person behind &#8212; no one behind.</p>



<p>Let’s be clear: When America’s recovery was flat on its back and the economy was flat on its back, it was the Democrats &#8212; without a single Republican vote &#8212; that brought us back.</p>



<p>Let’s talk about infrastructure.&nbsp; We passed the biggest investment in physical infrastructure in the history of the United States of America.</p>



<p>Now, in this case, we got some Republican help.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We got 12 Republicans in the House &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; and a couple handfuls in the Senate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I notice, every new bridge or highway &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; you have a Republicans who voted against the infra- &#8212; standing there, taking credit.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; As my mother would say, “God love them.”&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)</p>



<p>We got it done though.&nbsp; And we did get some Republican help, and I’m thankful for it.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, the fact is that this &#8212; this bill &#8212; this infrastructure bill is going to transform America.&nbsp; It’s not hyperbole.<br><br>We used to have the best infrastructure in the world.&nbsp; Now we rank number eightin the world.&nbsp; China is number two in the world.&nbsp; We’re already starting to do &#8212; make great progress.<br><br>Just this year, we’ve announced 4,000 projects across the country, with 1,500 bridges in disrepair.&nbsp; I was just talking to a good friend &#8212; county executive out in Pittsburg.&nbsp; When I went out there to talk to the folks out there, it was the day that bridge collapsed &#8212; just flat collapsed.&nbsp; Thank God it was two hours earlier, because there would have been school buses on that.&nbsp; No one was killed, but it was a drop of well over 100 feet.&nbsp; We have hundreds of those bridges all across America that are ready to collapse.<br><br>Look, we need to be clear with folks about why this is happening.</p>



<p>This bill is going to create millions of jobs &#8212; not &#8212; now, that&#8217;s not hyperbole; that&#8217;s literal &#8212; rebuilding America&#8217;s roads, bridges, highways, ports, airports.&nbsp;<br><br>It&#8217;s going to do something else.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to start to get rid of the poisonous lead pipes that our kids and our families have been drinking from their lead pipes coming through the water coming through their &#8212; it &#8212; it affects over 10 million homes and 450,000 schools.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s overwhelming evidence of the impact of lead on the brain of a developing child.<br><br>We&#8217;re going to invest $65 billion to deliver affordable high-speed Internet everywhere in America &#8212; urban, suburban, and rural and Tribal communities.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>See that little tyke up there clapping?&nbsp; God love her.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I want to meet &#8212; is it a boy or girl?&nbsp; I can&#8217;t see from here.<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Aww.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I want to see you &#8212; I want to see you before I leave, okay?&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Because, folks, you know, it&#8217;s not hyperbole; that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re doing this, folks.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, we can&#8217;t be a country where a mother has to take her child to the McDonald&#8217;s parking lot to get access to the Internet to be able to do their homework.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; This is the United States of America for God&#8217;s sake.<br><br>This law is going to put an end to that and so much more.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to bring about &#8212; we&#8217;re going to bring back something we thought &#8212; many people thought we had lost: the ability to manufacture product stamped “Made in America.”&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Look, just a few years ago &#8212; just a few years ago, the companies building in America, factories in America would have built them overseas.&nbsp; Now we&#8217;re buying them here in America.<br><br>That&#8217;s not only great for manufacturing, it&#8217;s great for cost.&nbsp; One third of all the inflation in America last year was a consequence of automobiles &#8212; not having access to computer chips to be able to build their automobiles.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to make them again in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Now, here&#8217;s more &#8212; one way to help families reduce their monthly costs as well, by the way.&nbsp; At a time when food and gas prices are rising, if you can lower other major costs for families, you cannot affect their &#8212; you can help their standard of living.<br><br>Let&#8217;s get Medicare the power to negotiate lower prescription drugs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It costs $10 for a pharmaceutical company to make insulin for those suffering from a serious, serious problem if they don&#8217;t get the insulin &#8212; Type 1 diabetes.<br><br>Look, folks &#8212; and wh- &#8212; you know what we’re going to do?&nbsp; You know how much people pay now?&nbsp; Some of you do know because you struggle with it.&nbsp; They pay an average of $647 a month, as high as $1,000 a month.<br><br>Folks, it cost them 10 bucks to make it.&nbsp; Talk about stripping &#8212; not only worrying about the health of your child &#8212; 200,000 of them &#8212; but what else is happening?&nbsp; You strip a mother or father of their dignity, their sense of responsibility if they can&#8217;t do it.&nbsp; Imagine &#8212; imagine if you have a child, you don&#8217;t have the insurance, you don&#8217;t have the cash.&nbsp; What in God&#8217;s name do you do?<br><br>So we&#8217;re going to cap the cost of insulin at $35.&nbsp; Period.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And by the way, they&#8217;ll still make a healthy profit.</p>



<p>We want to further help working-class and middle-class families that are dealing with cost of gas and food that’s gone up.<br><br>Well, let&#8217;s cap the cost of childcare at 7 percent of a family&#8217;s income.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We can afford to do this.<br><br>Folks, in major cities, it’s $14,000 a year per child.&nbsp; As the Delawareans can tell you, I got credit for 36 years for commuting every single solitary day from Washington to Wilmington, Delaware &#8212; over a 300-mile round trip.<br><br>But guess what, folks?&nbsp; I did it because when my wife and daughter were killed, I had two beautiful, young boys.&nbsp; I could not afford childcare.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Thank God I had a mom, a sister, and a brother who busted their neck to help me.&nbsp; How do families do it?&nbsp;<br><br>And by the way, 2 million women out of work &#8212; they’ll be able to go back to work.&nbsp; They’ll be able to go back to work.<br><br>And folks, look: For families, it&#8217;s going to cut the cost of childcare in half.&nbsp; As I said, you know, you&#8217;re not going to pay more than one &#8212; for one child, paying $14,000 a year some places.&nbsp; Many &#8212; most places $7,000.<br><br>Look, we can lower the cost of energy with tax credits.&nbsp; An average of 500 bucks a year by giving tax credits to families to weatherize their homes so they use less energy.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Folks, this is not rocket science.&nbsp; Even some of the CEOs of the biggest utility companies came to see me &#8212; nine of them &#8212; saying that if we continue the prospect that we br- &#8212; get tax credits, we promise you we will lower the cost of energy.</p>



<p>These are public utilities.  They&#8217;re going to pay for it by raising ta- &#8212; and by the way, all these programs and others I&#8217;m not going to mention in the interest of time, they&#8217;re going to be able to be done without raising the taxes one single penny on anyone making less than $400,000 a year.  Not a penny.  (Applause.)  Because we’re going to raise taxes on the wealthiest among us and corporations.<br><br>Look, I come from the state of Delaware.  More corporations are incorporated there than all the rest of the United States of America combined.  And I got elected seven times as senator.<br><br>I&#8217;m not anti-corporation or anti-people being able to go make a lot of money.  But everybody &#8212; everybody &#8212; everybody should pay a fair share.  Everybody.  (Applause.)  And our agenda is not only supported by the public, it’s enthusiastically supported.<br><br>Seventeen Nobel laureates in economics wrote me a letter unsolicited, saying that if we pass what I&#8217;m talking about, it would actually reduce inflationary pres- &#8212; reduce inflationary pressures.<br><br>I want to make two things clear.  Again, first, no one making less than $400,000 will pay a single, solitary additional penny in taxes.  And those earning less than that, as I said, are going to find themselves in good shape.<br><br>But I&#8217;m a capitalist; I&#8217;m not looking to punish anybody.  But it&#8217;s time the corporations and the very wealthy just begin to pay just their fair share.  (Applause.)<br><br>Last year &#8212; last year, 55 corporations in the Fortune 500 earned $40 billion and didn&#8217;t pay a single penny in income tax. <br><br>AUDIENCE:  Booo.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Not &#8212; not a penny.  It&#8217;s not only wrong, it&#8217;s not fair.  That&#8217;s why I proposed a 15 percent minimum tax rate for corporations.  (Applause.)  We&#8217;re going to get it done.<br><br>And as President of the United States, when I showed up at the so-called G7 where all the major in- &#8212; the major countries in the world are part of, I started to push for a minimum tax &#8212; global minimum tax rate on companies that can&#8217;t get out of &#8212; they get out of paying their taxes at home by going to jurisdictions that require very low taxes for profit made by corporations in their country.<br><br>So, what happens?  Not only do we lose jobs and they go overseas, they pay no tax at home, even though they&#8217;re here in in De- &#8212; in the state of Delaware, the state of Maryland, the state of California.  And they’re just shipping these jobs overseas.<br><br>Well, guess what?  We agreed &#8212; 170-some countries agreed that we should all pay a min- &#8212; they should all pay a minimum tax of 15 percent.  And guess what?  That&#8217;s going to bring in billions of dollars in taxation here at home again.  That&#8217;s why I proposed closing the loophole for the very wealthy who pay lower tax rates than a teacher or firefighter.<br><br>Look, the bottom line: This whole plan is paid for. <br><br>Secondly, I want to point out, for those facts [sic] who attack us &#8212; those folks who attack us for being fiscally irresponsible, let them know this: Last year, I cut the budget $360 billion &#8212; (applause) &#8212; while we did these other things &#8212; $360 billion.<br><br>And know I&#8217;m the only President who is on track to cut the deficit by more than $1 trillion in one year &#8212; $1 trillion.  (Applause.)<br><br>And folks, our agenda includes a bipartisan Unity Agenda as well for &#8212; around four big items:<br><br>One, opioid addiction &#8212; taking the lives of literally thousands of Americans.  We&#8217;re doing very little about it, especially our children and fentanyl being laced with them.<br><br>The second thing we can all agree on is dealing with mental health, especially for our kids.  There&#8217;s a serious, serious problem in America today.  (Applause.)<br><br>And the third thing on a Unity Agenda we can all do with &#8212; veterans, especially those who were exposed to toxic burn pits, and not getting the needs they &#8212; met.  (Applause.)<br><br>And fourthly, the only truly bipartisan thing I know that I&#8217;ve been involved in of late is ending cancer as we know it.  (Applause.)  We can do this.  We have the possibility of doing this. <br><br>But, folks, these are all within our reach.  Let &#8212; let me finish with this.  Unfortunately, I could go on for a long time &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; because I feel so good about what we&#8217;re doing.  (Applause.)<br><br>Look, I believe &#8212; I believe we have a record to be incredibly proud of; an agenda the public strongly supports if you look at the polling data; a message that resonates: Build a Better America.<br><br>Now we&#8217;ve got to do the work.  And I&#8217;ve seen what you can do.  I saw it in 2020.  Nothing was going to stop you then.  We can&#8217;t let anything stop us now.<br><br>We need to bring some real determination, the same work ethic, the same enthusiasm.  And if we do that, we&#8217;re going to keep the House and keep the Senate and add seats.  (Applause.)  And by the way, if we don&#8217;t do that &#8212; if we don&#8217;t do that, it&#8217;s going to be a sad, sad two years.<br><br>Think about Republicans if they had control of the Congress these last two years.<br><br>AUDIENCE:  Booo.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Ask your Republican friends &#8212; I mean this sincerely &#8212; name me something the National Republican Party is for.  (Applause.)<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:  Yes.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Not a joke.  What are they for?<br><br>Now, two people in the party laid out what they think it&#8217;s for.  They think we should raise the cost of Medicare, they think we should cut &#8212; but what are they for?<br><br>Folks, we’ll &#8212; we’ll strengthen our position with governorships, and up and down the ticket.  And more importantly, we&#8217;re going to change this country.<br><br>We&#8217;re going to improve the lives of millions of Americans.  We’ll meet the great challenges of our time: voting rights, climate crisis, gun violence, criminal justice, immigration, and so much more.  (Applause.) <br><br>It&#8217;s literally within our power to do this.  (Applause.)  And we can make sure that this nation is going to continue to be what it&#8217;s always been.<br><br>I&#8217;ve said it before.  I was in China with Xi Jinping, and he turned to me with just &#8212; we each had an interpreter, and he said, “Can you define America for me?”  And this &#8212; God’s true story &#8212; and I said, “Yes, I can, in one word: possibilities.”<br><br>We can do anything when we decide to do it together.  (Applause.)  When we do it as the United States of America, there&#8217;s nothing beyond our capacity.  (Applause.)  So let&#8217;s get it done.  Let&#8217;s remind people what we&#8217;ve done and keep it going.<br><br>God bless you all.  And may God protect our troops.  Thank you, thank you, thank you.  (Applause.)<br><br>7:51 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White&#160;House Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Senate Passage of the Bipartisan Funding&#160;Bill</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/10/statement-by-white-house-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-senate-passage-of-the-bipartisan-funding-bill/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 03:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48886</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The bipartisan funding bill proves once more that members of both parties can come together to deliver results for the American people. It will reduce costs for families and businesses, support our economic recovery, and advance American leadership abroad. With these resources, we will be able to deliver historic support for the Ukrainian people as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The bipartisan funding bill proves once more that members of both parties can come together to deliver results for the American people. It will reduce costs for families and businesses, support our economic recovery, and advance American leadership abroad. With these resources, we will be able to deliver historic support for the Ukrainian people as they defend their country and democracy, launch a bold new initiative to drive unprecedented progress in curing cancer and other diseases, and provide additional support to our law enforcement so they can protect our communities.</p>



<p>The bill also ends a damaging series of short-term continuing resolutions that have undermined the government’s ability to meet pressing challenges.  We thank leaders in the House and Senate for their partnership in getting this bill done, and the President looks forward to signing it into law. At the same time, we continue to call on Congress to provide the funds urgently needed to prevent severe disruptions to our COVID response.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by President Joseph R. Biden Jr. of the United&#160;States and President Iván Duque Márquez of the Republic of Colombia U.S.-Colombia Bicentennial&#160;Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/10/joint-statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-of-the-united-states-and-president-ivan-duque-marquez-of-the-republic-of-colombia-u-s-colombia-bicentennial-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48883</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We met today to commemorate 200 years of diplomatic relations and to outline a vision for the future for the U.S.-Colombia relationship based on shared prosperity, social equity, the defense of human rights and fundamental freedoms, and the reaffirmation of the hemispheric consensus in favor of democracy enshrined in the Inter-American Democratic Charter. The United&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We met today to commemorate 200 years of diplomatic relations and to outline a vision for the future for the U.S.-Colombia relationship based on shared prosperity, social equity, the defense of human rights and fundamental freedoms, and the reaffirmation of the hemispheric consensus in favor of democracy enshrined in the Inter-American Democratic Charter.</p>



<p>The United States intends to designate Colombia as a Major Non-NATO Ally in recognition of our uniquely close cooperation in the hemisphere, Colombia’s significant contributions as a NATO Global Partner, its commitment to NATO’s mission to promote democratic values and commitment to the peaceful resolution of disputes, and its rejection of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustifiable aggression against Ukraine.</p>



<p>We committed to expanding longstanding bilateral security cooperation, into a strategic partnership with positive bilateral, regional, and global implications. Recognizing that strengthening Colombia’s security is in the national security interest of the United States, we agreed to sustain robust cooperation to combat terrorism and transnational criminal actors, including drug trafficking and the smuggling and trafficking of people, as well as the malign influence of external actors.</p>



<p>We committed to advance our broader drug policy strategy, with a holistic approach to counternarcotics focused on expanding access to evidence-based prevention, treatment, harm reduction, and recovery support services, as well as reducing the supply of illicit drugs through renewed efforts that link eradication, interdiction, drug demand reduction, anti-money laundering efforts and robust rule of law institutions. Our comprehensive approach will combine rural security and development efforts and work to consolidate and sustain peace implementation and reconciliation programs, while ensuring that criminal actors are brought to justice.</p>



<p>In the face of sustained challenges to democracy and universal human rights around the world, we recognized the need for our governments to demonstrate that democracy can deliver to improve the lives of our citizens by cracking down on corruption and promoting transparency, by ensuring a green and equitable recovery to the COVID-19 pandemic. The crisis in Venezuela is a regional challenge and we commit to support the restoration of democracy as necessary to bring an end to the political, economic, and humanitarian crises.&nbsp; In our continued efforts to end the COVID-19 pandemic worldwide, the United States announced the donation of an additional two million vaccine doses to Colombia, including for displaced and migrant communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We agreed to prioritize investments in our shared prosperity through the Build Back Better World initiative focused on climate change, health and health technology, digital connectivity, and gender equity. Further, we committed to ensuring that the future of U.S.-Colombia cooperation is guided by a continued commitment to environmental and social justice, as well as racial equity and a respect for human rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, we agreed to work on a new framework for how nations throughout the hemisphere collectively manage migration. The current migrant crisis is bigger than any one country and any one border. This is a moment that calls us all to action. The United States and Colombia urge leaders across the Americas to join us in developing a Regional Declaration on Migration and Protection. The Americas have a rich tradition of welcoming refugees and immigrants and showing solidarity with our neighbors. Working hand in hand, we can overcome this current crisis and truly set an example for the rest of the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan Meeting with Africa Union Commission Chairperson Moussa Faki&#160;Mahamat</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/10/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-meeting-with-africa-union-commission-chairperson-moussa-faki-mahamat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:03:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48881</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Africa Union Commission Chairperson Moussa Faki Mahamat to reinforce President Biden’s commitment to Africa. Chairperson Faki and Mr. Sullivan discussed working together and through multilateral institutions like the African Union and the United Nations to face today’s global challenges. Mr. Sullivan reiterated the United States’ commitment to working&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met with Africa Union Commission Chairperson Moussa Faki Mahamat to reinforce President Biden’s commitment to Africa. Chairperson Faki and Mr. Sullivan discussed working together and through multilateral institutions like the African Union and the United Nations to face today’s global challenges. Mr. Sullivan reiterated the United States’ commitment to working with Africa to achieve our goals around the world – combatting the COVID-19 pandemic, advancing global health security, building a strong and inclusive global economy, combating the climate crisis, and revitalizing democracy and defending human rights.  Mr. Sullivan also welcomed the strong statement from the Chairperson and African Union chair President of Senegal Macky Sall calling on the Russian Federation to respect international law and the national sovereignty of Ukraine.  Mr. Sullivan also raised areas where the United States and the African Union have an interest in working together to restore democracy in Mali, Burkina Faso, and Guinea, support fragile transitions in Sudan and Chad, and work toward peaceful and stable futures for Ethiopia and Somalia. Both agreed to maintain close coordination as President Biden plans to convene leaders from across the African continent for a U.S. – Africa Leaders Summit and host the Global COVID-19 Summit this year.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and President Duque of the Republic of Colombia Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/10/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-duque-of-the-republic-of-colombia-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 22:47:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48877</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cabinet Room 2:31 P.M. EST PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Welcome, folks.&#160; I’m honored to welcome President Duque here today.&#160; He’s my friend.&#160; We’ve known each other for a long while.&#160; And we were reminiscing about how far back we go and &#8212; and how he &#8212; he knew Beau when &#8212; he met Beau when he was&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cabinet Room</p>



<p>2:31 P.M. EST<br><br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Welcome, folks.&nbsp; I’m honored to welcome President Duque here today.&nbsp; He’s my friend.&nbsp; We’ve known each other for a long while.&nbsp; And we were reminiscing about how far back we go and &#8212; and how he &#8212; he knew Beau when &#8212; he met Beau when he was here.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as you know, Mr. President, I&#8217;ve been deeply engaged with the relationship with Colombia for a long time, going back more than 20 years to that old Plan Colombia.&nbsp; And, in fact, we first met visiting Bogota, I think it was 2018 &#8212;</p>



<p>PRESIDENT DUQUE:&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; you and I.<br><br>And I&#8217;m proud that we&#8217;ve been able to work together during my first year of my administration and to continue strengthening what I consider to be &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said many times over the years &#8212; the essential partnership we need in this hemisphere.</p>



<p>Colombia is the linchpin, in my view, to the whole hemisphere &#8212; north and south.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; And &#8212; and it&#8217;s an essential partnership.</p>



<p>And I want to thank you for immediately condemning Russia&#8217;s unjustifiable invasion and the atrocities they are committing in Ukraine, and calling for the withdrawal of Russian troops.&nbsp; Not everyone in the hemisphere or anywhere else has done that, and I want to thank you for that.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s not just a threat to Europe and Ukraine, but it&#8217;s a threat to the international peace and stability.&nbsp; And so, Colombia &#8212; Colombia’s voice is making it clear that you share our view and that there&#8217;s a lot more at stake than just the immediate undertaking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The American people and the entire world have rallied to support the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; We have donated, thus far, a billion dollars in security assistance and more shipments of defensive equipment are on the way as I speak.&nbsp; We’re coordinating deliveries of anti-armor and anti-air capabilities with a wide range of our allies and &#8212; and partners, and we&#8217;re providing tens of thousands of tons of humanitarian needs, from food, water, and medicine.</p>



<p>And Vice President Harris, today, is in Poland, where she announced that we’ll be contributing another $53 million to the World Food Programme and other humanitarian organizations to support those displaced from their homes.&nbsp; And she also announced the delivery of Patriot missile battery to support our NATO Allies in Poland.</p>



<p>And our economic sanctions are crippling the Russian economy right now.&nbsp; The ruble has lost half its value.&nbsp; It now would take literally almost 200 rubles to equal $1 because of how it&#8217;s been so damaging.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ruble is &#8212; any &#8212; we cut off U.S. imports of Russian oil and gas, targeting the main artery of Russia&#8217;s economy.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And last night, the House of Representatives passed a bill that included more than $13 billion in Ukrainian assistance.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the United States and the people around the world are going to continue to support the Ukrainian people, I believe, as they defend their country.&nbsp; Ukraine will never, never be a victory for Putin.</p>



<p>Now, I&#8217;ve said for a long time, Colombia is the keystone to our shared efforts to build a hemisphere that is prosperous, secure, and democratic.&nbsp; And we talked about the struggle of democracies in the 21st century.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to thank you, Mr. President, for your leadership on issues that matter to everyone in this region: combating the pandemic, advancing health security, taking on the climate crisis with urgency and genuine ambition, and for welcoming refugees from Venezuela and working toward an orderly, secure, and humane way to tackle the unprecedented levels of migration.</p>



<p>Colombia has done an incredible job, and I know the political consequences for taking that kind of stand, which is the right stand, are not always the most popular.</p>



<p>Our &#8212; our hemisphere migration challenges cannot be solved by one nation and &#8212; or any &#8212; and any one border.&nbsp; We have to work together.</p>



<p>And so, today, I&#8217;m calling for a new framework of how nations throughout the region can collectively manage migration in the Western Hemisphere.&nbsp; There&#8217;s something we&#8217;ve been discussing with partners throughout the region, including you, Mr. President.&nbsp; And our goal is going to be to sign a regional declaration on migration and protection in June in Los Angeles when the United States hosts the Summit of the Americas, which we talked a little bit about.</p>



<p>And this can be a piecemeal approach, in my view.&nbsp; It needs to include far more support for countries like Colombia that are hosting the lion&#8217;s share of the refugees and migrants.&nbsp; It is an obligation of all of us, not just Colombia.&nbsp; And it needs to include far more support, as I said.&nbsp; And it needs to dramatically expand access to resettlement and other legal pathways to migration.&nbsp; And it needs to aggressively pursue the criminal smugglers and traffickers who prey on all these folks for profit.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s the best way, in my view, for us to live up to our collective values and welcome immigrants and refugees, keep migrants safe, and secure all our countries.</p>



<p>Mr. President, the United States is going to continue to do our part to support Colombia as you care for Venezuelan refugees.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already shared 5.5 million doses of COVID-19 vaccine with Colombia now.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m pleased to say I’m going to be able to send an additional 2 million doses to help vaccinate the migrant population.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re also going to continue to strengthen our longstanding bilateral security arrangements to fight the transnational criminal activities that occur in this hemisphere and to meet the regional and global challenges that we face, both north and south.</p>



<p>Today, I&#8217;m proud to announce that I intend to designate Colombia a Major Non-NATO Ally, because that&#8217;s exactly what you are &#8212; a major Major Non-NA- &#8212; Non-NATO Ally.<br><br>And this is a recognition of the unique and close relationship between our countries.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re approaching, as you pointed out to me and we talked about, the 100th anniversary of the rela- &#8212; that relationship.</p>



<p>We stood with Colombia as you fought for your country and negotiated historic peace.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to stand together and build peace, reconciliation, and, God willing, a prosperous future for all Colombians.</p>



<p>And finally, as we&#8217;re celebrating 200 years of diplomatic relations &#8212; I said 100; you can tell I&#8217;m getting old &#8212; it was 200 years of diplomatic relations between our countries, and we&#8217;ve a long, shared history.&nbsp; And we’re looking forward to a future that our nations will build together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To that end, Mr. President, I&#8217;m pleased that our nations are agreed on new bicentennial partnership that&#8217;s going to form the basis of a comprehensive cooperation going forward between our countries.</p>



<p>The U.S.-Colombia relationship is the foundation, in my view, of regional security and prosperity, and it’s only going to grow more important in the years ahead.</p>



<p>So thank you for the visit.&nbsp; It&#8217;s wonderful to be with you in person.&nbsp; And I look forward to our discussion today.</p>



<p>And we did talk about so much more that we can do together, which we had a chance to talk about when you and I had our conversation.&nbsp;&nbsp; We finally both had to look at one another and said, “I guess we have people out there.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; We were so wrapped up in our discussions.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But thank you, again, Mr. President, for being here.&nbsp; You’re welcome.&nbsp; You’re always welcome here.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT DUQUE:&nbsp; Thank you, Mr. President.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; The floor is yours.<br><br>PRESIDENT DUQUE:&nbsp; Thank you so much, President Biden, for &#8212; for having us here at the White House.&nbsp; It’s a great honor for us to &#8212; to visit you.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s also a great honor for us to celebrate 200 years of the bilateral relationship that we have built based on values and based on principles.</p>



<p>We have to also express not only our gratitude but the continuous gratitude for you being one of the architects of Plan Colombia.&nbsp; That was a milestone in the bilateral relationship and that allowed Colombia to face and defeat many challenges that we had over the last two decades.&nbsp; So I also want you commend &#8212; to commend you for that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also believe that the partnership that we have built has been bipartisan, bicameral, and has demonstrated that over time this relationship only gets to a higher level.&nbsp; And we appreciate a lot that you have made the decision to designate Colombia a primary non-NATO ally because that is the recognition of the values and the principles that we have shared.</p>



<p>We also want to thank your support for being the major donor of vaccines to Colombia.&nbsp; You have been able to contribute to save the lives of millions of citizens.&nbsp; And this additional 2 million donation of vaccines to Colombia will also be used to attend the needs of many migrants that are in our country.<br><br>We also want to reiterate that the next Summit of the Americas is going to be a great opportunity to embrace the cause of the Build Back Better World, an initiative that is aimed to increase investment, job opportunities, and to allow through trade and investment to generate jobs that would also be a deterrent of farther migratory pressures in the hemisphere.</p>



<p>We want Colombia to be one of the reference models of B3W.&nbsp; We have projects that are advancing in clean energy, climate adaptation, infrastructure.&nbsp; So we consider that we want to be a reference for other countries in Latin America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to express my gratitude for all the support we&#8217;ve gotten from U.S. agencies in order to attend the needs of the 1.8 million Venezuelan migrants in our territory.<br><br>They have crossed the border with frozen bones.&nbsp; They have come in &#8212; they have come to our country without any access to health services or food.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve been able to attend.&nbsp; And the support of USAID in the border zone is something that has made a very important contribution.</p>



<p>We also believe that the TPS status that we have granted to these 1.8 million citizens and that will receive their card by no longer than August this year, it&#8217;s going to allow them to look for jobs, enter the Social Security system, and, most importantly, Mr. President, they are going to be able to contribute to the Colombian economy but also to improve their life (inaudible).&nbsp; So this is something that makes a strong sense to us.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we also have to say that in the times we&#8217;re facing, we have made a strong stand against the brutal, unjustified attack from Russia to Ukraine.&nbsp; This has been a very horrifying moment for the world.&nbsp; And we have to condemn with a very strong sentiment.&nbsp; You have done it.&nbsp; We have done it.&nbsp; And we have also said that through the multilateral system, we will also be pressing for any sanctions to be implemented because nothing justifies the bloodbath that we have been seeing continuously over the news in the last weeks.</p>



<p>We have also spoken to the NATO Secretary General.&nbsp; And I have been speaking with leaders in Poland, Romania, Slovakia, and other countries in Europe to offer Colombia&#8217;s advice on migration management in their circumstances.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll be there.&nbsp; And we will also participate actively in giving that support.</p>



<p>We have also made a humanitarian contribution through NATO, as the only Latin American country that is a partner of NATO.&nbsp; And we believe that at this moment, we have to do all we can (inaudible).</p>



<p>And last but not least, Mr. President, I think there are two very important subjects in which we have been working closely.&nbsp; And it’s climate action &#8212; Colombia approved the climate action bill by a unanimous decision in Congress.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Impressive.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT DUQUE:&nbsp; And we have been also able to launch an energy transition program that has allowed us to pass from barely 28 megawatts of installed capacity non-conventional renewables to 2,800 megawatts, which is 100 times of what we had when we assumed office.</p>



<p>And we are working with your administration in the protection of areas in our country &#8212; maritime areas and on-land areas.&nbsp; So we will not wait on to 2030 to meet the 30 by 30 criteria.&nbsp; And this year, before the month of August, we&#8217;ll have 30 percent of the Colombian territory declared a protected area.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re having U.S. support in this.&nbsp; We&#8217;re also restoring 1 million corals and protecting the mangroves in very important zones of our country.&nbsp; And this is also part of their bilateral agenda.</p>



<p>So, President Biden, to you and to the administration but also to the American people, we feel proud that 200 years of this bilateral relationship, today, with your decision of declaring Colombia a strategic non-NATO partner, is taking the bilateral relationship to the highest peak ever.</p>



<p>Thank you so much.</p>



<p>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Thank you<br><br>2:45 P.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>CORRECTED: Remarks by Vice President Harris and President Andrzej Duda of Poland in Joint Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/10/corrected-remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland-in-joint-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 21:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48872</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Belweder PalaceWarsaw, Poland 12:57 P.M. CET PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  Your Excellency and distinguished Madam Vice President of the United States of America, distinguished ladies and gentlemen: This is a very important moment in our relations.  But, first and foremost, under these circumstances which we are facing right now in Europe, behind our Eastern border, in&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Belweder Palace<br>Warsaw, Poland</em></p>



<p>12:57 P.M. CET<br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  Your Excellency and distinguished Madam Vice President of the United States of America, distinguished ladies and gentlemen: This is a very important moment in our relations.  But, first and foremost, under these circumstances which we are facing right now in Europe, behind our Eastern border, in Ukraine &#8212; friendly to us and with us &#8212; where the Russian troops are carrying out a barbarious aggression and murdering innocent people, murdering civilians, bombing maternity hospitals from which, under dramatic circumstances, wounded women right before labor &#8212; are being carried out.<br> <br>None of us has ever expected that we would be able to see such things in the 21st century.<br> <br>Especially it is a great satisfaction to all of us here in Poland that Madam Vice President of the United States of America, Ms. Kamala Harris, is here with us in Warsaw, in our country.<br> <br>And she&#8217;s demonstrating that strength and depth of the atlantic &#8212; transatlantic and Allied bond, demonstrating decisive engagement and commitment of the United States to the security of NATO&#8217;s eastern flank and to Europe as a whole.<br> <br>Let me stress very forcefully: There is no doubt whatsoever that together with the United States and our other Allies within the framework of the North Atlantic Alliance, and along with the entire free and honest world, we stand with Ukraine.  We stand with Ukraine, and we will try to do our best to make sure that Ukraine can be defended.<br> <br>Thank you very much, Madam Vice President, for coming.  Thank you for our meetings today, for the conversations that we have had.<br> <br>We had a meeting just a couple of minutes ago.  We had a private meeting, a tête-à-tête meeting.  And we also met with Polish and American delegations.  We discussed all the important topics.  And I highlighted very forcefully how important it is, and I thanked also for the position of the President of the United States, Mr. Joe Biden.  I thanked for the position of Madam Vice President and her team.  But I also thanked for the position of the U.S. Congress.  <br> <br>I thanked for this necessity and, actually, the imposition of effective sanctions on the Russian Federation.  The United States is in the vanguard of those sanctions, and, speaking honestly, these sanctions are working.<br> <br>Above all, thank you also for all the support which is being provided to the fight in Ukraine &#8212; to Ukraine, which is defending itself.<br> <br>Thank you for the humanitarian assistance, which is being supplied there.<br> <br>And to you, Madam Vice President, I would like to thank for the involvement of all the organizations and of all the NGOs that are being involved in providing assistance &#8212; humanitarian assistance.  Also, they&#8217;re providing medical aid.  They&#8217;re providing equipment for children, for wounded, for the sick.<br> <br>My wife Agata is involved in this as well.  And I know that, in those respect, she is in cooperation with various institutions from the United States.  She is in contact with the First Lady of the United States, Jill Biden.<br> <br>I’m very happy that this Polish-American cooperation is developing.  But I&#8217;m pleased that it serves to provide common aid to the fight in Ukraine and common aid to all those who are suffering, all those who need this assistance from us.<br> <br>And today, I shared with Madam Vice President &#8212; I described the situation that we are facing.  I said that, today, for a number of days actually, we have been receiving refugees from Ukraine in Poland.  This number is close to 1.5 million persons who have come to us.  And I&#8217;m addressing my compatriots right now.  I was proud to tell Madam Vice President that all those people have not been sent to any camps and refugee camps.  They have been accepted and received by Polish families in Polish homes.  They are accommodated in Polish hotels, in Polish spa resorts, in Polish motels.<br> <br>Most often, however, they&#8217;re accommodated with private people.  They have been received by ordinary Polish people who feel in their hearts that they should extend a helping hand to the people in need. <br> <br>And I thank you so much for this, to my fellow Polish people.  This is a reason to be proud for us, for the Polish authorities.  And I&#8217;m very, very much grateful to you for that. <br> <br>At the same time, I asked Madam Vice President for support, as it is quite obvious that such a huge refugee crisis is a surprise for Poland.  And it is a complicated situation for Poland, for the Polish authorities in the era of the crisis.  The prices are growing &#8212; of fuel prices are growing; generally, the prices are growing.  That is why we do need this support.  And I&#8217;m going to be hugely grateful for any form of support because we have to survive this difficult time.<br> <br>And we have to do that by helping our neighbors, because that is extremely important right now. <br> <br>However, first and foremost, we discussed security issues.<br> <br>The presence of Madam Vice President here in Poland is yet another demonstration of U.S. presidents &#8212; of U.S. presence in Poland, next to the U.S. troops that we have here, next to U.S. defensive systems that are protecting our skies today and our land.<br> <br>We also have with us here today the political representation, the top-level political representation of the United States, led by Madam Vice President.  <br> <br>And this is a very clear political message where important &#8212; most important things are happening today on the global stage in Europe: We have to rescue Ukraine.  All of us are acutely aware of that.  All hands should be on board.  Ukraine needs to be helped.  And we have to stay united in that respect.  We need to stand together in this respect within the North Atlantic Alliance, keeping solidarity, speaking absolutely with one voice, just as we have to stand together in the European Union and in all the other international communities.  We have to impose more sanctions on Russia.<br> <br>We cannot accept such military activities, which bear the characteristics of the features of a genocide, because I don&#8217;t think that anybody is in any doubt if hospitals are bombed, if hospitals are bombed where pregnant women are staying, where children are staying, when ordinary people are killed, where bombs are dropped, when missiles are launched into residential houses where there are no military installations, then this is an act of barbarity bearing the features of a genocide.  It aims at eliminating and destroying a nation.  Hence, we have to stand and present a very tough stance here as representatives of the free world. <br> <br>And Poland stands here together with the United States of America, just like &#8212; I have no doubt about that &#8212; our Allies stand with Ukraine and all the honest authorities and states, especially democratic states. <br> <br>And at the end of our conversation, I mentioned the fact that we want to boost our security also on our own here in Poland.  Also, thanks to the purchase of American equipment for our armed forces, there are already ongoing programs such as Patriot programs, such as HIMARS program, the program of the purchase of F-35s, or the recently started program &#8212; the purchase of Abrams tanks for Poland. <br> <br>I asked Madam Vice President that those programs should be accelerated as far as this as possible, because we want to provide this state-of-the-art equipment to our armed forces as soon as possible.  <br> <br>If there is such a need &#8212; I think everybody can see that.  We do not need to comment on this situation.  We are able to witness the dramatic scenes unfolding in Ukraine every day in the media.  You can see those horrific &#8212; horrifying scenes. <br> <br>But at the same time, we&#8217;re able to witness the huge heroism and incredible determination of the Ukrainian people.  And we stand at the side of the Ukrainian people.  We’re going to support them with all our strength, but at the same time providing the security of our countries which is of crucial importance to us.<br> <br>Once again, thank you very much, Madam Vice President, for coming to Warsaw.  Thank you for this demonstration that we stand together and that we are a huge Euro-Atlantic community of freedom and security.  Thank you. <br> <br>I’d like to give the floor to Madam Vice President of the United States of America.  Madam Kamala Harris.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Thank you, President Duda, and for the warm welcome under unfortunate circumstances, given what is happening in Ukraine, our friend.  But I thank you for the warm welcome and for the very constructive and productive conversations we had today as part of our ongoing dialogue and friendship that spans generations. <br> <br>I would like to also speak directly to the Polish people.  I have shared with your president that, under his leadership &#8212; and your leadership has been extraordinary &#8212; the world has been watching Poland, Mr. President, your leadership and the leadership of the people of your country.  And we&#8217;ve witnessed extraordinary acts of generosity and kindness.  We have seen through images on the television &#8212; looking at images of ordinary people doing extraordinary things in support of the dignity and the wellbeing of perfect strangers.<br> <br>So I, first and foremost, want to express the thanks for the people of the United States to you, Mr. President, on behalf of our President, Joe Biden, and to the people of Poland for what you are doing every day.  It really represents the best of who we are.<br> <br>We are here and I am here in Poland today as part of an enduring, longstanding friendship and commitment between the United States and Poland based on shared values and priorities.  <br> <br>I am here, standing here on the northern flank &#8212; on the eastern flank talking about what we have in terms of the eastern flank and our NATO Allies and what is at stake at this very moment.  What is at stake this very moment are some of the guiding principles around the NATO Alliance and, in particular, the issue and the importance of defending sovereignty and territorial integrity, in this case, of Ukraine.<br> <br>As President Duda has described, we have been witnessing for weeks &#8212; and certainly just in the last 24 hours &#8212; atrocities of unimaginable proportion.  A maternity hospital, a children&#8217;s hospital, where we have witnessed pregnant women who were there for care, for one reason &#8212; being taken out, because they required care because of an act of violence &#8212; unprovoked, unjustified.<br> <br>I am here, in Poland, as an expression of the enduring and important relationship between the United States and Poland that, again, has been longstanding, but, in particular on the issue of Ukraine, is unified and is clear.  We will do everything together, in partnership, in solidarity, to support what is necessary at this very moment in terms of the humanitarian and security needs of Ukraine and the Ukrainian people. <br> <br>Today, we discussed, Mr. President, many issues that relate to our special bond also, because, I will say as a point of personal privilege, we have a substantial Polish American community in my hometown of Los Angeles but throughout the United States, who understands the relationship that we have on many levels, including the diplomatic but also cultural relationships that span generations. <br> <br>And so, through all of that and in the spirit of those relationships and our shared commitments &#8212; our shared commitment to the importance of international norms and rules &#8212; you and I discussed today many important topics, in particular as it relates to the eastern flank.  And we talked specifically about what we cared deeply about in terms of our commitment &#8212; the United States commitment to Article 5.  <br> <br>I&#8217;ve said it many times; I will say it again: The United States commitment to Article 5 is ironclad.  The United States is prepared to defend every inch of NATO territory.  The United States takes seriously that an attack against one is an attack against all.  We are here today to restate that commitment, but also do what we must do to reinforce our support of Poland and our Allies through the EU and NATO Alliance.<br> <br>In particular, as it relates to troop deployment, we have recently deployed an additional 4,700 American troops to Poland.  That&#8217;s on top of the years of rotation of about 5,000 American troops in Poland.  <br> <br>We are pleased to have announced this week that we have directed two Patriot missile defense systems to Poland.  And today, I can announce that we have delivered those Patriot systems to Poland.  We do this as a reminder and as a demonstration of our commitment to the security of our Allies and our commitment, in particular, to Poland at this moment in time.<br> <br>As it relates to the people of Ukraine: They have suffered immensely.  When we talk about humanitarian aid, it is because, yes, the assistance is necessary, but what compels us also is the moral outrage that all civilized nations feel when we look at what is happening to innocent men, women, children, grandmothers, grandfathers who are fleeing everything they&#8217;ve known.  Our outrage, which compels not only our security assistance but our humanitarian assistance, is rooted in the fact that also we support the people of Ukraine who have shown extraordinary courage and skill and their willingness and, yes, ability to fight against Putin’s war and Russia&#8217;s aggression. <br> <br>So, today we are also announcing, in pursuit of what must happen, which is to provide humanitarian assistance, that we will give another $50 million &#8212; the United States will &#8212; through the U.N.’s World Food Programme to assist with humanitarian aid. <br> <br>The President and I also talked about the fact that, as he mentioned, Poland has taken, in just a very short period of time, in excess of one and a half million refugees in from Ukraine.  And that has put an extraordinary burden on Poland and the people of Poland.  And so, we will continue with the support that we can give you, Mr. President, in terms of the work that you and the people of Poland have been doing to bear this burden, but in a way that really has been with such grace<br>and such generosity.<br> <br>We also are pleased to have shared with the President what our United States Congress has done, which is there is a commitment now of $13.6 billion in human- &#8212; humanitarian and security assistance that will be then distributed and shared with Ukraine and the people of this region and Europe, all again understanding that this moment in time requires both a humanitarian response as well as security assistance. <br> <br>And today, I&#8217;m also pleased to say that we are in ongoing discussions with Poland and our Allies about the effectiveness of sanctions thus far and going forward.  As we have announced in the United States, we have, through the United States Department of Justice, started a task force to do what is required and necessary and appropriate in terms of investigations as it relates to any criminal activities and behaviors on behalf of institutions and individuals, including oligarchs. <br> <br>We talked &#8212; the President and I &#8212; about the effectiveness of the sanctions we&#8217;ve seen thus far, in terms of the courage and the bold action that has been taken through the NATO Alliance to do what is necessary to send a clear signal that there will be, as we promised, severe cost and consequence for Russia&#8217;s aggression to the point that we have now seen a freefall of the ruble, to the point that we have now seen that Russia&#8217;s credit rating has been rated as junk, and what we know to be real economic consequence to Russia because of Putin&#8217;s war.<br> <br>As you know, the President of the United States also made the decision to do what was necessary in terms of the purchase of Russian oil in the United States.  <br> <br>Again, we will continue to focus on this issue, keeping in mind that this is a moment that requires severe and swift consequence for Russia&#8217;s aggression against Ukraine. <br> <br>And I&#8217;ll close by saying what we say every day for these last weeks, which is we stand with the people of Ukraine, that we admire their courage, and that we are aligned in our support of their sovereignty and territorial integrity. <br> <br>Thank you, Mr. President.<br> <br>Q    (As interpreted.)  My name is Żaklina Skowrońska.  I represent Polish Television.  I would like to ask my question to both Madam Vice President and Mr. President.  In what way has this brutal attack of Russia against Ukraine impacted Polish-American relations?  Antony Blinken, State Secretary, during his last visit to Poland was saying that the Polish-American friendship has never been so strong in history as it is now.  Is it going to translate also on the permanent military presence of the United States in Poland?  Thank you very much.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  It cannot be said too frequently or strongly enough: The relationship between the United States and Poland is a deep, enduring, and strong one and, dare I say, has become even stronger when we have been faced as a world with such adversity.  I think we all know, even in our personal lives, adversity really, truly, can present the real measure of an individual or a relationship.  And what we have seen without any doubt is that this friendship and relationship between the United States and Poland is a strong one.<br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  Ladies and gentlemen, answering your question, I want to go a little bit back into history &#8212; or deeper into history.  Let me put it in the following way: When I started my service as President of the Republic of Poland in 2015, I was perfectly aware of the fact that an aggressive Russia, like President Lech Kaczyński was saying in Georgia in 2008, would not stop only attacking Georgia in 2008 and attacking part of Ukraine in 2014.  I knew that this appetite, this imperial appetite will grow. <br> <br>And if the world does not react to that &#8212; if the world does not react, if the North Atlantic Alliance does not stand up, does not present a tough stance, then we will see more attacks from Russia &#8212; to which perhaps, sooner or later, also my country, Poland, would fall victim to.<br> <br>And when I started as President of Poland, I knew that I had to do everything that I could to protect Poland from such a scenario.  One has to use very clear and strong words here in the presence of Madam Vice President of the United States.  Those who understood well what I was saying back then, speaking about the Russian threat, were precisely the representatives of the United States, were the representatives of Barack Obama administration and the President himself back then, the U.S. generals as well.<br> <br>And precisely thanks to their support, we were able to obtain the North Atlantic Alliance presence on the eastern flank, were able to execute the strengthening of the eastern flank for the first time since we joined NATO in 1999.<br> <br>It was precisely in NATO Summit in Warsaw, through, first and foremost, the decisions of the U.S. President and his team, but also through the decisions of other Allies whom we were able to convince, has led to putting this presence on the eastern flank of the Alliance and, symbolically, in Poland.<br> <br>The United States is the framework nation.  At the same time, the U.S. soldiers came here and started the rotational presence in Poland.  It is a rotational but also a persistent presence, enduring presence.  It is a back-to-back presence.  Soldiers change, but the U.S. armed forces are present on our soil all the time.  And that was a breakthrough.<br> <br>If we recall the words of President Lech Kaczyński, which I quoted many times and who said those words to me back in 2008, he said, and I quote: “Andrzej, when U.S. soldiers are on our soil, when U.S. military installations are on our soil, when U.S. military equipment is put in our soil, then the whole world will be able to see that we are no longer a Russian sphere of influence.”  This is a true friendship. <br> <br>As Madam Vice President remarked today, “A friend in need is a friend indeed.”  That is why I&#8217;m really happy that today, when we are in need and when the NATO eastern flank is in need, the United States, by the decision of President Joe Biden, has deployed additional troops.  The U.S. is deploying more troops, and the U.S. is announcing the strengthening of this presence in our part of Europe and also in Poland, because this is precisely the understanding of the geopolitics of strategic goals that have to be achieved by this geopolitics and by the free world.  This is the understanding of the security.<br> <br>Is Polish American presence today, if we look at the last couple of years, stronger than ever?  Yes, Polish-American friendship, for sure, over the last seven years of my presidency is stronger than ever before. <br> <br>And today&#8217;s presence here today in Warsaw of Madam Vice President Kamala Harris is yet another strong evidence of that, just as the presence of all the representatives of Mr. President Joe Biden&#8217;s administration here recently on our soil.<br> <br>And also, this is evidenced by the frequency of contacts that I have with the President of the United States.  We frequently talk and discuss the most important security-related topics and our mutual relations. <br> <br>Yes, of course, whenever we speak about great politics and friendship, this is this friendship and great politics.  And this is the friendship between states for sure.  This is the friendship between Poland and the United States of America.  It is very strong right now &#8212; the strongest perhaps ever in history.<br> <br>WHITE HOUSE AIDE:  The next question will come from Nandita Bose of Reuters.<br> <br>Q    Hi, Madam Vice President.  Thank you for &#8212; and President Duda.  Thank you for taking my question. <br> <br>President Zelenskyy has strongly asked for better air power in recent days.  And my question is: What kind of alternative plans does the United States have to get materials to help Ukraine defend itself, especially now that you have declined Poland&#8217;s offer on jets?  Can you give us some specifics on what you discussed with the Polish leaders on this issue, Madam Vice President?<br> <br>And one for President Duda.  The United States says, Mr. President, it was not consulted before you made the offer to make your jets available to the United States.  Is that accurate?  And did Poland act unilaterally in making an offer?  If yes, why?  Especially now that you have spoken about the strong relationship that U.S. and Poland has shared over the years.  Thank you.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  I want to be very clear: The United States and Poland are united in what we have done and are prepared to do to help Ukraine and the people of Ukraine, full stop. <br> <br>In terms of the work that the United States has done thus far, we have, as you know, given military, humanitarian, and security assistance, and that is an ongoing process. <br> <br>As I mentioned earlier, Congress &#8212; the United States Congress has now made a decision for 13-plus billion dollars of United States &#8212; of U.S. money to go to Ukraine and our European allies to assist in terms of both their security and humanitarian needs.<br> <br>We have also, just this past week, given $240 million in security assistance delivered to Ukraine, and that’s on top of the $1 billion in just the past year that we have sent to Ukraine. <br> <br>I can tell you that the issue facing the Ukrainian people and our Allies in the eastern flank is something that occupies one of our highest priorities in terms of paying attention to the needs, understanding it is a dynamic situation and it requires us to be nimble and to be swift. <br> <br>I mentioned being swift in terms of accountability and consequence.  We also fully appreciate we must be swift in terms of providing assistance where we can be helpful.  And we will continue to do that.<br> <br>Q    Can you (inaudible) plans, especially in light of the issue with Poland on jets?<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Well, we&#8217;re making deliveries every day, in terms of what we can do in terms of assistance and, in particular, when you look at what we&#8217;ve been doing, as it relates to anti-tank and anti &#8212; defense systems.  That is an ongoing process, and that&#8217;s not going to stop to the extent that there is a need. <br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>POLISH AIDE:  (No translation provided.)<br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  One moment.  I need to give an answer as well. <br> <br>Madam, that situation is extremely complicated, because we are all saying that there is a fight going on in Ukraine for independence, for sovereignty, for freedom, and for survival.  And all of us support, with all the strength we have, the people of Ukraine. <br> <br>It is not only the military.  Also, the people of Ukraine have taken to arms to defend their homeland.  It is not only men; it’s also women who fight on the frontline shoulder-to-shoulder with men in order to defend their country.  And we have no doubt whatsoever that they need help and assistance.<br> <br>Let me say something more.  We accept that they have the right to demand this assistance from the international community.  They can demand this support from NATO.  We are providing them humanitarian assistance and material assistance the best we can.  We are trying to do our best. <br> <br>Some expectations were addressed in a very strong and unequivocal way, also towards us &#8212; towards Poland.  However, we are members of the North Atlantic Alliance.  And as far as security-related issues are concerned, we have to look at these not only through our own lens &#8212; through the prism of the security of Poland &#8212; but we also have to adopt the perspective of the security of NATO as a whole.  <br> <br>So, in a nutshell, we have to be a responsible member of the North Atlantic Alliance.  That is why there were requests addressed to us.  Those requests were addressed to us by the Ukrainian side and also, to a certain extent, by the media. <br> <br>We behaved in such a way as a reliable member of NATO should behave &#8212; a member of NATO who does not want to expose NATO to any difficult situation.  On the other hand, we, as members of NATO, also wanted and want to look for ways of support for the fight in Ukraine.  And that is why we formulated statements, together with the Polish government &#8212; so myself as president, together with the Polish government.  <br> <br>And this statement or this declaration was announced by the Polish Minister of Foreign Affairs.  It talked about the Polish possibilities &#8212; military possibilities of assisting Ukraine.  Simply, we decided to put those jets at the disposal of NATO, not expecting anything in return, because we stressed very clearly that, as a gap filler for the donated equipment, we were able to buy something that we would need as a replacement.  And we, ourselves, we’re ready to provide our equipment free of charge. <br> <br>But we wanted NATO as a whole to make a common decision so that Poland remains a credible member of NATO, not a country who decides on its own on important issues which impact the security of NATO as a whole &#8212; which would impact the security of all members of NATO &#8212; also our neighbors who are part of NATO &#8212; members of NATO. <br> <br>Thank you.<br> <br>Another question? <br> <br>POLISH AIDE:  Maja Wójcikowska, TVN24.<br> <br>Q    Madam Vice President, each day we can see death and unimaginable suffering of the Ukraine people caused by decisions made by Vladimir Putin.  My question is: Will the U.S. support an international investigation into war crimes committed by Russia in Ukraine?  And can you see any political future for Putin? <br> <br>(As interpreted.)  This is also the question to the Polish President. <br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Okay, I’ll go. <br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (Points to himself.)<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  You go this time, please.  (Laughs.)<br> <br>Q    (Inaudible) I will start with Madam Vice President.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  (Laughs.)  Okay.<br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (Points to Vice President Harris.) <br> <br>Q    Thank you.  I appreciate that.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Not at all.  I &#8212; we are very clear: The NATO Alliance is stronger and Russia is weaker because of what Putin has done.  That is very clear to us.  <br> <br>And when it comes to crimes and violations of international norms and rules, we are also very clear that any intentional attack on innocent civilians is a violation.  The U.N. has set up a process by which there will be a review and investigations, and we will of course participate as appropriate and necessary. <br> <br>But we all watched the television coverage of just yesterday.  That&#8217;s on top of everything else that we know and don&#8217;t know yet, based on what we&#8217;ve just been able to see.  And because we&#8217;ve seen it or not doesn&#8217;t mean it hasn&#8217;t happened.<br> <br>But just limited to what we have seen: Pregnant women going for healthcare being injured by &#8212; I don’t know &#8212; a missile, a bomb in an unprovoked, unjustified war, where a powerful country is trying to take over another country &#8212; violate its sovereignty, its territorial integrity, for the sake of what?  Nothing that is justified or provoked.  Absolutely there should be an investigation, and we should all be watching.  And I have no question the eyes of the world are on this war and what Russia has done in terms of this aggression and these atrocities.  I have no doubt. <br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  (As interpreted.)  It is obvious to us that in Ukraine, Russians are committing war crimes.  I hope that also in the future it will be obvious for a court investigating those issues who bears responsibility for that.<br> <br>Now, please remember that the refugees from Ukraine are coming to us right now.  And right now, as we speak, there are people crossing our border who witnessed their houses destroyed, who saw their neighbors being killed, who saw hospitals being bombed, who saw civilians being shot at, children being shot at.  These are proofs.  These are the reports of witnesses, and they also have those proofs on their smartphones.  If you look at those footages, it just makes your blood curl.  Such scenes are happening today, and they have been happening over the last days in Ukraine, and their perpetrators are Russians. <br> <br>A group of prosecutors has come to us delegated by the court to look at the facts of this case.  They are collecting evidence.  We, as Poland, try as much as we can to give them best &#8212; the best possible conditions for work and then to fulfill this very difficult task. <br> <br>Let us remember, the witnesses are here.  There is a lot of evidence &#8212; the footages as I mentioned.  We have those proofs and the evidence.  All of that is being collected.  The work is ongoing.  And I do believe that it is going to result in very serious indictment acts. <br> <br>And I do believe that the war crimes &#8212; criminals will be sentenced &#8212; those responsible for the war that is happening in Ukraine right now as a result of this (inaudible) Russian assault. <br> <br>WHITE HOUSE AIDE:  And the final question will be from Asma Khalid of NPR.<br> <br>Q    Thank you.  Thank you, Madam Vice President.  I wanted to ask you about some reporting that my colleague here in Poland noticed.  He recently spoke with the mayor of the largest border town, who told him that the refugee system is essentially not set up for this, that it will collapse.  It&#8217;s an improvised system that can work for maybe two weeks, but not indefinitely.  And I&#8217;m wondering what the United States is going to do more specifically to set up a permanent infrastructure.  And relatedly, is the United States willing to make a specific allocation for Ukrainian refugees? <br> <br>And for President Duda, I wanted to know if you think and if you asked the United States to specifically accept more refugees.<br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Okay.  (Laughs.)  A friend in need is a friend indeed.  (Laughter.) <br> <br>PRESIDENT DUDA:  Okay.  I’ll go first.  Okay, so this time &#8212; (as interpreted) &#8212; Madam, the situation is very complex.  This is what I was saying today and I discussed this at length with Madam Vice President Kamala Harris.  I said, in a very blunt way, that today we are seeing a refugee crisis.  It is unfolding because Poland is still able to receive &#8212; it is all the time able to find the accommodation for those people who are coming to us all the time.  <br> <br>But we have got almost 1,500,000 people who have come to us over the last couple of days.  So it&#8217;s been 10 days.  We have received more than 1 million people within 10 days.  Never before have we witnessed such a situation.  So this is something totally new to us, and we are grappling with this huge challenge.  Our entire society is facing up to this challenge.  I have already expressed my gratitude to the Polish people for their wonderful position in this very difficult situation &#8212; that they are so openhearted. <br> <br>But we are aware that the problem is growing and that this problem is increasing.  We have to somehow handle it, and we do not have the experience.  Therefore, yesterday, I had a long conversation with Mr. António Guterres, Secretary General of the United Nations organization.  And I flagged out that problem to him.  I described to him the situation &#8212; how it looks, how it develops.  I described to him the reaction of the Polish society, of the Polish authorities, how we have been handling with this problem.  But I told him that unless we receive international assistance, then, given further influx of refugees to Poland on this scale, this will end up in a refugee disaster.  And I asked for help &#8212; both the material assistance, financial assistance &#8212; so that we are able to solve this in Poland. <br> <br>I also asked for expertise, for the know-how, because the U.N. has got experts who have seen a multitude of crises of this dimension, and I&#8217;m sure that they have worked out methods of how to handle it.  And I&#8217;m sure they know how to solve the problems, which ensue due to such a crisis situation. <br> <br>And this is something that I described in detail also today to Madam Vice President.  I said that the assistance of the United States in this respect is invaluable to us, and we would be very much grateful if we could use this assistance as soon as possible. <br> <br>Furthermore, we discussed the refugees from Ukraine who have got relatives and families in the United States, and who would be willing &#8212; at least for the time when the war is still waging, they would like to visit those families, to stay with their families in the United States, and to wait there until the war is over and then come back to their homes.<br> <br>I asked to speed up and simplify the procedures for such people &#8212; the consular procedures to be simplified for those people who would like to leave for the United States, to give the opportunity to these people to see their families as soon as possible, to be reunited with their families, to help them to survive this time. <br> <br>So we are acting, and we are looking for international support because, indeed, the vast majority of Ukrainian refugees are coming to our country.  Frankly speaking, that is because, first of all, we are a big country.  And also, the material status of an ordinary citizen of Poland is for sure much better than the material status, the living conditions of an ordinary Ukrainian citizen, although we are not among those wealthy countries of Western Europe, but our living standards have increased over the last couple of years in Poland. <br> <br>But they are coming because I believe that also the &#8212; it is their belief that thanks to the presence of NATO armed forces, thanks to the presence of our Allies from NATO &#8212; from Canada, from the UK, from Romania, and from other countries whose soldiers are deployed in Poland &#8212; they believe that Poland, due to that presence, is a safe country, a country which is not going to be attacked, a country where you can safely wait out this difficult situation. <br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  As the President said, we did discuss this issue.  And I started by thanking the President in Poland and the people of Poland for what they have done.  And I will restate what I said earlier this afternoon: They&#8217;ve shown extraordinary generosity and kindness and courage.  And they have &#8212; there have been some here who have relatives who have arrived from Ukraine, but I think there are many more who are taking in perfect strangers with barely a lot to give but giving a lot nonetheless. <br> <br>So, we recognize that, and we recognize the burden that it places on the government of Poland, on the president, and the infrastructure of this country; when you look at &#8212; as the President said, over one and a half million people coming within two weeks, virtually.  Unprecedented if you track and look at refugee flows over the history of time from regions of conflict.<br> <br>So the United States is absolutely prepared to do what we can and what we must to support Poland in terms of the burden that they have taken on that I think all of us who understand the moral obligation we should feel to help people who are fleeing harm and seeking refuge; the burden we should all be prepared to take on to support those people who are fleeing their home when they don&#8217;t want to leave. <br> <br>In terms of what we are doing in the United States, we will then take this in terms of what we can do to support and look at those Ukrainians who want to come to the United States.  What we&#8217;re seeing thus far is large parts of that population who are fleeing Ukraine, who desire to stay in Europe. <br> <br>You probably know that we have made a decision as it relates to TPS &#8212; the Temporary Protected Status.  So for Ukrainians that are in the United States whose visa may expire or has expired: If they were in the United States before &#8212; I believe it&#8217;s March; I don&#8217;t have the exact date &#8212; they will be able to stay; they won&#8217;t be required to leave, even though their visa has expired because, of course, we would not send them back to what is a warzone.  <br> <br>And the bottom line is that I have stated the position to the President this afternoon.  As we have said many times through our work collectively in the U.N., through NATO, we will support Poland in terms of the burden it is facing and our collective responsibility to ensure the safety and wellbeing of these refugees.<br> <br>POLISH AIDE:  (As interpreted.)  This concludes our press conference.  Thank you very much for your participation, ladies and gentlemen. <br> <br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:  Thank you.<br> <br>                          END                 1:43 P.M. CET<br> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement of President Joe&#160;Biden on the Justice Department Naming a Chief Pandemic&#160;Prosecutor</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/10/statement-of-president-joe-biden-on-the-justice-department-naming-a-chief-pandemic-prosecutor/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 21:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48868</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In my State of the Union address, I made clear that we must conduct strong oversight and robust criminal enforcement of pandemic fraud. And I announced that the Department of Justice commitment would name a chief prosecutor for pandemic fraud — a watchdog to go after the criminals who stole billions in relief money meant&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In my State of the Union address, I made clear that we must conduct strong oversight and robust criminal enforcement of pandemic fraud. And I announced that the Department of Justice commitment would name a chief prosecutor for pandemic fraud — a watchdog to go after the criminals who stole billions in relief money meant for small businesses and working Americans.  Today, I applaud the Justice Department for moving forward so swiftly to fill that role. <br> <br>In the early days of the pandemic, the previous Administration consistently undermined the watchdogs whose job it was to keep relief funds from being wasted or abused.  Emergency loans that were supposed to help small businesses keep the lights on and keep employees on the payroll were siphoned off by wealthy scammers.  Foreign and domestic criminal syndicates intercepted benefits meant for Americans in dire need of relief.  Reports of identity theft spiked by 3,000 percent from 2019 to 2020 — and far too many working families bore the brunt of this unchecked fraud.<br> <br>The watchdogs are back.  The COVID-19 Fraud Enforcement Task Force has already initiated more than 1,000 criminal cases, aiming to recover billions of dollars for the American people.  We are taking the same meticulous approach that I employed when President Obama put me in charge of overseeing the Recovery Act in 2009. My administration is working with the oversight community to help put in place tools to prevent fraud in areas like small business loans and unemployment insurance.  With a Chief Pandemic Prosecutor now in place, the Department of Justice will escalate our efforts to crack down on bad actors — and take all efforts to seize relief money stolen from American families, businesses, and schools during the last Administration and deliver it back to the American people.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release: Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/10/press-release-nominations-sent-to-the-senate-9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 21:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48862</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: William Carl Blake, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.  (New Position) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Michael Blecker, of California, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&#160;&#160;(New Position) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;Shereef M. Elnahal, of New Jersey, to be Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>     William Carl Blake, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.  (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Michael Blecker, of California, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&nbsp;&nbsp;(New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Shereef M. Elnahal, of New Jersey, to be Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs, vice David J. Shulkin.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Christina Orzada Hill, of Georgia, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&nbsp;&nbsp;(New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Joyce M. Johnson, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&nbsp;&nbsp;(New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Rita M. Landgraf, of Delaware, to be Assistant Secretary for Aging, Department of Health and Human Services, vice Lance Allen Robertson.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Lucretia Maria McClenney, of Virginia, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&nbsp;&nbsp;(New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Patrick J. Murphy, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&nbsp;&nbsp;(New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Jose R. Ramos, of Texas, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&nbsp;&nbsp;(New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Roselyn Tso, of Oregon, to be Director of the Indian Health Service, Department of Health and Human Services, for the term of four years, vice Michael D. Weahkee.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Jonathan Woodson, of Massachusetts, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&nbsp;&nbsp;(New Position)</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Designation of the State of Qatar as a Major Non-NATO&#160;Ally</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/10/memorandum-on-the-designation-of-the-state-of-qatar-as-a-major-non-nato-ally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 21:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48857</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Presidential DeterminationNo.        2022-10 MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE SUBJECT:       Designation of the State of Qatar as a               Major Non-NATO Ally  By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and by section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-right"> Presidential Determination<br>No.        2022-10</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE<br><br>SUBJECT:       Designation of the State of Qatar as a<br>                            Major Non-NATO Ally <br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and by section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k) (the &#8220;Act&#8221;), I hereby designate the State of Qatar as a major Non-NATO Ally of the United States for the purposes of the Act and the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 <em>et seq</em>.). <br><br>You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register</em>. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and Prime Minister Trudeau of Canada Before Bilateral&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/10/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-prime-minister-trudeau-of-canada-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 19:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48847</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Warsaw Marriott HotelWarsaw, Poland 6:48 P.M. CET VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&#160; Mr. Prime Minister, it&#8217;s good to see you.&#160; And as part of the strong, enduring, lasting, and deep friendship between the United States and Canada, we find ourselves by coincidence, or maybe fate, to be here in Warsaw at the same time, with the same&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Warsaw Marriott Hotel<br><em>Warsaw, Poland</em></em></p>



<p>6:48 P.M. CET<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Mr. Prime Minister, it&#8217;s good to see you.&nbsp; And as part of the strong, enduring, lasting, and deep friendship between the United States and Canada, we find ourselves by coincidence, or maybe fate, to be here in Warsaw at the same time, with the same purpose, which is to continually reaffirm the strength of the NATO Alliance and our two countries&#8217; commitment, in that regard, to Ukraine &#8212; the people of Ukraine &#8212; and, as we are here in Warsaw, also the people of Poland.<br><br>And so, it is good to see you.&nbsp; We have many things to discuss &#8212; in particular, what we can continue to do together to strengthen our assistance in terms of security assistance, humanitarian assistance to the people of Ukraine, what we can continue to do to coordinate and collaborate within the NATO Alliance and with our EU partners in terms of the ongoing needs and the dynamic nature of what we are presented with in terms of this crisis.<br><br>I know we stand in solidarity in terms of our outrage at this war and the aggression that Russia has taken against Ukraine, unprovoked, unjustified.&nbsp; And we value, of course, the territorial integrity and sovereignty of Ukraine and look forward to continuing our partnership in that regard.&nbsp;<br><br>So, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>PRIME MINISTER TRUDEAU:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Madam Vice President. &nbsp;It&#8217;s a real pleasure to see you again and to see us once again standing so strongly, side to side, on issues that matter so deeply.&nbsp;<br><br>You, yourself, and the Biden administration, and President Biden particularly, have been so strong on this issue, coordinating likeminded countries over the past week to prepare for this possibility of the unthinkable &#8212; of Russia invading Ukraine.&nbsp; And so, when it did, the kind of alignment, the kind of strength of unity that we&#8217;ve shown, I think, has really made a difference.&nbsp;<br><br>First of all, Vladimir Putin totally underestimated the strength and resolve of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; But he also underestimated the strength and resolve of democracies to stand up in support of Ukraine but in support of those values and principles that underlie everything we do.&nbsp;<br><br>So, from crippling sanctions on Putin and his top supporters, to unprecedented humanitarian aid, to security and military support for Ukrainians who are fighting not just for Ukraine but for all of us, we continue to stand shoulder-to-shoulder and will continue to.<br><br>We also have lots of other things to discuss.&nbsp; But obviously, the priority that brings us both to Warsaw is our standing with Ukrainians and all Eastern Europeans as we reinforce the eastern flank of NATO and continue to do the work that matters in the world.<br><br>END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 6:52 P.M. CET<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
