<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 21:11:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the North&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-north-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 21:11:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55438</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the <em>Federal Register</em> for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to North Korea that was declared in Executive Order 13466 of June 26, 2008, expanded in scope in Executive Order 13551 of August 30, 2010, addressed further in Executive Order 13570 of April 18, 2011, further expanded in scope in Executive Order 13687 of January 2, 2015, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13722 of March 15, 2016, and Executive Order 13810 of September 20, 2017, is to continue in effect beyond June 26, 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The existence and risk of the proliferation of weapons-usable fissile material on the Korean Peninsula; the actions and&nbsp;policies of the Government of North Korea that destabilize the Korean Peninsula and imperil United States Armed Forces, allies, and trading partners in the region, including its pursuit of nuclear and missile programs; and other provocative, destabilizing, and repressive actions and policies of the Government of North Korea, continue to constitute an unusual and&nbsp;extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States. &nbsp;</p>



<p>For this reason, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 with respect to North Korea.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 13, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to North&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/13/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-north-korea-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 21:11:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55439</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 26, 2008, by Executive Order 13466, the President declared a national emergency with respect to North Korea pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United&#160;States constituted by the existence and risk&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On June 26, 2008, by Executive Order 13466, the President declared a national emergency with respect to North Korea pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq.</em>) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United&nbsp;States constituted by the existence and risk of the proliferation of weapons-usable fissile material on the Korean Peninsula.&nbsp; The President also found that it was necessary to maintain certain restrictions with respect to North&nbsp;Korea that would otherwise have been lifted pursuant to&nbsp;Proclamation 8271 of June 26, 2008, which terminated the exercise of authorities under the Trading With the Enemy Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. App. 1<em> et seq.</em>) with respect to North Korea.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On August 30, 2010, the President signed Executive Order 13551, which expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States posed by the continued actions and policies of the Government of North Korea, manifested by its unprovoked attack that resulted in the sinking of the Republic of Korea Navy ship <em>Cheonan</em> and the deaths of 46 sailors in March&nbsp;2010; its announced test of a nuclear device and its missile launches in 2009; its actions in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718 and 1874, including the procurement of luxury goods; and its illicit and deceptive activities in international markets through which it obtains financial and other support, including money laundering, the counterfeiting of goods and currency, bulk cash smuggling, and narcotics trafficking, which destabilize the Korean Peninsula and imperil United States Armed Forces, allies, and trading partners in the region.</p>



<p>On April 18, 2011, the President signed Executive Order 13570 to take additional steps to address the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 and expanded in Executive Order 13551 that would ensure implementation of the import restrictions contained in United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718 and 1874 and complement the import restrictions provided for in the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 <em>et</em><em>seq</em>.).</p>



<p>On January 2, 2015, the President signed Executive Order 13687 to expand the scope of, and to take further steps with respect to, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, as expanded in Executive Order 13551, and addressed further in Executive Order 13570, to address the threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United&nbsp;States constituted by the provocative, destabilizing, and&nbsp;repressive actions and policies of the Government of North Korea, including its destructive, coercive cyber-related actions during November and December 2014, actions in violation of United Nations Security Council Resolutions 1718, 1874, 2087, and 2094, and commission of serious human rights abuses.</p>



<p>On March 15, 2016, the President signed Executive Order 13722 to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, as modified in scope and relied upon for additional steps in subsequent Executive Orders, to address the Government of North Korea&#8217;s continuing pursuit of its nuclear and missile programs, as evidenced by its February 7, 2016, launch using ballistic missile technology and its January 6, 2016, nuclear test in violation of its obligations pursuant to numerous United Nations Security Council resolutions and in contravention of its commitments under the September 19, 2005, Joint Statement of the Six-Party Talks, that increasingly imperils the United States and its allies.</p>



<p>On September 20, 2017, the President signed Executive Order&nbsp;13810 to take further steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, as modified in&nbsp;scope and relied upon for additional steps in subsequent Executive Orders, to address the provocative, destabilizing, and&nbsp;repressive actions and policies of the Government of North&nbsp;Korea, including its intercontinental ballistic missile launches&nbsp;of July 3 and July 28, 2017, and its nuclear test of&nbsp;September&nbsp;2, 2017; its commission of serious human rights abuses; and its use of funds generated through international trade to support its nuclear and missile programs and weapons proliferation.</p>



<p>The existence and risk of the proliferation of weapons-usable fissile material on the Korean Peninsula and the actions and policies of the Government of North Korea continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466, expanded in scope in Executive Order 13551, addressed further in Executive Order 13570, further expanded in scope in Executive Order 13687, and under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13722 and Executive Order 13810, must&nbsp;continue in effect beyond June 26, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13466 with respect to North Korea.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register</em> and transmitted to the Congress.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 13, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Message to the Congress on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Western&#160;Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/a-message-to-the-congress-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-western-balkans/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55434</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES: Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the&#160;Federal Register&#160;and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>TO THE CONGRESS OF THE UNITED STATES:<br><br>Section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)) provides for the automatic termination of a national emergency unless, within 90 days prior to the anniversary date of its declaration, the President publishes in the&nbsp;<em>Federal Register</em>&nbsp;and transmits to the Congress a notice stating that the emergency is to continue in effect beyond the anniversary date.&nbsp; In accordance with this provision, I have sent to the&nbsp;<em>Federal&nbsp;Register</em>&nbsp;for publication the enclosed notice stating that the national emergency with respect to the Western Balkans that was declared in Executive Order 13219 of June 26, 2001, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13304 of May 28, 2003, and which was expanded in scope in Executive Order 14033 of June 8, 2021, is to continue in effect beyond June 26, 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The acts of extremist violence and obstructionist activity, and the situation in the Western Balkans, which stymies progress toward effective and democratic governance and full integration into transatlantic institutions, outlined in these Executive Orders, continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.  Therefore, I have determined that it is necessary to continue the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13219 with respect to the Western Balkans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 13, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Notice on the Continuation of the National Emergency with Respect to the Western&#160;Balkans</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/13/notice-on-the-continuation-of-the-national-emergency-with-respect-to-the-western-balkans-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 21:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55432</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 26, 2001, by Executive Order 13219, the President declared a national emergency with respect to the Western Balkans pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On June 26, 2001, by Executive Order 13219, the President declared a national emergency with respect to the Western Balkans pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.) to deal with the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States constituted by the actions of persons engaged in, or assisting, sponsoring, or supporting, (i) extremist violence in the former Republic of Macedonia (what is now the Republic of North Macedonia) and elsewhere in the Western Balkans region, or (ii) acts obstructing implementation of the Dayton Accords in Bosnia or United Nations Security Council Resolution 1244 of June 10, 1999, in Kosovo.&nbsp; The President subsequently amended that order in Executive Order 13304 of May 28, 2003, to take additional steps with respect to certain actions that obstruct implementation of, among other things, the Ohrid Framework Agreement of 2001 relating to Macedonia (what is now the Republic of North Macedonia).</p>



<p>On June 8, 2021, I signed Executive Order 14033, which expanded the scope of the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13219, as amended, finding that the situation in the territory of the former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia and the Republic of Albania (the Western Balkans), over the past two decades, including the undermining of post-war agreements and institutions following the breakup of the former Socialist Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, as well as widespread corruption within various governments and institutions in the Western Balkans, stymies progress toward effective and democratic governance and full integration into transatlantic institutions, and thereby constitutes an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.<br>The actions of persons threatening the peace and international stabilization efforts in the Western Balkans, including acts of extremist violence and obstructionist activity, and the situation in the Western Balkans, which stymies progress toward effective and democratic governance and full integration into transatlantic institutions, continue to pose an unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.&nbsp; For this reason, the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13219, under which additional steps were taken in Executive Order 13304, and which was expanded in scope in Executive Order 14033, must continue in effect beyond June&nbsp;26, 2022.&nbsp; Therefore, in accordance with section 202(d) of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1622(d)), I am continuing for 1 year the national emergency declared in Executive Order 13219 with respect to the Western Balkans.</p>



<p>This notice shall be published in the <em>Federal Register </em>and transmitted to the Congress.              </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR. </p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,<br>June 13, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris at Signing of H.R. 3525, the “Commission To Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture&#160;Act”</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/13/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-at-signing-of-h-r-3525-the-commission-to-study-the-potential-creation-of-a-national-museum-of-asian-pacific-american-history-and-culture/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 20:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:21 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Please have a seat.&#160; Good afternoon, everyone. President Biden, Speaker Pelosi, members of Congress, and my fellow Americans: It is an honor to be gathered with you today and to be joined by so many former colleagues from the Congressional Asian Pacific American&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>2:21 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Please have a seat.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.<br><br>President Biden, Speaker Pelosi, members of Congress, and my fellow Americans: It is an honor to be gathered with you today and to be joined by so many former colleagues from the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus.&nbsp; In particular, Congresswoman Grace Meng, you did so much to make this day possible.&nbsp; Thank you for that.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>So when my mother was 19 years old, she came to the United States from India to become a breast cancer researcher.&nbsp; Growing up, my mother made sure that my sister Maya and I learned of the important, glorious history of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders in America.&nbsp; Because that, of course, is part of the history of America.<br><br>To teach this history is to help all of us as Americans understand where we come from.&nbsp; And to teach this history is to help us understand who we are.&nbsp;<br><br>The National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture will teach and tell the story of our country.&nbsp; This is a story about heroes who shaped our nation for the better, from the South Asian Americans who helped transform farming up and down the Pacific coast, to the Japanese Americans who defended our freedom during World War Two, to the Chinese American garment workers who marched through the streets of New York City 40 years ago to win better pay and benefits for all workers.<br><br>This is also a story about some of our country&#8217;s darkest moments: the Chinese Exclusion Act, the internment of Japanese Americans, the murder of Vincent Chin, discrimination against South Asian Americans after 9/11, and today&#8217;s epidemic of hate, which is fueling violent acts against many communities including the AA and NHPI community.<br><br>Because, you see, this is also American history, and we must teach it as it really happened so that we can learn from our best moments and learn from our darkest moments, and in particular, then, to ensure they are never repeated, our darkest moments.&nbsp;<br><br>By equipping people with knowledge and historical context, then we can fight ignorance, dispel misinformation, and work toward a future where all people can live without fear and a future where all people &#8212; all people can help write the next chapter of American history.<br><br>With that, it is my great honor to introduce the President of the United States, Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good afternoon, folks.&nbsp; And thank you, Kamala.&nbsp; I think I should just stop right there &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; because if anybody can talk about this, Kamala can, like so many of you in the audience.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, it’s good to see you as well, Doug.&nbsp; Must be hard following this act all the time.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You do it well.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I&#8217;m honored to sign into law something that’s long overdue, and &#8212; the National Museum of Asian and Pacific American History and Culture here in Washington, D.C.&nbsp; You can clap for that because of this lady here.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And I want to thank the many members of Congress who made this possible, especially Grace.&nbsp; Grace, stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, and she started early.&nbsp; She&#8217;s not new to this.&nbsp; I think it was &#8212; the first time you introduced it was 2015.&nbsp; Is that right?&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, you&#8217;re only seven years ahead of everybody else.&nbsp;<br><br>All kidding aside &#8212; and Judy as well is here and Doris Matsui and Speaker Pelosi.&nbsp; And senators who couldn’t be here today because they&#8217;re not in session right now, but they &#8212; including Mazie Hirono and Tammy Duckworth and &#8212; and Chuck Schumer &#8212; all members of the Congressional Pacific &#8212; Asian Pacific American Caucus.&nbsp;<br><br>While this bill was being &#8212; been working its way through the Congress the past decade, its story behind it goes back centuries.&nbsp;<br><br>Throughout our history, beyond what the Vice President pointed out, Asian American, Native Hawaiians, Pacific Islanders have literally shaped the history and the contours of this country.&nbsp;<br><br>As I said last month at Asian History &#8212; Asian American History Month reception in the Rose Garden we had, there&#8217;s no single Asian American, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander identity.&nbsp; The diversity of the cultures is significant.&nbsp; And the breadth of achievement is equally as broad and significant.&nbsp;<br><br>The enrichment of our country has been &#8212; our communities &#8212; not just the country, but down to individual communities &#8212; the impact that the community has had.&nbsp;<br><br>All of it has been defined by who you are and who we are as a nation.&nbsp; And it’s defined us.&nbsp; And all of it is an embodiment of so many of you here today.&nbsp; Leaders in civil rights like Karen <s>Nagasaki</s> [Narasaki] and &#8212; and Karen Korematsu.&nbsp; Where &#8212; where are you?&nbsp; Where are the Karens?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And military men like four-star general Tony Taguba.&nbsp;&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Stand up, will you?&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; He&#8217;s the only one I can say “stand up” to because I&#8217;m still the Commander-in-Chief.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m serious &#8212; you’ve made a hell of a contribution.&nbsp;<br><br>In the arts and sciences, like the father of Erika Mo- &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; Moritsugu.&nbsp; Where &#8212; where is that guy?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Dad, stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Now, I was asked by your daughter not to do that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But how can I not do that?&nbsp; She&#8217;s the one who advises me on all these things.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And too many business and public service people to mention, and so many, so many more.&nbsp;<br><br>And many of you in the audience &#8212; we should go through all the contributions you’ve all made.&nbsp;<br><br>And it’s about time for a national museum to capture the courage, the character, and the imagination.&nbsp; And maybe, from my perspective, looking from a little bit from a distance, is the dreams and the heart and the soul of the generations of our fellow Americans who came before you and all of you.&nbsp; That’s what this law is going to do.&nbsp; That’s what it’s going to do.&nbsp; It going to create a commission that will examine how to make the museum a reality, including whether it should be part of the Smithsonian.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, we did this with the la- &#8212; we did this with other museums as well.&nbsp; This is the process.&nbsp; And the fact of the matter is it’s similar to the process that the African American History and Culture Museum, the Latino History and Culture Museum, and the National Women’s History Museum.&nbsp; Some of you are in both these museums, by the way, you know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And it comes at a critical time &#8212; all kidding aside.&nbsp; It comes at a critical time.<br><br>This year marks one year since the murder of six Asian American women in Atlanta &#8212; a symbol of the anti-Asian hate in America today.&nbsp;<br><br>This year commemorates the 80th anniversary of the incarceration of 120,000 American citizens who were Japanese Americans during World War Two, which included &#8212; if you excuse my reference to two friends &#8212; it included a dear friend who, as a child &#8212; the late Norm Mineta &#8212; who went on to serve &#8212; he was in those camps when he was a child &#8212; went on to serve in the United States Army and in Congress and the Cabinet &#8212; a commemoration at a time where there are those who seek to whitewash the history in our schools, what took place.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think &#8212; excuse again, in Senate language, a point of personal privilege &#8212; I want to thank my dear friend who’s not here, the late Senator Danny Inouye, who taught me so much about so many things.&nbsp; A Japanese American who tried to join &#8212; from Hawaii, but a Japanese American &#8212; who tried to join the military when the war broke out, who had to fight to enlist in the United States military out of high school.&nbsp;<br><br>Danny would recall what his father told him.&nbsp; And I remember Danny telling me &#8212; I had to go back and check this today &#8212; but I remember Danny telling me about this years ago.&nbsp; He said, “America has been…”&nbsp; This is what his dad said.&nbsp;<br>“America has been good to us, Danny.&nbsp; It has given us &#8212; given me two jobs.&nbsp; It has given you and your sisters and brothers an education.&nbsp; We all love this country.&nbsp; Whatever you do, do not dishonor your country.&nbsp; Remember, never dishonor your family.&nbsp; And if you must give your life, do it with honor.”&nbsp; End of quote.<br><br>Danny served in the famed 442nd Regimental Combat Team during World War Two.&nbsp; And, I might add, he earned the Medal of Freedom and he also went on to do so much more.&nbsp;<br><br>I was going to tell a story about he and Bob Dole, but I’m going to take too much time.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; For the 50th anniversary of D-Day, when we &#8212; they both got shot and mortally woun- &#8212; badly wounded on mountaintops &#8212; I was with them both &#8212; on mountaintops in Italy, on the west coast, that were literally, as the crow flies, less than two miles from one another.&nbsp; The same time, same day.&nbsp; Anyway.<br><br>Today, it’s clear that the battle for the soul of America continues.&nbsp; That’s why a museum like this is going to matter so much.&nbsp; Museums of this magnitude and consequence are going to inspire and educate.&nbsp; More than anything else, it’s going to help people see themselves in the story of America &#8212; a story that makes us a better America and it’s made us a better America.<br><br>And that’s why it was so important to me that this administration looks like America &#8212; the people representing them looks like America &#8212; starting with a Vice President, including Cabinet members and the staff at every single level.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s important to sign this bill with all of you here and &#8212; who &#8212; and from every walk of life.&nbsp; You represent every aspect of American life, many of whom will likely be celebrated in this museum as well.<br><br>Let me close with this: Maya Lin, born in Ohio and the daughter of Chinese immigrants and the architect of the Vietnam Memorial on the Mall and recipient of the Presidential Medal of Freedom, said, “It’s not a matter of finding an idea but allowing the idea to find you.”&nbsp;<br><br>This mus- &#8212; this museum is going to help the idea find so many American souls &#8212; so many people from around the world who will one day walk in this museum and better understand the idea of America, the only nation &#8212; the only nation, in my view, that can be defined in one single word: possibilities.&nbsp; Possibilities.<br><br>Much earlier, my ancestors came, but your ancestors came.&nbsp; What did they come for?&nbsp; Because they believed there was possibilities here unlike any other nation in the world.&nbsp; Possibilities.&nbsp; And you’ve all proven it.<br><br>And now I’m going to ask Speaker Pelosi, Grace, Judy, and the other members of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus to join me on stage while I sign this bill into law.&nbsp;<br><br>And I look forward, one day, to visiting the National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture with all of you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>(Walks to the signing desk.)<br><br>Now, I don&#8217;t know why they do this, but they only give me one pen.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I used to stand in absolute awe and watch Barack Obama sign with seven, eight, nine different pens “Barack Obama.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m in awe.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m going to give this pen to Grace, and all of you will get a pen.<br><br>(The bill is signed.)&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>2:35 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;3525</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/13/bill-signed-h-r-3525/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 19:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, June 13, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 3525, the &#8220;Commission To Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Act,&#8221; which establishes a Commission to Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture in Washington, D.C. Thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, June 13, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 3525, the &#8220;Commission To Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Act,&#8221; which establishes a Commission to Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Meng, Chu, and Matsui, and Senators Duckworth and Hirono, as well as the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus, for their work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Politburo Member Yang&#160;Jiechi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-politburo-member-yang-jiechi-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 18:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi in Luxembourg. This meeting, which followed their May 18 phone call, included candid, substantive, and productive discussion of a number of regional and global security issues, as well as key&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi in Luxembourg. This meeting, which followed their May 18 phone call, included candid, substantive, and productive discussion of a number of regional and global security issues, as well as key issues in U.S.-China relations. Mr. Sullivan underscored the importance of maintaining open lines of communication to manage competition between our two countries.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REMARKS BY VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS AT THE 2022 CAPITAL PRIDE&#160;PARADE</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/12/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-south-carolina-democratic-party-blue-palmetto-dinner/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 17:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pennsylvania AvenueWashington, D.C.  6:09 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Happy Pride, everyone!  (Applause.)  Oh, what a glorious day.  &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Listen, we have so much to celebrate, and we celebrate each other every day.&#160; We celebrate the progress we have made.&#160; And we celebrate the fact that we are in this to stand for what we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Pennsylvania Avenue<br>Washington, D.C.</em> </p>



<p>6:09 P.M. EDT</p>



<p> THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Happy Pride, everyone!  (Applause.)  Oh, what a glorious day. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Listen, we have so much to celebrate, and we celebrate each other every day.&nbsp; We celebrate the progress we have made.&nbsp; And we celebrate the fact that we are in this to stand for what we stand for and fight for what we stand for.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because no one should fear going to a nightclub for fear that a terrorist might try to take them down.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No one should fear going to a Pride celebration because of a white supremacist.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No one should fear loving who they love.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our children in Texas and Florida should not fear who they are.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Black and brown and women of color, transgender women should not fear for their lives.&nbsp; (Applause.) We should not have to be dealing with 300 laws in states around our country that are attacking our LGBTQ+ brothers and sisters.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So we know what we stand for and, therefore, we know what we will fight for.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we will do what we have always done in this movement, in this community, which is, collectively, we will continue to build unity.&nbsp; We will continue to build coalition.&nbsp; We will always be fueled by knowing we have so much more in common than what separates us.&nbsp; We will be fueled by saying, “No one should be made to fight alone.”&nbsp; We will be fueled by knowing we are all in this together.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we will fight with pride.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Happy Pride, everyone.  Happy Pride. </p>



<p>END       6:12 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Bipartisan Senate Gun Safety&#160;Proposal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/12/statement-by-president-biden-on-bipartisan-senate-gun-safety-proposal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 15:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I want to thank Senator Chris Murphy and the members of his bipartisan group—especially Senators Cornyn, Sinema, and Tillis—for their tireless work to produce this proposal. Obviously, it does not do everything that I think is needed, but it reflects important steps in the right direction, and would be the most significant gun safety legislation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I want to thank Senator Chris Murphy and the members of his bipartisan group—especially Senators Cornyn, Sinema, and Tillis—for their tireless work to produce this proposal. Obviously, it does not do everything that I think is needed, but it reflects important steps in the right direction, and would be the most significant gun safety legislation to pass Congress in decades. With bipartisan support, there are no excuses for delay, and no reason why it should not quickly move through the Senate and the House. Each day that passes, more children are killed in this country: the sooner it comes to my desk, the sooner I can sign it, and the sooner we can use these measures to save lives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Air Force One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/12/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 15:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles International AirportLos Angeles, California 10:26 A.M. PDT Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, do you have a m- &#8212; do you have a message for those marching for their lives today in Washington on gun safety? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Sorry, I didn&#8217;t hear what you said. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Do you have a message for those at the March&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles International Airport<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>10:26 A.M. PDT</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you have a m- &#8212; do you have a message for those marching for their lives today in Washington on gun safety?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sorry, I didn&#8217;t hear what you said.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a message for those at the March For Our Lives for gun safety today in Washington?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Keep marching.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important.&nbsp; Look, this has to become an election issue.&nbsp; The way people listen &#8212; senators, congressmen &#8212; is when people say, “I&#8217;m going to &#8212; this is going to affect my vote.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Too many people are dying needlessly.&nbsp; And what &#8212; and what&#8217;s even being proposed in the House and Senate is marginal. I mean, it’s &#8212; it’s important, but it&#8217;s not all that needs to be done.&nbsp; The idea we&#8217;re not going to do background checks, the idea we&#8217;re not &#8212; anyway, the answer: march.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you gotten an update from Senator Murphy or any of the negotiators about where their talks stand?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, they&#8217;re still mildly optimistic.&nbsp; I spoke with Murphy several times.&nbsp; I spoke with him yesterday as well &#8212; yesterday afternoon.&nbsp; And so &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about New Mexico, sir?&nbsp; They want you &#8212; the government to pay for all of the bills that they have from fighting this fire because it was started by the Forest Service. Are you willing to commit that?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t commit that on my own.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what&#8217;s being proposed by &#8212; in the Congress.&nbsp; And I support what they&#8217;re doing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You support doing that?&nbsp; You support doing that?&nbsp; You actually &#8212; you said that Congress support &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I support it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you decided, sir, whether to go to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; Not yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What would be the &#8212; holding up the decision at this point?&nbsp; Are there commitments you&#8217;re waiting for from the Saudis or &#8212; on the negotiations over peace talks?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; The commitments from the Saudis don&#8217;t relate to anything having to do with energy.&nbsp; It happens to be a larger meeting taking place in Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the reason I&#8217;m going.&nbsp; And it has to do with national security for them &#8212; for Israelis.&nbsp; I have a program &#8212; anyway.&nbsp; It has to do with much larger issues than having to do with the energy piece.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The average price of gas nationally today hit $5 a gallon for the first time.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your message to the American people, especially as we head into the summer months, who are really struggling with this?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; This is &#8212; it’s outrageous what the war in &#8212; in Ukraine is causing.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re trying very hard to make sure that we can &#8212; we&#8217;ve significantly increased the number of barrels of oil that are being pumped out of the &#8212; the reserve we have.&nbsp; We got 240,000 barrels as well coming from other nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to keep pushing on it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to keep pushing.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>10:28 A.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
