<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 14:39:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President Biden Establishes the White House Initiative on Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/28/fact-sheet-president-biden-establishes-the-white-house-initiative-on-asian-americans-native-hawaiians-and-pacific-islanders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18571</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden will sign an Executive Order establishing the White House Initiative on Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders, and delivering on the President’s commitment to reinstate and reinvigorate this historic Initiative. Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA and NHPI) communities together constitute the fastest growing ethnic group in the United&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden will sign an Executive Order establishing the White House Initiative on Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders, and delivering on the President’s commitment to reinstate and reinvigorate this historic Initiative.</p>



<p>Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander (AA and NHPI) communities together constitute the fastest growing ethnic group in the United States and make invaluable contributions to our society, our economy, and our culture. Yet for far too long, systemic barriers to equity, justice, and opportunity have put the American dream out of reach for many AA and NHPI communities, and racism, nativism, and xenophobia against AA and NHPI communities continues to threaten safety and dignity of AA and NHPI families. The new Initiative is charged with driving an ambitious, whole-of-government agenda to advance equity, justice, and opportunity for AA and NHPI communities by:</p>



<ul><li>Helping to coordinate a comprehensive Federal response to the rise in acts of anti-Asian bias and violence</li><li>Addressing the systemic lack of disaggregated data on AA and NHPI communities in Federal statistical systems</li><li>Expanding language access and language assistance programs for AA and NHPI individuals across federal programs</li><li>Strengthening economic security and opportunity for AA and NHPI communities by empowering AA and NHPI entrepreneurs, building new workforce training opportunities, and promoting workplaces that are free from harassment against AA and NHPI workers</li><li>Addressing the concentration of poverty experienced in many AA and NHPI communities</li><li>Addressing disparities in educational outcomes for AA and NHPI students of all ages, and addressing bullying, harassment, and discrimination in our Nation’s schools</li><li>Advancing climate and environmental justice for AA and NHPI communities who are particularly impacted by the climate crisis and are overburdened by environmental degradation</li><li>Promoting inclusion and belonging for all AA and NHPI communities by strengthening public awareness and education about AA and NHPI communities, cultures, and traditions</li><li>Empowering AA and NHPI communities to be civically engaged, including through electoral participation</li><li>Building a Federal workforce where AA and NHPI public servants are leaders at the most senior levels of our government</li><li>Ensuring that AA and NHPI communities are empowered and equitably served by Federal funding, grants, and contracts</li></ul>



<p>The COVID-19 pandemic, and the xenophobic rhetoric used by certain political leaders during this crisis, have led to a tragic spike in acts of anti-Asian bias, violence, and xenophobia. At the same time, the pandemic has disproportionately burdened many AA and NHPI communities, and exposed the significant health inequities faced by many Native Hawaiians and Pacific Islanders in particular. To ensure that the Federal government is mitigating COVID-19 related anti-Asian bias, advancing health equity for all AA and NHPI communities, and ensuring AA and NHPI communities can equitably recover from these crises, the Initiative will be led out of the Department of Health and Human Services.</p>



<p>Today, President Biden also announced that Krystal Ka’ai has been selected to serve as Executive Director of the Initiative. Krystal has served as the Executive Director of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus (CAPAC) since 2013, leading legislative, communications, and outreach strategy for a bicameral caucus composed of more than 70 members in both the U.S. House of Representatives and U.S. Senate. She worked to advanced key priorities impacting the AAPI community, including health care, immigration, education, civil rights, economic development, and more. She previously served in various roles with the U.S. Senate Committee on Indian Affairs and the State of Hawai‘i.</p>



<p>In addition, the Executive Order establishes a renewed Presidential Advisory Commission on Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders. The Commission will advise the President on ways the public, private and non-profit sectors can work together to advance equity and opportunity for every AA and NHPI community. The Commission is also charged with advising the President on policies to address anti-Asian xenophobia and violence, ways to build capacity in AA and NHPI communities through federal grantmaking, and policies to address the intersectional barriers that AA and NHPI women, LGBTQ+ people, and people with disabilities face. The Commission will include AA and NHPI civic leaders from across the country, and will reflect the rich diversity of AA and NHPI communities throughout the United States.</p>



<p>These announcements build on the Biden-Harris Administration’s historic actions to combat bias, violence, and xenophobia against AA and NHPI communities, including:</p>



<p><strong>Signing the COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act into law. </strong>On May 20, 2021, President Biden signed into law the COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act, bipartisan legislation that will make significant improvements to our Nation’s response to hate crimes. The bill addresses two challenges: the lack of resources and training for state and local law enforcement to accurately identify and report hate crimes to the FBI, and the language and cultural barriers that many communities of color face in reporting hate crimes to law enforcement.</p>



<p>The COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act will strengthen the Federal coordination and response to hate crime incidents, especially those that victimize Asian American communities, by appointing a designated official at the Department of Justice whose sole job is to facilitate the expedited review of hate crimes related to COVID-19. The Department of Justice will also issue new guidance for state, city, and Tribal law enforcement agencies on how to establish online reporting of hate crimes. The law will provide resources to create specialized hate crimes units that will also help states create hotlines for hate crimes at state and local levels that will be accessible for people with limited English proficiency. And it provides resources for training for state and local law enforcement to identify, investigate, and report these heinous crimes.</p>



<p><strong>Signing a Presidential Memorandum Condemning and Combating Racism, Xenophobia, and Intolerance Against Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders in the United States. </strong>In his first week in office, President Biden signed a Memorandum which established that it is the official policy of the Biden-Harris Administration to stand up against racism, xenophobia, nativism, and bias. The Memorandum directs all Federal agencies to take steps to ensure their official actions mitigate anti-Asian bias and xenophobia, especially in the Nation’s response to the COVID-19 pandemic. The Memorandum also charged the Department of Justice with partnering with AA and NHPI communities to respond to and prevent hate crimes and violence.</p>



<p><strong>Advancing equity and racial justice for AA and </strong><strong>NHPI</strong><strong> communities through the whole-of-government initiative. </strong>On his first day in office, President Biden signed a historic Executive Order establishing a whole-of-government initiative to advance equity and racial justice and root out systemic racism from federal policies, programs, institutions and laws. Under this Executive Order, all Federal agencies are charged with affirmatively advancing equity, civil rights, racial justice, and equal opportunity for the American people, including AA and NHPI communities.</p>



<p><strong>Appointing a White House Senior Liaison to Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander communities. </strong>President Biden announced the appointment of Erika L. Moritsugu to serve as Deputy Assistant to the President and Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Senior Liaison. Moritsugu serves as a vital voice to advance the President and the Administration’s priorities.</p>



<p><strong>Creating a historically diverse Administration in which 15 percent of all appointees identify as Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders. </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration reflects the diversity of the American people, and 15 percent of the Administration’s appointees identify as AAPI.</p>



<p><strong>Funding critical research to prevent and address bias and xenophobia against Asian American communities.</strong> The National Science Foundation (NSF) is taking a comprehensive approach to investing in research to understand, address, and end bias, discrimination and xenophobia, including against AAPI communities. NSF is currently supporting more than 100 grants across the country totaling more than $33 million dollars of investment. This wide array of researchers is advancing innovative studies to reveal new and more effective strategies for reducing the frequency and severity of discrimination experienced by historically underrepresented groups, and reduce targeting of, and violence towards, historically underrepresented communities and individuals, including Asian American communities.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden on the Economy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/27/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-economy-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 03:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18581</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cuyahoga Community CollegeCleveland, Ohio 2:23 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, all.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Please, please, please, please sit down. Shilaah, thank you very much for sharing your story; it&#8217;s impressive.&#160; Dr. Johnson, everyone at Cuyahoga Community College, thank you for being here and having me here.&#160; And, by the way, to all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Cuyahoga Community College<br>Cleveland, Ohio</p>



<p>2:23 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, all.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Please, please, please, please sit down.</p>



<p>Shilaah, thank you very much for sharing your story; it&#8217;s impressive.&nbsp; Dr. Johnson, everyone at Cuyahoga Community College, thank you for being here and having me here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, to all the elected officials: You know what we call this in my business?&nbsp; We call this a “busman&#8217;s holiday” &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to have to come and ride a bus again with another guy.&nbsp; You&#8217;re awful nice to be here.&nbsp; The only thing worse for an elected official when the President shows up is to say &#8212; the worst sentence in the English language is, “I&#8217;m at the airport.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And so &#8212; so &#8212; thank you all so much.</p>



<p>You got some really great friends here, starting with Marcy.&nbsp; Anyway, Mr. Mayor, thank you.&nbsp; Dr. Johnson, thank you very much and &#8212; for letting me borrow, by the way, Marcia Fudge to serve as Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, certain places, just by chance and circumstance, can become markers in the course of your life or of a na- &#8212; of the course of the nation.&nbsp; And for me, Tri-C is one of those places.</p>



<p>Just a little over a year ago, March 10, 220- &#8212; in 2020, I came to Cleveland as a candidate running for President to rally &#8212; hold a rally here at the community college.&nbsp; Upon unloading, we got word that Governor DeWine &#8212; he did the right thing &#8212; wanted large indoor events to shut down because of the growing concerns over the virus and &#8212; spreading all across America.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There would be no rally that night, and life in America had changed.&nbsp; And a long, dark year was about to descend upon all of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fourteen months later, we finally made it to campus.&nbsp; And from a year of darkness, we&#8217;re now emerging into the light.&nbsp; And I said from the very beginning: There&#8217;s no chance &#8212; no chance for this economy to come back unless we beat the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I remember Congressman Ryan and I talking about that a lot on the campaign trail.&nbsp; You had to beat the pandemic to bring the economy back.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s what we set out to do with the help of a lot of the people that are right here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And after administering 271 million doses of vaccine in the first 120 days &#8212; and we have &#8212; the cases are down now from January from &#8212; they’re down 83 percent &#8212; COVID cases &#8212; down.&nbsp; The number of deaths has fallen by 85 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Schools are reopening.&nbsp; Businesses are reopening.&nbsp; Restaurants are reopening.&nbsp; I hear that, as last night&#8217;s vaccine lottery, Ohio has a new millionaire.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I tell you what: Who woulda thunk it?&nbsp; A million bucks for getting the vaccine.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But it&#8217;s working.</p>



<p>Now, 56 percent of Ohioans have had at least one shot.&nbsp; We got to get to 70 percent.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the goal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve turned the tide on the once-in-a-century pandemic.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve turned the tide on a once-in-a-generation economic crisis.&nbsp; And families are beginning to be able to breathe just a little bit easier.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We still have work to do, but our future today is as bright and as wide open as it ever has been.&nbsp; And now we&#8217;re faced with a question: What kind of economy are we going to build for tomorrow?&nbsp; What are we going to do?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I believe this is our moment to rebuild an economy from the bottom up and the middle out, not a trickle-down economy from the very wealthy.&nbsp; That has never benefited people who are at this college or any other place where they&#8217;re trying to make a living.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To build an economy that rewards work, not just wealth.&nbsp; An economy that works for the backbone of this country &#8212; the people who get up every single day, work hard, raise their families, pay their taxes, serve their country, volunteer in their communities &#8212; just looking for a little bit of breathing room.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My dad used to say, “Just a little bit of breathing room, honey.”&nbsp; And Tim has heard me say this a thousand times &#8212; my dad used to say, “Joey, a job is about a lot more than a paycheck.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about your dignity.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about respect.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about your place in the community.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about being able to look your kid in the eye and say, ‘Honey, it&#8217;s going to be okay.’”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last few months have demonstrated what that economy can look like.&nbsp; When &#8212; when our event here was canceled in March, our economy was on the brink of collapse.&nbsp; My mom used to have &#8212; especially say, “You know, the greatest gift God gave mankind was the ability forget.&nbsp; Because if it didn&#8217;t do that, every woman would only have one child.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, the good news is we forget the bad times.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the good thing about we Americans: We’re always optimistic.&nbsp; But 10 months &#8212; 10 months ago, we were in trouble.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I was sworn in, there were 10 million fewer jobs in America, and a lot here in Ohio.&nbsp; But in my first three months in office, the economy has added back 500,000 jobs per month.&nbsp; In fact, we&#8217;ve created &#8212; with the help, again, of the members of Congress that are here today &#8212; 1.5 million jobs, more jobs than have ever been created in the first three months of any presidency in the history United States.</p>



<p>Before I took office, the average initial claims for unemployment insurance were over 830,000.&nbsp; This morning, we learned that number has fallen below 460,000 &#8212; cut in half the &#8212; and we&#8217;re at the lowest level we&#8217;ve seen since March 2020 when the pandemic first struck.</p>



<p>Before I took office, almost 24 million Americans were going hungry.&nbsp; Marcy has heard me say this before: Did you ever think you&#8217;d see people lined up for miles and miles and miles,&nbsp; going into a stadium to get someone to put a box of food in their trunk?&nbsp; People who never ever, ever, ever, ever, ever, ever thought they’d need that kind of help.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, that number of hungry Americans &#8212; food-starved Americans &#8212; has dropped by 30 percent.&nbsp; Still too many, but there&#8217;s clear progress.</p>



<p>Before I took office, independent experts were projecting that our economy would grow at 3 to 4 percent in the year 2021.&nbsp; But they’re now projecting that growth will be 6 percent or higher in 2021 &#8212; the fastest growth in this country in 40 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To sum it up: COVID cases are down, COVID deaths are down, unemployment filings are down, hunger is down, vaccinations are up, jobs are up, growth is up, people gaining health coverage is up, small business confidence is up.&nbsp; Put it simply: America is coming back.&nbsp; America is on the move.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And that wasn&#8217;t an accident.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t luck.&nbsp; It happened for two reasons.&nbsp; First, we made the vaccine program a priority.&nbsp; As my friends in Congress will tell you, I got a lot of heat for just focusing on the vaccine.&nbsp; It goes back to what we all talk about.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got to fix the pandemic before you can fix the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We were able to, with a lot of hard work, get 600 million doses of the vaccine &#8212; enough for every single solitary American.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We didn&#8217;t have enough vaccinators, so we went to FEMA, the United States military, went to the AMA and got retired docs and nurses to come out of retirement &#8212; got thousands and thousands of additional people to administer the vaccines that we didn&#8217;t have before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We created more places to get vaccinated, hitting my target to ensure that 90 percent of all Americans would have a vaccination site within five miles of where they live.&nbsp; And now, 50 percent of all of America &#8212; more than any other country &#8212; is fully vaccinated.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Seventy-five &#8212; seventy-five percent of seniors &#8212; Black, white, Hispanic &#8212; across the board are fully vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re getting lives back.&nbsp; The American economy is coming back.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the second reason we&#8217;re on the move.&nbsp; I committed to an approach of building an American economy, a re- &#8212; a different economy to build back better, not just build back &#8212; build back better.&nbsp; That approach recognizes that we do &#8212; all do better when we all do well.&nbsp; And the best way to grow our economy is from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I don&#8217;t have any anything against &#8212; against anybody in Wall Street.&nbsp; I don’t have anything against anybody making a million bucks, but Wall Street did not build this country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; The middle class built this country, and unions built the middle class.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; That&#8217;s a fact.&nbsp;</p>



<p>An approach that recognizes that this time when we rebuild the middle class, we have to bring everybody along, regardless of their background, regardless of their religion, regardless of their race.&nbsp; That’s the approach reflected in the American Rescue Plan, which my friends in the Congress helped get passed.</p>



<p>Because of that law, more than 167 million Americans got a rescue payment of $1,400 that’s gone out helping families pay their rent, pay their bills, buy their groceries &#8212; and maybe most important, gives them, for the first time, some hope &#8212; a little bit of hope.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hope goes a long, long, long way.&nbsp; Those checks matter. Small businesses, restaurants are getting &#8212; were getting killed.&nbsp; Now we’re delivering the loans and support they need to reopen and stay open.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Schools were struggling to reopen, so we made targeting vac- &#8212; teachers to get the vaccine as a priority.&nbsp; We delivered schools much-needed support.&nbsp; State and local governments &#8212; and you know, Mr. Mayor &#8212; a lot of them had to lay off their employees &#8212; cops, firefighters, first responders &#8212; because you have to balance your budget.</p>



<p>Well, now they&#8217;re coming back, thanks to the Rescue Plan. Beginning this summer, families with children will get tax relief &#8212; tax credit &#8212; the Child Tax Credit &#8212; which is going to deposit money directly into their banks every month until that money is paid out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, we had no problem passing a $2 trillion tax plan that went to the top 1 percent that wasn&#8217;t paid for at all; it just increased the debt $2 trillion.&nbsp; Every time I talk about tax cuts for working-class people, it’s, “Oh my god.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; “What are we going to do?”&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re going to take back some of that 1 percent money and make them pay for it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And thanks in part to a part of the Rescue Plan named for an Ohio labor leader, Butch Lewis, championed by Sherrod Brown, who &#8212; I don&#8217;t think Sherrod is here today &#8212; hundreds of thousands of retirees and workers across Ohio and millions more across the country can trust that their pensions they work so damn hard for and sacrificed to secure will be there for them, unlike my dad who busted his neck his whole life, and when the company went under, he lost his pension completely.</p>



<p>Even my Republican friends in Congress, not a single one of them voted for the Rescue Plan.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to embarrass any one of them, but I have here a list &#8212; (laughter and applause) &#8212; of how, back in their districts, they&#8217;re bragging about the Rescue Plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They touted the re- &#8212; the Restaurant Revitalization Fund.&nbsp; They touted the fact that we&#8217;re in a situation where the &#8212; dealing with &#8212; touted grants to community healthcare centers, touted &#8212; I mean, some people have no shame.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I&#8217;m happy.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy they know that it’s benefited their constituents.&nbsp; That&#8217;s okay with me.&nbsp; But if you&#8217;re going to try to take credit for what you&#8217;ve done, don&#8217;t get in the way of what we still need to do.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The bottom line &#8212; the bottom line is this: The Biden economic plan is working.&nbsp; We’ve had record job creation.&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing record economic growth.&nbsp; We&#8217;re creating a new paradigm &#8212; one that rewards work, the working people in this nation, not just those at the top.</p>



<p>We did a study: 85 percent of my Jobs Plan &#8212; or 95 percent of my Jobs Plan, you don&#8217;t need a bachelor&#8217;s degree; 75 percent, you don&#8217;t even need a degree that&#8217;s a community college degree &#8212; it helps, but guess what?&nbsp; The bottom line is that people are going to be going back to work.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a new bargain: Everyone is &#8212; is going to be in on the deal this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, as our economy recovers, there&#8217;s going to be some bumps in the road; we know that &#8212; of course there will be.&nbsp; You can&#8217;t reboot a global economy like flipping on a light switch.&nbsp; There&#8217;s going to be ups and downs in jobs and economic reports.&nbsp; There&#8217;s going to be supply chain issues, price distortions on the way back to a stable and steady growth.</p>



<p>In the coming weeks, my administration will take steps to combat these supply pressures, starting with the construction materials and transportation bottlenecks, and building off the work we&#8217;re doing on computer chips.&nbsp; We&#8217;re also announcing new initiatives to combat anti-competitive practices that hurt small businesses and families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fixing those problems can help build a more dynamic, innovative economy, and we&#8217;re going to have a lot more to say about that in the days ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But this &#8212; this is already clear: We&#8217;re on the right track.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan laid a strong foundation for a new economy that brings everybody along, but it&#8217;s just a first step.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to build on the incentive and incredible progress that we&#8217;ve made and set America on a sustainable path to a faster, more inclusive economic growth.&nbsp; We have to start investing in ourselves again and the American people again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Consider this: Three decades ago, the United States was number one &#8212; and some would argue number two &#8212; in the world for R&amp;D spending &#8212; research and development &#8212; as a share of our economy.&nbsp; You know where we are now in the international competition?&nbsp; We’re number nine.&nbsp; Nine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Meanwhile, China was number eight in their overall spending in research and development three decades ago; they&#8217;re now number two.&nbsp; Number two.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This past year, Japan, Canada, Italy, France, and the EU have announced significant infrastructure spending.&nbsp; China has announced that they&#8217;re increasing their research and development spending dramatically.&nbsp; Japan is making huge investments in reducing carbon emissions and building out the digital capacity they have.&nbsp; The &#8212; the European Union as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re in a race to see who wins the 21st century.&nbsp; Now if I could hold just for a second here &#8212; one of the things I&#8217;ve found &#8212; I&#8217;ve s- &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m supposedly &#8212; they&#8217;d always announce me in the past as an expert in foreign policy.&nbsp; Well, let me tell you something: Economic policy is harder than foreign policy.&nbsp; You know what the basis of foreign policy is in our stature in the world?&nbsp; One thing: our economic prowess.&nbsp; Our economic prowess.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We must be number one in the world to lead the world in the 21st century.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a simple proposition.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the starting gun has already gone off.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t afford to fall any further behind.&nbsp; Now is the time to build the foundation that we&#8217;ve laid &#8212; to make bold investments in our families, in our communities, in our nation.&nbsp; We know from history that these kinds of investments raise both the floor and the ceiling of the economy for everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like, when we brought electricity to every household in the country in 1930s or we connected the country through the Interstate Highway System in the ’50s.&nbsp; They created millions of jobs, good-paying jobs.&nbsp; They set the economy up to grow more quickly and share prosperity more broadly for decades to come.&nbsp; Those electrical poles and wires still help power rural communities 80 years after they were built, and it&#8217;s time now to rebuild them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A quarter of all the miles Americans travel on roads are on the Interstate Highway System built 60 years ago &#8212; 60 years after we build it.&nbsp; These are generational investments.&nbsp; Private sector does not make these kind of investments.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve neglected that kind of public investment for much too long.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The pandemic exposed just how badly we need to invest in the foundation of this country and the working people of this country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I proposed the American Jobs Plan and the American&#8217;s Family Plan &#8212; the generational investments we need today to succeed for tomorrow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, as my wife Jill, who’s been a teacher for a long time &#8212; she used to be about 10 years younger than me; now she&#8217;s 30 years younger than me &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and she is in every way, God love her.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; She&#8217;s the only First Lady ever to work full time &#8212; full time.&nbsp; She teaches 15 credits at a community college &#8212; 15 credits.&nbsp; She&#8217;s a remarkable person. &nbsp;And she&#8217;s out in Missouri right now and Kansas [City] doing other things &#8212; nothing to do with her job as a teacher.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my point is this, Jill has a constant refrain: “Joey, any nation that out-educates us is going to outcompete us.”&nbsp; It’s a simple proposition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, think about this: One of the reasons that &#8212; that caused us to move ahead so significantly as a world leader &#8212; an economic leader in the world was that in the late 1800s, early 1900s, we were the first nation in the world to say, “We&#8217;re going to have 12 years of free &#8212; without any limitation &#8212; free education.&nbsp; Twelve years.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now imagine if &#8212; and the rest of the world has caught up with us, and they&#8217;ve now passed us in many cases.&nbsp; Imagine if we were sitting today and say, &#8220;We&#8217;re going to set up an education system.&#8221;&nbsp; Does anybody think 12 years of education is enough for us to compete in the world in the second quarter of the 21st century?&nbsp; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; Just &#8212; just consciously think about that.&nbsp; Is it enough?&nbsp; It&#8217;s not.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I&#8217;m proposing four additional years of education: two years of high-quality pre-K for three- and four-years-old &#8212; not in daycare, in school.&nbsp; The studies show that if you do that, those children have an opportunity of 56 better &#8212; 56 percent better chance of going through all 12 years of school and beyond without getting into any trouble, no matter what the background or the family they come from.&nbsp; No matter what.&nbsp; On the front end, those two years are important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then two years of free community college.&nbsp; Free community college &#8212; (applause) &#8212; to better prepare our people to get these good-paying jobs of the future &#8212; jobs I saw students training for throughout the Manufacturing Technology Center.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we need to invest in transportation infrastructure.&nbsp; Drive anywhere and you can see why we&#8217;re rated 13th in the world in infrastructure.&nbsp; The United States of America is viewed to have the 13th-best infrastructure in the world.&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; This United States of America, for God&#8217;s sake.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need to invest in universal high-speed Internet, more seamlessly connect our businesses and their customers, expand the possibilities of job opportunities in every hometown in America, no matter how big or small.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, if you&#8217;ll hold for a second &#8212; think about this.&nbsp; How many of you men and women have children who were doing remote learning?&nbsp; Think of all the children throughout the country, in inner cities and in rural areas, that had no Internet connection.&nbsp; It&#8217;s estimated that some of those kids are going to be pushed &#8212; although it&#8217;s only been one year &#8212; three years behind in their education.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, investment in high-growth industries like clean energy and electric vehicles &#8212; it&#8217;s not just we want to deal with the environment.&nbsp; We want to lead the world in exports of these new technologies instead of ceding the global market and job creation to the Chinese.&nbsp; They&#8217;re building 20 times as many electric vehicles as we&#8217;re doing now, and the technology that goes with that.&nbsp; What are we doing?&nbsp; It&#8217;s millions of jobs in China instead of here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not that it&#8217;s the jobs we&#8217;re going to create here, but that we&#8217;re going to create to the export the technology.&nbsp; We used to be the net exporter of major technologies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also think and am pushing very hard to make major investments in medicines and cures of the future.&nbsp; Folks, diseases like Alzheimer&#8217;s, diabetes, cancer &#8212; they&#8217;re all on the cusp of being able to be dealt with.&nbsp; You know, if we don&#8217;t do something about Alzheimer&#8217;s in America, every single, solitary hospital bed that exists in America &#8212; as the nurses can tell you &#8212; every single one will be occupied in the next 15 years with an Alzheimer&#8217;s patient &#8212; every one &#8212; costing us in excess of a trillion dollars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So what are we doing?&nbsp; I came up with an idea, and I think is going to get done.&nbsp; And that is that &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a thing called DARPA, which is the Defense Applied Application Research &#8212; it&#8217;s an outfit that came up with the Internet in the Defense Department, it came up with geospacing and a whole range of things that are related to our security.&nbsp; I want to do the same thing at the NIH to focus on those diseases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s estimated if we do spend &#8212; if we spend $5 billion a year on that research and development, focusing with &#8212; on insurance companies can&#8217;t &#8212; don&#8217;t have the money to focus on &#8211;we can make significant breakthroughs.&nbsp; We&#8217;re already doing that &#8212; already doing that.</p>



<p>If we invest, we can create millions of jobs rebuilding the foundation of a strong, fair, resilient, competitive economy, and save hundreds of thousands of lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And 100 percent of our investment is going to be guided by one principle: Make it in America.&nbsp; Make it in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>If I can hold that for just a second, there is a law that was passed in the &#8217;30s &#8212; doesn&#8217;t violate any trade principle &#8212; saying that whatever money &#8212; that whatever program that taxpayers are paying for, you can spend it all on American contractors.&nbsp; No one&#8217;s ever done it &#8212; though, I promise you, I signed an executive order.&nbsp; If in fact we&#8217;re building the new deck of an aircraft carrier &#8212; well, guess what? &#8212; I get, as President, to make &#8212; let contracts for over $600 billion a year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I promise you, there&#8217;ll be no contract let to a foreign company or any of the product down the line.&nbsp; Right now, what can happen is you can hire an American company and they can sublet to &#8212; and they can &#8212; their downstream product can all be foreign.&nbsp; All you got to do is get that particular agency to say, &#8220;You got an exception.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t find that job here in America.&#8221;</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to find the job here in America, I promise you, or they&#8217;re not going to get the contracts.&nbsp; These jobs will be good jobs &#8212; American jobs that deliver good wages and dignity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And look, this is about choice.&nbsp; We can give &#8212; we can keep giving every break in the world to corporations and CEOs, or we can raise the corporate tax rate back to 28 percent.&nbsp; It was, by the way, 36 percent.&nbsp; It came down to 28 percent, which is still lower than it was at any point between World War One and 2017, and they&#8217;re making trillions of dollars.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m going to tell you this to the press again: In the 10-year period between &#8217;14 and &#8217;24 &#8212; excuse me, between &#8217;10 and &#8217;20 &#8212; 2010 and 2020, they made over a trillion dollars.&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s good.&nbsp; You know what they did with a trillion dollars?&nbsp; They went out and they bought back 56 percent of their stock.&nbsp; Because the more they buy back, the more valuable the stock, and that&#8217;s how CEOs get paid.</p>



<p>CEOs used to get paid 35, 36 times to the average employee, and they should get paid.&nbsp; Now it&#8217;s over 370 times more than the average employee.&nbsp; As my mother would say, &#8220;Who died and left them boss?&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious about it.</p>



<p>Now &#8212; so you got over 50 percent going to stock buybacks.&nbsp; And the other percent &#8212; I think it&#8217;s 42 percent &#8212; you get &#8212; let me see, 56 &#8212; it&#8217;s 40 &#8212; no, it&#8217;s 38 percent goes to dividends, which is reasonable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the point.&nbsp; After all is said and done, that leaves 8 percent of that trillion dollars for research and development, salaries, new product, new enterprises, new initiatives &#8212; 8 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I come from the corporate capital of the world, literally.&nbsp; More corporations are incorporated in the state of Delaware than in any place in America combined &#8212; all the rest of the corporate registrations combined don&#8217;t equal what&#8217;s in my state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It used to be corporations felt they had responsibilities beyond their taxpayer &#8212; beyond their shareholders and beyond their executives.&nbsp; But what is it now?&nbsp; The average CEO becomes a CEO for six to seven years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by the way, capitalism has incentives.&nbsp; One of the worst votes ever made was during the Carter &#8212; the Clinton administration, to say a corporation could not deduct in tax &#8212; deduct from their taxes more than a million dollars of pay for any CEO.&nbsp; So guess what they start doing?&nbsp; Eighty-some percent of CEOs now get paid in stock options.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why do you think they buy back the stock?&nbsp; To raise the price in &#8212; of the stock.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not bad guys.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just the incentives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So if we just raised the corporate tax to 28 percent, which is still lower than where it was, as I said, between World War One and 2017, that generates 90 billion additional dollars into the Treasury for a year, per year.&nbsp; That could put hundreds of thousands of people to work to modernize our roads, our bridges, our ports, our airports, and pay for it &#8212; pay for it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Put people to work to make sure every American has access to high-speed Internet so businesses can compete in the 21st century, kids in every community can get ahead.&nbsp; Another choice.</p>



<p>We can ask the top 1 percent of the taxpayers in America to get &#8212; pay the same tax rate they paid when George W. Bush was President.&nbsp; You know how much that would generate?&nbsp; That would generate $13 billion per year, allowing every student in America to go to community college for free.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I was in the last administration that I was part of &#8212; Obama-Biden &#8212; the President asked me to find out what the major corporate entities thought was the most important thing they needed.&nbsp; We interviewed over 340 &#8212; I think it was 348 CEOs.&nbsp; You know what they said &#8212; everyone of them?&nbsp; A better-educated workforce.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But they&#8217;re not spending money to educate the workforce, so imagine what we’d do &#8212; corporate America benefits with a better-educated population.&nbsp; Do you want to give the wealthiest people in America another tax cut?&nbsp; I &#8212; by the way, I don&#8217;t begrudge them the money they made, just start paying your fair share, just a little bit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In consequence, it would help every high school graduate earn an education like students here at Tri-C, one that puts people on a path to good-paying jobs in industries of the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I know &#8212; I know you know what&#8217;s best for America.&nbsp; And by the way, better-educated public helps everybody.&nbsp; Look, my plan is &#8212; my plan is the right way to invest, spreading key investments over time so we limit the price pressure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is the right time to invest when we have historically low interest rates, investing now with a plan to pay for it.&nbsp; That is the fiscally responsible thing to do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, there are critics out there who want to stand still.&nbsp; By the way, some of those critics are the same people who said that money was no object when it came, as I said, to that $2 trillion tax cut that went to the wealthiest 1 percent of America, who hold 30 percent of all the wealth in the country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But when we need to fix a road or a water system, or help millions of people return to the workforce by helping them afford childcare or eldercare, or help afford &#8212; attend &#8212; the ability to attend Tri-C, they think that&#8217;s &#8212; that&#8217;s a bridge too far.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Investing in America again is going to create growth and more jobs, but there&#8217;s something else we have to do to ensure the high-quality jobs exist.&nbsp; We must restore the connection between the success of our economy and the people who produce that success &#8212; hardworking Americans.&nbsp; The connection has been severed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You all remember &#8212; it used to be the case in this country when you were a part of generating success of a company, you got to share in the benefits.&nbsp; That&#8217;s long since gone &#8212; not a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by the way, I &#8212; I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; But here&#8217;s the deal: From 1948 after the war, to 1977 &#8212; I think it was 1977 &#8212; ’79 &#8212; productivity in America grew by 100 percent.&nbsp; We made more things &#8212; productivity.&nbsp; You know what the workers’ pay grew?&nbsp; By 100 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since 1979, all that changed.&nbsp; Produc- &#8212; productivity has grown four times faster than pay has grown.&nbsp; The basic bargain in this country has been broken.&nbsp; If you work hard and contribute to the success of enterprise, you get to share in the success &#8212; that&#8217;s not the case anymore &#8212; so you could carve out your place in the middle class.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s how it happens.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how it works in healthy capitalist economies.&nbsp; But along the way, we started seeing the stock market and corporate profits and executive pay as the sole measure of our economic success.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me tell you something.&nbsp; My sole measure of economic success is how working families are doing, whether they have jobs that deliver dignity.&nbsp; That means we have to focus on wages like we used to.</p>



<p>When it comes to the economy we&#8217;re building, rising wages aren&#8217;t a bug; they&#8217;re a feature.&nbsp; We want to get &#8212; we want to get something economists call “full employment.”&nbsp; Instead of workers competing with each other for jobs that are scarce, we want employees to compete with each other to attract work.&nbsp; We want the &#8212; the companies to compete to attract workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That kind of competition in the market doesn&#8217;t just give workers more ability to earn a higher wage, it gives them the power to demand to be treated with dignity and respect in the workplace.&nbsp; And it helps ensure that America &#8212; when you walk into work, you don&#8217;t have to check your right to be treated with respect at the door.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Full employment” also means more options and opportunities for workers &#8212; including Black, Hispanic workers, Amer- &#8212; Asian American workers, women &#8212; who&#8217;ve been left behind in previous economic recoveries when the labor market never tighten- &#8212; tightened up enough.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, this isn&#8217;t just good for individual workers, it also makes our economy a whole lot stronger.&nbsp; When American workers have more money to spend, American businesses benefit.&nbsp; We all benefit.&nbsp; Higher wages and more options for workers are a good thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A lot of companies have done extremely well in this crisis, and good for them.&nbsp; Good for them.&nbsp; The simple fact is, though, corporate profits are the highest they&#8217;ve been in decades, and workers’ pay is at the lowest it has been in 70 years.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have more than ample room to raise workers pay without raising customer prices.&nbsp; Soaring corporate profits and stagnant wages aren&#8217;t the American Dream, and they aren&#8217;t the American deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, I&#8217;m not looking to punish anyone or to say business shouldn&#8217;t be able to make a significant profit.&nbsp; I understand the risk and challenges businessowners face, and they should be rewarded for the success and the risks they take.&nbsp; I just think, after decades of workers getting a raw deal, it&#8217;s time they be given a fair shake.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Well, wait until you see what happens when employers have to compete for workers.&nbsp; Companies like McDonald&#8217;s, Home Depot, Bank of America, and others &#8212; what do they have to do?&nbsp; They have to raise wages to attract workers.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the way it&#8217;s supposed to be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we got to do two more things.&nbsp; Congress should raise the minimum wage to $15 an hour.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No one &#8212; no one should work 40 hours a week and live in poverty, live below the poverty level.&nbsp; And we ought to pass the Protect the Right to Organize &#8212; the PRO Act &#8212; supported by union workers.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, let me close with this.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s an overused phrase these days, but it&#8217;s still accurate: We’re at an inflection point in American history.&nbsp; It happens every several generations.&nbsp; We have a chance to seize the economic momentum of the first months of my administration not just to build back, but to build back better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this time, we&#8217;re going to deal everyone in &#8212; everyone that has been left out &#8212; and breathe new life into the middle class and new hope into those struggling to break into the middle class.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have a chance to make investments that Moody&#8217;s &#8212; not a liberal think tank &#8212; Wall Street, Moody&#8217;s &#8212; says my plan will increase the size of our economy by $4.5 trillion &#8212; Moody&#8217;s &#8212;&nbsp; $4.5 trillion over the next decade, and create well over 16 million new good-paying jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If we make these investments now, in 50 years, people are going to look back &#8212; and not even that long &#8212; your children or grandchildren will look back and say this was the moment when America won the future.&nbsp; Won the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, I’ve said it a thousand times &#8212; I mean it from the bottom of my heart: There is not a single thing America can&#8217;t do when we do it together.&nbsp; Never.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the only country in the world that has &#8212; when we set our mind to something, that has never ever, ever, ever failed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is an opportunity for the wealthy to stay wealthy, the poor to have a shot at the middle class, and the middle class to be able to breathe more easily.&nbsp; That’s what this is about.&nbsp; But this time, bring everybody along &#8212; everybody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>3:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Minister of External Affairs Subrahmanyam Jaishankar of India</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/27/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-minister-of-external-affairs-subrahmanyam-jaishankar-of-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:52:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Minister of External Affairs Subrahmanyam Jaishankar of India to review the strong partnership between the world’s largest democracies.&#160; They welcomed cooperation in recent weeks that resulted in deliveries of over $500 million in COVID-19 relief supplies from the U.S. federal and state governments, U.S. companies, and from&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Minister of External Affairs Subrahmanyam Jaishankar of India to review the strong partnership between the world’s largest democracies.&nbsp; They welcomed cooperation in recent weeks that resulted in deliveries of over $500 million in COVID-19 relief supplies from the U.S. federal and state governments, U.S. companies, and from private citizens across America for the people of India.&nbsp; They discussed a range of regional and global issues, and agreed the United States and India should continue working closely together to address common challenges throughout the Indo-Pacific region. &nbsp;They agreed that people-to-people ties and shared values are the foundation of the U.S.-India strategic partnership that is helping to end the pandemic, supporting a free and open Indo-Pacific, and providing global leadership on climate change.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/27/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18561</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Sarah Bianchi, of Virginia, to be Deputy United States Trade Representative (Asia, Africa, Investment, Services, Textiles, and Industrial Competitiveness), with the rank of Ambassador, vice Jeffrey Gerrish. &#160; &#160; &#160;Elizabeth Merrill Brown, of Maryland, to be General Counsel, Department of Education, vice Carlos G. Muniz, resigned. &#160; &#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Sarah Bianchi, of Virginia, to be Deputy United States Trade Representative (Asia, Africa, Investment, Services, Textiles, and Industrial Competitiveness), with the rank of Ambassador, vice Jeffrey Gerrish.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Elizabeth Merrill Brown, of Maryland, to be General Counsel, Department of Education, vice Carlos G. Muniz, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Brian Eddie Nelson, of California, to be Under Secretary for Terrorism and Financial Crimes, vice Sigal Mandelker, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Matthew G. Olsen, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Attorney General, vice John C. Demers.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Elizabeth Rosenberg, of Vermont, to be Assistant Secretary for Terrorist Financing, Department of the Treasury, vice Marshall Billingslea.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Arun Venkataraman, of the District of Columbia, to be Assistant Secretary of Commerce and Director General of the United States and Foreign Commercial Service, vice Ian Paul Steff.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Gwynne A. Wilcox, of New York, to be a Member of the National Labor Relations Board for the term of five years expiring August 27, 2023, vice Mark Gaston Pearce, term expired.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center is-style-default">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Vice President Harris Launches a Call to Action to the Private Sector to Deepen Investment in the Northern Triangle</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/27/fact-sheet-vice-president-harris-launches-a-call-to-action-to-the-private-sector-to-deepen-investment-in-the-northern-triangle/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18541</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[12 companies and organizations announce commitments to support economic development in the Northern Triangle, as part of the Call to Action launch In her role overseeing diplomatic efforts within El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras (the “Northern Triangle”), and with Mexico, Vice President Kamala Harris announced today a Call to Action for businesses and social enterprises to make&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>12 companies and organizations announce commitments to support economic development in the Northern Triangle, as part of the Call to Action launch</em></strong></p>



<p>In her role overseeing diplomatic efforts within El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras (the “Northern Triangle”), and with Mexico, Vice President Kamala Harris announced today a <em>Call to Action</em> for businesses and social enterprises to make new, significant commitments to help send a signal of hope to the people of the region and sustainably address the root causes of migration by promoting economic opportunity.<a> </a>As part of this <em>Call to Action</em> launch, 12 companies and organizations announced commitments to support inclusive economic development in the Northern Triangle, including: Accion, Bancolombia, Chobani, Davivienda, Duolingo, the Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health, Mastercard, Microsoft, Nespresso, Pro Mujer, the Tent Partnership for Refugees, and the World Economic Forum.</p>



<p>Our comprehensive strategy to address the root causes of migration will involve significant commitments of U.S. government resources to support the long-term development of the region—including efforts to foster economic opportunity, strengthen governance, combat corruption, and improve security. This approach will leverage commitments and resources from the governments in the Northern Triangle, as well as partnerships with multilateral development banks and international financial institutions.</p>



<p>Supporting the long-term development of the region, and in the Western Hemisphere more broadly, will require more than just the resources of the U.S. government. For this reason, Vice President Harris is calling on the private sector to draw on its unique resources and expertise to make commitments to support inclusive economic growth in the Northern Triangle<a>. </a>Together, we can work to overcome obstacles to investment, promote economic opportunity, and support long-term development in the region.  The Administration looks forward to increased collaboration with private companies—U.S., foreign, and local in the Northern Triangle and Latin America more broadly—to build upon this <em>Call to Action </em>in the months and years to come. </p>



<p><strong>U.S. Government Long-Term Commitments and <em>Call to Action</em> Focus Areas</strong></p>



<p>This <em>Call to Action</em> is one component under the U.S. government’s comprehensive, long-term strategy to address barriers to investment and to promote economic opportunity in the Northern Triangle. Just as government action alone will not be enough to achieve meaningful outcomes, private sector commitments will be facilitated and supported by strong U.S. government initiatives to address longstanding impediments to investment-led growth. Under our broader strategy, near-term private sector commitments will be mutually reinforced by sustained U.S. government efforts to foster a business-enabling environment, increased private sector investment, and sustainable economic growth and opportunity. As part of the broader strategy, this&nbsp;<em>Call to Action&nbsp;</em>aims to generate new commitments from businesses and social enterprises in six focus areas with an emphasis on supporting vulnerable populations, including women and youth, in the Northern Triangle region. These focus areas include:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Reform Agenda – </strong>Commitments to support greater transparency, predictability, and stability in the business enabling environment by facilitating regional government efforts to adopt international best practices in licensing, permitting, procurement, regulation, and taxation.<br></li><li><strong>Digital and Financial Inclusion –</strong> Commitments to expand affordable internet access and participation in the digital economy; facilitate access to financial technologies and capital for small businesses, particularly women- and indigenous-owned businesses; and ensure that the most vulnerable and the most likely to migrate have access to basic public services and financial institutions.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Food Security and Climate-smart Agriculture</strong> <strong>–</strong> Commitments to combat food shortages by increasing agricultural productivity and crop resilience.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Climate Adaptation and Clean Energy – </strong>Commitments to support the region’s resilience to climate change through adaptation and mitigation efforts; support industries impacted by climate change; and transition to clean energy.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Education and Workforce Development </strong>– Commitments to expand job-training programs; support greater access to technical and secondary education; and create higher paying formal sector jobs, especially for women and in rural areas.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Public Health Access </strong>– Commitments to support regional governments in addressing the impact of COVID-19 on their populations; build robust and resilient health economies to confront future health challenges; support access to clean water and sanitation; and ensure inclusive access to healthcare.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>How to Join the Call</strong></p>



<p>The State Department, in coordination with the <a href="https://www.centampartnership.org/">Partnership for Central America</a>, will manage follow-up to this <em>Call to Action, </em>which will involve:</p>



<ul><li>Connecting businesses with relevant U.S. interagency partners, such as the U.S. Agency for International Development, U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, Department of Commerce, Department of Labor, among others; non-governmental organizations (NGOs); multilateral development banks; UN agencies, other international organizations; and relevant government officials from the region to facilitate potential new partnerships and commitments;</li><li>Coordinating private sector partners to ensure sustained progress through strategic and high-impact initiatives aligned to social impact goals, and facilitating joint ventures between new and existing partners across global public, private, and social sectors;</li><li>Offering feedback on potential private sector initiatives, based on an assessment of potential migrants’ needs in the region;</li><li>Working with partner governments and institutions to promote reforms that address impediments to investment and foster a business-enabling environment;</li><li>Establishing metrics to measure the impact of commitments made in response to the&nbsp;<em>Call to Action</em>, to track program effectiveness and identify key trends across key economic and social impact metrics; and</li><li>Convening public forums and facilitating discussions on challenges, trends, and progress toward aspired social impact goals.</li></ul>



<p>The <a href="https://www.centampartnership.org/">Partnership for Central America</a> is a non-profit organization that was developed in support of the Vice President’s <em>Call to Action</em>. The Partnership aims to coordinate practical solutions to advance economic opportunity, address urgent climate, education and health challenges, and promote long-term investments and workforce capability in support a vision of hope for Central America.</p>



<p>The Administration and the Partnership welcome additional commitments to join this initiative and promote economic opportunity in the Northern Triangle. <strong><em>Vice President Harris invites </em></strong><strong><em>interested parties to get involved by contacting the State Department Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs at </em></strong><a href="mailto:jointhecall@state.gov"><strong><em>jointhecall@state.gov</em></strong></a><strong><em>. In addition, the Partnership for Central America can be reached at </em></strong><a href="mailto:support@centampartnership.org"><strong><em>support@centampartnership.org</em></strong></a><strong><em>.</em></strong></p>



<p><strong>Founding Participants in the&nbsp;<em>Call to Action</em></strong></p>



<p>The following 12 companies and organizations join the Vice President today in supporting the Administration’s <em>Call to Action</em>. All are also founding members of the Partnership.</p>



<p><em>These companies and organizations put forth summaries of their work to date and new initiatives to invest in the Northern Triangle, as follows:</em></p>



<p><strong><u>Accion</u></strong></p>



<p>Founded in 1961, Accion is a global nonprofit working to advance economic opportunity through microfinance and impact investing. Accion works with financial service providers across Latin America that are expanding the reach, quality, and affordability of financial services for low-income and underserved people. Over the next three years, Accion will provide advice, guidance, and consulting services to organizations that serve micro and&nbsp;small business owners in the Northern Triangle region, ultimately benefitting more than 400,000 people. Accion aims to&nbsp;connect small business owners to new markets and grow their businesses by improving their management, financial, and digital capabilities.&nbsp; Accion will help businesses shift from cash to digital, while expanding local access to finance through branchless banking. The effort aims to reduce barriers that have prevented women from accessing economic opportunities and boost the productivity of small-holder farmers. Accion will enable lenders that already serve the poor to make greater use of technology to reach more clients, supporting them more effectively and with greater security. Ultimately, Accion’s work will empower business owners and their families to recover from the COVID-19 pandemic,&nbsp;as well as build the financial health, resilience, and prosperity sorely needed to address the root causes of migration.</p>



<p><strong><u>Bancolombia</u></strong></p>



<p>Grupo Bancolombia is one of Latin America’s major financial institutions with operations in El Salvador and Guatemala. To further its commitment to sustainable development in Central America, Grupo Bancolombia will commit to expanding its financial inclusion efforts to reach the Northern Triangle’s unbanked and vulnerable populations through digital banking accounts, focusing on remittance-receiving families, women-led businesses and other small enterprises to increase investment and improve living conditions, and strengthen ties to their local communities, adding more than 400,000 new account holders by 2025. As part of this work, Grupo Bancolombia will work with its partners to expand access to credit and connect more than 50,000 small shopkeepers with suppliers, distributors and retail customers.</p>



<p><strong><u>Chobani</u></strong></p>



<p>Chobani’s mission is to make delicious, nutritious, and natural food for all people because access to good food is a right – not a privilege. Chobani will now extend its impact to the Northern Triangle and bring its incubator program to Guatemala, where local food entrepreneurs will get expertise and support to help them set up and scale their operations. Chobani will use knowledge from its global incubator program to determine how to best create and execute a program in Guatemala that will support local startups and contribute to regional economic empowerment. In the U.S., the Chobani Incubator has helped support the growth of 47 different companies in the food and beverage industry since its inception in 2016. Founders are given a monetary grant and have access to resources across the ecosystem, from retailers to investors and everything in between. The Incubator has also run programs internationally in both Australia and Turkey. Each program has its own unique operating model, but all serve Chobani’s mission of bringing better food to more people.</p>



<p><strong><u>Davivienda</u></strong></p>



<p>Davivienda is a multi-national, Colombian bank&nbsp;with a presence in the United States, Honduras, El Salvador, Costa Rica and Panama. To date, Davivienda has worked to expand financial inclusion by expanding its digital payment system, DAVIPLATA, and by increasing access to credit, particularly for women.&nbsp; In Colombia, Davivienda has connected nearly 13 million individuals to its digital services, 5 million of whom were previously unbanked. As part of this <em>Call to Action</em>, in collaboration with public and private sector partners, Davivienda will commit to connecting 1 million unbanked individuals in the Northern Triangle with financial services, including via its DAVIPLATA platform.&nbsp;Davivienda will also commit to contributing $500 million in loans to support low-income housing,&nbsp;small- and medium-sized businesses, renewable energy projects, and women entrepreneurs.</p>



<p><strong><u>Duolingo</u></strong></p>



<p>Duolingo is an education app with over 500 million downloads.&nbsp;In the Northern Triangle, the app is used by over 500,000 people to learn English in order to improve their education and job prospects. Duolingo will commit to ensuring that its content remains free so that everyone has access to high-quality education through mobile devices. The company recently created Duolingo ABC, an app designed to teach early literacy skills to children. In order to reduce high levels of illiteracy in the Northern Triangle, Duolingo will commit to developing Duolingo ABC in Spanish.&nbsp;Duolingo will also commit to providing fee waivers for the Duolingo English Test to high-achieving, low-income students to reduce barriers to higher education. Combined, these efforts will expand access to education in the region through the use of technology, helping to improve people’s livelihoods and prospects for a better future.</p>



<p><strong><u>Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health</u></strong></p>



<p>Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health&nbsp;brings together dedicated experts from multiple disciplines to produce powerful change to improve the lives and health of people around the globe. The Harvard Chan School will commit to adding an evidence-based lens by harnessing scientific data to maximize capacity to measure and report systems-wide impact of the partnership; improve access to health care; and train and enable workers to manage pipeline healthcare issues in the Northern Triangle. Harnessing qualitative and quantitative metrics, the School will provide partners and managers with the means to pilot and scale activities that support data-sharing in order to foster transformative change across all communities, platforms, and sectors.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Mastercard</u></strong></p>



<p>Through its work in financial inclusion, Mastercard has brought over 500 million individuals globally into the digital economy. In collaboration&nbsp;with public and private sector partners, the company&nbsp;aims to&nbsp;bring 5 million people in the Northern Triangle into the financial system and digitalize&nbsp;1 million micro and small businesses,&nbsp;leveraging&nbsp;its&nbsp;innovation and technology&nbsp;to improve access to vital services and drive inclusive economic growth. This includes enabling individuals to pay and get paid digitally, securely, and efficiently, and reaching previously underserved communities with technology that works on mobile phones and in rural, low-connectivity areas. Mastercard can also provide marginalized individuals with access to services like healthcare and agricultural marketplaces, and help small businesses grow with affordable tools and services. With access to financial and digital tools, and the ability to use them, Mastercard can help close the digital divide and improve livelihoods for generations to come.</p>



<p><strong><u>Microsoft</u></strong></p>



<p>Microsoft’s purpose is to ensure that technology helps promote inclusive opportunity, protects fundamental rights, and supports a sustainable future. Microsoft will build on its long-standing presence in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras to bring connectivity, skills, and greater opportunity to their citizens. First, with local partners including Albavision, Microsoft will expand internet access to up to 3 million people in the region by July 2022, as part of the Microsoft Airband Initiative. Microsoft will also expand its work with partner New Sun Road to establish community centers to provide internet, digital skills, devices, educational experiences and mentorship to women and youth in rural and high-migration areas. Second, Microsoft will build on its global skills initiative to provide access to digital skills learning paths to connect people to skills and certifications. Third, Microsoft is investing in technology to increase the transparency and accountability of government spending, and exploring the use of data science to evaluate the efficacy of interventions to address community needs.</p>



<p><strong><u>Nespresso</u></strong></p>



<p>By working directly with over 120,000 coffee farmers in 15 countries, Nespresso, which offers high quality portioned coffee to consumers, unlocks the potential of coffee for producers through its unique sustainable quality coffee sourcing approach by addressing the key social, economic and environmental challenges they face with practical solutions, focusing on improving yields and quality to drive revenues, paying higher prices for high quality coffee and driving activities to improve livelihoods, providing free agronomy support, promoting human rights protection and gender equality, and building resilience to climate change through regenerative agricultural practices and agroforestry. Nespresso is committed to improving livelihoods in the Northern Triangle by expanding its existing sourcing activities in Guatemala, and by starting to source quality coffees from El Salvador and Honduras from this year on, creating new economic opportunities for smallholder farmers and replicating the social and environmental impact of Nespresso’s programs in more communities. The company aims to support the local economy with a minimum of $150 million spent across coffee purchases, price premiums and technical assistance by 2025, more than doubling both the number of coffee farms it works with and total coffee volumes.</p>



<p><strong><u>Pro Mujer</u></strong></p>



<p>For over 30 years, Pro Mujer has been driving inclusive economic opportunities for women in Latin America by providing millions of families with access to finance, healthcare services, entrepreneurship support, and digital inclusion. Pro Mujer will commit to reaching three million people in the Northern&nbsp;Triangle by bringing these services&nbsp;directly, and with the collaboration of local partners, to&nbsp;vulnerable communities, including low income families, rural and indigenous populations.&nbsp;In addition, Pro Mujer will commit&nbsp;to structuring and launching blended finance vehicles that provide capital, technical assistance and capacity building support to micro, small and medium Enterprises (MSMEs) in the Northern Triangle. This critical support to MSMEs and the services Pro Mujer&nbsp;intends to bring to individuals and families will together have a transformative effect on these communities and directly address the root causes of migration from the region.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Tent Partnership for Refugees</u></strong></p>



<p>The Tent Partnership for Refugees mobilizes the business community to improve the lives and livelihoods of refugees displaced from their home countries. Tent pledges to share best practices and lessons learned with the Partnership for Central America from working with its network of over 150 major businesses to implement commitments in support of refugees around the world. In addition, Tent will leverage its business network to raise awareness of the root causes of migration and how companies can help improve conditions in Central America, for example by supporting education outcomes,&nbsp;creating jobs and entrepreneurship opportunities in the region, as well as sourcing more products from the Northern Triangle.</p>



<p><strong><u>World Economic Forum</u></strong></p>



<p>The Forum has been actively engaged in Latin America for decades, developing and supporting the implementation of a strategic agenda to address the region’s most pressing challenges and ensuring a robust participation of leaders in its various projects, activities and events. In response to this <em>Call to Action</em>, the World Economic Forum will convene a network of committed actors over time, with a special focus on the role that long-term, sustainable investment can play in transforming the lives and well-being of citizens throughout the area. To do so, the Forum would facilitate collaboration between governments, civil society, business, development institutions and others, to address the root causes of migration and for the Northern Triangle countries to realize their potential towards sustainable and inclusive growth and for quality job creation. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen Psaki</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/05/27/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-aboard-air-force-one-en-route-cleveland-oh/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 20:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Cleveland, OH 12:39 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Sorry.&#160; Thanks for your patience &#8212; a little business happening on the early part of the flight.&#160;&#160;Okay, welcome to our trip to Cleveland.&#160; Today, the President will deliver a speech on the economy where he will make a clear case that his&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Cleveland, OH</p>



<p>12:39 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; Thanks for your patience &#8212; a little business happening on the early part of the flight.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, welcome to our trip to Cleveland.&nbsp; Today, the President will deliver a speech on the economy where he will make a clear case that his economic plan is working.&nbsp; And he&#8217;ll discuss the economic inflection point we stand at and the opportunity before us.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>His remarks will be, as you all know, at Cuyahogie [sic] Community &#8212; Cuyahoga Community College &#8212; or “Tri-C,” as it is called locally &#8212; the site of the last rally he was scheduled to hold as a candidate in March of 2020 before the pandemic shut down our country.&nbsp; There, he’ll note the remarkable progress we&#8217;ve made in defeating COVID-19.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>During his speech, he will make the case that his economic &#8212; I already conveyed that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today&#8217;s positive GDP report is the latest proof that his policies are healing the economy and getting Americans back to work.&nbsp; We&#8217;re creating an average of 500,000 jobs a month, eight times more than before President Biden took office.&nbsp; And unemploy- &#8212; and unemployment insurance claims &#8212; out this morning &#8212; hit their lowest level since March of 2020.<br>&nbsp;<br>The four-week moving average of unemployment insurance claims has dropped by nearly 50 percent since the President took office.&nbsp; And these weekly numbers can be volatile &#8212; as we know, and we all discuss &#8212; but we&#8217;re encouraged by the fact that the four-week average continues to trend down.<br>&nbsp;<br>In his remarks, he will also make a forceful case that higher wages are good for American workers and good for our economy.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll argue that we need to make our tax code wo- &#8212; work fa- &#8212; work &#8212; ensure our tax code favors work not wealth so big corporations are incentivized to invest in America, not on stock buybacks or CEO pay.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he&#8217;ll talk about the need to make generational investments in our economy &#8212; through the Jobs Plan and the Families Plan &#8212; and advanced manufacturing; two years of community college; roads, bridges, broadband, and a host of other areas that will create good-paying jobs and help us outcompete the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, kick us off.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; The President spoke briefly on the tarmac about the Republican counteroffer on infrastructure.&nbsp; I was hoping you could give a little bit more on that.&nbsp; And to confirm that he&#8217;s going to be with Senator Capito next week, if you could confirm that.&nbsp; And then, also, will he be meeting with the other group &#8212; this bipartisan group &#8212; that includes Senator Romney?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Did a &#8212; did the statement that was out in my name come out before you took off?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I just wanted to absolutely make sure of that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as the President conveyed, and as it was conveyed in my statement earlier today, we are certainly encouraged to see Senator Capito&#8217;s group come forward with the kind of funding level &#8212; nearly $1 trillion &#8212; that they discussed with the President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is a negotiation, so the discussions will be ongoing.&nbsp; And, as he noted on the tarmac, and as you&#8217;ve seen in many &#8212; some of your reporting, there are a number of Republicans who&#8217;ve come forward with ideas who we are open to discussing and continuing to engage with.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In terms of the schedule for next week, it&#8217;s not quite set yet.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working around, of course, the President is going to Tulsa, Oklahoma, and other components of his week.&nbsp; But he will be closely engaged with Senator Capito&#8217;s group and with other groups as they have ideas come forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And obviously, Memorial Day is Monday, so that deadline is going to come and go.&nbsp; How much longer is the White House willing to go for these talks?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I’ll say that the Memorial Day timeline was always an opportunity for us to make an assessment of what the path forward looked like.&nbsp; And now, we&#8217;re look &#8212;&nbsp; we&#8217;re heading into Memorial Day weekend.&nbsp; We have a counteroffer on the table where the number came up significantly from the prior offer, where there was an increase in proposed funding in roads, rails, and bridges.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There are some areas that we would like to see more funding in that we think are essential to the American workforce.&nbsp; So this is a disc- &#8212; discussion and negotiation.<br>&nbsp;<br>As we look ahead, we think &#8212; we look at next week, we know it&#8217;s Memorial Day week; it&#8217;s going to be a work week for us.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be a week where we continue to be engaged with a range of members of Congress.&nbsp; And we look forward to making progress before Congress resumes on June 7th.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last one.&nbsp; COVID relief &#8212; the COVID relief funds, is that a nonstarter using those?&nbsp; Is that a nonstarter?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The &#8212; well, here&#8217;s the &#8212; here is the reason why that would be difficult to be a key funding mechanism: 95 percent of it is already allocated.&nbsp; Five percent of it would go towards some key areas, including boosting up small businesses, restaurants; rebuilding veterans’ hospitals &#8212; something that is of personal importance to the President.&nbsp; We think there are better ways to pay for it, and we think people should have a full understanding of what that is proposing.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You are saying 95 percent of the Rescue Plan is allocated already?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The COVID funds, which, I think, is the same synonym.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right. Right.&nbsp; And can I &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a red line about the care economy?&nbsp; You&#8217;ve made a big deal about including funding for human infrastructure; the Republicans don&#8217;t include that at all in their proposal.&nbsp; So is that a red line for the President?&nbsp; Does that have to be in there, or is there some other way to get that funding through?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not here to set new red lines.&nbsp; What I will &#8212; his only red line is inaction, but he &#8212; that has been included in our counterproposal back, even as we came down $550 billion last week.&nbsp; That shows how much of a priority it is to the President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>This is an ongoing negotiation.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue to have discussions about how to move it forward.&nbsp; There are a range of mechanisms to move ideas forward in Congress, and we&#8217;re open to that as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a particular day where you want to make a call about, you know, giving up on the hope of a bipartisan deal or, you know, wanting to get to one by a particular day?&nbsp; Is there a go/no-go date on the calendar?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Why would we do that now?&nbsp; We have a counterproposal and a range of others who want to have a discussion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m not saying now.&nbsp; But, like, is it two weeks from now?&nbsp; Is it six weeks from now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we &#8212; our focus is on continuing to work on having these discussions and negotiations through the course of next week.&nbsp; Again, it will be active; it will be engaged.&nbsp; We will be working hard.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll be in touch with Republicans and Democrats through the course of the recess week.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll look forward to, when they resume, seeing what our path forward looks like.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But at least Senator Toomey had asked also for an accounting of how the funds &#8212; the American Rescue Plan funds &#8212; have been spent already.&nbsp; Is that something you can or will provide to Capitol Hill?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President has been clear to his team that we should be engaged and be responsive to any follow-up questions members and their teams have.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m certain that will be applicable here.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To the timing &#8212; can we go back to the timing, just to clarify one thing?&nbsp; So, next week is the recess week; the meetings will go on.&nbsp; You mentioned, I think, in your statement June 7th week, which is the following week, as, sort of, a week that the Congress is back to do some work.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, is that &#8212; should we look for some kind of ending point at that point &#8212; that week, at the end of that week?&nbsp; Is there a point that you all are talking about?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s ended when the President signs the legislation into law.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, today, he said to us on the tarmac &#8220;very soon&#8221; &#8212; I think was his phrase.&nbsp; So I was trying to figure out what that meant &#8212; that he was wanting to get something done very soon.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He said &#8220;the summer.&#8221;&nbsp; That&#8217;s very soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a foreign policy question?&nbsp; So Secretary Blinken just wrapped up a trip to Egypt where he met with President Sisi &#8212; talking about Israel and Palestinian conflict, but also the Nile Dam.&nbsp; Was the Nile Dam a negotiation tactic or a bargaining chip to secure Egypt&#8217;s support for the Gaza truce?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It sounds like a question for the State Department given it was the Secretary&#8217;s trip.&nbsp; I would point you to the State Department.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, is the expectation that the White House will offer another counterproposal as these talks continue next week?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think we have to see how the discussions go.&nbsp; As was conveyed in my statement, there were areas where they came up; that&#8217;s encouraging.&nbsp; There are areas where we&#8217;d still like to see increased funding because we think it&#8217;s important to small businesses, to workers, to our clean energy economy.&nbsp; So that gives you a sense of what we&#8217;re looking to see more of.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And can I ask something on gun safety quickly after the San Jose shooting?&nbsp; The administration had mentioned, last month, there were still some executive actions the President was considering on this.&nbsp; Where does that stand?&nbsp; And has anything changed as a result of the mass shooting yesterday in California?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, clearly, every time there&#8217;s a mass shooting &#8212; and certainly the one we saw last night &#8212; it&#8217;s heartbreaking and devastating.&nbsp; And this is an issue that impacts the President personally, and he certainly noted that to all of us yesterday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are continuing to review what additional actions we can take, even while we&#8217;re pressing Congress to move forward with universal background check legislation.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a legal and policy review process for that, so it&#8217;s not that it can be expedited; it&#8217;s ongoing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But it&#8217;s a reminder to everyone &#8212; people who work in government, people in the public &#8212; about the need for additional gun safety measures.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On G7, Jen, can you have &#8212; give us an idea of how the strategy from the Biden administration to shore up other G7 leaders, in terms of creating a global strategy against a pandemic and vaccine sharing &#8212; how is that shaping up now?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say: As you all know, we have announced that we will be donating 80 million doses to the global community.&nbsp; What is happening now behind the scenes is that &#8212; is there is an internal policy process to determine how we can do that in an equitable and transparent way.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know you are all eager to know where they are going and what our process will be.&nbsp; We certainly understand that.&nbsp; We hope to have more soon.&nbsp; That will certainly be a point of discussion, we expect.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly, any questions that come up from our partner countries in the G7 or conversations in NATO about how we can work together to get the pandemic under control, we expect it to be a large topic of conversation at the meetings.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the expectation that the G7 countries will come up with some sort of agreement that, &#8220;This is how we&#8217;re going to help the world in terms of overcoming the pandemic and vaccine sharing&#8221;?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’re a couple of weeks away from the G7 meeting even starting, so I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of any discussions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will the President be meeting with the Queen while he&#8217;s in the United Kingdom?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to announce at this point in time.&nbsp; Who among us wouldn&#8217;t want to meet with the Queen?&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll let them announce any invitation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you, on the G7 summit &#8212; one of the issues is also sort of the shortage of semiconductors.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that &#8212; do you see, like, some movement going forward &#8212; both at the G7 level, but then, you know, in a sort of broader, multilateral group, perhaps?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, also, you are completing the supply-chain review; I think that&#8217;s supposed to be complete next week.&nbsp; Can you say a word or two about that and what your plans are for releasing that?&nbsp; And there&#8217;s four industrial sectors that are being looked at there.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; So, certainly, the semiconductor shortage is something that we do raise with partners and allies around the world.&nbsp; In terms of how it will fall on the agenda, I don&#8217;t have anything to preview on that front.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But as the President has conveyed, as Jake Sullivan has conveyed, as Brian Deese has conveyed, this is a priority.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to help our manufacturing workforce, jobs in the United States, and something that we&#8217;re looking to partners to help address, as, you know, we&#8217;ve seen over the past several weeks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I don’t think I have anything to preview for you in terms of the supply chain review, in terms of what we would put out publicly on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you are &#8212; you are expecting to complete that next week and you will release it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think that&#8217;s the intention, but I don&#8217;t know what format or anything at this point.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can I ask you a question about the &#8212; there is some reporting that the administration plans to lift the restriction on the border with Canada on June 22nd.&nbsp; Can you confirm that?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And a follow-up to that is: Will the United States look at re- &#8212; lifting those together &#8212; so both southern and northern, at the same time?&nbsp; Or is that something that can be done separately?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You mean Title 42 on the border?&nbsp; One, that &#8212; that would be &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s Canadian reporting that says it’s being lifted.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, it was &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The northern border.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It was just extended for about a month, I think, so that&#8217;s around that timeline.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think a decision has been made, that I&#8217;m aware of, about what would happen after that point.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And in terms of the southern border and Title 42, that&#8217;s really ro- &#8212; we rely on the CDC and their guidelines about what we need to do to continue to address the global pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But would one happen over the other?&nbsp; Or would they be simultaneous &#8212; northern and southern?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I &#8212; I don&#8217;t &#8212; I think they assess them differently &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; but I &#8212; I certainly would point you to the CDC and DHS about how make those &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me ask you this question a different way, Jen.&nbsp; I mean the Nile Dam was an issue that President Trump put in &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have anything more for you on this.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the President holding out hope for a bipartisan commission on January 6th, given what we&#8217;re seeing today on Capitol Hill?&nbsp; And are there any Republicans he&#8217;s reached out to personally to try to encourage them to vote for it?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I just talked to the President about a range of things.&nbsp; And certainly, he believes they should continue to move this forward, and he wants to see the commission &#8212; the bipartisan commission &#8212; passed.&nbsp; And he wants to make sure that&#8217;s law because that was a dark day in our history.&nbsp; And he thinks we should not only take a moment to recognize that, but also prevent it from happening ever in the future.<br>&nbsp;<br>Certainly, he&#8217;ll continue to convey that publicly.&nbsp; You know, I also think he recognizes that, you know, some of the people who oppose it aren’t necessarily looking for his point of view, which is very public and well known.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you elaborate what changed &#8212; what changed in terms of the President asking the intelligence agencies to find out the &#8212; just investigate the origins of the coronavirus?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Let me just take you through, quickly, the timeline here.&nbsp; So, back in March, the President asked his intelligence community to do an assessment &#8212; an internal assessment, which you all know happens all the time and he is presented often &#8212; often in PDBs what those assessments look like.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what they did.&nbsp; It was presented to him a couple of weeks ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In that PD- &#8212; or, following that PDB, he made clear &#8212; he asked them to see if we could declassify that information, make it available to the public.&nbsp; They came back just this week with what they would propose to be a public statement.<br>&nbsp;<br>Happening in the backdrop of that, as you all well know, was the World Health Assembly, where the Chinese made clear they were not going to engage constructively in the second stage of this &#8212; this investigation.&nbsp; And he felt that it was important, given a lot of confusion out there, to make public not only what the IC had done, but also to expand the investigation for 90 days, add more components of the federal government, including our national labs and our health and medical expertise.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s exactly what we did.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I would say it was just an &#8212; a process of declassifying and then a decision made to extend the &#8212; extend the investigation.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything you can say on the budget?&nbsp; Is there anything you can say on the budget &#8212; in particular, the topline reported &#8212; there was a $6 trillion topline, I believe.&nbsp; Is that an accurate report?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>AIDE:&nbsp; We&#8217;re about to land.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, let me first say that, one, we&#8217;re going to roll it out tomorrow, so stay tuned.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, two, it&#8217;s important to remember the President inherited $3 trillion of spending that had already been done to help get the pandemic under control.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What the p- &#8212; budget will reflect is that he is going to continue to deliver on his priorities of getting &#8212; doing more work to get the pandemic under control, putting people back to work.&nbsp; And those proposals &#8212; the American Jobs plan, the American Rescue Plan, the American Families Plan &#8212; will put us on better financial footing over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So as you look at all the budget details tomorrow, I think you&#8217;ll have a better assessment.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, will China face consequences if they don&#8217;t cooperate with the COVID origins report?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have 89 days left before we &#8212; this review is completed, and I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re going to make any assessments before that time.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What&#8217;s the President&#8217;s plan for Memorial Day weekend?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We’ll have &#8212; we’ll have more for you on that soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>12:53 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden Before Boarding Air Force One</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/05/27/remarks-by-president-biden-before-boarding-air-force-one-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 17:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Joint Base AndrewsPrince George&#8217;s County, Maryland 11:48 A.M. EDT Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, can you confirm that you’re going to (inaudible) trillion dollar budget? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; I beg your pardon. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Six trillion dollar budget.&#160; Can you confirm the topline number? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, we&#8217;ll confirm that &#8212; that&#8217;ll all be distributed.&#160; And one of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Joint Base Andrews<br>Prince George&#8217;s County, Maryland</p>



<p>11:48 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, can you confirm that you’re going to (inaudible) trillion dollar budget?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I beg your pardon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Six trillion dollar budget.&nbsp; Can you confirm the topline number?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ll confirm that &#8212; that&#8217;ll all be distributed.&nbsp; And one of the things I want to tell you is that I haven&#8217;t had a chance yet to go over the details of the counteroffer made by Capito.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be &#8212; we&#8217;re going to meet sometime next week, and we&#8217;ll see if we can move that.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll have more to say about that at the time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What do you expect to get from your review &#8212; your 90-day review on where the origins of the coronavirus were?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; If I knew that, I wouldn&#8217;t ask for a 90-day review.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you pledge to release it in full?&nbsp; Will you pledge to release the report in full after 90 days?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; unless there&#8217;s something I&#8217;m unaware of.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, what do you think of the proposal?&nbsp; Is the proposal too small for you from the Republicans?&nbsp; What is your thought on it?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I had a good conversation &#8212; very brief, but a good conversation &#8212; with Capito, the senator.&nbsp; And I told her we would &#8212; she&#8217;s going to contact me next week.&nbsp; I told her we have to finish this really soon.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s another Republican group that also wants it (inaudible).</p>



<p>And &#8212; but we&#8217;re going to have to close this down soon.</p>



<p>11:50 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen Psaki on Senate Republicans’ Infrastructure Proposal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/27/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-senate-republicans-infrastructure-proposal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 15:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We are grateful for the work of Senator Capito and her colleagues on this proposal.&#160;It is encouraging to see her group come forward with a substantially increased the funding level—nearing $1 trillion. We appreciate the hard work that went in to making this proposal and continuing these negotiations.&#160;Senator Capito told the President that her team&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We are grateful for the work of Senator Capito and her colleagues on this proposal.&nbsp;It is encouraging to see her group come forward with a substantially increased the funding level—nearing $1 trillion. We appreciate the hard work that went in to making this proposal and continuing these negotiations.&nbsp;Senator Capito told the President that her team would provide us with more details later today, and we look forward to getting that information. At first review, we note several constructive additions to the group’s previous proposals, including on roads, bridges and rail. At the same time, we remain concerned that their plan still provides no substantial new funds for critical job-creating needs, such as fixing our veterans’ hospitals, building modern rail systems, repairing our transit systems, removing&nbsp;dangerous lead pipes, and powering America’s leadership in a job-creating clean energy economy, among other things.&nbsp;Lastly, we are concerned that the proposal on how to pay for the plan remains unclear: we are worried that major cuts in COVID relief funds could imperil pending aid to small businesses, restaurants and rural hospitals using this money to get back on their feet after the crush of the pandemic.</p>



<p>As for the path forward, the President called Senator Capito thank her for the proposal, and to tell her that he would follow-up after getting additional detail. We are also continuing to explore other proposals that we hope will emerge. Though there are no votes in Congress next week, we will work actively with members of the House and Senate next week, so that there is a clear direction on how to advance much needed jobs legislation when Congress resumes legislative business during the week of June 7.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Amends Nebraska Disaster Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/27/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-amends-nebraska-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 14:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the State of Nebraska by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for Public Assistance projects undertaken in the State of Nebraska as a result of a severe winter storm, straight-line winds, and flooding during the period of March 9 to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the State of Nebraska by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for Public Assistance projects undertaken in the State of Nebraska as a result of a severe winter storm, straight-line winds, and flooding during the period of March 9 to July 14, 2019.<br><br>Under the major disaster declaration issued for the State of Nebraska on March 21, 2019, Federal funding was made available for Public Assistance, Hazard Mitigation, and Other Needs Assistance at 75 percent of the total eligible costs.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Under the President&#8217;s order today, the Federal share for Public Assistance has been increased to 90 percent of the total eligible costs.<br><br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Sayyid Munthir of the Omani Royal Office</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/05/26/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-sayyid-munthir-of-the-omani-royal-office/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 02:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=18511</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Sayyid Munthir of the Omani Royal Office to discuss Oman’s unceasing diplomatic efforts to advance a ceasefire in Yemen. They also discussed regional security developments and the longstanding friendship between Oman and the United States. The United States applauds Oman’s critical peacebuilding role in Yemen under Sultan Haytham’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Sayyid Munthir of the Omani Royal Office to discuss Oman’s unceasing diplomatic efforts to advance a ceasefire in Yemen. They also discussed regional security developments and the longstanding friendship between Oman and the United States. The United States applauds Oman’s critical peacebuilding role in Yemen under Sultan Haytham’s leadership.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
