<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 22:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden Economic Plan Delivers Robust Progress in all 50&#160;States</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/fact-sheet-biden-economic-plan-delivers-robust-progress-in-all-50-states/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 22:18:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the White House released new state-by-state fact sheets that highlight several economic indicators —including state employment, unemployment insurance claims, gross domestic product, supplemental poverty, and vaccination rates—which demonstrate the robust economic progress under President Biden’s leadership. This wasn’t by accident. This is the result of President Biden’s plan to build the economy from the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the White House released new state-by-state fact sheets that highlight several economic indicators —including state employment, unemployment insurance claims, gross domestic product, supplemental poverty, and vaccination rates—which demonstrate the robust economic progress under President Biden’s leadership. This wasn’t by accident. This is the result of President Biden’s plan to build the economy from the bottom up and the middle out.<br><br>When President Biden took office, our economy was in crisis and COVID-19 was wreaking havoc on our country. Thanks to his American Rescue Plan, unemployment is near historic lows, the vast majority of Americans are vaccinated, the number of adults with a <a href="https://www.federalreserve.gov/publications/files/2021-report-economic-well-being-us-households-202205.pdf">positive outlook</a> on their overall financial well-being reached an all-time high last year, the number of Americans relying on government unemployment benefits has dropped by more than 90%, and new businesses are being created at record rates. <br><br>The fact sheets highlight our historic economic recovery strong foundation to transition to stable and steady growth that works for working families. Fact sheets for all 50 states are linked below. <br><br><strong><u>Fact Sheets by State</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Alabama.pdf">Alabama</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Alaska.pdf">Alaska</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Arizona.pdf">Arizona</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Arkansas.pdf">Arkansas</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/California.pdf">California</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Colorado.pdf">Colorado</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Connecticut.pdf">Connecticut</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Delaware.pdf">Delaware</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/D.C..pdf">District of Columbia</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Florida.pdf">Florida</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Georgia.pdf">Georgia</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Hawaii.pdf">Hawaii</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Idaho.pdf">Idaho</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Illinois.pdf">Illinois</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Indiana.pdf">Indiana</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Iowa.pdf">Iowa</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Kansas.pdf">Kansas</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Kentucky.pdf">Kentucky</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Louisiana.pdf">Louisiana</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Maine.pdf">Maine</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Maryland.pdf">Maryland</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Massachusetts.pdf">Massachusetts</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Michigan.pdf">Michigan</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Minnesota.pdf">Minnesota</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Mississippi-1.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Mississippi</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Missouri.pdf">Missouri</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Montana.pdf">Montana</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Nebraska.pdf">Nebraska</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Nevada.pdf">Nevada</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/New-Hampshire.pdf">New Hampshire</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/New-Jersey.pdf">New Jersey</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/New-Mexico.pdf">New Mexico</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/New-York.pdf">New York</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/North-Carolina.pdf">North Carolina</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/North-Dakota.pdf">North Dakota</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Ohio.pdf">Ohio</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Oklahoma.pdf">Oklahoma</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Oregon.pdf">Oregon</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Pennsylvania.pdf">Pennsylvania</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Rhode-Island.pdf">Rhode Island</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/South-Carolina.pdf">South Carolina</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/South-Dakota.pdf">South Dakota</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Tennessee.pdf">Tennessee</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Texas.pdf">Texas</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Utah.pdf">Utah</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Vermont.pdf">Vermont</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Virginia.pdf">Virginia</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Washington.pdf">Washington</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/West-Virginia.pdf">West Virginia</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Wisconsin.pdf">Wisconsin</a></li><li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Wyoming.pdf">Wyoming </a>&nbsp;</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-6/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 21:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160; &#160; &#160;Chrissie C. Latimore, of South Carolina, to be United States Marshal for the District of South Carolina for the term of four years, vice Thomas M. Griffin, Jr., resigned. &#160; &#160; &#160;Kirk M. Taylor, of Colorado, to be United States Marshal for the District of Colorado for the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Chrissie C. Latimore, of South Carolina, to be United States Marshal for the District of South Carolina for the term of four years, vice Thomas M. Griffin, Jr., resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Kirk M. Taylor, of Colorado, to be United States Marshal for the District of Colorado for the term of four years, vice David A. Weaver, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Adair Ford Boroughs, of South Carolina, to be United States Attorney for the District of South Carolina for the term of four years, vice Peter M. McCoy, Jr., resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Natalie K. Wight, of Oregon, to be United States Attorney for the District of Oregon for the term of four years, vice Billy J. Williams, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;E. Martin Estrada, of California, to be United States Attorney for the Central District of California for the term of four years, vice Nicola T. Hanna, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Sopen B. Shah, of Wisconsin, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of Wisconsin for the term of four years, vice Scott C. Blader, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Gregory J. Haanstad, of Wisconsin, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Wisconsin for the term of four years, vice Matthew D. Krueger, resigned.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWAL SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Michael M. Contrades, of Hawaii, to be United States Marshal for the District of Hawaii for the term of four years, vice Charles L. Goodwin, retired, which was sent to the Senate on May 5, 2022.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Five New Nominees to Serve as U.S. Attorneys, Two to Serve as U.S.&#160;Marshals</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/president-biden-announces-five-new-nominees-to-serve-as-u-s-attorneys-two-to-serve-as-u-s-marshals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54936</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is announcing five new nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, as well as two new nominees to serve as U.S. Marshals. These are officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as top federal law enforcement officials. These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is announcing five new nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, as well as two new nominees to serve as U.S. Marshals. These are officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as top federal law enforcement officials.</p>



<p>These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and credentials, their dedication to pursuing equal justice for all, and their commitment to the independence of the Department of Justice.</p>



<p>The President has proposed a budget that would significantly increase funding for law enforcement as part of a comprehensive approach to tackling the rising crime rate this administration inherited last year.</p>



<p>The President has also launched a comprehensive effort to take on the uptick in gun crime that has been taking place since 2020—putting more cops on the beat, supporting community prevention programs, and cracking down on illegal gun trafficking. Confirming U.S. Attorneys as the chief federal law enforcement officers in their district is important for these efforts.</p>



<p>The President has now announced 53 nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys, and 11 nominees to serve as U.S. Marshals.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>U.S. Attorney Announcements</u></strong></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Adair Ford Boroughs, United States Attorney Nominee for the District of South Carolina</span></p>



<p>Adair Ford Boroughs is a founding partner of Boroughs Bryant, LLC where she has practiced since 2021. From 2017 to 2019, she was the Executive Director of Charleston Legal Access. Ms. Boroughs served as a law clerk for Judge Richard M. Gergel on the U.S. District Court for the District of South Carolina from 2013 to 2017. She was previously a trial attorney in the Tax Division of the United States Department of Justice from 2007 to 2013. Ms. Boroughs received her J.D. from Stanford Law School in 2007 and B.S.,&nbsp;<em>summa cum laude</em>, from Furman University in 2002.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">E. Martin Estrada, United States Attorney Nominee for the Central District of California</span></p>



<p>E. Martin Estrada is a partner at Munger, Tolles, &amp; Olson LLP where he has practiced since 2014. He also served as an associate at the same firm from 2004 to 2007.&nbsp; Mr. Estrada previously served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Central District of California from 2007 to 2014.&nbsp; He served as a law clerk for Judge Arthur L. Alarcón on the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit from 2003 to 2004 and Judge Robert J. Timlin on the United States District Court for the Central District of California from 2002 to 2003. Mr. Estrada received his J.D. from Stanford University,&nbsp;<em>with distinction,</em>&nbsp;in 2002 and B.A.,&nbsp;<em>magna cum laude</em>, from University of California, Irvine in 1998.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Gregory J. Haanstad, United States Attorney Nominee for the Eastern District of Wisconsin</span></p>



<p>Gregory J. Haanstad has served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Wisconsin since 2002. Mr. Haanstad was previously United States Attorney for the Eastern District of Wisconsin from 2016 to 2018, and also served as the Acting United States&nbsp; Attorney for the Eastern District of Wisconsin from 2015 to 2016. He served as a law clerk for Magistrate Judge William E. Callahan, Jr., on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Wisconsin from 2000 to 2002. Mr. Haanstad received his J.D.,&nbsp;<em>cum laude</em>, from the University of Wisconsin Law School in 2000 and B.S. from the University of Wisconsin, La Crosse in 1995.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Sopen B. Shah, United States Attorney Nominee for the Western District of Wisconsin</span></p>



<p>Sopen B. Shah is Counsel at Perkins Coie LLP where she has practiced since 2019. Ms. Shah was previously a Deputy Solicitor General of Wisconsin from 2017 to 2019. She served as a law clerk for Judge Debra Ann Livingston on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit from 2016 to 2017 and Judge Amul R. Thapar on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Kentucky from 2015 to 2016. Ms. Shah received her J.D. from Yale Law School in 2015 and A.B.,&nbsp;<em>magna cum laude</em>, from Harvard College in 2008.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Natalie K. Wight, United States Attorney Nominee for the District of Oregon</span></p>



<p>Natalie K. Wight has served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Oregon since 2012. She was previously an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Northern District of California from 2008 to 2012. Ms. Wight was an attorney at the Federal Bureau of Prisons from 2003 to 2008. Ms. Wight received her J.D. from the University of Notre Dame Law School in 2003, M.S. from California State University in 2000, and B.S. from the College of Idaho in 1996.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>U.S. Marshal Announcements</u></strong></p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Chrissie Latimore, United States Marshal nominee for the District of South Carolina</span></p>



<p>Chrissie C. Latimore has served as Chief of Police for the Laurens Police Department since 2018. Chrissie C. Latimore has served as Chief of Police for the Laurens Police Department since 2018. Chief Latimore previously served as Assistant Chief of Police of the Laurens Police Department from 2014 to 2018, and in various other roles with the Department from 1999 to 2013. She was a Special Agent for the South Carolina Law Enforcement Division from 2013 to 2014. Chief Latimore received her M.S. from Anderson University in 2014, her B.S. from Lander University in 2011, and her A.S. from Piedmont Technical College in 2007. Chief Latimore is a veteran of the United States Army and Army Reserve.&nbsp;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Kirk Taylor, United States Marshal nominee for the District of Colorado</span></p>



<p>Kirk Taylor is the Sheriff of Pueblo County, Colorado where he has served since 2007.&nbsp;He was previously an Investigator for the 10th Judicial District Attorney’s Office in Pueblo, Colorado from 1994 to 2007.&nbsp;From 1987 to 1992 he was a patrolman for the Alamosa, Colorado Police Department.&nbsp;Sheriff Taylor received his J.D. from University of Colorado School of Law in 2002 and B.A. from University of Southern Colorado in 1995. Sheriff Taylor is a veteran of the United States Navy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Fifth Operation Fly Formula&#160;Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/president-biden-announces-fifth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 17:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[formula]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54784</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 1.6 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Nestlé NAN SupremePro Stage 1 infant formula this week Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Nestlé infant formulas&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate air shipment of approximately 1.6 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of</em> <em>Nestlé </em><em>NAN SupremePro Stage 1</em><em> infant formula this week</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing a flight, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport <a>Nestlé </a>infant formulas from Cologne, Germany to Fort Worth, Texas on June 9. This delivery will include 110,000 pounds of Nestlé NAN SupremePro Stage 1<em> </em>infant formula, approximately 1.6 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available across the country through Nestlé/Gerber distribution channels, and additional deliveries of Nestlé formula will be announced in the coming days.</p>



<p>Last week, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Nestlé can export additional infant formula into the U.S.<a> </a>Nestlé will import both standard and specialty infant formulas to the U.S. including <a>Nestlé </a>NAN SupremePro 1, Nestlé NAN SupremePro 2, Nestlé Health Science Alfamino/Alfamino, Jr., Gerber® Good Start® Gentle and Gerber Good Start® Extensive HA®. Nestle plans to export approximately 41 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market.</p>



<p><a></a>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. Operation Fly Formula has <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/22/biden-administration-announces-second-operation-fly-formula-flight/">shipped</a> 1.5 million bottle equivalents of Nestle infant formula, and is sourcing flights for an additional 8.3 million bottle equivalents of <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/president-biden-announces-fourth-operation-fly-formula-mission/">Bubs Australia</a> and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/01/president-biden-announces-third-operation-fly-formula-mission/">Kendamil infant formula</a>.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA to reopen Abbott Nutrition’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Picture1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-54786" width="211" height="211" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Picture1.jpg 173w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Picture1.jpg?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Picture1.jpg?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Picture1.jpg?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Picture1.jpg?resize=1200,1200 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 211px) 100vw, 211px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on&#160;Insulation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/06/memorandum-on-presidential-determination-pursuant-to-section-303-of-the-defense-production-act-of-1950-as-amended-on-insulation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 16:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54853</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential DeterminationNo.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;2022-16&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY SUBJECT: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Insulation Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national security, a resilient energy sector,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-right">Presidential Determination<br>No.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;2022-16&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY</p>



<p>SUBJECT: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Presidential Determination Pursuant to<br>                           Section 303 of the Defense Production Act<br>                           of 1950, as amended, on Insulation</p>



<p>Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national security, a resilient energy sector, and the preservation of domestic critical infrastructure. &nbsp;Therefore, by the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the &#8220;Act&#8221;) (50 U.S.C. 4533), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 303(a)(5) of the Act, that:</p>



<p>(1) &nbsp;insulation is an industrial resource, material, or critical technology item essential to the national defense;</p>



<p>(2) &nbsp;without Presidential action under section 303 of the Act, United States industry cannot reasonably be expected to provide the capability for the needed industrial resource, material, or critical technology item in a timely&nbsp;manner; and</p>



<p>(3) &nbsp;purchases, purchase commitments, or other action pursuant to section 303 of the Act are the most cost effective, expedient, and practical alternative method for meeting the need.</p>



<p>Pursuant to section 303(a)(7)(B) of the Act, I find that action to expand the domestic production capability for insulation is necessary to avert an industrial resource or critical technology item shortfall that would severely impair national defense capability. &nbsp;Therefore, I waive the requirements of section&nbsp;303(a)(1)–(a)(6) of the Act for the purpose of expanding&nbsp;the domestic production capability for insulation.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in&nbsp;the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Electric Heat&#160;Pumps</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/06/memorandum-on-presidential-determination-pursuant-to-section-303-of-the-defense-production-act-of-1950-as-amended-on-electric-heat-pumps/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 16:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54854</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential DeterminationNo.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;2022-18&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Electric Heat Pumps Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national security, a resilient energy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-right">Presidential Determination<br>No.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;2022-18&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Presidential Determination Pursuant to<br>                            Section 303 of the Defense Production Act<br>                             of 1950, as amended, on Electric Heat Pumps</p>



<p>Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national security, a resilient energy sector, and the preservation of domestic critical infrastructure. &nbsp;Therefore, by the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the &#8220;Act&#8221;) (50 U.S.C. 4533), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 303(a)(5) of the Act, that:</p>



<p>(1) &nbsp;electric heat pumps are industrial resources, materials, or critical technology items essential to&nbsp;the&nbsp;national defense;</p>



<p>(2) &nbsp;without Presidential action under section 303 of the Act, United States industry cannot reasonably be expected to provide the capability for the needed industrial resource, material, or critical technology item in a timely&nbsp;manner; and</p>



<p>(3) &nbsp;purchases, purchase commitments, or other action pursuant to section 303 of the Act are the most cost effective, expedient, and practical alternative method for&nbsp;meeting the need.</p>



<p>Pursuant to section 303(a)(7)(B) of the Act, I find that action to expand the domestic production capability for electric heat pumps is necessary to avert an industrial resource or critical technology item shortfall that would severely impair national defense capability. &nbsp;Therefore, I waive the requirements of section 303(a)(1)–(a)(6) of the Act for the purpose of expanding the domestic production capability for electric heat pumps.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in&nbsp;the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Presidential Determination Pursuant to  Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Transformers and Electric Power Grid&#160;Components</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/memorandum-on-presidential-determination-pursuant-to-section-303-of-the-defense-production-act-of-1950-as-amended-on-transformers-and-electric-power-grid-components/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 16:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54852</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY SUBJECT: Presidential Determination Pursuant to  Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Transformers and Electric Power Grid Components Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national security, a resilient&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY</p>



<p>SUBJECT: Presidential Determination Pursuant to  Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Transformers and Electric Power Grid Components</p>



<p>Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national security, a resilient energy sector, and the preservation of domestic critical infrastructure. &nbsp;Therefore, by the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the &#8220;Act&#8221;) (50 U.S.C. 4533), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 303(a)(5) of the Act, that:</p>



<p>(1) &nbsp;transformers and electric power grid components are industrial resources, materials, or critical technology items essential to the national defense;</p>



<p>(2) &nbsp;without Presidential action under section 303 of the Act, United States industry cannot reasonably be expected to provide the capability for the needed industrial resource, material, or critical technology item in a timely&nbsp;manner; and</p>



<p><a></a>(3) &nbsp;purchases, purchase commitments, or other action pursuant to section 303 of the Act are the most cost effective, expedient, and practical alternative method for&nbsp;meeting the need.</p>



<p>Pursuant to section 303(a)(7)(B) of the Act, I find that action to expand the domestic production capability for transformers and electric power grid components is necessary to avert an industrial resource or critical technology item shortfall that would severely impair national defense capability. &nbsp;Therefore, I&nbsp;waive the requirements of section 303(a)(1)–(a)(6) of the Act for the purpose of expanding the domestic production capability for transformers and electric power grid components.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in&nbsp;the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Solar Photovoltaic Modules and Module&#160;Components</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/memorandum-on-presidential-determination-pursuant-to-section-303-of-the-defense-production-act-of-1950-as-amended-on-solar-photovoltaic-modules-and-module-components/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 16:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54849</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY SUBJECT:       Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Solar Photovoltaic Modules and Module Components Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national security, a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY</p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Solar Photovoltaic Modules and Module Components</p>



<p><a></a>Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national security, a resilient energy sector, and the preservation of domestic critical infrastructure. &nbsp;Therefore, by the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the &#8220;Act&#8221;) (50 U.S.C. 4533), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 303(a)(5) of the Act, that:</p>



<p>(1) &nbsp;solar photovoltaic modules and module components, including ingots, wafers, solar glass, and cells, are industrial resources, materials, or critical technology items essential to the national defense;</p>



<p>(2) &nbsp;without Presidential action under section 303 of the Act, United States industry cannot reasonably be expected to provide the capability for the needed industrial resource, material, or critical technology item in a timely&nbsp;manner; and</p>



<p>(3) &nbsp;purchases, purchase commitments, or other action pursuant to section 303 of the Act are the most cost effective, expedient, and practical alternative method for&nbsp;meeting the need.</p>



<p>Pursuant to section 303(a)(7)(B) of the Act, I find that action&nbsp;to expand the domestic production capability for solar photovoltaic modules and module components is necessary to avert an industrial resource or critical technology item shortfall that would severely impair national defense capability. &nbsp;Therefore, I waive the requirements of section 303(a)(1)–(a)(6) of the Act for the purpose of expanding the domestic production capability for solar photovoltaic modules and module components.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in&nbsp;the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Electrolyzers, Fuel Cells, and Platinum Group&#160;Metals</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/06/memorandum-on-presidential-determination-pursuant-to-section-303-of-the-defense-production-act-of-1950-as-amended-on-electrolyzers-fuel-cells-and-platinum-group-metals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 16:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54845</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential DeterminationNo.        2022-17         MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY SUBJECT:&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Presidential Determination Pursuant to Section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended, on Electrolyzers, Fuel Cells, and Platinum Group Metals Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-right">Presidential Determination<br>No.        2022-17        </p>



<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF ENERGY</p>



<p>SUBJECT:&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Presidential Determination Pursuant to<br>                            Section 303 of the Defense Production Act<br>                             of 1950, as amended, on Electrolyzers,<br>                             Fuel Cells, and Platinum Group Metals</p>



<p>Ensuring a robust, resilient, and sustainable domestic industrial base to meet the requirements of the clean energy economy is essential to our national security, a resilient energy sector, and the preservation of domestic critical infrastructure. &nbsp;Therefore, by the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section 303 of the Defense Production Act of 1950, as amended (the &#8220;Act&#8221;) (50 U.S.C. 4533), I hereby determine, pursuant to section 303(a)(5) of the Act, that:</p>



<p>(1) &nbsp;electrolyzers, fuel cells, and platinum group metals are industrial resources, materials, or critical technology items essential to the national defense;</p>



<p>(2) &nbsp;without Presidential action under section 303 of the Act, United States industry cannot reasonably be expected to provide the capability for the needed industrial resource, material, or critical technology item in a timely&nbsp;manner; and</p>



<p>(3) &nbsp;purchases, purchase commitments, or other action pursuant to section 303 of the Act are the most cost effective, expedient, and practical alternative method for&nbsp;meeting the need.</p>



<p>Pursuant to section 303(a)(7)(B) of the Act, I find that action to expand the domestic production capability for electrolyzers, fuel cells, and platinum group metals is necessary to avert an industrial resource or critical technology item shortfall that would severely impair national defense capability. &nbsp;Therefore, I&nbsp;waive the requirements of section 303(a)(1)–(a)(6) of the Act for the purpose of expanding the domestic production capability for electrolyzers, fuel cells, and platinum group metals.</p>



<p>You are authorized and directed to publish this determination in&nbsp;the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre on the Louisiana Abortion&#160;Bill</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/06/statement-from-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-on-the-louisiana-abortion-bill/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 16:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Louisiana legislature has taken the latest step in a growing attack against the fundamental freedoms of Americans. Louisiana’s extreme bill will criminalize abortion with no exceptions for rape or incest and punish reproductive healthcare professionals with up to ten years in prison. The President is committed to protecting the constitutional rights of Americans afforded&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Louisiana legislature has taken the latest step in a growing attack against the fundamental freedoms of Americans. Louisiana’s extreme bill will criminalize abortion with no exceptions for rape or incest and punish reproductive healthcare professionals with up to ten years in prison. The President is committed to protecting the constitutional rights of Americans afforded by Roe for nearly 50 years, and ensuring that women can make their own choices about their lives, bodies, and families. An overwhelming majority of the American people agree and reject these kinds of radical measures.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
