<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 12:51:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on DACA and Legislation for Dreamers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/17/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-daca-and-legislation-for-dreamers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 12:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 2012, the Obama-Biden Administration created the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy, which has allowed hundreds of thousands of young immigrants to remain in the United States, to live, study, and work in our communities. Nine years later, Congress has not acted to provide a path to citizenship for Dreamers. Yesterday’s Federal court&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In 2012, the Obama-Biden Administration created the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) policy, which has allowed hundreds of thousands of young immigrants to remain in the United States, to live, study, and work in our communities. Nine years later, Congress has not acted to provide a path to citizenship for Dreamers.</p>



<p>Yesterday’s Federal court ruling is deeply disappointing. While the court’s order does not now affect current DACA recipients, this decision nonetheless relegates hundreds of thousands of young immigrants to an uncertain future. The Department of Justice intends to appeal this decision in order to preserve and fortify DACA. And, as the court recognized, the Department of Homeland Security plans to issue a proposed rule concerning DACA in the near future.</p>



<p>But only Congress can ensure a permanent solution by granting a path to citizenship for Dreamers that will provide the certainty and stability that these young people need and deserve. I have repeatedly called on Congress to pass the American Dream and Promise Act, and I now renew that call with the greatest urgency. It is my fervent hope that through reconciliation or other means, Congress will finally provide security to all Dreamers, who have lived too long in fear.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by White House Spokesperson Jen Psaki on the Visit of Prime Minister Mustafa al-Kadhimi of Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/16/statement-by-white-house-spokesperson-jen-psaki-on-the-visit-of-prime-minister-mustafa-al-kadhimi-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:28:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24303</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden looks forward to welcoming the Prime Minister of Iraq, Mustafa Al-Kadhimi, to the White House on July 26, 2021. The Prime Minister’s visit will highlight the strategic partnership between the United States and Iraq and advance bilateral cooperation under the Strategic Framework Agreement. The visit will also focus on key areas of shared&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden looks forward to welcoming the Prime Minister of Iraq, Mustafa Al-Kadhimi, to the White House on July 26, 2021. The Prime Minister’s visit will highlight the strategic partnership between the United States and Iraq and advance bilateral cooperation under the Strategic Framework Agreement. The visit will also focus on key areas of shared interest including through education, health, cultural, energy, and climate initiatives. President Biden also looks forward to strengthening bilateral cooperation with Iraq on political, economic, and security issues to include joint efforts to ensure the enduring defeat of ISIS.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 16, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/16/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-16-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 1:20 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Hello. MS. PSAKI:&#160; Happy Friday. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Happy Friday. MS. PSAKI:&#160; Brian Karem has got some sunglasses on.&#160; Everybody is ready for the weekend. Okay, I have a couple of items for all of you at the top. Last week, we launched&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>1:20 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Happy Friday.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Happy Friday.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Brian Karem has got some sunglasses on.&nbsp; Everybody is ready for the weekend.</p>



<p>Okay, I have a couple of items for all of you at the top.</p>



<p>Last week, we launched the Supply Chain Disruption Task Force to monitor, engage, and act on current and emerging supply chain disruptions and bottlenecks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This afternoon, the White House is hosting a convening of the Supply Chain Disruptions Task Force with Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Marcia Fudge, Director of the National Economic Council Brian Deese, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice, Council of Economic Advisers Chair Cecilia Rouse, and groups representing the full range of the homebuilding supply chain, from loggers and log- &#8212; and lumber contractors, labor leaders, realtors, and affordable housing advocates.</p>



<p>At this convening, these administration officials and key stakeholders will discuss strategies to address short-term supply chain disruptions in the homebuilding sector and how they can work together to address them.</p>



<p>I also wanted to note that yesterday, senior White House officials, led by Susan Rice and Julie Rodriguez, launched the Community Violence Intervention Collaborative announced by the President on June 23rd as part of his comprehensive plan to reduce gun crime.</p>



<p>The Community Violence Intervention is an evidence-based approach that’s been shown to reduce violence by as much as 60 percent.&nbsp; CVI prevents gun violence and crime in communities around the country before it happens by intervening in disputes early, and connecting potential perpetrators and victims with services and support to divert them &#8212; to divert them away from crime.&nbsp; It’s an approach that’s been embraced by an increasing number of law enforcement leaders nationally, as well as by mayors of both parties in cities around America.&nbsp; So this will be an ongoing initiative.</p>



<p>Also want to give you an update: I noted earlier this week that there have been 2 million people who now have access to affordable healthcare, thanks to the reopening of the &#8212; of the enrollment &#8212; special enrollment period.</p>



<p>Yesterday, we launched a “Summer Sprint to Coverage” campaign, leveraging robust paid media, increased community outreach, and more to get Americans signed up.&nbsp; This President Biden is urging Americans who need health insurance to visit HealthCare.gov or to call 1-800-318-2596, if they would prefer, to enroll today.&nbsp; We’ll keep talking about this quite a bit until August 15th, which is the end of the timeline.</p>



<p>I also have promised you that I would give you updates on interesting initiatives we’re taking to reach people, meet people where they are, as it relates to getting vaccinated.&nbsp; So, on Saturday, NASCAR will host the Get Vaccinated 200.&nbsp; They’ll have vaccines on site and will be encouraging vaccinations.&nbsp; This is the type of whole-of-country approach that is reaching people in convenient locations with messengers they trust.</p>



<p>Finally, a quick week ahead:</p>



<p>On Monday, the President and the First Lady will welcome Their Majesties King Abdullah II and Queen Rania of Jordan, and His Royal Highness Crown Prince Hussein, to the White House.&nbsp; Their Majesties’ visit will highlight the enduring and strategic partnership between the United States and Jordan, a key security partner and ally of the United States.&nbsp; It will be an opportunity to discuss the many challenges facing the Middle East and showcase Jordan’s leadership role in promoting peace and stability in the region.</p>



<p>On Monday, the President will also deliver remarks on the economic recovery and the progress made under his administration &#8212; taking the country from 60,000 new jobs per month to 600,000 new jobs per month, and from 1 percent of Americans vaccinated to more than two thirds of adults with at least one shot.</p>



<p>He’ll explain why his Rescue Plan has helped us get here and will continue supporting Americans throughout the year, and why we need the infrastructure agreement and his Build Back Better plan to sustain that growth in the years to come while keeping inflation in check for the long term.</p>



<p><a>On Tuesday, the President will hold his second Cabinet meeting of his administration &#8212; his first in the Cabinet Room &#8212; get excited, everyone &#8212; and he looks forward to that.</a></p>



<p>And on Wednesday, the President will travel to Cincinnati, Ohio, to participate in a CNN townhall.</p>



<p>With that, Alex, why don’t you kick us off?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I have a few questions on China and then one on the BIF.&nbsp; Can you talk &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I love that “BIF” is happening, just to note that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, you made it happen.&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit more about the Hong Kong business advisory, and the latest sanctions and what triggered those?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, there have been reports that Wendy Sherman may tack a China visit onto the end of her Asia visit.&nbsp; Can you talk about what her goal might be with something like that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And does this mean that we&#8217;re moving closer to &#8212; I know last month there was talk of a potential Biden/President Xi summit.&nbsp; Are we moving closer to that?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, well, first, as the President said yesterday, the situation in Hong Kong is continuing to deteriorate, and we continue to see Beijing assault Hong Kong&#8217;s autonomy and democratic institutions.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen authorities use the National Security Law to make politically motivated arrests.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve seen a general deterioration of fundamental freedoms, which were guaranteed by an international agreement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s why the United States &#8212; we announced steps we’re taking today to promote accountability and transparency.&nbsp; On the accountability front, the State Department announced earlier today seven officials who were sanctioned for their actions &#8212; threatening the peace, stability, security, and autonomy of Hong Kong.</p>



<p>On the transparency front, today, the U.S. government issued a business advisory &#8212; as you noted, Alex, I just wanted to give the full context &#8212; for Hong Kong, which is intended to inform businesses and highlight the growing risk for those operating in Hong Kong.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The bottom line is that businesses should be aware that the risks faced in mainland China are now increasingly present in Hong Kong.&nbsp; And as the President said last month, of course, we will not waver in our support for Hong Kong and all those who stand up for the basic freedoms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But as businesses are making decisions &#8212; and obviously they&#8217;re making decisions themselves &#8212; we want them to be aware of the use of data &#8212; accessing of data inappropriately, of the restriction of information.&nbsp; And they should be aware of that happening on &#8212; in Hong Kong, as well as in mainland China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then Wendy Sherman and President Xi?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Got it.&nbsp; In terms of Wendy Sherman&#8217;s trip, we &#8212; I don&#8217;t have an update on travel.&nbsp; We, of course, have been and continue to explore opportunities to engage with PRC officials.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been clear we will engage in conversations at the appropriate level when there&#8217;s an opportunity for them to be substantive and, hopefully, consequential.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I don&#8217;t have an update on intended travel.&nbsp; Obviously, they are quite adept over there at the State Department of adding things as needed.</p>



<p>And as it relates to plans for the President: As we&#8217;ve said, he will look for opportunities to engage with President Xi going forward.&nbsp; He &#8212; we don&#8217;t have any particular plans at this moment, so no decisions have been made.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ll continue to evaluate what&#8217;s appropriate and what would be constructive in the relationship moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just on the BIF, there are reports that it could be financed in part by tariffs on carbon-heavy imports, which could end up rising &#8212; hiking prices on goods for American families.&nbsp; Is the White House open to that?&nbsp; Or would that be a concern similar to the gas tax increase?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There are ongoing discussions about the final components, of course, as we look to &#8212; and I know you are all eager to see bill language and legislative language and, of course, having discussions about the payfors are part of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President&#8217;s bottom lines have not changed about the fact that that any payfors cannot raise taxes on individuals making less than $400,000 a year, and anything that would impact that would not be something he would support.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Follow-up on &#8212; I can’t believe we’re calling it the &#8220;BIF” &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You note that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Those of us old enough think of &#8220;Back to the Future&#8221;; those who were younger &#8212; I don&#8217;t know what they think of.&nbsp; But &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’m in the “Back to the Future” category.&nbsp; Given the fact that discussions are ongoing, if the discussions are still ongoing come Wednesday, does the President believe that the Senate should vote to take the procedural vote to move forward if there’s no bill text or a deal in hand?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, one, Leader Schumer, of course, will be running point and leading the effort to determine and making the determination about the timeline, the process, and the sequencing of votes in the Senate.&nbsp; And we certainly work closely with him, and &#8212; but we certainly trust his &#8212; his path that he is mapping out for the legislative process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have several days, I would note, before Monday for more information to become available.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see what is known.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will note that the President is quite familiar with the rollercoaster and ups and downs of legislating, having spent 36 years there and even having had some successes over the last few months in working with legislators.&nbsp; He &#8212; we had a productive meeting &#8212; members of our team had a constructive, productive meeting yesterday.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d also note that there are a number of Republicans and Democrats who feel the same in terms of the path forward.</p>



<p>Senator Portman said, “We&#8217;re going to get it done, and we’ll end up with a good package.”&nbsp; Senator Cassidy said he did not feel squeezed by the timing.&nbsp; Senator Romney affirmed there were going &#8212; things were going in a good direction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We certainly understand the ups and downs &#8212; no one better than the President.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the period of time we&#8217;re in at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just &#8212; you went through kind of the topline details of this yesterday, but can you elaborate a little bit on the Facebook &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the administration to Facebook flagging of disinformation.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s also some reporting that we&#8217;ve had that Facebook maybe hasn&#8217;t been as proactive as the White House would like it to be in response to some of the flagging.&nbsp; So, the process of how the flagging works, and then whether Facebook has been amenable to those requests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, I would say first, it shouldn&#8217;t come as any surprise that we&#8217;re in regular touch with social media platforms &#8212; just like we&#8217;re in regular touch with all of you and your media outlets &#8212; about areas where we have concern, information that might be useful, information that may or may not be interesting to your viewers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You all make decisions, just like the social media platforms make decisions, even though they&#8217;re a private-sector company and different, but just as an example.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we are ma- &#8212; regularly making sure social media platforms are aware of the latest narratives dangerous to public health that we and many other Americans seeing &#8212; are seeing across all of social and traditional media.&nbsp; And we work to engage with them to better understand the enforcement of social media platform policies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So let me give you an example, just to illustrate it a little bit.&nbsp; The false narrative that remains active out there about COVID-19 vaccines causing infertility &#8212; something we&#8217;ve seen out there, flowing on the internet quite a bit, in other places as well &#8212; which has been disproven time and time again.&nbsp; This is troubling, but a persistent narrative that we and many have seen, and we want to know that the social media platforms are taking steps to address it.&nbsp; That is inaccurate, false information.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you are a parent, you would look at that information and then that would naturally raise concerns, but it&#8217;s inaccurate.&nbsp; And that is an example of the kind of information that we are flagging or raising.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then has Facebook been as proactive as the White House would like in terms of its response to those flags?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, as I noted yesterday, Phil, there is more &#8212; there are more steps that everyone can take.&nbsp; And I would just note, again, this is a responsibility of officials speaking, of course, on behalf of the government; it&#8217;s the responsibility of members of the media; it&#8217;s the responsibility of citizens and civic leaders and people who are trusted voices in communities around the country.&nbsp; That has a broad definition.&nbsp; Social media platforms is one of them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as we know, it is also &#8212; there are also areas where a lot of people get news and information.&nbsp; Sometimes those are accurate news items reported by some of your outlets or accurate information shared by a neighbor.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sometimes there is information that is not.&nbsp; It is hard to discriminate, as we know.&nbsp; This is not a new issue, but it is an issue that is impacting people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So a couple of the steps that we have &#8212; you know, that could be constructive for the public health of the country are providing for &#8212; for Facebook or other platforms to measure and publicly share the impact of misinformation on their platform and the audience it&#8217;s reaching, also with the public, with all of you to create robust enforcement strategies that bridge their properties and provide transparency about rules.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You shouldn&#8217;t be banned from one platform and not others if you &#8212; for providing misinformation out there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Taking faster action against harmful posts.&nbsp; As you all know, information travels quite quickly.&nbsp; If it&#8217;s up there for days and days and days when people see it, you know, there&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s hard to put that back in a box.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, of course, promoting quality information algorithms.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know how they work, but they all do know how they work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those are some of the steps that we think could be constructive for public health, for public information, for public &#8212; and, you know, the right of the public to know.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to quickly follow up on the Facebook aspect of this: You said yesterday that 12 people were producing 65 percent of the misinformation on vaccines on social media platforms.&nbsp; Do you have a sense of who those people are?&nbsp; Are they bad actors like Russia?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Facebook responded yesterday after the press briefing.&nbsp; They say that they removed 18 million pieces of COVID misinformation; they&#8217;ve connected more than 2 billion people to reliable information.&nbsp; So does the White House find that sufficient?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Clearly not, because we&#8217;re talking about additional steps that should be taken.&nbsp; And frankly, information that media organizations could detr- &#8212; could decide whether you&#8217;re going to report on or not.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not talking just about the misinformation storyline; I&#8217;m talking about these individuals.&nbsp; I&#8217;m talking about, you know, how prevalent the spreading of this information is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The public has a right to know.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the point that we&#8217;re making.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re dealing with a life-or-death issue here, and so everybody has a role to play in making sure there&#8217;s accurate information.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, those are steps they have taken.&nbsp; They’re a private-sector company.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to make decisions about additional steps they can take.&nbsp; It&#8217;s clear there are more that can be taken.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;ll actually on &#8212; can I just &#8212; on the foreign government piece, because I think that&#8217;s an important point, or an important, interesting question.&nbsp; The State Department&#8217;s Global Engagement Center has found that Russia and China have promoted their own vaccines through messaging that undermines Western origin vaccine development programs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, that is more than just competition about vaccines.&nbsp; The risk and impact there is that this type of information magnifies, you know, the risk of potential side effects associated with Western vaccines.&nbsp; This is what they&#8217;re &#8212; what the information &#8212; some of this misinformation is doing &#8212; and misleads the public by falsely alleging that mRNA vaccines are untested and, thus, risky, even though many of them are approved and have gone through the gold standard of the FDA approval process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the PRC, for example, has also suggested that the United States hoards COVID-19 treatments and prevents other countries from acquiring vaccines, despite evidence to the contrary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, certainly, pushing information out there that these tested, approved vaccines are ineffective and unhelpful &#8212; a lot of people on these platforms, they&#8217;re not discriminating, as you all know, between the source of the information.&nbsp; And that is damaging as well.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ve seen that trend.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more, if I could, just on Afghanistan.&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.</p>



<p>As we look at the withdrawal in Afghanistan, what is your assessment of the Taliban&#8217;s advancements?&nbsp; We heard from the President; he said the likelihood that there was going to be the Taliban overrunning everything and owning the whole country is “highly unlikely.”&nbsp; Does the administration still believe that the Afghan government can maintain control of the region?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think that what the President was conveying is that it is not inevitable.&nbsp; And we have provided a range of &#8212; a great deal of support, supplies, training.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing to do that.&nbsp; We will continue to provide security assistance in the coming months to the Afghan National Forces.&nbsp; But it is up to them to determine: Are they going to unite as a country?&nbsp; Are they going to stand up and fight against the Taliban?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that is &#8212; it&#8217;s really in their hands at this &#8212; it will be in their hands, moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So his point is that it is not inevitable.&nbsp; There has been no intelligence assessment that has said it is inevitable, even as they &#8212; we are assessing what the consequences could be.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; When you talk about misinformation, it seems like one of the best ways to counteract some of the vaccine misinformation that&#8217;s out there would be for the FDA to fully authorize these vaccines with the full weight of government approval behind the vaccines.&nbsp; But now we&#8217;re hearing that may not happen until January 2022 or even later.&nbsp; Is the President comfortable with that timeline?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President is comfortable with scientists and data experts moving on the timeline that that &#8212; they see is appropriate.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know that we know that to be factually true, to that &#8212; that to be the main driver.&nbsp; I haven&#8217;t seen data to suggest that, that the main driver of it is if it&#8217;s formally approved or not.</p>



<p>A lot of the misinformation that is traveling out there is about the consequences and the impact of the vaccine.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not always tied to or necessarily tied to whether it&#8217;s been formally approved or not.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, that may give medical experts or others some greater level of confidence.&nbsp; We will see.&nbsp; But the President is going to leave it to the FDA to determine the timeline.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the President doesn&#8217;t have any concerns about the length of time that the approval process takes currently at the FDA?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to allow them to move at the pace of science.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then I want to ask you about the new reporting about Joint Chiefs Chairman General Milley, who had, apparently, some very serious national security concerns just before President Biden took office.&nbsp; Did he brief then President-elect Biden about his fears about a strike on Iran or about the possibility of an attempted coup?</a></p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to speak to private national security consequ- &#8212; or conversations, I should say.&nbsp; Obviously, the President had many conversations with General Milley &#8212; Miller during his time in his role, and most of those &#8212; or none of those &#8212; do we read out.</p>



<p>I will say that he strongly respects General Miller.&nbsp; As you know, he had the opportunity to sit down with him on Wednesday, thank him for his outstanding leadership of the Resolute Support Mission, including overseeing the vast majority of our drawdown from Afghanistan, which is a particular vulnerable period &#8212; during a particularly vulnerable period for our troops.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How close does the President think we came to a possible war with Iran or an attempted coup here at home?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m just not going to speak to intelligence matters from here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; First on COVID origins: Is the White House worried that China continues stonewalling the World Health Organization investigators and now is saying things like they think maybe COVID-19 got into China through frozen food?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We are certainly remain- &#8212; continue to be concerned, Peter, about misinformation coming from voices in China about, certainly, the origins, their lack of participation in the process, their lack of willingness to provide data and information to the World Health Organization.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, we&#8217;re &#8212; are undergoing our own process here, our 90-day review here.&nbsp; But certainly, the Chinese providing information, being in &#8212; a participant in the process, would aid &#8212; aid the effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then speaking of misinformation and the announcement from yesterday: For how long has the administration been spying on people&#8217;s Facebook profiles looking for vaccine misinformation?</a></p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that was quite a loaded and inaccurate question, which I would refute.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Inaccurate how?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, first of all, as you know, we&#8217;re in &#8212; we&#8217;re in a regular touch with &#8212; with a range of media outlets &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And we expect that the White House &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; as &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; is watching Fox &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Let me finish &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; but I don’t think &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; as we are &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; people posting on Facebook expect that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; as we are in regular touch with social media platforms.&nbsp; This is publicly open information &#8212; people sharing information online &#8212; just as you are all reporting information on your news stations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; okay, so these 12 people who you have on a list &#8212; 12 individuals &#8212; do they know that somebody at the Surgeon General&#8217;s office is going through their profile?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to get you the citation of where that comes from.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no secret list.&nbsp; I will tell you that these are people who are sharing information on public platforms &#8212; on Facebook &#8212; information that is traveling, is inaccurate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our biggest concern here &#8212; and I, frankly, think it should be your biggest concern &#8212; is the number of people who are dying around the country because they&#8217;re getting misinformation that is leading them to not take a vaccine &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Young people, old people, kids, children &#8212; this is all being &#8212; a lot of them are being impacted by misinformation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The big concern though, I think, for a lot of people on Facebook is that now this is Big Brother watching you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; They&#8217;re more concerned about that than people dying across the country because of a pandemic where misinformation is traveling on social media platforms?&nbsp; That feels unlikely to me.&nbsp; If you have the data to back that up, I&#8217;m happy to discuss it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, and just about things that are on Facebook: I looked this morning, there are videos of Dr. Fauci from 2020, before anybody had a vaccine, and he&#8217;s out there saying there&#8217;s no reason to be walking around with a mask.&nbsp; So, is the administration going to contact Facebook and ask them to take that down?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I think what Dr. Fauci has said himself &#8212; who&#8217;s been quite public out there &#8212; is that science evolves, information evolves, and we make that available in a public way to the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Exactly &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have never seen any data to suggest that &#8212; that the vaccines cause infertility.&nbsp; That is information that is irresponsibly traveling.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But &#8212; I just &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; just one more &#8212; sorry &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; excuse me, just one more &#8212; okay, about &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About the science &#8212; about the science evolving: Facebook used to post &#8212; used to block people from posting that COVID may have originated for a lab.&nbsp; That is something this President now admits is a possibility.&nbsp; So is there any concern that the things you&#8217;re trying to block or have taken down might someday turn out to be &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t take anything down.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t block anything.&nbsp; Facebook and any private-sector company makes decisions about what information should be on their platform.&nbsp; Our point is that there is information that is leading to people not taking the vaccine, and people are dying as a result.&nbsp; And we have a responsibility, as a public health matter, to raise that issue.&nbsp; The responsibility we all have &#8212; the government, media platforms, public messengers &#8212; to give accurate information.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About the 12 individuals that are on that separate site &#8212; it’s not from the White House; I don’t have the source in front of me, but we’ve read it as well.&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of who those individuals are, as was asked before?</p>



<p>And what specifically &#8212; you’ve given a tough message to the social platforms that they should do more &#8212; the social media platforms.&nbsp; What, from this podium, is the message to those individuals &#8212; the 12 of them &#8212; who are responsible for 65 percent of the misinformation that&#8217;s out there?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The message is the same message as it is to every person out there who has a platform, whether that is an elected official or that is a person who is a civic leader: The vaccines are safe.&nbsp; They&#8217;re effective.&nbsp; If people take them, they will save their life, in many cases.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so our message to everyone who is sharing misinformation is that your &#8212; the steps you&#8217;re taking are irresponsible, they could lead to people&#8217;s &#8212; people getting very sick, and people ultimately losing their lives.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t we all participate in a process that will help provide accurate information out there?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the White House participated in any direct contact with these individuals, given the impact they&#8217;re having, through any avenue to try to say, “Knock it off”?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m happy to get you guys the &#8212; the data on where we got that information &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s public.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, this a publicly available data &#8212; we’ll get you the citation, is what I mean.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Let me ask you, if I can, then about some of the other numbers as they relate to COVID.&nbsp; Right now, obviously, due to the Delta variant, COVID cases are up sharply right now.&nbsp; Testing is down right now.&nbsp; How concerned is the White House that this variant, COVID, in general, is much more widespread than we&#8217;re aware of publicly at this time?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to speak out of turn here, because it&#8217;s really a question for the health and medical experts on how they&#8217;re tracking it and how concerned they are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We certainly know, on transmissibility &#8212; and based on the CDC data &#8212; that the Delta variant is the &#8212; is impacting the majority of people who are getting sick with COVID now.&nbsp; We also know that 99.5 percent of people who are in the hospital are people who are unvaccinated, and people who are dying of COVID &#8212; unvaccinated.&nbsp; The data is very clear.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As Dr. Walensky said on an earlier &#8212; an earlier briefing today, this is really becoming a pandemic of the unvaccinated, and that means getting vaccinated, you can save yourself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there anything that the White House is doing differently?&nbsp; We saw the President, proudly, in Philadelphia, shaking hands with a lot of folks when he was there for his voting rights speech earlier this week.&nbsp; We saw something similar last week when he was in Illinois.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Given the reporting about some breakthrough cases right now, are there any things that the White House is doing differently as it relates to your own staffing or the President&#8217;s handling of his, sort of, activities due to those new numbers?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, we are vaccinated.&nbsp; The President is vaccinated.&nbsp; You are all vaccinated.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, so breakthrough cases are not something that you &#8212; that you or Americans &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We get test- &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; should worry about?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We still have a testing protocol and process in place for White House staff.&nbsp; So that &#8212; that has continued.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And for those individuals that he would be shaking hands with, there&#8217;s not any &#8212; basically, shaking hands is good if you’re vaccinated?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have &#8212; we abide by public health guidelines as it relates to the President&#8217;s engagements.&nbsp; And if public health guidelines changed, which I&#8217;m not predicting, we would continue to abide by them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Voting rights, Jen?&nbsp; Voting rights?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll come to you next, April.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just a question on the meeting that you&#8217;re having with the housing industry &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; today at the White House.&nbsp; How concerned is the White House about the supply shortage in the industry leading to inflationary pressures?&nbsp; Is that a serious concern?&nbsp; Is that why this meeting is being held?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The &#8212; the meeting is being held as part of our effort to connect suppliers who have said, in the past, to our economic experts, they don&#8217;t always have the opportunity to talk to one another.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We know for &#8212; because of the pandemic, there have been supply shortages in areas that have led to a reduction of new building and construction, which has led to also an increase in housing prices, because there are just &#8212; certainly just not enough houses on the market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s what it&#8217;s related to, is an opportunity to discuss with them, bring them all together in a room.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s part of our multifaceted effort to address issues in the supply chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one on Cuba.&nbsp; The President did say yesterday that the United States is trying to reinstate Internet access &#8212;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; for Cubans.&nbsp; And I was wondering if &#8212; if the White House or the administration has reached out to U.S. tech companies &#8212; I mean the Googles of the world &#8212; to help with that effort.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So it would really be led &#8212; that effort would really be led by the State Department and other appropriate entities within the federal government.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the President noted yesterday, returning Internet access to Cuba would certainly be something we&#8217;d love to be a part of.&nbsp; It is &#8212; we&#8217;re looking at what our capacities and what our tools are we have.&nbsp; In terms of more specific &#8212; the specifics, the State Department would be the best entity to talk to about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, you said I was next.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Oh, sorry, April.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll come to you.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On voting rights &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Tuesday, President Biden said &#8212; he called for activists to act on the issue of voting rights.&nbsp; What did he mean by that?&nbsp; Is that to escalate it higher to Republicans so that they can change their minds and maybe stop using the filibuster?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, what does he think about what happened yesterday with the arrest of the congresswoman and nine other Black women who peacefully walked through the Senate halls in the Hart building, chanting and singing and were arrested &#8212; not taken to a holding cell &#8212; holding area, but taken to a jail cell?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, April, first, he &#8212; what he meant by speaking out or having your voice heard, or the range of ways he said it, is that in order to make change happen in Washington, often you need to create a grassroots movement that&#8217;s led by the American people.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s not just about whether we can &#8212; whether the minds of 10 Republicans can be changed directly by a phone call from a President.&nbsp; It often requires activism, engagement of vocal opposition or &#8212; or excitement from &#8212; from members of the public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s going to take a lot of different forms &#8212; right? &#8212; and formats.&nbsp; It can take letter writing, phone calling.&nbsp; There&#8217;s peaceful protesting.&nbsp; There are a range of mechanisms for that.&nbsp; And certainly, our country, even in recent years, has a great history of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And these &#8212; these members who were &#8212; some of them were members, I should say &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One member.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; One member who was arrested yesterday &#8212; they were peacefully protesting.&nbsp; I would note that our support for the right to peacefully protest and to voice support for moving forward on voting rights is exemplified by the fact that the Vice President is currently meeting right now with a number of members &#8212; they&#8217;re here, a number of them are at the White House discussing exactly this issue, because we want to be standing by their side in this effort.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So the &#8212; some of the civil rights leaders are here, as you said.&nbsp; But last week, when the civil rights leaders were here, they said, “This is a summer of action.”&nbsp; They&#8217;re expecting more protests.&nbsp; Reverend Barber says he&#8217;s going to have a bunch of women out on Monday.&nbsp; There&#8217;s going to be more protests on Wednesday.&nbsp; More arrests &#8212; they&#8217;re anticipating arrest to bring more attention to this.&nbsp; Does the White House support that civil disobedience for arrests?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We support the right to peacefully protest.&nbsp; We support people having their voices heard.&nbsp; And certainly, there are a few issues that are more fundamental to our rights in this country than the right to vote.</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, thank you &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; For Africa, please.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll go to you right next, if that’s okay. Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a clarifying question &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and then a follow-up on Afghanistan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yesterday, you said that 10,000 SIV applicants &#8212; or, excuse me, 20,000 Afghans have applied and that about half of that have completed necessary paperwork to move forward in the process.&nbsp; Just what’s &#8220;move forward in the process&#8221;?&nbsp; Does that mean 10,000 SIV applicants will be evacuated?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No, that&#8217;s not what it means.&nbsp; It just means that they&#8217;re in a later stage of the process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, it just &#8212; it &#8212; just giving an update kind of on the (inaudible).&nbsp; And as I said yesterday, that doesn&#8217;t include family members; that includes individual interpreters or translators.&nbsp; So it just means they&#8217;re farther forward in the process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There&#8217;s another step in the process, which is security vetting, which would need to be completed before any individual is relocated to a base in the United States.&nbsp; Individuals could be relocated to third countries before that process is completed. &nbsp;So it was just an update kind of on where people stand in the process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then just to take a step back, too &#8212; why did the administration wait until June 24th to commit to the evacuation? Why not have this be one of the early steps, right when the President announced this in April, I believe, while American troops were still on the ground?&nbsp; I mean, announcing this just days before the combat mission is essentially over would seem to complicate the mission.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, there&#8217;s always ongoing discussions, both with our partners in the region and others, before an announcement is made.&nbsp; And sometimes it requires a process to get to the point where you are making an announcement about the relocation of thousands of individuals out of a country.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, I would say: We&#8217;ve also committed to not only relocating these individuals in advance of our men and wo- &#8212; servicemen and women coming out of Afghanistan.&nbsp; We have quite a capable Department of Defense and diplomatic apparatus in Afghanistan and around the world to implement this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we&#8217;ve also committed to continuing this process from there and having a diplomatic presence on the ground from there.&nbsp; So, this is not a process that will end, but this is a process that we announced at a time when a final decision was made, based on a range of factors internally.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And have third countries outside of U.S. territories given the U.S. commitment &#8212; the administration commitment that they will house SIV applicants while they&#8217;re still having their applications processed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We&#8217;re having a range of discussions, as you know.&nbsp; When we&#8217;re at the point where we have final agreements, and we don&#8217;t &#8212; and we&#8217;re &#8212; we’re confident that it won&#8217;t impact the security of individuals who are being relocated, we&#8217;ll share all of that information with you as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But there&#8217;s no commitments as of today?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any updates to provide to you today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; What can Africa expect from this administration in terms of its engagement in helping solving some problems that we are having right now?&nbsp; For example, Angola is fighting corruption.&nbsp; And also, can we expect some revision in the sanctions in Zimbabwe?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any update for you on considerations around sanctions.&nbsp; I&#8217;d point you to the Department of Treasury or the Department of State on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We, of course, will remain deeply engaged with our African partners on a range of issues &#8212; whether it&#8217;s corruption, or facing and fighting the COVID pandemic, or economic opportunity and development.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would note that we have a number of leaders high up in the government, including our U.N. ambassador, Linda Thomas-Greenfield, who has spent quite a bit of time of working with leaders in the region and playing a front-and-center role for the United States government.&nbsp; But in terms of specifics on Zimbabwe or Angola, I would point you to the State Department.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Regarding misinformation, do you have any data that shows that children have been affected by misinformation?&nbsp; And how do you see if we should educate children about these issues?&nbsp; Because I&#8217;m working on a show that will inform little kids about many different things, and I&#8217;m also concerned about misinformation.&nbsp; So, in your research about misinformation, is there any misinformation affecting children as well?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a really interesting question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any data at my fingertips.&nbsp; I will reiterate that, of course, children are not eligible &#8212; under the age of 12 &#8212; yet for vaccines in the United States.&nbsp; And health &#8212; and health infor- &#8212; or decisions about the health of children &#8212; as a parent myself &#8212; would obviously be made by the parents in &#8212; in coordination with doctors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I would say there&#8217;s no question that when there&#8217;s information &#8212; the example I gave earlier about the impact on fertility of &#8212; which is inaccurate and false; which is still traveling around the Internet.&nbsp; If you&#8217;re a parent, that would give you pause, if you think that is accurate information, about your child and about your child getting vaccinated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s an example.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have data, but just an example that could be applicable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I had a question about the direct funding to states and cities from the American Rescue Plan &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the $350 mil- &#8212; billion.&nbsp; I was talking to the Treasury Department; about $200 billion has gone out, and several cities and states have been quick to allocate that money.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s other mayors and governors who I&#8217;ve talked to who have spent very little of that funding so far &#8212; in some cases, none of it &#8212; either because of battles with their state legislatures over the funds, their late budget cycles, lengthy public input processes, or they&#8217;re simply doing better than expected, revenue wise, and so there hasn&#8217;t been a sense of urgency for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, my questions are: You know, does it concern the White House that some places haven&#8217;t gotten their money out quicker?&nbsp; And does the White House have a message to governors and mayors that don&#8217;t have any plans yet to spend their funds?&nbsp; And finally, does that signal &#8212; the situation I described of not &#8212; of some folks not spending their money quickly &#8212; does that signal that the money wasn&#8217;t urgently needed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, the &#8212; in the &#8212; ensuring that states and local governments had the funding they needed to keep employees on the job, to keep cops on the beat, to rehire them, in many cases, was a priority when we were negotiating the American Rescue Plan for a range of elected officials, including mayors and governors across the country, for good reason.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It sounds like there&#8217;s some different case-by-case scenarios that have made it more challenging in certain governments and localities.&nbsp; We have an entire team here and at the Treasury Department that works closely with them.&nbsp; It may be most constructive for you to talk directly to them &#8212; either Gene Sperling or Jacob Leibenluft &#8212; about different issues that are having &#8212; happening in different cities or states.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you have confidence that money is being well spent and that, you know, they&#8217;re going to get it out to address what you identified as a problem for cities and states?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; And there is, of course, a range of options that cities and localities have for using the funding.&nbsp; And we wanted to provide that flexibility on purpose because one city or town or state does not fit all.&nbsp; One size doesn&#8217;t fit all, I should say, for cities, towns, and localities.&nbsp; That was important &#8212; that flexibility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are still restrictions on how it can be used and how it&#8217;s implemented.&nbsp; We, obviously, also &#8212; which is not what you&#8217;re asking, but I&#8217;m just going to reiterate &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; take waste, fraud, and abuse incredibly seriously.&nbsp; The President is “Sheriff Joe” in his heart and forever.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s something we watch, but I would &#8212; I would say it might be constructive for you to talk to them directly about the implementation piece, and I&#8217;m happy to connect you directly.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Jen, vaccination rates are actually going up in the five states that have the highest &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; case rates right now.&nbsp; What does the White House think is driving that?&nbsp; And what is being done there that the administration could apply to other hotspots?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Karen &#8212; and I know this was announced on our COVID briefing, for those of you who were not on it &#8212; in the past week, the five states with the highest case rates &#8212; Arkansas, Florida, Louisiana, Missouri, and Nevada &#8212; had a significantly higher rate of people getting newly vaccinated compared to the national average, which we obviously see is a good sign.&nbsp; And in the last 10 days, 5 million shots have been administered and millions got their first shots.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It&#8217;s hard to pinpoint one particular piece.&nbsp; But what I would say is that we&#8217;re continuing to work to apply the lessons we&#8217;ve learned over the last few months.&nbsp; The biggest issue far and away is access, and that means something different in different communities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In some communities, it is ensuring that people know that they can take time off of work &#8212; because of the kind of jobs they&#8217;re working.&nbsp; In some communities, it is meeting people where they are: in places of worship; mobile clinics, which is something we&#8217;re doing a lot in rural communities; walk-up pharmacy appointments; at their workplace or in schools.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We are also continuing to fund, support trusted messengers because we have seen, time and time again, that it is more effective.&nbsp; And many of you have covered political campaigns; this is not a surprise to most people who have covered a ca- &#8212; political campaigns.&nbsp; Trusted messengers are people in communities &#8212; they are neighbors, they are civic leaders, they are clergy.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not always the President of the Uni- &#8212; sometimes it is, but &#8212; and they are medical experts.</p>



<p>And so, we are continuing to support those efforts.&nbsp; We think that all of those have been effective.&nbsp; There&#8217;s still &#8212; still more work to be done, but certainly, that&#8217;s encouraging &#8212; those trends that we&#8217;ve seen.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, how concerned are you, though, that things have to get worse in these hotspots before they get better; that fear is driving the vaccination rate?&nbsp; How concerning is that to the White House?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that is not our preference.&nbsp; You know, that is why we have made vaccines so readily available for months now.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we have employed these tactics for months now &#8212; making vaccines readily available, accessible, working with trusted messengers and partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also, though, have seen &#8212; in some communities where local news stations are covering young people, unfortunately, who are getting sick &#8212; some being put on ventilators.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; I can&#8217;t tell you from data what impact that is having, but we are seeing, in areas where there are lower vaccination rates, some &#8212; some positive signs over the last week.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see if that continues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, thank you.&nbsp; I have two COVID questions and one voting rights question.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I’ll try to make it fast.&nbsp; On COVID, you and Dr. Walensky have used this phrase: “the pandemic of the unvaccinated.”&nbsp; And I am wondering if any part of that is the administration distancing itself from responsibility for the pandemic, because you&#8217;ve been trying to get people vaccinated, or if it&#8217;s a scare tactic.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first, the data speaks for itself, which 99.5 percent of people who are in hospitals because of COVID are unvaccinated.&nbsp; What it is our responsibility to do is provide accurate public health information to the public.&nbsp; It is also our responsibility to stay at it and continue to communicate, to fund programs, to support trusted messengers, to get out into local communities, to use what we see as creative partnerships, to meet people where they are.</p>



<p>We haven&#8217;t stopped that.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t halted it.&nbsp; We haven&#8217;t even slowed it down.&nbsp; But certainly, from the public health experts, et cetera &#8212; and I repeated what Dr. Walensky said, because she is, of course, a doctor and I am not &#8212; it is important for people to understand that the vaccine is safe.&nbsp; It will keep &#8212; it will protect them.&nbsp; And it is as simple as that sometimes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Olivia Rodrigo, was this sort of a one-off thing?&nbsp; I know that you had worked with other celebrities before and you announced the NASCAR thing, but is there more work with young celebrities or country stars or anything else that&#8217;s coming?&nbsp; Or was that more of &#8212; part of the month of action that&#8217;s behind us?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Wouldn&#8217;t it be great if this was the cue for like Blake Shelton and Gwen Stefani to come out &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; from &#8212; that would be awesome.&nbsp; I wish that was happening today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is &#8212; it is a part of an ongoing effort.&nbsp; And we want to partner with trusted voices and individuals in communities &#8212; many of whom you will never have heard of, and they may have five Twitter followers &#8212; if they&#8217;re on Twitter, which they probably are not if they&#8217;re not on the coast and not liberal.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we will also use &#8212; we&#8217;ll also work with celebrities.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Slipped that one in, didn&#8217;t you?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And we will work &#8212; we will also work with individuals like Olivia Rodrigo.&nbsp; I know I said this the other day, but obviously she&#8217;s a very well-known pop star.&nbsp; She&#8217;s 18 years old.&nbsp; She doesn&#8217;t have to use her time to do this.&nbsp; She is speaking to a broad swath of an audience that I bet you is not watching the White House briefing and is probably not watching the President of the United States.&nbsp; And we recognize that we need to meet people where they are, including as we use partnerships and medi- &#8212; and engage with media as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I&#8217;m very sorry to have one more.&nbsp; But on voting rights, you know, the President, on Tuesday, called on Congress to pass federal voting legislation.&nbsp; He spoke about the urgency of it.&nbsp; The question is: What comes next?&nbsp; Is he going to travel around the country and make this case?&nbsp; Is he going to go up to the Hill and have meetings specifically about voting rights?&nbsp; I know that he has talked about, you know, activist need to build the grassroots.&nbsp; But some activists are sort of pushing back on that idea, saying like, “We can&#8217;t always be the ones that are asked to do the work.”</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s not saying to do it alone.&nbsp; He&#8217;s saying, “I will be with you.”&nbsp; But he&#8217;s also saying that grassroots activism is what is going to move and change the country for the better.&nbsp; That&#8217;s always been the case throughout history.&nbsp; In terms of what he will say and do, I don&#8217;t have any scheduling announcements for you at this point in tim<a>e, but he has said this would be a cause of his presidency.&nbsp; That means he will use his time, use the plat- &#8212; his platform to make sure he&#8217;s speaking about elevating it, engaging in it.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>And, as you know, the Vice President &#8212; this will be a top priority for her.&nbsp; She will be front and center for the administration on this issue moving forward.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Just given the Wednesday timeline that Senator Schumer has laid out, what will the President be doing over the weekend to help things move along?&nbsp; Will he be making calls all weekend?&nbsp; And then what&#8217;s his response as well to Republicans who are concerned that tougher enforcement in the IRS won&#8217;t be enough to generate enough revenue?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say: The President has proposed a number of ways to pay for these proposals that have &#8212; have been out there in the public and has been a part of these ongoing discussions, which are continuing.&nbsp; And those proposals &#8212; he has a number of proposals out there that would more than cover the cost of this &#8212; of this infrastructure agreement that do not violate what the Republicans have said is their red line in this case, which is the 2017 tax cuts, regardless of his point of view on that; we&#8217;ll take that on in the Build Back Better reconciliation package.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In terms of what he will be doing, the President is ready, willing, able, looking forward to playing any constructive role he can play in getting these pieces of legislation across the finish line.&nbsp; Will that mean phone calls?&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Will it mean bringing more people to the White House?&nbsp; It probably will.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have anything to, kind of, lay out for you here.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And separately, has the intelligence community attributed the Kaseya ransomware attack to the Russian government?&nbsp; And has it been concluded that the RNC was indeed hacked?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say: The RNC put out a statement, when that news came out, saying it was a third party that had their information accessed, not the RNC &#8212; a vendor of the RNC’s.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of the information there changing.&nbsp; I would point you to them on that.&nbsp; The FBI is, of course, doing an investigation and in touch with them.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think they&#8217;ve put out any new information since then.</p>



<p>In terms of the Kaseya attack, we have pointed to the fact that REvil has &#8212; many cyber experts have &#8212; have attributed &#8212; have assessed their engagement here.&nbsp; We have not attributed the Russian government&#8217;s involvement in this case.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an ongoing &#8212; an ongoing review, but we have not &#8212; we don&#8217;t have any new information on that front.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Jen.&nbsp; I&#8217;m curious if the uptick in the Delta variant, if that is playing any part in where the President is leaning in terms of extending that federal mask policy on public transportation?&nbsp; I know it&#8217;s set to expire in September.&nbsp; Is he leaning towards extending that even more?&nbsp; We&#8217;re seeing some health officials say that they want to extend it even now.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s going to lean into the advice of his health and medical experts and teams on any steps that need to be taken to keep the American people safe.&nbsp; Given we&#8217;re talking about September, I know that feels like a short period of time away.&nbsp; It is actually some time away.&nbsp; But he&#8217;ll continue to receive updates from them on a range of issues as it relates to COVID.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;ll discuss this and their views.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on that same note, he said yesterday that he&#8217;s going to take into consideration some factors before he talks about what will happen with the European travel ban.&nbsp; Is that going to play a part into that with the Delta variant coming up?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as it relates to the travel ban, we certainly know we&#8217;ve made important progress in the pandemic.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll continue to put public health first.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President &#8212; all decisions about reopening international travel will be guided by our public health and medical experts.&nbsp; There are ongoing working groups that are having these discussions to keep open lines of communication.&nbsp; He will be receiving an update soon, I believe &#8212; if not today, then in the coming days &#8212; on where things stand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we must be vigilant, particularly about the spread of variants.&nbsp; We’ll reopen when health and medical experts expect it is safe to do so.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; Does the President plan to reappoint the Fed Chairman to another term?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have no announcements or pronouncements on the Federal Reserve Chair or any other personnel to convey to you today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a timeline for that decision?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a timeline to project.&nbsp; I know that there&#8217;s a timeline for when the &#8212; when his &#8212; his service is &#8212; will need to be reviewed or determined.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I do a quick follow-up on that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Let me just get around.&nbsp; Let me just get around.&nbsp; Let me just get around.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I had a question about the Belarus, if I may &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Belarusian opposition leader, Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, will be in Washington next week.&nbsp; And she said she would meet high-ranking officials.&nbsp; I was wondering whether you have details about that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t with me. Let us get it to you after the briefing.&nbsp; Members of the national security team or the State Department &#8212; was she more specific &#8212; or just people from the U.S. government?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; She just said “high-ranking officials.”</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Let us get you more information after the briefing.</p>



<p>Reese, who is our special guest from &#8212; tell us where you&#8217;re from.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Oklahoma.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Who’s not been &#8212; have you been here before?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;ve never been here before.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Dun-dun-dun.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Welcome.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; So I &#8212; my question is really just about what we kind of touched on &#8212; the vaccination rates in like rural country &#8212; rural counties.&nbsp; Especially in Oklahoma, we&#8217;re seeing a significant rise in COVID cases.&nbsp; Is there any specific plans that the administration has to help increase vaccination rates in these rural counties that &#8212; really, these people don&#8217;t have any intentions of even getting the vaccine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ve talked about this a little bit.&nbsp; But what we&#8217;re doing in rural communities is employing a number of the tactics that we&#8217;ve seen work around the country.&nbsp; So, we also &#8212; we know access is a huge issue in rural communities, because people may not le- &#8212; live near a pharmacy.&nbsp; They may not know, still, where to get a vaccine.&nbsp; We certainly understand that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, part of what we&#8217;re trying to do is deploy and make sure we&#8217;re expediting our deployment of mobile vaccine units to rural communities to bring the vaccine to people where they are and where they live to make it as easy as possible.&nbsp; And so, this work is going to continue person to person, community to community.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re also working with a range of trusted part- &#8212; partners, locally, you may &#8212; people may not have heard of &#8212;&nbsp; those are also very important trusted voices &#8212; but also groups like the National Rural Health Association to make sure that we&#8217;re deploying effective tactics that they think will work to get vaccines out to communities and meet people where they are.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve talked about it a little bit here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And obviously, these states have a combination of rural and city communities, but there are states &#8212; states like Arkansas, Louisiana, Missouri &#8212; where there are large, rural communities where we have seen an uptick, which is a po- &#8212; in terms of vacci- &#8212; getting vaccinated, higher than the na- &#8212; national average.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a positive sign.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ll look at that and apply those tactics other places &#8212; in Oklahoma &#8212; to make sure we&#8217;re continuing to go community by community to meet people where they are.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And following up on that: I know the administration has said they&#8217;re not interested in any sort of federal mandate.&nbsp; Do you encourage, though, employers to require the vaccine for their employees?&nbsp; Or state and local &#8212; I know there&#8217;s a little bit of discussion about local governments.&nbsp; Is the White House encouraging others to require the vaccine of their employees or their residents?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We know that some employers, hospitals, health systems, colleges, universities, local leaders have chosen to take this step.&nbsp; And we expect others to do so as well.&nbsp; But our role we&#8217;re playing from here is continuing to go community by community, person to person, making sure we are meeting people where they are to get the vaccine out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We believe that local communities, entities, organizations are going to make decisions about what they need to do to keep their community safe.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what about for federal workers or members of the military?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new to report on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Question.&nbsp; The Justice Department Inspector General&#8217;s report on the FBI handling the Nassar case &#8212; that&#8217;s the latest embarrassment in a string of embarrassments for the FBI this summer.&nbsp; Does the President have complete confidence in Christopher Wray?&nbsp; And what is the administration&#8217;s message to people who see this bungling and want to know if the FBI is up to task with ransomware, domestic terrorism, and other threats?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would &#8212; I would point you all to the expansive statement that was put out by the FBI in response to the Inspector General&#8217;s report.&nbsp; Second, yes, he has confidence in Christopher Wray.&nbsp; Third, as it relates to ransomware, this is an across-government interagency effort, one that we have not seen done in the past.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I gave a little bit of an update in a readout of it yesterday, where we&#8217;re tapping into all of the resources and expertise across the federal government.&nbsp; The FBI has been a key partner in that, as have another &#8212; number of entities in our national security team who can play a role in fighting against ransomware.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; And then we&#8217;ll go &#8212; oh, I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll go to you in the back.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, you haven&#8217;t talked about APEC.&nbsp; This was a &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; conversation that the President had this morning.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No one has asked about it.&nbsp; Now is the moment.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m asking right now.&nbsp; And so there seems to be a convergence between President Biden, President Xi, and also President Putin in terms of making and sharing and distributing vaccines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My question is the mechanism of it.&nbsp; We know that APEC supports the TRIPS waiver, as does President Biden.&nbsp; Was there pressure from APEC member countries to have the U.S. put more diplomatic pressures on WTO countries to pass the patent waivers?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say the President&#8217;s view continues to be exactly as you laid it out there.&nbsp; This is a long-going &#8212; ongoing process.&nbsp; And Ambassador Tai is our lead representative in these discussions and negotiations.&nbsp; The APEC summit, for any of you who watched parts of it, was virtual and was individuals delivering sets of remarks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It wasn&#8217;t an interactive opportunity, I would say, and President Xi actually delivered prerecorded remarks, so he wasn&#8217;t even there participating in person.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to follow up on the health misinformation &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Or on virtually live, I should say.&nbsp; Yes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Following up on the health misinformation, do you consider claims by some in the conservative circles that ivermectin &#8212; am I pronouncing that right? &#8212; as a promising treatment for COVID as misinformation?&nbsp; I know that the FDA has weighed in on this &#8212; I believe in March &#8212; but I just wanted the administration&#8217;s latest position on the drug.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Information that&#8217;s inaccurate we consider misinformation.&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s more complicated than that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go &#8212; oh, oh.&nbsp; Let Ebony go.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Did you all delay the departure?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Did we what?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you all delayed the departure?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, we were supposed to gather at 2:10, but I was told hard out at 2:15.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, we were supposed to gather.&nbsp; I’m just making sure that &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, okay.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Brian, thank you.&nbsp; You get an internship or something, I don&#8217;t know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; we have four more minutes left.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll get to as many as we can.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead, Ebony.&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; And then we’ll go &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The women that are meeting with the Vice President today, most of which have basically said that they want the President to really talk about the filibuster &#8212; removing it or reforming the filibuster.&nbsp; And so, with each of the meetings that they&#8217;re having, still coming out wondering, what is the hope that&#8217;s going to happen?&nbsp; Because just about every single woman that is in that room has spoken about it.&nbsp; That&#8217;s my first &#8212; my first question.</p>



<p>And even though you also said that there isn&#8217;t a plan right now for the President to go to Arizona or to go to other states,&nbsp; why isn&#8217;t there, right now, that kind of plan?&nbsp; Because they have come out and said that they put &#8212; the administration has put a lot on them, but they&#8217;re waiting to see something back.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;ve laid out for you what we know about our schedule, which is through next Wednesday.&nbsp; So it doesn&#8217;t mean that he&#8217;s not going to go out in the country and talk about a range of important priorities in the future.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t want you to take it that way.&nbsp; That was not what I was implying.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re &#8212; we’re about &#8212; we have about four days out here, in terms of our scheduling, that I can provide to all of you.</p>



<p>As it relates to the women who are in this room, let&#8217;s see; maybe they&#8217;ll go to the stakeout and they&#8217;ll talk about their meeting and their engagement.&nbsp; And the message that the President is sending, the Vice President is sending is that we&#8217;re absolutely committed to getting the For the People Act signed into law; that we&#8217;re committed to advocating for, to elevating voting rights &#8212; is an important issue for people across this country.&nbsp; And I think our actions clearly exemplify that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quickly, a clarifying question &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on how you identify this misinformation.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you could tell us specifically how the administration identifies what is misinformation and how you flag it to Facebook?&nbsp; That&#8217;s one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Two is: How many times had the administration flagged this kind of information?</p>



<p>And then three, how long has this been going?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, finally, I know that you are deadly serious about this conversation.&nbsp; You talked about how this is life and death.&nbsp; But are there any types of safeguards that the administration is putting in place to make certain that they do not chill free speech while they are going after this kind of misinformation?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; First of all, to be crystal clear: Any decision about platform usage and who should be on the platform is orchestrated and determined by private-sector companies.&nbsp; Facebook is one of them, right?&nbsp; And there are a range of media who are &#8212; also have their own criteria and rules in place, and they implement them.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s their decision to do.&nbsp; That is not the federal government doing that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is life and death.&nbsp; It is a public health issue in the country.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the Surgeon General was here talking about it yesterday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are trends, we can see, any &#8212; you can all probably see on Facebook and other social media platforms.&nbsp; And so what we raise are issues like: there is a lot of information out there about &#8212; about the false claim that COVID-19 causes infertility.&nbsp; Everyone in this room knows that&#8217;s factually inaccurate.&nbsp; We raised for them, in our direct channels &#8212; of which every administration has always had with every social media platform &#8212; that we are seeing this trend.&nbsp; It&#8217;s troubling.&nbsp; That information is inaccurate.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But specifically, so you&#8217;re not going after &#8212; you&#8217;re saying these are general areas of misinformation that you should take a look at &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; and not specific posts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, it is also publicly available who the individuals are who have &#8212; who have spread most of the information.&nbsp; It wasn&#8217;t publicly available by the United States government.&nbsp; It&#8217;s publicly available information.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s how it works.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Cross-talk.)</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, thank you, everyone.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got to wrap it up.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>2:17 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Summit on the Homebuilding Supply Chain</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/16/readout-of-white-house-summit-on-the-homebuilding-supply-chain/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 21:40:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24267</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Marcia Fudge, National Economic Council Director Brian Deese, and Council of Economic Advisers Chair Cecilia Rouse hosted a virtual event with CEOs and senior executives across the housing and homebuilding sector to discuss supply chain disruptions in the homebuilding industry as well as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, Secretary of Commerce Gina Raimondo, Secretary of Housing and Urban Development Marcia Fudge, National Economic Council Director Brian Deese, and Council of Economic Advisers Chair Cecilia Rouse hosted a virtual event with CEOs and senior executives across the housing and homebuilding sector to discuss supply chain disruptions in the homebuilding industry as well as shortages in the availability of homes for purchase and rent. The convening included housing advocates and representatives from builders, lumber companies, retailers, realtors, loggers and labor unions, as well as other companies and organizations focused on homebuilding and affordable housing. &nbsp;<br><br>The U.S. has a longstanding shortage of affordable housing, and participants discussed how that challenge is being exacerbated by short-term supply chain disruptions across the homebuilding sector, including fluctuations in lumber prices, supply chain disruptions in other critical inputs including resins and engineered wood products, transportation challenges with ports and trucking, and underinvestment in training and skilled workforce development.&nbsp;<br><br>Participants discussed core challenges across the housing supply chain, and helped Administration leaders collect additional input to inform the Administration’s near- and medium-term efforts to further strengthen housing supply. Participants also focused on the demand for housing and how the President’s necessary and historic investments in the Build Back Better agenda will expand housing supply and strengthen the country’s affordable housing stock.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Seven Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/16/president-biden-announces-seven-key-nominations-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 19:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles: Laurie E. Locascio, Nominee for Under Secretary for Standards and Technology, Department of Commerce Andrew Hunter, Assistant Secretary of the Air Force, Acquisition, Technology, Logistics, Department of Defense James D. Rodriguez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following seven individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>Laurie E. Locascio, Nominee for Under Secretary for Standards and Technology, Department of Commerce</li><li>Andrew Hunter, Assistant Secretary of the Air Force, Acquisition, Technology, Logistics, Department of Defense</li><li>James D. Rodriguez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Veterans Employment and Training, Department of Labor</li><li>Caryn R. McClelland, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Brunei Darussalam</li><li>Michael J. Murphy, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Bosnia and Herzegovina</li><li>Tom Udall, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to New Zealand and to the Independent State of Samoa</li><li>Howard A. Van Vranken, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Republic of Botswana</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Laurie E. Locascio, Nominee for Under Secretary for Standards and Technology, Department of Commerce</u></strong></p>



<p>Laurie E. Locascio, Ph.D., is the Vice President for Research at the University of Maryland, College Park and the University of Maryland, Baltimore. In this role, Dr. Locascio oversees the University of Maryland’s vibrant research and innovation enterprise at these two campuses, which garner a combined $1.1 billion in external research funding each year. Within Locascio’s purview are the development of large interdisciplinary research programs, technology commercialization, innovation and economic development efforts, and strategic partnerships with industry, federal, academic, and nonprofit collaborators. She is a professor in Maryland’s Fischell Department of Bioengineering, and professor (secondary) in the Department of Pharmacology at the University of Maryland School of Medicine.</p>



<p>Prior to the University of Maryland, Dr. Locascio had a long fruitful career as a researcher, innovator, and scientific leader at the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST).&nbsp; Her last role at NIST was Acting Principal Deputy Director and Associate Director for Laboratory Programs. In that position, she was responsible for leading the internal scientific research and laboratory programs across two campuses in Gaithersburg, MD and Boulder, CO.</p>



<p>Locascio received a B.Sc. in chemistry from James Madison University, a M.Sc. in bioengineering from the University of Utah, and a Ph.D. in toxicology from the University of Maryland, Baltimore. As a biomedical researcher, she published more than 100 scientific papers and 11 patents.</p>



<p><strong><u>Andrew Hunter, Assistant Secretary of the Air Force, Acquisition, Technology, Logistics, Department of Defense</u></strong></p>



<p>Andrew Hunter is as a senior fellow in the International Security Program and Director of the Defense-Industrial Initiatives Group at the Center for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS) where he has worked since November 2014.&nbsp; He focuses his research at CSIS on the defense acquisition system, the defense industrial base, defense technology issues, and defense trade. From 2011 to November 2014, Mr. Hunter served as a senior executive in the Department of Defense (DOD).&nbsp; Appointed as Director of the Joint Rapid Acquisition Cell in 2013, his duties included fielding solutions to urgent operational needs and leading the work of the Warfighter Senior Integration Group to ensure timely action on critical issues of warfighter support.&nbsp; From 2011 to 2012, Mr. Hunter served as the Chief of Staff to the Honorable Ashton B. Carter and the Honorable Frank Kendall, while each was serving as Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics.&nbsp; Additional duties while at DOD included providing support to the Deputy’s Management Action Group and leading a team examining ways to reshape acquisition statutes.</p>



<p>From 2005 to 2011, Mr. Hunter served as a Professional Staff Member of the House Armed Services Committee, leading the committee’s policy staff and managing a portfolio focused on acquisition policy, the defense industrial base, technology transfers, and export controls. From 1994 to 2005, Mr. Hunter served in a variety of staff positions in the House of Representatives including as Appropriations Associate for Congressman Norman D. Dicks; as Military Legislative Assistant and Legislative Director for Congressman John M. Spratt, Jr.; and as a staff member for the Select Committee on U.S. National Security and Military/Commercial Concerns with the People’s Republic of China. Mr. Hunter holds a Master of Arts degree in Applied Economics from The Johns Hopkins University and a Bachelor of Arts degree in Social Studies from Harvard University.</p>



<p><strong><u>James D. Rodriguez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Veterans Employment and Training, Department of Labor</u></strong></p>



<p>James D. Rodriguez is the current Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for Policy within the Department of Labor’s Veterans’ Employment and Training Services agency responsible for preparing America&#8217;s veterans, service members, and their spouses for meaningful careers upon transition from active duty.</p>



<p>Mr. Rodriguez is an executive leader and retired Marine with over 30 years as a leader in the U.S. government, corporate sector, and United States Marine Corps. He possesses a comprehensive background in program management, interagency collaboration, and policy development. He also has extensive senior level experience building and managing multi-million-dollar budgets and large diverse teams to include his recent executive experience in leadership roles within Deloitte LLP’s Government and Public Sector practice and BAE Systems Inc. Government relations department. He also previously served as the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense, Office of Warrior Care Policy, Office of the Secretary of Defense from 2014 through 2017.</p>



<p>Mr. Rodriguez possesses a Bachelor’s Degree in Political Science from the University of Maryland, University College and a Masters of Arts Degree in International Commerce and Policy from the George Mason University School of Public Policy.&nbsp; He also serves as an adjunct faculty member in the government and political science department within the University of Maryland Global Campus. He is married to Vanessa Rodriguez and has two daughters, Courtney and Casey.</p>



<p><strong><u>Caryn R. McClelland, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Brunei Darussalam</u></strong></p>



<p>Caryn R. McClelland, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the Minister Counselor for Economic Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in London.&nbsp; She previously served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. embassies in Vietnam and Latvia, and as Consul General in Surabaya, Indonesia.&nbsp; She also served at the U.S. embassies in Azerbaijan, Malaysia, Turkmenistan and Ireland.&nbsp; She was Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, and Deputy Special Representative for Commercial and Business Affairs in the Bureau of Economic and Business Affairs at the Department of State.&nbsp; Earlier, McClelland was Senior Advisor for Caspian Basin Energy Diplomacy, and Regional Energy Advisor in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs.&nbsp; McClelland earned a B.A. at the University of California &#8211; Los Angeles, an M.A. at San Francisco State University, and an M.S. at the National War College.&nbsp; She speaks Indonesian, Latvian and Russian</p>



<p><strong><u>Michael J. Murphy, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Bosnia and Herzegovina</u></strong></p>



<p>Michael J. Murphy, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as a Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs.&nbsp; He oversees European security, including NATO, the OSCE, conventional arms control, and Arctic security policy, as well as bilateral relations with the Northern European and Baltic countries.&nbsp; Previously, Mr. Murphy served as Director of the Office for European Security &amp; Political-Military Affairs in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs.&nbsp; Earlier, he served as the Associate Dean of the Leadership and Management School at the National Foreign Affairs Training Center.&nbsp; Prior to that, Mr. Murphy was the Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Gaborone, Botswana and also as Chargé d’Affaires, a.i., in Botswana.&nbsp; He was Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Pristina, Kosovo and served for three years as Political Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in Sarajevo, Bosnia and Herzegovina.&nbsp; Other overseas postings include London, United Kingdom; Yaoundé, Cameroon; and Lagos, Nigeria.&nbsp; In Washington, D.C., he served as Chief of Staff to both the Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs and the Director General of the Foreign Service.&nbsp; Prior to joining the Foreign Service, Murphy worked in the U.S. Congress as the Senior Legislative Aide to Congresswoman Marilyn Lloyd of Tennessee.&nbsp; He is a Phi Beta Kappa graduate of Hamilton College with a Bachelor of Arts degree in International Relations.&nbsp; He speaks Serbo-Croatian and French.</p>



<p><strong><u>Tom Udall, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to New Zealand and to the Independent State of Samoa</u></strong></p>



<p>Tom Udall has a long and distinguished career in public service.&nbsp; He most recently served two terms as United States Senator from New Mexico (2009-2021) and served five terms as United States Representative from New Mexico’s 3rd Congressional District (1999-2009).&nbsp; While in office, Udall was a notable champion for the environment, for Native Americans, for government and election reform and for resolving international disputes peacefully, if possible.&nbsp; Earlier in his career, Udall was elected twice as Attorney General of New Mexico (1991-1999) and also served as an Assistant United States Attorney.&nbsp; His Senate Committee assignments included the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Committee on Indian Affairs, the Committee on Rules and Administration, the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, and the International Narcotics Control Caucus.&nbsp; Udall has a B.A. degree from Prescott College, a Bachelor of Law from Cambridge University, and a J.D. from the University of New Mexico.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Howard A. Van Vranken, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to Republic of Botswana</u></strong></p>



<p>Howard A. Van Vranken, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as Executive Director and Deputy Executive Secretary for the Executive Secretariat at the U.S. Department of State. Previously, he was Executive Director and Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs and Deputy Executive Director in the Executive Office for the Bureaus of Near Eastern Affairs and South and Central Asian Affairs. Earlier, Van Vranken was Management Counselor and, prior to that, the Deputy Political Counselor, for U.S. Embassy Baghdad.&nbsp; Van Vranken served in Israel as Management Officer and later as Acting Political Counselor in Jerusalem and as the Human Resource Officer at the Embassy in Tel Aviv. He was also the leader of a Provincial Reconstruction Team in Babil Province, Iraq. Van Vranken earned his B.A. degree from the University of California, Davis and his M.A. from Harvard University Kennedy School of Government. He speaks Arabic, Farsi, and Norwegian.&nbsp; He is the recipient of as the Presidential Distinguished Service Award.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by NSC Spokesperson Emily Horne on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of Turkey</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/16/statement-by-nsc-spokesperson-emily-horne-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-ibrahim-kalin-spokesperson-and-chief-advisor-to-the-president-of-turkey-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 18:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of Turkey. Following the meeting between President Joe Biden and President Recep Tayyip Erdogan on June 14, Mr. Sullivan and Dr. Kalin discussed a range of regional issues. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Ibrahim Kalin, Spokesperson and Chief Advisor to the President of Turkey. Following the meeting between President Joe Biden and President Recep Tayyip Erdogan on June 14, Mr. Sullivan and Dr. Kalin discussed a range of regional issues.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/16/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-45/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 18:26:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[11:07 A.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:&#160; Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&#160; Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic and the Delta variant.&#160; Then, Dr. Fauci will present the data from other countries facing the Delta variant.&#160; I will provide an update on how we’re working on a number&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>11:07 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Good morning, and thanks for joining us.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, Dr. Walensky will provide an update on the state of the pandemic and the Delta variant.&nbsp; Then, Dr. Fauci will present the data from other countries facing the Delta variant.&nbsp; I will provide an update on how we’re working on a number of fronts to manage this virus.&nbsp; And Dr. Murthy will discuss vaccine confidence with a focus on combatting misinformation and disinformation.&nbsp; And then we’ll open it up for a few questions.<br><br>Now, over to you, Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Let’s begin with an overview of the data.<br><br>Yesterday, CDC reported more than 33,000 new cases of COVID-19.&nbsp; Our seven-day average is about 26,300 cases per day, and this represents an increase of nearly 70 percent from the prior seven-day average.<br><br>The seven-day average of hospital admissions is about 2,790 per day &#8212; an increase of about 36 percent from the previous seven-day period.&nbsp; And, after weeks of declines, seven-day average daily deaths have increased by 26 percent to 211 per day.<br><br>Today, Dr. Fauci and I want to provide some perspective about these numbers and how we should be thinking about where we are at this critical moment in the pandemic.<br><br>There is a clear message that is coming through: This is becoming a pandemic of the unvaccinated.&nbsp; We are seeing outbreaks of cases in parts of the country that have low vaccination coverage because unvaccinated people are at risk.&nbsp; And communities that are fully vaccinated are generally faring well.<br><br>You can see the patterns of local outbreaks in the slide of community transmission.&nbsp; The blue and yellow counties have low or moderate transmission.&nbsp; The orange and red counties have substantial to high transmission.&nbsp; On the left, you can see where we were just a short month ago, and compare it to where we are now, on the right.&nbsp;<br><br>In the last week, 10 percent of counties have moved into “high transmission risk,” in the red, and 7 percent of counties have moved into “substantial risk,” in the orange.&nbsp; Those counties most frequently correspond to counties with low vaccination rates.&nbsp;<br><br>When we look over time, we can put these increasing cases in perspective.&nbsp; In January, shown in the middle of the slide, we were averaging nearly 200,000 cases per day.&nbsp; The entire country was in a high level of transmission.&nbsp;<br><br>You can see that from January to June, as you move from left to right on the slide, we made remarkable progress, where the percent of counties with high transmission decreased &#8212; as shown by the decrease in red, and increases in blue and yellow.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, in the upper righthand corner, which is where we are today, you can see the recent growth in cases where the red and orange are again increasing.&nbsp; So, while we are in a far better position than we were in January through April, this increased in red area is giving us all a reason to double-down and get more people vaccinated.<br><br>The good news is that if you are fully vaccinated, you are protected against severe COVID, hospitalization, and death, and are even protected against the known variants &#8212; including the Delta variant &#8212; circulating in the country.<br><br>If you are not vaccinated, you remain at risk.&nbsp; And our biggest concern is that we are going to continue to see preventable cases, hospitalizations, and, sadly, deaths among the unvaccinated.<br><br>Lastly, I want to reiterate the importance of getting fully vaccinated.&nbsp; I want to reiterate that people who got the Pfizer and Moderna vaccines are most effective, especially when &#8212; against the Delta variant when given as two shots in a series.&nbsp;<br><br>Both vaccines are most effective two weeks after the second dose, with each exceeding 90 percent effectiveness against severe disease, hospitalization, and death in real-world studies.&nbsp; Not completing the series puts those partially vaccinated at risk of illness.&nbsp;<br><br>We encourage that people get vaccinated on schedule three or four weeks after your first dose.&nbsp; But if you are beyond that window, I want to reiterate: There is no bad time to get your second shot.<br><br>Do it for yourself, your family, and for your community.&nbsp; And please do it to protect your young children who, right now, can’t get vaccinated themselves. &nbsp;<br><br>With that, I will now turn it over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Thank you very much, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to continue it along the lines that Dr. Walensky had mentioned, but now maybe take a look at it from a global standpoint, if I could have the first slide.&nbsp;<br><br>Clearly, the Delta variant is dominant in the world.&nbsp; If you look at this map of the world, they&#8217;re at about 100 countries that have now have the Delta variant that is detected in them in June of &#8212; since June in 2020.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>If you look at the average daily prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 Delta variant worldwide, if you look at the righthand part of the slide, you see the extraordinary surge in the dominance of this variant worldwide.&nbsp;<br><br>And we, as was mentioned in several briefings that we&#8217;ve had, are seeing increment in our own country to the point of now having more than 50 percent dominance and, in some areas of the country, greater than 70 percent.<br><br>That is the sobering news, but take a look at what&#8217;s going on worldwide with hospitalizations.&nbsp; Although Israel has the same issue with the dominance of the Delta strain, their hospitalizations have dramatically diminished.&nbsp; And if you look at the far right of the slide, as of just a couple of days ago, they are very low. &nbsp;<br><br>In the next slide, we see the UK.&nbsp; Similar.&nbsp; A dramatic diminution in hospitalizations.&nbsp;<br><br>However, if you look at the trend on the far righthand part of that slide, there’s that uptick, which somehow was reflecting what Dr. Walensky just told you about the slight uptick that we&#8217;re seeing in hospitalizations in our own country.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide.&nbsp;<br><br>However, we know that the vaccines that are listed on the lefthand part of this slide that are being used in this country &#8212; namely the Pfizer, Moderna, and the J&amp;J &#8212; both in lab studies and in clinical effectiveness studies show the effectiveness of these vaccines against the Delta variant, particularly, and importantly, against hospitalization.&nbsp;<br><br>Next slide shows data from the UK with the Delta variant, which the Pfizer-BioNTech, which clearly reflects what we&#8217;ll be seeing with Moderna, is 96 percent effective against hospitalization.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line is: We are dealing with a formidable variant in the Delta variant, as reflected by the data that Dr. Walensky told you, and the extreme vulnerability of people who are not vaccinated, which will account for infections, hospitalizations, and, ultimately, deaths.<br><br>And so the message loud and clear that we need to reiterate is that these vaccines continue to strong protection against SARS-CoV-2, including the Delta variant.&nbsp; And so &#8212; why it&#8217;s so important for yourself, your family, and your community to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>Back to you, Jeff.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Dr. Fauci and Dr. Walensky.<br><br>Stepping back, we have come a long way in our fight against this virus.&nbsp; Because we have fully vaccinated more than 160 million Americans, we&#8217;ve fundamentally changed the course of this pandemic from one that puts the lives and livelihoods of all Americans at risk, to one that predominantly threatens unvaccinated people.<br><br>As Dr. Walensky said, as the more transmissible Delta variant continues to spread across the country, we will likely continue and experi- &#8212; continue to experience an increase in COVID cases in the weeks ahead, with these cases concentrated in communities with lower vaccination rates.&nbsp;<br><br>In fact, just four states accounted for more than 40 percent of all cases in the past week, with one in five of all cases occurring in Florida alone.&nbsp; And within communities, these cases are occurring primarily among unvaccinated individuals.&nbsp;<br><br>At the same time, as Dr. Fauci said, because we have so many people fully vaccinated, including about 80 percent of seniors &#8212; those who are most vulnerable, those over 65 years of age &#8212; we will likely see smaller increases in hospitalizations, similar to the Israel and UK experience.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line continues to be very, very simple: While fully vaccinated individuals have a high degree of protection against serious illness from COVID-19, including the Delta variant, unvaccinated Americans are not protected against serious illness, hospitalization, and death.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;re seeing it in the data.&nbsp; Unvaccinated Americans account for virtually all recent COVID-19 hospitalizations and deaths.&nbsp; Each COVID-19 death is tragic.&nbsp; And those happening now are even more tragic because they are preventable.&nbsp;<br><br>Every American 12 and older, no matter where they live, has vaccines readily available to them.&nbsp; So, if you are unvaccinated, please get vaccinated now.&nbsp; The vaccines work.&nbsp; It’s safe, it’s free, it’s readily available, and it’s never been more important.<br><br>As we manage this virus, our whole-of-government effort continues to work to get more people vaccinated, address areas where we’re seeing outbreaks among the unvaccinated, and prepare for every scenario.<br><br>First and foremost, we continue to vaccinate hundreds of thousands of new people each day &#8212; meeting unvaccinated Americans where they are, answering their questions, helping them make up their mind, and making it even easier and more convenient to get a shot as soon as they are ready to do so.<br><br>We’re doing this by trus- &#8212; by entrusting and empowering messengers &#8212; trusted messengers &#8212; to have the conversations we know work&nbsp;&#8212; whether it’s vaccinated people in communities across the country talking directly to their neighbors, sharing their own vaccination journey and answering question; or it’s Olivia Rodrigo using her voice and platform to spread the word.<br><br>We’re working with doctors, pharmacists, employers, educators, and school administrators to bring vaccines to where people are.<br><br>And as Dr. Murthy will discuss, we’re taking disinformation and misinformation head on.<br><br>We continue to see efforts to deliberately mislead the American people about the importance of vaccination.&nbsp; Those who peddle and promote these dangerous lies are harming the very people who are most at risk and furthering a pandemic that has already taken more than 600,000 American lives.<br><br>We are calling on everyone &#8212; social media platforms, news organizations, individual Americans &#8212; to call this activity out and to help get the facts out to your friends, families, and communities so that we&#8217;re protecting our fellow Americans, not purposely putting them in harm’s way.<br><br>As I said last week, vaccinating more and more Americans each day is an individual-by-individual, community-by-community effort.&nbsp; And this type of localized, person-to-person approach takes some time, but it is working.<br><br>In the past 10 days, 5 million Americans have rolled up their sleeves to get a shot in their arms, and millions more Americans will get vaccinated across the summer months.<br><br>Importantly, states with the highest case rates are seeing their vaccination rates go up.&nbsp; In fact, in the past week, the five states with the highest case rates &#8212; Arkansas, Florida, Louisiana, Missouri, and Nevada &#8212; had a higher rate of people getting newly vaccinated compared to the national average.<br><br>At the same time, our COVID-19 Surge Response Teams are working with governors and local public health officials to provide specific federal resources and capabilities to fight outbreaks due to the spread of the Delta variant.<br><br>We are already helping many states to identify and address specific needs, including testing, therapeutics, and vaccinations.&nbsp; And this week, at the request of the Nevada governor, we are deploying more than a hundred people to the state to help enhance vaccine access and support vaccine outreach efforts.<br><br>And we’re providing CDC’s technical expertise &#8212; including on genetic sequencing, data analysis, and outbreak response &#8212; to Missouri to help support the state in its response.<br><br>We stand ready to support our state partners with the help they need to curb the spread of the virus and increase vaccinations in their states.<br><br>And finally, we continue to be prepared for any and every scenario, including the possibility of booster shots, if and when the science shows they are needed.<br><br>At this time, the CDC and FDA have said Americans who have been fully vaccinated do not need a booster shot.&nbsp; Independent and rigorous scientific CDC and FDA processes will determine if and when boosters are needed and who might need a booster shot.<br><br>I want to be clear: The science will guide this.&nbsp; And as Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci are making clear, this is a question that they are continually evaluating.&nbsp; We are ready for whatever the science tells us.<br><br>We have secured enough vaccine supply, and, if needed, we will ensure Americans who might need a booster shot are able to get it quickly and easily.&nbsp;<br><br>Before I turn it over to Dr. Murthy, let me reiterate: The best thing we can do right now is to get more Americans vaccinated.&nbsp; Every person matters.&nbsp;&nbsp; Every shot matters.&nbsp; Every shot is progress.&nbsp; It’s another life protected.&nbsp; It’s another community that is safer.&nbsp; It’s another step toward putting this pandemic behind us.<br><br>Now, let me turn to Dr. Murthy. &nbsp;<br><br>Dr. Murthy.<br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; Well, thanks so much, Jeff.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s great to be with all of you again today.&nbsp; For months, on these briefings, we&#8217;ve talked about barriers to getting vaccinated.&nbsp; And today, I want to focus on the challenge of health misinformation that&#8217;s affecting millions of Americans.&nbsp;<br><br>Yesterday I issued a Surgeon General&#8217;s Advisory on the dangers of health misinformation.&nbsp; Surgeon General Advisories are reserved for urgent public health threats.&nbsp; And while those threats have often been related to what we eat, drink, and smoke, today we live in a world where misinformation poses an urgent and insidious threat to our nation&#8217;s health.&nbsp;<br><br>Health misinformation is false, inaccurate, or misleading information about health according to the best evidence at the time.&nbsp; And during this pandemic, health misinformation has led people to resist wearing masks in high-risk settings; to turn down proven treatments &#8212; in some cases to turn to unproven treatments and to choose not to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>All this has led to avoidable illnesses and deaths.&nbsp; Simply put, health misinformation has cost us lives.&nbsp; And just this week, I traveled to New Mexico to meet with youth leaders, clinicians, and public health leaders from across the state.&nbsp; And the common thread that ran through our conversations was their struggle to help their communities navigate information about COVID-19.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, health misinformation has been a problem long before COVID.&nbsp; What&#8217;s different now is the speed and scale at which health misinformation is spreading.&nbsp; If we want to address health misinformation, we&#8217;ll need an all-of-society response, and that&#8217;s why the advisory has recommendations for everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>First, we include recommendations for individuals and families.&nbsp; We&#8217;re asking people to raise their bar for sharing health information by checking sources before they share information to ensure it&#8217;s backed by credible, scientific sources.&nbsp; As we say in the advisory: If you are not sure, don&#8217;t share.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re also asking other organizations to do their part in every sector from health and education, to research and journalism, to philanthropy and government.&nbsp;<br><br>But very importantly, technology companies must act as well.&nbsp; Technology companies have enabled misinformation to poison our information environment with little accountability to their users.&nbsp; It allowed people who intentionally spread misinformation &#8212; what we call “disinformation” &#8212; to have extraordinary reach.<br><br>In this advisory, we&#8217;re telling technology companies that we expect more. &nbsp;We&#8217;re asking them to operate with greater transparency, to modify their algorithms to avoid amplifying misinformation, and to swiftly and consistently take action against misinformation super-spreaders on their platforms.<br><br>Shortly after releasing the advisory, we saw organizations &#8212; like the Rockefeller Foundation, the Digital Public Library of America, and the American Academy of Pediatrics &#8212; step up and respond to this call to action by committing their time, resources, and networks to confronting health misinformation.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m encouraged by these commitments because turning the tide against health misinformation will take all of us.&nbsp; The longer we wait, the more lives we lose.&nbsp;<br><br>As someone who has lost 10 family members to COVID-19 and who wishes each and every day that they had had access to the vaccine, it&#8217;s painful to know that nearly every death we are seeing now from COVID-19 could have been prevented.&nbsp;<br><br>The truth is that, across our nation, the voices of doctors, nurses, scientists, and public health experts are too often being drowned out by the false sirens of misinformation.&nbsp; Misinformation robs us of our freedom to make decisions for our health based on science and facts.<br><br>Addressing health misinformation is an urgent challenge, a moral and civic responsibility that we must meet together.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why I issued the Surgeon General Advisory.&nbsp; You can read the full advisory at SurgeonGeneral.gov/HealthMisinformation.<br><br>Thanks for your time.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll pass it back to Jeff.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Well, thanks, Dr. Murthy.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s take a few questions.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, Jeff.&nbsp; We only have time for a few questions today.&nbsp; First, let&#8217;s go to Carl O&#8217;Donnell at Reuters.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, and thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I just was wondering if you guys could share a little bit more detail on the current state of thinking around boosters.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;ve said and other persons have also said that they&#8217;re not needed now.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve heard some commentary though, suggesting that among immunosuppressed people and the elderly, they might be needed.&nbsp; Maybe, you know, latter part of this year, early next year &#8212; just curious.<br><br>I also know that there can be higher risk of side effects, potentially, with a third booster shot.&nbsp; So, just curious if you can offer any additional color.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr Fauci?&nbsp;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Yes, well, as Dr. Rochelle Walensky has said multiple times, the CDC is looking at a number of different cohorts that will get the information that will be needed &#8212; as she said &#8212; if and when and to whom we will be giving boosters.&nbsp;<br><br>I think we should be making sure people understand &#8212; because the question often gets asked, particularly among the unvaccinated &#8212; &#8220;If you&#8217;re talking about boosting people, does that mean that the vaccines don&#8217;t work?”&nbsp; That&#8217;s not the case at all.&nbsp;<br><br>We are dealing with highly effective vaccines.&nbsp; When you talk about a third shot for a two-shot vaccine regimen or another shot for the J&amp;J single-dose regimen, you&#8217;re talking about enhancing the durability of an already highly effective vaccine.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s the thing that&#8217;s being actively studied right now.&nbsp;<br><br>So, literally, in real time, we talk about this literally on a daily basis, and evidence is being accumulated on a daily and weekly basis.&nbsp; And when we get enough information to make that decision, then that decision will be forthcoming.&nbsp;<br><br>But as we&#8217;ve all said: At this particular time, right now, we don&#8217;t recommend that there be boosters for people.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; I just want to also be very crystal clear from an operational perspective: We&#8217;re prepared for every scenario, including the possibility of boosters, if and when the science, as Dr. Fauci said, shows that they are needed.&nbsp; If and when.&nbsp;<br><br>So we&#8217;ve secured enough vaccine supply.&nbsp; And if needed, we&#8217;ll ensure Americans who might need a booster shot are able to get one quickly and easily.&nbsp;<br><br>The science, as always, will guide us.&nbsp; And as Dr. Walensky and Dr. Fauci have said &#8212; they&#8217;ve made it very clear &#8212; this is a question that they are continually evaluating.&nbsp;<br><br>Next question.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; And maybe &#8212;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Oh, go ahead, Dr. Walensky.&nbsp; Please.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; I was just going to say, with regard to the immunosuppressed population, this is a little bit of a different scenario where we might be concerned that in fact they didn&#8217;t get full protection from their initial two doses, so we would be looking at a third prime dose in that situation.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s a situation that the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices is going to look at next week.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Thank you, Dr. Walensky.<br><br>Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Go to Erin Billups at Spectrum News.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; Younger unvaccinated people we&#8217;ve spoken to believe they will likely be fine if they get infected with coronavirus.&nbsp; So, wondering if you all can paint a picture of who is actually being hospitalized by the Delta variant.&nbsp; Is the rate of younger people being hospitalized by coronavirus now any different than what we were seeing at other &#8212; during other surges in the pandemic?&nbsp; And are we seeing any breakthrough infections among more vulnerable people who have been vaccinated who might have been around younger people?&nbsp; Is there any more data you can share with us?&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Fauci?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, with regard to the breakthrough infections that we&#8217;re seeing: So, certainly, we are seeing them, but you got to remember what the denominator of the vaccinated people are.&nbsp;<br><br>When you&#8217;re talking about young people, specifically, getting hospitalized, we are seeing younger people hospitalized right now, relatively speaking to a more extent than we were before.&nbsp; Because when we did not have the large group of elderly people vaccinated, then the elderly people dominated the people who were hospitalized and got into trouble.<br><br>Since we have more of a veil of protection among people &#8211;because about 85 percent of people who are elderly, greater than 65 are vaccinated &#8212; when you look at the relative number of people who get hospitalized, clearly, we&#8217;re seeing younger people, from a relative standpoint, more hospitalized than we were seeing before because of the shift of the veil of protection, which is much more dominant among the elderly.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; And maybe I&#8217;ll just add: When we look at the age demographics of people being hospitalized now, we are seeing them go up in all age demographics, exactly as Dr. Fauci noted, differently for the vaccinated and unvaccinated.&nbsp; But, importantly, over 97 percent of people who are entering the hospital right now are unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Kaitlan Collins at CNN.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve got two questions: one on breakthrough cases and then a second one on some news that just broke.<br><br>One, for these breakthrough cases, are they contributing to the spread of coronavirus?&nbsp; Or is it mainly unvaccinated people that that&#8217;s happening since this is, as Walensky phrased it, “a pandemic of the unvaccinated.”&nbsp;<br><br>And secondly, Pfizer just announced that the FDA has granted a priority review designation for their application for approval of their vaccine.&nbsp; They said the goal date for a decision is January 2022.&nbsp; So does that mean we&#8217;re not going to see full approval for their vaccine until January 2022?&nbsp; Or is that just a “must have decision by” date.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, Dr. Fauci on breakthrough cases.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. FAUCI:&nbsp; Well, what we do know in the cases that were looked at: If you are vaccinated and you get infected, and you compare that person &#8212; if you&#8217;re an asymptomatic infected breakthrough vaccinated case &#8212; and compare that to someone who is infected but not vaccinated and asymptomatic, the level of virus in the nasal pharynx of the vaccinated person is considerably less than the virus in the nasal pharynx of a person who is infected, unvaccinated, and asymptomatic.&nbsp;<br><br>Based on that, you could make a reasonable assumption that the rate of transmissibility from the asymptomatic vaccinated person to an uninfected person would be less likely than if the person was unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>But the actual studies to do whether or not the transmission occurs is a large study that&#8217;s ongoing right now.&nbsp; So, Kaitlan, we don&#8217;t have the data &#8212; the clinical data &#8212; but I think one can make the reasonable assumption based on the level of virus in the nasal pharynx that it would be less likely that that vaccinated breakthrough person would transmit, compared to an unvaccinated person.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; And, Kaitlan, on the second question, we’ll defer to the FDA.&nbsp;<br><br>Next question.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s go to Zeke Miller with AP.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you all for doing this.&nbsp; The President, yesterday, said that he was hoping for a timeline &#8212; to set a timeline for lifting some travel restrictions in the next couple of days.&nbsp; I was hoping you could talk about the objective metrics that you&#8217;re looking to present to the President for when some of these travel restrictions can be eased.&nbsp;<br><br>And then, secondly, to Dr. Walensky’s point a few minutes ago that this is becoming a pandemic of the unvaccinated: How does that change the administration&#8217;s response to the pandemic?&nbsp; Is it a different sort of strategy?&nbsp; Does it mean that large-scale mitigation measures, if we start seeing cases going up &#8211;you know, mask mandates and the like &#8212; are not necessary because so many people are vaccinated?&nbsp; How does it change the strategy going forward?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Dr. Walensky, do you want to take the second question?&nbsp; And then I&#8217;ll make a comment on international travel.&nbsp;<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:&nbsp; Yeah, absolutely.&nbsp; Thank you, Zeke.&nbsp; You know, as we have said, this is very heterogeneous across the country and these decisions have to be made at the local level.&nbsp; If you have areas of low vaccination and high case rates, then I would say local policymakers might consider whether masking at that point would be something that would be helpful for their community until they scale up their vaccination rates because more people than not in the community are unvaccinated.<br><br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY:&nbsp; And, Jeff, can I just add &#8212;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; Please.<br><br>SURGEON GENERAL MURTHY: &#8212; on thought there?&nbsp;<br><br>You know, this strategy &#8212; as we think, going forward, about how to get the rest of the country vaccinated &#8212; has got to involve everyone.&nbsp; Look, there&#8217;s a lot government can do.&nbsp; There’s a lot that we are doing and we&#8217;ll continue to do more, but this is a moment where we need technology companies to step up and do more to stop the spread of misinformation.&nbsp;<br><br>We want to work closely with schools and employers to get their help, increasingly, in getting people vaccinated in schools and in workplaces.&nbsp; But it&#8217;s also going to take each one of us, you know, as Americans across this country, looking to our family and our friends and asking them if they are vaccinated.<br><br>You know, this vaccination campaign is going to move, in part, driven by trusted relationships.&nbsp; And so, if you&#8217;ve got people in your life who trust you, who look to you for advice, then you have the power to help them get them accurate information and help get them vaccinated and protected from COVID-19.&nbsp; It will take all of us.&nbsp;<br><br>I think governments can play an important role here, but this has got to be an “all of the above” strategy with everybody in.&nbsp;<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:&nbsp; So, lastly, on international travel, you know, we&#8217;ve made, as we talked about today, important progress on the pandemic.&nbsp; At the same time, we have an increase in cases and the existence of the Delta variant.&nbsp; We’ll continue to put public health first.&nbsp; Any decision about opening international travel will be guided by our public health and medical experts.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ll be looking at many metrics, including case rates, vaccination rates, and the prevalence of any variants, including the Delta variant.<br><br>As you heard yesterday, the President said that we will be planning to update him in the next few days on the metrics and on the public health, and we must remain vigilant, particularly about the spread of variants.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll reopen when the medical folks and the health experts believe it&#8217;s safe to do so.&nbsp;<br><br>I want to thank everybody for joining today&#8217;s briefing and look forward to next week.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>11:38 A.M. EDT<br><br>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_16July2021_for-transcript.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/07/COVID-Press-Briefing_16July2021_for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joe Biden’s Participation in the APEC Virtual Leaders’ Retreat</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/16/readout-of-president-joe-bidens-participation-in-the-apec-virtual-leaders-retreat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 16:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24173</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today President Joseph R. Biden Jr. participated in the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Virtual Leaders’ Retreat, hosted by Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand. President Biden welcomed the opportunity to directly engage with APEC Leaders. He underscored the importance the United States places on the region, noting that we are a Pacific nation and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today President Joseph R. Biden Jr. participated in the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) Virtual Leaders’ Retreat, hosted by Prime Minister Jacinda Ardern of New Zealand.<br><br>President Biden welcomed the opportunity to directly engage with APEC Leaders. He underscored the importance the United States places on the region, noting that we are a Pacific nation and vowing that the United States will remain deeply engaged in the region for generations to come. President Biden emphasized the importance of multilateral cooperation and reiterated his commitment to a free and open Indo-Pacific. He put forward a vision for the region that is affirmative, values-based, and transparent.<br><br>President Biden articulated the U.S. approach for ending the pandemic and outlined our global vaccine strategy, whereby the U.S. is donating more than half a billion safe and effective vaccines to more than 100 countries in need around the world, several of which are APEC economies. He made clear that the United States is donating our vaccines, not selling them, and underscored the importance of not attaching any political or economic conditions to the provision of vaccines. Our singular goal remains saving lives. President Biden also discussed the importance of investing in better global health security and preparedness so that we are ready the next time we face a pandemic.<br><br>On the global economic recovery, President Biden reaffirmed the U.S. interest in serving as a strong, reliable partner to APEC economies as we pursue sustained and inclusive growth. He discussed ways to unleash the economic power of the region and to deepen U.S. economic engagement throughout the Indo-Pacific, including through the recently announced Build Back Better World partnership, which will provide high-standard, climate-aligned, and transparently financed infrastructure to APEC economies that need support.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of First Meeting of White House Community Violence Intervention Collaborative</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/16/readout-of-first-meeting-of-white-house-community-violence-intervention-collaborative/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 15:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24167</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director Julie Rodriguez convened the inaugural meeting of The White House Community Violence Intervention (CVI) Collaborative, a 16-jurisdiction cohort of mayors, law enforcement, CVI experts, and philanthropic leaders committed to using American Rescue Plan funding or other public funding to increase investment in their&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Intergovernmental Affairs Director Julie Rodriguez convened the inaugural meeting of The White House Community Violence Intervention (CVI) Collaborative, a 16-jurisdiction cohort of mayors, law enforcement, CVI experts, and philanthropic leaders committed to using American Rescue Plan funding or other public funding to increase investment in their community violence intervention infrastructure. Investing in evidence-based, community violence interventions to reduce gun violence is a key pillar of President Biden’s comprehensive strategy to prevent and respond to gun crime.</p>



<p>The Collaborative will spend the next 18 months strengthening and scaling the jurisdictions’ community violence intervention infrastructure to reduce gun crime and promote public safety. The effort will include peer-to-peer learning and community-based evaluations to strengthen the existing evidence base for community violence interventions. National experts and federal agencies will provide training and technical assistance to help communities assess their existing public safety ecosystem, identify gaps, and build the capacity to expand programming that saves lives—both this summer and beyond.</p>



<p>During the meeting, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice stressed that through American Rescue Plan funding and other investments, cities have a historic opportunity to invest in building out their community violence prevention and intervention infrastructure. Intergovernmental Affairs Director Julie Rodriguez thanked mayors and other participants for their leadership and underscored the value of sharing best practices and lessons learned through the Collaborative.</p>



<p>Several mayors in attendance highlighted their efforts to support community violence interventions through the use of American Rescue Plan funds, and how the Collaborative will allow them to strengthen their programs. Community violence intervention experts, who will be lending their decades of expertise to the Collaborative, noted the historic nature of this White House initiative.</p>



<p>Participants in the meeting represented the following jurisdictions:</p>



<ul><li>Atlanta, GA</li><li>Austin, TX</li><li>Baltimore, MD</li><li>Baton Rouge, LA</li><li>Chicago, IL</li><li>Detroit, MI</li><li>King County, WA</li><li>Los Angeles, CA</li><li>Memphis, TN</li><li>Miami-Dade, FL</li><li>Minneapolis &amp; St. Paul, MN</li><li>Newark, NJ</li><li>Philadelphia, PA</li><li>Rapid City, SD</li><li>St. Louis, MO</li><li>Washington, DC</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Captive Nations Week, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/07/16/a-proclamation-on-captive-nations-week-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 13:39:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=24157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[From the founding of our Nation to today, through the crucibles of war and the struggle of successive generations, America has strived to uphold the ideals of freedom and democracy upon which our country was built and expand the ability of people around the world to freely exercise their rights.&#160; As the world&#8217;s longest-standing democracy,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>From the founding of our Nation to today, through the crucibles of war and the struggle of successive generations, America has strived to uphold the ideals of freedom and democracy upon which our country was built and expand the ability of people around the world to freely exercise their rights.&nbsp; As the world&#8217;s longest-standing democracy, we carry a special responsibility to lead at home and abroad, not only by the example of our power, but by the power of our example &#8212; to prove to ourselves and to the world that democracy can deliver for all people.&nbsp; Though much has changed in the world since President Eisenhower issued the first Captive Nations Proclamation in 1959, its call for liberty and opportunity still ring true.&nbsp; During Captive Nations Week, we recommit ourselves to those principles which form the foundation of our Nation, and to amplify the voices of courageous individuals around the world who are striving to advance the principles of human rights, justice, and the rule of law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, far too many people are subject to routine abuses of power, as oppressive governments detain, harass, or commit acts of violence against dissenting voices; disseminate disinformation and propaganda; undermine democratic systems; and otherwise violate the public trust.&nbsp; These abuses are not new &#8212; but they remain as stern a threat to human rights and freedom as they have ever been.</p>



<p>No nation or person of conscience can ignore the voices of those crying out for liberty.&nbsp; We hear Belarusians peacefully calling for democratic elections, and the courageous people of Hong Kong demanding the autonomy and liberty promised by Beijing under the Sino-British Joint Declaration and Hong Kong&#8217;s Basic Law.&nbsp; We hear millions of Uyghurs and other ethnic and religious minorities in Xinjiang, China, who have been unjustly interned and subject to surveillance and forced labor.&nbsp; We hear the determination of those rejecting military rule in Burma, resisting dictatorship in Venezuela, taking to streets in Cuba to demand freedom in the face of brutal state repression, and pressing for free and fair elections in Nicaragua &#8212; as well as the Crimean Tatars, ethnic Ukrainians, and other ethnic and religious minorities who suffer repression for opposing Russia&#8217;s illegal occupation of Crimea.</p>



<p>The American creed, which defines our Nation, proclaims that all people are created equal, and deserve to be treated equally, with dignity and respect, throughout their lives.&nbsp; We stand in solidarity with the brave human rights activists and pro-democracy advocates around the world who risk their lives for the rights of others. &nbsp;We are committed to ensuring that all those who are oppressed across the globe &#8212; including people with disabilities, women and girls, members of the LGBTQI+ community, indigenous populations, and racial and ethnic minorities &#8212; are heard, respected, and protected.</p>



<p>During Captive Nations Week, we recommit ourselves to the timeless, vital work of advancing freedom and justice for all. &nbsp;</p>



<p>We do that by forging a more equitable and inclusive society, by solving problems and helping to ease the burdens people face, and by fulfilling our role as a global leader for human rights and fundamental freedoms of expression, association, peaceful assembly, and religion or belief.&nbsp; Together with our allies and partners, we must continue to strengthen democratic institutions, defend independent civil society and media freedom, promote free and fair elections, protect human rights online, insist on accountability for those who commit abuses and foster cultures of corruption, and push back against authoritarianism around the world.</p>



<p>The Congress, by joint resolution approved July 17, 1959 (73 Stat. 212), has authorized and requested the President to issue a proclamation designating the third week of July of each year as &#8220;Captive Nations Week.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim July 18 through July 24, 2021, as Captive Nations Week.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to reaffirm our commitment to championing those around the world who strive for liberty and justice for all.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this sixteenth day of July, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
