<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 20:29:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris at Signing of H.R. 3525, the “Commission To Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture&#160;Act”</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/13/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-at-signing-of-h-r-3525-the-commission-to-study-the-potential-creation-of-a-national-museum-of-asian-pacific-american-history-and-culture/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 20:29:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 2:21 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; Please have a seat.&#160; Good afternoon, everyone. President Biden, Speaker Pelosi, members of Congress, and my fellow Americans: It is an honor to be gathered with you today and to be joined by so many former colleagues from the Congressional Asian Pacific American&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>2:21 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Please have a seat.&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.<br><br>President Biden, Speaker Pelosi, members of Congress, and my fellow Americans: It is an honor to be gathered with you today and to be joined by so many former colleagues from the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus.&nbsp; In particular, Congresswoman Grace Meng, you did so much to make this day possible.&nbsp; Thank you for that.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>So when my mother was 19 years old, she came to the United States from India to become a breast cancer researcher.&nbsp; Growing up, my mother made sure that my sister Maya and I learned of the important, glorious history of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders in America.&nbsp; Because that, of course, is part of the history of America.<br><br>To teach this history is to help all of us as Americans understand where we come from.&nbsp; And to teach this history is to help us understand who we are.&nbsp;<br><br>The National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture will teach and tell the story of our country.&nbsp; This is a story about heroes who shaped our nation for the better, from the South Asian Americans who helped transform farming up and down the Pacific coast, to the Japanese Americans who defended our freedom during World War Two, to the Chinese American garment workers who marched through the streets of New York City 40 years ago to win better pay and benefits for all workers.<br><br>This is also a story about some of our country&#8217;s darkest moments: the Chinese Exclusion Act, the internment of Japanese Americans, the murder of Vincent Chin, discrimination against South Asian Americans after 9/11, and today&#8217;s epidemic of hate, which is fueling violent acts against many communities including the AA and NHPI community.<br><br>Because, you see, this is also American history, and we must teach it as it really happened so that we can learn from our best moments and learn from our darkest moments, and in particular, then, to ensure they are never repeated, our darkest moments.&nbsp;<br><br>By equipping people with knowledge and historical context, then we can fight ignorance, dispel misinformation, and work toward a future where all people can live without fear and a future where all people &#8212; all people can help write the next chapter of American history.<br><br>With that, it is my great honor to introduce the President of the United States, Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Good afternoon, folks.&nbsp; And thank you, Kamala.&nbsp; I think I should just stop right there &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; because if anybody can talk about this, Kamala can, like so many of you in the audience.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, it’s good to see you as well, Doug.&nbsp; Must be hard following this act all the time.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You do it well.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, I&#8217;m honored to sign into law something that’s long overdue, and &#8212; the National Museum of Asian and Pacific American History and Culture here in Washington, D.C.&nbsp; You can clap for that because of this lady here.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And I want to thank the many members of Congress who made this possible, especially Grace.&nbsp; Grace, stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, and she started early.&nbsp; She&#8217;s not new to this.&nbsp; I think it was &#8212; the first time you introduced it was 2015.&nbsp; Is that right?&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, you&#8217;re only seven years ahead of everybody else.&nbsp;<br><br>All kidding aside &#8212; and Judy as well is here and Doris Matsui and Speaker Pelosi.&nbsp; And senators who couldn’t be here today because they&#8217;re not in session right now, but they &#8212; including Mazie Hirono and Tammy Duckworth and &#8212; and Chuck Schumer &#8212; all members of the Congressional Pacific &#8212; Asian Pacific American Caucus.&nbsp;<br><br>While this bill was being &#8212; been working its way through the Congress the past decade, its story behind it goes back centuries.&nbsp;<br><br>Throughout our history, beyond what the Vice President pointed out, Asian American, Native Hawaiians, Pacific Islanders have literally shaped the history and the contours of this country.&nbsp;<br><br>As I said last month at Asian History &#8212; Asian American History Month reception in the Rose Garden we had, there&#8217;s no single Asian American, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander identity.&nbsp; The diversity of the cultures is significant.&nbsp; And the breadth of achievement is equally as broad and significant.&nbsp;<br><br>The enrichment of our country has been &#8212; our communities &#8212; not just the country, but down to individual communities &#8212; the impact that the community has had.&nbsp;<br><br>All of it has been defined by who you are and who we are as a nation.&nbsp; And it’s defined us.&nbsp; And all of it is an embodiment of so many of you here today.&nbsp; Leaders in civil rights like Karen <s>Nagasaki</s> [Narasaki] and &#8212; and Karen Korematsu.&nbsp; Where &#8212; where are you?&nbsp; Where are the Karens?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And military men like four-star general Tony Taguba.&nbsp;&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Stand up, will you?&nbsp; Come on.&nbsp; He&#8217;s the only one I can say “stand up” to because I&#8217;m still the Commander-in-Chief.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I&#8217;m serious &#8212; you’ve made a hell of a contribution.&nbsp;<br><br>In the arts and sciences, like the father of Erika Mo- &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; Moritsugu.&nbsp; Where &#8212; where is that guy?&nbsp; There you go.&nbsp; Dad, stand up.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Now, I was asked by your daughter not to do that.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But how can I not do that?&nbsp; She&#8217;s the one who advises me on all these things.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And too many business and public service people to mention, and so many, so many more.&nbsp;<br><br>And many of you in the audience &#8212; we should go through all the contributions you’ve all made.&nbsp;<br><br>And it’s about time for a national museum to capture the courage, the character, and the imagination.&nbsp; And maybe, from my perspective, looking from a little bit from a distance, is the dreams and the heart and the soul of the generations of our fellow Americans who came before you and all of you.&nbsp; That’s what this law is going to do.&nbsp; That’s what it’s going to do.&nbsp; It going to create a commission that will examine how to make the museum a reality, including whether it should be part of the Smithsonian.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, we did this with the la- &#8212; we did this with other museums as well.&nbsp; This is the process.&nbsp; And the fact of the matter is it’s similar to the process that the African American History and Culture Museum, the Latino History and Culture Museum, and the National Women’s History Museum.&nbsp; Some of you are in both these museums, by the way, you know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And it comes at a critical time &#8212; all kidding aside.&nbsp; It comes at a critical time.<br><br>This year marks one year since the murder of six Asian American women in Atlanta &#8212; a symbol of the anti-Asian hate in America today.&nbsp;<br><br>This year commemorates the 80th anniversary of the incarceration of 120,000 American citizens who were Japanese Americans during World War Two, which included &#8212; if you excuse my reference to two friends &#8212; it included a dear friend who, as a child &#8212; the late Norm Mineta &#8212; who went on to serve &#8212; he was in those camps when he was a child &#8212; went on to serve in the United States Army and in Congress and the Cabinet &#8212; a commemoration at a time where there are those who seek to whitewash the history in our schools, what took place.&nbsp;<br><br>And I think &#8212; excuse again, in Senate language, a point of personal privilege &#8212; I want to thank my dear friend who’s not here, the late Senator Danny Inouye, who taught me so much about so many things.&nbsp; A Japanese American who tried to join &#8212; from Hawaii, but a Japanese American &#8212; who tried to join the military when the war broke out, who had to fight to enlist in the United States military out of high school.&nbsp;<br><br>Danny would recall what his father told him.&nbsp; And I remember Danny telling me &#8212; I had to go back and check this today &#8212; but I remember Danny telling me about this years ago.&nbsp; He said, “America has been…”&nbsp; This is what his dad said.&nbsp;<br>“America has been good to us, Danny.&nbsp; It has given us &#8212; given me two jobs.&nbsp; It has given you and your sisters and brothers an education.&nbsp; We all love this country.&nbsp; Whatever you do, do not dishonor your country.&nbsp; Remember, never dishonor your family.&nbsp; And if you must give your life, do it with honor.”&nbsp; End of quote.<br><br>Danny served in the famed 442nd Regimental Combat Team during World War Two.&nbsp; And, I might add, he earned the Medal of Freedom and he also went on to do so much more.&nbsp;<br><br>I was going to tell a story about he and Bob Dole, but I’m going to take too much time.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; For the 50th anniversary of D-Day, when we &#8212; they both got shot and mortally woun- &#8212; badly wounded on mountaintops &#8212; I was with them both &#8212; on mountaintops in Italy, on the west coast, that were literally, as the crow flies, less than two miles from one another.&nbsp; The same time, same day.&nbsp; Anyway.<br><br>Today, it’s clear that the battle for the soul of America continues.&nbsp; That’s why a museum like this is going to matter so much.&nbsp; Museums of this magnitude and consequence are going to inspire and educate.&nbsp; More than anything else, it’s going to help people see themselves in the story of America &#8212; a story that makes us a better America and it’s made us a better America.<br><br>And that’s why it was so important to me that this administration looks like America &#8212; the people representing them looks like America &#8212; starting with a Vice President, including Cabinet members and the staff at every single level.&nbsp;<br><br>It’s important to sign this bill with all of you here and &#8212; who &#8212; and from every walk of life.&nbsp; You represent every aspect of American life, many of whom will likely be celebrated in this museum as well.<br><br>Let me close with this: Maya Lin, born in Ohio and the daughter of Chinese immigrants and the architect of the Vietnam Memorial on the Mall and recipient of the Presidential Medal of Freedom, said, “It’s not a matter of finding an idea but allowing the idea to find you.”&nbsp;<br><br>This mus- &#8212; this museum is going to help the idea find so many American souls &#8212; so many people from around the world who will one day walk in this museum and better understand the idea of America, the only nation &#8212; the only nation, in my view, that can be defined in one single word: possibilities.&nbsp; Possibilities.<br><br>Much earlier, my ancestors came, but your ancestors came.&nbsp; What did they come for?&nbsp; Because they believed there was possibilities here unlike any other nation in the world.&nbsp; Possibilities.&nbsp; And you’ve all proven it.<br><br>And now I’m going to ask Speaker Pelosi, Grace, Judy, and the other members of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus to join me on stage while I sign this bill into law.&nbsp;<br><br>And I look forward, one day, to visiting the National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture with all of you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>(Walks to the signing desk.)<br><br>Now, I don&#8217;t know why they do this, but they only give me one pen.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I used to stand in absolute awe and watch Barack Obama sign with seven, eight, nine different pens “Barack Obama.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m in awe.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m going to give this pen to Grace, and all of you will get a pen.<br><br>(The bill is signed.)&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>2:35 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: H.R.&#160;3525</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/06/13/bill-signed-h-r-3525/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 19:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55423</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, June 13, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 3525, the &#8220;Commission To Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Act,&#8221; which establishes a Commission to Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture in Washington, D.C. Thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, June 13, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 3525, the &#8220;Commission To Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Act,&#8221; which establishes a Commission to Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture in Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Meng, Chu, and Matsui, and Senators Duckworth and Hirono, as well as the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus, for their work.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Politburo Member Yang&#160;Jiechi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/13/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-politburo-member-yang-jiechi-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 18:15:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi in Luxembourg. This meeting, which followed their May 18 phone call, included candid, substantive, and productive discussion of a number of regional and global security issues, as well as key&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi in Luxembourg. This meeting, which followed their May 18 phone call, included candid, substantive, and productive discussion of a number of regional and global security issues, as well as key issues in U.S.-China relations. Mr. Sullivan underscored the importance of maintaining open lines of communication to manage competition between our two countries.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>REMARKS BY VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS AT THE 2022 CAPITAL PRIDE&#160;PARADE</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/12/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-south-carolina-democratic-party-blue-palmetto-dinner/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 17:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55339</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Pennsylvania AvenueWashington, D.C.  6:09 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Happy Pride, everyone!  (Applause.)  Oh, what a glorious day.  &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Listen, we have so much to celebrate, and we celebrate each other every day.&#160; We celebrate the progress we have made.&#160; And we celebrate the fact that we are in this to stand for what we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Pennsylvania Avenue<br>Washington, D.C.</em> </p>



<p>6:09 P.M. EDT</p>



<p> THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Happy Pride, everyone!  (Applause.)  Oh, what a glorious day. </p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Listen, we have so much to celebrate, and we celebrate each other every day.&nbsp; We celebrate the progress we have made.&nbsp; And we celebrate the fact that we are in this to stand for what we stand for and fight for what we stand for.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because no one should fear going to a nightclub for fear that a terrorist might try to take them down.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No one should fear going to a Pride celebration because of a white supremacist.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No one should fear loving who they love.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Our children in Texas and Florida should not fear who they are.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Black and brown and women of color, transgender women should not fear for their lives.&nbsp; (Applause.) We should not have to be dealing with 300 laws in states around our country that are attacking our LGBTQ+ brothers and sisters.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So we know what we stand for and, therefore, we know what we will fight for.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we will do what we have always done in this movement, in this community, which is, collectively, we will continue to build unity.&nbsp; We will continue to build coalition.&nbsp; We will always be fueled by knowing we have so much more in common than what separates us.&nbsp; We will be fueled by saying, “No one should be made to fight alone.”&nbsp; We will be fueled by knowing we are all in this together.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And we will fight with pride.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Happy Pride, everyone.  Happy Pride. </p>



<p>END       6:12 P.M. EDT</p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Bipartisan Senate Gun Safety&#160;Proposal</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/12/statement-by-president-biden-on-bipartisan-senate-gun-safety-proposal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 15:49:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55363</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I want to thank Senator Chris Murphy and the members of his bipartisan group—especially Senators Cornyn, Sinema, and Tillis—for their tireless work to produce this proposal. Obviously, it does not do everything that I think is needed, but it reflects important steps in the right direction, and would be the most significant gun safety legislation&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I want to thank Senator Chris Murphy and the members of his bipartisan group—especially Senators Cornyn, Sinema, and Tillis—for their tireless work to produce this proposal. Obviously, it does not do everything that I think is needed, but it reflects important steps in the right direction, and would be the most significant gun safety legislation to pass Congress in decades. With bipartisan support, there are no excuses for delay, and no reason why it should not quickly move through the Senate and the House. Each day that passes, more children are killed in this country: the sooner it comes to my desk, the sooner I can sign it, and the sooner we can use these measures to save lives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before Air Force One&#160;Departure</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/12/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-18/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 15:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55366</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles International AirportLos Angeles, California 10:26 A.M. PDT Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Mr. President, do you have a m- &#8212; do you have a message for those marching for their lives today in Washington on gun safety? THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Sorry, I didn&#8217;t hear what you said. Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Do you have a message for those at the March&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles International Airport<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>10:26 A.M. PDT</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, do you have a m- &#8212; do you have a message for those marching for their lives today in Washington on gun safety?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sorry, I didn&#8217;t hear what you said.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a message for those at the March For Our Lives for gun safety today in Washington?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Keep marching.&nbsp; It&#8217;s important.&nbsp; Look, this has to become an election issue.&nbsp; The way people listen &#8212; senators, congressmen &#8212; is when people say, “I&#8217;m going to &#8212; this is going to affect my vote.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Too many people are dying needlessly.&nbsp; And what &#8212; and what&#8217;s even being proposed in the House and Senate is marginal. I mean, it’s &#8212; it’s important, but it&#8217;s not all that needs to be done.&nbsp; The idea we&#8217;re not going to do background checks, the idea we&#8217;re not &#8212; anyway, the answer: march.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you gotten an update from Senator Murphy or any of the negotiators about where their talks stand?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes, they&#8217;re still mildly optimistic.&nbsp; I spoke with Murphy several times.&nbsp; I spoke with him yesterday as well &#8212; yesterday afternoon.&nbsp; And so &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What about New Mexico, sir?&nbsp; They want you &#8212; the government to pay for all of the bills that they have from fighting this fire because it was started by the Forest Service. Are you willing to commit that?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I can&#8217;t &#8212; I can&#8217;t commit that on my own.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what&#8217;s being proposed by &#8212; in the Congress.&nbsp; And I support what they&#8217;re doing.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You support doing that?&nbsp; You support doing that?&nbsp; You actually &#8212; you said that Congress support &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I support it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Have you decided, sir, whether to go to Saudi Arabia?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; Not yet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What would be the &#8212; holding up the decision at this point?&nbsp; Are there commitments you&#8217;re waiting for from the Saudis or &#8212; on the negotiations over peace talks?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; The commitments from the Saudis don&#8217;t relate to anything having to do with energy.&nbsp; It happens to be a larger meeting taking place in Saudi Arabia.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the reason I&#8217;m going.&nbsp; And it has to do with national security for them &#8212; for Israelis.&nbsp; I have a program &#8212; anyway.&nbsp; It has to do with much larger issues than having to do with the energy piece.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The average price of gas nationally today hit $5 a gallon for the first time.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your message to the American people, especially as we head into the summer months, who are really struggling with this?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; This is &#8212; it’s outrageous what the war in &#8212; in Ukraine is causing.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re trying very hard to make sure that we can &#8212; we&#8217;ve significantly increased the number of barrels of oil that are being pumped out of the &#8212; the reserve we have.&nbsp; We got 240,000 barrels as well coming from other nations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re going to keep pushing on it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to keep pushing.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>10:28 A.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in an Overview of the New Mexico State Emergency Operations&#160;Center</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/11/remarks-by-president-biden-in-an-overview-of-the-new-mexico-state-emergency-operations-center/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 02:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55372</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Mexico State Emergency Operations CenterSanta Fe, New Mexico 4:43 P.M. MDT THE PRESIDENT:  Well, first of all, thanks for what you do.  (Applause.)  And we have a little outfit like this back in Washington, too.  And we &#8212; one of the things that we understand &#8212; and I made the point today with the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">New Mexico State Emergency Operations Center<br>Santa Fe, New Mexico</p>



<p>4:43 P.M. MDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, first of all, thanks for what you do.  (Applause.)  And we have a little outfit like this back in Washington, too.  And we &#8212; one of the things that we understand &#8212; and I made the point today with the Governor and others &#8212; is that we have a responsibility &#8212; a responsibility.  And not just at the state level, but at the federal level.  And I hope you&#8217;re aware that we&#8217;ve me- &#8212; we’re meeting that responsibility to the tune of billions of dollars.  (Applause.)</p>



<p>One of the things that we talked about a moment ago with your elected officials and the Governor in a couple of buildings over was the &#8212; the need to &#8212; for us to get more agile in dealing with the aftermath of fires, the aftermath of tornados, the aftermath of hurricanes &#8212; because the damage done there &#8212; your monsoon season is coming up.&nbsp; If you don’t get out &#8212; we don’t get out there and clear the way, a lot more damage will be done even maybe than the fires caused &#8212; even maybe than the fires caused.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I have had the dubious distinction of being to &#8212; I think it’s now 15 of these events, including the tornados in Kentucky, the hurricanes in Louisiana, the fires that range all the way from &#8212; we&#8217;ve &#8212; I&#8217;ve been in &#8212; in Idaho, Oregon, the state of Washington, northern California, flying over &#8212; closely over areas with &#8212; in helicopters that &#8212; where you can see the granular impact of all of this.&nbsp; And it’s been profound.&nbsp; It’s been profound.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what my &#8212; my director &#8212; is &#8212; is FEMA here &#8212; in here?&nbsp; Is she &#8212; she had to catch the flight.&nbsp; Anyway, what &#8212; what we’re doing in talking with the Governor &#8212; I learned early on as President: When the Governor calls and they say, “The Governor of New Mexico is on the phone,” I just say, “Just tell her yes.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Better say “yes” right away.</p>



<p>But look at what the coordination has required.&nbsp; Those helicopters &#8212; and a lot of those helicopters and those aircraft, you wouldn’t have them without the federal government and the National Guard and &#8212; you know, a lot of what&#8217;s going on here.&nbsp; And I &#8212; I&#8217;m not saying “federal government” like that’s a big thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my point is that we have to all cooperate.&nbsp; This is a long-term &#8212; you know, your &#8212; your delegation has been incredibly helpful to doing everything that’s happening here and the Governor is requesting.&nbsp; But they&#8217;re also working like hell to make sure that we end up with circumstances where you have nothing that &#8212; that we pay 100 percent of the damage done.</p>



<p>For example, people can only get 35 grand to get back in their home.&nbsp; But we’re &#8212; these guys have a bill in the Congress right now &#8212; and I&#8217;m strongly supporting it &#8212; saying that you get complete reimbursement to rebuild your home as it was, your ranch as it was, your circumstance as it was.&nbsp; We are doing that in areas where I have the authority to allow for 100 percent reimbursement.</p>



<p>But one of the things that you guys are going to have to be &#8212; we need your input on as we go down the road here is the aftermath of these fires, the aftermath of the tornados, the aftermath of the hurricanes.</p>



<p>For example, I come from an area of the world &#8212; the state of Delaware &#8212; a little state, but it’s a wealthy little state &#8212; but it’s on the ocean.&nbsp; We’re two feet above sea level for most of the &#8212; excuse me, three feet above sea level for most of the &#8212; of the state.&nbsp; And the seas are rising.&nbsp; Global warm- &#8212; global changes are happening that are enormous.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I just want everybody out here to remember that we are a federal system.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I have no reluctance to do everything we possibly can to meet all of New Mexico&#8217;s needs and stay as long as it takes to meet those needs.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>But one of the &#8212; (applause) &#8212; but one of the things that I mentioned in the last &#8212; and I&#8217;ll &#8212; I’ll end with this &#8212; the last little discussion we had next door was that &#8212; you know, remember: This is a federal system.&nbsp; And when other states need the help, y&#8217;all have to ante up too.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t mean just the emergency issue.&nbsp; I mean the people of the state have to ante up.</p>



<p>There is a reluctance to say, “My state needs help.&nbsp; But, I don&#8217;t know, we&#8217;re going to do that for that other state?”&nbsp; The answer is: This a federal system.&nbsp; We have a responsibility to every single solitary state in the union &#8212; not based on whether you&#8217;re Democrat, Republican; rich, poor &#8212; no matter what it is.</p>



<p>And so I think there&#8217;s a lot we can do.&nbsp; And one of the things that I&#8217;ve been talking to some of your mayors about, as well as all across the country, is global change and climate change is going to continue.&nbsp; I know I&#8217;ve been pushing it really, really hard to spend more money.&nbsp; We have a lot of money being held up &#8212; as a matter of fact, about $40 billion &#8212; to provide for alternatives to what we&#8217;re seeing now by providing &#8212; anyway, without getting into it, to deal with climate change.</p>



<p>And by the way, I want to promise you: Windmills do not cause cancer.&nbsp; And this matters.&nbsp; I know I&#8217;m joking, but I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; We got to get smart.&nbsp; And you all understand it better than anybody because you sit here every day when there&#8217;s a crisis and you wonder: What little kid is dying?&nbsp; What little kid is dying in one of those fires you can&#8217;t get to?&nbsp; What&#8217;s happening?</p>



<p>I had to do the fun- &#8212; so damn many funerals for firefighters.&nbsp; The Hotshots, when they got trapped in that canyon, I went out there.&nbsp; And what I saw was not them; I saw their families, their kids, their wives, their husbands, their mothers, their fathers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so it&#8217;s all over.&nbsp; You guys get it because you&#8217;re the ones sending out people to risk their lives.&nbsp; And some of you are the ones out risking your lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I said earlier that I&#8217;ve said it all the time: “God made man, then he made a few firefighters.”&nbsp; And that&#8217;s true.&nbsp; The only thing that protects firefighters is more firefighters.&nbsp; So when you need to increase the funding for your firefighters, step up, vote for it, pay for it.&nbsp; When you want to make sure you&#8217;re going to protect all these folks, it requires input.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by the way, there&#8217;s only been &#8212; you know, my Secretary of Interior, her family has only been here for 34 generations, so she&#8217;s new to the place.&nbsp; But &#8212; is that right?&nbsp; It’s 34 or 36?</p>



<p>SECRETARY HAALAND:&nbsp; Thirty-five.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thirty-five generations.&nbsp; But the point is that there&#8217;s so much we can do, but we&#8217;re going to have to do. We&#8217;re going to have to do it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, I hope everybody understands that what you&#8217;re doing here, you&#8217;re saving people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; You&#8217;re not just saving their property, they&#8217;re saving lives.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re prepared to make sure we can do everything we can to make it &#8212; be easy for you to be able to do it.&nbsp; And for all the Hotshots who go out there, all the firefighters, all the &#8212; all the National Guard, all that &#8212; that they have what they need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the last thing I&#8217;ll say is that I was talking to some of the mayors on the way out, as you &#8212; you saw me when I was trying to get out of the last ni- &#8212; walking out the last meeting.&nbsp; You know what?&nbsp; I used to be a local official.&nbsp; If I never attend a zoning hearing again in my life, I&#8217;ll die a happy man.&nbsp; Talk about war and peace.&nbsp; Zoning is something else.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, we have to rethink how we develop.&nbsp; We have to rethink how we build.&nbsp; We have to rethink where we build.&nbsp; Not I&#8217;m talking &#8212; not talking about those magnificent mountains I just flew up.&nbsp; And we didn&#8217;t get to fly in Air Force One &#8212; flew the whole perimeter.&nbsp; We didn&#8217;t get to go in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you know as well &#8212; you know better than most people what&#8217;s at stake here.&nbsp; So talk to your &#8212; talk to your fellow citi- &#8212; talk to your neighbors, talk to your friends about what we have to do.&nbsp; And we can do this.&nbsp; This is the United States of America.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing beyond our capacity when we&#8217;re united.&nbsp; And this is one of those areas that’s going to increase.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like I said &#8212; for example, I was recently down in Kentucky &#8212; not recently; six months ago.&nbsp; Beautiful middle-class neighborhood, old homes.&nbsp; Actually, technically, I guess economically slightly lower-middle class, like where I grew up, on little &#8212; in a rolling area &#8212; the rolling hills.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; A fire came, burned a lot of them down.&nbsp; But guess what came next?&nbsp; The heavy rains.&nbsp; Wiped everything out.&nbsp; Blew everything away that wasn’t down.</p>



<p>So we got to figure out what we do.&nbsp; What are the aftermath?&nbsp; What are you going to &#8212; what are we going to do?&nbsp; Is it going to land on your laps?&nbsp; You&#8217;re the ones who are going to have to be the ones doing it and directing it.&nbsp; So there&#8217;s a lot we can do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by the way, when I think climate change &#8212; and I know I get &#8212; people are tired of hearing me talk about climate change &#8212; I think jobs.&nbsp; Jobs.&nbsp; It creates a lot of good-paying jobs &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and saves a lot of lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But with that, I&#8217;m violating a cardinal principle.&nbsp; I&#8217;m in a very important Governor’s state and I&#8217;m talking too much.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>4:52 P.M. MDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden in a Briefing on the New Mexico&#160;Wildfires</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/11/remarks-by-president-biden-in-a-briefing-on-the-new-mexico-wildfires/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New Mexico State Regional Training Installation FacilitySanta Fe, New Mexico 3:18 P.M. MDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, Governor, thank you very much.&#160; Before I begin, we&#8217;re on National Guard property.&#160; I just want to say that the National Guard, obviously, is controlled by the governor, except when federalized.&#160; And I have federalized you a number of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">New Mexico State Regional Training Installation Facility<br>Santa Fe, New Mexico</p>



<p>3:18 P.M. MDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, Governor, thank you very much.&nbsp; Before I begin, we&#8217;re on National Guard property.&nbsp; I just want to say that the National Guard, obviously, is controlled by the governor, except when federalized.&nbsp; And I have federalized you a number of times nationwide to fight fires, to fight every disaster we&#8217;ve had.&nbsp; And my son was a major in the National Guard.&nbsp; And I think the people don&#8217;t quite understand the extent &#8212; the extent of the work you do and the risk you take for us.&nbsp;<br><br>And secondly, there&#8217;s an expression where I come from: “God made man, then he made some firefighters.”&nbsp; You&#8217;re all crazy &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; but I love you.&nbsp; I grew up in a neighborhood called Claymont, Delaware, when we moved from Scranton when coal died.&nbsp; And, you know, my parents weren&#8217;t in the coal mines &#8212; they were in sales &#8212; but the economy shriveled and we moved down to this little steel town.&nbsp; And I went to a little Catholic school across from the fire department &#8212; a fire station.&nbsp; And everybody I grew up with &#8212; you either became a cop, a firefighter, or a priest.&nbsp; I wasn’t qualified for any of them, so here I am.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>I &#8212; but, you know, just so you know, I&#8217;ve done too many<br>individual and mass funerals for firefighters and hotshots and &#8212; and, you&#8217;re an incredible group of people.&nbsp; I mean, a truly incredible group of people.&nbsp;<br><br>Anybody &#8212; and the &#8212; and the overwhelming human instinct is you run away from a fire, not into it.&nbsp; And the only thing that protects firefighters is more firefighters &#8212; the only thing.&nbsp; More firefighters.&nbsp;<br><br>And I just wanted to say that at the outset because I &#8212; you have my indebted gratitude.&nbsp; And my fire department saved my life literally, not figuratively.&nbsp; My house got struck by lightning and it mostly burned down.&nbsp; It had to be rebuilt.&nbsp;<br><br>Saved &#8212; the thick &#8212; the smoke was so thick, Gov.&nbsp; It was literally that thick.&nbsp; And you couldn&#8217;t see through the windows or out the windows.&nbsp; And the floors were collapsing, and these guys went in and did two things: Most importantly, they got my wife out &#8212; I was in Washington when it happened &#8212; and saved our cat.&nbsp; But equally important, almost &#8212; not equally, but important &#8212; I have a ‘67 Corvette they got out.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>And so, anyway.&nbsp; But my point is: You&#8217;re incredible.&nbsp; And so, Governor, thank you.&nbsp; And Senators Heinrich and Luján, thank you very much for all you do.&nbsp; And Teresa Leger Fernández and &#8212; you know, Herrell, and &#8212; and, you know, Stansbury, and all members of the House doing a great job.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; but maybe the proudest thing I&#8217;ve done is I appointed the first Native American to be a Cabinet member.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But she&#8217;s only been in New Mexico 35 generations.&nbsp; You&#8217;re a newcomer.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; A newcomer.&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, a special thanks again to the firefighters &#8212; over 4,000 of you.&nbsp; Over 4,000 of you are putting your lives on the line.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;re about to receive a briefing about the largest, most destructive wildfire in America so far this year and the largest wildfire in New Mexico&#8217;s history.&nbsp;<br><br>I just flew over some of the damage.&nbsp; And Air Force One is so damn big we couldn&#8217;t go in, but we flew the perimeter of the &#8212; of the fire.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s an astounding amount of territory.&nbsp;<br><br>And the impact on families that have been there for so long are so consequential.&nbsp; And in this &#8212; in a way &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s, you know, nearly 700,000 acres.&nbsp; And a new fire just started &#8212; have just started.&nbsp; Thousands of people displaced.&nbsp; Ranchers wiped out.&nbsp; Schools shuttered.&nbsp; And wilderness &#8212; it looks like a moonscape.&nbsp; You could see parts of it where I &#8212; I was able to see.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;m thinking about what you&#8217;re thinking, and that is our responsibility.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not a gift.&nbsp; We have a responsibility to help this state recover, to help the families who have been here for centuries, and the beautiful northern New Mexico villages who can&#8217;t go home and whose livelihoods have been fundamentally changed.<br><br>Governor, let me be clear: We will be here for you in response and recovery for as long as it takes.&nbsp; As long as it takes.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And I learned something about this Governor: When she asks something, I just say, “Yes.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I don’t think there&#8217;s &#8212;<br><br>GOVERNOR LUJAN GRISHAM:&nbsp; Can you get the legislator to do that?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, that’s &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; that’s what we’re trying.&nbsp; You know, I&#8217;ve publicly gone on record of supporting it &#8212; of supporting it.&nbsp; That is 100 percent &#8211;anyway.&nbsp;<br><br>There &#8212; I hope we&#8217;re able to get that done.&nbsp; I know that Ben Ray is working like hell in the House to get passage.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to &#8212; I have a little more trouble in the United States Senate.&nbsp; We have 50 Democratic senators, which means we have 51 presidents.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, we got to get a consensus and we can&#8217;t &#8212; not a consensus, in some cases, if they insist on it being a &#8212; requiring cloture, and we need 60 votes.&nbsp; So, it &#8212; it remains to be seen.&nbsp;<br><br>And so &#8212; but, you know, when you asked for major disaster declaration, Governor, I immediately responded, providing millions of dollars in housing assistance and cash grants and funding for emergency responders &#8212; not because they&#8217;re doing any favor; it’s an obligation.&nbsp; I think we have a responsibility, as a government, as a &#8212; to deal with the communities who are put in &#8212; in such jeopardy.&nbsp;<br><br>And today, I&#8217;m announcing the federal government is covering 100 percent of the cost of &#8212; (applause) &#8212; of debris removal and emergency protective measures for the next critical months that are &#8212; in this recovery.&nbsp;<br><br>And then there&#8217;s going to be a strong bridge until we &#8212; that we pass the &#8212; the Hermit&#8217;s Peak Fire Assistance Act, introduced by Senator Luján and Senator Heinrich and your &#8212; and Senator Fernández, as well as Stansbury, to fully compensate &#8212; fully compensate survivors for their total loss.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re also &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we’re also providing funding and loans for small businesses, farmers, and ranchers.&nbsp; And we need to be sure this doesn&#8217;t happen again.&nbsp; We know the circumstances of Hermit’s Park and <s>Calfe</s> [Calf] Canyon Fires are unique, starting with the prescribed burn.<br><br>Every year, the Forest Service, to put this in perspective &#8212; they do a pretty damn good job &#8212; conduct 4,500 prescribed burns.&nbsp; 99.8 percent go as planned.&nbsp; And &#8212; but this time, tragically, it did not.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why the Forest Service has just put a complete pause on prescribed burns in our &#8212; in the Forest Service lands.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s conducting an intensive 90-day review, which will make public the &#8212; all the detail of that review.&nbsp; And this needs to happen.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll be briefed on the results, and we’ll brief the world on the results &#8212; the country on the results.&nbsp;<br><br>And for folks at home, there are hundreds of fire &#8212; of federal personnel on the ground trying to help you get through this.&nbsp; I think, if you take a look, the most important thing you can do is register with FEMA, which allows you to get assistance you deserve and you need quickly.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a FEMA mobile app that allows you to quickly register for assistance.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s available in Spanish as well.&nbsp;<br><br>And our Director of FEMA, who I think has done an incredible job &#8212; how many folks you have here now roughly?<br><br>ADMINISTRATOR CRISWELL:&nbsp; Just under 400.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Just under 400 here.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I don&#8217;t &#8212; we &#8212; if you don&#8217;t have phone &#8212; phone service yet, you have Disaster Recovers &#8212; Recovery Centers in Mora and Las Vegas where you can register as well.&nbsp;<br><br>And we also have a team on the ground to help you register.&nbsp; And FEMA is calling every person who is denied assistance &#8212; anybody denied assistance to ensure they get the help they need and in the language they speak.&nbsp;<br><br>A lot of, you know &#8212; you know, you got to know how to know.&nbsp; You got to know what you need to know to be able to get something done.&nbsp; I can walk into the Library of Congress &#8212; one of the great libraries in the world &#8212; if you don&#8217;t know how to work the card catalog, it’s not very much use to you.&nbsp; I mean, it.&nbsp; You got to know how to know.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we&#8217;ve learned, in our administration, that it&#8217;s not just enough to provide the help but let people know how they can access the help, and when they can&#8217;t, how they can go about to fix that.&nbsp;<br><br>And so eligible residents can sign up for a state program that provides benefits to buy groceries and &#8212; and hot meals as well.<br><br>For the longer term, but beginning right now, we have to help with the combined impacts of drought and wildfires and &#8212; which threaten your vital watershed.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s hard to explain to people back east when I talk about this, because we&#8217;ve gone to &#8212; we&#8217;ve spent some time, the FEMA Director and I, in other parts of the country &#8212; in Northern California, Oregon, up in Idaho &#8212; to explain what we&#8217;re talking about &#8212; the scope and size and the consequence &#8212; and how the watershed is not &#8212; not &#8212; literally but in (inaudible) evaporating in many places.&nbsp; Find yourself in a position where it has vital, vital im- &#8211;impact.<br><br>And through the Bipartisan Infrastructure, we are already investing hundreds of millions of dollars in the state &#8212; of your drought relief and wildfire mitigation and water infrastructure.<br><br>And as the monsoon season approaches, we&#8217;ve authorized another $22 million to protect critical water infrastructure from post-fire flooding &#8212; (applause) &#8212; post-fire flooding and debris flows.&nbsp; And &#8212; and the work starts today.&nbsp; It starts today.&nbsp; Not &#8212; not next week, not next month.&nbsp; Today.&nbsp;<br><br>The bottom line is, Gov &#8212; to the people of New Mexico: We’ll do whatever it takes, as long as it takes, to follow your leadership and what &#8212; telling us what you need.&nbsp; And I promise you, I &#8212; and I &#8212; and we kind of joke.&nbsp; They say the “Governor is on the phone.”&nbsp; I say, “Just tell her yes.”&nbsp; And then I start the conversation.&nbsp; Y&#8217;all think I&#8217;m kidding.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not kidding.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>So, I&#8217;m going to stop here.&nbsp; And I guess we&#8217;re going to get &#8212; start the briefing, if we could.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I guess, David, I&#8217;m talking to you first.&nbsp; You&#8217;re Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security and Emergency Management, so I&#8217;m going to yield to you.&nbsp; Okay?</p>



<p>3:29 P.M. MDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Reception for the Democratic National&#160;Committee</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/11/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-reception-for-the-democratic-national-committee-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55355</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Private ResidenceBeverly Hills, California (June 10, 2022) 7:34 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, hello, hello.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; Thank you.&#160; Please have a seat, if you have one. Well, thank you.&#160; Haim, thank you very, very much.&#160; And, Cheryl, I &#8212; I told &#8212; I told Haim that we &#8212; we have something in common: We both married&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Private Residence<br>Beverly Hills, California<br> (June 10, 2022)</p>



<p>7:34 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, hello, hello.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Please have a seat, if you have one.<br><br>Well, thank you.&nbsp; Haim, thank you very, very much.&nbsp; And, Cheryl, I &#8212; I told &#8212; I told Haim that we &#8212; we have something in common: We both married way above our station.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And we both have incredibly bright and beautiful daughters.&nbsp;<br><br>And, Tanya, it&#8217;s good to see you.&nbsp; And thank you for everything.<br><br>Folks, look, Adam Schiff &#8212; you know, I hear so much about Adam.&nbsp; I get these phone &#8212; no, that’s not a joke.&nbsp; I get these phone calls from Nancy Pelosi.&nbsp; Whenever there’s anything I need, she says, “Call Adam.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; “Call Adam.”&nbsp; I said, “What in the hell am I going to call Adam for?”&nbsp; “He can help you.&nbsp; He can help you.”<br><br>Adam, you&#8217;ve done an incredible job, pal.&nbsp;&nbsp; You really have.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And I’m proud to be (inaudible).<br><br>And when I asked Jaime <s>Harris</s> [Harrison] to be chairman of the party, he said yes.&nbsp; And he hasn’t spoken to me since.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; He said, “How the hell did you get me into this thing?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Being chairman of a political organization is the most important, least thankful job in the world.&nbsp; But thank you, Jaime.&nbsp; I appreciate what you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; I really do.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, by the way, I &#8212; I have grown to love his home state of South Carolina, because I think I&#8217;m the only person who ever won every single solitary district and precinct in the state.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And as they say &#8212; they say in Claymont, Delaware, where we moved from, when coal got &#8212; died in Northeast Pennsylvania, and we moved from Scranton, Pennsylvania, down to Claymont, Delaware, a little steel town in the northern part of Delaware.&nbsp; There were jobs in those days.&nbsp; I was going into third grade.&nbsp;<br><br>The &#8212; you know, the fact of the matter was that my &#8212; my dad used to say that it matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; And &#8212; and I want to thank your senior senator, the leader of the House, for &#8212; I said “senator”; I meant to say “congressman” &#8212; in South Carolina.&nbsp; We have an expression in Claymont, Delaware &#8212; the little town we moved to &#8212; that “you all brung me to the dance.”<br>(Laughter.)&nbsp; You brung me to the dance.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Haim has laid out what I &#8212; I&#8217;m glad he did &#8212; a little bit of what I was going to talk about, about: In spite of the fact things are pretty &#8212; a lot of people are really worried because of inflation and the cost of food and other issues, the fact is that we have the fastest-growing economy in the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Not &#8212; no, no, not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s laid it all out.<br><br>But one of the things that I want to make clear when your friends, who are on the other team, come up to you and say about Democrats creating a deficit &#8212; it is true: We are.&nbsp; We have reduced the deficit by $320 billion last year.&nbsp; And this year, with all that we&#8217;ve done to generate growth, we invite a bit &#8212; we&#8217;re predicting a trillion seven hundred billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And the reason I bother to say that is: This idea that inflation is caused by the economic growth we created is simply not true.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not true.&nbsp;<br><br>And one of the things I wanted to make clear is that there&#8217;s a clear contrast between us and the other side these days.&nbsp; The biggest investment that we&#8217;ve ever made &#8212; we used to be number one in the world in infrastructure.&nbsp; Now we rank number 13 in the world in infrastructure.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s why I went to Adam and the leadership in the House and Senate and passed &#8212; we passed an infrastructure bill &#8212; road, highways.&nbsp; But not only that &#8212; and bridges and airports &#8212; but also the whole idea of an Internet that is affordable for everyone.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to spend over a trillion dollars &#8212; a trillion 200 billion dollars to make sure we become the leading country in the world in terms of the modernization of infrastructure.<br><br>The point I&#8217;m trying to make is that the &#8212; you know, the idea is we also have had a few other things land on our plate, like &#8212; like Putin.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You know, the idea that we can stand by and let Vladimir Putin not only invade a country, the country of Ukraine &#8212; which, by the way, nothing like this has happened since World War Two.&nbsp; This is an incredibly consequential initiative.&nbsp; Over 100,000 Russians invading a country in the middle of Europe at a time when we thought those days were over.<br><br>But this is a guy who I had been meeting with in Geneva, trying to put together around Christmastime last, and &#8212; to talk about dealing with a strategic compromise relating to nuclear weapons and space and the like.&nbsp;<br><br>And here he goes ahead and he decides he&#8217;s going to take over.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t want to just invade Ukraine, he wants to obliterate the Ukrainian culture, because he believes there&#8217;s no such thing as an independent Ukrainian culture.&nbsp;<br><br>Look what he&#8217;s doing.&nbsp; He is not only dealing with wiping, trying to go after what&#8217;s left &#8212; what was a small military to begin with in Ukraine.&nbsp; He&#8217;s knocking out all their cultural centers &#8212; their museums, their schools, their historic landmarks.&nbsp; He&#8217;s trying to obliterate the culture.<br><br>And the idea that we could stand by and let that happen was just not &#8212; not possible.&nbsp; Not possible.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we reinforced NATO, and that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re giving help to Ukraine.<br><br>But the point I&#8217;m making is this: that it is &#8212; it&#8217;s really consequential.&nbsp; And the &#8212; and the byproduct &#8212; and I said at the time, when we decided we were going to help Ukraine &#8212; the point that I was making was that it&#8217;s going to cost us too.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to cost the Western countries.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to cost NATO.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to cost the European countries and cost us.&nbsp; Because you know what was going to happen: The cost of gasoline and oil was going to go up, and the cost of food was going to go up.&nbsp;<br><br>The breadbasket of the world for &#8212; not a joke &#8212; has been Ukraine and Russia, creating more grain &#8212; producing more grain and corn than any countries in the world.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s 14 million tons of grain that is really stored now in the silos in Ukraine, but there&#8217;s no way to get it out.&nbsp; No way to get it out.&nbsp; The Russians will blow the ships up as they come out of the Black Sea, if they do.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re in a situation where we&#8217;re trying to figure out how to get it out through Poland and get it out through possibly even Belarus, believe it or not.<br><br>But the problem is the gage of the railroads are different.&nbsp; Literally, the tracks that their trains in Ukraine work on are not as wide as the tracks that are on in Europe.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re building temporary silos along the &#8212; along the border so that we can transfer this grain and this material.&nbsp;<br><br>And we can break down the price of food if we do that.&nbsp; We can bring down &#8212; and we&#8217;re dealing with the whole issue of, in terms of inflation &#8212; this is boring as hell, I know.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But do you &#8212; but it&#8217;s the reason for inflation.&nbsp; The only way we can reach out and try to do something is bring down the cost of food by getting this grain to market and by providing for the access to more fertilizer, which is a big deal in all these &#8212; not only our country, but around the world.<br><br>And we&#8217;re trying to bring down the price of gas, keep it from going up as rapidly as it is.&nbsp; I was able to release a million barrels a day from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve and convince our allies to come up with another 240 million barrels a da- &#8212; 240 million barrels, so that it kept the price from going up further.<br><br>But the point is this: We&#8217;re going to live with this inflation for a while.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to come down gradually, but we&#8217;re going to live with it for a while.<br><br>And I come from a family where, in fact, when the price of a gallon of gasoline went up, it was a discussion at the dinner table.&nbsp; Like most middle- or lower-middle-class families, it made a difference.&nbsp; The cost of heating oil, the cost of a whole range of things.<br><br>But we &#8212; there&#8217;s more than one way to deal with the impact of inflation on average families.&nbsp; We can lower the prices for other things they have to pay for on a monthly basis.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, right now you have a circumstance where if you know anybody who has Stage 2 diabetes, they have to have insulin, and they have to have it every week.&nbsp;<br><br>Well, it can cost as much as $1,000 a month.&nbsp; Average price $647, as low as $200, depending on where you are and what insurance you have.<br><br>But you know how much it costs to make?&nbsp; It cost to make $10 a va- &#8212; $10 a vial.&nbsp; That’s what it costs.&nbsp; No change in the formula to make it.&nbsp; And so if we allow Medicare to negotiate the price, it will bring it down to $35.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The generic point I&#8217;m making: Some of you &#8212; some of you moms, if you have &#8212; have young children and you work and you need dayca- &#8212; and you need childcare, it averages in this &#8212; in this city about $14,000 a <s>month</s> [year].&nbsp; Most people have no ability to pay that.&nbsp;<br><br>But if we have a plan where you could easily afford what we&#8217;re doing here to bring it down to no more than 7 percent of your disposable income, putting another 200,000 women back to work, increasing the economic growth, and not costing us anything.<br><br>My generic point is: There&#8217;s more than one way to deal with this &#8212; to deal with the immediate problem.&nbsp; But as Adam pointed out, it gets down to we need two more senators.&nbsp;<br><br>And &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the other point I&#8217;d make &#8212; I talk about how the Democratic Party is divided.&nbsp; We have 50 United States senators, which means we have 51 presidents.&nbsp; Now &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; 50 uni- &#8212; but here&#8217;s the deal: Forty-eight of them vote with me 100 percent of the time.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not much division.&nbsp; And the others, by the way, vote with me 65 percent of the time.&nbsp; The other two, they disagree on some very fundamental things, slowing up what we&#8217;re able to do.&nbsp;<br><br>But the point is this: What you&#8217;re doing by contributions today are enabling us to be in a position to win the off-year election, and a lot depends on it.&nbsp; Because guess what?&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t say this to frighten anybody or concern you, but, you know, the Republi- &#8212; this is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party.&nbsp; This is a di- &#8212; no, I really mean it.&nbsp;<br><br>I &#8212; you know, I&#8217;ve &#8212; as you can tell, that I&#8217;ve been around a long time.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;I was a senator.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve dealt with a lot of &#8212; a lot of conservative Republicans &#8212; men and women of principle.&nbsp; But this is &#8212; this is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party.&nbsp; This is the MAGA party.&nbsp; This is &#8212; although they are a minority of the Republican Party, Trump still controls the heart and soul of the Republican Party.&nbsp;<br><br>I have had six &#8212; and I will not &#8212; I&#8217;ve told people I would never say who went, and I won&#8217;t &#8212; six U- &#8212; Republican U.S Senators told me they know we&#8217;re right.&nbsp; “I&#8217;d like to vote with you on A, B, C, or D, Joe, but I can&#8217;t because I&#8217;ll lose my primary.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll be in real trouble.”&nbsp;<br><br>Look what&#8217;s happening, folks, out there.&nbsp; Look what&#8217;s happening on guns now.&nbsp; Now, I don&#8217;t ca- &#8212; I&#8217;m a gun owner.&nbsp; I own two shotguns.&nbsp; My son Beau passed away.&nbsp; He had another shot gun.&nbsp; We used to like to skeet shoot.&nbsp; We weren&#8217;t hunters.<br><br>But the point I&#8217;m making is that the Second Amendment is not absolute.&nbsp; These ideas &#8212; these AR-15s &#8212; (applause) &#8212; we outlawed the &#8212; them when I was a senator.&nbsp; I passed the law. I&#8217;m the guy that wrote the laws that eliminated assault weapons. And &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and I&#8217;m the guy who wrote the law that limited the number of bullets you could have in a magazine.&nbsp;<br><br>And when I was &#8212; everybody said, “Well, you come from a state that doesn&#8217;t matter a lot.”&nbsp; There are more gunowners in Delaware because there are duck hunters and hunters in that &#8212; in that &#8212; what they call the Eastern Shore than there are in percentage than any state &#8212; there was back then; I don&#8217;t know what it is exactly now &#8212; but any state.<br><br>And I &#8212; the way to sell this &#8212; I&#8217;d walk through the fishing areas.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of lowland swamp area in the southern part of the Delmarva Peninsula.<br><br>And the guys would be fishing, and I was &#8212; when I was campaigning to get this done.&nbsp; And they&#8217;d say, “God darn, Joe, what the hell are you doing taking my gun away?”&nbsp; And I said, “Let me ask you a question.”&nbsp; I said, “How many &#8212; when you go deer hunting, how many deer are wearing Kevlar vests?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And they’d look at me.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m not joking.&nbsp; This is what I &#8212; and they&#8217;d kind of look at me and g &#8212; and I said, “And, by the way, if you need 30, 40, 60, up to 100 rounds to fire,” I said, “you&#8217;re a danger to yourself, man.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And they&#8217;d go, “Yeah, well, Joe, but they say you&#8217;re going to take my gun.”&nbsp;<br><br>The point of the matter is that we passed it for 10 years, this ban.&nbsp; And significant violent crime and particularly &#8212; went to &#8212; mass shootings went down 70 percent.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>But I could only get it passed for 10 years.&nbsp; It had to be reauthorized in 10 years.&nbsp; The Bush administration came into play.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not &#8212; I don’t want to pick on the Bush administration because they weren&#8217;t all bad, but they &#8212; they didn&#8217;t have the courage to try to pass it again.&nbsp;<br><br>And guess what?&nbsp; Violent shootings went up seven &#8212; seven times what they were.<br><br>We have more people &#8212; and, by the way, the other piece I want to remind everybody of: It&#8217;s not just these mass shootings in our schools and the like.&nbsp; There&#8217;s a mass shooting on the streets of African American communities and minority communities every single day.&nbsp; Every single day.&nbsp; I’ll say it again: Every single day, more children are killed by gunfire than any other reason.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; Think about that.<br><br>The reason I bother to go through this with you is it&#8217;s not just what you saw the last couple months.&nbsp; I met with every single solitary family member in Uvalde.&nbsp; I met with every single solitary family member and spent time with them up in Buffalo, New York.&nbsp; I saw &#8212; that little girl hugged me and ha- &#8212; was hanging on my leg, who had the courage &#8212; the courage, at 10 years old, to take the &#8212; the blood off her friend &#8212; one of her closest friend’s body and put it on her face to pretend she was dead.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp;<br><br>And think about these guys &#8212; what they&#8217;re unwilling to do.&nbsp; Think about &#8212; my wife is a teacher.&nbsp; She teaches full-time still as a community college teacher.&nbsp; The idea we&#8217;re going to provide the way to deal with gun safety is to provide teachers with guns and classrooms?&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s a reason why the military takes so long to train somebody.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not easy to pick up a rifle or a gun and blow somebody&#8217;s brains out in front.&nbsp; More people get killed with their own gun in their home trying to stop a burglar than, in fact, any other cause.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; Because it&#8217;s hard to do.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a hard thing to do.<br><br>You know, I was in &#8212; in Buffalo meeting with the families.&nbsp; Sat &#8212; I spent three hours with them.&nbsp; And to hear the stories &#8212; the stories about how they &#8212; what they just did and how “we just finally got a grocery store,” and the community is finally coming back.<br><br>It’s so damn sad.<br><br>But here&#8217;s the point I&#8217;m trying to make: This is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party.&nbsp; These guys are extreme.&nbsp; They&#8217;re extreme.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re extreme &#8212; you talk about Roe v. Wade. Even if you didn&#8217;t agree with Roe v. Wade &#8212; it’s 50 years in the making, by the way.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been there 50 years.&nbsp;<br><br>And it had a rational balance to it, no matter what your background or faith was.&nbsp; But it gets thrown out.&nbsp; But here&#8217;s what else gets thrown out.&nbsp; If that reading &#8212; if &#8212; if the case comes down the way it&#8217;s been written &#8212; and I taught constitutional law for 14 years &#8212; if it comes out the way that it looks like &#8212; that the draft was, guess what?&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to have a circumstance where there may &#8212; what may be in jeopardy is whether you can marry, who you can marry.&nbsp; Because if you say there&#8217;s no right to privacy that exists in the Constitution at all, you got a very &#8212; he got a very different read.&nbsp;<br><br>And there used to be a case in Connecticut &#8212; Griswold vs. Connecticut.&nbsp; Up until &#8212; up until 1974, I think it was &#8212; I think that&#8217;s the year &#8212;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Sixty-five.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sixty-five?<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>You know what it said?&nbsp; It said you could not &#8212; you could not &#8212; a married couple could not use contraceptives in the privacy of their own bedroom.&nbsp; And guess what&#8217;s happening now?&nbsp; If they pass this law &#8212; if the Supreme Court rules as expected, we&#8217;re going to be in a situation where it becomes a crime for a woman to order across a state line a &#8212; a pill that would curtail pregnancy, no matter what &#8212; no matter at what stage.&nbsp; A crime.&nbsp;<br><br>And they&#8217;re talking about being able to go across state lines to arrest people.&nbsp; They&#8217;re talking about changes that are going to fundamentally &#8212; we don&#8217;t know how far it&#8217;s going to go.&nbsp; But this isn&#8217;t just the issue of whether or not Roe v. Wade and the rationale of Roe v. Wade is maintained.&nbsp; There&#8217;s so much else at stake.&nbsp;<br><br>The reason I bore you with this is that the idea &#8212; we have to make sure we remind people what&#8217;s at stake here.&nbsp; This Republican Party is different than anyone you&#8217;ve ever dealt with, other than the &#8212; the previous four years with &#8212; with our &#8212; with our good friend.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal, guys: It goes well beyond that.&nbsp; It goes well beyond those two cases.&nbsp; It goes to so many other issues that are &#8212; this is a guy who says &#8212; not a joke &#8212; windmills cause cancer.&nbsp; This is a guy who denies that there&#8217;s global warming.&nbsp; This is a guy whose party will &#8212; is trying &#8212; is taking on every single initiative I put forward on green energy.&nbsp;<br><br>And so this is, you know &#8212; let me close this way: I think it&#8217;s fair to say &#8212; and the one thing even the folks in the back in the press give me credit for &#8212; is holding NATO together.&nbsp; Because what happened was there was a clear expectation on the part of Putin that he&#8217;d be able to break NATO.&nbsp;<br><br>So I&#8217;ve spent well over 140 calls &#8212; I&#8217;ve either been in, in Europe and/or had them here and/or on &#8212; on video with them, and to &#8212; (applause) &#8212; but here’s the deal &#8212; and thank you &#8212; to maintain &#8212; to maintain the cohesion that we need to have.&nbsp;<br><br>But one of the things I found when I showed up at the first what they call “G7 meeting” &#8212; the largest economies in the world &#8212; and it was back last year in &#8212; I guess it was February.&nbsp; And I showed up, and I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And some of the leaders looked at me and said, “For how long?”&nbsp; “For how long?”&nbsp; “For how long?”&nbsp; Because he&#8217;s changed the world.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve spent most of my time, including today and this week, with the &#8212; with the American &#8212; with the conference I have going on for the Americas, trying to convince people that, “Just hang on.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be okay.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to change.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to go back.”&nbsp; But people are worried about it.&nbsp;<br><br>And we got to remind people in this off-year election what&#8217;s at stake &#8212; what&#8217;s at stake.&nbsp; And it’s really &#8212; it&#8217;s a pretty big deal what&#8217;s at stake.&nbsp;<br><br>In addition to all that I&#8217;ve talked about, what they&#8217;re worried about &#8212; for example, the Republicans have put out &#8212; the guy heading up the campaign committee for Republicans put out their plan, what they’re for.&nbsp; It has three major parts.<br><br>One, 70 percent of all the people making under $100,000 are going to have their taxes raised.&nbsp; Under $100,000, nobody above.&nbsp; Under $100,000.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be an average increase of $1,500 in taxes for them.&nbsp;<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal: They also &#8212; every five years, if their program becomes law &#8212; every five years, Social Security, Medicare, and Medicaid are on the chopping block.&nbsp; They automatically go out of existence unless they affirmatively vote it back into existence.&nbsp; Think about that now.&nbsp; They go out of existence unless they&#8217;re affirmatively voted back into existence.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, it&#8217;s unlikely they&#8217;ll vote them all out of existence &#8212; not let it happen.&nbsp; But guess what they&#8217;ll do?&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to make sure they curtail every one of those programs.&nbsp;<br><br>And you still have the &#8212; I call him the “gentleman senator from the state of Wisconsin,” arguing that we have to do away with the healthcare proposals we have.&nbsp;<br><br>The Affordable Care Act: They tried hundreds of times to try to get rid of it; they&#8217;re back at it again.&nbsp; We were able to lower the cost of healthcare for the average family by $400 a month &#8212; a gigantic impact.&nbsp;<br><br>So the point we got to remind people of: There&#8217;s so much at stake.&nbsp; So much at stake, from your basic human rights, all the way to the economic impact that will occur if we do not &#8212; if we do not win this election.&nbsp; And if we do, we have so much opportunity.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve never been as optimistic about America as I am today, and I really mean it.&nbsp; And the main reason I am is because of your generation and my daughter&#8217;s generation.&nbsp; No, I really mean it.&nbsp; Because think about it: The generation between the ages of 18 and 30 is the single-best-educated generation in American history, the single-most-openminded generation, the least prejudiced generation in American history, and the generation that has volunteered more than any other generation except mine when it &#8212; back in the ‘60s when I was graduating in 1968.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; There&#8217;s an enormous opportunity.&nbsp;<br><br>And the rest of the world is looking to us.&nbsp; And those of you who have &#8212; you traveled abroad, those of you have businesses abroad, those of you who have family or friends abroad, you know what I&#8217;m talking about.&nbsp; There really is, “What happens if the United States goes back to a Trumpian government?”&nbsp; It is a gigantic, gigantic setback.&nbsp;<br><br>And here&#8217;s the last point I&#8217;ll make: When I ran for this &#8212; I had no intention of running for the presidency, as you well know, because we talked at length about it.&nbsp; Because I decided I was out of &#8212; I &#8212; when I left the vice presidency, I decided I wasn&#8217;t going to run again for anything.&nbsp; And in large part, I must admit to you, because I lost my &#8212; part of my soul.&nbsp; I lost my son who was in Iraq for a year, won the Conspicuous Service Medal, the Bronze Star.&nbsp; He was the Attorney General of the State of Delaware.&nbsp; He should be the one standing and talking to you, not &#8212; not me.&nbsp;<br><br>And I wasn&#8217;t going to run again.&nbsp; And then what happened was &#8212; and I mean this sincerely; I want to remind you &#8212; I remember sitting before the television.&nbsp; I become a professor at the University of Pennsylvania.&nbsp; And I was teaching there, and I remember turning on the television &#8212; it was in the evening at home &#8212; watching these guys come out the woods in Charlottesville, Virginia, carrying torches.&nbsp; Remember?&nbsp; Hundreds of them carrying torches, Nazi flags, swastikas, and singing the same antisemitic bile, the same language (inaudible) that was sung in Europe in the early ‘30s.&nbsp; Accompanied by the Ku Klux Klan.&nbsp; And the head of the Ku Klux Klan saying he promised he “would not let us down.”<br><br>And a young woman was killed in the process &#8212; protesting them.<br><br>And the President was asked, “What do you think, Mr.&nbsp; President?”&nbsp; And his response was &#8212; his response was &#8212; and this is &#8212; I&#8217;m not making this up.&nbsp; Remember it?&nbsp; He said, “There are good people on both sides.”<br><br>That&#8217;s when I decided that I had to try to think about doing this again.&nbsp; But here &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, no, no.&nbsp; But I must tell you &#8212; I must tell you, I held off because I knew how ugly it would be.<br><br>And I have five grandchildren &#8212; I had four at the time &#8212; and a surviving son and a surviving daughter.&nbsp; And I knew what they would do.&nbsp; And so, I decided I wasn&#8217;t going to do it.&nbsp;<br><br>We have a &#8212; we &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t be so personal with you, but we have a tradition in our family, for real, going back to my dad.&nbsp; Any child in the family can ask for a family meeting &#8212; not a joke &#8212; and it has to be taken seriously.&nbsp; And you sit down, and whatever is on that child&#8217;s mind or that young person’s mind gets discussed openly among the family.&nbsp;<br><br>I got a phone call from my eldest granddaughter, who was then a sophomore &#8212; a junior at Columbia Law School &#8212; and said, “Pop, we&#8217;d like to have a family meeting.”&nbsp; And it was on a Wednesday she called me.&nbsp; And my deceased son’s children live only a mile as the crow flies from my home in Delaware.&nbsp; Two others lived &#8212; one was still in high school in Washington and one was at the University of Pennsylvania.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, they all showed up on Saturday.&nbsp; And they sat down in my library with my wife and I, and my &#8212; Naomi &#8212; named after my deceased daughter who was killed in an accident &#8212; said, “Pop, you&#8217;ve got to run.&nbsp; Daddy wants you to run.”&nbsp; And she &#8212; and they went on to lay out why.&nbsp;<br><br>Because their whole life they have been either this granddaughter or daughter of a attorney general or a vice president or a senator or &#8212; at the time, Vice President.&nbsp; But they know what it&#8217;s like; it&#8217;s good and bad being in that spotlight.&nbsp; It’s not all &#8212; you know, it&#8217;s not all happy days for kids who are &#8212; no matter how good they are over the &#8212; if your father is a well-known &#8212; or your mother is a well-known personality.<br><br>And so they started giving me the reasons why they should run.&nbsp; And my youngest son &#8212; my youngest grandson at the time &#8212; I have a new one &#8212; named Hunter &#8212; Hunter Biden &#8212; he was then 13 years old.&nbsp; And he said, “Pop, we know it’s going to be mean.”&nbsp; And he took out his cellphone.&nbsp; My wife doesn’t like me telling this story, but it&#8217;s important.&nbsp; Took out his cellphone and showed me a picture &#8212; a photograph &#8212; this was on the Internet &#8212; of me walking out of the church when my son&#8217;s burial, with a military honor guard escorting his casket, my hand on the &#8212; on the flag-draped coffin, and my other hand on &#8212; underneath the chin of my little guy, Hunter, holding them up like just this.<br><br>And you know what it said?&nbsp; It said, “Biden molests another child.”&nbsp;<br><br>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Ooh!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So he said, “Pop, we know it&#8217;s going to be mean.&nbsp; Daddy is not here, but he wants you to run.”<br><br>The only reason I ran is because Donald Trump was running.<br><br>Here&#8217;s the deal, guys: What you&#8217;re doing here really, really matters.&nbsp; We cannot afford to let this MAGA Republican Party win.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ve never said that before.&nbsp;<br><br>Some of you have been helping me for a long time.&nbsp; A lot of conservative Republicans I&#8217;ve worked with, argued like hell with, but they were honorable people.<br><br>But this is a different &#8212; as they say in the old days, “This is a different breed of cat.”&nbsp; And so we got to remind people what&#8217;s at stake, and not by misrepresenting anything other than what is exactly true what they&#8217;re saying.&nbsp; Because there&#8217;s so much at stake.&nbsp; So much at stake.&nbsp;<br><br>And that&#8217;s why &#8212; mainly, I should have just come out here and said the first thing: Thank you, thank you, thank you for what you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; I really mean it.<br><br>So let&#8217;s go get them.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And you know what you’re doing.&nbsp; Well, get the hell out of here, guys.&nbsp;<br><br>PARTICIPANT:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Sure you can.&nbsp;<br><br>By the way, every time I’d walk out of my Grandfather Finnegan’s house in Scranton, he’d yell, “Joey, keep the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandmother, “No, Joey spread it.&nbsp; Go spread the faith.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>8:06 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Reception for the Democratic National&#160;Committee</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/11/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-reception-for-the-democratic-national-committee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:48:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55354</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Private ResidenceLos Angeles, California(June 10, 2022) 5:05 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:  Those who know me and know my family &#8212; the story of my granddaughter &#8212; hearing that was worth the trip.  (Laughter.)    Look, you know, one of the things that I’ve found is that you never quite know exactly what&#8217;s going to happen, but &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Private Residence<br>Los Angeles, California<br>(June 10, 2022)</p>



<p>5:05 P.M. PDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Those who know me and know my family &#8212; the story of my granddaughter &#8212; hearing that was worth the trip.  (Laughter.)   <br> <br>Look, you know, one of the things that I’ve found is that you never quite know exactly what&#8217;s going to happen, but &#8212; in public life.  But, folks, we really are &#8212; I&#8217;m tired &#8212; you&#8217;re probably tired of hearing me say it because I&#8217;ve said it all during the campaign &#8212; and, Jeffrey, you&#8217;ve heard me say it &#8212; we&#8217;re at a real inflection point in our history, and we&#8217;re at an inflection point in world history. <br> <br>So much is changing regardless of what we do and regardless of what anybody says.  The change is going to be amazing.  You&#8217;re going to see more change &#8212; good and bad &#8212; in the next 10 years than you saw in the last 35 years.  It&#8217;s a different world.  It really is a different world. <br> <br>And one of the things that I have tried to do from the outset is what the &#8212; the world is looking for reassurance.  I mean, the world was looking for reassurance that America is back, and America is not what it was the previous four years.  And that&#8217;s not a joke.  That&#8217;s not a joke. <br> <br>I&#8217;ve been all over the world now.  And I&#8217;ve probably spent more time abroad than I&#8217;ve wanted to, but I&#8217;ve had no choice.  I spent an incredible amount of time in the &#8212; in the Indian-Pacific region &#8212; the Indian Ocean and the &#8212; and the &#8212; I&#8217;ve spent a lot of time in the western &#8212; in the &#8212; out west, in the Pacific.  I spent a lot of time in &#8212; I spent probably &#8212; I spent well over 150 hours just dealing with nothing but &#8212; just nothing but NATO and Ukraine.  Just because one of the things that people around the world are worried about is can every- &#8212; can we hold us all together with things changing so rapidly that they&#8217;re going to &#8212; that we can&#8217;t hold it together. <br> <br>And so one of the things that Putin was counting on, and I was &#8212; I had just been in Geneva with him.  We were setting up a conference on security that we were going to allegedly get underway, dealing with nuclear weapons and space and another &#8212; when he went into &#8212; when he went into Ukraine.<br> <br>And, folks, nothing like this has happened since World War Two.  I know a lot of people thought I was maybe exaggerating, but I knew &#8212; and we had data to sustain &#8212; he was going to go in, off the border.  There was no doubt.  And Zelenskyy didn&#8217;t want to hear it, nor did a lot of people.  Understanding why they didn&#8217;t want to hear it.  But he went in. <br> <br>And what he&#8217;s trying to do &#8212; he’s trying to obliterate the culture, not just the &#8212; not just take the nation, but of the culture &#8212; the Ukrainian culture &#8212; because he doesn&#8217;t there&#8217;s such an independent thing as “Ukrainian culture.”  He thinks that Kyiv is the mother &#8212; is a seed of Mother Russia and all is going to change. <br> <br>But, you know, what we&#8217;re doing is &#8212; the hardest thing to do has been &#8212; initially, is to keep the West together.  Keep everybody on the same page. <br> <br>I went to the first G7 &#8212; the largest economies in the world &#8212; meeting in England right after we were elected.  And I sat down, and I said, “America is back.”  And &#8212;<br> <br>Is the press here?<br> <br>PARTICIPANT:  Yes.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Yeah, well, I&#8217;m not going to say what I&#8217;m going to say in front of the press here &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; because I never quite know what they&#8217;re going to say. <br> <br>But I said, “America is back.”  And two of the leaders said &#8212; looked at me and said, “For how long?”  “For how long?” <br> <br>I just spent &#8212; and not by &#8212; the press will probably not say it, but I wish they&#8217;d go back and interview all the heads of state in the Latin American conference we &#8212; the American conference we just had.  And there was overwhelming &#8212; overwhelming support for what we were trying to do by holding all the hemisphere together. <br> <br>There&#8217;s no reason why this hemisphere can&#8217;t be the most democratic, the most middle class, and the most secure hemisphere in the world.  Not a joke.  No reason for it. <br> <br>And so, the point I&#8217;m making is: The first part of all this is to make sure we&#8217;re in a position that we were able to sustain, in the minds of the rest of the world, that America is back with the basic values we&#8217;ve always shared. <br> <br>But the point of the matter is that that&#8217;s not what the world is &#8212; the world is not so sure about that. <br> <br>And we have a lot to &#8212; a lot to discuss.  So, are we going to get into questions and answers and &#8212; why don’t I just do that? <br> <br>Is the press staying for that?<br> <br>PARTICIPANT:  No. <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, good.  Nice seeing you all.  (Laughter.)  Great being with you.  Been great being with you.  (Laughter.) <br> <br>5:10 P.M. PDT </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
