<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 02:59:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Launches New Federal-State Offshore Wind Partnership to Grow American-Made Clean&#160;Energy</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/23/fact-sheet-biden-administration-launches-new-federal-state-offshore-wind-partnership-to-grow-american-made-clean-energy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[White House Convenes Governors, Labor Leaders, and Private Companies to Boost Offshore Wind Supply Chains, Lower Energy Costs, and Support Manufacturing Jobs  Today, the White House is joining with eleven governors from up and down the East Coast to launch a new Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership that will accelerate the growing offshore wind industry.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>White House Convenes Governors, Labor Leaders, and Private Companies to Boost Offshore Wind Supply Chains, Lower Energy Costs, and Support Manufacturing Jobs</em></p>



<p> <br>Today, the White House is joining with eleven governors from up and down the East Coast to launch a new Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership that will accelerate the growing offshore wind industry. The partnership will support efforts to provide Americans with cleaner and cheaper energy, create good-paying jobs, and make historic investments in new American energy supply chains, manufacturing, shipbuilding, and servicing.<br> <br>As a first step of this Partnership, the White House and governors are announcing commitments to collaborate on expanding key elements of the offshore wind supply chain, from manufacturing facilities to port capabilities to workforce development. The Administration is also announcing steps to advance a National Offshore Wind Supply Chain Roadmap and designating offshore wind vessels as Vessels of National Interest to facilitate more offshore wind construction.<br> <br>After years of Americans facing energy uncertainty, President Biden has taken decisive action to jumpstart the American offshore wind industry. He set a bold goal of deploying 30 gigawatts (GW) of offshore wind by 2030, enough to power 10 million homes with clean energy, support 77,000 jobs, and spur $12 billion per year in private investment in offshore wind projects. Since then, the Biden Administration has approved the first large-scale projects, established new wind energy areas, and held record-breaking wind auctions—signature achievements that advance the President’s commitment to tackle the climate crisis and strengthen American energy security.<br> <br>These bold actions have unleashed historic private sector investments to expand an American-made wind energy supply chain. In 2021 alone, investors <a href="https://laborenergy.org/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/5-BNOW-FINAL.pdf">announced</a> $2.2 billion in new funding, including commitments to develop nine major manufacturing facilities to produce the foundations, towers, cables, and blades of offshore wind turbines. Supplier contracts to provide materials and services to offshore wind projects more than doubled. And <a href="https://nabtu.org/press_releases/nowa-agreement-orsted">historic project labor agreements</a> are helping to grow a diverse union workforce and support training programs.<br> <br>More opportunities are ahead, including an estimated $109 billion revenue opportunity across the offshore wind supply chain this decade, and East Coast Governors are laying the groundwork to seize them. Having already set commitments to procure nearly 40 GW of offshore wind, these states are providing a strong demand signal for clean energy that will lower energy costs for American families while protecting them from volatile fossil fuel price spikes. Collaboration between state and federal governments already is helping to create good-paying jobs and establish a durable domestic supply chain to facilitate the responsible development of America’s world-class offshore wind resource. The Biden-Harris Administration is committed to further partnering with states to maximize benefits to American workers and communities.<br> <br>That’s why today at the White House, alongside labor and industry leaders, Governors will join National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy, Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland, Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm, Deputy Secretary of Transportation Polly Trottenberg, and National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Administrator Rick Spinrad to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Launch the Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership: </strong>Eleven leading states along the East Coast will participate in this new Partnership, a first-of-its-kind forum for collaboration between federal and state officials to accelerate offshore wind progress. The partners will work together to build  a strong, U.S.-based supply chain for offshore wind, grow a skilled U.S. workforce, and build on work to address important regional matters such as transmission and interconnection, fishing and other ocean co-use issues, and other key priorities. The Federal-State Partnership will look to expand to the West Coast and the Gulf of Mexico as offshore wind energy projects develop in those regions.<br></li><li><strong>Leverage State and Federal Actions to Strengthen the U.S. Offshore Wind Supply Chain: </strong>As a first step of this new Partnership, the Biden Administration and Governors are endorsing a set of federal, state, and mutual commitments to expand key elements of the supply chain, including manufacturing facilities for offshore wind components, port capabilities, logistics networks needed to install projects, and workforce development to fill good-paying jobs. Working together, federal and state partners will track progress, anticipate future needs, and collaborate on a regional and national basis.<br></li><li><strong>Advance the National Offshore Wind Supply Chain Roadmap: </strong>The Department of Energy, along with New York and Maryland, is providing funding to develop a comprehensive offshore wind supply chain roadmap, through a collaboration led by the National Offshore Wind Research and Development Consortium and with partners including the Business Network for Offshore Wind. As part of this effort, in March 2022 the National Renewable Energy Laboratory released a <a href="https://www.energy.gov/eere/articles/report-outlines-supply-chain-needs-achieve-offshore-wind-2030-goal">report</a> on supply chain needs, including manufactured components, ports, and vessels, to deploy 30 GW by 2030. Today, Secretary Granholm will announce a July workshop for stakeholders, including state officials, to provide input on a roadmap, for release later this year, laying out actions to meet these supply chain needs.<br></li><li><strong>Announce Priority Financing for Offshore Wind Vessels: </strong>Constructing offshore wind projects requires specialized installation vessels, and projections from the National Offshore Wind Supply Chain Roadmap show that U.S. and global vessel supply will need to increase to meet and accelerate offshore wind deployment. Today, the Department of Transportation’s Maritime Administration (MARAD) is announcing the designation of offshore wind vessels as Vessels of National Interest for support through the Federal Ship Financing Program, giving these applications priority for review and funding. The program assists the domestic shipbuilding industry, providing support for U.S. shipyards to modernize their facilities, to build and retrofit vessels, and to assist U.S shipowners to cost-effectively obtain domestically produced new vessels.</li></ul>



<p>Today’s announcements build on the President Biden’s leadership in launching the American offshore wind industry. His Administration has already:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Approved the nation’s first two commercial-scale offshore wind projects</strong>, <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-approves-first-major-offshore-wind-project-us-waters">Vineyard Wind</a> and <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-approves-second-major-offshore-wind-project-us-federal-waters">South Fork Wind</a>, both now under construction and being built by union labor. The Department of the Interior (DOI) initiated the review of an additional 10 projects that, if approved, represent 22 GW of clean new energy for the nation.<br></li><li><strong>Announced an ambitious leasing strategy</strong> for the DOI to hold up to <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/secretary-haaland-outlines-ambitious-offshore-wind-leasing-strategy">seven offshore wind auctions by 2025</a>—two of which were held earlier this year—including areas in Gulf of Maine, New York Bight, Central Atlantic, and Gulf of Mexico, as well as offshore the Carolinas, California, and Oregon.<br></li><li><strong>Held a record-breaking wind lease sale in the New York Bight</strong>, bringing in <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-sets-offshore-energy-records-437-billion-winning-bids-wind">$4.37 billion in winning bids</a> for areas with the potential to power nearly two million homes. DOI &nbsp;also joined with New York and New Jersey to launch a <a href="https://www.boem.gov/sites/default/files/documents/renewable-energy/state-activities/BOEM%20NY%20NJ%20Shared%20Vision.pdf">shared vision</a> on offshore wind supply chain development, with a focus on delivering benefits to underserved communities. The Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership will build on these efforts.<br></li><li><strong>Utilized Lease Provisions to Leverage Union Jobs and Supply Chain Development to Accelerate Wind Development: </strong>The historic New York Bight lease sale included incentives to source major components like blades, turbines and foundations domestically and encouraged use of project labor agreements to ensure that these projects are built as quickly and safely as possible. Last month, &nbsp;DOI’s <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/biden-harris-administration-announces-winners-carolina-long-bay-offshore-wind-energy">Carolina Long Bay lease sale</a> included a new credit for bidders who committed to support workforce training programs or U.S. supply chain development, generating $42 million in funding.</li></ul>



<p><em>Read more about the new Partnership and the supply chain commitments made today:</em><br><br><strong>Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership</strong><br><br>The new Federal-State Offshore Wind Implementation Partnership is a joint effort of the White House National Climate Advisor, the Secretaries of the Interior, Energy, Commerce, and Transportation, and the Governors of several East Coast states who are early leaders on offshore wind development: Connecticut, Delaware, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, Pennsylvania, and Rhode Island.<br><br>An initial focus area of the Partnership will be collaboratively growing a strong U.S. offshore wind supply chain. Going forward, the Partnership will provide a forum for new initiatives and in coordination with existing efforts to address ocean co-use, transmission needs and other offshore wind priorities that may benefit from additional federal, state, and regional coordination. The Partnership will expand to include Governors from the West Coast and the Gulf of Mexico as offshore wind energy projects develop in those regions.<br><br><strong>New Commitments to Strengthen the U.S. Offshore Wind Supply Chain</strong></p>



<p>During today’s White House event, Administration officials and Governors will endorse this set of commitments to solidify and expand the domestic manufacturing capacity, logistics networks, and workforce development needed for a U.S. offshore wind supply chain that creates good-paying jobs and equitably benefits local communities.<br><br><em>Mutual Federal-State Commitments</em><br>To ensure the development of a robust U.S. offshore wind industry and domestic supply chain, the federal and state governments jointly commit to:</p>



<ul><li>Work collaboratively to enhance the U.S. domestic manufacturing, logistics, and workforce development network to support the orderly and expeditious development of a robust U.S. offshore wind industry, across both fixed-bottom and floating technologies.</li><li>Work together to most effectively address commonly identified high-priority gaps within the offshore wind manufacturing, logistics, and workforce network, and to facilitate regional solutions including, where possible, the use of public funds to advance these efforts.</li><li>Engage with underserved communities, ocean users, Tribes, local governments, and other stakeholders to ensure that supply chain development provides equitable benefits and minimizes any potential adverse impacts.</li><li>Explore aligning planned offshore wind procurements with offshore wind lease auctions.</li><li>Support the development of a domestic fleet of offshore wind installation and service vessels.</li></ul>



<p><em>State Commitments</em><br>State governments recognize that it is vital to facilitate and enable these offshore wind economic opportunities and ensure efficient and equitable processes so that communities can benefit at all scales. Cross-state collaboration and coordination will build a more robust and sustainable network of manufacturing, logistics, and workforce development that can realize larger and longer-term opportunities. The state governments commit to:</p>



<ul><li>Explore opportunities to use project solicitations to support domestic content commitments alongside local content commitments in offshore wind procurements, including mechanisms to prioritize manufacturing and logistics commitments that address commonly identified high priority gaps and provide benefits to underserved communities.</li><li>Explore opportunities to take regional approaches to advance development of a robust domestic offshore wind manufacturing and logistics network and workforce that is sustainable over the longer term.</li></ul>



<p><em>Federal Commitments</em><br>The federal government recognizes the importance of ensuring efficient policies and effective funding mechanisms to enable companies and communities to realize economic opportunities, securing regional networks that benefit all, including underserved communities.&nbsp;The federal government commits to:</p>



<ul><li>Facilitate timely and effective permitting and environmental reviews and advance a pipeline of projects and lease sales that reinforce strong market demand for investment in the U.S. offshore wind supply chain.</li><li>Utilize the lease auction process, consistent with applicable law, to incentivize investment in the U.S. offshore wind supply chain, including in domestic manufacturing, logistics, and workforce development.&nbsp;</li><li>Develop, in conjunction with states and other key stakeholders, an offshore wind supply chain roadmap that identifies critical gaps and opportunities to meet state and federal offshore wind goals and pathways to meet those goals, including opportunities where regional collaboration will provide greater, sustained local benefits.</li><li>Seek to leverage federal funding opportunities to promote a U.S.-based offshore wind supply chain, consistent with applicable law, including by providing appropriate incentives toward the Administration’s goal that 40 percent of overall benefits are directed to disadvantaged communities.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and Secretary of Energy Jennifer&#160;Granholm</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/22/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-secretary-of-energy-jennifer-granholm/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2022 02:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[3:06 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Good afternoon, everybody.&#160; Okay.&#160; Today I would like to welcome Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm back to the Briefing Room.&#160; Secretary Granholm is here to talk about gas prices and Putin&#8217;s price hike, which you just heard the President talk about just about an hour ago. So we&#8217;re really glad&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>3:06 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everybody.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Today I would like to welcome Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm back to the Briefing Room.&nbsp; Secretary Granholm is here to talk about gas prices and Putin&#8217;s price hike, which you just heard the President talk about just about an hour ago.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re really glad to have her here.&nbsp; Secretary Granholm flew in over 800 miles &#8212; we were counting this up &#8212; just this morning to be here with all of you to take your questions, because we know how important this is to us and to the President.&nbsp; And so, therefore, she&#8217;ll have some brief remarks, and then she&#8217;ll take your questions.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; All yours.</p>



<p>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you, Karine.&nbsp; Hi, everybody.<br>So as we all know, the summer driving season is underway, and Americans are paying more at the pump every time they fill up their gas tu- &#8212; gas tank.</p>



<p>This is a global problem.&nbsp; There are two causes for it, which these high prices derive from.&nbsp; One is, of course, Vladimir Putin’s war in Ukraine.&nbsp; Vladi- &#8212; Russia is a very high exporter of oil.&nbsp; Because of the invasion of Ukraine, countries like the United States and Canada rightfully have said, “We are not going to take any Russian oil.”&nbsp; Therefore, about a million barrels per day have been taken off the market as a result of that.&nbsp; And secondly, the supply and refining capacity constraints that have been created by COVID-19 in the United States but also around the world.</p>



<p>Since Putin’s buildup of troops began, our citizens are paying an additional $2.00 per gallon.&nbsp; And, of course, other countries are dealing with this as well.&nbsp; If you went to the UK today, for a gallon equivalent, you would be paying $7.71.&nbsp; If you went to France, you&#8217;d be paying $8.49.&nbsp; If you went to Canada, you&#8217;d be paying over $6.00 per gallon.&nbsp; If you went to Singapore, you&#8217;d be paying over $9.00 per gallon.&nbsp; So it’s happening around the world.</p>



<p>And President Biden, like all other leaders around the world, are grappling with this for their citizens.&nbsp; And the President is doing everything he can to reduce prices for American families.<br>So, as you heard today, the President is calling upon Congress to suspend the national gas tax for the next 90 days.&nbsp; Suspending the tax &#8212; the gas tax is going to provide families immediate relief from this Putin price hike.&nbsp; Of course, suspending the federal gas tax on its own will not solve the problem.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why the President is also doing several other things.</p>



<p>One, he&#8217;s calling upon states as well to consider doing gas tax holidays on the state side.&nbsp; He&#8217;s urging oil companies to use their profits to increase output.&nbsp; He is calling upon the industry to pass along the decrease in oil prices &#8212; which we have seen at the barrel level over the past week, for example, at the pump &#8212; and he is demanding that these &#8212; that the industry come to the table with some solutions on refinery, which is what is going to happen tomorrow when I&#8217;ll be meeting with many &#8212; the biggest refiners.</p>



<p>Collectively, we know that these steps will save American families their hard-earned dollars every time they fill up their gas tank.&nbsp; Of course, this is &#8212; sits in a context because the President has said that he is willing to use the full span of his authorities to help lower prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just to remind you, of course, he&#8217;s used the biggest tool at his disposal, which is our Strategic Petroleum Reserve, releasing a million barrels per day to try to stabilize supply, even as demand increases too, especially with the summer driving season.</p>



<p>He has also rallied other countries to release from their reserves as well.&nbsp; Collectively, about 240 million barrels are being released from reserves around the world.<br><br>And he&#8217;s increased the share of biofuels in gasoline that can help lower prices at thousands of gas stations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, of course, at the same time, we are working to save money for people &#8212; have people save money by cutting other essential costs: for example, help with heating bills, weatherization; other ways that citizens are trying to grapple with these high fuel prices: energy efficiency, rental assistance, for example.</p>



<p>The fact is that no President alone can control the price of gasoline, and we need more players at the table.&nbsp; So the President is asking Congress to act.&nbsp; He&#8217;s asking states to act.&nbsp; He&#8217;s asking the oil and gas industry to do their part as well.</p>



<p>And I will say that many domestic producers have been heeding the President&#8217;s call to increase domestic supply, in terms of at the wellhead.&nbsp; We &#8212; you know, some, I know, have made the claim that this administration is in the way of domestic production.&nbsp; But the numbers here are inarguable: We are now at close to record levels of oil production here in the U.S., averaging now 12 million barrels a day.</p>



<p>Under this President, the Presid- &#8212; the country is producing more oil on average than it did during the Bush, Obama, or Trump administrations.&nbsp; But still, we need more creativity and collaboration to get us through this unprecedented situation.</p>



<p>And so, tomorrow, as I mentioned, I&#8217;ll be speaking with executives from the major domestic refiners to discuss actions that government and industry can take to increase capacity and to safely operate their existing refineries and to overcome the hurdles that are in the way to meeting American &#8212; America&#8217;s demand and to increase supply.</p>



<p>With so many businesses enjoying high profits, our message is simple: That this is the time to reinvest those profits that will enable them to better meet the needs of our citizens.&nbsp; And instead of using it for shareholders or stock buybacks &#8212; we are not against profit &#8212; we are encouraging these oil and gas companies to invest to help their citizen &#8212; fellow citizens, to help their own workers.&nbsp; We need them to come to the table.</p>



<p>The real truth is that as long as our nation rela- &#8212; remains overly reliant on oil and fossil fuels, we will feel the &#8212; these price shocks again. &nbsp;This is not going to be the last time.&nbsp; The next time there&#8217;s a war, the next time there&#8217;s a pandemic or another hurricane, these extreme weather events we are experiencing, they will impact the access that we have to fossil fuels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The only way out of these boom-and-bust cycles is to break that sole reliance.&nbsp; And that means diversifying our fuel sources by deploying clean energy.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re laying a foundation for this clean energy economy with the President&#8217;s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why the President has invoked the Defense Production Act to increase domestic manufacturing of these key clean energy technologies.&nbsp; It&#8217;s why we need federal clean energy tax credits to get the private sector jumping headfirst into these new markets, which will all make us secure both from a national security perspective and an energy security perspective, so that we are not under the thumb of petro dictators like Putin.</p>



<p>So we are looking at some significant challenges in the way of ensuring that American people have access to affordable clean energy, but we&#8217;re going to use every lever that we have across the federal government to overcome these challenges.</p>



<p>So, thanks for that.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m happy to answer any questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Granholm, you said that this will bring immediate relief if it gets passed to drivers.&nbsp; But if there&#8217;s no guarantee from companies that they will pass on these benefits to those drivers, isn&#8217;t there a chance that this passes and consumers, drivers see no benefit whatsoever?</p>



<p>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Well, it&#8217;s one of the reasons why I&#8217;m meeting with the refiners tomorrow, the oil companies tomorrow, to ensure that they would pass this on.&nbsp;<br>Second, there was &#8212; we have some evidence of this.&nbsp; Because in the &#8212; very recently, and even ongoing, there are states that have actually cut their gas tax.&nbsp; And Penn &#8212; Wharton &#8212; did a study about whether that was actually passed through, and they found that the majority of it, in fact, was.<br>So I get the nervousness about that, the mistrust about some of that.&nbsp; But our recent history suggests &#8212; and this just came out, this study, on June 15th &#8212; that there will be a passing through, and we want to &#8212; we want to make sure that that happens.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And did you and President Biden consult with Democratic leaders on Capitol Hill about them actually being willing to pass something like this before the President&#8217;s speech today?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Well, as you know, we&#8217;re in touch with Congress all the time.&nbsp; And I know that there are a number of proposals in Congress that are already &#8212; that have already been, you know, proposed.&nbsp; I think Senator Kelly and Congressman O&#8217;Halleran.&nbsp; I think there were supportive statements from a number of members of Congress today.&nbsp;<br><br>So that is ongoing &#8212; that conversation is ongoing.&nbsp; I know that Speaker Pelosi just put out a statement and said that she&#8217;s going to bring it to the &#8212; to the caucus.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp; So if in this meeting tomorrow the refiners don&#8217;t play ball or are not responding in a satisfactory way, what is the administration prepared to do?&nbsp; What emergency powers is the administration prepared to use?&nbsp; What&#8217;s the next step here?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Let&#8217;s just take it one step at a time.&nbsp; I believe that &#8212; you know, we are going into this to have an earnest conversation with them about what it would take. We know that there have been six refineries closed since 2020, a vast ma- &#8212; I think five of them in 2021 &#8212; in 2021.&nbsp; And we want to ask, “Is there capacity to bring something back online, to expand?”&nbsp; So let me &#8212; let&#8217;s see how that conversation goes.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to assume anything.<br><br>We know that they are feeling the pressure not just from the administration, but from people out there about the price at the pump.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s important that they listen to their own employees, as well as the communities that they serve.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is this the kind of thing where the DPA could be used?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a tool.&nbsp; It&#8217;s certainly a tool, not to &#8212; let me just be clear about this: The DP- &#8212; I want to hear from them, “Is there a &#8212; is there a chink in the supply chain that is preventing some refinery from coming back online?&nbsp; Is there something that&#8217;s difficult to acquire?”&nbsp;<br><br>Those are the kinds of questions we&#8217;ll be asking.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; In the back.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary Granholm.&nbsp; The President has said of the war in Ukraine and the subsequent price hikes that have resulted that, quote, “We will be stronger and the world will be stronger and less reliant on fossil fuels when all this is over.”&nbsp; So I&#8217;m wondering: Does he fear that by pausing the gas tax, that by giving a sort of gas-addicted economy another hit that he might be slowing that transition away from fossil fuels?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; I think what he&#8217;s most concerned about is what real people are experiencing right now in their pocketbooks, this &#8212; especially for moderate &#8212; for low-income people who have no choice that they have to get to work.&nbsp; This is really what the President is fixated on: How do we provide relief to real people?&nbsp;<br><br>We can, we want to, and we must move to a clean energy future.&nbsp; And we can accelerate production right now.&nbsp; I mean, let&#8217;s be very clear that fossil fuels will remain in the mix of the energy system of the globe for years to come.&nbsp; This is why we call this a transition.&nbsp; I mean, the President&#8217;s goal is to get to net zero by 2050.&nbsp; And that suggests that there will, of course, still be a need for fossil fuels.&nbsp;<br><br>So we &#8212; but we also know that everything we&#8217;re experiencing in terms of these extreme weather events &#8212;<br>we spent $150 billion as a nation last year cleaning up after these extreme weather events that are all fueled by climate change.&nbsp; So we have to do both.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, I guess if you&#8217;re putting yourselves in the shoes of some of these refiners or some of these oil producers, what guarantee can the administration give them as you&#8217;re asking them to increase production but more regulation as you pursue that transition isn&#8217;t coming down the pipe for them as you&#8217;re asking them to (inaudible)?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re asking them to increase supply.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not ask &#8212; telling them we&#8217;re going to increase regulation on them.&nbsp; We are hopeful that they will see the opportunity of investing as well in this clean energy future.&nbsp; In fact, a number of these refineries have transitioned to biofuels, and that&#8217;s good.&nbsp;<br><br>We want to see them be part of this clean energy future as well.&nbsp; So we want to build more energy.&nbsp; We want to build clean energy.&nbsp; And we know that, ultimately, that&#8217;s where our security will lie.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Jacqui and then Kristen.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Granholm, you and the President have framed this war in Ukraine as the primary driver of the spikes in energy costs that&#8217;s the largest contributor to overall inflation.&nbsp; But the Fed chairman was on the Hill today, testified.&nbsp; He was asked a question: “Is the war the primary driver of inflation?”&nbsp; And his answer was “No.”&nbsp; How do you square that?&nbsp; Is he wrong?&nbsp;<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; I &#8212; I didn&#8217;t hear what he said on that, but I think most people acknowledge that the price of fuel is a big driver of inflation.&nbsp; And, in fact, they&#8217;ve put large percentages on it.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we know that the war in Ukraine, having driven up the price of fuel because it crimps supply &#8212; t&#8217;s a little supply-and-demand question &#8212; we&#8217;ve got to make up for the million barrels per day that have lost.&nbsp; We will have a demand problem when China opens up after COVID.&nbsp; There will be additional upward pressure on supply.&nbsp; This is why we need &#8212; not just in the U.S. &#8212; but we need globally more supply brought on board.&nbsp;<br><br>And so &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; His &#8212; his full quote was, “No, inflation was high before, certainly before the war in Ukraine broke out.”<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Well, I think most would say that the price of fuel has exacerbated inflation.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And is there any concern that this gas tax holiday will increase demand and then, thereby, increase inflation?&nbsp; Some economists and analysts have been raising that.<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Yeah, I understand that.&nbsp; And I also know that this President is focused on costs for real people as well.&nbsp; And this cost of gas is the most tangible, most real for people at the pump.&nbsp; So he wants to do everything.&nbsp; He understands the importance of it.&nbsp; He&#8217;s very concerned about inflation, obviously; it&#8217;s a top priority.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s also concerned about this price at the pump.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s going to do what he can to resolve that.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Kristen.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Secretary Granholm, thank you for being here.&nbsp; Senator Manchin said he&#8217;s not yet a yes on this.&nbsp; Steny Hoyer said he&#8217;s not sure that they have the votes to pass this.&nbsp; Why is the President proposing something that doesn&#8217;t have the support of Democrats yet &#8212; enough support to pass?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Well, I mean, this is &#8212; this is a conversation, right?&nbsp; So that conversation is ongoing.&nbsp; And I know that those Democrats are also concerned about the price their constituents are paying at the pump, and Republicans are as well.&nbsp; I mean, that is &#8212; that is the issue.&nbsp;<br><br>So, hopefully &#8212; you know, in the past, Republicans have introduced a gas tax holiday, and there&#8217;s no time that&#8217;s more acute than right now.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the strategy to get it passed, though?&nbsp; The President, obviously, making this announcement ahead of the July 4th holiday.&nbsp; What is he going to do to get those Democrats and Republicans on board to pass this?&nbsp; And how does he respond to the criticism from some Republicans that this is a stunt because he doesn&#8217;t have the votes?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s going to be having these conversations with Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; I would hope that both sides of the aisle are listening to their constituents about getting relief.&nbsp; I think the citizens will be the loudest voice, you know, in the room.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead.&nbsp; You had a question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Two sort of decision-making questions.&nbsp; One, why 90 days?&nbsp; Is there a belief that, after 90 days, that the market will stabilize?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; It&#8217;s the summer &#8212; it&#8217;s the summer driving season &#8212; is how they were framing this, how &#8212; the focus was on.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what would be the proposal to Congress to backfill the Highway Trust Fund?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Yeah, I mean&#8211;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you have an estimate for how much the trust fund would be hit?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Ten billion.&nbsp; About $10 billion.&nbsp; And yeah, the &#8212; clearly, we do not want to see the Highway Trust Fund hurt, so the President is asking for Congress to backfill. That could be &#8212; obviously, we&#8217;ve seen a $1.6 trillion reduction in the deficit.&nbsp; There are ways to be able to identify the funds to be able to do this, and he&#8217;s asking that the trust fund be repaid.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But is the administration putting forward any proposals to &#8212;<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; He&#8217;s having those conversations with Congress.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Cleve, did you have &#8212; do you still have &#8212; you had a (inaudible).<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, sure.&nbsp; I do have a question.&nbsp; I do wonder if there is a particular point where the President decides to invoke these emergency powers he&#8217;s talking about.&nbsp; Is it if gas reaches a certain level?&nbsp; If it &#8212; is it if you don&#8217;t hear the right things from the administrators?<br><br>I also wonder about the tone and the timbre of the conversations tomorrow.&nbsp; The President has been very splenetic, critical of them.&nbsp; I wonder what your conversation will be like.<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; I mean, honestly, we&#8217;re going in, in good faith, asking them this question about what can be done, what &#8212; what would it take, what do you need to open up additional refining capacity.<br><br>Obviously, they&#8217;re making huge amounts of profits.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not about funding, but perhaps there is something that they need &#8212; some additional help with identifying a supply chain issue.&nbsp; We &#8212; I just don&#8217;t know.&nbsp; So we&#8217;ll see.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have that &#8212; this is an honest, earnest conversation tomorrow asking how can we be partners in providing relief for people at the pump.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And are there any hard lines where emergency powers are invoked with gas prices, with answers, with whatever?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; We have not &#8212; we have not drawn any lines in the sand at this moment.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Two more.&nbsp; Nancy and then Nandita.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you so much, Secretary Granholm, for being here. Just following up on Kristen’s question, what do you say to lawmakers who are already calling this federal gas tax holiday a “gimmick” and saying, “Best-case scenario, it&#8217;ll save drivers about 20 bucks a month”?<br><br>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Well, it &#8212; there&#8217;s no doubt this is a modest &#8212; if it were just the federal gas tax &#8212; right? &#8212; 18 cents is &#8212; you know, is a modest &#8212; you know, a modest amount.&nbsp; But if you combine it with if the states &#8212; you know, not all states would do it, but certain states might be willing to, some already have &#8212; you combine it with that.<br><br>If the oil and gas industry is willing to reduce prices to the extent that historically they have when the price per barrel has come down.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, for example, right now, the price per barrel has dropped about $10 since last week, so it&#8217;s about 110, roughly, dollars per barrel.&nbsp; Normally, when you see that kind of a drop &#8212; $10 per barrel &#8212; the rule of thumb is that you see a 25-cent drop in the price at the pump.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re going to be asking why that hasn&#8217;t happened yet and when that will happen.&nbsp; So there could be some much more significant help.</p>



<p>And I will say that the Energy Information Administration has projected that by the end of the third quarter, because the oil and gas industry has increased and is intending on continuing to increase supply &#8212; that’s not refining but supply at the wellhead &#8212; that we will see gas prices at about $4.37,&nbsp; they are projecting, at the end of the third quarter.</p>



<p>Now, all caveats aside, because who knows what could happen on a &#8212; in the global economy if &#8212; you know, the EU, China, et cetera.&nbsp; All of that, is &#8212; is still very front of mind.&nbsp; So projected forecasts are always subject to all of those caveats.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re hopeful that we will start to see this come down.&nbsp; And this is one step in that direction.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Nandita.&nbsp; Last question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Just a quick question on refining capacity, especially when we&#8217;re talking about, sort of, asking refiners to produce more.&nbsp; That sort of takes time.&nbsp; Right, Secretary?&nbsp; I mean, it&#8217;s more sort of &#8212;</p>



<p>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; it appears to be more of a medium-term solution.&nbsp; What &#8212; according to you, how much of an impact do you think that will have immediately on gas prices?</p>



<p>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Well, this is the question to ask them.&nbsp; I mean, you know, obviously, building a new refinery takes &#8212; is a much longer strategy.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; But they have &#8212; there have been refineries that have been announced to be closed, there are some that have recently closed.&nbsp; What is the capacity?&nbsp; These are the questions.&nbsp; What is the capacity to bring some of that &#8212; and what is their capacity to bring more capacity online?&nbsp; These are the questions that we&#8217;ll be asking.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick one on &#8212; you know, some of the industry participants who are expected at this meeting tomorrow with you are expected to talk about, sort of, urging the administration not to ban fuel exports, and that is something that we&#8217;re reporting from sources.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just sort of wondering what your response to that would be if such a demand is made.&nbsp; And, you know, are you considering such a decision in the first place?</p>



<p>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Yeah, I will say this, that, you know, there have been an awful lot of solutions that the President has been considering over &#8212; over the &#8212; since the war began, since these prices started to jump up.&nbsp; And &#8212; and I don&#8217;t think any &#8212; anyone is taking anything off the table.&nbsp; He&#8217;s not proposing that at this moment.&nbsp; But he&#8217;s not willing to take tools off the table.</p>



<p>But we do want to listen, for sure.&nbsp; And there may be consequences that have to be considered on doing something like that, that would have adverse impacts on everyday citizens.&nbsp; And we don&#8217;t want that either.</p>



<p>Okay.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thank you, Secretary.</p>



<p>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Appreciate it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SECRETARY GRANHOLM:&nbsp; Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay, I just have one thing at the top, and we&#8217;ll take your questions.&nbsp; One hundred seventy-five million Americans hold at least one credit card.&nbsp; And in 2020, credit card companies charge customers $12 billion in penalties, including billions in late fees.</p>



<p>Today, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau announced that it is taking a step &#8212; a first step to review excessively high late fees, including how these fees are affected by inflation and how they contribute to credit card companies’ profits.</p>



<p>Americans deserve transparency and a little more breathing room in their family budgets.&nbsp; This is just one of the ways the Biden administration is going after excessive fees that companies use to hide the true cost of products.</p>



<p>From airline tickets to high-speed Internet service, agencies are taking action to make prices clearer upfront so that consumers can save money by choosing the best deals for them.</p>



<p>And with that, Josh.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Two subject areas.&nbsp; First, we heard the President today say what he would like to see Congress, states, and companies do on oil production.&nbsp; What is the case that he is making to Saudi Arabia and the Emirates for increased production ahead of his visit?&nbsp; Should we expect the rest of the world to kick in more supplies than they have committed to already?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as you know, the President is going to be going to the Middle East next month, and there&#8217;s going to be an array of subjects that he will &#8212; they will be discussing.</p>



<p>He&#8217;s going there at the &#8212; for the GCC+3.&nbsp; Saudi &#8212; Saudi Arabia is clearly hosting that.&nbsp; The Middle East is an important part of the region.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to be talking about, yes, energy security, but a whole host of other things, including a way to make peace, national security.</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have a &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any &#8212; we don&#8217;t have a specific list of details of what is going to be discussed next month.</p>



<p>And, as you know, Saudi Arabia is the chair of OPEC+, and we welcome the &#8212; the steps that they have taken as it &#8212; as it relates to oil production.</p>



<p>But again, they are the chair of that.&nbsp; Again, energy security will be part of the conversation, but not the only thing.&nbsp; And &#8212; and we&#8217;ll see what happens next month.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, on the President&#8217;s upcoming travel, does he plan to meet with Turkish president Erdoğan with regard to Finland and Sweden being in NATO?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a &#8212; I don&#8217;t &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you as far as any bilats that may occur at NATO or G7 in whole &#8212; as a whole.&nbsp; He&#8217;s &#8212; clearly, he&#8217;s leaving on the 25th, returning on the 30th, to Europe.&nbsp; As &#8212; when we do, we always share those bilats with all of you.</p>



<p>As it &#8212; as it relates to Ukraine and NATO, they were having &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry, not Ukraine &#8212; Finland, they were having a &#8212; a trilateral conversation with &#8212; on &#8212; on their NATO application.&nbsp; And so we leave it to them to speak to where that progress has been.</p>



<p>Go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; A couple more questions on &#8212; on gas.&nbsp; One is a housekeeping.&nbsp; Can you say which companies are attending the meeting tomorrow?&nbsp; Is it all seven that were on the initial letter?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Oh, my goodness.&nbsp; I should have &#8212; I should have called on you.&nbsp; She &#8212; she was right here &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; to answer that question.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was raising my hand &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; It is &#8212; it is &#8212; I do not have a &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; repeatedly.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; I’m trying to get to everybody.&nbsp; Trying to give everybody love here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not easy.&nbsp; So many &#8212; so many of you to cover.&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>But I would &#8212; I would suspect it&#8217;s the, as you stated, the folks who received the letter.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a list in front of me, clearly.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I would suspect those are the seven CEOs that will be joining tomorrow.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then I want to circle back on &#8212; on a question that you were asked yesterday.&nbsp; You said that this was the first step, but &#8212; the President expressed this &#8212; this sentiment again today on &#8212; on really laying down the hammer on these big oil companies.&nbsp; And so why is he not in the room tomorrow to express this message himself?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, the President talked about this, as you said, as you just stated, earlier today.&nbsp; The Secretary of Energy &#8212; <s>Senator</s> [Secretary] Granholm, who was just standing before you &#8212; is going to have those conversation.&nbsp;And &#8212; and what we want to see is a solution, come up with ideas.&nbsp; There will be representatives from the White House who will be in the room as well, so that will be happening.</p>



<p>And, you know, the hope is that there are ideas that come out of this, there&#8217;s a res- &#8212; some resolution, some solutions that come out of this.&nbsp; And so we have to wait and see how &#8212; how that goes.&nbsp; But that is the first step.&nbsp;<br><br>The second step, as I said yesterday, is hopefully to come up with some ideas in how to move forward and how to &#8212; how to bring up their capacity, because that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re talking about here.&nbsp; Because we have the crude oil, the crude oil is there, as the &#8212; as the Secretary was just saying.&nbsp; We just need the oil refineries to refine that oil so that it could help bring down gas ta- &#8212; gas prices.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, finally, what does it say to &#8212; about the prospect of the White House winning congressional support on this idea that just minutes after the President finished speaking on this, Nancy Pelosi sent out a very lukewarm statement about its prospects on Capitol Hill, saying, “We will see where the consensus” goes.&nbsp; That is hardly a vote of approval from her.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, we have immense respect for the Speaker.&nbsp; I think she also said that she was going to bring this to her caucus, which is also important to note.</p>



<p>Look, this is just the beginning of the process.&nbsp; The President talked about this about an hour and a half ago.&nbsp; And we will continue to have conversations with Congress &#8212; congressional members and their staff.</p>



<p>Look, just to step back for a second and really talk about what &#8212; how this President sees this: He sees this as an opportunity &#8212; a straightforward, simple way to deal with the pain that the &#8212; the American people is dealing with, giving them some relief at the pump.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re talking about.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s straightforward.&nbsp; It&#8217;s simple.&nbsp; The President would like Congress to &#8212; to act.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re talking about, you know, 18 cents per gallon, which is going to go a long way.</p>



<p>If you look at the average of states, that’s 30 cents.&nbsp; Just looking at those two things, that&#8217;s almost 50 cents.&nbsp; That&#8217;s going to go a long way.&nbsp; For three months.&nbsp; That&#8217;s it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s an “if.”</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Three months.&nbsp; That&#8217;s a “if,” but &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is all predicated on “if.”</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, absolutely.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to continue to work hard and to &#8212; to get the &#8212; the American public some relief.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about three months &#8212; 90 days &#8212; during one of the busiest driving times in our country for American people, American families.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how this President sees this.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m going to call on folks I &#8212; go ahead, Steve.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; The Sec- &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; If we have time, I’ll come &#8212; if we have time, I’ll come back.&nbsp; I just want to make sure I &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Secretary laid out the questions that she wants to ask the oil executives tomorrow.&nbsp; Is there a working theory that the administration currently has as to why the oil companies have not already increased their refining capacity?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; there&#8217;s no working theory on our part.&nbsp; What I can say is &#8212; let me just &#8212; just lay out some facts here.<br><br>So, as of this morning, crude oil prices have dropped by nearly 15 percent from two weeks ago.&nbsp;&nbsp; About prices at the pump have &#8212; have barely &#8212; but prices at the pump have barely budged.&nbsp;<br><br>The last time the price of crude oil was $110 a barrel, the price of gas was $4.60 a gallon.&nbsp; Today, it&#8217;s about 35 cents higher.&nbsp; That difference is a result of companies’ record-high profit margins for refini- &#8212; refining.<br><br>Oil refiners’ margins have tripled since the beginning of the year.&nbsp; In just the first three months of the year, the biggest oil companies made $35 billion &#8212; four times &#8212; four times what they made in the first quarter of last year.&nbsp;<br><br>So they would have to speak to that themselves as to why they are not bringing up their capacity.&nbsp; Because again, the crude oil is there.&nbsp; We need them to refine that oil so that we could bring up the capacity and so, therefore, the gas prices could come down.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we&#8217;re asking them to do.<br><br>The conversation will happen tomorrow with Secretary Granholm.&nbsp; There will be White House officials as well in the room with her until they&#8217;ll have that conversation.&nbsp; And hopefully, we can get to some solutions and some ideas.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Secretary spoke about “creativity.”&nbsp; Do you have any sense of what she meant by that?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;ll &#8212; she&#8217;ll &#8212; we’ll hear &#8212; we&#8217;ll hear from &#8212; from them directly.&nbsp; She&#8217;ll hear from them directly about what ideas that they might have to &#8212; to get this &#8212; to get their capacity up.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This topic of a tax break has been out there for weeks, if not months.&nbsp; And you&#8217;re just talking now about starting the conversation.&nbsp; Why is it just starting now?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, this is something &#8212; you know, the President talked about this even on Sunday.&nbsp; So some of you who were &#8212; who were there with him.&nbsp;<br><br>And, you know, for him, he wanted to make sure he looked at the data.&nbsp; He wanted to make sure he spoke to his economic team.&nbsp; And it was just an important, important piece of it.&nbsp;<br><br>But I do want to take &#8212; take a step back.&nbsp; If we look at the last several months, if we look at what has happened during &#8212; during the time that Putin amassed his forces along the border of Ukraine, we have seen gas prices rise by $2.00 per gallon.&nbsp; That is just the facts.&nbsp; That is what we have seen.&nbsp; And the President has taken historic action.&nbsp;<br><br>So, yes, it&#8217;s been a couple of &#8212; it&#8217;s been a couple of months, but he has taken action.&nbsp; He has not just been sitting around, waiting to make a decision on this.&nbsp; He&#8217;s taken action on the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, where we&#8217;re seeing 1 million barrels of oil per day.&nbsp; That is happening.&nbsp;<br><br>The ethanol 15, which is our homegrown biofuels, which he made &#8212; took action on that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re hoping to see &#8212; what we&#8217;re going to see is, you know, a few thousand gas stations in the &#8212; in middle America, across the country.&nbsp; Hopefully, that has &#8212; has an impact on that as well.&nbsp; And the 240 million barrels of oil that he rallied his partners across the globe to do.<br><br>So, those are actions that he&#8217;s taken.&nbsp; And so, this is just another solution.&nbsp; I want to make sure that we&#8217;re not looking at gas tax as the only solution.&nbsp; It is one of an array of actions that the President is doing.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I totally understand that.&nbsp; But &#8212; but, again, why is it just happening now?<br><br>And secondly, what was the threshold for him where he said, “I want to push for this now”?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, he spoke to this.&nbsp; He said he&#8217;s going to look at the data, he&#8217;s going to talk to his economic team.&nbsp; He did that.&nbsp;<br><br>The &#8212; the thing about this is: He took actions, as I mentioned, and when &#8212; with the gas tax &#8212; holiday gas tax &#8212; the way that he sees it is it&#8217;s a direct, straightforward way to deal with &#8212; to deal with something that the American public is &#8212; is really not feeling any relief right now at the pump.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;re also in the season &#8212; we&#8217;re in the summer season, as well, where a lot of people are traveling.&nbsp; And so, these next three months are critical for many families, American families.&nbsp; So, the timing is &#8212; also makes sense as well, when you think about where we are with &#8212; with families traveling in the next three months during the summer time.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A quick follow-up to that, and then something else.&nbsp; What &#8212; you keep referencing the data that the President wanted to look at.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What, specifically, data did he look at that that got him to a “yes”?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I think he talks to his econom- &#8212; his economic team.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; They present him with information that he needs with any other decision that he makes that &#8212; that deals with a &#8212; with a decision like this &#8212; you know, a decision that he has to make that&#8217;s going to really have a direct effect.&nbsp; I mean, this happens with any decision that he makes.&nbsp;<br><br>But, look, here&#8217;s the thing.&nbsp; The most important thing here is: The way that this President sees this &#8212; on top of all of the actions that he&#8217;s already taken, which I just listed out &#8212; he sees this as straightforward.&nbsp; He sees this as simple.&nbsp; He sees this as something that can have a direct effect on &#8212; on the pocketbooks of many Americans across the country.&nbsp; This is one of the ways that he feels that we can have an effect &#8212; a real effect.&nbsp;<br><br>And this is something that the American public wants to see, right?&nbsp; This is something that they&#8217;ve been asking for &#8212; how &#8212; in ways that we can lower the cost at the pump.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the administration still considering gas rebate cards for Americans also?&nbsp; And how much would be on those cards? And is the chip shortage complicating that decision?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any more on that to share besides, you know, the gas tax holiday.<br><br>Look, the President is looking at many options.&nbsp; I just don&#8217;t have any more on the gas card <s>holiday</s>.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I have two foreign policy questions.&nbsp; First, on Afghanistan: The White House released a statement saying that the President will assist options of helping the Afghani people after the earthquake, whether it&#8217;s via USAID or federal government partners.&nbsp; Can you tell us what kind of help the United States will offer?&nbsp; And second, how can you make sure that this help will not fall into Taliban hands?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; They’re all good questions.&nbsp; Let me just say the United States is deeply saddened to see the devastating earthquake that prim- &#8212; premilinary [sic] reports indicate &#8212; preliminary reports indicate took the lives of at least 1,000 people in Afghanistan.&nbsp; President Biden is monitoring developments as &#8212; and as &#8212; has directed USAID and other federal government partners to assess U.S. response options to help those most affected.&nbsp;<br><br>The United States is the single-largest donor of humanitarian aid to Afghanistan, and our humanitarian partners are already delivering medi- &#8212; medical care and shelter supplies on the ground.&nbsp;<br><br>We are committed to continuing our support for the needs of the Afghan people as we stand with them during and in the aftermath of this terrible tragedy.&nbsp;<br><br>Again, I just wanted to give a little bit of what we have committed: more than $720 million since August 2021, directly to humanitarian partners.&nbsp; So, this aid does &#8212; does not go to the Taliban.&nbsp; The aid goes directly to the Afghan people via &#8212; via humanitarian partners on the ground.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And another question on Russia.&nbsp; The Russian government spokeswoman said that the United States is destroying &#8212; what she called destroying bilateral relationship that already are in lamented state.&nbsp; And she&#8217;s accusing the U.S. of not allowing Russian planes to pick up Russian diplomats and their families from here, and insinuating that they might do the same.&nbsp;<br><br>So, how do you assess her response?&nbsp; Is it &#8212; do you think that actually the Russians have thought of the United States relations at &#8212; now at stake?&nbsp; Do you think that diplomatic relationships are in jeopardy?&nbsp; Or is it just the usual statement (inaudible)?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You&#8217;re talking about the bilateral relationship with the U.S. and Russia?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Correct.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, we have to be very clear here what we&#8217;re seeing currently.&nbsp; This is &#8212; Russia invaded a sovereign country.&nbsp; They &#8212; they started this war.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been talking about the gas tax.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been talking about inflation, just in general &#8212; global inflation and the challenges.&nbsp; A lot of that, when you look at gas and you look at food, that&#8217;s because of Russia&#8217;s war.&nbsp;<br><br>You know, this is something that if &#8212; if President Putin wanted to stop this and wanted to end this war, he could.&nbsp; You know, and &#8212; and to go &#8212; he attacks &#8212; he attacked another country&#8217;s democracy.&nbsp;<br><br>So the President has been very clear: He is going to make sure that we defend democracies, that we defend freedoms.&nbsp; And he rallied &#8212; helped to rally the West &#8212; the West and NATO to make sure that it was a forceful response to what Russia is doing.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, you know, this is &#8212; the question that &#8212; that the spokesperson is asking or the statement that she&#8217;s making, it really goes back to them.&nbsp; What are they doing for their bilateral relationship?<br><br>This is something that the Pres- &#8212; President Putin has caused, not us.<br><br>Go ahead, Jenny.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two quick ones; one on insulin.<br><br>Senators Shaheen and Collins introduced a bill today.&nbsp; I&#8217;m wondering if you&#8217;re involved in that, supporting it?&nbsp; Or are you negotiating something separate on reducing the price of insulin, which the President talks about a lot, with Manchin and Senator Schumer as part of a broader reconciliation package?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, on that particular piece of legislation, I would just have to go back to the Office &#8212; our Office of Leg Affairs to get more information to provide to you.&nbsp; So I just want to make sure I get that right.&nbsp;<br><br>As you stated, the President has talked about insulin, the importance of bringing down the price and cost for families.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had &#8212; he’s had several events where he has talked about those &#8212; that specifically.&nbsp;<br><br>Right now, we have to &#8212; probably after this, I&#8217;ll go and check with them and get specifics on that piece of legislation for you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more on your favorite topic: the China tariffs, which just seems to have become, like, a stale debate inside the White House because it’s &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Stale debate?&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, you know, I think there&#8217;s two sides.&nbsp; And one argues that it helps inflation, and one argues that it doesn’t.&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us any sense of, like, where the President is coming down on this?&nbsp; Because you guys are deliberating your decisions for a long time.&nbsp; And, you know, if it does help inflation, if he does support that view, then why not just do it?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, no decision has been made, as you just stated.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been discussed &#8212; he&#8217;s been discussing &#8212; the President has been discussing this with his team.&nbsp; I &#8212; we just don&#8217;t have anything to share at this time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No timing?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No timeline.&nbsp; A decision hasn&#8217;t been made.&nbsp; It&#8217;s being discussed with the team.<br><br>Go ahead, Zolan.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I had a question again about Afghanistan, but on the humanitarian parole program.&nbsp; CBS had some reporting a couple of days ago that showed that for those Afghans that are applying for parole remotely from still Afghanistan, that 90 percent had been denied &#8212; 90 percent of some 5,000 applicants at this point.<br><br>Is &#8212; in the White House&#8217;s view, is that &#8212; that program, which President Biden pointed to as really the main relief program for those that aided military officials &#8212; is that, that program, working as it should be?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, we are aware of the report.&nbsp; We are reviewing it at this time.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re not yet public- &#8212; we&#8217;re not ready to speak about it publicly.&nbsp; But I do want to give a little perspective as you&#8217;re asking about how this works.&nbsp;<br><br>So the report outlines our efforts under the humanitarian parole process, which is separate and distinct from the refugee process, as you &#8212; as you know, Zolan; I know you’ve followed this closely.&nbsp; Humanitarian parole has strict &#8212; strict criteria that requires applicants’ protection needs to be so urgent that they are unable to wait a while &#8212; an application &#8212; to receive protection via U.S. refugee admissions and process &#8212; in process.<br><br>The refugee process is typically how such applicants relocate to the United States.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s one piece.<br><br>But also, it requires applicants to leave Afghanistan before completing the mandatory screening and vetting.&nbsp; The vast majority of Afghans applying are still in Afghanistan.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s kind of the confusion there.<br><br>So, we are proud to have welcomed nearly 80,000 Afghans to this country through the Operation Allies Welcome, which is an unprecedented historic effort, and many &#8212; and more than any other nation.&nbsp; We continue to welcome additional Afghan allies and vulnerable Afghans and will do so over the coming weeks and months.<br><br>The State Department is also actively assisting eligible individuals to leave Afghanistan.&nbsp; In fact, we recently set up a processing hub in Qatar to process eligible Afghans for special immigrant or refugee status.<br><br>But we&#8217;re going to review the report.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to that right now.&nbsp; But I just wanted to make sure we gave you a &#8212; laid it out.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The report &#8212; as in, what was in CBS, that?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, we&#8217;re reviewing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re reviewing it.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, because that was &#8212; that was based off data released by USCIS as well.&nbsp; It was not leaked or &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m just telling you that we&#8217;re reviewing it, and then we&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;ll get back to you on that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One more refugee question, too.&nbsp; The administration committed to admitting 100,000 Ukrainian refugees.&nbsp; There were USCIS officials that recently released data that showed the U.S. admitting Ukrainian &#8212; not just refugees, but also asylum seekers at the border.&nbsp;<br><br>My question is: Does that 100,000 &#8212; commitment for 100,000 include those who crossed the border?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let me get information for you on that.&nbsp; I &#8212; so I can get an update on that particular program.&nbsp; And we can get some breakdown and get back to you on that piece.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow-up?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Hold on.&nbsp; Let me see.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I &#8212; I already called on you.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Go ahead, Karen.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Karine &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I can’t call on you and not call on them.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Got to try.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; I feel like it&#8217;s a classroom.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions on COVID.&nbsp; First, if you could just give us a status of where things stand with talks with Congress on funding and what the administration’s planning is right now for funding for testing in the fall after the funds are diverted from that.<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know &#8212; as you know, the virus has not been waiting for Congress to act.&nbsp; And we have been clear that a lack of funding would force us to make hard decisions, including last week, by having to pull funds from essential response needs, like testing capacity for some of our urgent needs for vaccines.<br><br>When we notified Congress of pulling funds early in June, we made clear to Congress the continued need for additional funding, the consequences we have long warned of real &#8212; are real.<br><br>Our fight for COVID funding is active and regular and robust because COVID, as we all know, is not over and we risk even more severe and lethal consequences for American people if we do not secure this funding, even if members of Congress may think otherwise.<br><br>And so, that was your &#8212; the first part of your question. And what was the second part of your question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The second part was, last week, during a hearing, one of the Senate Republicans who has been supportive of approving the funding request, Mitt Romney, was expressing frustration at the request now after that funding had been diverted.&nbsp;<br><br>He had said, &#8220;…for the administration to say they could not purchase these things and then, after several months, divert some funds and then purchase them is unacceptable and makes our ability to work together and have confidence in what we&#8217;re being told very much shaken to the core.&#8221;<br><br>I mean, is this process now sort of spoiled because of the way the administration had done that with that funding?&nbsp; Is there any prospects for this funding to actually get through Congress now?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just to respond to what &#8212; what Mitt Romney said: Look, we&#8217;ve &#8212; if you go back to January, we&#8217;ve been working with members of Congress, whether it&#8217;s a Democrat or a Republican, on funding needs for the COVID response.<br><br>We have been very active in doing that since then.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve hosted countless briefings, conference calls, shared more than a dozen funding tables all in a bipartisan basis.&nbsp; And these engagements, it’s &#8212; has had full of count of every dollar that has been spent and allocated on the COVID medical response and a full accounting of the entire American Rescue Plan, which goes well beyond the direct medical needs.<br><br>So we have been above and beyond.&nbsp; We have been transparent.&nbsp; We have broken down how we have been spending this &#8212; the funds.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been doing this for several months.<br><br>And so, the bottom line is: Every day that Congress fails to act puts further beh- &#8212; puts us further behind on us &#8212; on &#8212; behind other countries in securing that COVID response funding and the resources that we need.<br><br>And so, again, we have been transparent.&nbsp; We have laid things out.&nbsp; We have &#8212; we have had a 385-page document that I know Jen shared &#8212; had came out and shared it with all of you.<br><br>And so, this is incredibly important.&nbsp; We need Congress to act.&nbsp; We need Congress to move, and we need Congress to act.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Lawmakers serving on the January 6th Committee are getting security details.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve had Supreme Court Justices get threats.&nbsp; Is President Biden going to do anything to address these growing threats of violence against public figures?&nbsp; And have there been any security changes here at the White House, given that we&#8217;re seeing threats on the rise?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to any security changes &#8212; changes here.&nbsp; You guys are here every day, so you see for yourselves.<br><br>Look, the President has &#8212; you know, has spoken against the violence that we have seen, that &#8212; and the threats, the intimidation that we have seen against Supreme Court Justices.<br><br>He has been very clear: It is inappropriate.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not &#8212; it is not &#8212; it is not part of our &#8212; it should not be part of our political discourse.&nbsp; And he has condemned that from &#8212; you know, from &#8212; from him &#8212; from himself.&nbsp;<br><br>And also, he just recently signed the security funding that&#8217;s going to be for the Supreme Court justice.&nbsp; He signed that this past Thursday.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, on the Juul news, could you &#8212; a follow-up.&nbsp; Do you trust the Juul news &#8212; that it’s going to be banned by the FDA?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that one more time.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; There are reports today that the FDA is preparing to ban Juul &#8212; which is an extremely popular e-cigarette that&#8217;s used by millions of people, primarily young adults &#8212; to stop smoking cancer-causing combustible cigarettes.&nbsp; Is that true?&nbsp; And if so, is the President involved in that decision making?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I would refer you to the FDA.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything for you on that at this time.<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions &#8212; one foreign, one domestic.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll just follow up on the violence we&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp; As we get closer to the Supreme Court decision on Roe, there&#8217;s a group that has been distributing flyers around Washington, D.C., but also across the country and also online, called “Jane&#8217;s Revenge” that declares there will be a night of rage &#8212; looting, burning, rioting &#8212; if Roe is overturned.&nbsp; What message does this White House have in advance of that ruling as we get closer to it?&nbsp; And &#8212;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, again, fi- &#8212; violence and destruction of property have no place in our country under any circumstance, and the President denounces this action.&nbsp; Actions like this are completely unacceptable, regardless of our &#8212; of our politics.&nbsp; So we have denounced that, and we will continue to denounce any violence or threats.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the foreign question: With respect to the President&#8217;s trip to Israel, he is potentially scheduled to meet virtually with the Indian leader, Modi.&nbsp; Does the White House have any comment on the Indian authorities demolishing the homes of people who have been protesting the derogatory comments made by Indian authorities against the Prophet Muhammad?&nbsp; They&#8217;ve been having their homes destroyed by bulldozers in recent weeks.&nbsp; Is there any chance that the President will be pressing the Indian leader to protect Muslim minorities in India?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of what the &#8212; the President&#8217;s schedule.&nbsp; We will have more in the upcoming days on exactly what the President is going to be doing on that trip.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to speak to &#8212; clearly, the President &#8212; we have said this &#8212; he&#8217;s a straight shooter.&nbsp; He has no problem talking to leaders about humanitarian rights, about freedoms, about the importance of democracy.&nbsp; This is something that the President has done in the past.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to, specifically, what&#8217;s going to be on the agenda and what their conversation is going to be.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But, generally, just the fact that people&#8217;s homes are being demolished right now.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, I &#8212; I understand that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just saying the President has no &#8212; he is a straight shooter and speaks &#8212; and speaks very frankly.&nbsp; And when it comes to humanitarian rights, has no problem having those direct conversations &#8212; leader-leader conversations.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow-up?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Follow-up?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to go to &#8212; go ahead, Niels.&nbsp; Niels.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Thank &#8212; thank you.&nbsp; Has there been &#8212; as we&#8217;re looking at the student loan piece, that there was a number of senators and House members with &#8212; over at the AFL-CIO this morning, led by Chuck Schumer, who were renewing their push for the President to cancel student debt.&nbsp; I know that there needs to be a decision on that by the end of August.&nbsp; What is the status of that decision?&nbsp; And what is the status of &#8212; specifically, of the legal review that we know has been underway in terms of what exactly the President&#8217;s authorities may be?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So the administ- &#8212; we&#8217;re still continuing &#8212; the President, the administration &#8212; to assess options of cancellation.&nbsp; We have not made a decision yet.<br><br>As the President said just recently, I think on Sunday, he expects to make a decision on that soon.&nbsp; I do want to add: No one &#8212; no one has been required to pay a single dime of student loans since the President took office, which is 41 million borrowers; provided $20 billion in targeted debt relief to 1.3 million borrowers.&nbsp; We just don&#8217;t have a decision that&#8217;s been made, and he actually spoke to this most recently.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And more broadly, on questions where there are these sort of legal questions about what the executive authority is versus when you need to go to Congress on the gas tax:&nbsp;Obviously, I think there&#8217;s a general assessment, but to suspend a tax, you need Congress involved.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But sort of how much is going on here behind the scenes to try and review options for when you need to go look to Congress for something versus something that can be done at the executive level to help bring down costs and deal with inflation and help people with their pocketbooks?<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, look, when it comes to the gas tax holiday, the way that the President sees this: It&#8217;s a simple, straightforward way to do deal with an issue that&#8217;s really hurting families at the gas pump.&nbsp; If you look at the next three months &#8212; where it is going to be a very busy three months of families going on vacation, driving, maybe across the country, whatever families do &#8212; it is important that we really have a &#8212; really have an action and have a reaction to what families are feeling.&nbsp;<br><br>And so this is the way that the President &#8212; when he made the decision, he understood it&#8217;s a simple, straightforward way. It is 18 cents at the federal level.&nbsp; It is &#8212; average out 30 cents in states.&nbsp; If you &#8212; if oil refineries and companies do their part, that&#8217;s almost a dollar per gallon.&nbsp;<br><br>So this is &#8212; this is real for many people.&nbsp; This is very real for everyday Americans and incredibly important.<br><br>So the way that the President sees this: He wants to make sure that we do something that the American people are going to feel directly.&nbsp;<br><br>I think I’m being given &#8212; given the &#8212; I’ll take one more.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In the back?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow on India, please.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; One more.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Oh, my.&nbsp; Go ahead, sir.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; You just mentioned that dollar that people would feel that&#8217;s real.&nbsp; It&#8217;s three months, though.&nbsp; Then what do you tell people who are all of a sudden going to be paying a dollar more in three months?&nbsp; Why &#8212; why build in volatility like that when people are already very anxious about this economy?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, as the Secretary said, we&#8217;re going to take this step by step.&nbsp; We are &#8212; I think &#8212; like I said, the next three months, the next 90 days is when American families &#8212; people are going to be driving the most.&nbsp; And so this is an important &#8212; we saw this as an important time to do this now, or in this timeframe.&nbsp;<br><br>And so we&#8217;re going to &#8212; you know, the President feels that this is going to have a direct effect.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll &#8212; we’ll talk more about what the next steps are.&nbsp; The President is not afraid to use his executive authority.&nbsp; We have said that.&nbsp; He said all &#8212; all things are on the table to make sure that we lower cost for American families.&nbsp;<br><br>So he&#8217;s going to continue to look at other options.&nbsp; But again, this is not the only solution.&nbsp; This is not the only solution.&nbsp; This is one way to deal with high prices &#8212; gas prices in particular.&nbsp; We talked about the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.&nbsp; We talked about the ethanol 15.&nbsp;<br><br>All of these things are important actions that the President has taken.&nbsp; But for now, with the gas tax holiday, we encourage &#8212; we ask Congress to act.<br><br>Thanks, everybody.<br><br>4:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at a Film Screening at the White&#160;House for PBS’ Hiding In Plain Sight: Youth Mental&#160;Illness</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/22/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-a-film-screening-at-the-white-house-for-pbs-hiding-in-plain-sight-youth-mental-illness/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 23:24:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56099</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room &#124; White House *** I’m proud to welcome you to the White House for this special screening of “Hiding in Plain Sight.”  You know, a lot of the stories that we’re going to see today are hard to watch.  It’s impossible not to be moved by the pain that these young people and their families share.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room | White House<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">***</p>



<p class="has-text-align-left">I’m proud to welcome you to the White House for this special screening of “Hiding in Plain Sight.” <br><br>You know, a lot of the stories that we’re going to see today are hard to watch. <br><br>It’s impossible not to be moved by the pain that these young people and their families share.<br><br>As a parent, the only thing we want to do is protect our children. We do everything we can to help them grow up safely. <br><br>If they break a leg, we put them in a cast. <br><br>If they have strep throat, we get them antibiotics. <br><br>Mental health is health. But the solutions to address these challenges aren’t always clear cut. <br><br>The journey to treatment is rarely a straight line and it can be hard to find the resources that you need. Far too often, struggles are cloaked in secrecy and shame. <br><br>About a month ago, we invited a group of incredible young mental health leaders here to the White House. <br><br>Like everyone in this documentary, they shared their struggles—often through tears. <br><br>They talked about being afraid, about hiding who they are. It broke my heart. <br><br>But there was so much hope there, too. Because they had all found a way from that darkness towards the light. <br><br>They found it through treatment. Through community. Through storytelling and other creative new ways to build resilience.   <br><br>One young man said, “It was beautiful when I realized, wow, I’m not so alone anymore.”<br><br>For many years, an alarming number of young people have struggled with mental health challenges—and the pandemic has made it exponentially worse. <br><br>The isolation. The anxiety. The grief. <br><br>We have so much work to do to help our children heal. <br><br>We have so much work to do to make sure that no one feels like their pain has to be hidden. <br><br>We want young people everywhere to know: We see you. We hear you. And we will work to make this better. <br><br>That’s why Joe made this a key part of his Unity Agenda. <br><br>He’s working to expand the mental health workforce and invest in counselors and other mental health resources in our schools. <br><br>In October, the Department of Education released new resources and evidence-based recommendations for educators. <br><br>They’ve also committed to collaborating with the Department of Health and Human Services to address the mental health needs of youth across the country. <br><br>And starting in July, all Americans experiencing a mental health crisis, including thoughts of self-harm, can dial “9-8-8” to be connected with trained crisis responders who can connect them to resources.<br><br>This isn’t a red or a blue issue. It’s an American issue—a global issue. And we must come together to find better solutions. <br><br>Because it’s not going to be easy. But I know that it starts with this: bringing the problem into the light. <br><br>Having the conversation. Helping our children—and everyone who suffers from this disease—understand that they aren’t alone. None of us are.  <br><br>So, I want to thank Ken Burns, and directors Erik You-ers and Christopher Loren You-ers for creating a documentary that can help us do just that.<br><br>Ken has such a gift for breaking open the stories we don’t always see. <br><br>And I especially want to thank the brave young people who took part in this. <br><br>Would all of you stand?<br><br>It takes incredible courage to tell your story. To be honest about the struggles you’ve faced and say, “I’m not OK.”<br><br>And it’s on us to meet that courage with action. To do everything in our power to give you what you need to heal. <br><br>So, thank you. You are a light to so many lives and I want you to know that your President and I are grateful for your courage. Today is about you.<br><br>Thank you to everyone for coming out this afternoon. <br><br>And now, Ken Burns.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of U.S.-EU Task Force on European Energy Security&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/readout-of-u-s-eu-task-force-on-european-energy-security-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 21:02:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S.-EU Task Force on European Energy Security met virtually on June 22, 2022 convened by co-chairs Amos Hochstein, U.S. Senior Advisor for Energy Security, and Björn Seibert, Head of Cabinet of the European Commission President, and under the leadership of Ditte Juul Jørgensen, European Commission Director General for Energy, and Melanie Nakagawa, Special Assistant&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-left">The U.S.-EU Task Force on European Energy Security met virtually on June 22, 2022 convened by co-chairs Amos Hochstein, U.S. Senior Advisor for Energy Security, and Björn Seibert, Head of Cabinet of the European Commission President, and under the leadership of Ditte Juul Jørgensen, European Commission Director General for Energy, and Melanie Nakagawa, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Climate and Energy at the National Security Council.  The discussion focused on reviewing progress since the March 25 Joint Statement by Presidents Biden and Von der Leyen and charting its next steps. The sides denounced Russia’s continued energy coercion of European Union Member States and underscored their continued commitment to reduce dependency on Russian fossil fuels by diversifying Europe’s energy supply and taking concrete steps to reduce energy demand through energy efficiency, smart technology deployment and greater use of renewable energy. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the&#160;Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-72/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 20:36:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Randy W. Berry, of Colorado, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Namibia. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Anjali Chaturvedi, of Maryland, to be General Counsel, Department of Veterans Affairs, vice Richard&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Randy W. Berry, of Colorado, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Career Minister, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Namibia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Anjali Chaturvedi, of Maryland, to be General Counsel, Department of Veterans Affairs, vice Richard A. Sauber.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Robert William Forden, of California, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Kingdom of Cambodia.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thomas E. Harvey, of Florida, to be a Member of the Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Moshe Z. Marvit, of Pennsylvania, to be a Member of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission for a term expiring August 30, 2028, vice Arthur R. Traynor III, term expiring.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Arati Prabhakar, of California, to be Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, vice Eric S. Lander, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Robert E. Primus, of New Jersey, to be a Member of the Surface Transportation Board for a term expiring December 31, 2027.&nbsp;&nbsp; (Reappointment)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Rolfe Michael Schiffer, of New York, to be an Assistant Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, vice Jonathan Nicholas Stivers.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Lucy Tamlyn, of Rhode Island, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Democratic Republic of the Congo.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp; Pamela M. Tremont, of Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Zimbabwe.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Gas Prices and Putin&#8217;s Price&#160;Hike</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/22/remarks-by-president-biden-on-gas-prices-and-putins-price-hike/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 20:03:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[South Court AuditoriumEisenhower Executive Office Building 2:03 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good afternoon, everyone.&#160; I&#8217;d like to talk to you about the actions I’m announcing to bring down gas prices. First, today I’m calling on Congress to suspend the federal gas tax for the next 90 days, through the busy summer season &#8212; busy travel&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">South Court Auditorium<br>Eisenhower Executive Office Building</p>



<p>2:03 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good afternoon, everyone.&nbsp; I&#8217;d like to talk to you about the actions I’m announcing to bring down gas prices.<br><br>First, today I’m calling on Congress to suspend the federal gas tax for the next 90 days, through the busy summer season &#8212; busy travel season.</p>



<p>Here’s what that means: Every time you go to the gas station to fill your tank, the federal government charges an 18-cent tax per gallon of gas that you purchase and a 24-cent tax per gallon of diesel you purchase.&nbsp; It’s a tax that’s been around for 90 years.</p>



<p>It’s important because we use it for the Highway Trust Fund to keep our highways going.&nbsp; But what I’m proposing is suspending the federal gas tax without affecting the Highway Trust Fund.</p>



<p>And here’s how we do that: With the tax revenues up this year and our deficit down over $1.6 trillion this year alone, we’ll still be able to fix our highways and bring down prices of gas.&nbsp; We can do both at the same time.</p>



<p>By suspending the 18-cent gas tax &#8212; federal gas tax for the next 90 days, we can bring down the price of gas and give families just a little bit of relief.</p>



<p>I call on the companies to pass this along &#8212; every penny of this 18-cents reduction &#8212; to the consumers.&nbsp; This is &#8212; there&#8217;s no time now for profiteering.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are a number of other proposals by Democrats in the House and the Senate, and I hope my call for action can help move those proposals forward as well.&nbsp; But we can also cut gas prices even more in another way.</p>



<p>That’s why the second action I’m taking is calling on states to either suspend the state gas tax as well or find other ways to deliver some relief.</p>



<p>State gas taxes average [another] 30 cents per gallon.&nbsp; Already, some states have acted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Connecticut and New York, the governors have temporarily suspended their gas tax as well.</p>



<p>In Illinois and Colorado, governors delayed theirs to give families a bit more breathing room as well.</p>



<p>In Minnesota, Governor Walz proposes using state budget surpluses to give households a rebate that will help them pay for gas at the pump or other essential needs.</p>



<p>I’m calling on more states and local governments to take actions like these.</p>



<p>Thanks to our historic economic recovery, which fortified state budgets that had been hurt in the pandemic, states are now in a strong position to be able to afford to take some of these actions.</p>



<p>Now, I fully understand that a gas tax holiday alone is not going to fix the problem, but it will provide families some immediate relief &#8212; just a little bit of breathing room &#8212; as we continue working to bring down prices for the long haul.</p>



<p>Third, I’m calling on the industry to refine more oil into gasoline and to bring down gas prices.</p>



<p>Let me explain.&nbsp; I know my Republican friends claim we’re not producing enough oil and I’m limiting oil production.&nbsp; Quite frankly, that’s nonsense.</p>



<p>Here’s the truth: Just this month, America produced 12 million barrels of oil per day.&nbsp; That’s the highest &#8212; that’s higher than average under my predecessor.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m &#8212; we’re on track to set a new record for production next year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Plus, I’ve added to that supply of oil by releasing a record 1 million barrels of oil per day from what’s called the Strategic Petro- &#8212; Petroleum Reserve.</p>



<p>In fact, I just led the world to coordinate the largest release of global oil reserves in history, including from other countries.&nbsp; In total, that’s 240 million barrels to boost global supply.<br><br>And Republicans falsely claim that I’m blocking production on federal lands.&nbsp; But again, that’s nonsense.</p>



<p>The industry has more approved permits for production on federal lands than they can possibly use.&nbsp; That’s a fact.</p>



<p>My administration also directed the sale of gasoline using homegrown biofuels &#8212; ethanol, E15 &#8212; this summer, which will boost gasoline supplies and lower the price at thousands of gas stations across America.</p>



<p>And I welcome the recent announcement from what’s known as the OPEC+, a group of nearly two dozen oil-producing nations, to increase global oil supply.</p>



<p>The bottom line is: We are setting records in terms of American energy production.&nbsp; We’re supplementing that supply with a release from our oil reserves.&nbsp; So the issue isn’t oil production alone; the problem is the refining of that oil into gas at the pump.</p>



<p>During the pandemic, some oil and gas companies shut down refining facilities.</p>



<p>Last week, I sent a letter to the CEOs of the largest oil-refining companies asking them to work with my administration to bring refineries back online to get more gas to the pump at lower prices.</p>



<p>The Secretary of Energy, Jennifer Granholm, and members of my team will be meeting with many of these refining companies tomorrow.&nbsp; And I hope they’ll come up to the table with some real ideas and practical steps in the near term.</p>



<p>And I’m prepared to act quickly and decisively on their recommendations if they make sense to address the immediate challenge in front of us and the American people.</p>



<p>Finally, when the cost of oil does come down, we need the price at the gas stations &#8212; that they &#8212; what they charge at the pump &#8212; to come down as well.</p>



<p>For example, in the last two weeks, the price of oil has fallen by more than $10.00 a barrel.&nbsp; Normally, this would reduce the cost at the pump about 25 cents a gallon.&nbsp; Yet, so far, gas stations have only reduced prices by a few cents a gallon.&nbsp; Some haven’t reduced prices at all.</p>



<p>I’ve heard plenty of explanations from companies and economists about why it normally takes time for these price reductions to reach the consumer.&nbsp; I might note that when the price of a barrel of oil goes up, it doesn&#8217;t make &#8212; ta- &#8212; take much time for the price at the pump to go up.</p>



<p>So, let&#8217;s be honest with one another.&nbsp; My message is simple.&nbsp; To the companies running gas stations and setting those prices at the pump: This is a time of war, global peril, Ukraine.&nbsp; These are not normal times.</p>



<p>Bring down the price you are charging at the pump to reflect the cost you are paying for the product.&nbsp; Do it now.&nbsp; Do it today.&nbsp; Your customers, the American people, they need relief now.</p>



<p>So, let me summarize:&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, I’m calling for a federal gas tax holiday, state gas tax holiday <s>for</s> [or] the equivalent relief to consumers; oil companies to use their profits to increase refining capacity rather than buy back their own stock; gas stations to pass along the decree &#8212; excuse me, not the decree, but the decrease in oil prices to lower prices at the pump.</p>



<p>And together, these actions could help drop the price at the pump by up to $1.00 a gallon or more.&nbsp; It doesn’t reduce all of the pain, but it would be a big help.</p>



<p>I’m doing my part.&nbsp; I want the Congress, the states, and the industry to do their part as well.</p>



<p>And let’s remember how we got here: Putin invaded Ukraine.&nbsp; Putin invaded Ukraine with 100,000 forces.</p>



<p>Just look at the facts: Since the start of the war in Ukraine this year, gas prices have risen by almost $2.00 a gallon in the United States, and sometimes more, around the world.</p>



<p>But it wasn’t just Putin’s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; It was the refusal of the United States and the rest of the free world to let Putin get away with something we haven&#8217;t seen since World War Two.</p>



<p>I said at the time: Siding with Ukraine during the most serious aggression in Europe since World War Two &#8212; defending freedom, defending democracy &#8212; was not going to go without cost for the American people and the rest of the free world.&nbsp; We were going to have to pay a price as well &#8212; in the cost of military equipment, economic assistance, humanitarian relief.&nbsp; And sanctioned Russian banking industries.</p>



<p>Russia is also the largest oi- &#8212; one of the largest oil producers in the world.&nbsp; We cut off Russian oil into the United States, and our partners in Europe did the same, knowing that we would see higher gas prices.</p>



<p>We could have turned a blind eye to Putin’s murderous ways, and the price of gas wouldn’t have spiked the way it has.</p>



<p>I believe that would have been wrong.&nbsp; I believed it then &#8212; I believed then and I believe now: The free world had no choice.</p>



<p>America could not stand by and the West could not have stood by &#8212; although some suggested at the time &#8212; and just watch Putin’s tanks roll into Ukraine and seize a sovereign country.</p>



<p>If we did stand by, Putin wouldn’t have stopped.&nbsp; Putin would’ve kept going, and we’d face an even steeper price.</p>



<p>And it wasn’t just me.&nbsp; The American people understood.&nbsp; The American people rose to the moment.&nbsp; The American people did what they always have done: defend freedom around the world.&nbsp; They chose to stand with the people of Ukraine.</p>



<p>We had near unanimous support in the Congress &#8212; Democrats, Republicans, and independents &#8212; for supporting Ukraine, knowing full well the cost.</p>



<p>So, for all those Republicans in Congress criticizing me today for high gas prices in America, are you now saying we were wrong to support Ukraine?&nbsp; Are you saying we were wrong to stand up to Putin?&nbsp; Are you saying that we would rather have lower gas prices in America and Putin’s iron fist in Europe?&nbsp; I don’t believe that.</p>



<p>Look, I get the easy politics of the attack.&nbsp; I get that.&nbsp; But the simple truth is gas prices are up almost $2.00 a gallon because of Vladimir Putin’s ruthless attack on Ukraine, and we wouldn’t let him get away with it.&nbsp; And we’re doing everything we can to reduce this pain at the pump now.</p>



<p><br>And if those experiences has shown us anything, it’s that we need to grow and harness more energy here at home.</p>



<p>Let’s lower the price of electric vehicles so we never have to pay at the pump in the first place.<br><br>Major auto companies are preparing for 50 percent of future sales to be electric vehicles by 2030, 100 percent by 2035.&nbsp; We’re already building secure supply chains to build these electric vehicles here in America.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re investing almost $100 billion in public transit and rail, for all the studies show that it will take millions of cars off the road and significantly reduce pollution if there’s a serious transportation system available.</p>



<p>Let’s keep accelerating our deployment of homegrown resources &#8212; sources of energy like solar and wind and nuclear and hydrogen and carbon capture and storage &#8212; and keep developing battery technologies so we can store that power we need when the sun doesn’t shine or the wind doesn’t blow.</p>



<p>Folks, let’s make sure we’re never again forced to pay the price of a menacing dictator halfway around the world.</p>



<p>We can deal with the imme- &#8212; this immediate crisis of high gas prices and still seize the clean energy future.</p>



<p>We’re Americans.&nbsp; We can do both.&nbsp; We have the most qualified people in the world.</p>



<p><br>Let me close with this: Even as we lead the world in defending democracy and standing up to a brutal autocrat, there are actions we can take to help American families now.&nbsp; We have taken them.&nbsp; We are taking them.&nbsp; The federal gas tax holiday, state gas tax holiday.&nbsp; Bringing back refineries, putting them back online.</p>



<p>We just have to keep going.&nbsp; I promise you I’m doing everything possible &#8212; everything possible to bring the price of energy down, gas prices down.&nbsp; And I want to make sure we all work on this together.</p>



<p>May God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you very much.</p>



<p><br>2:16 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-22/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:  Anjali Chaturvedi, Nominee for General Counsel, U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs Patrice H. Kunesh, Nominee for Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services Kristina A. Kvien,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration: </p>



<ul><li>Anjali Chaturvedi, Nominee for General Counsel, U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs</li><li>Patrice H. Kunesh, Nominee for Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</li><li>Kristina A. Kvien, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Armenia</li><li>Robert William Forden, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Cambodia</li><li>Lucy Tamlyn, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Republic of the Congo</li><li>Randy W. Berry, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Namibia</li><li>Pamela M. Tremont, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Zimbabwe</li><li>Manuel P. Micaller, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Tajikistan</li><li>Kimberly McClain, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Congressional and Intergovernmental Relations, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Rolfe Michael Schiffer, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Asia, United States Agency for International Development</li><li>Moshe Marvit, Nominee for Member of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission</li><li>Robert E. Primus, Nominee for Member of the Surface Transportation Board</li><li>Thomas E. Harvey, Nominee for Member of the Veterans Affairs Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Anjali Chaturvedi, Nominee for General Counsel, U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs</u></strong></p>



<p>Anjali Chaturvedi is a Deputy Assistant Attorney General in the Criminal Division of the U.S. Department of Justice.&nbsp;During her career, Chaturvedi has worked in all three branches of the government and in private practice.&nbsp;Prior to returning to government service, Chaturvedi was the Assistant General Counsel and Director of Investigations for Northrop Grumman Corporation, leading the company’s global investigations team.&nbsp;She earlier served as an Assistant General Counsel at British Petroleum and as a partner at the Washington, DC law firm of Nixon Peabody. Before entering private practice, Chaturvedi was a federal prosecutor. During her time at the Justice Department, she served both in the District of Columbia and the Northern District of California US Attorneys’ Offices, including as Deputy Chief of the Felony Trial Section and Chief of the Organized Crime Strike Force, and a detail as Counsel to Senator Dianne Feinstein on the Senate Judiciary Committee. She began her legal career clerking for the Honorable Gregory E. Mize of the District of Columbia Superior Court. Chaturvedi also taught trial advocacy and criminal procedure as an Adjunct Professor at Georgetown University and Hastings College of Law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Born in Cortland, New York, Chaturvedi is a first-generation American. She is a graduate of the Georgetown University Law School and Cornell University.&nbsp;She is also a certified yoga teacher and leadership coach.&nbsp;She lives in Chevy Chase, MD with her husband and son.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Patrice H. Kunesh, Nominee for Commissioner of the Administration for Native Americans, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services</u></strong></p>



<p>Patrice H. Kunesh, of Standing Rock Lakota descent, has committed her career to public service, including several positions at the tribal, state, and federal level. Kunesh recently returned to the Native American Rights Fund, where she began her legal career. Since then, she has served as in-house Counsel to the Mashantucket Pequot Tribal Nation and on the faculty at the University of South Dakota School of Law. Kunesh also held appointments as the Deputy Under Secretary for Rural Development at the U.S. Department of Agriculture and as the Deputy Solicitor for Indian Affairs at the U.S. Department of the Interior. In addition, she established the Center for Indian Country Development, an economic policy research initiative, at the Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis.</p>



<p>Kunesh recently founded Peȟíŋ Haha Consulting, a social enterprise committed to fostering culturally-centered Native economic development, and she was appointed to the US Treasury Community Development Advisory Board (CDFI Fund) as the representative for Native communities. She holds a JD from the University of Colorado School of Law and an MPA from the Harvard Kennedy School of Government.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kristina A. Kvien, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Armenia</u></strong></p>



<p>Kristina A. Kvien, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, serves as Deputy Chief of Mission at U.S. Embassy Kyiv. She was previously Chargé d’Affaires ad interim from 2020-2022.&nbsp;Prior to that, Kvien served as Minister-Counselor for Economic Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in Paris, France and as Economic Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in Bangkok, Thailand.&nbsp;In both Paris and Bangkok, she served more than one year as Acting Deputy Chief of Mission.&nbsp;She also served as Economic Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in London.&nbsp;Earlier in her career, Kvien was detailed to the National Security Council in Washington, D.C. as Director for EU, Ukraine and Belarus affairs.&nbsp;Other overseas assignments include the U.S. Embassy in Moscow, Russia; the U.S. Mission to the EU in Brussels; and the U.S. Embassy in Manila, Republic of the Philippines.&nbsp;Domestic assignments include the Office of European and Regional Affairs, and the Office of Central European Affairs, both in the Bureau of Europe and Eurasian Affairs.&nbsp;Kvien, a native of California, holds a BA from Occidental College and an MS from the U.S. Army War College.&nbsp;She is a recipient of multiple State Department performance awards and speaks Russian and French.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Robert William Forden, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Cambodia</u></strong></p>



<p>Robert Forden is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor.&nbsp;He currently serves as a Senior Advisor in the East Asian and Pacific Affairs Bureau at the Department of State in Washington, D.C.&nbsp;Prior to that, he was the Deputy Chief of Mission and also Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim of the U.S. Embassy in the People’s Republic of China.&nbsp;Earlier, Forden was the Deputy Director of the American Institute in Taiwan and before that the Economic Counselor of the U.S. Embassy in Tel Aviv, Israel.&nbsp;He was also Deputy Economic Counselor of the U.S. Embassy in Beijing and, in Washington, the Deputy Director of the Office of Chinese and Mongolian Affairs in the State Department’s Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs.&nbsp;Among his other assignments, Forden was Chief of the Kaohsiung Branch of the American Institute in Taiwan and an Economic Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Hanoi, Vietnam.&nbsp;Forden earned his Bachelor’s degree from the University of California, Santa Cruz.&nbsp;He speaks Chinese (Mandarin) and Vietnamese.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lucy Tamlyn, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Democratic Republic of the Congo</u></strong></p>



<p>Lucy Tamlyn, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is currently the Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim at the U.S. Embassy in Khartoum, Sudan.&nbsp;Previously, she served as U.S. Ambassador to the Central African Republic, U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Benin, and as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassies in Portugal and in Chad.&nbsp;Earlier she had assignments as Economic Counselor at the U.S. Mission to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, as a Provincial Reconstruction Team Leader in Erbil, Iraq, and as Director of the Office of the Special Envoy for Sudan and South Sudan in the State Department’s Bureau of African Affairs. Among other postings during her four decades of diplomatic service, Tamlyn has worked as Alternate Permanent Representative, Deputy Director, Economic and Social Council Section at the U.S. Mission to the UN, New York and as Alternate Permanent Representative, U.S. Mission to the UN Agencies for Food and Agriculture in Rome, Italy. She earned a Bachelor’s degree from St. John’s College, Annapolis, Maryland and a Master’s degree from Columbia University School of International Affairs. Tamlyn is the recipient of numerous State Department awards, including the Secretary’s Award for Expeditionary Service. She speaks French and Portuguese.</p>



<p><strong><u>Randy W. Berry, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Namibia</u></strong></p>



<p>Randy Berry is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Career Minister.&nbsp;He currently serves as the U.S. Ambassador to Nepal. Prior to that, Berry was Deputy Assistant Secretary in the State Department’s Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights and Labor and, before that, the State Department’s first Special Envoy for the Human Rights of LGBTI Persons. Berry served as Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy, Kathmandu, and was twice a Principal Officer and Consul General &#8212; first at the U.S. Consulate General in Auckland, New Zealand and then at the U.S. Consulate General in&nbsp;Amsterdam, The Netherlands.&nbsp;His other assignments include service as Deputy Principal Officer, U.S. Consulate General, Cape Town, South Africa; Senior Desk Officer for South Africa, Bureau of African Affairs, Department of State; and as Political Section Chief, and then Regional Refugee Coordinator at the U.S. Embassy in Kampala, Uganda. Early in his career Berry was Vice Consul at the U.S. Embassy in Dhaka, Bangladesh, and then at the U.S. Embassy in Cairo, Egypt. Berry earned his B.A. from Bethany College, Lindsborg, Kansas.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Pamela M. Tremont, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Zimbabwe</u></strong></p>



<p>Pamela Tremont is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor. She currently is assigned as the Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Stockholm, Sweden and had the additional responsibility of serving as Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim for 18 months. Previously, Tremont was assigned first as Assistance Coordinator and then as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Kyiv, Ukraine.&nbsp;Prior to that, she served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Nicosia, Cyprus.&nbsp;Among her other roles, Tremont has been Deputy Director for NATO Policy in the Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs at the State Department, the Political/Economic Counselor at the U.S. Embassy in Lusaka, Zambia, and a Political Military Officer in the U.S. Embassy in London, United Kingdom. Tremont also served as Political Military Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Ankara, Turkey, as a Desk Officer for South Africa in the Bureau of African Affairs, and as a Watch Officer in the State Department’s Operations Center. Tremont earned B.A. and M.A. degrees from Baylor University and a Master’s degree from the Dwight D. Eisenhower School at the National Defense University.&nbsp;She speaks French and Turkish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Manuel P. Micaller, Jr., Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Tajikistan</u></strong></p>



<p>Manuel P. Micaller, Jr. is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor.&nbsp;He currently serves as the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Kathmandu, Nepal.&nbsp;Prior to that, Micaller was Deputy Chief of Mission (and Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim) at the U.S. Embassy in Ulaanbaatar, Mongolia.&nbsp;Micaller also served as the Deputy Director of the Office of India Affairs in the State Department’s Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs in Washington, D.C and held assignments as the Political – Economic Section Chief at the U.S. Embassy in Dushanbe, Tajikistan and as an Economic Officer in the South and Central Asian Affairs Bureau’s Office of Regional Affairs.&nbsp;Earlier, Micaller was an Economic Officer at the U.S. Embassy in Rabat, Morocco, worked in the State Department Executive Secretariat and Operations Center, and was posted to positions in Russia and Tajikistan.&nbsp;Micaller earned his Bachelor’s degree from The Johns Hopkins University and his Master’s in Business Administration from George Washington University.&nbsp;He also received a Master’s degree from the National Defense University.&nbsp;His foreign languages include Russian and Tajik.</p>



<p><strong><u>Kimberly McClain, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Congressional and Intergovernmental Relations, U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Kimberly McClain currently serves in the Biden-Harris Administration as the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Congressional and Legislative Affairs at the Department of Veterans Affairs. In this position she advises the Secretary, Deputy Secretary, Under Secretaries and Assistant Secretaries on matters involving congressional and legislative affairs. Throughout her 30-year career, McClain has served in a variety of legislative affairs, international affairs, and policy positions in the public and private sectors. Prior to being appointed to the Biden-Harris Administration, McClain served as Director for Congressional Strategy for the Department of the Air Force, where she led teams charged with planning, execution, and management of the Department’s congressional engagement strategy. Her public service career includes several legislative roles in the Air Force, including Legislative Advisor to the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, and also several roles in the Department of Defense, including serving as Director of the Defense Senior Leader Program in the Office of the Undersecretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness.</p>



<p>In the private sector, McClain served as Senior Executive Communications Advisor to the Chief Executive Officer for Accenture Federal Services and its clients. She also served for two years as a Corporate Training and Development Executive for Sonic Restaurant Industries and as Risk Operations Manager for Capital One Financial Services. A retired Air Force Reserve Officer, McClain earned her Bachelor of Arts in Psychology and a minor in Sociology from the University of Texas. McClain also earned a Master of Science in Human Relations and International Business with Latin America concentration from Amberton University and a Ph.D. in International Business with a concentration in Africa and Brazil from Northcentral University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Rolfe Michael Schiffer, Nominee for Assistant Administrator for Asia, United States Agency for International Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Rolfe Michael Schiffer is Senior Advisor and Counselor on the Democratic Staff of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee. He formerly served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of Defense for East Asia in the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Asian and Pacific Security Affairs. Before joining the Department of Defense, he was a Program Officer at the Stanley Foundation, responsible for the Foundation`s Asia programs as well as a range of other U.S. national and global security issues and also was a Council on Foreign Relations Hitachi International Affairs Fellow in Japan. Prior to that, worked on the staff of U.S. Senator Dianne Feinstein (D-CA), including as her Senior National Security Adviser and Legislative Director. Prior to that, he was Director of International Security Programs at New York University`s Center for War, Peace, and the News Media, and Co-Manager of the Poipu Bed and Breakfast Inn in Kauai. Schiffer received his undergraduate degree from Georgetown University and graduate degrees from the London School of Economics and New York University.</p>



<p><strong><u>Moshe Z. Marvit, Nominee for Member of the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Moshe Z. Marvit has worked for the last decade with the Federal Mine Safety and Health Review Commission (FMSHRC), where he currently serves as a Supervisory Attorney Advisor. In this capacity, he manages the Pittsburgh field office, writes decisions for federal Administrative Law Judges, and mediates cases between mine operators and the Mine Safety and Health Administration. He is also a fellow at The Century Foundation, where he researches and writes on workers’ rights issues. His writings have been published widely in a variety of law reviews. He has been awarded the Labor and Employment Relations Association Ken May Media Award and the Sidney Hillman Award for his writings in the field of workers’ rights. Prior to coming to FMSHRC, he worked in private practice, representing the United Steelworkers, and employees in pension and discrimination matters.</p>



<p>Marvit has served as a member of the faculty of the University of Pittsburgh School of Law, the Duquesne University School of Law, the Pennsylvania State Unemployment Compensation Advisory Council, and the Steel Valley Authority. He received his JD from Chicago-Kent College of Law, where he also earned a Certificate in Labor and Employment Law. Marvit served on the Employee Rights and Employment Policy Journal, and received a Peggy Browning Fellowship to work at the National Labor Relations Board. He has an M.A. from the University of Chicago, an M.A. from Carnegie Mellon University and a B.A. from the Pennsylvania State University. He lives in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania with his wife and son.</p>



<p><strong><u>Robert E. Primus, Nominee for Member of the Surface Transportation Board</u></strong></p>



<p>Robert E. Primus is a Member of the Surface Transportation Board. Primus previously served in the office of Congressman Tony Cárdenas (D-CA), first as his Senior Advisor and then as Chief of Staff. Prior to this, Primus served as Senior Advisor to Congressman Tim Ryan (D-OH) and Chief of Staff to Representative Nanette Diaz Barragán (D-CA). Primus formerly served in the Office of Representative Michael Capuano (D-MA), first as Legislative Director and then as Chief of Staff. In addition to his Chief of Staff duties, Primus advised Representative Capuano on national security, health care, transportation and Coast Guard-related matters. Primus spent four years at Van Scoyoc Associates, Inc. where he represented and advised firm clients on budgetary, appropriations, transportation, and national security matters. Primus also served on the staffs of Representative Mel Reynolds (D-IL), Representative Carrie Meek of (D-FL), and Senator Frank Lautenberg (D-NJ).</p>



<p>Primus is a native of Madison, New Jersey.&nbsp;He graduated with honors from Hampton University in 1991, receiving a Bachelor of Science degree in Marketing.&nbsp;Additionally, Primus received a certificate from Harvard University’s John F. Kennedy School of Government in 2007 for his participation in the school’s Executive Education Program.&nbsp;He is married and has three children.</p>



<p><strong><u>Thomas E. Harvey, Nominee for Member of the Veterans Affairs Asset and Infrastructure Review Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Tom Harvey, an Army veteran who served two and a half years in the Infantry in Vietnam, is the recipient of the Silver Star, Purple Heart and a dozen other decorations for valor and service. He arrived in Washington, DC in 1977 as a White House Fellow and spent much of his career in positions caring for his fellow veterans. He served as Chief Counsel and Staff Director of the U.S. Senate Veterans Affairs Committee on two different occasions, Deputy Administrator of the Veterans Administration, and Assistant Secretary of the Department of Veterans Affairs for Congressional Relations. He also held a number of senior positions within the Department of Defense and the United States Information Agency. Harvey is married with two grown children. He resides in Palm Beach, Florida.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of the June National Climate Task Force&#160;Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/readout-of-the-june-national-climate-task-force-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 18:40:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56071</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Task Force Discussed Tackling Extreme Heat, Bolstering Resilience, and Lowering Energy Costs Yesterday, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the 12th meeting of the National Climate Task Force to discuss President Biden’s commitment to protecting the most vulnerable Americans from extreme heat, strengthening the nation’s resilience to extreme weather events, and lowering energy costs for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Task Force Discussed Tackling Extreme Heat, Bolstering Resilience, and Lowering Energy Costs</em></p>



<p>Yesterday, National Climate Advisor Gina McCarthy convened the 12<sup>th</sup> meeting of the National Climate Task Force to discuss President Biden’s commitment to protecting the most vulnerable Americans from extreme heat, strengthening the nation’s resilience to extreme weather events, and lowering energy costs for families.</p>



<p>The Task Force received a science briefing on this summer’s forecasted extreme heat, drought and wildfires in the West and flood risk across the East. The Task Force discussed how these climate and weather extremes disproportionately impact historically disadvantaged communities across America, and how the Task Force is taking action to fight back by weatherizing homes; updating building codes to boost resilience; setting flood-risk reduction standards to protect homeowners and businesses; shielding workers from extreme heat exposure on the job; increasing federal firefighters pay across the country to fight wildfires; and accelerating construction of grid-strengthening clean energy projects that will cut consumer costs.</p>



<p>In addition, the Task Force discussed efforts to leverage domestic climate action to spur international efforts, including recent successes advanced through the President’s action-focused <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/17/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-galvanize-global-action-to-strengthen-energy-security-and-tackle-the-climate-crisis-through-the-major-economies-forum-on-energy-and-climate/">call to world leaders</a> at last week’s Major Economies Forum on Energy and Climate.</p>



<p>As outlined by President Biden’s January 27&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/executive-order-on-tackling-the-climate-crisis-at-home-and-abroad/">Executive Order on Tackling the Climate Crisis at Home and Abroad</a>, the Task Force is chaired by the National Climate Advisor and includes Cabinet-level leaders from more than 25 federal agencies to mobilize the Biden-Harris Administration’s implementation of a whole-of-government approach.</p>



<p>Task Force membership is comprised of the following government officials:</p>



<ul><li>National Climate Advisor (Chair)</li><li>Secretary of the Treasury</li><li>Secretary of Defense</li><li>Attorney General</li><li>Secretary of the Interior</li><li>Secretary of Agriculture</li><li>Secretary of Commerce</li><li>Secretary of Education</li><li>Secretary of Labor</li><li>Secretary of Health and Human Services</li><li>Secretary of Housing and Urban Development</li><li>Secretary of Transportation</li><li>Secretary of Energy</li><li>Secretary of Homeland Security</li><li>Administrator of General Services</li><li>CEO of AmeriCorps</li><li>Chair of the Council on Environmental Quality</li><li>Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency</li><li>Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration</li><li>Administrator of the Small Business Administration</li><li>Director of the Office of Management and Budget</li><li>Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy</li><li>Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs</li><li>Assistant to the President for Homeland Security and Counterterrorism</li><li>Assistant to the President for Economic Policy</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on the Earthquake in&#160;Afghanistan</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-the-earthquake-in-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 16:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56066</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is deeply saddened to see the devastating earthquake that took the lives of at least 1,000 people in Afghanistan. President Biden is monitoring developments and has directed USAID and other federal government partners to assess U.S. response options to help those most affected. The United States is proud to be the single largest&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States is deeply saddened to see the devastating earthquake that took the lives of at least 1,000 people in Afghanistan. President Biden is monitoring developments and has directed USAID and other federal government partners to assess U.S. response options to help those most affected. The United States is proud to be the single largest donor of humanitarian aid to Afghanistan, and our humanitarian partners are already delivering medical care and shelter supplies on the ground. We are committed to continuing our support for the needs of the Afghan people as we stand with them during and in the aftermath of this terrible tragedy.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Tenth Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/22/president-biden-announces-tenth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 15:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56056</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden Administration will facilitate trucking shipment of approximately 16 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Gerber® Good Start® Gentle infant formula this weekend Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing trucking, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Gerber infant formula from Mexico&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden Administration will facilitate trucking shipment of approximately 16 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Gerber® Good Start® Gentle infant formula this weekend</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration is sourcing trucking, facilitated by the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), for Operation Fly Formula to transport Gerber infant formula from Mexico to Fort Worth, Texas starting on June 24. This delivery will include approximately 1 million pounds of Gerber Good Start Gentle infant formula, the equivalent of approximately 16 million 8-ounce bottles. The product will be available through retail channels.</p>



<p>In May, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) announced that the agency is exercising enforcement discretion so that Nestlé can export additional infant formula into the U.S. &nbsp; Nestlé plans to export approximately 42 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents into the U.S. market.</p>



<p>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the import of infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards, so it can get to store shelves faster. By June 26, Operation Fly Formula flights will have completed 32 flights and imported almost 19 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of infant formula.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA and Abbott Nutrition to reopen the company’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market. Details of our actions can be found at whitehouse.gov/formula.</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-full is-resized"><img src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png" alt="" class="wp-image-56061" width="298" height="298" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png 596w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png?resize=150,150 150w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png?resize=300,300 300w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png?resize=600,600 600w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/OFF10.png?resize=1200,1200 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 298px) 100vw, 298px" /></figure></div>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
