<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 09:32:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/fact-sheet-national-strategy-for-countering-domestic-terrorism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20851</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On his first full day in office, President Biden directed his national security team to lead a 100-day comprehensive review of U.S. Government efforts to address domestic terrorism, which has evolved into the most urgent terrorism threat the United States faces today. As a result of that review, the Biden Administration is releasing the first-ever&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On his first full day in office, President Biden directed his national security team to lead a 100-day comprehensive review of U.S. Government efforts to address domestic terrorism, which has evolved into the most urgent terrorism threat the United States faces today. As a result of that review, the Biden Administration is releasing the first-ever <strong>National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism</strong> to address this challenge to America’s national security and improve the federal government’s response.</p>



<p>Domestic terrorism is not a new threat in the United States, yet it is a threat Americans have endured too often in recent years. The comprehensive strategy provides a nationwide framework for the U.S. Government and partners to understand and share domestic terrorism related information; prevent domestic terrorism recruitment and mobilization to violence; disrupt and deter domestic terrorism activity; and confront long term contributors to domestic terrorism. Our approach will protect both the nation and the civil liberties of its citizens.</p>



<p>Under Federal law, “<strong>domestic terrorism</strong>” is defined as “activities that involve acts dangerous to human life that are a violation of the criminal laws of the United States or of any State; appear to be intended to intimidate or coerce a civilian population, to influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion, or to affect the conduct of a government by mass destruction, assassination, or kidnapping; and occur primarily within the territorial jurisdiction of the United States.”</p>



<p>The review was <strong>rooted in an expert assessment of the domestic terrorism threat</strong> provided by the intelligence and law enforcement communities. An unclassified summary of that assessment was released in March so the public could see the key findings. It found that the two most lethal elements of today’s domestic terrorism threat are (1) racially or ethnically motivated violent extremists who advocate for the superiority of the white race and (2) anti-government or anti-authority violent extremists, such as militia violent extremists.</p>



<p>To develop a government-wide strategy to counter domestic terrorists, the Biden Administration consulted extensively with a wide array of experts across the U.S. Government as well as with leaders in Congress, state and local governments, academia, civil society, religious communities, and foreign governments. Throughout the process, <strong>we embraced the protection of civil rights and civil liberties as a national security imperative</strong>. The strategy we are releasing today is carefully tailored to address violence and reduce the factors that lead to violence, threaten public safety, and infringe on the free expression of ideas. It is organized around four pillars – the core elements of how the Biden Administration will improve the U.S. Government’s response to this persistent, evolving, and lethal threat to our people, our democracy, and our national security:</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">PILLAR 1: UNDERSTAND AND SHARE DOMESTIC TERRORISM-RELATED INFORMATION</span></p>



<p><strong>The U.S. Government will enhance domestic terrorism analysis and improve information sharing throughout law enforcement </strong>at the federal, state, local, tribal, and territorial levels, and, where appropriate, private sector partners. The Department of Justice (DOJ) and Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) have implemented a robust system to methodically track domestic terrorism cases nationwide. The Department of State as well as the intelligence and law enforcement communities are learning more from foreign partners about the international dimensions of this threat.</p>



<p><br>The Department of State will continue to <strong>assess whether additional foreign entities linked to domestic terrorism can be designated </strong>as Foreign Terrorist Organizations or Specially Designated Global Terrorists under relevant statutory criteria. The Department of the Treasury, in coordination with law enforcement, is exploring ways to enhance the identification and analysis of financial activity of domestic terrorists. The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) is enhancing its analysis of open-source information to identify threats earlier and will create a structured mechanism for receiving and sharing within government credible non-governmental analysis.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">PILLAR 2: PREVENT DOMESTIC TERRORISM RECRUITMENT AND MOBILIZATION TO VIOLENCE</span></p>



<p>Drawing on the expertise of a variety of departments and agencies,<strong> the U.S. Government has revamped support to community partners who can help to prevent individuals from ever reaching the point of committing terrorist violence</strong>. The U.S. Government will<strong> strengthen domestic terrorism prevention resources</strong><strong>and services</strong>. For the first time, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) has designated “Domestic Violent Extremism” as a National Priority Area within the Department’s Homeland Security Grant Program, which means that over $77 million will be allocated to state, local, tribal, and territorial partners to prevent, protect against, and respond to domestic violent extremism. DHS and FBI are working to strengthen local prevention, threat assessment, and threat management frameworks. The Department of Defense (DOD) is incorporating training for servicemembers separating or retiring from the military on potential targeting of those with military training by violent extremist actors. The U.S. Government will <strong>improve public awareness</strong> of federal resources to address concerning or threatening behavior before violence occurs.</p>



<p>The U.S. Government will augment its efforts to <strong>address online terrorist recruitment and mobilization to violence by domestic terrorists</strong> through increased information sharing with the technology sector and the creation of innovative ways to foster digital literacy and build resilience to recruitment and mobilization. <strong>The United States also recently joined the <em>Christchurch Call to Action to Eliminate Terrorist and Violent Extremist Content Online</em></strong>, an international partnership between governments and technology companies that works to develop new multilateral solutions to eliminating terrorist content online while safeguarding the freedom of online expression.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">PILLAR 3: DISRUPT AND DETER DOMESTIC TERRORISM ACTIVITY</span></p>



<p>The work of Federal law enforcement as well as our state, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement partners is critical to countering domestic terrorism. The U.S. Government will increase<strong> support to Federal, state, and local law enforcement in addressing domestic terrorism nationwide</strong>. U.S. Attorney’s Offices and FBI field offices across the country have formally made domestic terrorism a top priority and are tracking comprehensively domestic terrorism-related cases, reallocating or requesting appropriate funding and resources as needed to target the threat. That includes over $100 million in additional resources for DOJ, FBI, and DHS included in the President’s Fiscal Year 2022 Budget to ensure that the Federal Government has the analysts, investigators, prosecutors, and other personnel and resources it needs to thwart domestic terrorism and do justice when the law has been broken. State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement will have access to increased intelligence sharing and training on domestic terrorism and associated threats. <strong>DOJ is closely examining whether new legislative authorities that balance safety and the protection of civil liberties are necessary and appropriate.<br><br></strong>The U.S. Government is improving employee screening to enhance methods for <strong>identifying domestic terrorists who might pose insider threats</strong>. The Office of Personnel Management will consider updates to the forms used to apply for sensitive roles in the Federal Government that could assist investigators in identifying potential domestic terrorism threats. DOD, DOJ, and DHS are similarly pursuing efforts to <strong>ensure domestic terrorists are not employed</strong> within our military or law enforcement ranks and improve screening and vetting processes. Training and resources will be developed for state, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement partners as well as sensitive private sector partners to enable them to enhance their own employee screening programs and prevent individuals who pose domestic terrorism threats from being placed in positions of trust.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">PILLAR 4: CONFRONT LONG-TERM CONTRIBUTORS TO DOMESTIC TERRORISM</span></p>



<p><strong>Every component of the government has a role to play in rooting out racism and bigotry</strong> and advancing equity for all Americans. The U.S. Government, in close partnership with civil society, will <strong>address the long-term contributors that are responsible for much of today’s domestic terrorism.</strong> This includes reducing and protecting Americans from racial, ethnic, and religious hatred, and stemming the flow of firearms to individuals intending to commit acts of domestic terrorism. <strong>We will work to ensure that law enforcement operates without bias</strong> in countering domestic terrorism and provides for the public safety of all Americans. In a true democracy, <strong>violence cannot be an acceptable mode of seeking political or social change</strong>.</p>



<p>The U.S. Government is committed to <strong>strengthening trust in</strong> American democracy and its ability to deliver for the American people, including through relief and opportunity provided by the American Rescue Plan, the American Jobs Plan and the American Families Plan. The U.S. Government will also work to find ways to <strong>counter the polarization often fueled by disinformation, misinformation, and dangerous conspiracy theories online</strong>, supporting an information environment that fosters healthy democratic discourse.</p>



<p>In implementing this strategy, and at the direction of President Biden, we will remain focused on addressing violence and reducing the threat of violence while vigilantly safeguarding peaceful expression of a wide range of views and freedom of political association.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on the National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-the-national-strategy-for-countering-domestic-terrorism/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20843</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Domestic terrorism – driven by hate, bigotry, and other forms of extremism— is a stain on the soul of America. &#160;It goes against everything our country strives for and it poses a direct challenge to our national security, democracy, and unity. To meet this serious and growing threat, on my first day in office I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Domestic terrorism – driven by hate, bigotry, and other forms of extremism— is a stain on the soul of America. &nbsp;It goes against everything our country strives for and it poses a direct challenge to our national security, democracy, and unity.<br><br>To meet this serious and growing threat, on my first day in office I directed my national security team to confront the rise in domestic terrorism with the necessary resources and resolve.&nbsp; Today, I am releasing the first-ever National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism.&nbsp; It lays out a comprehensive approach to protecting our nation from domestic terrorism while safeguarding our bedrock civil rights and civil liberties – values that make us who we are as Americans. &nbsp;We have to take both short-term steps to counter the very real threats of today and longer-term measures to diminish the drivers that will contribute to this ongoing challenge to our democracy.<br><br>This is a project that should unite all Americans.&nbsp; Together we must affirm that domestic terrorism has no place in our society.&nbsp; We must work to root out the hatreds that can too often drive violence.&nbsp; And we must recommit to defending and protecting our basic freedoms, which belong to all Americans in equal measure, and which are not only the foundation of our democracy – they are our enduring advantage in the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing the U.S.-EU Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/15/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-the-u-s-eu-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20879</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (June 14, 2021) 3:08 P.M. CEST MODERATOR: Good afternoon, everyone. Thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing previewing tomorrow&#8217;s U.S.-EU Summit. This call will be on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; embargoed until 7:00 a.m. Central European Summer Time tomorrow. By joining this call, you are agreeing to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>(June 14, 2021)</p>



<p>3:08 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>MODERATOR: Good afternoon, everyone. Thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing previewing tomorrow&#8217;s U.S.-EU Summit. This call will be on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; embargoed until 7:00 a.m. Central European Summer Time tomorrow.</p>



<p>By joining this call, you are agreeing to these ground rules. Not for reporting or attribution, but just for your knowledge, on today&#8217;s call, we will have joining us [senior administration official].</p>



<p>Before we dive into the embargoed session of the preview of the U.S.-EU Summit, our speaker is going to also provide a brief, unembargoed, on-background update of some of President Biden&#8217;s engagements today at NATO, including the President&#8217;s meeting with Baltic leaders. So, I&#8217;ll turn it over to him to kick us off on that. [Senior administration official], go ahead.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thanks, everybody, for joining the call. And greetings from NATO headquarters, where I&#8217;ve just stepped out of the session of the leaders here at the summit that is currently ongoing.</p>



<p>President Biden has delivered his remarks a short while ago, and other leaders are now speaking. On the margins of the NATO Summit, he had the opportunity to meet with the leaders of the three Baltic countries: Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania. And he got the chance to discuss with them and coordinate with them in advance of his meeting with Putin on Wednesday to talk about the threat that Russia poses to NATO&#8217;s eastern flank, to talk about common commitment to Article 5 and collective defense, to coordinate on the resilience of those states in the face of multiple dimensions of the threat posed by Russia &#8212; from cyber, to provocative military exercises on their borders, to information warfare.</p>



<p>He was able to communicate to them what he has communicated publicly, which is that the United States seeks a stable and constructive relationship with Russia, but also will respond in the face of Russia&#8217;s harmful activities and will always stand up for NATO Allies.</p>



<p>They also discussed the emerging security challenge posed by China, including in the domain of technology. And he thanked the three leaders for the steps that they have taken to support a trusted 5G platform &#8212; to not accept Huawei within their systems.</p>



<p>They also had the opportunity to confer on Belarus and, in particular, the recent egregious air piracy that occurred with respect to a flight that was actually bound for Vilnius, Lithuania. And they had the opportunity to talk more broadly about and an affirmative agenda around emerging technologies and innovation.</p>



<p>It was a constructive, warm, vigorous engagement between him and the three leaders, and a real symbol of solidarity and unity with NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.</p>



<p>In that vein, he also had the opportunity to do a brief meeting with the Presidents of Poland and Romania, who are the co-chairs of the Bucharest Nine, the same group of eastern flank Allies that he engaged with at their virtual summit a few weeks ago. He was able to speak with the two of them about his commitment to (inaudible) security; his commitment, again, to stand up in the face of the threat posed by Russia; and to let them know his intentions for the summit in Geneva on Wednesday.</p>



<p>He had a separate encounter &#8212; an engagement with President Duda of Poland, where they got to go a little bit deeper into the questions of America&#8217;s security and military cooperation and engagement with Poland and the United States&#8217; strong support for the defense of Poland and our common collective commitment to NATO.</p>



<p>He had the chance to talk to a number of other leaders as well, just very briefly &#8212; from the Prime Minister of Spain to the Prime Minister of the Netherlands &#8212; on a range of different issues &#8212; and, of course, to see his colleagues who have just come with him from Cornwall and the G7 &#8212; President Macron, Chancellor Merkel, Prime Minister Draghi, Prime Minister Johnson.</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s on that. And now, I will now switch to previewing tomorrow and the U.S.-EU Summit.</p>



<p>MODERATOR: And this preview is embargoed until 7:00 a.m. tomorrow &#8212; again, as a reminder to everyone. Go ahead.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: So, the U.S.-EU Summit is an opportunity for President Biden to meet with President Ursula von der Leyen and President Charles Michel to cover a broad-ranging agenda facing the United States and the European Union, from climate, to health, to foreign policy challenges, to the global economy.</p>



<p>One of the most significant outcomes of this meeting and a very important initiative that will serve as a platform for U.S.-EU cooperation in the years ahead will be the launch of a Trade and Technology Council.</p>



<p>The notion here is that the United States and Europe laid the foundation for the world economy after World War Two and now have to work together to write the rules of the road for the next generation, particularly in the areas of economics and emerging technologies.</p>



<p>The Trade and Technology Council will cover a number of significant areas of priority for both the United States and the European Union, from coordinating on standards for new technologies like artificial intelligence, quantum computing, biotechnology; to coordinating on supply chain resilience; to coordinating on import &#8212; or investment screening and export controls; to coordinating on how best to reform the WTO.</p>



<p>Addressing regulations of technology platforms, competition policy, the intersection between climate and trade &#8212; all of these will also be on the agenda for a Trade and Technology Council that will be co-chaired by Secretary Blinken, Secretary Raimondo, and Ambassador Tai.</p>



<p>So this will be a joint undertaking, at the President&#8217;s direction, by the State Department, the Department of Commerce, and the U.S. Trade Representative.</p>



<p>And the basic cadence of the Trade and Technology Council will be intensive work in all of these areas, leading to regular leader-level engagement to ratify outcomes and develop a common strategy and way forward.</p>



<p>The Trade and Technology Council is fundamentally about setting out an affirmative vision to the world rooted in our shared values and our shared economic interests.</p>



<p>Of course, we also have to take account of the fact that China poses a significant challenge in both of these areas. And dealing with China&#8217;s nonmarket practices, its economic abuses, and, of course, its efforts to shape the rules of the road on technology for the 21st century will be important &#8212; an important part of the work of this council.</p>



<p>And this fits with President Biden&#8217;s fundamental strategy of managing competition with China by coordinating closely with and developing common approaches with likeminded democratic partners and allies.</p>



<p>The summit will also cover the steps that the U.S. and the EU can take together to combat COVID-19 and prepare for the next pandemic. They will address and reinforce commitments announced at the Leaders Summit on Climate for how the U.S. and the EU can work together on the climate crisis.</p>



<p>And, of course, they will discuss a number of significant foreign policy challenges, including the Iranian nuclear issue, where the EU has played an important role over the course of the past several years.</p>



<p>The President will also, tomorrow, meet with the King of Belgium and the Prime Minister, and have the opportunity to speak to them about advancing all of the priorities in the bilateral relationship between the U.S. and Belgium.</p>



<p>Let me pause there for the moment, and I&#8217;d be happy to answer any of your questions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR: Thanks again, everyone. Everybody, by now, I&#8217;m sure, is quite familiar: Use this &#8220;raise hand&#8221; function on Zoom. Raise your hand, and we&#8217;ll try to get through a few questions before [senior administration official] has to run. So again, please use the &#8220;raise hand&#8221; function.</p>



<p>All right, why don&#8217;t we start with Franco Ordoñez with NPR.</p>



<p>Q Hey, sorry about that. I wanted to ask about &#8212; two questions, if I can. One, if you can give an update on discussions about steel and aluminum tariffs. What&#8217;s the status of those? Second question (inaudible): Do you expect that China will be mentioned in those &#8212; the joint statements, communiqués coming out of NATO and the EU? And how do you anticipate that will play back in the States in, you know, kind of making foreign policy work for domestic &#8212; you know, foreign policy being domestic policy for middle America. Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: I&#8217;m sorry. Your first question, I couldn’t hear what you were asking. It cut out briefly. You were asking about the status of what?</p>



<p>Q So, I was hoping for an update on the President&#8217;s discussions or your &#8212; the administration&#8217;s discussions with Allies about steel and aluminum tariffs.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Oh, steel and &#8212; okay. Okay.</p>



<p>Q What&#8217;s the &#8212; what&#8217;s the status of those &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah.</p>



<p>Q &#8212; and what progress you made?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: So, as you know, on the 232 tariffs, there was a determination made by the European Union not to raise tariffs as they had previously intended to do, to hold on for six months to provide time for the two sides to work together on the fundamental issue of overcapacity, and to come up with a common way forward to deal with what is &#8212; what is a challenge from China of dumping, subsidization, and overcapacity.</p>



<p>And so those negotiations and discussions are ongoing. They&#8217;ve been very constructive. They will take some time. So, I don&#8217;t anticipate that you&#8217;ll see an outcome this week on the 232 tariffs, but the direction of travel is positive, and we &#8212; we do believe that there is a way to resolve this that works for both the United States and the European Union.</p>



<p>In terms of the communiqués, the NATO communiqué will discuss China &#8212; that&#8217;s unusual &#8212; but (inaudible) Allies recognize that China represents a growing and evolving security challenge, as well as an economic and technology challenge to the Euro-Atlantic. And that will be reflected and spoken to in the &#8212; in the NATO communiqué.</p>



<p>Similarly, in the EU-U.S. Summit statement, China will be addressed, but I want to let the two leaders &#8212; or the three leaders &#8212; have the opportunity to consult and interact before I go further in previewing the precise outcome on China, although it certainly will be reflected &#8212; the agreement and convergence on issues related to China will be reflected in the summit outcome there.</p>



<p>And then, finally, on the foreign policy for the middle-class issue: You know, we took a huge step forward with the agreement on the global minimum tax, and the EU played a &#8212; an important role in getting there. That is &#8212; was one of the President&#8217;s biggest priorities in terms of delivering on foreign policy for the middle class.</p>



<p>And so, he will obviously consult with them on how we take the G7 commitment and bring on board the rest of the world in order to make that a full reality.</p>



<p>In other areas &#8212; from supply chain resilience, to competition policy, to how we deal with the issue of investment screening and intellectual property protection, and the nature of WTO reform so that the WTO is better protecting the rights of workers and middle-class communities in both the United States in Europe &#8212; across all of those dimensions, foreign policy for the middle class will be front and center in &#8212; in his dialogue with European Union leaders.</p>



<p>MODERATOR: Thanks so much. Next, let&#8217;s go to Yamiche Alcindor with PBS.</p>



<p>Q Hi, thanks so much for taking my question. I have a follow-up on the foreign policy for the middle class. Can you talk about anything else that &#8212; that hasn&#8217;t been mentioned that you want to highlight specifically as it relates to foreign policy and the middle class?</p>



<p>And another question I had was: Could you talk a little bit about how all of these summits work together? I think there are a lot of Americans who kind of see these summits and maybe &#8212; maybe even get a little confused about that there&#8217;s been G7 and EU. Obviously, there are different member nations &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah.</p>



<p>Q &#8212; but I wonder how &#8212; you could talk a little bit about how they all work together.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Sure. So, the G7 &#8212; particularly in the format that came together in Cornwall, which was the G7+ &#8212; the G7 plus South Africa, India, Australia, and South Korea &#8212; reflects the world’s largest democracies from multiple continents coming together on strategic and economic issues to set out a vision for how democracies can deliver against the most significant challenges of our time, namely COVID-19 and future pandemics, climate change, economic opportunity, and economic fairness.</p>



<p>And they delivered particular, specific, tangible outcomes in each of those areas that, you know, that we spent the last three days describing &#8212; from the billion-dose commitment and the plan to end the pandemic, to the global minimum tax commitment, to the new Build Back Better World Partnership for infrastructure investment in low- and middle-income countries, to the collective commitment by the G7 to end overseas financing of coal by the end of this year.</p>



<p>So, the G7+ is really about the big global challenges and how democracies from around the world come together to solve them.</p>



<p>NATO is fundamentally about security &#8212; the security dimension of the Euro-Atlantic, the transatlantic partnership. And so, today is about issues like cyber and Russia and Afghanistan and &#8212; and the growing security challenge that China poses.</p>



<p>The U.S.-EU Summit is fundamentally about two very large economies. I mean, the European Union economy in &#8212; in total is about the size of the U.S. economy. And the fundamental decisions about that economy are made by the European Union in Brussels. And so, you got to have coordination between those two economies on a critical set of foundational issues in both trade and technology.</p>



<p>That has more of a direct negotiating element to it. The U.S. and the EU will, in fact, work out particular outcomes on particular issues, including the steel overcapacity issue I just described, including aligning export controls, including aligning climate policy.</p>



<p>And so, it has much more of a feeling of a bilateral dimension, even though the EU is comprised of more than two dozen states.</p>



<p>So, that&#8217;s how we think about the three. But they all fit together under a single banner, and that banner is: key democracies converging around a strategy for dealing both with great power competition and with solving the significant transnational challenges of our time.</p>



<p>And they each bring different vectors to doing that. But when you add up three summits, the whole &#8212; we believe &#8212; will be greater than the sum of its parts. It will be the United States rallying the world&#8217;s democracies around a tangible agenda to make real differences in the lives of the American people in terms of their health, their economic wellbeing, their physical security, and the planet that we live on.</p>



<p>In terms of other areas, with respect to foreign policy for the middle class, I’d just say maybe three or four things.</p>



<p>First, we believe that foreign policy for the middle class fundamentally comes down to the proposition that everything we do in our foreign policy should ultimately be judged by the metric of whether it is making life better, safer, and easier for families in the United States.</p>



<p>And against that metric, there&#8217;s a range of different priorities the President has been pursuing on this trip. One of them is to take the single-biggest impact on the lives and livelihoods of Americans in recent memory, which is a global pandemic, and say, “What can we put in place to make sure that does not happen again?”</p>



<p>Another has been to adjust our approach to trade so that we put the middle class at the center of it, rather than multinational corporations or making the world safe for corporate investment. And that has to do with everything from how we deal with currency policy, to tax policy, to protecting American supply chains in a way that builds manufacturing capacity and creates jobs in the United States, to protecting our intellectual property so that industries are not siphoned off and jobs are not siphoned off elsewhere.</p>



<p>So if you actually look across, particularly the G7 and the U.S.-EU Summit, you&#8217;ll see at the heart of both of those communiqués is the American middle class.</p>



<p>And we believe that what works for the American middle class also, frankly, ends up working for middle classes across Europe and around the world and that this is the most effective and sustainable way to pursue an international economic policy and a foreign policy more broadly.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll stop there.</p>



<p>MODERATOR: Thanks. It looks like [senior administration official] probably has time for one more question, so why don&#8217;t we go to Andrew Restuccia with the Wall Street Journal?</p>



<p>Q Thanks, [senior administration official], for doing this. I was hoping you could speak to the issue of Afghanistan and whether any of the NATO members raised concerns with Biden about the withdrawal. And then separately, I would just ask, broadly, on behalf of the media here, if we could get these bilats on the schedule or delivered to the press because we were unaware of several of them today, and also that we could get some access to them, which has been a pretty tradition &#8212; a tradition of both parties in the past. Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, on the second thing, you know, this was at the initiative of President Biden today that he wanted the opportunity to seek out key leaders, particularly on the eastern flank, to be sure he had the time &#8212; the opportunity to spend time with them, especially given the fact that for the key Western European countries, he&#8217;s just spent three days with them, and he wanted to maximize this opportunity to talk to the Poles, the Romanians, the (inaudible), et cetera. So, a lot of this was evolving in real time and there was not an effort to –- frankly, we would have loved to had &#8212; have more press access to them. But we’ll endeavor always to do better as we go forward.</p>



<p>In terms of Afghanistan, I listened –- I was in the room for the first hour of the summit and heard many of the significant troop-contributing countries speak and speak to the issue of Afghanistan. And each of them said that they ultimately agreed with the decision to come &#8212; to draw down this year. They understood that the time had come.</p>



<p>And the real focus in the room was not on the question of staying or going in 2021; the real focus was on how we work together as an Alliance to continue to provide support to the Afghan National Security Forces, the Afghan government, and the Afghan people.</p>



<p>And there is a considerable amount of practical work being done on that and strategic alignment on the desire to keep embassy presences, to maintain the necessary security to do that, and to work together as an alliance on everything from training &#8212; you know, particularly on over-the-horizon training; to counterterrorism and how we keep suppressing the terrorist threat in Afghanistan; to the provision of economic assistance in various forms to government.</p>



<p>So I&#8217;ve read some of the stories about this question of support or nonsupport for the drawdown from Afghanistan, and I&#8217;ve got to tell you that that is not the vibe in the room today. And, you know, it is &#8212; there is an incredible amount of warmth and unity around the entire agenda, including the &#8220;in together, out together&#8221; aspect of the Afghanistan drawdown.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thanks so much, again, everybody, for taking the time and hopping on this call. Really appreciate it.</p>



<p>Again, the contents of this call will be embargoed until 7:00 a.m. Central European Summer Time, tomorrow, on background, from a senior administration official.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ll talk to you all, again, more later today and tomorrow. Thank you.</p>



<p>3:32 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Rebuilding, Revitalizing, and Raising the Ambition of U.S.-EU Relations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/fact-sheet-rebuilding-revitalizing-and-raising-the-ambition-of-u-s-eu-relations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20827</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States and the European Union represent 780 million people who share democratic values and the largest economic relationship in the world.  Together the U.S. and EU laid the foundations of the world economy and the rules-based international order after World War II.  We share a deep commitment and investment in the multilateral system,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States and the European Union represent 780 million people who share democratic values and the largest economic relationship in the world.  Together the U.S. and EU laid the foundations of the world economy and the rules-based international order after World War II.  We share a deep commitment and investment in the multilateral system, which was built based on enduring universal values, including the strong protection of human rights, and which remains indispensable to addressing global challenges.  The U.S. and EU also wrote the rules of the road based on openness, fair competition, transparency, and accountability.  The U.S.-EU Summit will begin the work of updating those rules—to protect our health, to protect our climate, and to ensure democracy delivers and technology improves our lives.<br><br>President Biden’s participation underscores the U.S. commitment to a strong Transatlantic partnership based on shared interests and values.  The United States is committed to working with the EU to ensure global health security, stimulate global economic recovery, tackle climate change, enhance digital and trade cooperation, strengthen democracy, and address mutual foreign policy concerns. <br><br><strong>Launching the U.S-EU Trade and Technology Council:</strong>  The leaders will launch the U.S.-EU Trade and Technology Council to write the rules of the road for the economy of the 21st century. They will expand and deepen trade and investment ties, align key policies on technology and standards, launch a new initiative on biotechnology and genomics, and drive a digital transformation that boosts innovation and is based on democratic values. <br><br><strong>Fight and End the COVID-19 Pandemic and Drive a Sustainable Global Economic Recovery:</strong> The leaders will reiterate support for COVAX and commit to reforming the World Health Organization. They are also launching an expert working group to determine how best to reopen travel safely.<br><br><strong>Protect Our Planet and Foster Green Growth:</strong> The leaders will commit to leading by example in the fight against climate change, including by becoming net zero greenhouse gas economies by 2050.  They will re-affirm their commitment to the Paris Agreement, and to conserving at least 30 percent of land and sea areas by 2030. To this end, the U.S.-EU Climate Working Group will tackle climate change and environmental degradation, promote green growth, and urge ambitious action by all other major players. Additionally, the EU-US Energy Council will continue to coordinate on strategic energy issues, including decarbonization of the energy sector, energy security, and sustainable energy supply chains.<br><br><strong>Build a Stronger, More Democratic, and Peaceful World:</strong>  The leaders will commit to support democracy, uphold transparency, combat corruption, end forced labor, and protect the human rights of all people.  The U.S. will work with the EU on shared foreign policy priorities, including Belarus, China, the Eastern Mediterranean, Ethiopia, Iran, Russia, Venezuela, and the Western Balkans. They will launch U.S.-EU dialogues on Russia, on cyber issues, and migration.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden in Press Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/14/remarks-by-president-biden-in-press-conference-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 23:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20859</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATO HeadquartersBrussels, Belgium 9:28 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Before I turn to today’s meetings, I want to say a short word about our ongoing fight against COVID-19 at home. We&#8217;ve made enormous progress in the United States.  Much of the country is returning to normal, and our economic growth is leading the world,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>9:28 P.M. CEST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Before I turn to today’s meetings, I want to say a short word about our ongoing fight against COVID-19 at home.<br><br>We&#8217;ve made enormous progress in the United States.  Much of the country is returning to normal, and our economic growth is leading the world, and the number of cases and deaths are dropping dramatically.  But there&#8217;s still too many lives being lost.<br><br>We’re still averaging, in the last seven days, loss of 370 deaths per day &#8212; 370 deaths.  That’s significantly lower than at the peak of this crisis, but it’s still a real tragedy.  We’re approaching a sad milestone: almost 600,000 lost lives because of COVID-19 in America. <br><br>My heart goes out to all those who have lost a loved one.  I know that black hole that seems to consume you, that fills up your chest when you lose someone that&#8217;s close to you that you adored.<br><br>That’s why I continue to say to America: If you’ve not been vaccinated, get vaccinated.  Get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We have plenty of vaccination, plenty of sites.  We have more work to do to beat this virus, and now is not the time to let our guard down.  So, please &#8212; please get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We’ve had enough pain.  Enough pain.<br><br>Folks, I know it&#8217;s after 9:30, Brussels time &#8212; 9:30 p.m., and I&#8217;m still at NATO.  You&#8217;re all excited about that.  I know.  (Laughter.) <br><br>But I&#8217;ve had a chance to meet with several leaders recently, and I’ve had calls with others.  It&#8217;s been an incredibly productive day here. <br><br>I just finished a meeting with President Erdoğan of Turkey.  We had a positive and productive meeting, much of it one-on-one.  We had detailed discussions on how to proceed on a number of &#8212; a number of issues.  Our two countries have big agendas.  Our teams are going to continue our discussions, and I’m confident we&#8217;ll make real progress with Turkey and the United States.<br><br>But now I want to thank Secretary General Stoltenberg for leading a very successful NATO Summit today.<br><br>I had the honor of leading off the discussion today among the 30 nations, and I pointed out that we’re facing a once-in-a-century global health crisis.  At the same time, the democratic values that undergird our Alliance are under increasing pressure both internally and externally.  Russia and China are both seeking to drive a wedge in our transatlantic solidarity.  We’re seeing an increase in malicious cyber activity.<br><br>But that our Alliance is the strong foundation on which we can &#8212; our collective security and our shared prosperity can continue to be built. <br><br>And I made a point to make clear that the U.S. commitment to Article 5 of the NATO Treaty is rock solid and unshakable.  It’s a sacred commitment.<br><br>NATO &#8212; NATO stands together.  That’s how we’ve met every other threat in the past.  It’s our greatest strength as we meet our challenges of the future &#8212; and there are many. <br><br>And everyone &#8212; everyone in that room today understood the shared appreciation, quite frankly, that America is back.<br><br>We talked about Russia’s aggressive acts that pose a threat to NATO and to our collective security.<br><br>That’s why I met with the Bucharest 9 &#8212; the eastern flank allies &#8212; in advance of this summit.  And today I also met with the leaders of the three Baltic states: Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania.<br><br>I shared with our Allies that I will convey to Pre- &#8212; what I&#8217;ll convey to President Putin: that I’m not looking for conflict with Russia, but that we will respond if Russia continues its harmful activities and that we will not fail to defend the Transatlantic Alliance or stand up for democratic values.<br><br>As Allies, we also affirmed our continued support<br>for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.<br><br>We agreed to keep consulting closely on nuclear deterrence, arms control, and strategic stability.<br><br>And there was a strong consensus among the leaders in that meeting on Afghanistan.  Our troops are coming home, but we agreed that our diplomatic, economic, and humanitarian commitment to the Afghan people and our support for<br>the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces will endure.<br><br>And I welcomed our Allies and partners to recognize that counterterrorism &#8212; that counterterrorism efforts must continue to ensure that Afghanistan never again becomes a ca- &#8212; a safe haven for attacks on our countries, even as we take on terrorist networks in the Middle East and Africa.<br><br>And I’m deeply gratified that, as an Alliance, we adopted a far-reaching plan to make sure that NATO can meet the challenges<br>that we face today and in the future, not yesterday &#8212; the NATO 2030 agenda &#8212; and that we agreed to fully resource that agenda.<br><br>The last time NATO put together a strategic plan was back in 2010, when Russia was considered a partner and China wasn’t even mentioned.<br><br>We talked about the long-term systemic challenges that China’s activities pose to our collective security today.<br><br>We agreed to do more to enhance the resilience of our critical infrastructure around the world, including trusted telecommunications providers, supply chains, and energy networks.<br><br>We agreed to enhance our cooperation with our democratic partners in the Indo-Pacific to meet challenges that exist there.<br><br>We also endorsed a new cyber defense policy &#8212; NATO&#8217;s first in the past seven years &#8212; to improve the collective ability to defend against counter threats from state and nonstate actors against our networks and our critical infrastructure. <br><br>And we adopted a Climate Security Action Plan &#8212; which, several years ago, people thought we would never would do &#8212; for reducing emissions from NATO installations and adapting to the security risk of climate change while keeping a sharp &#8212; very sharp on our ability to deter and defend against threats.<br><br>And finally, we agreed that among the most important shared missions is renewing and strengthening the resilience of our democracies by pointing out we have to prove to the world and to our own people that democracy can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs of our people.<br><br>We have to root out corruption that siphons off our strength; guard against those who would stoke hatred and division for political gain &#8212; this phony populism; invest in strengthening the institutions that underpin and safeguard our cherished democratic values, as well as protecting the free press and independent judiciaries.  All of those run the agenda. <br><br>That&#8217;s how I’ll prove that democracy and that our Alliance can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs and the needs of our people.<br><br>This is going to be looked at 25 years from now as whether or not we stepped up to the challenge, because there&#8217;s a lot of &#8212; a lot of autocracies that are counting on them being able to move more rapidly and successfully in an ever-complicated world than democracies can.  We all concluded we&#8217;re going to prove them wrong. <br><br>And now I&#8217;m happy to take some questions. <br><br>Cecilia Vega of ABC.<br><br>Q    Thank you so much, sir.  Good evening.  You mentioned your sit-down with Vladimir Putin and Russian aggression that came up in your conversations today.  I&#8217;d like to ask you two questions, if I may, on that front.  Is it your sense, walking into this meeting, that Americans back home shouldn&#8217;t expect much in terms of an outcome?  Could you provide some specifics on what a successful meeting would look like to you?  Are there going to be specific concessions you want Putin to make?<br><br>And then, I&#8217;ll just give you my follow-up right now.  You&#8217;ve met Vladimir Putin before.  What have you learned about him that informs how you approach this sit-down with him?  And what&#8217;s your mindset walking into a meeting with a former KGB agent who you&#8217;ve said has no soul?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ll tell you all that when it&#8217;s over. <br><br>Look, I&#8217;ve been doing this a long time.  The last thing anyone would do is negotiate in front of the world press as to how he&#8217;s going to approach a critical meeting with another adversary and/or someone who could be an adversary.  It’s the last thing I&#8217;m going to do.<br><br>But I will tell you this: I’m going to make clear to President Putin that there are areas where we can cooperate, if he chooses.  And if he chooses not to cooperate and acts in a way that he has in the past, relative to cybersecurity and some other activities, then we will respond.  We will respond in kind. <br><br>There need not be &#8212; we should decide where it&#8217;s in our mutual interest, in the interest of the world, to cooperate, and see if we can do that.  And the areas where we don&#8217;t agree, make it clear what the red lines are.<br><br>I have met with him.  He&#8217;s bright.  He&#8217;s tough.  And I have found that he is a &#8212; as they say, when you used to play ball, “a worthy adversary.” <br><br>But the fact is that I will be happy to talk with you when it&#8217;s over, and not before, about what the discussion will entail.<br><br>Nancy Cordes, CBS.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  I also have two questions about Vladimir Putin.  The first is: Have any of the world leaders you&#8217;ve met with this week expressed concern that by meeting with President Putin this early in your presidency, that it&#8217;ll look like you&#8217;re rewarding him?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What&#8217;s your second question?<br><br>Q    The section &#8212; the second question is: What it will mean for the U.S.-Russia relationship if Aleksey Navalny were to die or be killed in prison.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Every world leader here, as a member of NATO, that spoke today &#8212; and most of them mentioned it &#8212; thanked me for meeting with Putin now.  Every single one that spoke.  And I think there were probably about 10 or 12 that spoke to it, saying they were happy that I did that and that I was going to do that.  And they thought it was thoroughly appropriate that I do, and I had discussions with them about &#8212; in the open &#8212; about what they thought was important from their perspective and what they thought was not important.<br><br>And so the interesting thing is, I know &#8212; and I’m not being critical of the press &#8212; I really mean this; I give you my word &#8212; but, generically, you all thought, “Was Biden meeting him too soon?”  I haven’t found a world leader who doesn’t think it’s not soon &#8212; it’s just soon enough.  Everyone that I’ve spoken to, privately and publicly. <br><br>It doesn’t mean there aren&#8217;t some out there, but it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not likely that a head of state is going to stand up in front of 29 other heads of state and say, “Boy, I&#8217;m glad you&#8217;re doing this,” in effect.  So there is a consensus.  And they thanked me for being willing to talk with them about the meeting and what I was &#8212; what I intended to do.<br><br>So, I haven&#8217;t found any reluctance.  There may be someone, but not in the open today or in the meetings I privately had as well.<br><br>And Navalny’s death would be another indication that Russia has little or no intention of abiding by basic fundamental human rights.  It would be a tragedy.  It would do nothing but hurt his relationships with the rest of the world, in my view, and with me. <br><br>Jeff Zeleny, CNN.<br><br>Q    Sir, good evening.  Thank you.  In a weekend interview, Vladimir Putin laughed at the suggestion that you had called him a &#8220;killer.”  Is that still your belief, sir, that he is a killer? <br><br>And I&#8217;ll continue the trend, if you don&#8217;t mind, of asking a second question.  Do you believe &#8212; if he does agree to cooperate, then what kind of a challenge do you find yourself in?  How would you ever trust him?  And if Ronald Reagan said “trust but verify,” what do you say to Vladimir Putin? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (Laughs.)  To answer the first question &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I’m laughing too.<br><br>They actually &#8212; I &#8212;<br><br>Q    So he is a killer?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, look, I mean, he has made clear that &#8212; the answer is: I believe he has, in the past, essentially acknowledged that he was &#8212; there were certain things that he would do or did do. <br><br>But look, when I was asked that question on air, I answered it honestly.  But it&#8217;s not much of a &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it matters a whole lot, in terms of this next meeting we&#8217;re about to have. <br><br>The second question was rela- &#8212;<br><br>Q    (Inaudible.)  How would you ever trust him?  And what is your version of &#8220;trust but verify&#8221;?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;d verify first and then trust.  In other words: Everything would have to be shown to be actually occurring.  It&#8217;s not about, you know, trusting; it&#8217;s about agreeing. <br><br>You know, when we &#8212; when you write treaties with your adversaries, you don&#8217;t say, “I trust you.”  You say, “This is what I expect, and if you violate the agreement you made then, we &#8212; the, quote, &#8216;The treaty is off.  The agreement is off.'&#8221; <br><br>And I&#8217;m hoping that &#8212; that President Putin concludes that there is some interest, in terms of his own interests, in changing the perception that the world has of him, in terms of whether or not he will engage in behavior that&#8217;s more consistent with what is considered to be appropriate behavior for a head of state.<br><br>Anne Gearan, Washington Post. <br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  Here at this meeting and earlier at the G7, you&#8217;ve said several times that America is back at Allies’ side, but a lot of those Allies are themselves pretty rattled by what happened on January 6th &#8212; an attempted overturning of your election &#8212; and they may still be alarmed by the continued hold that Donald Trump has over the Republican Party and the rise of nationalist figures like him around the world. <br><br>What do you say to those Allies, what have you been saying to them at these meetings about how the next President of the United States can keep any promises you make? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What I&#8217;m saying is them &#8212; to them is: Watch me.  I mean, I&#8217;m not saying anything, quite frankly.  I&#8217;m just going out &#8212; people, as I&#8217;ve said before, don&#8217;t doubt that I mean what I say, and they believe that I keep my commitments when I say it. <br><br>I&#8217;m not making any promises to anyone that I don&#8217;t believe are overwhelmingly likely to be kept.  I think that we&#8217;re at a moment where &#8212; I mean, let me put it this way: You may have had a different view, but I think an awful lot of people thought that my showing up at the G7 would not produce any kind of enthusiasm about American leadership and about where America was.  I would suggest that it didn&#8217;t turn out that way. <br><br>I would suggest that there is a &#8212; the leaders I&#8217;m dealing with in NATO and the G7 are leaders who know our recent history; know, generically, the character of the American people; and know where the vast center of the public stands &#8212; not Democrat, Republican &#8212; but who we are.  We&#8217;re a decent, honorable nation. <br><br>And I think that they have seen things happen, as we have, that shocked them and surprised them that could have happened.  But I think they, like I do, believe the American people are not going to sustain that kind of behavior. <br><br>And so, I &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t want to get into the &#8212; the statistics because you know that old phrase of Disraeli&#8217;s: “There&#8217;s three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.”<br><br>But I think it&#8217;s appropriate to say that the Republican Party is vastly diminished in numbers; the leadership of the Republican Party is fractured; and the Trump wing of the party is the bulk of the party, but it makes up a significant minority of the American people. <br><br>Now, we&#8217;ll see.  We’ll see.  I believe that by us standing up and saying what we believe to be the case, not engaging in the &#8212; the overwhelming hyperbole that gets engaged in by so many today, that we &#8212; I guess that old expression, “The proof of the pudding is in the eating.” <br><br>When we said &#8212; when I said I was going to deal with beating the virus and I was going to focus on that and I was going to get millions of shots in people&#8217;s arms, it wasn&#8217;t me &#8212; I just knew the American people.  I knew the kind of help I&#8217;d get from the Defense Department, from police departments, from &#8212; from the hospitals, from &#8212; from retired docs, from &#8212; I just knew.  And look how rapidly we moved. <br><br>Now, we have a group of people who were &#8212; everything from the political rejection of the notion of taking a vaccine, to people who were simply afraid of a needle and everything in between.  And we have a way to go. <br><br>But I never doubted that we would be able to generate the kind of support we got and get so many millions of people step up and get vaccinated.  So, I &#8212; I think it is a shock and surprise that what&#8217;s happened, in terms of the consequence of President Trump&#8217;s phony populism, has &#8212; has happened.  And it is disappointing that so many of my Republican colleagues in the Senate, who I know know better, have been reluctant to take on, for example, an investigation because they&#8217;re worried about being primaried. <br><br>But, at the end of the day, we&#8217;ve been through periods like this in American history before where there has been this reluctance to take a chance on your reelection because of the nature of your party&#8217;s politics at the moment. <br><br>I think this is passing.  I don&#8217;t mean easily passing.  That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that I succeed in my agenda &#8212; the agenda, whether it&#8217;s dealing with the vaccine, the economy, infrastructure.  It&#8217;s important that we demonstrate we can make progress and continue to make progress.  And I think we&#8217;re going to be able to do that.<br><br>So, as I said, the proof will be in where it is, you know, six months from now &#8212; where &#8212; where we are.  But I think you&#8217;re going to see that there&#8217;s &#8212; that, God willing, we&#8217;re going to be making progress, and there&#8217;s going to be a coalescing of a lot of Republicans, particularly younger Republicans who are coming up in the party. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And last question, Sebastian Smith of AFP.<br><br>Q    Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.  Ukraine wants a clear “yes” or “no” on getting into the NATO Membership Action Plan.  So, what&#8217;s your answer? <br><br>And, if I may, a second part to the same question: Well, now that Russia has invaded parts of Ukraine, does that effectively rule out Ukraine ever entering NATO, given that being in NATO would mean the U.S. and NATO having to defend Ukrainians against Russia? <br><br>Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The second question is &#8212; the answer is no. <br><br>The first question: It depends on whether they meet the criteria.  The fact is they still have to clean up corruption.  The fact is they have to meet other criteria to get into the Action Plan. <br><br>And so, it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, school is out on that question.  It remains to be seen.  In the meantime, we will do all that we can to pu- &#8212; put Ukraine in the position to be able to continue to resist Russian physical aggression.  And it will not just depend on me whether or not we conclude that &#8212; that Ukraine can become part of NATO; it will depend on the Alliance and how they vote.<br><br>But I know, for one thing, there has to be a co- &#8212; they have to convince, and it&#8217;s not easy.  I made a speech, years ago, to the Rada saying that &#8212; that Ukraine had an opportunity to do something that&#8217;s never occurred in the history of Ukraine: actually generate a democratically elected and not corrupt &#8212; led by oligarchies in any of the regions &#8212; nation.  And I pointed out to them when I made that speech that they will go down in history as the founding fathers of Ukraine if, in fact, they do that.<br><br>They have more to do.  But that does not justify &#8212; the fact they have more to do &#8212; Russia taking aggressive action, either in the Donbas or in &#8212; on the sea, or in any part of Ukraine.  And we&#8217;re going to put Ukraine in a position to be able to maintain their physical security.<br><br>Thank you all so very much.  Sorry you&#8217;re all here so late.  Thank you very much.<br><br>9:54 P.M. CEST<br><br>NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium<br><br><br>9:28 P.M. CEST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Before I turn to today’s meetings, I want to say a short word about our ongoing fight against COVID-19 at home.<br><br>We&#8217;ve made enormous progress in the United States.  Much of the country is returning to normal, and our economic growth is leading the world, and the number of cases and deaths are dropping dramatically.  But there&#8217;s still too many lives being lost.<br><br>We’re still averaging, in the last seven days, loss of 370 deaths per day &#8212; 370 deaths.  That’s significantly lower than at the peak of this crisis, but it’s still a real tragedy.  We’re approaching a sad milestone: almost 600,000 lost lives because of COVID-19 in America. <br><br>My heart goes out to all those who have lost a loved one.  I know that black hole that seems to consume you, that fills up your chest when you lose someone that&#8217;s close to you that you adored.<br><br>That’s why I continue to say to America: If you’ve not been vaccinated, get vaccinated.  Get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We have plenty of vaccination, plenty of sites.  We have more work to do to beat this virus, and now is not the time to let our guard down.  So, please &#8212; please get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We’ve had enough pain.  Enough pain.<br><br>Folks, I know it&#8217;s after 9:30, Brussels time &#8212; 9:30 p.m., and I&#8217;m still at NATO.  You&#8217;re all excited about that.  I know.  (Laughter.) <br><br>But I&#8217;ve had a chance to meet with several leaders recently, and I’ve had calls with others.  It&#8217;s been an incredibly productive day here. <br><br>I just finished a meeting with President Erdoğan of Turkey.  We had a positive and productive meeting, much of it one-on-one.  We had detailed discussions on how to proceed on a number of &#8212; a number of issues.  Our two countries have big agendas.  Our teams are going to continue our discussions, and I’m confident we&#8217;ll make real progress with Turkey and the United States.<br><br>But now I want to thank Secretary General Stoltenberg for leading a very successful NATO Summit today.<br><br>I had the honor of leading off the discussion today among the 30 nations, and I pointed out that we’re facing a once-in-a-century global health crisis.  At the same time, the democratic values that undergird our Alliance are under increasing pressure both internally and externally.  Russia and China are both seeking to drive a wedge in our transatlantic solidarity.  We’re seeing an increase in malicious cyber activity.<br><br>But that our Alliance is the strong foundation on which we can &#8212; our collective security and our shared prosperity can continue to be built. <br><br>And I made a point to make clear that the U.S. commitment to Article 5 of the NATO Treaty is rock solid and unshakable.  It’s a sacred commitment.<br><br>NATO &#8212; NATO stands together.  That’s how we’ve met every other threat in the past.  It’s our greatest strength as we meet our challenges of the future &#8212; and there are many. <br><br>And everyone &#8212; everyone in that room today understood the shared appreciation, quite frankly, that America is back.<br><br>We talked about Russia’s aggressive acts that pose a threat to NATO and to our collective security.<br><br>That’s why I met with the Bucharest 9 &#8212; the eastern flank allies &#8212; in advance of this summit.  And today I also met with the leaders of the three Baltic states: Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania.<br><br>I shared with our Allies that I will convey to Pre- &#8212; what I&#8217;ll convey to President Putin: that I’m not looking for conflict with Russia, but that we will respond if Russia continues its harmful activities and that we will not fail to defend the Transatlantic Alliance or stand up for democratic values.<br><br>As Allies, we also affirmed our continued support<br>for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.<br><br>We agreed to keep consulting closely on nuclear deterrence, arms control, and strategic stability.<br><br>And there was a strong consensus among the leaders in that meeting on Afghanistan.  Our troops are coming home, but we agreed that our diplomatic, economic, and humanitarian commitment to the Afghan people and our support for<br>the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces will endure.<br><br>And I welcomed our Allies and partners to recognize that counterterrorism &#8212; that counterterrorism efforts must continue to ensure that Afghanistan never again becomes a ca- &#8212; a safe haven for attacks on our countries, even as we take on terrorist networks in the Middle East and Africa.<br><br>And I’m deeply gratified that, as an Alliance, we adopted a far-reaching plan to make sure that NATO can meet the challenges<br>that we face today and in the future, not yesterday &#8212; the NATO 2030 agenda &#8212; and that we agreed to fully resource that agenda.<br><br>The last time NATO put together a strategic plan was back in 2010, when Russia was considered a partner and China wasn’t even mentioned.<br><br>We talked about the long-term systemic challenges that China’s activities pose to our collective security today.<br><br>We agreed to do more to enhance the resilience of our critical infrastructure around the world, including trusted telecommunications providers, supply chains, and energy networks.<br><br>We agreed to enhance our cooperation with our democratic partners in the Indo-Pacific to meet challenges that exist there.<br><br>We also endorsed a new cyber defense policy &#8212; NATO&#8217;s first in the past seven years &#8212; to improve the collective ability to defend against counter threats from state and nonstate actors against our networks and our critical infrastructure. <br><br>And we adopted a Climate Security Action Plan &#8212; which, several years ago, people thought we would never would do &#8212; for reducing emissions from NATO installations and adapting to the security risk of climate change while keeping a sharp &#8212; very sharp on our ability to deter and defend against threats.<br><br>And finally, we agreed that among the most important shared missions is renewing and strengthening the resilience of our democracies by pointing out we have to prove to the world and to our own people that democracy can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs of our people.<br><br>We have to root out corruption that siphons off our strength; guard against those who would stoke hatred and division for political gain &#8212; this phony populism; invest in strengthening the institutions that underpin and safeguard our cherished democratic values, as well as protecting the free press and independent judiciaries.  All of those run the agenda. <br><br>That&#8217;s how I’ll prove that democracy and that our Alliance can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs and the needs of our people.<br><br>This is going to be looked at 25 years from now as whether or not we stepped up to the challenge, because there&#8217;s a lot of &#8212; a lot of autocracies that are counting on them being able to move more rapidly and successfully in an ever-complicated world than democracies can.  We all concluded we&#8217;re going to prove them wrong. <br><br>And now I&#8217;m happy to take some questions. <br><br>Cecilia Vega of ABC.<br><br>Q    Thank you so much, sir.  Good evening.  You mentioned your sit-down with Vladimir Putin and Russian aggression that came up in your conversations today.  I&#8217;d like to ask you two questions, if I may, on that front.  Is it your sense, walking into this meeting, that Americans back home shouldn&#8217;t expect much in terms of an outcome?  Could you provide some specifics on what a successful meeting would look like to you?  Are there going to be specific concessions you want Putin to make?<br><br>And then, I&#8217;ll just give you my follow-up right now.  You&#8217;ve met Vladimir Putin before.  What have you learned about him that informs how you approach this sit-down with him?  And what&#8217;s your mindset walking into a meeting with a former KGB agent who you&#8217;ve said has no soul?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ll tell you all that when it&#8217;s over. <br><br>Look, I&#8217;ve been doing this a long time.  The last thing anyone would do is negotiate in front of the world press as to how he&#8217;s going to approach a critical meeting with another adversary and/or someone who could be an adversary.  It’s the last thing I&#8217;m going to do.<br><br>But I will tell you this: I’m going to make clear to President Putin that there are areas where we can cooperate, if he chooses.  And if he chooses not to cooperate and acts in a way that he has in the past, relative to cybersecurity and some other activities, then we will respond.  We will respond in kind. <br><br>There need not be &#8212; we should decide where it&#8217;s in our mutual interest, in the interest of the world, to cooperate, and see if we can do that.  And the areas where we don&#8217;t agree, make it clear what the red lines are.<br><br>I have met with him.  He&#8217;s bright.  He&#8217;s tough.  And I have found that he is a &#8212; as they say, when you used to play ball, “a worthy adversary.” <br><br>But the fact is that I will be happy to talk with you when it&#8217;s over, and not before, about what the discussion will entail.<br><br>Nancy Cordes, CBS.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  I also have two questions about Vladimir Putin.  The first is: Have any of the world leaders you&#8217;ve met with this week expressed concern that by meeting with President Putin this early in your presidency, that it&#8217;ll look like you&#8217;re rewarding him?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What&#8217;s your second question?<br><br>Q    The section &#8212; the second question is: What it will mean for the U.S.-Russia relationship if Aleksey Navalny were to die or be killed in prison.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Every world leader here, as a member of NATO, that spoke today &#8212; and most of them mentioned it &#8212; thanked me for meeting with Putin now.  Every single one that spoke.  And I think there were probably about 10 or 12 that spoke to it, saying they were happy that I did that and that I was going to do that.  And they thought it was thoroughly appropriate that I do, and I had discussions with them about &#8212; in the open &#8212; about what they thought was important from their perspective and what they thought was not important.<br><br>And so the interesting thing is, I know &#8212; and I’m not being critical of the press &#8212; I really mean this; I give you my word &#8212; but, generically, you all thought, “Was Biden meeting him too soon?”  I haven’t found a world leader who doesn’t think it’s not soon &#8212; it’s just soon enough.  Everyone that I’ve spoken to, privately and publicly. <br><br>It doesn’t mean there aren&#8217;t some out there, but it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not likely that a head of state is going to stand up in front of 29 other heads of state and say, “Boy, I&#8217;m glad you&#8217;re doing this,” in effect.  So there is a consensus.  And they thanked me for being willing to talk with them about the meeting and what I was &#8212; what I intended to do.<br><br>So, I haven&#8217;t found any reluctance.  There may be someone, but not in the open today or in the meetings I privately had as well.<br><br>And Navalny’s death would be another indication that Russia has little or no intention of abiding by basic fundamental human rights.  It would be a tragedy.  It would do nothing but hurt his relationships with the rest of the world, in my view, and with me. <br><br>Jeff Zeleny, CNN.<br><br>Q    Sir, good evening.  Thank you.  In a weekend interview, Vladimir Putin laughed at the suggestion that you had called him a &#8220;killer.”  Is that still your belief, sir, that he is a killer? <br><br>And I&#8217;ll continue the trend, if you don&#8217;t mind, of asking a second question.  Do you believe &#8212; if he does agree to cooperate, then what kind of a challenge do you find yourself in?  How would you ever trust him?  And if Ronald Reagan said “trust but verify,” what do you say to Vladimir Putin? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (Laughs.)  To answer the first question &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I’m laughing too.<br><br>They actually &#8212; I &#8212;<br><br>Q    So he is a killer?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, look, I mean, he has made clear that &#8212; the answer is: I believe he has, in the past, essentially acknowledged that he was &#8212; there were certain things that he would do or did do. <br><br>But look, when I was asked that question on air, I answered it honestly.  But it&#8217;s not much of a &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it matters a whole lot, in terms of this next meeting we&#8217;re about to have. <br><br>The second question was rela- &#8212;<br><br>Q    (Inaudible.)  How would you ever trust him?  And what is your version of &#8220;trust but verify&#8221;?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;d verify first and then trust.  In other words: Everything would have to be shown to be actually occurring.  It&#8217;s not about, you know, trusting; it&#8217;s about agreeing. <br><br>You know, when we &#8212; when you write treaties with your adversaries, you don&#8217;t say, “I trust you.”  You say, “This is what I expect, and if you violate the agreement you made then, we &#8212; the, quote, &#8216;The treaty is off.  The agreement is off.'&#8221; <br><br>And I&#8217;m hoping that &#8212; that President Putin concludes that there is some interest, in terms of his own interests, in changing the perception that the world has of him, in terms of whether or not he will engage in behavior that&#8217;s more consistent with what is considered to be appropriate behavior for a head of state.<br><br>Anne Gearan, Washington Post. <br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  Here at this meeting and earlier at the G7, you&#8217;ve said several times that America is back at Allies’ side, but a lot of those Allies are themselves pretty rattled by what happened on January 6th &#8212; an attempted overturning of your election &#8212; and they may still be alarmed by the continued hold that Donald Trump has over the Republican Party and the rise of nationalist figures like him around the world. <br><br>What do you say to those Allies, what have you been saying to them at these meetings about how the next President of the United States can keep any promises you make? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What I&#8217;m saying is them &#8212; to them is: Watch me.  I mean, I&#8217;m not saying anything, quite frankly.  I&#8217;m just going out &#8212; people, as I&#8217;ve said before, don&#8217;t doubt that I mean what I say, and they believe that I keep my commitments when I say it. <br><br>I&#8217;m not making any promises to anyone that I don&#8217;t believe are overwhelmingly likely to be kept.  I think that we&#8217;re at a moment where &#8212; I mean, let me put it this way: You may have had a different view, but I think an awful lot of people thought that my showing up at the G7 would not produce any kind of enthusiasm about American leadership and about where America was.  I would suggest that it didn&#8217;t turn out that way. <br><br>I would suggest that there is a &#8212; the leaders I&#8217;m dealing with in NATO and the G7 are leaders who know our recent history; know, generically, the character of the American people; and know where the vast center of the public stands &#8212; not Democrat, Republican &#8212; but who we are.  We&#8217;re a decent, honorable nation. <br><br>And I think that they have seen things happen, as we have, that shocked them and surprised them that could have happened.  But I think they, like I do, believe the American people are not going to sustain that kind of behavior. <br><br>And so, I &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t want to get into the &#8212; the statistics because you know that old phrase of Disraeli&#8217;s: “There&#8217;s three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.”<br><br>But I think it&#8217;s appropriate to say that the Republican Party is vastly diminished in numbers; the leadership of the Republican Party is fractured; and the Trump wing of the party is the bulk of the party, but it makes up a significant minority of the American people. <br><br>Now, we&#8217;ll see.  We’ll see.  I believe that by us standing up and saying what we believe to be the case, not engaging in the &#8212; the overwhelming hyperbole that gets engaged in by so many today, that we &#8212; I guess that old expression, “The proof of the pudding is in the eating.” <br><br>When we said &#8212; when I said I was going to deal with beating the virus and I was going to focus on that and I was going to get millions of shots in people&#8217;s arms, it wasn&#8217;t me &#8212; I just knew the American people.  I knew the kind of help I&#8217;d get from the Defense Department, from police departments, from &#8212; from the hospitals, from &#8212; from retired docs, from &#8212; I just knew.  And look how rapidly we moved. <br><br>Now, we have a group of people who were &#8212; everything from the political rejection of the notion of taking a vaccine, to people who were simply afraid of a needle and everything in between.  And we have a way to go. <br><br>But I never doubted that we would be able to generate the kind of support we got and get so many millions of people step up and get vaccinated.  So, I &#8212; I think it is a shock and surprise that what&#8217;s happened, in terms of the consequence of President Trump&#8217;s phony populism, has &#8212; has happened.  And it is disappointing that so many of my Republican colleagues in the Senate, who I know know better, have been reluctant to take on, for example, an investigation because they&#8217;re worried about being primaried. <br><br>But, at the end of the day, we&#8217;ve been through periods like this in American history before where there has been this reluctance to take a chance on your reelection because of the nature of your party&#8217;s politics at the moment. <br><br>I think this is passing.  I don&#8217;t mean easily passing.  That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that I succeed in my agenda &#8212; the agenda, whether it&#8217;s dealing with the vaccine, the economy, infrastructure.  It&#8217;s important that we demonstrate we can make progress and continue to make progress.  And I think we&#8217;re going to be able to do that.<br><br>So, as I said, the proof will be in where it is, you know, six months from now &#8212; where &#8212; where we are.  But I think you&#8217;re going to see that there&#8217;s &#8212; that, God willing, we&#8217;re going to be making progress, and there&#8217;s going to be a coalescing of a lot of Republicans, particularly younger Republicans who are coming up in the party. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And last question, Sebastian Smith of AFP.<br><br>Q    Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.  Ukraine wants a clear “yes” or “no” on getting into the NATO Membership Action Plan.  So, what&#8217;s your answer? <br><br>And, if I may, a second part to the same question: Well, now that Russia has invaded parts of Ukraine, does that effectively rule out Ukraine ever entering NATO, given that being in NATO would mean the U.S. and NATO having to defend Ukrainians against Russia? <br><br>Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The second question is &#8212; the answer is no. <br><br>The first question: It depends on whether they meet the criteria.  The fact is they still have to clean up corruption.  The fact is they have to meet other criteria to get into the Action Plan. <br><br>And so, it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, school is out on that question.  It remains to be seen.  In the meantime, we will do all that we can to pu- &#8212; put Ukraine in the position to be able to continue to resist Russian physical aggression.  And it will not just depend on me whether or not we conclude that &#8212; that Ukraine can become part of NATO; it will depend on the Alliance and how they vote.<br><br>But I know, for one thing, there has to be a co- &#8212; they have to convince, and it&#8217;s not easy.  I made a speech, years ago, to the Rada saying that &#8212; that Ukraine had an opportunity to do something that&#8217;s never occurred in the history of Ukraine: actually generate a democratically elected and not corrupt &#8212; led by oligarchies in any of the regions &#8212; nation.  And I pointed out to them when I made that speech that they will go down in history as the founding fathers of Ukraine if, in fact, they do that.<br><br>They have more to do.  But that does not justify &#8212; the fact they have more to do &#8212; Russia taking aggressive action, either in the Donbas or in &#8212; on the sea, or in any part of Ukraine.  And we&#8217;re going to put Ukraine in a position to be able to maintain their physical security.<br><br>Thank you all so very much.  Sorry you&#8217;re all here so late.  Thank you very much.<br><br>9:54 P.M. CEST<br><br>NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium<br><br><br>9:28 P.M. CEST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Good evening.  Before I turn to today’s meetings, I want to say a short word about our ongoing fight against COVID-19 at home.<br><br>We&#8217;ve made enormous progress in the United States.  Much of the country is returning to normal, and our economic growth is leading the world, and the number of cases and deaths are dropping dramatically.  But there&#8217;s still too many lives being lost.<br><br>We’re still averaging, in the last seven days, loss of 370 deaths per day &#8212; 370 deaths.  That’s significantly lower than at the peak of this crisis, but it’s still a real tragedy.  We’re approaching a sad milestone: almost 600,000 lost lives because of COVID-19 in America. <br><br>My heart goes out to all those who have lost a loved one.  I know that black hole that seems to consume you, that fills up your chest when you lose someone that&#8217;s close to you that you adored.<br><br>That’s why I continue to say to America: If you’ve not been vaccinated, get vaccinated.  Get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We have plenty of vaccination, plenty of sites.  We have more work to do to beat this virus, and now is not the time to let our guard down.  So, please &#8212; please get vaccinated as soon as possible.  We’ve had enough pain.  Enough pain.<br><br>Folks, I know it&#8217;s after 9:30, Brussels time &#8212; 9:30 p.m., and I&#8217;m still at NATO.  You&#8217;re all excited about that.  I know.  (Laughter.) <br><br>But I&#8217;ve had a chance to meet with several leaders recently, and I’ve had calls with others.  It&#8217;s been an incredibly productive day here. <br><br>I just finished a meeting with President Erdoğan of Turkey.  We had a positive and productive meeting, much of it one-on-one.  We had detailed discussions on how to proceed on a number of &#8212; a number of issues.  Our two countries have big agendas.  Our teams are going to continue our discussions, and I’m confident we&#8217;ll make real progress with Turkey and the United States.<br><br>But now I want to thank Secretary General Stoltenberg for leading a very successful NATO Summit today.<br><br>I had the honor of leading off the discussion today among the 30 nations, and I pointed out that we’re facing a once-in-a-century global health crisis.  At the same time, the democratic values that undergird our Alliance are under increasing pressure both internally and externally.  Russia and China are both seeking to drive a wedge in our transatlantic solidarity.  We’re seeing an increase in malicious cyber activity.<br><br>But that our Alliance is the strong foundation on which we can &#8212; our collective security and our shared prosperity can continue to be built. <br><br>And I made a point to make clear that the U.S. commitment to Article 5 of the NATO Treaty is rock solid and unshakable.  It’s a sacred commitment.<br><br>NATO &#8212; NATO stands together.  That’s how we’ve met every other threat in the past.  It’s our greatest strength as we meet our challenges of the future &#8212; and there are many. <br><br>And everyone &#8212; everyone in that room today understood the shared appreciation, quite frankly, that America is back.<br><br>We talked about Russia’s aggressive acts that pose a threat to NATO and to our collective security.<br><br>That’s why I met with the Bucharest 9 &#8212; the eastern flank allies &#8212; in advance of this summit.  And today I also met with the leaders of the three Baltic states: Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania.<br><br>I shared with our Allies that I will convey to Pre- &#8212; what I&#8217;ll convey to President Putin: that I’m not looking for conflict with Russia, but that we will respond if Russia continues its harmful activities and that we will not fail to defend the Transatlantic Alliance or stand up for democratic values.<br><br>As Allies, we also affirmed our continued support<br>for the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.<br><br>We agreed to keep consulting closely on nuclear deterrence, arms control, and strategic stability.<br><br>And there was a strong consensus among the leaders in that meeting on Afghanistan.  Our troops are coming home, but we agreed that our diplomatic, economic, and humanitarian commitment to the Afghan people and our support for<br>the Afghan National Defense and Security Forces will endure.<br><br>And I welcomed our Allies and partners to recognize that counterterrorism &#8212; that counterterrorism efforts must continue to ensure that Afghanistan never again becomes a ca- &#8212; a safe haven for attacks on our countries, even as we take on terrorist networks in the Middle East and Africa.<br><br>And I’m deeply gratified that, as an Alliance, we adopted a far-reaching plan to make sure that NATO can meet the challenges<br>that we face today and in the future, not yesterday &#8212; the NATO 2030 agenda &#8212; and that we agreed to fully resource that agenda.<br><br>The last time NATO put together a strategic plan was back in 2010, when Russia was considered a partner and China wasn’t even mentioned.<br><br>We talked about the long-term systemic challenges that China’s activities pose to our collective security today.<br><br>We agreed to do more to enhance the resilience of our critical infrastructure around the world, including trusted telecommunications providers, supply chains, and energy networks.<br><br>We agreed to enhance our cooperation with our democratic partners in the Indo-Pacific to meet challenges that exist there.<br><br>We also endorsed a new cyber defense policy &#8212; NATO&#8217;s first in the past seven years &#8212; to improve the collective ability to defend against counter threats from state and nonstate actors against our networks and our critical infrastructure. <br><br>And we adopted a Climate Security Action Plan &#8212; which, several years ago, people thought we would never would do &#8212; for reducing emissions from NATO installations and adapting to the security risk of climate change while keeping a sharp &#8212; very sharp on our ability to deter and defend against threats.<br><br>And finally, we agreed that among the most important shared missions is renewing and strengthening the resilience of our democracies by pointing out we have to prove to the world and to our own people that democracy can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs of our people.<br><br>We have to root out corruption that siphons off our strength; guard against those who would stoke hatred and division for political gain &#8212; this phony populism; invest in strengthening the institutions that underpin and safeguard our cherished democratic values, as well as protecting the free press and independent judiciaries.  All of those run the agenda. <br><br>That&#8217;s how I’ll prove that democracy and that our Alliance can still prevail against the challenges of our time and deliver for the needs and the needs of our people.<br><br>This is going to be looked at 25 years from now as whether or not we stepped up to the challenge, because there&#8217;s a lot of &#8212; a lot of autocracies that are counting on them being able to move more rapidly and successfully in an ever-complicated world than democracies can.  We all concluded we&#8217;re going to prove them wrong. <br><br>And now I&#8217;m happy to take some questions. <br><br>Cecilia Vega of ABC.<br><br>Q    Thank you so much, sir.  Good evening.  You mentioned your sit-down with Vladimir Putin and Russian aggression that came up in your conversations today.  I&#8217;d like to ask you two questions, if I may, on that front.  Is it your sense, walking into this meeting, that Americans back home shouldn&#8217;t expect much in terms of an outcome?  Could you provide some specifics on what a successful meeting would look like to you?  Are there going to be specific concessions you want Putin to make?<br><br>And then, I&#8217;ll just give you my follow-up right now.  You&#8217;ve met Vladimir Putin before.  What have you learned about him that informs how you approach this sit-down with him?  And what&#8217;s your mindset walking into a meeting with a former KGB agent who you&#8217;ve said has no soul?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;ll tell you all that when it&#8217;s over. <br><br>Look, I&#8217;ve been doing this a long time.  The last thing anyone would do is negotiate in front of the world press as to how he&#8217;s going to approach a critical meeting with another adversary and/or someone who could be an adversary.  It’s the last thing I&#8217;m going to do.<br><br>But I will tell you this: I’m going to make clear to President Putin that there are areas where we can cooperate, if he chooses.  And if he chooses not to cooperate and acts in a way that he has in the past, relative to cybersecurity and some other activities, then we will respond.  We will respond in kind. <br><br>There need not be &#8212; we should decide where it&#8217;s in our mutual interest, in the interest of the world, to cooperate, and see if we can do that.  And the areas where we don&#8217;t agree, make it clear what the red lines are.<br><br>I have met with him.  He&#8217;s bright.  He&#8217;s tough.  And I have found that he is a &#8212; as they say, when you used to play ball, “a worthy adversary.” <br><br>But the fact is that I will be happy to talk with you when it&#8217;s over, and not before, about what the discussion will entail.<br><br>Nancy Cordes, CBS.<br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  I also have two questions about Vladimir Putin.  The first is: Have any of the world leaders you&#8217;ve met with this week expressed concern that by meeting with President Putin this early in your presidency, that it&#8217;ll look like you&#8217;re rewarding him?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What&#8217;s your second question?<br><br>Q    The section &#8212; the second question is: What it will mean for the U.S.-Russia relationship if Aleksey Navalny were to die or be killed in prison.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Every world leader here, as a member of NATO, that spoke today &#8212; and most of them mentioned it &#8212; thanked me for meeting with Putin now.  Every single one that spoke.  And I think there were probably about 10 or 12 that spoke to it, saying they were happy that I did that and that I was going to do that.  And they thought it was thoroughly appropriate that I do, and I had discussions with them about &#8212; in the open &#8212; about what they thought was important from their perspective and what they thought was not important.<br><br>And so the interesting thing is, I know &#8212; and I’m not being critical of the press &#8212; I really mean this; I give you my word &#8212; but, generically, you all thought, “Was Biden meeting him too soon?”  I haven’t found a world leader who doesn’t think it’s not soon &#8212; it’s just soon enough.  Everyone that I’ve spoken to, privately and publicly. <br><br>It doesn’t mean there aren&#8217;t some out there, but it&#8217;s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not likely that a head of state is going to stand up in front of 29 other heads of state and say, “Boy, I&#8217;m glad you&#8217;re doing this,” in effect.  So there is a consensus.  And they thanked me for being willing to talk with them about the meeting and what I was &#8212; what I intended to do.<br><br>So, I haven&#8217;t found any reluctance.  There may be someone, but not in the open today or in the meetings I privately had as well.<br><br>And Navalny’s death would be another indication that Russia has little or no intention of abiding by basic fundamental human rights.  It would be a tragedy.  It would do nothing but hurt his relationships with the rest of the world, in my view, and with me. <br><br>Jeff Zeleny, CNN.<br><br>Q    Sir, good evening.  Thank you.  In a weekend interview, Vladimir Putin laughed at the suggestion that you had called him a &#8220;killer.”  Is that still your belief, sir, that he is a killer? <br><br>And I&#8217;ll continue the trend, if you don&#8217;t mind, of asking a second question.  Do you believe &#8212; if he does agree to cooperate, then what kind of a challenge do you find yourself in?  How would you ever trust him?  And if Ronald Reagan said “trust but verify,” what do you say to Vladimir Putin? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  (Laughs.)  To answer the first question &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; I’m laughing too.<br><br>They actually &#8212; I &#8212;<br><br>Q    So he is a killer?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Well, look, I mean, he has made clear that &#8212; the answer is: I believe he has, in the past, essentially acknowledged that he was &#8212; there were certain things that he would do or did do. <br><br>But look, when I was asked that question on air, I answered it honestly.  But it&#8217;s not much of a &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it matters a whole lot, in terms of this next meeting we&#8217;re about to have. <br><br>The second question was rela- &#8212;<br><br>Q    (Inaudible.)  How would you ever trust him?  And what is your version of &#8220;trust but verify&#8221;?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;d verify first and then trust.  In other words: Everything would have to be shown to be actually occurring.  It&#8217;s not about, you know, trusting; it&#8217;s about agreeing. <br><br>You know, when we &#8212; when you write treaties with your adversaries, you don&#8217;t say, “I trust you.”  You say, “This is what I expect, and if you violate the agreement you made then, we &#8212; the, quote, &#8216;The treaty is off.  The agreement is off.'&#8221; <br><br>And I&#8217;m hoping that &#8212; that President Putin concludes that there is some interest, in terms of his own interests, in changing the perception that the world has of him, in terms of whether or not he will engage in behavior that&#8217;s more consistent with what is considered to be appropriate behavior for a head of state.<br><br>Anne Gearan, Washington Post. <br><br>Q    Thank you, Mr. President.  Here at this meeting and earlier at the G7, you&#8217;ve said several times that America is back at Allies’ side, but a lot of those Allies are themselves pretty rattled by what happened on January 6th &#8212; an attempted overturning of your election &#8212; and they may still be alarmed by the continued hold that Donald Trump has over the Republican Party and the rise of nationalist figures like him around the world. <br><br>What do you say to those Allies, what have you been saying to them at these meetings about how the next President of the United States can keep any promises you make? <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  What I&#8217;m saying is them &#8212; to them is: Watch me.  I mean, I&#8217;m not saying anything, quite frankly.  I&#8217;m just going out &#8212; people, as I&#8217;ve said before, don&#8217;t doubt that I mean what I say, and they believe that I keep my commitments when I say it. <br><br>I&#8217;m not making any promises to anyone that I don&#8217;t believe are overwhelmingly likely to be kept.  I think that we&#8217;re at a moment where &#8212; I mean, let me put it this way: You may have had a different view, but I think an awful lot of people thought that my showing up at the G7 would not produce any kind of enthusiasm about American leadership and about where America was.  I would suggest that it didn&#8217;t turn out that way. <br><br>I would suggest that there is a &#8212; the leaders I&#8217;m dealing with in NATO and the G7 are leaders who know our recent history; know, generically, the character of the American people; and know where the vast center of the public stands &#8212; not Democrat, Republican &#8212; but who we are.  We&#8217;re a decent, honorable nation. <br><br>And I think that they have seen things happen, as we have, that shocked them and surprised them that could have happened.  But I think they, like I do, believe the American people are not going to sustain that kind of behavior. <br><br>And so, I &#8212; you know, I don&#8217;t want to get into the &#8212; the statistics because you know that old phrase of Disraeli&#8217;s: “There&#8217;s three kinds of lies: lies, damned lies, and statistics.”<br><br>But I think it&#8217;s appropriate to say that the Republican Party is vastly diminished in numbers; the leadership of the Republican Party is fractured; and the Trump wing of the party is the bulk of the party, but it makes up a significant minority of the American people. <br><br>Now, we&#8217;ll see.  We’ll see.  I believe that by us standing up and saying what we believe to be the case, not engaging in the &#8212; the overwhelming hyperbole that gets engaged in by so many today, that we &#8212; I guess that old expression, “The proof of the pudding is in the eating.” <br><br>When we said &#8212; when I said I was going to deal with beating the virus and I was going to focus on that and I was going to get millions of shots in people&#8217;s arms, it wasn&#8217;t me &#8212; I just knew the American people.  I knew the kind of help I&#8217;d get from the Defense Department, from police departments, from &#8212; from the hospitals, from &#8212; from retired docs, from &#8212; I just knew.  And look how rapidly we moved. <br><br>Now, we have a group of people who were &#8212; everything from the political rejection of the notion of taking a vaccine, to people who were simply afraid of a needle and everything in between.  And we have a way to go. <br><br>But I never doubted that we would be able to generate the kind of support we got and get so many millions of people step up and get vaccinated.  So, I &#8212; I think it is a shock and surprise that what&#8217;s happened, in terms of the consequence of President Trump&#8217;s phony populism, has &#8212; has happened.  And it is disappointing that so many of my Republican colleagues in the Senate, who I know know better, have been reluctant to take on, for example, an investigation because they&#8217;re worried about being primaried. <br><br>But, at the end of the day, we&#8217;ve been through periods like this in American history before where there has been this reluctance to take a chance on your reelection because of the nature of your party&#8217;s politics at the moment. <br><br>I think this is passing.  I don&#8217;t mean easily passing.  That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so important that I succeed in my agenda &#8212; the agenda, whether it&#8217;s dealing with the vaccine, the economy, infrastructure.  It&#8217;s important that we demonstrate we can make progress and continue to make progress.  And I think we&#8217;re going to be able to do that.<br><br>So, as I said, the proof will be in where it is, you know, six months from now &#8212; where &#8212; where we are.  But I think you&#8217;re going to see that there&#8217;s &#8212; that, God willing, we&#8217;re going to be making progress, and there&#8217;s going to be a coalescing of a lot of Republicans, particularly younger Republicans who are coming up in the party. <br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  And last question, Sebastian Smith of AFP.<br><br>Q    Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.  Ukraine wants a clear “yes” or “no” on getting into the NATO Membership Action Plan.  So, what&#8217;s your answer? <br><br>And, if I may, a second part to the same question: Well, now that Russia has invaded parts of Ukraine, does that effectively rule out Ukraine ever entering NATO, given that being in NATO would mean the U.S. and NATO having to defend Ukrainians against Russia? <br><br>Thank you.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  The second question is &#8212; the answer is no. <br><br>The first question: It depends on whether they meet the criteria.  The fact is they still have to clean up corruption.  The fact is they have to meet other criteria to get into the Action Plan. <br><br>And so, it&#8217;s &#8212; you know, school is out on that question.  It remains to be seen.  In the meantime, we will do all that we can to pu- &#8212; put Ukraine in the position to be able to continue to resist Russian physical aggression.  And it will not just depend on me whether or not we conclude that &#8212; that Ukraine can become part of NATO; it will depend on the Alliance and how they vote.<br><br>But I know, for one thing, there has to be a co- &#8212; they have to convince, and it&#8217;s not easy.  I made a speech, years ago, to the Rada saying that &#8212; that Ukraine had an opportunity to do something that&#8217;s never occurred in the history of Ukraine: actually generate a democratically elected and not corrupt &#8212; led by oligarchies in any of the regions &#8212; nation.  And I pointed out to them when I made that speech that they will go down in history as the founding fathers of Ukraine if, in fact, they do that.<br><br>They have more to do.  But that does not justify &#8212; the fact they have more to do &#8212; Russia taking aggressive action, either in the Donbas or in &#8212; on the sea, or in any part of Ukraine.  And we&#8217;re going to put Ukraine in a position to be able to maintain their physical security.<br><br>Thank you all so very much.  Sorry you&#8217;re all here so late.  Thank you very much.<br><br>9:54 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/14/a-proclamation-on-world-elder-abuse-awareness-day-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 18:14:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Older Americans make invaluable contributions to our families, our communities, and our Nation every day.&#160; But for far too many, the sacred promise of aging with dignity in America is broken by unconscionable incidents of abuse, neglect, or exploitation. &#160;On World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, Americans of all ages join the international community to raise&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Older Americans make invaluable contributions to our families, our communities, and our Nation every day.&nbsp; But for far too many, the sacred promise of aging with dignity in America is broken by unconscionable incidents of abuse, neglect, or exploitation. &nbsp;On World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, Americans of all ages join the international community to raise awareness and help bring an end to elder abuse.</p>



<p>Elder abuse can take many forms, including financial, emotional, physical, or sexual abuse, as well as exploitation and neglect.&nbsp; Every year, one in ten Americans aged 60 and older experiences abuse &#8212; and for every case of elder abuse that comes to the attention of authorities, it is estimated that 23&nbsp;cases are never brought to light.&nbsp; Since the start of the COVID-19 pandemic, we have also seen a chilling increase in hate crimes targeting Asian-Americans, many of whom have been elders.&nbsp; These attacks are shameful and deeply un-American.</p>



<p>Central to our Nation is the idea that we are all in this together, and that as Americans we owe one another a basic duty of care.&nbsp; The pandemic has both reinforced the importance of that duty and tested our capacity to meet it &#8212; the virus has exacerbated the quiet harm of social isolation among seniors around the world, a condition that makes abuse, neglect, and exploitation more likely.&nbsp; Having lost so many cherished seniors to this virus, we must recommit ourselves to fully including older Americans in our communities and systems of support.&nbsp; We&nbsp;must care for one another &#8212; and leave no one behind.</p>



<p>With over three-quarters of Americans 65 and over now fully vaccinated and more progress being made every day, the future for seniors is growing brighter and brighter.&nbsp; After a painful year, grandparents around the world are hugging their grandchildren again.&nbsp; Vaccinated seniors who were socially isolated are able to reengage with the broader community again.&nbsp; And as we begin to build back better, we are working to ensure that older Americans have greater opportunities to live with dignity, safety, independence, and social connections.</p>



<p>My Administration is committed to fulfilling that promise.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why the American Rescue Plan included more than $1.4 billion in additional funding for programs that promote community living and ensure the safety and protection of older adults.&nbsp; The law also enhances the Elder Justice Act and ensures that Adult Protective Services can be used to protect the safety and dignity of all seniors.&nbsp; Additionally, the plan included new Medicaid funding to expand access to critical home and community-based health care services, and over $275 million for elder justice programs that address abuse, neglect, and exploitation.&nbsp; The American Jobs Plan and American Families Plan will further that progress, building up the care infrastructure that our economy and so many families depend on &#8212; expanding day programs for seniors, programs that bring care workers to seniors&#8217; homes to cook meals, and programs to help seniors get around their home safely and live more independently.</p>



<p>As we expand opportunities for older Americans, my Administration will also not tolerate elder abuse or hate in any&nbsp;form.&nbsp; I have instructed agencies across the Federal Government to do their part to combat elder abuse and support survivors. &nbsp;We are working to renew and strengthen the Violence Against Women Act, which also dedicates Federal funds to develop a more comprehensive approach to addressing abuse and neglect in&nbsp;later life, including through the funding of victim service providers, law enforcement, and prosecutors working to prevent and respond to domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking experienced by older adults, whether caused by a spouse, family member, caregiver, or others.&nbsp; And this year, for the first time, the Federal Government has provided funding to Adult Protective Services programs in every State and Territory to support their critical, on-the-ground work investigating abuse and connecting victims to resources. &nbsp;</p>



<p>During World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, we also recognize the individuals who dedicate themselves to preventing elder abuse.&nbsp; All across our Nation, caregivers work to help older adults stay connected to their communities while preventing elder abuse and intervening if it occurs.&nbsp; These unsung heroes include family members, Adult Protective Services workers, social service providers, nonprofit victim services organizations, long-term care ombudspersons, law enforcement officers, judges and judicial personnel, legal professionals, health care professionals, and financial professionals.</p>



<p>On World Elder Abuse Awareness Day, we stand with all older Americans, and elderly people around the world, who are victims of elder abuse, neglect, and financial exploitation, and we recommit ourselves to protecting every senior&#8217;s right to live their golden years with dignity and respect.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do&nbsp;hereby proclaim June 15, 2021, as World Elder Abuse Awareness Day. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to work for elder justice by building inclusive communities that welcome people of all ages and abilities; by learning the warning signs of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation; and by challenging age-related biases.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fourteenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right"><br>                              JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with President Andrzej Duda of Poland</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/14/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-andrzej-duda-of-poland/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 14:14:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20711</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke today on the margins of the NATO Summit with President Andrzej Duda of Poland. The President reiterated his support for NATO’s strengthened defense and deterrence agenda and his resolute commitment to the defense of Allies on NATO’s eastern flank, including Poland. He discussed his plans for the upcoming summit with President Putin.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke today on the margins of the NATO Summit with President Andrzej Duda of Poland. The President reiterated his support for NATO’s strengthened defense and deterrence agenda and his resolute commitment to the defense of Allies on NATO’s eastern flank, including Poland. He discussed his plans for the upcoming summit with President Putin.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg During Greeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/14/remarks-by-president-biden-and-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-during-greeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 14:11:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATO HeadquartersBrussels, Belgium 12:28 P.M. CEST&#160;SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&#160; Mr. President, it is great to see you again and just a week after we met in the White House.&#160; And thank you so much for your strong personal commitment and powerful leadership on the transatlantic bond on what to do together &#8212; North America and Europe.&#160;&#160;We&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">NATO Headquarters<br>Brussels, Belgium</p>



<p>12:28 P.M. CEST<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; Mr. President, it is great to see you again and just a week after we met in the White House.&nbsp; And thank you so much for your strong personal commitment and powerful leadership on the transatlantic bond on what to do together &#8212; North America and Europe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We meet at a pivotal time for our Alliance.&nbsp; We will open a new chapter in our transatlantic relationship with the meeting today; address a wide range of issues, including Russia.&nbsp; And I think that the Allied leaders look forward to consulting with you ahead of the meeting with President Putin.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will address China, and we have seen the convergence of views among Allies.&nbsp; We all recognize that China&#8217;s heavy investments in military capabilities, continued coercive behavior, and their growing influence matters for our security.&nbsp; And we need to respond to that together as an Alliance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We will review the NATO 2030 agenda, an ambitious agenda for the future of NATO.&nbsp; And to do all this, we need to invest more.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re doing with seven consecutive years of increased defense spending: 260 billion extra U.S. dollars across Europe and Canada.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So a strong NATO is good for Europe, but is also good for America.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s very good for America.&nbsp; It&#8217;s essential for America.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; And I know that &#8212; that no other major power has as many friends and allies as United States has in NATO.&nbsp; So I know that we can count on America and that America can count on Europe.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, welcome, Mr. President.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, thank you.&nbsp; And thank you for your incredible leadership over the years.&nbsp; I really mean this: You have been incredible.&nbsp; I &#8212; quite frankly, we have competent people coming, but I wish you weren&#8217;t leaving, because &#8212; and, no, I really mean it &#8212; you have been absolutely incredible and you&#8217;ve been strong.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve been &#8212; you&#8217;ve been able to pull people together.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I think that there is a growing recognition over the last couple of years that we have new challenges.&nbsp; And we have Russia that is not acting in a way that is consistent with what we had hoped, and &#8212; as well as China.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I must say that we had as (inaudible) a number of my colleagues and our colleagues who are in the G7 have stepped up as well, in terms of the need for there to be greater coordination.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve had &#8212; but I want to make it clear: NATO is critically important for U.S. interests in and of itself.&nbsp; If there weren&#8217;t one, we&#8217;d have to invent one.&nbsp; It is &#8212; it allows America to &#8212; to conduct its business around the world in a way that never would have occurred were it not for NATO, number one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Number two, you know, I believe &#8212; and I&#8217;ve said this my whole career and the four years I was out, when I decided to run for President again &#8212; that NATO is &#8212; Article 5, we take as a sacred obligation.&nbsp; And I constantly remind Americans that when America was attacked for the first time on its shores since what happened back in the beginning of World War Two, NATO stepped up.&nbsp; NATO stepped up and they honored Article 5.&nbsp; And I just want all of Europe to know that the United States is there.&nbsp; The United States is there.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we &#8212; and we are pleased, back in Wales, the decision was made to increase spending.&nbsp; You&#8217;re right, it&#8217;s moving up.&nbsp; I guess there&#8217;s more than 10 countries that have met the goal, and others are on the way.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s important, but it&#8217;s &#8212; I just want to thank you for your leadership.&nbsp; A lot of this wouldn&#8217;t happen without you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>SECRETARY GENERAL STOLTENBERG:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>12:32 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia, President Egils Levits of Latvia, and President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/14/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-prime-minister-kaja-kallas-of-estonia-president-egils-levits-of-latvia-and-president-gitanas-nauseda-of-lithuania/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 12:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20693</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia, President Egils Levits of Latvia, and President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania on the margins of the NATO Summit in Brussels. The President underscored strong U.S. support for the security of Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania, as well as the entire Baltic region.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia, President Egils Levits of Latvia, and President Gitanas Nauseda of Lithuania on the margins of the NATO Summit in Brussels. The President underscored strong U.S. support for the security of Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania, as well as the entire Baltic region. The four leaders committed to further strengthening our political, military, and economic partnerships, including working together through NATO to address challenges posed by Russia and China.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official On President Biden’s Engagements at NATO Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/14/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-on-president-bidens-engagements-at-nato-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 09:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 3:08 P.M. CEST MODERATOR: Good afternoon, everyone. [Redacted.] Our speaker is going to also provide a brief, unembargoed, on-background update of some of President Biden&#8217;s engagements today at NATO, including the President&#8217;s meeting with Baltic leaders. So, I&#8217;ll turn it over to him to kick us off on that. [Senior administration official], go&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>3:08 P.M. CEST</p>



<p>MODERATOR: Good afternoon, everyone. [Redacted.] Our speaker is going to also provide a brief, unembargoed, on-background update of some of President Biden&#8217;s engagements today at NATO, including the President&#8217;s meeting with Baltic leaders. So, I&#8217;ll turn it over to him to kick us off on that. [Senior administration official], go ahead.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thanks, everybody, for joining the call. And greetings from NATO headquarters, where I&#8217;ve just stepped out of the session of the leaders here at the summit that is currently ongoing.</p>



<p>President Biden has delivered his remarks a short while ago, and other leaders are now speaking. On the margins of the NATO Summit, he had the opportunity to meet with the leaders of the three Baltic countries: Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania. And he got the chance to discuss with them and coordinate with them in advance of his meeting with Putin on Wednesday to talk about the threat that Russia poses to NATO&#8217;s eastern flank, to talk about common commitment to Article 5 and collective defense, to coordinate on the resilience of those states in the face of multiple dimensions of the threat posed by Russia &#8212; from cyber, to provocative military exercises on their borders, to information warfare.</p>



<p>He was able to communicate to them what he has communicated publicly, which is that the United States seeks a stable and constructive relationship with Russia, but also will respond in the face of Russia&#8217;s harmful activities and will always stand up for NATO Allies.</p>



<p>They also discussed the emerging security challenge posed by China, including in the domain of technology. And he thanked the three leaders for the steps that they have taken to support a trusted 5G platform &#8212; to not accept Huawei within their systems.</p>



<p>They also had the opportunity to confer on Belarus and, in particular, the recent egregious air piracy that occurred with respect to a flight that was actually bound for Vilnius, Lithuania. And they had the opportunity to talk more broadly about and an affirmative agenda around emerging technologies and innovation.</p>



<p>It was a constructive, warm, vigorous engagement between him and the three leaders, and a real symbol of solidarity and unity with NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.</p>



<p>In that vein, he also had the opportunity to do a brief meeting with the Presidents of Poland and Romania, who are the co-chairs of the Bucharest Nine, the same group of eastern flank Allies that he engaged with at their virtual summit a few weeks ago. He was able to speak with the two of them about his commitment to (inaudible) security; his commitment, again, to stand up in the face of the threat posed by Russia; and to let them know his intentions for the summit in Geneva on Wednesday.</p>



<p>He had a separate encounter &#8212; an engagement with President Duda of Poland, where they got to go a little bit deeper into the questions of America&#8217;s security and military cooperation and engagement with Poland and the United States&#8217; strong support for the defense of Poland and our common collective commitment to NATO.</p>



<p>He had the chance to talk to a number of other leaders as well, just very briefly &#8212; from the Prime Minister of Spain to the Prime Minister of the Netherlands &#8212; on a range of different issues &#8212; and, of course, to see his colleagues who have just come with him from Cornwall and the G7 &#8212; President Macron, Chancellor Merkel, Prime Minister Draghi, Prime Minister Johnson.</p>



<p>[Redacted.]</p>



<p>Q Thanks, [senior administration official], for doing this. I was hoping you could speak to the issue of Afghanistan and whether any of the NATO members raised concerns with Biden about the withdrawal. And then separately, I would just ask, broadly, on behalf of the media here, if we could get these bilats on the schedule or delivered to the press because we were unaware of several of them today, and also that we could get some access to them, which has been a pretty tradition &#8212; a tradition of both parties in the past. Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Yeah, on the second thing, you know, this was at the initiative of President Biden today that he wanted the opportunity to seek out key leaders, particularly on the eastern flank, to be sure he had the time &#8212; the opportunity to spend time with them, especially given the fact that for the key Western European countries, he&#8217;s just spent three days with them, and he wanted to maximize this opportunity to talk to the Poles, the Romanians, the (inaudible), et cetera. So, a lot of this was evolving in real time and there was not an effort to –- frankly, we would have loved to had &#8212; have more press access to them. But we’ll endeavor always to do better as we go forward.</p>



<p>In terms of Afghanistan, I listened –- I was in the room for the first hour of the summit and heard many of the significant troop-contributing countries speak and speak to the issue of Afghanistan. And each of them said that they ultimately agreed with the decision to come &#8212; to draw down this year. They understood that the time had come.</p>



<p>And the real focus in the room was not on the question of staying or going in 2021; the real focus was on how we work together as an Alliance to continue to provide support to the Afghan National Security Forces, the Afghan government, and the Afghan people.</p>



<p>And there is a considerable amount of practical work being done on that and strategic alignment on the desire to keep embassy presences, to maintain the necessary security to do that, and to work together as an alliance on everything from training &#8212; you know, particularly on over-the-horizon training; to counterterrorism and how we keep suppressing the terrorist threat in Afghanistan; to the provision of economic assistance in various forms to government.</p>



<p>So I&#8217;ve read some of the stories about this question of support or nonsupport for the drawdown from Afghanistan, and I&#8217;ve got to tell you that that is not the vibe in the room today. And, you know, it is &#8212; there is an incredible amount of warmth and unity around the entire agenda, including the &#8220;in together, out together&#8221; aspect of the Afghanistan drawdown.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL: Thanks so much, again, everybody, for taking the time and hopping on this call. Really appreciate it.</p>



<p>3:32 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
