<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 23:41:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Before a Briefing from the FEMA Administrator, Homeland Security, and COVID-&#8288;19 Response&#160;Teams</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/10/remarks-by-president-biden-before-a-briefing-from-the-fema-administrator-homeland-security-and-covid-19-response-teams/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26809</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[State Dining Room 4:46 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, folks.  I’ll make a brief opening statement here.  I want to thank you, Administrator Criswell, for the job you’ve been doing &#8212; outstanding work helping our country navigate what is overlapping challenges we’ve been facing.  And you’ve been very busy. We’ve got wildfires in the West. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">State Dining Room</p>



<p>4:46 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:  Hey, folks.  I’ll make a brief opening statement here.  I want to thank you, Administrator Criswell, for the job you’ve been doing &#8212; outstanding work helping our country navigate what is overlapping challenges we’ve been facing.  And you’ve been very busy.<br><br>We’ve got wildfires in the West.  We’ve got &#8212; approaching the peak of Atlantic hurricane season.  All across the country, the Delta variant is spreading, as Dr. Fauci and others can tell you, and it&#8217;s spreading rapidly &#8212; rapidly among the unvaccinated.  When these crises intersect, they compound one another &#8212; natural disasters and the Delta variant.<br><br>And that’s what we’re going to be discussing today with the group I’ve assembled here.  We need to be ready to manage our natural disasters caused by hurricanes hitting the Southeast and the environment and with a broad community spread of COVID-19.<br>And the best thing we can do is &#8212; to prepare for that is for everyone who is not vaccinated &#8212; I know it’s a broken record, and I keep saying it &#8212; but to get vaccinated.<br><br>With the Delta variant, we’re seeing a pandemic of the unvaccinated.  Cases and hospitalizations are rising faster in states with low vaccination rates, such as Florida, Texas, Louisiana, Alabama, and Mississippi, which are the states that &#8212; from a hurricane-prone &#8212; they’re the states that are most at risk.<br><br>And so, we don’t wait until it’s too late.  And if, God forbid, a natural disaster strikes, we have to make sure we’re ready to be protected against COVID-19 as well.<br><br>Let me be clear: If you’re in a state where hurricanes often strike &#8212; like Florida or the Gulf Coast or into Texas &#8212; a vital part of preparing for hurricane season is to get vaccinated now.  Everything is more complicated if you’re not vaccinated and a hurricane or a natural disaster hits.<br><br>If you wind up having to evacuate, if you wind up having to stay in a shelter, you don’t want to add COVID-19 to the list of dangers that you’re going to be confronting. <br><br>Get vaccinated now so you’re ready for whatever may come this month.  And it’s likely some serious hurricanes are going to come this month. <br><br>So, go to Ready.gov to make sure that you’re prepared with the hurricane &#8212; with a hurricane plan.  Know your evacuation zones.  Have a plan with your family.  And get your emergency supplies and a go-bag ready, and don’t forget to pack one for your pets as well.  I mean that seriously.<br><br>And if you’ve got older neighbors or people in your community who might need your help, check in to see if you can help them make a plan as well. <br><br>And the bottom line is this: The more we do to prepare, the better off we are when disaster strikes.<br><br>We can’t prevent hurricanes making landfall, but we can prevent people from getting seriously sick and dying from COVID-19.  Get vaccinated and make a plan.<br><br>Thank you, all.  That’s what we’re going to discuss in some detail today with my team.  Thank you all very much.<br><br>4:49 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting on Hurricane Preparedness During COVID-&#8288;19&#160;Pandemic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-on-hurricane-preparedness-during-covid-19-pandemic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 23:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26803</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden met with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Chief Medical Advisor and NIAID Director Dr. Anthony Fauci, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, and COVID-19 Response Coordinator and Counselor to the President Jeff Zients, as well as members of his Homeland Security and COVID-19 Response teams, for a briefing on the state of the COVID-19&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden met with FEMA Administrator Deanne Criswell, Chief Medical Advisor and NIAID Director Dr. Anthony Fauci, Homeland Security Advisor Liz Sherwood-Randall, and COVID-19 Response Coordinator and Counselor to the President Jeff Zients, as well as members of his Homeland Security and COVID-19 Response teams, for a briefing on the state of the COVID-19 pandemic in hurricane-prone states in the South and Southeast.  They discussed efforts underway to protect public health, enhance preparedness, and adapt response and recovery operations to meet the challenges of the combined effects of hurricanes and the spread of the Delta variant. </p>



<p>The President was briefed on the data that demonstrates that the most important preparatory step people can take to prepare for peak hurricane season is to get vaccinated to ensure they will be protected from COVID-19 if they have to evacuate their homes. They also discussed how FEMA is innovating during the pandemic by working with partner organizations to enable COVID-safe sheltering, providing vaccination options at shelters and recovery centers, and protecting its workforce so they maintain mission readiness.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><br>###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Eight New Nominees to Serve as U.S.&#160;Attorneys</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/president-biden-announces-eight-new-nominees-to-serve-as-u-s-attorneys/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 22:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26797</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is announcing eight new nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as the top federal law enforcement officials for their districts. These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and credentials in this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is announcing eight new nominees to serve as U.S. Attorneys across the country, officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law as the top federal law enforcement officials for their districts.<br><br>These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and credentials in this field, their dedication to pursuing equal justice for all, and their commitment to the independence of the Department of Justice.<br><br>The President has launched a comprehensive effort to take on the uptick in gun crime that has been taking place for the last 18 months—putting more cops on the beat, supporting community prevention programs, and cracking down on illegal gun trafficking. Confirming U.S. Attorneys as the chief federal law enforcement officers in their district is important for these efforts.<br><br><strong>Jessica D. Aber, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Eastern District of Virginia</strong><br><br>Jessica D. Aber is an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of Virginia, where she has served since 2009. Since 2016, Ms. Aber has been the Deputy Chief of the Criminal Division for the office. From 2015 to 2016, she served on a detail assignment as Counsel to the Assistant Attorney General for the Criminal Division of the United States Department of Justice. Prior to joining the Department of Justice, Ms. Aber was an associate at McGuireWoods LLP from 2007 to 2008. Ms. Aber served as a law clerk for then-Magistrate Judge Hannah Lauck on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia from 2006 to 2007.<br><br>Ms. Aber received her J.D. from William &amp; Mary Law School in 2006 and her B.A., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from the University of Richmond in 2003.<br><br><strong>Carla B. Freedman, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Northern District of New York</strong><br><br>Carla B. Freedman is an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Northern District of New York, where she has served since 2007. Since 2018, Ms. Freedman has served as the Narcotics Chief for the office. From 1988 to 2004, Ms. Freedman was an Assistant District Attorney in the New York County District Attorney’s Office in Manhattan, where she led a unit that focused on investigating organized crime from 1997 to 2004.<br><br>Ms. Freedman received her J.D. from New York Law School in 1988 and her B.A. from Syracuse University in 1985.<br><br><strong>William J. Ihlenfeld, II, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Northern District of West Virginia</strong><br><br>William J. Ihlenfeld is a special counsel at Bowles Rice LLP, where he is a member of the firm’s Litigation and Cybersecurity practice groups. Since he joined Bowles Rice in 2019, Mr. Ihlenfeld has also been a member of the West Virginia State Senate. Mr. Ihlenfeld was a partner at Bailey Glasser LLP from 2017 to 2019, and served as United States Attorney for the Northern District of West Virginia from 2010 to 2016. Prior to that, from 2007 to 2010, he was a state prosecutor in Brooke County, West Virginia. From 1997 to 2007, Mr. Ihlenfeld prosecuted domestic violence cases in Ohio County, West Virginia. Throughout his legal career, Mr. Ihlenfeld has advocated for victims of domestic and sexual violence through pro bono legal representation and service to local and statewide nonprofit organizations.<br><br>Mr. Ihlenfeld received his J.D. from the West Virginia University College of Law in 1997 and his B.S. from Ohio University, with honors, in 1994.<br><br><strong>Christopher R. Kavanaugh, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Western District of Virginia</strong><br><br>Christopher R. Kavanaugh is Senior Counsel to the Deputy Attorney General at the Department of Justice in Washington, D.C. He is currently on detail from the United States Attorney’s Office for the Western District of Virginia, where he has served as an Assistant United States Attorney since 2014. In his role as Assistant United States Attorney, Mr. Kavanaugh is the chief national security prosecutor, senior litigation counsel, and counsel to the United States Attorney for the Western District of Virginia. From 2007 to 2014, Mr. Kavanaugh was an Assistant United States Attorney for the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia. Since 2011, Mr. Kavanaugh has been an adjunct professor at the University of Virginia School of Law, where he teaches federal criminal practice and trial advocacy. Mr. Kavanaugh served as a law clerk for Judge James C. Cacheris on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia from 2006 to 2007.<br><br>Mr. Kavanaugh received his J.D. from the University of Virginia School of Law in 2006 and his B.S. in engineering, <em>summa cum laude</em>, from Georgia Tech in 2002.<br><br><strong>Darcie N. McElwee, U.S. Attorney nominee for the District of Maine</strong><br><br>Darcie N. McElwee is an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the District of Maine, where she has served since 2002. She has served as the Project Safe Neighborhoods Coordinator for the office since 2005. Between 2005 and 2008, Ms. McElwee was an adjunct professor of advanced trial advocacy at the University of Maine School of Law.  Ms. McElwee began her legal career as an Assistant District Attorney for the Penobscot and Piscataquis Counties in Maine from 1998 to 2002.<br><br>Ms. McElwee received her J.D. from the University of Maine School of Law in 1998 and her A.B. from Bowdoin College in 1995.<br><br><strong>Breon S. Peace, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Eastern District of New York</strong><br><br>Breon S. Peace has been a partner at Cleary Gottlieb Steen &amp; Hamilton LLP in New York since 2007, and previously worked as an associate at the firm from 1996 to 1997, 1998 to 1999, and from 2003 to 2007. He was an Acting Assistant Professor of Clinical Law at New York University School of Law from 2002 to 2003. Mr. Peace previously served as an Assistant United States Attorney in the United States Attorney’s Office for the Eastern District of New York from 2000 to 2002. Pearce served as a law clerk for Judge Sterling Johnson, Jr. on the United States District Court for the Eastern District of New York from 1997 to 1998.<br><br>Mr. Peace received his J.D. from New York University School of Law in 1996 and his B.A. from the University of California, Berkeley in 1993.<br><br><strong>William S. Thompson, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Southern District of West Virginia</strong><br><br>Judge William S. Thompson is a judge for the 25th Judicial Circuit of West Virginia. He was appointed to that position in 2007 and re-elected in 2008 and 2016. As a part of his duties, Judge Thompson presides over several treatment courts, including the first family treatment court in West Virginia. Prior to his appointment, he was an associate at the law firm of Cook and Cook in Madison, West Virginia from 1995 to 2007. His primary focus was litigation, which included representing several hundred indigent clients in criminal defense and other matters. Judge Thompson also served as President of Madison Healthcare, Incorporated from 1997 to 2007, and as Vice President of Danville Lumber Company from 1994 to 2007.<br><br>Judge Thompson received his J.D. from West Virginia University in 1995 and his B.S. from West Virginia University in 1992.<br><br><strong>Damian Williams, U.S. Attorney nominee for the Southern District of New York</strong><br><br>Damian Williams is an Assistant United States Attorney for the United States Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of New York, where he has served since 2012. He has served as a Chief of the Securities and Commodities Fraud Task Force for the office since 2018. From 2009 to 2012, he was a litigation associate at Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton &amp; Garrison LLP. Mr. Williams served as a law clerk for Justice John Paul Stevens on the United States Supreme Court from 2008 to 2009 and Judge Merrick B. Garland on the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit from 2007 to 2008.<br><br>Mr. Williams received a J.D. from Yale Law School in 2007, a M.Phil. in International Relations from the University of Cambridge in 2003, and an A.B. in Economics from Harvard University in 2002.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Senate Passage of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/08/10/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-senate-passage-of-the-bipartisan-infrastructure-investment-and-jobs-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26767</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 3:10 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, thank you, Madam Vice President. First of all, I want to thank the group of senators &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; for doing what they told me they would do.&#160; The death of this legislation was mildly premature, as reported.&#160; They said they were willing to work&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>3:10 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you, Madam Vice President.<br><br>First of all, I want to thank the group of senators &#8212; Democrats and Republicans &#8212; for doing what they told me they would do.&nbsp; The death of this legislation was mildly premature, as reported.&nbsp; They said they were willing to work in a bipartisan manner, and I want to thank them for keeping their word.&nbsp; That’s just what they did.&nbsp;<br><br>After years and years and years of “Infrastructure Week,” we’re on the cusp of an infrastructure decade that I truly believe will transform America.<br><br>As you all know, just a short while ago the United States Senate passed the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act &#8212; the very legislation I ran on when I announced my candidacy for the nomination for President &#8212; a historic investment in the nation’s roads and highways, bridges and transit; in our drinking water systems; in broadband, clean energy, environmental clean-up; and making infrastructure more resilient and the climate crisis much more in our minds as to how do we deal with it.<br><br>You know, we&#8217;re poised once again &#8212; and I mean this in a literal sense &#8212; to make the same kind of historic investments that have so often made possible &#8212; made it possible for America to build the future and allow us to outcompete the rest of the world.<br><br>From building the Erie Canal in the early 1800s &#8212; a bipartisan effort; to the Transcontinental Railroad, to construction &#8212; that was constructed during the Civil War; to Dwight Eisenhower’s Interstate Highway System in the 1950s &#8212; the investments that literally connected our entire nation and fundamentally changed the pattern of life in America. &nbsp;<br><br>To the public investments that took us to the Moon, and the discovery of lifesaving medicines and vaccines, and gave us the Internet &#8212; America has often had the greatest prosperity and made the most progress when we invest in America itself.<br><br>And that’s what this infrastructure bill does with overwhelming support from the United States Senate &#8212; 69 votes in the Senate &#8212; a vote margin bigger than when the Interstate Highway System passed in the Senate in 1956.<br><br>It makes key investments that will, one, create millions of good union jobs all across the country in cities, small towns, rural and Tribal communities.<br><br>America &#8212; America, this is how we truly Build Back Better.&nbsp;<br><br>This bill is going to put people to work modernizing our roads and our highways and our bridges so commuters and truckers don’t lose time in traffic, saving billions of dollars nationally.<br><br>Today, up to 10 million homes in America and more than 400,000 schools and schools &#8212; and childcare centers have pipes with lead in them, including for drinking water.&nbsp; This is a clear and present danger to the health of America, particularly to our children’s health.&nbsp;<br><br>This bill is going to put plumbers and pipefitters to work replacing all of the nation’s lead pipes so every child, every American can turn on a faucet at home or in school and know they&#8217;re drinking clean water.<br><br>During remote learning in the &#8212; during the pandemic last year, we saw too many families forced to sit &#8212; literally sit &#8212; in their vehicles in a fast food parking lot so their children could get on the Internet they couldn’t afford and didn’t have access to at home.&nbsp; This bill will deliver affordable, high-speed Internet to every American &#8212; a necessity for the 21st century.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ll also see in the last &#8212; we’ve seen in the last couple of years the damage done in Texas and other places when transmission lines carrying power were taken down by extreme and unanticipated weather, leaving millions of folks without electricity for weeks and weeks, and costing our economy billions and billions of dollars.&nbsp; This bill provides upgrades to our power grid so that more secure and resilient and cleaner energy can be transferred across those wires.<br><br>Down in New Orleans, I met with the incredible women and men who are in charge of the water system, some of it running on technology that is literally 100 years old.&nbsp; This bill is going to provide opportunities to upgrade their system.&nbsp;<br><br>It also allows American workers to strengthen our national &#8212; our natural infrastructure, like our levees.&nbsp; These are at risk of catastrophic collapse in the face of extreme weather like superstorms, wildfires, droughts, hurricanes, and heat waves.<br><br>Last week, I stood &#8212; and many of you were with me &#8212; on the South Lawn of the White House with the United Auto Workers and the leaders from the Big Three automobile companies in America, surrounded by iconic American vehicles that will all be electric and made right here in America in the not-too-distant future.<br><br>This bill is also going to put IBEW workers &#8212; electrical workers &#8212; to work installing a truly national network of electric vehicle charging stations that will transform the way we travel and move commerce.&nbsp;<br><br>And, by the way, around those charging stations, you&#8217;ll see &#8212; just like around &#8212; we put in gas stations in our state highways &#8212; you&#8217;ll see other industries build up.&nbsp; We have the benefit of significantly reducing pollution from vehicles on our roads.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, this bill, I believe, will make the most important investment in public transit in American history.<br><br>When I went to Philadelphia not too long ago for Amtrak’s 50th anniversary, I was proud to be able to say that this bill was in the works and that it would be the most important investment in rail since the creation of Amtrak itself.&nbsp; This bill will upgrade railroad tracks so people can get to work and their destinations faster, and it will build new lines to get people to more places faster &#8212; reducing, I might add, pollution, as well.<br><br>And here’s another critical part of the bill: 90 percent of the jobs created don’t require a college degree.&nbsp; You&#8217;re tired of hearing me saying it, I know, but this is a blue-collar blueprint to rebuild America.&nbsp;<br><br>We’re going to do all of this by keeping my commitment.&nbsp; We will not raise taxes by one cent on people making less than $400,000 a year.<br><br>Everyone from union to business leaders to economists &#8211;left, right, and center &#8212; believe the public investments contained in this bill will generate more jobs, higher productivity, higher growth for our economy over the long term.<br><br>Forecasters on Wall Street project that over the next 10 years our economy will expand by trillions of dollars, and it will create an additional 2 million jobs a year beyond what was already projected &#8212; good-paying jobs all around the country.&nbsp;<br><br>Experts believe that the majority of the bill’s benefits will flow to working families: faster commutes, cleaner water, less expense, available and affordable Internet &#8212; these are the things that working families needs &#8212; that they need.<br><br>As last week’s jobs report shows, our economy is recovering at a record rate &#8212; 934,000 new jobs created in July.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to go up and down, but 4 million jobs created since I took office.<br><br>This bill is going to help make a historic recovery a long-term boom.<br><br>Folks, above all, this historic investment in infrastructure is what I believe you, the American people, want &#8212; what you’ve been asking for for a long, long time. &nbsp;This bill shows that we can work together.<br><br>I know a lot of people &#8212; some sitting in the audience here &#8212; didn’t think this could happen.&nbsp; This bill was declared dead more often than &#8212; anyway.&nbsp; That bipartisanship was a thing of the past.&nbsp; From the time I announced my candidacy (inaudible) bringing the country together and doing things in a bipartisan way, it was characterized as a relic of an &#8212; an earlier age.&nbsp;<br><br>As you may well remember, I never believed that.&nbsp; I still don’t.<br><br>So, I want to thank those senators who worked so hard to bring this agreement together.&nbsp; I know it wasn’t easy.<br><br>For the Republicans who supported this bill, you showed a lot of courage.&nbsp; And I want to personally thank you for that, and I’ve called most of you on the phone to do just that.<br><br>You have &#8212; and no doubt, you will –- disagree with me on many issues.&nbsp; But where we can agree, we should.&nbsp; And here, on this bill, we proved that we can still come together to do big things, important things for the American people.<br><br>For the Democrats who supported this bill, we can be proud of these unprecedented investments that are going to transform this nation and change millions of lives for the better.<br><br>Think about what’s going to happen, in a practical sense.&nbsp; Clogged arteries at the heart of our economy &#8212; they’re going to be opened up.&nbsp; That will reduce transportation costs, reduce commuting costs, and, as a result, reduce costs overall for families and businesses.<br><br>And there’s safety provisions being &#8212; as I said not long ago, everyone can tell you what the most dangerous intersections in their communities are.&nbsp; There’s money in there to deal with those pac- &#8212; those specific needs.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thousands of bridges will be safer and more accessible.<br><br>And, by the way, as you’ve heard me say before, some bridges are so weak that they couldn’t have a firetruck go across it &#8212; requiring the fire department to go 10, 12 miles out of the way to get just, literally, a mile away to put out a fire.<br><br>Millions of lead pipes carrying drinking water to our homes and schools and daycare centers &#8212; they’re finally going to rep- &#8212; be replaced.&nbsp; Never again can we allow what happened in Flint, Michigan; and Jackson, Mississippi.&nbsp; Can never let it happen again.<br><br>High-speed Internet &#8212; going to be available and affordable everywhere, to everyone, so farmers nationwide can get the brest [sic] prices for their products at home and abroad by knowing when to sell, and children in Chicago or Philadelphia never have to again sit in a McDonald&#8217;s parking lot to do their homework.<br><br>This is transformational.&nbsp; I know compromise is hard for both sides, but it’s important &#8212; it’s important, it’s necessary &#8212; for a democracy to be able to function.<br><br>So, I want to thank everyone on both sides of the aisle for supporting this bill.&nbsp; Today, we proved that democracy can still work.&nbsp; A lot more work to do.<br><br>But I want to thank the Republican &#8212; Senate Republican Leader Mitch McConnell for supporting this bill.<br><br>And I want to give special thanks to Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer.&nbsp; Your leadership, Chuck, in the Senate was masterful.<br><br>But, look, let’s be clear: The work is far from done.&nbsp; The bill now has to go the House of Representatives, where I look forward to winning its approval.&nbsp;<br><br>And we have to get to work on the next critical piece of my agenda &#8212; my Build Back Better plan &#8212; making housing more affordable &#8212; it’s so unaffordable to so many Americans; providing clean energy tax cuts, including homeowners to make energy efficiency improvements in their homes; bringing down the cost of prescription drugs; making eldercare more affordable; and continuing to give middle-class families with children a tax break &#8212; a tax cut &#8212; the one they’re receiving now &#8212; well-deserved childcare and healthcare that gives them just a little bit of breathing room.<br><br>This is a plan that invests in the American people &#8212; in their future and their success.&nbsp; And it will be paid for by having the largest corporations &#8212; including 55 of them who didn’t pay a single penny in federal income tax &#8212; and the super-wealthy to begin to pay their fair share.&nbsp;<br><br>I want you to be able to be millionaires and corporations to do incredibly well, but this isn’t going to change anything for you.&nbsp; You’ll still have your three homes.&nbsp; You’ll still have whatever you need.&nbsp; And corporations will continue to do well.<br><br>I’ll have more to say about this later as the Senate continues its work.&nbsp; But today, I’m happy to mark this significant milestone on the road toward making what we all know are long-overdue, much-needed investments in basic, hard infrastructure of this nation.<br><br>I truly believe that this bill proves the voice of the people will be heard and that we can all come together to make a difference in people’s lives.&nbsp; As you heard me say it before and I apologize for repeating it, but there are no Republican bridges or Democratic roads.<br><br>This is a moment that lives beyond the headlines, beyond partisan soundbites, beyond the culture of instant outrage,<br>disinformation, and conflict-as-entertainment.<br><br>This is about us doing the real, hard work of governing.&nbsp; This is about democracy delivering for the people.&nbsp; This is about winning the future.&nbsp; It’s about doing our job.&nbsp; This is about building an economy from the bottom up and the middle out, giving everyone a decent chance at a decent life.<br><br>And by the way, when the bottom and middle do well, the wealthy do very, very well.&nbsp; Nobody, nobody, nobody gets hurt.&nbsp;<br>This is what I call governing and government doing its job &#8212; ensuring everybody is better off.<br><br>As I’ve said many times and I’ll say it again today: We are the United States of America.&nbsp; And there is nothing &#8212; nothing –- we can’t do if we do it together.<br><br>So, thank you.&nbsp; God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.<br><br>Darlene at AP.&nbsp; Darlene, AP.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes, thank you.&nbsp; What is your reaction to Governor Cuomo&#8217;s &#8212; his announcement that he is stepping down?&nbsp; You called on him to resign.&nbsp; Did you think he would?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I respect the governor&#8217;s decision and &#8212; I respect the decision he made.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how concerned are you right now about children in schools, given that 94 percent of children, many of them unable to get vaccinated because they&#8217;re too young, have now tested positive?&nbsp; What are your concerns, and how concerned are you that schools will not be able to stay open as you&#8217;ve asked for?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; My concerns are deep and I&#8217;m very concerned, and we all know why.<br><br>Look, I understand that there are millions of people who decided &#8212; adults &#8212; who decided not to get vaccinated.&nbsp; And I understand that to badger those folks is not likely to get them to move and get vaccinated.&nbsp; But I also understand that the reason children are becoming infected is because, in most cases, they live in low-vaccination-rate states and communities, and they&#8217;re getting it from unvaccinated adults.&nbsp; That is what is happening.&nbsp;<br><br>And so, my plea is that for those who are not vaccinated: Think about it.&nbsp; God willing, the FDA is going to be coming out in a reasonable timeframe to say this vaccine is totally safe.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen millions of doses around the world &#8212; a billion doses already &#8212; and we know how it&#8217;s transmitted.&nbsp;<br><br>And one of the things that I find a little disingenuous: When I suggest that people in zones where there is a high risk wear the masks like you all are doing, I&#8217;m told that government should get out of the way and not do that; they don’t have the authority to do that.&nbsp;<br><br>And I find it interesting that some of the very people who are saying that, who hold government positions, are people who are threatening that if a schoolteacher asks a student if they&#8217;ve been vaccinated, or if a principal says that, &#8220;Everyone in my school should wear a mask,&#8221; or the schoolboard votes for it, that governor will nullify that. &nbsp;That governor has the authority to say, &#8220;You can&#8217;t do that.&#8221; &nbsp;I find that totally counterintuitive and, quite frankly, disingenuous.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have presidential powers to intervene in states like Texas and Florida where they are banning mask mandates?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t believe that I do thus far.&nbsp; We&#8217;re checking that.&nbsp; We &#8212; but there are on &#8212; federal workforce, I can.<br><br>And I think that people should understand, seeing little kids &#8212; I mean, four, five, six years old &#8212; in hospitals, on ventilators, and some of them passing &#8212; not many, but some of them passing &#8212; it&#8217;s almost, I mean, it&#8217;s just &#8212; well, I should not characterize beyond that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Andrew Cuomo, his resignation: What impact &#8212; as the head of the Party, what impact does his resignation have on the Democratic Party?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I think the impact is all on Andrew Cuomo and his decision to make that judgement, and I respect his decision.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sir, on Afghanistan: In just the last few days, multiple cities in Afghanistan have fallen to the Taliban. There&#8217;s irrefutable evidence that a vast majority of those Afghan forces cannot hold ground there.&nbsp; Has your current plan to withdraw U.S. troops changed at all?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; Look, we spent over a trillion dollars over 20 years.&nbsp; We trained and equipped with modern equipment over 300,000 Afghan forces.&nbsp; And Afghan leaders have to come together.&nbsp; We lost thousands &#8212; lost to death and injury &#8212; thousands of American personnel.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve got to fight for themselves, fight for their nation.<br><br>The United States &#8212; I&#8217;ll insist we continue to keep the commitments we made of providing close air support, making sure that their air force functions and is operable, re- &#8212; resupplying their forces with food and equipment, and paying all their salaries.&nbsp; But they&#8217;ve got to want to fight.&nbsp; They have outnumbered the Taliban.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;m getting daily briefings.&nbsp; I think there&#8217;s still a possibility &#8212; you have a significant new Secretary of Defense &#8212; our equivalent of a Secretary of Defense in Afghanistan, Bismillah Khan, who is a serious fighter.&nbsp;<br><br>I think they&#8217;re beginning to realize they&#8217;ve got to come together politically at the top and &#8212; but we&#8217;re going to continue to keep our commitment.&nbsp; But I do not regret my decision.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; To this side.&nbsp; Yes, ma&#8217;am.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, on the issue of the infrastructure bill and the work that you have ahead of you now, are you concerned that you &#8212; are you confident that you have the support of all the Democrats on board to get this $3.5 trillion package through?&nbsp; I keep asking you that.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know you do.&nbsp; As my mother would say, &#8220;God love you, dear.&#8221;<br><br>Look, I have, as I said &#8212; and I&#8217;m not referring to you, in particular, just overall.&nbsp; I was going over some of the quotes from the moment that I got elected how my plan was &#8220;dead.&#8221;&nbsp; This is the exact same plan I ran on.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;ll see.&nbsp; I continue to be an optimist.&nbsp; As I told you, I was once referred to by a doctor as a &#8220;congenital optimist.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>I think that we can get a significant portion of the &#8212; if not all &#8212; of the reconciliation bill, the budget &#8212; they&#8217;re doing &#8212; they&#8217;re having the vote-a-thon now.<br><br>I think, over the next month, which is the way it&#8217;s going to work, they vote on all of these amendments, and then they get to the business of seeing how they can make it work, and then come back &#8212; I know you understand this well, but the public wonders what we&#8217;re talking about sometimes &#8212; and decide exactly what&#8217;s in that reconciliation bill and how much is going to be spent.<br><br>I think we will get enough Democrats to vote for it, and I think that the House will eventually put two bills on my desk: one on infrastructure, and one on reconciliation.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212; thank you so much, Mr. President.&nbsp; Just sort of turning to the Delta &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, sorry.&nbsp; Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just turning to the Delta variant for a moment, I wanted to see if, in retrospect, you think your administration put enough mitigation measures in place early enough, and whether or not you should&#8217;ve, perhaps, heeded some of the lessons from other countries that had data as early as May and June about how the variant spread?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, we knew how the variant spread, and we know the vaccines prevent the spread.&nbsp; So &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; it&#8217;s like &#8212; you know, a lot of countries didn’t have the vaccines we were able to put together to make sure every single American &#8212; we have over 300 million dos- &#8212; 600 million doses of vaccine for Americans.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve exported over a half a billion &#8212; we will over a half a billion.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we knew &#8212; what is disappointing is that more people were not willing to take the vaccine.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve done everything in our power &#8212; well, I shouldn&#8217;t say &#8212; there&#8217;s probably more &#8212; we will do more.&nbsp; But we continue to try to make the case to the American people who haven&#8217;t taken the vaccine that it&#8217;s in your interest, can save your life, and can fundamentally impact on the lives of your children or people you love.&nbsp;<br><br>Now, one of the things that&#8217;s happening, as bad as things have gotten, the death rate is one fiftieth &#8212; or, I don&#8217;t &#8212; don&#8217;t hold me to the number, but significantly, significantly lower than when the &#8212; when I inherited this job &#8212; inherited the job &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; when I inherited the &#8212; the coronavirus pandemic when I first got elected.&nbsp;<br><br>So, the thing that I &#8212; I continue to hope that people will overcome their fears because their fears are based on &#8212; some are just as a political statement, but very few.&nbsp; I think most people are worried.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m hoping that the FDA will say that we permanently approve of these vaccines, because we have enough for everyone.&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;m hoping that, as people realize &#8212; and it is picking up.&nbsp; Vaccines are picking up, but not at the rate they were before.&nbsp;<br><br>Remember, I was setting up, you know, stadiums &#8212; sports stadiums, and we were doing thousands of vaccines a day.&nbsp; And I wish I could have thought of something beyond what we&#8217;ve thought of that would make everybody want to get the vaccine, but that hadn&#8217;t been the case.<br><br>Now, at a federal level, what I&#8217;m going to be doing is more &#8212; is making sure that they understand that I do have authority to say, &#8220;If you&#8217;re going to come into this building &#8212; into a federal building that you have to have been vaccinated or show that, or be wearing a mask.&#8221;&nbsp;<br><br>And I think that I&#8217;m going to use &#8212; and I anticipate that it&#8217;s probable that the Defense Department will &#8212; as they put in place all the mechanisms needed to be able to, in fact, impose or initiate a mandate for all the regular forces and reserves to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>But I continue to be hopeful.&nbsp; You see, I had a long talk &#8212; not a long &#8212; I had a talk with Governor Asa Hutchin- &#8212; Asa Hutchinson, who said he made a mistake.&nbsp; And he is working really hard, going around.&nbsp; And he told me that he&#8217;s doing a lot of town meetings &#8212; not all of which are being embraced, but he&#8217;s making the case.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to continue to make the case.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; If I may, ironically, one of the &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, I do have a question.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; one of the Democrats, through the years, that you spoke with about infrastructure the most was Andrew Cuomo, who is resigning &#8212; who announced he&#8217;s resigning today.&nbsp; You had traveled New York with him when you were Vice President to the launch of the reconstruction on LaGuardia.&nbsp; He was someone who supported your campaign early on.&nbsp;<br><br>I know you called on him to resign.&nbsp; I know you condemned the alleged behavior.&nbsp; But you&#8217;re someone who spends a lot of time with mayors and governors.&nbsp; How would you assess his 10 and a half years as governor of the state?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; In terms of his personal behavior, or what he&#8217;s done as a governor?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What he&#8217;s done as a governor.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, he&#8217;s done a hell of job.&nbsp; I thought he&#8217;s done a hell of a job.&nbsp; And, I mean, both on &#8212; everything from access to voting, to infrastructure, to a whole range of things.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why it&#8217;s so sad.<br><br>Okay.&nbsp; Last question.&nbsp; Right here.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Mr. President, I have a question about the significance of the bipartisan nature of the infrastructure agreement.&nbsp; Are there lessons learned from that agreement that can be applied to voting reform, police reform, or LGBTQ civil rights?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; By you guys or by me?&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; By anyone.&nbsp; By &#8212; and &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I shouldn&#8217;t kid, because I was just reading about 50 statements from very serious press people about how I &#8212; my whole plan was &#8220;dead&#8221; from the beginning.&nbsp;<br><br>Look, the lesson learned is being willing to talk and listen.&nbsp; Listen.&nbsp; Call people in.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no, let me finish it.&nbsp; And I think the lesson learned is exposing people to other views.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s why, from the beginning, on all the subjects you raised, I&#8217;ve sat with people and listened to their positions, some in agreement with where I am and some disagreement.&nbsp; And so, I think it&#8217;s a matter of listening.&nbsp; It&#8217;s part of democracy.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all so very much.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Why have you not named an FDA commissioner, sir, to this point?&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, should Andrew Cuomo resign immediately?&nbsp; He&#8217;s leaving in 14 days.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to comment anymore on Andrew Cuomo.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the FDA, you haven&#8217;t &#8212; you haven&#8217;t named an FDA commissioner.&nbsp; Why have you not yet named an FDA commissioner, sir?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Say again.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You haven&#8217;t named an FDA commissioner yet.&nbsp; I was wondering why you haven&#8217;t found or named a permanent FDA commissioner yet.<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We&#8217;re working on that very hard to make sure we can get it passed.<br><br>Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question for you on infrastructure, but &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Would you like to see &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; can I quickly follow up on your &#8212; your comment on Governor Cuomo?&nbsp; Can you really say that he has done a, quote, &#8220;hell of a job&#8221; if he&#8217;s accused of sexually harassing women &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Now, look, you asked two different questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; on the job?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I asked the substantive &#8220;Should he remain as governor&#8221; as one question.&nbsp;<br><br>And women should be believed when they make accusations that are able to &#8212; on the face of them, makes sense &#8212; and investigated &#8212; they&#8217;re investigated and the judgement was made and what they said was correct.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one thing.<br><br>The question is, &#8220;Did he do a good job on infrastructure?&#8221;&nbsp; That was the question.&nbsp; He did.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, the question was, &#8220;How did he do as a governor?&#8221;&nbsp; He was accused of &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, the question was &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; sexually harassing women.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Correct me if I&#8217;m wrong.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; About &#8212; about how was he as a governor, generally &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, as a governor, generally, obviously &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; outside of his personal behavior.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Outside of his personal behavior.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But can you separate the two since he was (inaudible) &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m not.&nbsp; I was asked a specific question.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, how &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I&#8217;m trying to answer it specifically.&nbsp; What do you want to ask me, specifically?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;d like to ask you about infrastructure as well.&nbsp; Given that you have said this is such an urgent bill that needs to be passed, why not have the House take it up immediately for a vote?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; We&#8217;ll get it done.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll get both.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>3:40 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Lowers Health Care&#160;Costs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-lowers-health-care-costs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 22:07:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris Outlines How Build Back Better Lowers Health Care Costs, Announces 2.5 Million Americans Signed Up for Health Insurance Ahead of Aug. 15 Deadline Like President Biden, Vice President Harris believes that health care is a right, not a privilege. Together, they promised to ensure that every American has access to quality, affordable&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris Outlines How Build Back Better Lowers Health Care Costs, Announces 2.5 Million Americans Signed Up for Health Insurance Ahead of Aug. 15 Deadline</em></p>



<p><br>Like President Biden, Vice President Harris believes that health care is a right, not a privilege. Together, they promised to ensure that every American has access to quality, affordable health care and the peace of mind that health insurance brings.&nbsp; As part of that promise, just weeks after taking office, the Biden-Harris Administration opened a special enrollment period through HealthCare.gov to provide all Americans the opportunity to sign up for health insurance.<br><br>Today, during an event at Unity Health Care’s Brentwood Health Center in Washington D.C., Vice President Harris is announcing that 2.5 million people have newly signed up for health insurance during the 2021 Special Enrollment Period as she delivers remarks on how the Build Back Better Agenda will lower health care costs for Americans.&nbsp; That is millions more people who can now rest easy knowing they are covered, and who join the <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=d315d409ab&amp;e=60572324a0">over 30 million people</a> who have health coverage through the Affordable Care Act (ACA). With six days left in the Special Enrollment Period, Vice President Harris encourages all Americans who need access to quality, affordable health insurance to visit <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=bcfdacc4d4&amp;e=60572324a0">HealthCare.gov</a> to sign up for coverage before the August 15 deadline.<br><br>Health insurance is now more affordable than ever thanks to the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; Because of the law’s enhanced tax credits, nine million Americans who buy their coverage through the Affordable Care Act have lower premiums, saving families an average of $40 per person per month — that’s nearly $2,000 per year for a typical family of four.&nbsp; Since April 1, <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=8fbc2a4971&amp;e=60572324a0">over one-third of</a> new and returning HealthCare.gov customers have found a quality plan with a premium of $10 or less per month, and returning HealthCare.gov consumers have seen their premiums drop, on average, <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=b3ac929e08&amp;e=60572324a0">by 40 percent.</a><br><br>This success is why it is so critical to pass the Build Back Better Agenda through budget reconciliation: to ensure that Americans can continue to take advantage of these savings.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Reducing Health Care Costs.</strong></li></ul>



<p>The Build Back Better Agenda will extend the enhanced tax credits that lower premiums. Those lower costs helped drive more than 2.5 million people to enroll in coverage since the beginning of this Administration.&nbsp; Extending these lower premiums will allow <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=e2953fed6c&amp;e=60572324a0">nine million</a>&nbsp;people to continue to save hundreds of dollars per year on their premiums, and&nbsp;<a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=056fb4cf92&amp;e=60572324a0">four million</a>&nbsp;uninsured people will gain coverage.&nbsp; At a time when health care costs are too high, extending enhanced ACA tax credits is critically important to families.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Passing the Build Back Better Agenda Is Urgent.</strong></li></ul>



<p>The premium reductions in the American Rescue Plan have provided a critical lifeline for millions of people and buoyed our work to enroll consumers to date.&nbsp; We cannot let this critical assistance come to an end.&nbsp; If it expires, millions of Americans will see their premiums increase. On average, premiums would nearly double, and some Americans (particularly those in the their 50s and 60s), could see their premiums increase by thousands of dollars per year.&nbsp; That’s just not right; Americans should be able to continue to count on the lower premiums available today.&nbsp;<br><br>President Biden and Vice President Harris are committed to building on this progress through the Build Back Better Agenda, which will expand on these efforts and make health care more accessible and affordable.&nbsp; Specifically, the President’s Build Back Better Agenda includes:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Medicare Coverage.</strong>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Medicare today doesn’t cover dental, vision, or hearing services, with very limited exceptions.  Many beneficiaries have to pay out of pocket, often costing them thousands of dollars per year. Americans who can’t afford that are forced to go without these critical services instead. That’s why it’s critical we add comprehensive dental, vision, and hearing services to Medicare, so that all beneficiaries will have affordable access to these vital health services.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Lowering Prescription Drug Costs.</strong></li></ul>



<p>For every other type of health care service, Medicare works to get the best prices for American seniors. But for prescription drugs – and only prescription drugs – Medicare is prohibited by law from negotiating for the best deal. Medicare should be able to negotiate the prices it pays for prescription drugs, and drug companies that raise their prices faster than inflation should have to pay a penalty.&nbsp; We must also cap the amount that Medicare beneficiaries have to pay out-of-pocket for drugs each year, so that seniors with expensive drugs can still make ends meet.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Closing the Medicaid Coverage Gap.</strong></li></ul>



<p>The Affordable Care Act created new pathways to health coverage by expanding Medicaid. Yet, <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=0ae7f75ebacfaef55ba39fcdb&amp;id=5851324a81&amp;e=60572324a0">nearly 4 million people</a> can’t get covered because they live in states that refuse to expand Medicaid. The Biden-Harris Administration believes people deserve to have the peace of mind that health insurance brings, which is why we must close the Medicaid gap by providing federally-administered coverage for people in states that refuse to expand, and therefore can’t get covered through no fault of their own.<br><br>The Biden-Harris Administration continues to do everything we can to make high quality health care more affordable and accessible. By lowering health care costs, expanding access to coverage, and enabling Medicare to negotiate prescription drugs, Congress can do its part to bring down costs and secure the health and financial security of the American people.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki, August 10,&#160;2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/08/10/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-august-10-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26737</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:50 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Happy Tuesday.&#160; Okay.&#160;Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Happy Tuesday.&#160;MS. PSAKI:&#160; Happy Tuesday.&#160; That&#8217;s quite a sign over there.&#160;Okay, a couple of items for all of you at the top.&#160; President Biden promised to reach across the aisle and deliver results for families across the country.&#160; And, today,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:50 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Happy Tuesday.&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Happy Tuesday.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Happy Tuesday.&nbsp; That&#8217;s quite a sign over there.<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, a couple of items for all of you at the top.&nbsp; President Biden promised to reach across the aisle and deliver results for families across the country.&nbsp; And, today, on the President&#8217;s 203rd day in office &#8212; in case all of you weren&#8217;t counting &#8212; 19 Republican senators joined the Democratic Caucus to pass historic infrastructure legislation.<br>&nbsp;<br>The most important piece of this to the President is not the bipartisan piece &#8212; which, of course, he is pleased to see the opportunity to work with Democrats and Republicans &#8212; but that this will deliver huge benefits, millions of jobs to the American people.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It will deliver clean drinking water and high-speed Internet to every household in the country.&nbsp; It will help us tackle the climate crisis by electrifying school buses, building electric vehicle chargers across the station, upgrade our power infrastructure to be resilient against national &#8212; natural disasters.&nbsp; And it will rebuild roads and bridges, and modernize American&#8217;s &#8212; America&#8217;s airports, rail, and public transit systems &#8212; something that even our Secretary of State talked about yesterday, in terms of its benefits to our competitiveness around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>And this inter- &#8212; this legislation will create benefits in communities across the country for decades to come.&nbsp; So we are pleased to see the progress, looking forward to the next step.<br>&nbsp;<br>Also wanted to note for all of you that as a part of our ongoing efforts to boost vaccinations, meet people where they are with information about the vaccines, today, Dr. Fauci is doing five Q&amp;A conversations on Instagram and TikTok with Millennial mom influencers and Gen Z influencers.<br>&nbsp;<br>Throughout the month of August, Dr. Fauci will do weekly conversations and questions with notable influencers that aim to reach specific audiences we are looking to boost vaccinations with, alongside many of the other specific efforts we are already doing, including amplifying local Black doctors across the country in local media interviews, and partnerships with PTA organizations and doctors to incorporate vaccination information into sports physicals.&nbsp; So, continuing to take a range of steps.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, since we didn’t do a briefing yesterday, I wanted to take a quick second and address the IPCC from yesterday &#8212; the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change report that came out.&nbsp; What the IPCC told us is what President Biden has believed all along: Climate change is an urgent threat that requires bold action.<br>&nbsp;<br>Since his first day in office, President Biden has taken unprecedented, bold, and swift action to tackle the climate crisis: He rejoined the Paris Climate Agreement on day one, restoring leadership at home and on the world stage.<br>&nbsp;<br>He &#8212; the United States hosted a first-ever U.S. Global Climate Summit for 40 world leaders to encourage strong and ambitious commitments to reduce their emissions.<br>&nbsp;<br>We committed to bold, ambitious climate goals, including reducing emissions from 2005 levels by 50 to 52 percent in 2030, producing 100 percent clean electric vehicles by 20- &#8212; clean electricity by 2035 and reaching net-zero emissions economy-wide by 2050.<br>&nbsp;<br>And just last week, the President announced steps to drive American leadership forward on clean cars and trucks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally &#8212; it doesn’t stop there &#8212; obviously, a step forward with the bipartisan infrastructure deal today.&nbsp; And his Build Back Better agenda will set America on the path towards clean energy, clean cars, clean buildings, and cleaner &#8212; and cleaner industry &#8212; all in a way that will grow our economy, create jobs, and enhance America&#8217;s competitiveness.<br> <br>Darlene.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On the other news of the day, what is the President&#8217;s reaction to Governor Cuomo stepping down?&nbsp; And did anyone in the White House reach out to the governor and sort of nudge him to leave office?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Well, first, let me say, the President made clear his views last week, and those stand. &nbsp;He &#8212; our view is that this is a story about these courageous women who came forward, told their stories, shared their stories, and the &#8212; an investigation &#8212; overseen by the Attorney General, that, of course, concluded today &#8212; and an outcome that the President called for just last week.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know a number of you have asked whether the President has talked to the Attorney General since this report came out.&nbsp; The answer is no.&nbsp; Whether we had a heads up on this announcement today, the answer is no.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said the &#8220;Attorney General&#8221; &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry.&nbsp; The &#8212; the governor.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; And thank you for that clarification.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Any plans for the President to now reach out to talk to the governor now that he has announced that he&#8217;s going to step down?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No plans that I&#8217;m aware of, no.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How ticked is the White House that he chose today &#8212; Infrastructure Day &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; to make the announcement?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Darlene, what I can assure you of is that the American people across the country who are commuting back and forth to work, driving their kids to camp, worried about whether their kids have access to clean drinking water, focused on whether schools are going to have the resources they need, are most focused on the fact that 69 members of the Senate &#8212; 19 Republicans &#8212; joined the Democratic Caucus to take an important step forward.&nbsp; That&#8217;s my bet, in terms of what people are talking about at home.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On Afghanistan, we&#8217;re still a few weeks away from the President&#8217;s initial deadline to withdraw all U.S. troops from the country.&nbsp; We&#8217;re now seeing so many cities fall to the Taliban.&nbsp; Is the President frustrated by this at all?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President &#8212; there are difficult choices every Commander-in-Chief has to make on behalf of the American people.&nbsp; And President Biden was very clear when he delivered his speech in May announcing his decision that, after 20 years at war, it&#8217;s time for American troops to get home.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would also note and just harken back to some of the points he made when he made that speech that were the drivers for his decision.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We went to Afghanistan to deliver justice to those who attacked us on September 11th, to disrupt terrorists seeking to use Afghanistan as a safe haven to attack the United States.&nbsp; We achieved those objectives some years ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>We judge the threat now against our homeland, which is his responsibility as Commander-in-Chief to focus on, as being one where the threat emanates from outside of Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So &#8212; and the President also, at the time &#8212; just to go back to your original question &#8212; he asked for a clear assessment, for a review from his team on what the possible implications could be.&nbsp; He asked them not to sugarcoat that.&nbsp; He asked them to lay out specifically and clearly what the consequences could be.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll also note that we have provided a great deal and a range of assistance to the Afghan National Security Defense Forces, and also proposed a significant amount of funding in the FY 2022 budget request for $3.3 billion for the Afghan Security Forces.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we &#8212; he made a decision as Commander-in-Chief.&nbsp; Those are difficult decisions to make.&nbsp; He did it because, after 20 years at war, it&#8217;s time to bring our troops &#8212; our men and women &#8212; home.&nbsp; And we will continue to be partners and supporters of their efforts on the ground.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With that assistance, (inaudible) overestimate at all the Afghans&#8217; ability to hold off the Taliban, though?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, ultimately &#8212; there have been assessments by members of the intelligence committee, members of our national security team that have been made public.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re the appropriate entities to, of course, make those assessments.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But ultimately, our view is that the Afghan National Security Defense Forces has the equipment, numbers, and training to fight back, which will strengthen their position at the negotiating table.<br>&nbsp;<br>We believe there&#8217;s a political process &#8212; that&#8217;s the only process that will successfully bring peace and stability to Afghanistan.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; One more on the vaccine &#8212; sorry.&nbsp; Secretary Austin says that he will make the request of the President&#8217;s &#8212; of &#8212; request for the President to approve a waiver for the vaccine to be mandatory in the military no later than mid-September, unless the FDA approves the vaccine before then.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But given that the consensus is that the vaccines are safe and effective, why not move forward with that waiver right away?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, the President and Secretary agree &#8212; and they have agreed &#8212; that making sure our military is safe and prepared is &#8212; is of utmost importance.&nbsp; And given the size and scale and geographic dispersal of the Department of Defense&#8217;s workforce, it was determined that DOD would need some time to develop an implementation plan.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;re talking about with the September 15th timeline to make sure it&#8217;s most feasible for fully vaccinating their personnel.&nbsp; There are a range of steps that are components of an implementation plan.<br>&nbsp;<br>Obviously, if the Delta variant becomes worse and we need to move things forward, we have that option.&nbsp; If the FDA &#8212; which we don&#8217;t control their timeline, as you all well know &#8212; is not approve of vaccine by then, that timeline stands.&nbsp; But this was a timeline put in place so we would have the necessary resources and &#8212; and avail- &#8212; available time to make this happened with the diverse military personnel around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I know the President isn&#8217;t weighing in on legislative sequencing at this point in time, but there&#8217;s a letter sent by a group of House moderate &#8212; House Democratic moderates basically calling on Speaker Pelosi to take up the infrastructure bill now, saying (inaudible) have time for a delay.&nbsp; What is the President&#8217;s message to those moderates regarding sequencing, but who are &#8212; right now, feel like this needs to move immediately?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; His message is that he remains committed to passing each of these pieces of legislation on dual tracks; that he is going to work in lockstep with Speaker Pelosi, just as we have worked in lockstep with Leader Schumer successfully over the last several weeks and months to get this done.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And he is confident in the leadership, the strategic approach of Speaker Pelosi and looks forward to being her partner in the weeks ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one more: You know, Leader McConnell has made very clear over the course of the last couple of weeks that he doesn&#8217;t believe any Republicans will vote for a debt ceiling increase.&nbsp; Does the President believe he&#8217;s bluffing on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think &#8212; for those of you who have followed this quite closely, let me just &#8212; for those of you who have not followed this quite closely, let me &#8212; let me actually provide you some additional details of context, and then I&#8217;ll come back to your good question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Congress has raised or suspended the debt limit approximately 80 times.&nbsp; In fact, Congress has raised the debt limit more times under Republican Presidents than under Democratic Presidents.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Republican-led Congress raised the debt limit three times on a bipartisan basis during the prior administration, and 98 percent of the debt, subject to this limit &#8212; this limit, we&#8217;re talking about right now &#8212; accrued before President Biden took office.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a shared responsibility.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that during the Trump years, former Majority Leader McConnell himself said that failing to raise the debt ceiling was unacceptable because it would cause unforced harm to our economy and kill jobs.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our view is that Congress should move forward as they have multiple times &#8212; 80 times in the past; 3 times during the Trump administration &#8212; to raise the debt limit.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I was going to &#8212; I want to ask you about infrastructure in a second.&nbsp; But on some other news on COVID and Delta right now: Governor DeSantis in Florida, as you know, is now threatening to withhold salaries of schoolboard members and superintendents in districts that do not comply with his order outlawning [sic] &#8212; outlawing mask mandates at schools.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the White House&#8217;s take on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I do want to call out the &#8212; the courage and the boldness of a number of leaders in Florida, including in Miami-Dade County &#8212; people who are stepping up to do the right thing to protect students and keep schools safe and open.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are continuing to look for ways &#8212; to go back to your question, Peter &#8212; to &#8212; for the U.S. government to support districts and schools as they try to follow the science, do the right thing, and save lives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I would note: What is publicly available and knowable is that the American Rescue Plan funds that were distributed to Florida to provide assistance to schools have not yet been distributed from the state level.&nbsp; So, the question is: Why not?<br>&nbsp;<br>And those can be used to cover expenses that come up in this period of time.&nbsp; They&#8217;re federal funds, and they&#8217;re not under &#8212; they&#8217;re under federal discretion.&nbsp; So they just need to be distributed to the schools.&nbsp; We&#8217;re looking into what&#8217;s possible.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, in simple terms, what is the &#8212; what do you say directly to Governor DeSantis about this &#8212; about this threatened punishment?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we would say what we&#8217;ve said from the beginning, Peter, which is that if you&#8217;re not interested in following the public health guidelines to protect the lives of people in your state, to give parents some comfort as they&#8217;re sending their kids to school &#8212; schools are opening in Florida, this week, I know, in many parts of Florida &#8212; then get out of the way and let public officials, let local officials do their job to keep students safe.&nbsp; This is serious, and we&#8217;re talking about people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we know, based on public health guidelines, that even though kids under a certain age are not yet eligible, masks can have a huge impact.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple of follow-ups on the Cuomo news that just happened.&nbsp; We saw the President arrive only moments before the announcement.&nbsp; Did the President watch the announcement or who informed him?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President was meeting with members of his senior team, talking about the vote in the Senate today and preparing to deliver remarks, so I&#8217;m not &#8212; I don&#8217;t have any information on who made him specifically aware.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has he spoken to the soon-to-be Governor Kathy Hochul yet?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Not yet.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what message does the White House have, given this is also a historic day &#8212; the first female governor of the state of New York?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, certainly, we look forward to working with her and with a range of New York officials and continuing to deliver relief to the people of New York as we work to fight the pandemic, put people back to work, and show people government can work for them.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is 14 days soon enough for him to depart?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think I&#8217;m going to leave our comments at what we&#8217;ve made.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; First about immigration.&nbsp; The Washington Post&#8217;s Editorial Board wrote &#8212; after looking at everything happening at the border &#8212; that the administration has &#8220;driven a policy whose incoherence has yielded pressure at the border that may cost…Democrats control of one or both Houses of Congress.&#8221;&nbsp; Is there any plan to try to do something different down there?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me give you an overview &#8212; a short overview, I promise &#8212; of some of the steps that we&#8217;re taking, some of them that have been newly implemented over the last week or two.&nbsp; And I know there&#8217;s been a lot of news going on.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, there are a number &#8212; one is, steps we&#8217;re continuing to take under Title 42.&nbsp; Lateral flights &#8212; which is a newer step that we have started to take &#8212; which is moving migrants from one part of the border to another where there might be more processing capability or facility capacity to expel migrants under Title 42.&nbsp; There are some higher traffic areas.&nbsp; That is one step we just started taking recently.<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;ve also started initiating, as of last week, as of last Friday, expulsion flights into Mexico.&nbsp; The Department of Homeland Security started transferring certain families expelled under Title 42 by plane to the interior of Mexico.&nbsp; This is in order to attempt to cut down on recidivism and further spread of the Delta variant.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, the last piece that we&#8217;ve started implementing more recently is expedited removal.&nbsp; Under &#8212; with the exception of unaccompanied minors, as you well know, it&#8217;s currently U.S. policy to expel families and individuals under Title 42 when possible.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>However, under a variety of reasons, that is not always possible.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why expedited removal come in &#8212; comes in.&nbsp; It allows an immigration offisal [sic] &#8212; official, generally a CBP official, to determine if a migrant is seeking protection or has an intent of applying for asylum.&nbsp; If they do, of course, they would go through the process.&nbsp; If they do not, this would allow for removal on a more rapid basis.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then about &#8212; with the votes in Congress and the next steps.&nbsp; A trillion for the infrastructure; three and a half trillion for the reconciliation.&nbsp; Is anybody here concerned that all of this government spending could lead to inflation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, as you know, we take inflation incredibly seriously.&nbsp; It&#8217;s, of course, under the purview of the Federal Reserve.&nbsp; I would note that when we&#8217;re talking about the budget reconciliation process, there are payfors put forward, including asking corporations and the highest &#8212; wealthiest individuals to pay a bit more &#8212; something a broad swath, the vast majority of the American public supports.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also in our interest to help pay for these vital investments.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I would note: We take it seriously.&nbsp; We watch it closely.&nbsp; The Federal Reserve, who has the purview, has predicted &#8212; or put out a forecast that it &#8212; we expect it go up a bit this year &#8212; we&#8217;ve long anticipated that &#8212; but to come back down to normal levels next year.&nbsp; And those are the projections we follow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And last one.&nbsp; You talk about these &#8220;vital investments&#8221; in the infrastructure package.&nbsp; If it is so vital, then why is the President okay waiting to &#8212; for the House to take it up until reconciliation is done.&nbsp; Why not just ask Speaker Pelosi, &#8220;We need to do this.&nbsp; These bridges are crumbling.&nbsp; People need clean drinking water now&#8221;?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, these are vital because they&#8217;re long overdue, and it&#8217;s important to modernize our infrastructure and make sure kids have access to clean drinking water.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s also designed as a plan that would be implemented over the course of eight years.&nbsp; It wouldn&#8217;t be a huge injection immediately into the economy &#8212; to go back to your prior question &#8212; and we are confident and comfortable with the strategic approach of Speaker Pelosi.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President, of course, looks forward to signing each of these pieces of legislation into law.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Ed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A few clean-up items on all the good questions already raised.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you recall or can you help us run down the last time the President would have ever talked to Kathy Hochul?&nbsp; I realize you may not know that right now, but &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check and we can get that back to all of you as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given that they share a lot of similarities in terms of their politics and what not, undoubtedly that happened at some point.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the DeSantis-Florida situation, you mentioned the relief money that&#8217;s heading to Florida.&nbsp; Are you guys aware of any mechanism you could use to withhold federal funds from Florida if the governor keeps up this kind of activity?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have any announcements to preview today.&nbsp; Obviously, we don&#8217;t want to hurt the people of Florida.&nbsp; We want the people of Florida to continue doing what they&#8217;ve done, which is to go out and get vaccinated, make sure they&#8217;re protecting themselves and their neighbors and loved ones.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What I&#8217;m really &#8212; what I was really speaking to, at that point, is these schools being under the threat &#8212; and their administrators &#8212; of not getting pay.&nbsp; And, certainly, we&#8217;re looking into that and what &#8212; how we could help address that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you could &#8212; you are looking into a workaround, if need be, if the governor withholds funds?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, it&#8217;s knowable that the &#8212; the American Rescue Plan&#8217;s school funds have not been distributed to &#8212; across the state to all the schools that would be eligible.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re continuing to look into what our options are to help protect and help support these teachers and administrators who are taking steps to protect the people in their communities.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two other quick ones.&nbsp; Now that things are shifting to reconciliation, how does the White House, sort of, congressional outreach strategy change, if at all?&nbsp; You had a lot of meetings over here.&nbsp; And I realize they&#8217;re on recess.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But you had a lot of meetings over here with Republicans back in the day &#8212; a few weeks and months ago.&nbsp; What is the President, the Vice President, the legislative team doing now to ensure that all 50 Democratic senators and potentially all members of the House are on board with this?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I probably will have an updated number at some point.&nbsp; But, as of late last week, we had done about 375 engagements on just the reconciliation package with member offices and members.&nbsp; So that will, of course, increase, and those numbers will continue to grow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the President will &#8212; of course, members are in their home districts.&nbsp; They&#8217;re on recess.&nbsp; But he will be picking up the phone, as he did quite a bit over the weekend, to have conversations with members, address any concerns or questions they have, and work to get this piece of legislation also &#8212; both pieces, I should say &#8212; across the finish line.<br>&nbsp;<br>And if it will help move things forward to bring people to the Oval Office, I&#8217;m sure he&#8217;ll do that when people return in September as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And ahead of Thursday&#8217;s census data release, I&#8217;m curious what the White House and your party might be able to do to stop Republican state legislatures from drawing or redrawing lines in ways that you guys are worried about.&nbsp; You obviously have the presidential bully pulpit, you currently have the congressional majority, but you don&#8217;t control a lot of the state houses where most of these lines are going to be redrawn.&nbsp; So how is the White House, the Democratic Party thinking about this fight to come?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You are right; the Census will be releasing data used my &#8212; by many states for redistricting on Thursday &#8212; so, two days from now.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say that the career experts at the Census Bureau who did this data have taken the time needed to produce the high-quality statistics that the public expects and deserves.&nbsp; We, obviously, haven&#8217;t seen the data they are releasing, so we aren&#8217;t going to weigh in further at this point in time<br>&nbsp;<br>Certainly, the President has also, at the same time, expressed concern about gerrymandering and about steps taken that reduce our &#8212; our democracy, our democratic values across the country.<br>&nbsp;<br>But I expect we&#8217;ll have more to say when that data comes out on Thursday.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Andrea.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, there was the conversation yesterday with Vice President and the President of Mexico in which she promised additional doses.&nbsp; Today, the Mexican Foreign Minister said that it would be 8.5 million doses.&nbsp; Can you confirm those numbers?&nbsp; And will those be loans of doses or will they be donated?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then I have a another question.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I have, of course, seen that reporting.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have anything that&#8217;s been finalized quite yet.&nbsp; We do intend to provide more doses &#8212; donate more doses to Mexico, I believe.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll double check that for you.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t have anything confirmed at this point in time, in terms of the numbers or the timeline on that decision.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And then, tomorrow we&#8217;ll see the inflation data &#8212; I know we&#8217;ve just talked a little bit about inflation.&nbsp; Are you concerned at all about what we&#8217;re seeing?&nbsp; So it&#8217;s been a sustained increase in used car prices &#8212; has been one of the big drivers, right?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Is there any work being done within the administration to sort of look at what&#8217;s happening in those markets and how that pricing is continuing &#8212; you know, what are the factors that are behind the bump in inflation?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, one, of course, we look very closely at the factors that impact a range of industries.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve talked in the past as these numbers have come out &#8212; which the data that will come out tomorrow &#8212; about how a percentage of the impact is from the used car industry, and there are a range of factors at play there, including, as you know, supply chain issues and challenges that are related.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re also &#8212; have been addressing through a separate channel, through our supply chain efforts, our work with &#8212; with a range of companies and our work with our global partners.<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d also note that we&#8217;ve seen impacts, because of the Delta variant, on parts of the world and markets where there are some &#8212; some materials coming from &#8212; and that&#8217;s one of the reasons it&#8217;s so important to provide vaccines to the global community, to help address that and get the workforce back working again.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we look at every component that might impact prices, that might impact the car industry, but prices that impact the American people, most importantly.&nbsp; And certainly, the used car industry continues to be one of the big driving factors.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll see what the data says tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you interested in meeting with the automotive industry and with the dealers about the kind of financing schemes that they&#8217;ve got going as well?&nbsp; The financing has been stretched over longer periods so that people are paying more over a longer period of time for both new and used vehicles.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, is there some kind of intervention that&#8217;s needed to ensure that dealers are not making, you know, sort of, excessive profits, if you will, on this current &#8212; on these current supply chain problems?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure, I know that our supply chain team is in touch with auto industry executives, with dealers &#8212; as is our economic team &#8212; and they have been having discussions.&nbsp; I can see if there&#8217;s more of an update to provide to you as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I have two areas of questioning.&nbsp; One is, can you give me a sen- &#8212; give us a sense of whether the President is just &#8212; is disappointed by the Afghan military performance, just given the amount of time and money that taxpayer money &#8212; taxpayer funds went to training the forces?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I don&#8217;t think we have the luxury of just feeling disappointed.&nbsp; Our view and the President&#8217;s view is that now is the time for them to&nbsp;utilize the training, the assistance, the security guidance that they have been provided over the last two decades &#8212; and they will continue to be provided &#8212; and unite as a &#8212; Afghan leaders &#8212; both the military and leaders who are leading the country &#8212; to push back against the Taliban.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s our view.&nbsp; The President continues to believe that it is not inevitable that the Taliban takes over Kabul or the country and that they need to show political will at this point to push back.&nbsp; And obviously there&#8217;s a political process that we continue to support.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But should there be a look at whether the right training was provided or whether the funds were used well?&nbsp; I mean, it’s just &#8212; so much time and money went into this effort, and it seems that these cities are falling quite quickly.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;I mean, would there be a reassessment that maybe next time there would be a different type of training?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I certainly would point you to DOD for any assessment along those lines.&nbsp; But I think there&#8217;s no question that, over the course of two decades, the amount &#8212; to your point &#8212; of training, of assistance, of security equipment that has been provided is extensive.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we are continuing to propose additional assistance in the form of $1 billion to ensure the Afghan Air Force and Special Mission Wing have the capabilities and maintenance to support ongoing combat operations; $1 billion to purchase and deliver key supplies for Afghan forces; $700 million to fund continued payment of salaries for Afghan soldiers.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We &#8212; it is important to us and it is a fundamental value to continue to be partners and support their effort, but, ultimately, it is up to the Afghans to determine what their future looks like.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then I just wanted to follow up on questions by my colleagues, Peter Alexander and Ed O’Keefe.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On COVID and Florida, in particular: When you were talking about federal funds being used in some way to affect an outcome with the state&#8217;s school districts, can you describe whether you&#8217;re talking about, sort of, paying directly &#8212; paying these funds directly to the school districts?&nbsp; Or are you talking about withholding funds?&nbsp; Like, what is, sort of, the flow of funding?&nbsp; And what is the amount that we&#8217;re talking about?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have in front of me how much Florida was allocated through the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we can get you that number.&nbsp; But that &#8212; in the American Rescue Plan allocation, or in the &#8212; the guidelines f- &#8212; or parameters for how that money could be spent, certainly paying for salaries is a part of that &#8212; or it could be a part of that and could cover those needs for these officials, and now that money would have to be distributed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the Department of Education is looking at options.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not making a threat of withholding.&nbsp; Certainly, we don&#8217;t want to hurt the people of Florida, but we&#8217;re looking at a range of options to support the public health officials, the leader &#8212; the teachers and officials who are trying to protect students and their communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just quickly: Is this limited to Florida or are there other states and school districts where there are similar dynamics at play?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure we can check on where allocation has been distributed or not.&nbsp; Obviously, it&#8217;s only a handful of states that are putting in place measures that make it more difficult for education leaders &#8212; leaders in the education field to protect students and their community.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it doesn&#8217;t apply, necessarily, nationally because of that, fortunately.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m sure we can look at the data, state to state.<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Quick question, following up on the border.&nbsp; There was a filing yesterday in the Flores Settlement that described, quote, “shocking deplorable conditions.”&nbsp; This is at emergency shelters at two facilities in Texas.&nbsp; I do realize one of them is under investigation &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that being Fort Bliss.&nbsp; But given that there is another one in &#8212; I believe it’s Pecos, Texas &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>The administration’s strategy was framed early on to move kids out into HHS facilities &#8212; into these very facilities that are emergency shelters.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we were told over and over again when we saw those high numbers in CBP facilities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, given that these very shelters &#8212; the ones that, you know, the administration wanted to move kids into out of CBP facilities &#8212; are now being described as “shockingly deplorable,” what&#8217;s now the strategy to both improve conditions, but also move those minors out of CBP facilities at a faster rate?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s always our objective &#8212; both of those is always our objective.&nbsp; And the mission of HHS is to safely care for unaccompanied children until they can be unified with a parent or a vetted sponsor.&nbsp; We want to do that as quickly as possible.&nbsp; We also don&#8217;t want to put kids in the hands of people who are not vetted.&nbsp; So, there is a balance there.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will say that we are continuously working to improve the conditions and services required to safely care for children.&nbsp; So, currently &#8212; I know we&#8217;ve talked about one of these facilities and the IG investigation, which we&#8217;ve been supporting and we have been participating in, and number of the conditions have been improved at that facility.<br>&nbsp;<br>In the Pecos site, it ha- &#8212; now it has an on-site clinic with various medical services, including pediatricians, nurses, mental health professionals, physician assistants.&nbsp; It is compliant with the required ratio of medical and clinical staff to unaccompanied children.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The children receive educational and recreational activities, including reading, art, indoor and outdoor games, journaling, and dance.&nbsp; And children at Pecos also have access to provided laundry service, calls to homes, appointments with legal and counseling.&nbsp; And currently, the children at the intake site at Pecos meet with a case manager weekly.<br>&nbsp;<br>We are continuing to assess and make sure children are treated with &#8212; humanely, treated with care, and treated &#8212; and kept safe until we can find &#8212; connect them with their families or a vetted individual to care for them further.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Given all of that, I mean, is the administration satisfied with the conditions, specifically at Pecos?&nbsp; Or would it support a similar investigation that&#8217;s going on into Fort Bliss?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, that would be up to the interna- &#8212; the Inspector General.&nbsp; We have &#8212; again, we remain committed to continuing to improve conditions where there are &#8212; any concerns arise, and we will continue to do that at this site and any other where they arise.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just one more.&nbsp; The administration &#8212; I mean, why haven’t we seen, like, a supplemental request at this point?&nbsp; I mean, capacity has been an issue now, for &#8212; what? &#8212; six months, I mean, at the border.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Mm-hmm.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the administration considering that at this point?&nbsp; And do you still identify capacity as an issue at the border?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think capacity issues we&#8217;ve made huge improvements on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Specifically talking about beds in HHS facilities (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; I know what you&#8217;re saying.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve made huge improvements.&nbsp; And when we had this conversation a couple of months ago, the conditions were different.&nbsp; I mean, people were in the Border Patrol facilities for far too long.&nbsp; They were in these HHS facilities longer than we wanted them to be in.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think if we assessed that additional funding would help us expedite any aspect of the process, we would request those.&nbsp; But we also have some flexibility in the budget to make sure we have the resources needed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, we have to gather soon, so &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; maybe one more.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Let me just go to &#8212; why don’t I go to Eugene, and then I&#8217;ll go to somebody in the back.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Back on inflation, what does the administration have to say to people who, for example, aren’t getting raises or are essentially making less than they did two years ago &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Inflation, you said?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; making less than they did two years ago.&nbsp; Because it&#8217;s really hard for Americans to hear, you know, &#8220;Focus on these long-term investments; this is going to be temporary&#8221; when they’re dealing with those issues right this second.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that one of the steps that we&#8217;ve taken as an administration is to provide a range of assistance to the American people, whether it is in the form of $1,400 checks, or the form of the Child Tax Credit that the President has advocated for a multi-year extension of, or whether it&#8217;s the form of unemployment benefits that will &#8212; people will continue to receive for the coming weeks.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We understand this is a period of time, as the economy turns back on, as we&#8217;re recovering from a pandemic &#8212; and these dual crises are related &#8212; where people needed extra assistance, so we did exactly that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We also knew that as the economy turned back on, there would be a range of impacts.&nbsp; One is prices going back to a pre-pandemic levels in some industries.&nbsp; One is we&#8217;re seeing, of course, the impact &#8212; as Andrea was asking about &#8212; of the supply-chain shortages that have impacted some industries as well &#8212; the used car industry and others.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working to address each of these components and challenges in the economy as we see it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s also important to note, though &#8212; because we rely on the Federal Reserve for projections &#8212; that they are projecting to come back to normal levels next year, and this is still foreseen as a transitory impact on prices.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Governor Cuomo &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t I go &#8212; I&#8217;m just going to go to one in the way back.&nbsp; Okay, why don&#8217;t you go ahead?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, two questions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yep.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, what&#8217;s &#8212; what&#8217;s the White House guidance now on outdoor events?&nbsp; We just had Lollapalooza in Chicago.&nbsp; There will be others.&nbsp; So what should people do?&nbsp; Should they be masking at outdoor events?&nbsp; Is there sort of a capacity past which people should mask outdoors?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, second, I just want to be clear: Are you encouraging school districts in Florida and Texas specifically to resist the governors in those states and impose mask mandates?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re certainly encouraging any officials and local leaders to follow public health guidelines to save lives.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the first step, it&#8217;s not White House guidance; it&#8217;s CDC guidance.&nbsp; That has not changed, and they&#8217;ve put out pretty clear, detailed explanation on that, so I&#8217;d point you to them.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>All right.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.<br>&nbsp;<br>1:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Continuation of U.S. Drug Interdiction Assistance to the Government of&#160;Colombia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/memorandum-on-continuation-of-u-s-drug-interdiction-assistance-to-the-government-of-colombia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 21:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26745</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE               THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE  SUBJECT:       Continuation of U.S. Drug Interdiction Assistance to the Government of Colombia  By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, and pursuant to the authority vested in me by&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF STATE               </p>



<p>                                              THE SECRETARY OF DEFENSE </p>



<p>SUBJECT:       Continuation of U.S. Drug Interdiction Assistance to the Government of Colombia <br></p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, and pursuant to the authority vested in me by section 1012 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1995, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2291-4), I hereby certify, with respect to Colombia, that:  (1) interdiction of aircraft reasonably suspected to be primarily engaged in illicit drug trafficking in that country&#8217;s airspace is necessary, because of the extraordinary threat posed by illicit drug trafficking to the national security of that country; and (2) Colombia has appropriate procedures in place to protect against innocent loss of life in the air and on the ground in connection with such interdiction, which includes effective means to identify and warn an aircraft before the use of force is directed against the aircraft.<br><br>The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register</em> and to notify the Congress of this determination. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Ten Key&#160;Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/president-biden-announces-ten-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 20:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26719</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following ten individuals to serve in key roles: María Luisa Pagán, Nominee for Deputy United States Trade Representative, Geneva Office Christopher Wilson, Nominee for Chief Innovation and Intellectual Property Negotiator, Office of the United States Trade Representative Leopoldo Martinez, Nominee for Executive Director&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following ten individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>María Luisa Pagán, Nominee for Deputy United States Trade Representative, Geneva Office</li><li>Christopher Wilson, Nominee for Chief Innovation and Intellectual Property Negotiator, Office of the United States Trade Representative</li><li>Leopoldo Martinez, Nominee for Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank</li><li>M. Fabiana Jorge, Nominee for Alternate Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank</li><li>Sasha Baker, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Policy</li><li>Sean Coffey, Nominee for General Counsel of the Department of the Navy</li><li>Sarah H. Cleveland, Nominee for Legal Adviser of the Department of State</li><li>Joshua Frost, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Financial Markets, Department of the Treasury</li><li>Amy Loyd, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education, Department of Education</li><li>Sam Slater, Member of the Board of Directors of the Metropolitan Washington Airport Authority</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>María Luisa Pagán, Nominee for Deputy United States Trade Representative, Geneva Office</u></strong></p>



<p>María L. Pagán has spent almost three decades as a trade lawyer in the U.S. government.&nbsp; She is currently the Deputy General Counsel at the Office of the United States Trade Representative.&nbsp; In that role, she provides legal advice to senior USTR officials on all legal aspects regarding trade negotiations, implementation of trade agreements, and trade related legislation and regulations.&nbsp; She has been the lead U.S. attorney for numerous trade agreement negotiations.&nbsp; She was the lead lawyer for the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement, handling the legal aspects of the negotiation, as well as the implementation package that passed Congress in early 2020.&nbsp;&nbsp; Before becoming Deputy General Counsel, she specialized in providing legal advice on services, government procurement, and the section 421 country-specific safeguard, and also litigated several disputes before the WTO.&nbsp; Prior to joining USTR in 2003, Ms. Pagán worked as an attorney advisor in the Office of the Chief Counsel for International Commerce at the U.S. Department of Commerce.</p>



<p>Ms. Pagán was born and raised in Puerto Rico, and resides in Maryland.&nbsp; She received her law degree and a Master’s in Foreign Service from Georgetown University, and a B.A. from Tufts University.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Christopher Wilson, Nominee for Chief Innovation and Intellectual Property Negotiator, Office of the United States Trade Representative</u></strong></p>



<p>Christopher Wilson is a 20-year veteran of the Office of the United States Trade Representative, where he has served in a variety of trade policy leadership roles, including Deputy Assistant U.S. Trade Representative for Innovation and Intellectual Property (2006-2008) and several Assistant U.S. Trade Representative positions.&nbsp; Wilson’s USTR experience encompasses periods focused on regional trade relationships with Latin America, Europe and the Middle East, and South and Central Asia.&nbsp; He has represented USTR at the U.S. Mission to the European Union, and at the U.S. Mission to the World Trade Organization as Deputy U.S. Permanent Representative.&nbsp; Prior to his USTR service, Wilson worked at the Commerce Department’s International Trade Administration and as a State Department Foreign Service Officer (with assignments in Africa and Southeast Asia).&nbsp; He also spent several years consulting on trade policy issues in the private sector.&nbsp; A native of Kansas and longtime resident of Washington, D.C., Wilson is married to Mark Hegedus.</p>



<p><strong><u>Leopoldo Martinez, Nominee for United States Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank</u></strong></p>



<p>Leopoldo Martinez Nucete is a Venezuelan-American international lawyer, writer, and social entrepreneur. He is also a former Congressman in Venezuela. He is the Founder of the Center for Democracy and Development in the Americas, publishers of IQ Latino, and the Principal of LMN Consulting, LLC. Mr. Martínez is a member the Democratic National Committee (DNC), one of the leaders of its Hispanic Caucus, and a founding Board Member of Latino Victory Project.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. Martinez served on the Small Business Legislative Commission of the Commonwealth of Virginia, and currently sits on the University Of Mary Washington Board of Visitors and the Sorensen Institute at the University of Virginia. He also served in the Transition Committee for Virginia Governor Ralph Northam. Leopoldo Martínez is a graduate of Harvard Law School (‘89), Princeton University School of Public and International Affairs (‘96), and The University of Miami Law School (‘07). Mr. Martinez has worked with large international law and accounting firms, and has extensive experience advising Fortune 500 companies, private equity funds, Multi-Latina corporations, international business, and non-profit organizations.</p>



<p><strong><u>M. Fabiana Jorge, Nominee for United States Alternate Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank</u></strong></p>



<p>M. Fabiana Jorge is the founder and president of MFJ International, a global consulting firm based in Washington, DC that specializes in international trade and business. Ms. Jorge has three decades of experience in trade negotiations with a focus on intellectual property and access to medicines.&nbsp; She has been deeply involved in many trade negotiations, including the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA), the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership (CPTPP), the New Trade Policy of 2007, the Dominican Republic-Central American Free Trade Agreement (CAFTA-DR), the EU-Canada Comprehensive and Trade Agreement (CETA), the EU-Mercosur Trade Agreement, and most recently in the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership (RCEP).&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ms. Jorge was previously a Principal at Verner, Liipfert, Bernhard, McPherson and Hand, where she was the head of the Latin American Affairs Division.&nbsp; She was an adjunct professor at the University of El Salvador in Buenos Aires, Argentina, where she was born.&nbsp; She holds a Bachelor degree in Political Science with a Specialization in International Relations from Catholic University in Buenos Aires.&nbsp; She has a Masters in Business Administration from Columbia University.&nbsp; Ms. Jorge is fluent in Spanish and French and has working knowledge of Portuguese. She moved to the United States over 30 years ago and resides in Washington, DC with her husband Doug and three kids, Christopher, Phillip and Nicole.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sasha Baker, Nominee for Deputy Under Secretary of Defense for Policy</u></strong></p>



<p>Sasha Baker currently serves as a Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Strategic Planning at the National Security Council. Previously, Ms. Baker served as national security advisor for Senator Elizabeth Warren of Massachusetts, and as Deputy Chief of Staff for Secretary of Defense Ashton Carter during the Obama administration. She was a budget analyst at the Office of Management and Budget, joining the civil service as a Presidential Management Fellow and serving in the Homeland Security and National Security divisions and later as Special Assistant to the OMB Director. Ms. Baker began her public service career with the House Armed Services Oversight and Investigations Subcommittee, where she supported bipartisan congressional reviews on a variety of national security topics.</p>



<p>A New Jersey native, Ms. Baker earned a B.A. from Dartmouth College and a Master in Public Policy from the Harvard Kennedy School, where she was a fellow at the Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs. She is a recipient of the Department of Defense Distinguished Public Service Medal.</p>



<p><strong><u>John “Sean” Coffey, Nominee for General Counsel of the Department of the Navy</u></strong></p>



<p>John P. (“Sean”) Coffey is a retired Navy captain and former federal prosecutor who currently serves as the Chair of Complex Litigation at Kramer Levin Naftalis &amp; Frankel LLP in New York City.&nbsp; The oldest of seven children born to Irish immigrants, Coffey is an honors graduate of the United States Naval Academy and Georgetown University Law Center.&nbsp; After graduating from Annapolis, Coffey completed Naval Flight Officer training and served eight years on active duty, including assignments as a P-3C Orion mission commander, junior officer intern to the Organization of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and personal military assistant to Vice President George H.W. Bush.&nbsp; After completing Georgetown Law’s evening program while assigned to the Pentagon and White House, Coffey transitioned to the Navy Reserve and returned home to New York to begin his legal career.&nbsp; Coffey has over three decades of active, high-profile trial experience, including serving as an Assistant United States Attorney in the Southern District of New York and, in private practice, as co-lead trial counsel in the landmark WorldCom securities case.&nbsp; While practicing law in New York, Coffey continued to serve for eighteen years in the Navy Reserve, where he commanded a reserve P-3C squadron and the reserve component of the Enterprise carrier battle group staff, and served as a staff officer in the Office of the Secretary of Defense. He retired at the rank of Captain in 2004 after thirty years of uniformed service.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Coffey has long been active in philanthropic and educational efforts.&nbsp; He is currently the president of the Federal Bar Foundation, a not-for-profit that supports law-related programs located in the Second Circuit Court of Appeals. He also serves on the boards of the Holocaust &amp; Human Rights Education Center, Common Cause New York, and ThanksUSA, a not-for-profit that provides scholarships for military dependents.&nbsp; Coffey is also a member of the board of visitors at Georgetown Law, where he has taught trial practice as an adjunct professor.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Sarah H. Cleveland, Nominee for Legal Adviser of the Department of State</u></strong></p>



<p>Sarah H. Cleveland is an American law professor and expert in international law and the constitutional law of U.S. foreign relations.&nbsp; A native of Alabama, she holds the Louis Henkin Chair in Human and Constitutional Rights and is Faculty Co-Director of the Human Rights Institute at Columbia Law School. She previously served as the Co-Coordinating Reporter of the American Law Institute’s Restatement (Fourth) of the Foreign Relations Law of the United States (2018), and as Counselor on International Law to the Legal Adviser of the U.S. Department of State.&nbsp; She was nominated by the U.S. government and served as an independent expert on the United Nations Human Rights Committee (2015-18) and the Venice Commission of the Council of Europe (2013-19). Cleveland began her career as a Skadden Fellow representing migrant farmworkers with Florida Legal Services, and then joined the faculty at the University of Texas School of Law. The author of numerous publications, she also has taught at Oxford, Harvard, Michigan, Sciences Po Paris, Paris II Panthéon-Assas, and the European University Institute, Florence.&nbsp; She earned a Bachelor’s Degree with honors at Brown University (Junior Phi Beta Kappa); a Master’s Degree at Oxford University, where she studied as a Rhodes Scholar; and a J.D. at Yale University Law School.&nbsp; She clerked for Judge Louis F. Oberdorfer on the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, and then for Supreme Court Justice Harry A. Blackmun.</p>



<p><strong><u>Joshua Frost, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Financial Markets, Department of the Treasury</u></strong></p>



<p>Josh Frost has spent nearly 23 years at the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, most recently as the co-chair of the liquidity risk program for large bank supervision. He also oversaw the two Corporate Credit Facilities launched in response to the pandemic. Josh is currently on a detail assignment from the New York Fed to the U.S. Department of the Treasury to provide temporary assistance. Prior roles at the New York Fed included Director of Money Markets and Director of Treasury Markets, where he was responsible for the teams that launched the Secured Overnight Financing Rate (SOFR), and conducted auctions of debt on behalf of the U.S. Department of the Treasury.</p>



<p>Mr. Frost received his MBA in Finance from New York University and his BA in Mathematics and Psychology from Rutgers College.</p>



<p><strong><u>Amy Loyd, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Career, Technical, and Adult Education, Department of Education</u></strong></p>



<p>Amy Loyd, Ed.L.D., is a Senior Advisor in the Office of the Secretary at the U.S. Department of Education.  She oversees national programs related to career and technical education, community colleges, adult education and literacy, and correctional education.</p>



<p>Prior to joining the Biden-Harris Administration, Dr. Loyd was a Vice President at Jobs for the Future (JFF), where she designed and led programs across the United States that improve education and workforce outcomes. Her work at JFF focused on state and regional policies, practices, and cross-sector partnerships that engaged K-12 education, community colleges, adult education, workforce development, economic development, and employers to build systems of college and career pathways. She also oversaw JFF’s work in workforce development with a lens on economic advancement, state and federal policy, and diversity, equity, and inclusion. She previously was the Director of Education at Cook Inlet Tribal Council, leading a network of schools providing culturally responsive education, training, and wraparound services to the Alaska Native and Native American communities. Dr. Loyd attended Santa Fe Community College and Northern New Mexico Community College, and holds a bachelor&#8217;s degree from St. John&#8217;s College and a doctorate in education leadership from the Harvard Graduate School of Education, where she was an adjunct lecturer on building career pathways to increase opportunity and equity.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sam Slater, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority</u></strong></p>



<p>Sam Slater is a Managing Partner at Tremont Asset Management LLC, which owns and manages a diversified portfolio of apartments, commercial, industrial, and agricultural properties throughout the United States and Canada. He directly manages the acquisition, development, and finance of all real estate assets. Slater is a co-owner of the Seattle Kraken and the Climate Pledge Arena and serves on the board of the team. He serves on the Board of Overseers at both The New England Aquarium and The Boston Children’s Museum and is a director of The Slater Foundation. Additionally, in 2012, Massachusetts Governor Deval Patrick appointed Slater to the Board of Directors of The Massachusetts Cultural Council, a state agency that funds cultural, arts, and interpretive science programs throughout the state.</p>



<p>As a Co-Founder and Partner at Burn Later Productions, Slater has produced over thirty feature films that have been distributed by Paramount, Sony Pictures, Universal, and Netflix, among others. He is a member of the Producers Guild of America. In addition, he is a frequent guest lecturer at the Communications School at Northeastern University. Slater graduated from The George Washington University with a Bachelor of Arts in History and earned his Master’s in Public Administration at Suffolk University.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Call with Governor Asa Hutchinson of&#160;Arkansas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-call-with-governor-asa-hutchinson-of-arkansas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 15:34:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26625</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, President Biden spoke with Governor Asa Hutchinson of Arkansas to discuss the increasing COVID-19 case rates in the State and what more the federal government can do to offer support. Last month, the Administration announced COVID-19 Surge Response resources, including increased testing, treatment and vaccination support, and the Surge Response teams are working hand&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, President Biden spoke with Governor Asa Hutchinson of Arkansas to discuss the increasing COVID-19 case rates in the State and what more the federal government can do to offer support. Last month, the Administration announced COVID-19 Surge Response resources, including increased testing, treatment and vaccination support, and the Surge Response teams are working hand in hand with state officials to help get the virus under control. The President commended Governor Hutchinson on his efforts to get more Arkansans vaccinated, including through his Community COVID Conversations, and noted the increasing rate of vaccinations in Arkansas. Governor Hutchinson thanked the President for his support and the two leaders committed to continue to work together to protect the health and well-being of all Arkansans.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to Japan to Attend the Opening Ceremony of the Tokyo 2020 Summer Paralympic&#160;Games</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/08/10/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-japan-to-attend-the-opening-ceremony-of-the-tokyo-2020-summer-paralympic-games/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 12:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=26633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to Japan to attend events of the Tokyo 2020 Summer Paralympic Games and the Opening Ceremony on Tuesday, August 24, 2021. Mr. Douglas Emhoff, Second Gentleman of the United States, will lead the delegation. Member of the Presidential Delegation: Mr. Raymond Greene,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to Japan to attend events of the Tokyo 2020 Summer Paralympic Games and the Opening Ceremony on Tuesday, August 24, 2021.</p>



<p>Mr. Douglas Emhoff, Second Gentleman of the United States, will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline">Member of the Presidential Delegation:</span></p>



<p>Mr. Raymond Greene, Chargé d’Affaires ad interim, U.S. Embassy Tokyo</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
