<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 03:12:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden-Harris Administration Issues Proposed Buy American Rule, Advancing the President’s Commitment to Ensuring the Future of America is Made in America by All of America’s Workers</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/28/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-issues-proposed-buy-american-rule-advancing-the-presidents-commitment-to-ensuring-the-future-of-america-is-made-in-america-by-all-of-americas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25187</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Biden-Harris Administration will increase American-made content in federal purchases and bolster critical supply chains The President believes that when we spend American taxpayers’ dollars, it should support American workers and businesses. In his first week in office, President Biden signed Executive Order 14005, Ensuring the Future is Made in All of America by All of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Biden-Harris Administration will increase American-made content in federal purchases and bolster critical supply chains</em></p>



<p>The President believes that when we spend American taxpayers’ dollars, it should support American workers and businesses. In his first week in office, President Biden signed Executive Order 14005, <em>Ensuring the Future is Made in All of America by All of America’s Workers</em>, launching a whole-of-government initiative to strengthen the use of federal procurement to support American manufacturing.</p>



<p>Since January, the Biden-Harris Administration has made significant progress implementing the President’s vision. In April, the President <a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-04-27/biden-names-trade-expert-drake-as-made-in-america-director">opened</a> his new Made in America Office. The Office reviews proposed waivers of Made-in-America laws and helps agencies use taxpayer dollars to support U.S. manufacturing.</p>



<p>The Made in America Office issued new waiver guidance to fulfill the President’s commitment to scrutinize and reduce waivers to Made-in-America laws. The guidance lays out a whole of government agenda to maximize the use of taxpayer dollars on domestic products and services to strengthen our industrial base and create good-paying, union jobs for Americans.</p>



<p>Today, the President is announcing another significant step in fulfilling his commitment: the most robust changes to the implementation of the Buy American Act in almost 70 years. His proposal would increase U.S. content in the products the federal government buys and support the domestic production of products critical to our national and economic security.</p>



<p>With $600 billion in annual procurement spending, almost half of which is in manufactured products from helicopter blades to trucks to office furniture, the Federal government is a major buyer in a number of markets for goods and services, including the single largest purchaser of consumer goods in the world. Leveraging that purchasing power to shape markets and accelerate innovation is a key part of the Biden <a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/commentary/transcript/brian-deese-on-bidens-vision-for-a-twenty-first-century-american-industrial-strategy/">industrial strategy</a> to grow the industries of the future to support U.S. workers, communities, and firms. As the pandemic has demonstrated, federal procurement can strengthen the resiliency of domestic supply chains, and reduce the risk of Americans being adversely impacted by the actions of competitor nations during a time of crisis.</p>



<p>Today’s Notice of Proposed Rulemaking marks just the first set of proposed reforms to procurement policy under the Biden-Harris Administration to ensure taxpayer dollars help America’s businesses compete in strategic industries and help ensure America&#8217;s workers thrive.</p>



<p>The proposed rule directs the following changes to strengthen Buy American requirements:</p>



<ul><li><strong>“Make Buy American Real” and close loopholes by raising the domestic content threshold. </strong>The Buy American statute says products bought with taxpayer dollars must “substantially all” be made in the U.S. However, today, products could qualify if just 55%&#8211;just over half—of the value of their component parts was manufactured here. The NPRM proposes an immediate increase of the threshold to 60% and a phased increase to 75%. This proposal would close a problematic loophole in the current regulation, while also allowing businesses time to adjust their supply chains to increase the use of American-made components. If adopted, this change would create more opportunities for small- and medium-sized manufacturers and their employees, including small and disadvantaged enterprises, from all parts of the country. To support this work, the Small Business Administration has created a new manufacturing office in its federal contracting division.</li><li><strong>Strengthens domestic supply chains for critical goods with new price preferences. </strong>As the pandemic made clear, supply chain disruptions can impact the health, safety, and livelihoods of Americans—leaving us without access to critical goods during a crisis. Some products are simply too important to our national and economic security to be dependent on foreign sources. The NPRM proposes applying enhanced price preferences to select critical products and components identified by the Critical Supply Chain review, mandated under E.O. 14017, and the pandemic supply chain strategy called for under E.O. 14001. These preferences, once in place, would support the development and expansion of domestic supply chains for critical products by providing a source of stable demand for domestically produced critical products.</li><li><strong>Increases transparency and accountability in Buy American rules.</strong> Reporting challenges have hampered implementation of Buy American rules for decades. Currently, contractors only tell the government if they meet the content threshold rather than reporting the total domestic content in their products. The NPRM proposes to establish a reporting requirement for critical products. The new reporting requirement would bolster compliance with the Buy American Act and improve data on the actual U.S. content of goods purchased. More complete and accurate data would be used to target future improvements to support America’s entrepreneurs, farmers, ranchers, and workers— and along the way, create good jobs and resilient communities.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>THE BIDEN ADMINISTRATION IS ALREADY BUYING AMERICAN</u></strong></p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has not waited for new rules to go into place in order to Buy American. At his first Cabinet meeting, the President made it clear that supporting U.S.-based manufacturing through procurement was a top priority. Agencies have delivered.</p>



<p>As part of the whole-of-government initiative, today, agencies are highlighting more than $2 billion in new purchases to support the manufacturing of innovative technologies and products in America.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The Department of Energy</strong> acquired new electric vehicles for its fleet, all of which were manufactured in the US or have batteries that were produced at US facilities. The Department will also purchase steel products, advanced computing, and hazardous materials isolation equipment manufactured in Texas, Iowa, Idaho, Louisiana, South Carolina, Ohio, Connecticut and Wisconsin.</li><li><strong>The General Services Administration (GSA)</strong> worked with 8(a) small business to procure energy efficient technologies for federal facilities. These contracts are a part of GSA’s Green Proving Ground program, which tests emerging technologies at federal facilities in order to help them scale and become viable in the market.</li><li><strong>The Department of Defense</strong> funded prototypes to sustainably source critical minerals and to create a new training hub with the Department of Energy to increase the productivity of the U.S. machine tool base.</li><li><strong>NASA</strong> added new project recipients to its programs to rapidly acquire lunar delivery services from American companies to further U.S. capabilities for science, exploration, or commercial development of the Moon and to demonstrate a commercially-developed habitable space station elements with the potential to transition to free-flying, self-sustaining commercial destinations in low earth orbit.</li><li><strong>The Office of Naval Research</strong> issued Phase 1 awards for a Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) project to accelerate the pace, security and quality of autonomous vehicles.</li><li><strong>The Department of Labor</strong> purchased $1.5 million of Made in America products, spanning a range of needs from office furniture to state of the art testing equipment to ensure America’s mines and other workplaces are safe.</li><li><strong>The Army Corps of Engineers</strong> Mississippi Valley Division issued over $42 million in new contracts to help make communities more storm and flood resistant and to improve the flow of goods along the Mississippi River to support the region’s manufacturers.</li></ul>



<p>These purchases are aligned with the President’s commitment in his Build Back Better legislative proposal to strengthen R&amp;D, manufacturing and grow jobs in the industries of the future, including through a $48 billion commitment to federal procurement of clean energy and clean technologies.</p>



<p>The President’s COVID-19 response has also advanced his Buy American strategy by increasing U.S. capacity to produce critical products.</p>



<ul><li>In March, the Department of Defense and Department of Health and Human Services procured over $22 million in American-made cloth face masks for communities hard-hit by the pandemic.</li><li>In May and June, the Department of Defense purchased more than $1.8 billion in U.S.-made COVID treatment and testing supplies.</li><li>In addition, since February, we have invested more than a billion dollars in expanding American production capacity for critical pandemic response throughout the healthcare supply chain to meet current and future needs.</li></ul>



<p>The President’s Build Back Better agenda will continue this work through its call for $30 billion to prevent and prepare for future pandemics.</p>



<p>Beyond direct purchasing, the Biden-Harris Administration is making investments in workforce training and small business supports that will bolster the President’s Made in America agenda. As noted above, SBA has created a new manufacturing office to help small manufacturers access federal contracts, financing, and business development support. The office will coordinate activities across the Agency in response to the President’s Executive Orders on Made-in-America, supply chain resiliency, and racial equity.</p>



<p>The Department of Labor invested $430 million in workforce training and apprenticeships in June this year, including grantees focused on bolstering the domestic manufacturing workforce. The funding supports programs across the country, including in Colorado, Texas, California, Michigan, Idaho and Nevada. These investments will ensure that as the manufacturing sector expands, workers will be able to transition quickly and succeed in good-quality jobs.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong>###</strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from Senior Advisor and Chief Spokesperson Symone Sanders on Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with Tribal leaders and Leaders from American Indian and Alaska Native Communities about Voting Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/statement-from-senior-advisor-and-chief-spokesperson-symone-sanders-on-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-tribal-leaders-and-leaders-from-american-indian-and-alaska-native-communities/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:32:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today Vice President Kamala Harris hosted a discussion in her ceremonial office to engage with Tribal leaders and leaders from American Indian and Alaska Native communities about voting rights. She was joined by Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland. The Vice President thanked the participants for their work to protect voting rights, and they discussed&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today Vice President Kamala Harris hosted a discussion in her ceremonial office to engage with Tribal leaders and leaders from American Indian and Alaska Native communities about voting rights. She was joined by Secretary of the Interior Deb Haaland. The Vice President thanked the participants for their work to protect voting rights, and they discussed ways to make voting more accessible.<br>&nbsp;<br>During the meeting, the leaders shared how Native Americans have long faced challenges to exercise their fundamental right to vote&#8211;from the long distance voters must travel to reach their polling places to anti-voter laws that directly impact Tribal communities. The leaders also shared how they are engaging voters&#8211;and in particular young voters&#8211;in their communities, by connecting the issues they care about to their vote.<br>&nbsp;<br>In her role leading the Biden-Harris Administration’s efforts on voting rights, the Vice President is working with a broad coalition to protect and strengthen the right to vote. The Vice President has convened Americans from all walks of life to share their stories and provide input – including a meeting the Vice President held last week with poll workers to hear about their experiences helping voters cast their ballot and have their ballots counted.<br>&nbsp;<br>The leaders who participated in today’s meeting included:</p>



<ul><li>Secretary Deb Haaland, (Pueblo of Laguna)</li><li>President Kevin Killer, (Oglala Lakota Nation) (SD)</li><li>Allie Young, (Dine’ or Navajo Nation) (AZ)</li><li>Chairwoman Shelly Fyant, (Confederated Salish and Kootenai Tribes) (Bitterroot-Salish) (MT)</li><li>Julie Kitka, (President of the Alaska Federation of Natives) (Chugach Eskimo Village of Nuchek) (AK)</li><li>Prairie Rose Seminole, (Three Affiliated Tribes of Mandan Hidatsa and Arikara) (ND)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at the Office of the Director of National Intelligence</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/07/27/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-office-of-the-director-of-national-intelligence/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 23:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Counterterrorism CenterLiberty Crossing Intelligence CampusMcLean, Virginia THE PRESIDENT:&#160; It’s an honor to be here.&#160; I guess you all are the ones that lost the lottery, huh?&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; You had to be here in person.&#160;Well, I&#8217;d like to thank Director Haines and Director of the National Counterterrorism Center, Christy Abizaid, for showing me around the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">National Counterterrorism Center<br>Liberty Crossing Intelligence Campus<br>McLean, Virginia</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It’s an honor to be here.&nbsp; I guess you all are the ones that lost the lottery, huh?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You had to be here in person.<br>&nbsp;<br>Well, I&#8217;d like to thank Director Haines and Director of the National Counterterrorism Center, Christy Abizaid, for showing me around the watch floor.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Folks, the main reason I came &#8212; and I mean this sincerely &#8212; is to say thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; The American people, almost by definition, are not able to know what you do.&nbsp; And you devote so much of your time, your effort, and many of you end up risking your lives in the Intelligence Community to do things to make sure that your families and people back here are safe &#8212; make a difference.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you&#8217;d be amazed &#8212; as I traveled the world as Chairman of the Foreign Relations Committee or member of the Intelligence Committee for all those years, or as Vice President of the United States dealing with national security issues, or as President of the United States &#8212; how many of now my foreign counterparts thank you for what you do.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;d like to introduce you, by the way, to my National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan.&nbsp; Jake, would you stand up?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, the leaders of many of our intelligence agencies are here today.&nbsp; And I thank you for your diligence and keeping our country safe, and your commitment to supporting your teams.&nbsp; Because, if there’s anything, a team sport is what y’all are doing if there&#8217;s going to be anything that’s going to be accomplished.<br>&nbsp;<br>Because the people I most want to honor and thank today are the intelligence professionals whose names the public is never, ever going to know, never have any notion of what you’ve done for us: the analysts; the linguists; the collectors and field officers; scientists; support staff; so many others who are real experts, whose careers started much longer before my administration and whose service to our nation is going to extend well beyond my presidency.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, you&#8217;re the eyes and ears around the world &#8212; in the frontlines of our national defense, and in many cases, for the world, through us.&nbsp; And you serve the American people no matter which political party holds power in Congress or the White House.&nbsp; It’s so vital &#8212; so vital that you are and should be totally free of any political pressure or partisan interference.&nbsp; That’s basic.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I want to be absolutely clear that my administration is getting us back to the basics.&nbsp; To the basics.&nbsp; I promise you:&nbsp; You will never see a time, while I&#8217;m President of the United States, when my administration in any way tries to affect or alter your judgments about what you think the situation we face is.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll never politicize the work you do.&nbsp; You have my word on that.&nbsp; It’s too important for our country.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Getting back to basics also making &#8212; to make sure the IC scrupulously acts within the legal constraints and abides by our strong traditions of internal and congressional oversight, including respect for whistleblower protections.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And it also means understanding that much of the work you must do is in secret but necessary and for the sake of safety.&nbsp; But we should strive to be as open as possible with the American people about the nature of the threats we face and just how serious they are &#8212; and they are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Every one of you joined up because you believe in being part of something that’s bigger than yourself, especially you guys and women in uniform &#8212; bigger than yourself.&nbsp; You’re patriots.&nbsp; It’s a word that we use lightly, but I mean it.&nbsp; It’s not &#8212; it’s not &#8212; I don’t use it lightly.&nbsp; I really don’t.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My son, who spent a year in Iraq and died, he was a patriot.&nbsp; He wasn’t just somebody else.&nbsp; You all are patriots.&nbsp; You risk your lives and your sacred honor for all that we need to have done for us.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you believe in the American idea.&nbsp; And living up to that idea is embracing democratic values that are our greatest strength at the end of the day, leading not just by the example of our power, but by the power of your example.&nbsp; The power of your example.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to thanking you for your bravery, integrity, and your sacrifices, I want to make it clear to everyone here today and to the members of the Intelligence Community working around the globe that you have my full confidence.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That’s doesn’t mean I don’t question what you send me.&nbsp; That meant &#8212; doesn’t mean &#8212; it’s not that I &#8212; I &#8212; you know, I&#8217;m not a new guy on the block in terms of these issues.&nbsp; But one of the reasons I question is to push &#8212; push you to the limits to determine just how certain you are about what you&#8217;re doing.&nbsp; Lots of times, the only honest answer: “We’re not certain.&nbsp; We’re not certain, but this is what our best judgment is.”<br>&nbsp;<br>I know &#8212; I really do &#8212; know how hard the work you do is.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve been doing this for a long, long time before I became President.&nbsp; I know there’s no such thing as 100 percent certainty in the intelligence world.&nbsp; Occasionally that happens, but rarely, rarely, rarely.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But I also know that your work is invaluable to our ability to make informed, strategic national security decisions.&nbsp; And I just had an interesting meeting, as you all know, with my very close friend, Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I can tell &#8212; one thing: I&#8217;ve been dealing with world leaders a long, long time.&nbsp; And just like all of you men and women, you can sort of sense somebody else after a while.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>He knows that you&#8217;re better than his team, and it bothers the hell out of him.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; And he, as a consequence of you, think we have capacities he may even exaggerate.&nbsp; That’s a good thing.&nbsp; That’s a good thing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, one of the things I miss most during the four years between my time serving as Vice President and being a professor in a college &#8212; and I mean this sincerely: From the time I was 31 years old, every morning I woke up and got in the train to come to &#8212; I commuted every day from Delaware after my wife and daughter were killed.&nbsp; And I&#8217;d come every day, and one of the things I would get &#8212; I&#8217;d get a brief in the morning.&nbsp; And I was more informed than 99 percent of the American people.&nbsp; You know what I miss most, for real, from those four years of being a professor?&nbsp; The PDB.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, you think I&#8217;m joking.&nbsp; I am not.&nbsp; A sense of knowing where all the pieces were.&nbsp; Whether we had it all down, we knew where all the pieces were.&nbsp; We knew where the pieces were.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so now I have access again &#8212; and to the chagrin of many of you, I read it in detail.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And I ask questions of my briefers and follow up with my team.&nbsp; And I ask each of you the same thing I asked Director Haines, &#8220;Just give it to me straight.&#8221;&nbsp; I&#8217;m not looking for pablum; I&#8217;m looking for straight-from-the-shoulder assessments.&nbsp; And when you&#8217;re not sure, say you&#8217;re not sure.&nbsp; But give me your best judgment of what you think is &#8212; your best judgment is better than almost anybody else&#8217;s judgment in the whole world &#8212; even if the news is hard, even if the news is bad.<br>&nbsp;<br>I can’t make the decisions I need to make if I&#8217;m not getting the best unvarnished, unbiased judgments you can give me.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not looking to hear nice things.&nbsp; I&#8217;m looking to hear what you think to be the truth.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I greatly appreciate just how much work goes into the analysis that the IC produces and the tactical and intelligence supporting our warfighters and the superb effort to ensure our IT, our human capital, and the facilities are the best in the world.&nbsp; Because, again, without knowing what &#8212; without you telling me, I don’t know enough to know what to ask for from the Congress &#8212; how much money we need, what we need to focus on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It’s a massive, coordinated, global effort to pull together reliable intelligence in a timely way.&nbsp; And all of you, no matter which agency you work for, are part of one team with one shared mission: keeping America strong and secure in the world, or simply making sure your families are safe.&nbsp; It gets down to basic things.&nbsp; Just really basic things.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, for most of the last 20 years, much of the work has been focused on counterterrorism, making sure the United States doesn’t experience another horror like occurred on September the 11th.&nbsp; And that work has to continue and evolve to address the changing shape of terrorism as we find it today.&nbsp;<br>And that’s no great insight on my part, it&#8217;s going to change significantly more.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to change significantly more.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I always get kidded by my colleagues when I served in the Senate for 36 years for quoting Irish poets.&nbsp; They think I quoted Irish poets because I&#8217;m Irish.&nbsp; That’s not the reason I quote them; they&#8217;re simply the best poets in the world.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>And there&#8217;s a famous poem written by &#8212; that says, &#8220;All has changed, changed utterly.&nbsp; A terrible beauty has been born.&#8221;&nbsp; The world is changing so rapidly &#8212; technologically and in terms of alliances and human intercourse &#8212; that war is going to change across the board in the next 10 years than in the last 50 years.&nbsp; That’s not hyperbole; that&#8217;s a fact.<br>&nbsp;<br>If I talked to you 15 years ago about hypersonic flight, you&#8217;d look at me like I was crazy.&nbsp; So much is going to change and that’s going to put an enormous burden on you to stay ahead of the curve.&nbsp; It&#8217;s really going to get tougher.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But we have the best folks in the world.&nbsp; And one of the things that I think &#8212; and I don’t want to get off too far afield here, but one of the things that is really important is &#8212; our greatest strength, in fact, is our diversity, bringing completely different perspectives to it.&nbsp; And I really mean that.&nbsp; That’s not hyperbole.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not trying to be &#8220;Kumbaya, everybody get along.&#8221;&nbsp; It&#8217;s just a fact.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a fact.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, threats that are more geographically dispersed than they were 20 years ago are going to continue to require our vigilance.&nbsp; And we have to continue our efforts to better understand some of the hardest and most important intelligence targets we face as a nation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But, you know, we also need to make sure that we’re positioning ourselves to stay ahead of security challenges that will stretch the IC in new ways it has never been stretched before.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, we’ve seen how cyber threats, including ransomware attacks, increasingly are able to cause damage and disruption to the real world. &nbsp;I can&#8217;t guarantee this, and you&#8217;re as informed as I am, but I think it&#8217;s more likely we&#8217;re going to end up &#8212; well, if we end up in a war, a real shooting war with a major power, it&#8217;s going to be as a consequence of a cyber breach of great consequence. &nbsp;And it&#8217;s increasing exponentially &#8212; the capabilities.<br>&nbsp;<br>When I was with Mr. Putin, who has a real problem &#8212; he is &#8212; he&#8217;s sitting on top of an economy that has nuclear weapons and oil wells and nothing else.&nbsp; Nothing else.&nbsp; Their economy is &#8212; what? &#8212; the eighth smallest in the world now &#8212; largest in the world?&nbsp; He knows &#8212; he knows he&#8217;s in real trouble, which makes him even more dangerous, in my view.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Take a look at China.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve spent more time with Xi Jinping as a world leader than anyone else has.&nbsp; I spent 25 hours alone with him when I was Vice President because it was important that, according to President Obama, that someone knew who the new guy coming on board was, and it couldn’t be the President.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I traveled 17,000 miles with him.&nbsp; I&#8217;ve sat with him, with me and just an interpreter &#8212; each of us have a simultaneous interpreter.&nbsp; He is deadly earnest about becoming the most powerful military force in the world, as well as the largest &#8212; the most prominent economy in the world by the mid-40s &#8212; the 2040s.&nbsp; It&#8217;s real.<br>&nbsp;<br>I don’t know.&nbsp; We probably have some people who aren’t totally cleared &#8212; I don’t know, but you saw just what we found out about hypersonic &#8212; we &#8212; anyway, as they say in Southern Delaware, &#8220;This boy has got a plan.&#8221;&nbsp; And, you know, we better figure out how we&#8217;re going to keep pace without exacerbating and moving us in a position where we increase the hostilities unnecessarily.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I think we also need to take on the rampant disinformation that is making it harder and harder for people to access &#8212; assess the facts, be able to make decisions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In today&#8217;s PDB you all prepared for me, look what Russia is doing already about the 2022 elections and misinformation.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a pure violation of our sovereignty.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Now you see what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; More people get their information from the Internet than they do from any other outlet.&nbsp; What&#8217;s &#8212; all the disinformation that&#8217;s having real consequences in terms of people&#8217;s access.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, there&#8217;s so much that you all &#8212; particularly those of you who are new and coming along &#8212; are going to have to be &#8212; keep up with and ahead of in ways that are not even happening now, as good as everything is.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, as we compete for the future of the 21st century with China and other nations, we have to stay on top of the cutting-edge developments of science and technology.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you&#8217;d hold for a second here, I want to point out something.&nbsp; You know, we used to &#8212; we used to be, when I first got here as a U.S. senator, actually three and a half decades ago, we invested more money &#8212; R&amp;D &#8212; money in R&amp;D as a percent of our GDP than any nation in the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re now number eight.&nbsp; China was number nine; they&#8217;re now number two.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look at where we are on things that intelligence communities and others don&#8217;t even think very often about &#8212; about how educated the public is.&nbsp; We&#8217;re coming around right now.&nbsp; This doesn&#8217;t relate to the intelligence community per se, but it does.<br>&nbsp;<br>Think about it.&nbsp; If we were having the debate that was taking place in the United States in the late 1890s and the early 1900s about public education, do you think any of us would say 12 years of free public education was enough to compete in the 21st century?&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; What do you think?&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a shot if we were doing that today.<br>&nbsp;<br>So the fact we have the best-educated public in the world &#8212; well, that&#8217;s our objective &#8212; will matter a great deal.&nbsp; It will matter a great deal.&nbsp; It is as much a part of national defense, in my view, as anything else is.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I think we have to think differently.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t expect you to agree with me.&nbsp; I expect you to at least understand where I&#8217;m coming from because the world is changing so significantly.<br>&nbsp;<br>And it&#8217;s especially important that we work closely with our partners and allies to maintain our technological edge; shore up supply chains; ensure that the rules that govern technologies support democracies, not autocracies.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, at the same time, we have to work in cooperation with nations like China and Russia that are our competitors &#8212; and possibly mortal competitors down the road &#8212; in the context of there&#8217;s &#8212; to meet the existential threats, for example, of climate change.&nbsp; There are certain things that are in our mutual interest.&nbsp; But we can&#8217;t &#8212; we can&#8217;t be lulled into thinking that that&#8217;s enough and that we don&#8217;t really have to keep a watchful eye on what the ultimate objective of the other team is.&nbsp; But there are things where we should be &#8212; where we should be cooperating.<br>&nbsp;<br>This shared danger impacts all of nations.&nbsp; Climate challenges are already accelerating instability in our own country and around the world: extreme weather events that are more common and more deadly; food and water insecurity; sea levels rising, resulting in changing climates and driving greater migration and posing fundamental risk to the most vulnerable of communities.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>If you could hold for just a second again.&nbsp; We&#8217;re in a situation where &#8212; think about this.&nbsp; Think about this: I&#8217;ll never forget the first time I went down in the tank as Vice President, after I got elected.&nbsp; The Defense Department said what the greatest threat facing America: climate change.<br>&nbsp;<br>If, in fact, the seas’ level rises another two and half feet, you&#8217;re going to have millions of people migrating, fighting over arable land.&nbsp; You saw what happened in North Africa.&nbsp; What makes us think this doesn&#8217;t matter?&nbsp; It&#8217;s not your responsibility, but it&#8217;s something you&#8217;re watching because you know what&#8217;s going to happen.<br>&nbsp;<br>People who were Muslim, and the only difference was Black and/or Arab, killing each other by the thousands for arable &#8212; a piece of arable &#8212; arable land in North Central Africa.&nbsp; But what happens &#8212; what happens in Indonesia if the projections are correct that, in the next 10 years, they may have to move their capital because they&#8217;re going to be underwater?<br>&nbsp;<br>It matters.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a strategic question as well as an environmental question.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>A dramatically warming Arctic is opening up competition for resources that once were hard to access.&nbsp; I had &#8212; as they say in Southern Delaware &#8212; they talk at you like this, you know what I mean?&nbsp;&#8212; I had a &#8220;Come to Jesus&#8221; meeting, an “altar call” with Mr. Putin about what he thinks is what Russia&#8217;s property is in the Arctic.&nbsp; China looking very closely at that as well, where they are.<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what I mean about the world changing.&nbsp; What is that going to do to our strategic doctrine in the next 2, 5, 10, 12 years, when you can circumvent the Arctic without icebreakers?<br>&nbsp;<br>So, look, we need your insight, we need your expertise on all these issues.&nbsp; The one thing you all have in common is you all have high IQs.&nbsp; You&#8217;re all smart.&nbsp; You have significant intelligence quotients, and you put it to use to help the elected leaders in this country decide what the best route to go is.<br>&nbsp;<br>So just as you always have been essential as we’ve sought to counter traditional threats, the Intelligence Community is going to be critical to America’s strength as we take on these new challenges and hybrid threats.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, I’ve laid out a broad agenda, and that’s just a fraction of it.&nbsp; But we can’t do any of this without taking care of our best and most important asset: the American people.<br>&nbsp;<br>I know the intelligence community is already one of the best places to work in the federal government.&nbsp; I asked my staff when I found out you came in second just after NASA &#8212; I said, &#8220;Don&#8217;t tell me what the White House is ranked.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; “It will hurt my feelings.”&nbsp; And they assured me, no, you don’t rank them.&nbsp; That was a good thing: “We don’t rank the Oval Office.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br>&nbsp;<br>But all kidding aside, it’s about the comradery you have, and most of all, it’s about being able to trust one another &#8212; to trust one another.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>My highest priority as President is the safety and security of all Americans, and that includes those who serve in our Intelligence Community.<br>&nbsp;<br>You take on unique risks in these jobs, and we’re taking the cases of anomalous health incidents that are affecting intelligence officers, government officials, and their families very seriously, for example.<br>&nbsp;<br>My administration is coordinating a government-wide effort to respond to these incidents, because this challenge demands &#8212; demands that departments and agencies, including the entire Intelligence Community, work together with urgency.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Talked about changes.&nbsp; What&#8217;s going to happen as we move on and we’re able to develop around the world pathogens that can be transmitted to societies and communities?&nbsp; It may not be a nuclear weapon.&nbsp; It may not be a hypersonic missile.&nbsp; It may not be any of the things we think of.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But think about it.&nbsp; Just think about what&#8217;s happened with one &#8212; I&#8217;m not suggesting it was intended &#8212; a lot more we need to know &#8212; but think what&#8217;s happened: More people have been killed in the United States of America because of COVID than in every single major war we fought combined.&nbsp; Every single one.&nbsp; What&#8217;s next?&nbsp; What is intended?&nbsp; There&#8217;s a lot of research going on.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to find &#8212; you&#8217;re going to have to increase your ranks with people with significant scientific capacity relative to pathogens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, my point is: Your value is going to increase and increase and increase and increase in terms of security.&nbsp; You know, from the CIA to all the agencies, there&#8217;s a lot that’s going to happen.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And to all of you who’ve been affected, we recognize how important it is to make sure that they have the best possible care at a time you&#8217;re figuring out how to deal with what&#8217;s happening, not only to some of those who have been stationed abroad, but their families.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, this is a priority for our entire leadership team.&nbsp; So let me just close by saying how much I value the work you do.&nbsp; That’s why I wanted to come here today.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So much of the work you do is in secret.&nbsp; It means many, many times you don’t get credit &#8212; the credit you deserve &#8212; and the things you prevented from happening, the catastrophes you’ve enabled us to avoid, the judgments you’ve provided us to make our people safer.<br>&nbsp;<br>And America is probably never going to learn about the lives you’ve saved or the disasters that never come to pass because of your diligent, professional intelligence work.&nbsp; But I want you to know I know.&nbsp; For the time being, at least as long as I’m around, I know.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And on behalf of the American people, thank you all for what you do every single day.&nbsp; And we’re grateful &#8212; we’re grateful that you’re there for us.&nbsp; We’re safer because of your dedication, your honesty, your integrity, and your significant intellectual capacity to act in our interest.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We’re stronger because of your insight.&nbsp; We’re a more noble nation because of your insight.&nbsp; And American lives have been saved repeatedly because of your insight. I know it may sound like hyperbole, but from the bottom of my heart, I thank you.&nbsp; I thank you for all you do and continue to do.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And may God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops and all those patriots serving in harm’s way, because there&#8217;s a lot still there.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>I have to seek permission to leave.&nbsp; I had to check, if you noticed.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Thank you again.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, will you require federal employees to get vaccinated?&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Beg your pardon?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Will you require all federal employees to get vaccinated?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; That’s under consideration right now.&nbsp; But if you&#8217;re not vaccinated, you&#8217;re not nearly as smart as I thought you were.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you concerned that the CDC’s mask guidance could sow confusion?<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We have a pandemic because of the unvaccinated, and they&#8217;re sowing enormous confusion.&nbsp; And the more we learn &#8212; the more we learn about this virus and the Delta variation, the more we have to be worried and concerned.&nbsp; And only one thing we know for sure:&nbsp;If those other hundred million people got vaccinated, we’d be in a very different world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, get vaccinated.&nbsp; If you haven’t, you’re not nearly as smart as I said you were.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Thanks.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br>&nbsp;<br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by Press Secretary Jen Psaki, July 27, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/07/27/press-briefing-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-july-27-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 20:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25157</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[James S. Brady Press Briefing Room 12:51 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; Hi, everyone.&#160; Okay, I have a couple of notes for you at the top. Today, the Department of Health and Human Services, through the Health Resources and Services Administration, awarded $121 million in American Rescue Plan funding to support the work of trusted community-based&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">James S. Brady Press Briefing Room</p>



<p>12:51 P.M. EDT<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Hi, everyone.&nbsp; Okay, I have a couple of notes for you at the top.<br><br>Today, the Department of Health and Human Services, through the Health Resources and Services Administration, awarded $121 million in American Rescue Plan funding to support the work of trusted community-based efforts to increase vaccinations in underserved communities.<br><br>This is the second round of funding for community-based groups.&nbsp; Back in June, HHS awarded $125 million to similar groups for these efforts.<br><br>And these groups will undertake efforts such as mobilizing community outreach workers to educate and assist individuals in accessing and receiving COVID-19 vaccinations, organize pop-up or mobile vaccine locations, and assist in making vaccine appointments or arranging transportation and childcare assistance for vaccine appointments.<br><br>One grantee in Jacksonville, Florida &#8212; one of the states where there, as you know, has been the highest transmission rates &#8212; one of the highest transmission rates &#8212; will use the funding to establish a sustainable community-based workforce and infrastructure to maximize COVID-19 vaccine uptake, minimize disparities, and advance health equities in vulnerable populations.<br><br>Another grantee in Oklahoma will reach rural communities, including Hispanic community members, and will recruit and train community health workers.<br><br>I also wanted to give you a small preview of the President&#8217;s visit to ODNI this afternoon.&nbsp; As we announced earlier &#8212; last week, I guess it was &#8212; he will visit the Office of the Director of National Intelligence later this afternoon to meet with leaders of the Intelligence Community and to thank all of our intelligence professionals for their service to our nation.<br><br>After the meeting &#8212; after meeting with Director of National Intelligence Avril Haines, the President will tour the National Counterterrorism Center Operations Center with NCTC Director Christy Abizaid to see firsthand how we remain ever vigilant in fighting threats to our country.<br><br>He&#8217;s particularly proud of Director Haines and Director Abizaid, who are both the first Senate-confirmed women to hold these positions.<br><br>He will then address the intelligence community workforce to express his admiration and appreciation for their service.&nbsp; In his remarks, he will highlight the integral role our public servants play in shaping national security decision-making and protecting the American people.&nbsp; He will also underscore the importance of intelligence collection and analysis that is free from political interference or pressure.<br><br>And I think many of you have been on these trips with him.&nbsp; He&#8217;s visited a number of national security agencies, and it&#8217;s part of his effort to support the workforce.<br><br>Another item for you: The Justice Department has successfully blocked a merger between two of the three largest insurance brokers in the world &#8212; I know this had been reported on &#8212; Aon and Willis Tower Watson.<br><br>These companies provide insurance brokerage services to thousands of American businesses and charge billions a year for their services.<br><br>The merger would have raised prices for a wide swath of American businesses that need to use a broker to obtain insurance and benefit packages for their employers &#8212; employees, sorry.<br><br>Those higher insurance costs would ultimately have led Americans to pay more for all kinds of products and services, such as banking services, hospital care, cars, and trucks.&nbsp;<br><br>And the proposed merger, as the Justice Department explained in its complaint, was a clear and presumptive violation of the antitrust laws under established law.<br><br>So, these actions, which I&#8217;m &#8212; the reason I&#8217;m lifting them up &#8212; are very much in line with the Presi- &#8212; what the President was talking about when he called for more robust enforcement of the antitrust laws in his executive order to promote competition.<br><br>Last piece, I think, here &#8212; second to last piece, but hopefully useful: Tomorrow, the President will travel to Lehigh Valley, in Pennsylvania, where he will be emphasizing the importance of American manufacturing, buying products made in America, and supporting good-paying jobs for American workers during a trip to the Lehigh Valley Operations facility for Mack Trucks.&nbsp; The President will take a tour of the Mack Trucks facility and meet with local union members.&nbsp; More than 85 percent of the 2,500 employees at the Mack Trucks location are UAW members.<br><br>And a little bit about Mack Trucks, as you&#8217;re preparing for tomorrow: The company has been making vehicles for the military since at least World War One.&nbsp; There are more than 1,500 Mack Trucks in the federal fleets used by both military and civilian agencies.<br><br>He&#8217;ll also receive a briefing on the Mack Trucks electrical refuse truck.&nbsp; The company is currently piloting their electric dump trucks in New York City and North Carolina.&nbsp; And this is all a part of his effort to lift up and talk about his &#8220;Buy American&#8221; agenda as well as the infrastructure package.<br><br>Finally, I just wanted to note that, after additional engagement with a bipartisan group yesterday, we&#8217;re enthusiastic about getting the bipartisan infrastructure plan across the finish line and confident we&#8217;ll be there soon.<br><br>We were encouraged this morning by positive comments by Senator Romney.&nbsp; Our team remains hard at work, as do a number of the supporters on the Hill.<br><br>With that, go ahead, Alex.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; I have a few questions on the CDC&#8217;s revised masking guidance &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that some vaccinated Americans should wear masks indoors where there&#8217;s risk of high transmission or currently high transmission.&nbsp; That covers, according to the CDC, about 63 percent of the country right now, which has significant or high transmission.&nbsp; So how will the White House get Americans to start wearing masks when they&#8217;ve gone for more than two months without them?&nbsp; Will we see President speak more about this?&nbsp; I mean, how exactly do you plan to push this publicly?<br><br>And then, along those same lines, on July 4th, the President gave his, sort of, &#8220;independence from the virus&#8221; speech.&nbsp; He declared, quote, &#8220;We are closer than ever to declaring our independence from a deadly virus&#8221; and, quote, &#8220;we&#8217;ve gained the upper hand on the virus.&#8221;&nbsp; Was that declaring premature victory?&nbsp; And are you at all concerned that those statements will make it tougher for you guys to implement this revised guidance now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Well, first, I know this is slightly awkward timing, but &#8212; and I know there&#8217;s a lot of reporting out there about the CDC guidance.&nbsp; It is not only appropriate for them to make the decisions, it&#8217;s also appropriate for them to officially announce their own guidance.<br><br>I will say, though, that how we view this, as you asked about, Alex &#8212; implementation of their guidelines that they&#8217;ll outline on a call with all of you later this afternoon &#8212; that we are still in the midst of a once-in-a-generation pandemic battling an ever-evolving virus.&nbsp;<br><br>We have said since the beginning of June that the Delta variant &#8212; a rising variant that had increasing &#8212; was clear from the beginning had great &#8212; a great deal of transmissibility &#8212; was a threat to people who were unvaccinated.&nbsp; We did more than a hundred interviews with officials conveying exactly that.&nbsp;<br><br>And the reality is: We are dealing with a much different strain of this virus than we were even earlier in the spring, back in May, when the masking guidance was done &#8212; provided by the CDC at that time.<br><br>That is their job.&nbsp; Their job is to look at evolving information, evolving data, an evolving historic pandemic, and provide guidance to the American public.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what they will do and what they will provide specific details on later this afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; With respect to the President&#8217;s comments, though, do you, in retrospect, regret those comments?&nbsp; Do you think that that was wise at the time, considering, you know, they could make it tougher for Americans to take this seriously?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say that, in the President&#8217;s remarks, he also made clear &#8212; and I&#8217;m quoting him &#8212; that today, &#8220;while the virus hasn&#8217;t been vanquished,” we &#8212; you know, he made clear that it was not over; that those who were unvaccinated were still at risk. &nbsp;<br><br>He made clear that you were protected from serious illness, disea- &#8212; or hospitalization if you were vaccinated.&nbsp; That remains the case.&nbsp; And he encouraged people who are not vaccinated to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>But, again, the role of the federal government and our public health officials is to continue to look at evolving data, evolving threats of a historic virus, provide that public health guidance to the American people to protect more people and save more lives.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what they&#8217;re doing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One quick one on infrastructure.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President met with Senator Kyrsten Sinema.&nbsp; Can you tell us anything about how that meeting went?&nbsp; And does he have other meetings planned with any of the primary negotiators or Democratic leadership on the bill as it gets to the &#8212; potentially, the finish line?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would expect &#8212; yes, the President saw Senator Sinema this morning.&nbsp; They are very much aligned on the path forward.&nbsp; Both feel optimistic about the path forward.&nbsp;<br><br>And clearly, both understand, having lived through many iterations of legislating and negotiating before, that it is always at the tail end when you have, you know, some of the trickiest discussions.&nbsp;<br><br>So &#8212; but they, again, remain quite positive about the forward momentum and the path we see the infrastructure package on at this point in time.<br><br>I don&#8217;t have any additional meetings to preview for you, but I will tell you that the President is somebody who just picks up the phone when somebody tells him it&#8217;s going to be constructive.&nbsp; That certainly, I think, will continue to happen as we work to get this across the finish line.<br><br>Go ahead, Kelly.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When the President travels, as in Lehigh County, will you be looking at the rate of infection there?&nbsp; And will that cause us to see any change in the President’s own masking posture or that of people in the entourage there?<br><br>And what should Americans &#8212; who should they look to for specific guidance about making these decisions, day to day?&nbsp; Do they need to be looking at a CDC website for the positivity rate in their community?&nbsp; Do they need to be looking to the White House for that guidance?&nbsp; What is your prescription for how Americans should adjust with these mask guidelines?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.&nbsp; First, we will, of course, be abiding by every aspect of the CDC guidelines on masking that they will provide this afternoon.&nbsp; And that does mean, as you conveyed, that we will be looking at the rates in different areas where the President may visit, and also the rates as they &#8212; if they move in Washington, D.C., and we will apply guidance accordingly.&nbsp;<br><br>That means we will be prepared to wear masks again if required, if the guidance is leading to that, as would the President.&nbsp; And that will continue to be the case.&nbsp;<br><br>And as it relates to the American public &#8212; I mean, our hope is certainly that elected officials, leaders, civic leaders, public health experts around the country will also look at the CDC guidance and they will be constructive partners and voices in sharing with their communities what steps they could take.<br><br>The CDC is going to have the map and the guidance to provide to the public on how this guidance applies to them, and that would be the most accurate place to seek information.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the “summer of freedom,” as the President described it, is that still operative now, given the change in the Delta variant?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say, first &#8212; I have this little handy chart; I suspected that we might talk a little bit about COVID today, understandably.&nbsp; And what I would note is that what has not changed is the fact that people are &#8212; who are vaccinated have a huge deal of protection from serious illness, from hospitalization, and from death.&nbsp; And I know Shannon &#8212; actually, I see her in the back there &#8212; asked a good question yesterday about the data, so I wanted to give you a little bit of a better understanding of how this data process works.&nbsp;<br><br>So the data that Dr. Walensky, the CDC Director, spoke to back in July was based on data up through the beginning of June &#8212; or the end of May, the beginning of June.&nbsp; That will be updated in August as it relates to individuals who are hospitalized or get sick, who are vaccinated, and those who are unvacc- &#8212; what hospitalizations look like as the percentage breaks down.<br><br>But this is all based on data from either state officials or health agencies &#8212; or the Florida Hospital Association, as it relates to the Florida-specific example here.<br><br>And how the information flows &#8212; to your question earlier yesterday, Shannon &#8212; is it goes from hospitals to states to the CDC.&nbsp; So I&#8217;m using this example to show you &#8212; because this kind of breaks through the reporting of this data &#8212; this is from hospital systems that will go to states.&nbsp;<br><br>And what you can see here: Florida, which is one of the states with the high- &#8212; one of the highest transmiss- &#8212; or one of the highest rates of COVID, I should say &#8212; officials have said that more than 95 percent of those who were hospitalized were not vaccinated.&nbsp; That is information from last week, or just a couple of days ago.<br><br>North Carolina: Unvaccinated make up more than 99 percent of new COVID cases in May and June.&nbsp; That&#8217;s from a few weeks ago, but still updated data.<br><br>Colorado: More than 96 percent of Colorado&#8217;s COVID hospitalizations, deaths in the first half of 2021 were among unvaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;m using these examples because even as the masking guidance is put out later today by the CDC, we are still going to be sending a very clear message to the public that in order to protect yourself or save your life, save the lives of those around you, you need to get vaccinated.&nbsp; Masking is guidance, but &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, can I follow up &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; just on this data point?&nbsp; Because, yeah, I appreciate you looking into this.&nbsp; It seems the problem, from when I talk to doctors, though, is that the Delta variant is evolving in this situation so rapidly that even data from May or June might not be representative of what&#8217;s happening now.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; This is from July.&nbsp; A number of these examples are from July.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It was only July 9th, I think, or mid-July &#8212; which I know isn&#8217;t that long ago, though, that the Delta variant became the dominant spread.&nbsp; So, you know, when I talk to hospitals in places like Nevada, Missouri, Kansas City, you know, those doctors are saying they&#8217;re seeing more like 1 in 10, which I know is still not a majority, but it&#8217;s different than some of these numbers.<br><br>You know, the situation in May and June, for the first half of the year when most people weren&#8217;t vaccinated, is much different than it is now.&nbsp; So, are you guys aware of that?&nbsp; Are you talking to people in some of the harder-hit areas about, like, what they&#8217;re seeing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Shannon, one, I think it&#8217;s really important to project data across a spectrum, right?&nbsp; Not from individual hospitals or individual cases.&nbsp; Because what people are really looking at or what we&#8217;re looking at is how it relates to across-state data.<br><br>Florida &#8212; this data is from four days ago.&nbsp; Florida is one of the states that has the highest rate; it accounts for about 20 percent of COVID cases in the country, from the last data I saw.&nbsp; This is from four days ago; 95 percent of those who were hospitalized were not vaccinated.&nbsp; That&#8217;s across-Florida data from the Florida Hospital Association.<br><br>Of course, we absolutely look at data, as does the CDC, and we&#8217;re going to continue to evaluate and assess.&nbsp; But because this data goes into what the CDC reports, I thought it would be relevant to all of you to see and understand how we look at the across-the-state data.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, Jen.&nbsp; The CDC data showed, though, on July 6th, that the Delta variant was the prominent strain: 51.7 percent of cases.&nbsp; So, what took so long between then and now?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Even higher now, as you know.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what led to the change in guidance?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; You &#8212; I’m sure you will get on the call with the CDC later this afternoon, and I think that’s a great question to ask them.&nbsp;<br><br>Our guidance is based on the public health experts and what they are advising in terms of steps that should be taken.&nbsp; I think it’s, though, important to note it has always been the case that the guidance has been, if you are not vaccinated, to wear a mask.&nbsp; That has not changed.&nbsp; That has been the case from the beginning.&nbsp; And also, to get vaccinated if you’re not vaccinated.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But the President’s message was get vaxxed <em>or</em> masked, and now it’s get vaxxed <em>and</em> masked, in some cases.&nbsp; So does he regret sending the message that it was a binary choice there?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Weijia, I think that those comments were back in May.&nbsp; And as I noted at the time, the Delta variant was a &#8212; was by no means a variant &#8212; the variant that it is today.&nbsp; It was not even a &#8212; I can look at the specific data, but it was &#8212; 99 percent of cases were not Delta at the time.&nbsp; That was based on guidance from the CDC.&nbsp;<br><br>Today, they&#8217;re changing their guidance, they&#8217;re changing their advice to the American public &#8212; their public health advice based on evolving data and an evolving, historic &#8212; vari- &#8212; virus.&nbsp; That&#8217;s exactly what they should be doing.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what is your message to Americans who are feeling whiplash right now?&nbsp; Why should they trust the same group of health officials who, just two months ago, told them they don&#8217;t have to wear a mask anymore inside?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because our goal is to save their lives, and our responsibility and the responsibility of public health officials is to continue to provide updated guidance, if it warrants, from an evolving virus.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more on something related.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve said many times from the podium, as recently as Friday, that it is not the federal government&#8217;s role to mandate vaccines.&nbsp; Can you help us understand what changed between then and yesterday when that&#8217;s exactly what the VA did?&nbsp; And is it a sign of what&#8217;s to come for other agencies?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think the context of the question, which I think is important here, is: Can we mandate vaccines across the country?&nbsp; No, that&#8217;s not a role that the federal government, I think, even has the power to make.<br><br>The federal workforce is part of the workforce of the federal government; that&#8217;s different and very different from the question you just posed, in important context.&nbsp;<br><br>The VA is a huge provider of public health officials and to patients who are some of the men and women who served our country bravely as parts of the military &#8212; as members of the military.&nbsp; And this was a decision that followed, and was aligned with, I should say, the decision by 57 hospitals associations across the country to make sure we were taking &#8212; they were taking every step they could to protect the servicemen and women who seek health services at the VA.<br><br>I will also say, as a big employer &#8212; the federal government &#8212; it is also our responsibility to continue to look at ways that we can protect people and save lives.&nbsp; And so we will continue to look, agencies will continue to look, we will continue to look at what steps we need to take for our workforce.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks Jen.&nbsp; How closely has the President been monitoring the January 6th hearing on the Hill?&nbsp; And what&#8217;s his reaction to some of the testimony from the law enforcement officers today?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, first, I would say &#8212; I know you didn&#8217;t ask me this question, but I know a number of us have watched the testimony this morning, which has been incredibly compelling, heart wrenching, and, you know, at moments, a reminder of the shameful events of January 6th and of the incredible bravery of the men and women of law enforcement who put themselves in harm&#8217;s way to protect the Capitol, our democracy, and members of Congress from both parties.&nbsp;<br><br>The President has had a range of meetings and briefings and engagements this morning.&nbsp; I know he&#8217;s intending to catch updates and clips, and certainly staff will share with him what they&#8217;ve seen as we&#8217;ve watched the briefings, but he has not been in a position, via his schedule, to watch the hearings this morning.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we anticipate a statement from him at the end of the day after he’s been updated on this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would not anticipate that, no.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then one on vaccines before we move on.&nbsp; You know, you just said that the message for unvaccinated Americans has always been to wear a mask.&nbsp; But how concerned is the White House that the message that unvaccinated Americans will hear after this afternoon is that, even if you&#8217;re vaccinated, you now have to wear a mask in some settings, and then just say, “why bother then” on the vaccine?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, here&#8217;s the good news: We’re all here.&nbsp; You all are all here.&nbsp; You’ve got millions of people and Americans who watch your broadcasts and watch your shows and listen to you to hear what they should know about how to protect themselves and save their lives.&nbsp;<br><br>So our message to the American public is: We are at war.&nbsp; We continue to be at war with a virus and evolving pandemic.&nbsp; Our responsibility here is to always lead with the science and always lead with the advice of health and medical experts.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re going to continue to provide information to all of you about how to protect yourself and save your lives.&nbsp;<br><br>We&#8217;re not saying that wearing a mask is convenient or people feel like it, but we are telling you that that is the way to protect yourself, protect your loved ones, and that&#8217;s why the CDC is issuing this guidance.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow on those two questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; What was &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’ll come back to you, April.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When was the White House told that this CDC guidance was changing?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; There&#8217;s been &#8212; it&#8217;s obviously a decision the CDC made.&nbsp; The President was briefed this morning by Dr. Fauci.&nbsp; But beyond that, we&#8217;ve been aware of their discussions with our public health officials.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the CDC is also going to recommend that children in schools all wear a ma- &#8212; that everyone in schools wear a mask regardless of vaccination status.&nbsp; But there are at least eight states that actually prohibit their districts from requiring a mask in schools.&nbsp; So what are parents who have children in those schools, in those states supposed to do?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, look, Kaitlan, I&#8217;m happy not to live in a state where that is the guidance.&nbsp; And this is new guidance that is being issued by the CDC today.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know how it will influence local elected officials in these states, but I certainly hope, for the health and wellbeing of the next generation, that they take a close look at the guidance.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And one more question.&nbsp; You just said you don&#8217;t think the federal government has the power to mandate vaccinations across the country, but they do have the power to mandate them within the government.&nbsp; So why is everyone who works in the federal government not mandated to get vaccinated?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would say first, Kaitlan, that we &#8212; you saw the VA announcement yesterday, which was really about public health and about protecting the patients, the men and women who have served our country.&nbsp; But we are going to continue to look at ways to protect our workforce and to save more lives.&nbsp; I just have nothing to preview for you at this point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should we expect more vaccination mandates from federal agencies?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think a range of agencies and leaders will look at what steps they should take to protect their workforce and save lives.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jen.&nbsp; Just explicitly, when President Biden was presented with this latest guidance from CDC, what was his reaction?&nbsp; I mean, he welcomed the guidance back in May.&nbsp; What was his reaction this time?&nbsp; How concerned was he when he was told about this latest guidance?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Concerned in what way?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Concerned about, you know, how this will impact the administration&#8217;s ability to perhaps vaccinate those who don&#8217;t &#8212; do not want to get vaccinated.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would say, first, that the President has always said that he is going to be guided by public health experts, by the CDC, and what our doctors are recommending.&nbsp; That has always been the case.&nbsp; And there have been discussions, as you would expect, for months now, from the beginning, about what steps need to be taken, should be taken to protect from an evolving virus.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So he did not explicitly talk about, you know, “Let&#8217;s &#8212; maybe the administration should start worrying about, you know, how this impacts your messaging, the work that you&#8217;re doing on the ground”?&nbsp; Did he have anything to say about that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not how he looks at this.&nbsp; He looks at &#8212; as the President of the United States, at a time where we came in with a dangerous distrust in science and government and institutions, he felt &#8212; feels it&#8217;s important to be led by data and scientists, and will be helping &#8212; le- &#8212; helping lead the effort to implement this, of course, in the federal government.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I did have a follow-up to Kelly’s question there.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Not just when he&#8217;s traveling, but just when he&#8217;s at the White House, and even for White House staff, is there any decision on whether he or staff will start wearing masks?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We will be abiding by public health guidance.&nbsp; And if that is where we fall in the geographical guidance given by the CDC, we will also be following that masking guidance.<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks, first on crime: As shootings spike in Chicago, the superintendent of police there is blaming courts for releasing attempted murderers on electronic surveillance.&nbsp; Does the President agree with the superintendent, who was just here earlier this month, that ankle bracelets do not cut down on attempted murder?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I have to tell you, I have not seen these comments or looked at the full context of them.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to do that after the briefing.&nbsp;<br><br>I think we know &#8212; from seeing, broadly, the rising crime or the rising gun violence across the country, including in cities like Chicago &#8212; that there needs to be greater assistance, greater efforts to make sure guns don&#8217;t get in the hands of criminals who could do harm, and more assistance to local police forces and community policing programs as well.<br><br>The President doesn&#8217;t just use that as rhetoric; he delivers it with action.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know he&#8217;s in discussions &#8212; or in discussions about reforming the police, generally.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got cops now saying that the courts are too soft.&nbsp; Some progressives, including Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, are saying the courts are too strict.&nbsp; So, what does the President think?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, the President &#8212; I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s a secret that the President disagrees at times with Congresswoman &#8212; the congresswoman about some aspects of policing.&nbsp;<br><br>He believes we need to reform our prison system to keep our community safe while addressing mass incarceration and by diverting nonviolent drug offenders and taking other steps that will improve rehabilitation and reduce recimit [sic] &#8211;recidivism.&nbsp;<br><br>If you &#8212; but he also believes, let&#8217;s be clear, if you commit a violent crime and are found guilty and pose a threat to society, you should serve that time.&nbsp; And when you get out, you should have the support you need to successfully reenter society.&nbsp; That&#8217;s his view.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on the CDC guidance, why did the President say, “If you&#8217;ve been fully vaccinated, you no longer need to wear a mask.&nbsp; Let me repeat: If you are fully vaccinated, you no longer need to wear a mask” if it was possible that that was going to turn out not to be true?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, I think we&#8217;re all dealing with an evolving virus where there&#8217;s no playbook and no historic precedent.&nbsp; And what the American people should feel confident in is that we are going to continue to be guided by science, look at public health data in order to provide new guidance, if it&#8217;s needed, to save lives, to protect the American people.<br><br>When he made those comments back in May, we were dealing with a very different strain of the virus than we were &#8212; than we are today.&nbsp; And Delta is more transmissible.&nbsp; It&#8217;s spreading much more quickly.&nbsp; It was nearly non-existent in the United States back in May.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And so my last one would be: You guys have been saying this is a pandemic of the “unvaccinated.”&nbsp; If that is coming from the CDC, is the President satisfied with the leadership at the CDC right now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President is satisfied with the fact that they are continuing to look at public health data and give &#8212; provide public health guidance to the American public about how they can protect their lives and the lives of loved ones around them.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And if it’s a pandemic of the unvaccinated still, then why do vaccinated people need to put the masks back on?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, Peter, first of all, I would say again &#8212; just to go back to this chart, which I will handily point to again: If you are vaccinated &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Overwhelmingly, the unvaccinated.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; &#8212; if you are vaccinated, your li- &#8212; it can save your life.&nbsp; And I think the clear data shows that this pandemic is killing, is hospitalizing, is making people very sick who are not vaccinated.&nbsp; That co- &#8212; still continues to be the case, regardless of what the mask guidance looks like.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But if the vaccines work, which this sign says that they do, then why do people who had the vaccine need to now wear masks &#8212; the same as people who have not had it?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Because the public health leaders in our administration have made the determination, based on data, that that is a way to make sure they&#8217;re protected, their loved ones are protected.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s an extra step, given the transmissibility of the virus, that people &#8212; that they&#8217;re advising people to take.<br><br>Go ahead, Steve.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Last year, when we went through this as a national discussion &#8212; talk about social distancing and shutdowns.&nbsp; Is this White House eyeing anything other than mask guidance?&nbsp; I mean, this week, you said you wouldn&#8217;t lift the travel restrictions.&nbsp; Is anything else coming?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, again, we&#8217;re always going to be guided by the public health guidance.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how the travel restrictions decision was made.&nbsp; But we are not &#8212; this is not guidance about businesses shutting down or communities shutting down.&nbsp; This is guidance to individuals about how they can protect themselves.<br><br>We&#8217;ve seen some communities &#8212; L.A. County, for example &#8212; where they have applied versions of mask guidance.&nbsp; It has not shut businesses down.&nbsp; It is meant to protect people&#8217;s lives.&nbsp; That is the goal and the objective.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you about expedited removals &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; down at the border?&nbsp; As you know, there are advocates for immigrants who say that what this administration is now doing is taking away due process rights by empowering asylum officers to make decisions in the immediate moment for expedited removal.&nbsp; What&#8217;s your response to that criticism?&nbsp;<br><br>And on the other side of that coin, is it this administration&#8217;s view that most of the people who are claiming credible fear on the border are not entitled to asylum?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, no, that is certainly not our claim.&nbsp; We are &#8212; of course, people who are applying for asylum, who will go through the process, and if their case and their &#8212; may &#8212; warrants, they will be granted asylum.&nbsp; What this is, is that &#8212; I should say, those families process for expedited removal who claim fear will have the opportunity to present their cases before an immigration judge and request asylum or other forms of relief or protection from removal.&nbsp; So even &#8212; even those who are being processed.&nbsp;<br><br>What &#8212; the processing of migrants for expedited removal is a traditionally employed, lawful mean to secure our border, and it is a step toward our broader aim of having a safe and orderly immigration system.&nbsp;<br><br>I will say, at the same time, we continue to work to build a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system.&nbsp; We recently expanded the Central American Minors Program and made 6,000 H-2B visas available to Central Americans.<br><br>But we also want to be crystal clear: Attempting to cross into the United States between ports of entry or circumventing inspection of ports of entry is dangerous.&nbsp; It carries long-term conse- &#8212; immigration consequences.&nbsp;<br><br>But, no, we will still, of course &#8212; individuals who are applying for asylum, who warrant asylum, will be treated accordingly.<br><br>Go ahead. &nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, does the President&#8217;s economic team see any ramifications to this masking policy?&nbsp; Are they concerned at all that it could affect consumer spending or any of the economic growth projections?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; That&#8217;s a great question.&nbsp; I will say, I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;re quite at that point.&nbsp; The guidance, of course, is not, as you know, being released until later this afternoon.&nbsp;<br><br>I will also say that as we&#8217;ve looked at, kind of, the economic impact of the Delta variant, one of the things we&#8217;ve looked at is that we have &#8212; one, we have programs in place that are meant to be implemented over the course of time to ensure that Americans are getting assistance, getting additional funding into their pockets as needed, which was a lesson learned from the past about ensuring that there wasn&#8217;t an abrupt halt to economic assistance as we&#8217;re going through a historic pandemic, still at war with it, and as we&#8217;re still going through an economic recovery.&nbsp;<br><br>There&#8217;s no significant signs at this point of the Delta variant’s impact in that sense.&nbsp; And we&#8217;d expect that much of the economic impact will be felt in communities with lower vaccination rates.&nbsp; But we don&#8217;t expect to turn back the clock to what it was in March of 2020 or even six months ago.&nbsp;<br><br>But in terms of longer-term analysis, I don&#8217;t &#8212; we&#8217;re not at that point yet.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just on the infrastructure talks &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; the President obviously met with Senator Sinema, and he’s making calls on this.&nbsp; Does he see the end of the week as a more or less deadline to get a bipartisan deal on this?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to be setting new deadlines today, but what I will tell you is that we were quite encouraged by the conversations overnight and into this morning.&nbsp; We see momentum.&nbsp; It&#8217;s moving in a positive direction.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve heard that from Democrats and Republicans.&nbsp; That certainly is a good sign &#8212; and it&#8217;s only Tuesday.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, the federal eviction moratorium is scheduled to expire at the end of the week, and millions of renters are still behind on payments.&nbsp; I know the administration has taken other steps to aid with assistance, but is there any discussion about an extension of that moratorium, especially as we&#8217;re seeing the Delta variant, you know, rear its head?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI: &nbsp;Sure.&nbsp; Well, let me just give you &#8212; I know you follow this closely, but for others, just as a reminder: On day one of the administration, as part of the American Rescue Plan rollout, the President did call on Congress to extend the eviction moratorium through September 30th of 2021.&nbsp; The final plan, of course, did not include that proposed moratorium extension, and so the CDC extended the moratorium administratively in January, March, and most recently in June for a final month.&nbsp; So it&#8217;s in place, as you noted, until <s>January 31st</s> [July 31st].<br><br>I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you at this point in time or &#8212; but certainly, we will be watching this closely, ongoing discussions about how we can continue to help renters.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, just on another subject related to January 6th.&nbsp; Yesterday, the White House said that it would nominate Matthew Graves to be U.S. Attorney for D.C., and if confirmed, he would oversee the prosecutions of hundreds of people who were arrested for what happened on January 6th at the Capitol.&nbsp; Did the President or anybody else in the administration discuss those cases with Graves before his nomination?&nbsp; Did they seek any particular position on those cases, such as being aggressive and charging and prosecuting them?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more on this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m happy to check and see if there&#8217;s more we can convey about the personnel process.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on Peter&#8217;s point: Does President Biden have confidence right now in Director Walensky’s leadership?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Absolutely.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And is a reason why Dr. Fauci briefed President Biden on the new CDC guidance and not Dr. Walensky &#8212; or Director Walensky?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think Dr. Fauci is likely in town, but also has provided briefings to the President on a regular basis, as has Dr. Walensky, throughout the course of the pandemic.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And on a different topic: What is the White House doing to specifically win over support from Democrats on the nomination of David Chipman to lead the ATF?&nbsp; Senator Durbin just told us this morning that Democrats don&#8217;t have the votes, and Senator Tester also signaled this morning that the nomination could even be pulled.&nbsp; So does &#8212; is the White House still pushing through on that nomination?&nbsp; And what is the White House doing to whip up votes?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I’d first remind people, as you well know, but for others, that not only is he a veteran of the ATF, but he&#8217;s somebody who has been a supporter of smart gun reform measures that could save lives of people across the country.&nbsp; And we &#8212; the President felt quite confident in the &#8212; his qualifications and his ability to lead the agency at a time where it hasn&#8217;t been led for many years.&nbsp;<br><br>In terms of our specific legislative strategy, I&#8217;d really have to talk to the team and see where things stand with that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And a quick follow-up: Senate appropriators just announced a deal on a supplemental on Capitol Police security funding.&nbsp; It does include about a billion dollars for the Special Immigrant Visa program.&nbsp; Does the White House support that deal between Leahy and Shelby?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We certainly have supported and advocated for additional funding for the Special Immigrant Visa program &#8212; something that is a huge priority to the President.&nbsp; I&#8217;d also reiterate, since you gave me the opportunity, that our first flight of Afghan SIV applicants will be coming into the United States this week, which is a very exciting step forward and will be the first of many.<br><br>In terms of the amount of funding, I would have to check with our legislative team on that as well.&nbsp;<br><br>Go ahead, April.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Jen, a couple of questions.&nbsp; On COVID: Are we at a point where we are saying that there&#8217;s just no absolutes when it comes to what&#8217;s happening in this moment?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not at that point.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because we&#8217;re possibly beginning to wear masks again in the building &#8212; in buildings, kids could possibly be wearing masks in schools, and those who are vaccinated are getting breakthrough COVID cases.&nbsp; So you&#8217;re saying &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I think &#8212; here&#8217;s what we all have responsibility to do: is to provide the guidance and clear information that is being presented by public health officials to the American public &#8212; not to project confusion, but to alleviate the confusion.&nbsp; And it is &#8212; also, it&#8217;s incumbent upon the public health officials to continue to look at and evaluate and make recommendations based on data to save people&#8217;s lives and protect people from getting the virus, getting &#8212; being hospitalized or, of course, dying.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; And a question on Johnson &amp; Johnson and on the testimony today.&nbsp;<br><br>Johnson &amp; Johnson is in the news again.&nbsp; This time, the National Council of Negro Women &#8212; who the President just had at his table &#8212; is suing Johnson &amp; Johnson because they targeted Black women, starting in the ‘90s, with talcum powder that is said to cause ovarian cancer.&nbsp; Is this administration concerned with the credibility, the integrity of Johnson &amp; Johnson, a company that is administering some of these vaccines in COVID?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, April, first, it&#8217;s ongoing litigation, as you noted, so of course I can&#8217;t speak to that.&nbsp; But I do think it&#8217;s important to note that the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine, which is entirely separate from baby powder, was approved by the gold standard, the FDA, which requires a rigorous look at the data and safety guardrails.&nbsp;<br><br>The FDA approved the distribution and the use of the Johnson &amp; Johnson vaccine.&nbsp; And again, it&#8217;s entirely separate from the baby powder, talcum powder litigation.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But it’s still that same company, the brand.&nbsp; And people will associate &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; But the FDA is a U.S. government entity and, again, the gold standard, and has a rigorous review process, so people should remain confident in the vir- &#8212; in the vaccine.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And lastly, on the January 6th Select Committee: Last week, President Biden said he “has faith in the American people to ultimately get to the right place.”&nbsp; And what is that “right place,” particularly when you hear testimony today from some of these police officers who &#8212; some are minority &#8212; some of the Black officers said Black officers fought a “different battle.”&nbsp; One officer said he was called the N-word &#8212; N-I-G-G-E-R &#8212; after answering questions of the rioters &#8212; the insurrectionists &#8212; as to who he voted for when he said he voted for Joe Biden.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think, April, as I said a little bit earlier, I mean, today&#8217;s testimony &#8212; for anybody who watched it &#8212; it was a searing reminder of the shameful events of January 6th.&nbsp; And certainly that testimony, I think, will stick with people for some time to come.&nbsp;<br><br>And what the President meant is that he is confident in the American people to fight for democracy; to fight for voting rights; to fight for, you know, moving forward from the events that were a dark day in our democracy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why he supports &#8212; strongly supports the actions by Speaker Pelosi and the efforts to get to the bottom of what happened on January 6th so that we can prevent it from ever happening again.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Okay, we&#8217;ve got to wrap up guys, sorry.&nbsp; You got an event.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; Have a good day.&nbsp;<br><br>1:27 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Nine Key Nominations</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/president-biden-announces-nine-key-nominations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 20:08:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25153</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following nine individuals to serve in key roles: William Valdez, Nominee for Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security Erik Hooks, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Federal Emergency Management Agency Lisa Gomez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Employee Benefits Security, Department of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following nine individuals to serve in key roles:</p>



<ul><li>William Valdez, Nominee for Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security</li><li>Erik Hooks, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Federal Emergency Management Agency</li><li>Lisa Gomez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Employee Benefits Security, Department of Labor</li><li>Adrienne Wojciechowski, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations, Department of Agriculture</li><li>Mark Gitenstein, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the European Union, with rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</li><li>Laura S. H. Holgate, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the Vienna Office of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador, and Representative of the United States of America to the International Atomic Energy Agency, with the Rank of Ambassador&nbsp;</li><li>Patricia Mahoney, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Central African Republic</li><li>Julissa Reynoso Pantaleon, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Spain and to the Principality of Andorra</li><li>Peter Hendrick Vrooman, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mozambique</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>William Valdez, Nominee for Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security</u></strong></p>



<p>William J. Valdez is a former career member of the Senior Executive Service at the Department of Energy and past President of the Senior Executives Association.&nbsp; He is currently the co-founder and Board President of the Alliance of Latinx Leadership &amp; Policy, which supports a leadership pipeline for Latinx professionals who want to pursue a career in public service.&nbsp; Valdez is a recognized thought leader in the management of government agencies and has worked for 27 years to improve the effectiveness of government, with a goal of providing maximum mission delivery on behalf of the U.S. taxpayer.&nbsp; A current focus is using technology to improve human capital, procurement, and financial management processes to free up Federal employees from paperwork and focus on delivering mission.</p>



<p>Valdez was raised in an Air Force family and is the proud father of three extraordinary professional women, and is Papi to four grandchildren.&nbsp; He and his wife Marlana Valdez live in Takoma Park, MD.&nbsp; Valdez was the recipient of a 2007 Presidential Rank Award (Meritorious) and is an elected Fellow of the American Association for the Advancement of Science.</p>



<p><strong><u>Erik Hooks, Nominee for Deputy Administrator for Federal Emergency Management Agency</u></strong></p>



<p>In January 2017, Secretary Hooks was appointed by the Governor of North Carolina as the Secretary of Public Safety and the State’s Homeland Security Advisor.&nbsp; Secretary Hooks provides cabinet level leadership to the NC Division of Emergency Management and Homeland Security Section, the NC National Guard, the NC Office of Recovery and Resilience, the NC State Highway Patrol, the NC Alcohol Law Enforcement Division, the NC State Capitol Police, the Division of Adult Correction and Juvenile Justice, the Governor’s Crime Commission, and support divisions within the state’s Department of Public Safety. Secretary Hooks leads approximately 27,000 sworn and civilian public safety professionals as well as approximately 12,000 National Guard soldiers and Airmen.</p>



<p>A native of North Carolina, Secretary Hooks has more than 30 years of public safety experience. He is responsible for leadership coordination of homeland security and emergency management functions to provide comprehensive and coordinated preparedness, mitigation, prevention, protection, response and recovery for emergencies, disasters, and acts or threats of terrorism. As North Carolina’s State Administrative Agent, Secretary Hooks administers federal funds to state, local and tribal entities across North Carolina. Secretary Hooks chairs the North Carolina State Emergency Response Commission and coordinates law enforcement counterterrorism prevention, preparedness, and response training on a statewide basis resulting in a cohesive team response by both law enforcement and emergency first responders to acts of terrorism or a terrorist threat.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Secretary Hooks has a master’s degree and undergraduate degree from North Carolina University. Additionally, he successfully completed the FBI National Executive Institute, and the Commandant’s National Security Program at the US Army War College. Secretary Hooks serves on the Executive Committee of the National Governors Homeland Security Advisors Council and is a member of the International Association of Chiefs of Police.</p>



<p><strong><u>Lisa Gomez, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Employee Benefits Security, Department of Labor</u></strong></p>



<p>Lisa M. Gomez is a partner with the law firm Cohen, Weiss and Simon LLP and the Chair of the Firm’s Management Committee.&nbsp; Since 1994, she has developed her deep technical and practical experience in the multifaceted field of employee benefits law, representing various Taft-Hartley and multiemployer pension and welfare plans, single employer plans, jointly administered training program trust funds, a federal employees health benefit (FEHB) plan, supplemental health plans, and VEBAs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gomez serves as a Co-Chair of the Board of Senior Editors of the Bloomberg BNA treatise <em>Employee Benefits Law</em>. Gomez also served as the Union Co-Chair of the ABA Section of Labor and Employment Law Committee on Employee Benefits , as a member of the Programming Committee for the ABA Section of Labor and Employment Law Committee on Employee Benefits’ Midwinter Meeting, and as a Union Co-Chair of the ABA Section of Labor and Employment Law’s E-FLASH newsletter.&nbsp; She is a graduate of the American Bar Association Section of Labor and Employment Law’s Leadership Development Program and is currently the Union Co-Chair for that Program.&nbsp; She is a member of the International Foundation of Employee Benefit Plans and the AFL-CIO Union Lawyers Alliance.&nbsp; She is a frequent lecturer on topics such as health care reform, various health plan compliance issues, benefit claim and appeals procedures and litigation, subrogation, ethics, LGBTQIA+ benefits, multiemployer plan contribution enforcement, qualified domestic relations orders, and other topics.&nbsp; In 2014, she was inducted as a Fellow of The American College of Employee Benefits Counsel, Inc. in recognition of her over twenty years of practice in employee benefits law and her contributions to the field. Lisa is also a member of the Advisory Board of The Peggy Browning Fund, a non-profit organization devoted to advancing law students who wish to pursue careers protecting workers’ rights.&nbsp; She previously served as a volunteer mediator for the New Jersey Supreme Court, Law Division, Special Civil Part, Somerset County.</p>



<p>Lisa is admitted in the United States District Court for the Southern and Eastern Districts of New York and the District of New Jersey, as well as the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit.&nbsp; She is a graduate of the Fordham University School of Law (J.D. 1994) and Hofstra University (B.A. 1991).</p>



<p><strong><u>Adrienne Wojciechowski, Nominee for Assistant Secretary for Congressional Relations, Department of Agriculture</u></strong></p>



<p>Adrienne Wojciechowski has worked in the Senate for 14 years and is currently serving as Professional Staff of the Agriculture Subcommittee of the U.S. Senate Appropriations Committee. In that capacity she leads the Subcommittee&#8217;s work on farm production, conservation, climate change, dairy, crop insurance, specialty crops and organic, local food systems, marketing, and research and education at land grant institutions. Prior to joining the Appropriations Committee, she served as a senior policy advisor for U.S. Senator Patrick Leahy of Vermont, advising the senator on agriculture, environment, forestry, and energy issues and as a professional staff member on the U.S. Senate Judiciary Committee. In that role she oversaw his work on the 2018 and 2014 Farm Bills, the Healthy, Hunger-Free Kids Act of 2010, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) portions of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, and supported his work on the 2008 Farm Bill.</p>



<p>Earlier in her career she was a government relations associate at The Nature Conservancy, leading efforts to strengthen federal agriculture and forestry programs to achieve cleaner water, healthier soil, improved habitat, and greater outdoor recreation opportunities. She is a graduate of the University of Maryland, College Park where she earned a Bachelor of Science in Agricultural and Resource Economics and a Bachelor of Arts in Government and Politics. Growing up in Maryland, Wojciechowski developed a passion for agriculture from her parents and her active involvement in 4-H, where she showed beef cattle.</p>



<p><strong><u>Mark Gitenstein, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the European Union, with rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary</u></strong></p>



<p>Mark Gitenstein is Senior Counsel at Mayer Brown LLP, and a former U.S. Ambassador to Romania. He has spent most of the last decade working on projects in Central and Eastern Europe.&nbsp; As Ambassador, he focused on fighting corruption and preserving democratic institutions, issues he continued to focus on through his work as a lawyer and with NGOs. Since his term as ambassador ended in 2012, he has returned to the region over two dozen times since then.</p>



<p>Earlier in his career, Gitenstein worked for 17 years in the U.S. Senate as Chief Counsel or Minority Chief Counsel of the Judiciary Committee, Chief Counsel of the Judiciary Committee’s Subcommittee on Criminal Justice, and Counsel for the Intelligence Committee.&nbsp; In 2008 he co-chaired then Senator Biden&#8217;s transition to the vice presidency. In 2021 he served as a senior advisor to and member of the advisory committee to the Biden presidential transition.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Gitenstein earned an A.B. at Duke University and a J.D. at Georgetown University Law School.&nbsp; He was awarded the Star of Romania, the nation’s highest civilian honor, by the President of Romania in 2012.</p>



<p><strong><u>Laura S. H. Holgate, Nominee for Representative of the United States of America to the Vienna Office of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador, and Representative of the United States of America to the International Atomic Energy Agency, with the Rank of Ambassador&nbsp;</u></strong></p>



<p>Laura S. H. Holgate is Vice President for Materials Risk Management at the Nuclear Threat Initiative, in Washington, D.C., where she leads NTI’s activities to prevent nuclear terrorism, including reducing quantities and enhancing security of nuclear and radiological materials around the world, promoting cooperation between the United States and key partners on nuclear and radiological security, and strengthening the global nuclear security architecture.&nbsp; She served as U.S. Representative to the International Atomic Energy Agency and Vienna Office of the United Nations, with the rank of Ambassador, in 2016, and previously was Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for weapons of mass destruction terrorism and threat reduction on the National Security Council. In this role, she led the preparation of four Nuclear Security Summits and co-initiated the Global Health Security Agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Previously, Holgate directed the U.S. Department of Energy’s Office of Fissile Materials Disposition and was special coordinator for cooperative threat reduction at the U.S. Department of Defense.&nbsp; She is a co-founder of Gender Champions in Nuclear Policy, and serves on multiple advisory boards.&nbsp; Holgate received a B.A. at Princeton University, an M.S. from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, and spent two years on the research staff at Harvard University’s Belfer Center for Science and International Affairs.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Patricia Mahoney, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Central African Republic</u></strong></p>



<p>Patricia Mahoney, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Benin. Previously she was an Acting Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs and the Office Director of the Office of Mainland Southeast Asia, also in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs. Earlier, Mahoney was the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Kampala, Uganda, and before that the Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Kathmandu, Nepal. Mahoney also served as Director for South Asia at the National Security Council. Mahoney earned her B.A. cum laude from Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts and her M.A. from the University of Hawaii.&nbsp; She is a Distinguished Graduate of the National War College in Washington, D.C., receiving an M.S. degree in 2009.&nbsp; Ms. Mahoney speaks French, Thai, Nepali and Lao.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Julissa Reynoso Pantaleon, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Kingdom of Spain and to the Principality of Andorra</u></strong></p>



<p>Julissa Reynoso is an Assistant to the President and Chief of Staff to Dr. Jill Biden, and the Co-Chair of the Gender Policy Council at the White House.&nbsp; A former U.S. Ambassador to Uruguay, Reynoso also served as Deputy Assistant Secretary of State in the Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs.&nbsp; She is a former partner at the international law firm of Winston &amp; Strawn LLP, in New York, and served on the faculty of Columbia University School of Law and School of International and Public Affairs.&nbsp; Reynoso is widely published in English and Spanish on an array of issues including comparative law, regulatory reform, community organizing, immigration policy, and Latin American politics for both popular press and academic journals.&nbsp; She holds a B.A. in Government from Harvard University, a Masters in Philosophy from the University of Cambridge in the United Kingdom and a J.D. from Columbia University School of Law.&nbsp; She clerked for the Honorable Federal Judge Laura Taylor Swain.&nbsp; She is fluent in Spanish.</p>



<p><strong><u>Peter Hendrick Vrooman, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Mozambique</u></strong></p>



<p>Peter Hendrick Vrooman, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, class of Minister-Counselor, is the U.S. Ambassador to the Republic of Rwanda.&nbsp; Ambassador Vrooman recently served as the Chargé d’Affaires and Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.&nbsp; Prior to that he served as the spokesperson for the U.S. Embassy in New Delhi; Director for Iraq on the staff of the National Security Council in Washington, D.C.; and Deputy Political Counselor in Tel Aviv and at the U.S. Mission to the United Nations.&nbsp; He also worked at the U.S. embassies in Baghdad, Beirut, and Djibouti, as well as the U.S. Liaison Office in Mogadishu, Somalia.&nbsp; In Washington, he was a Watch Officer in the Department of State’s Operations Center and the Desk Officer for Algeria in the Bureau of Near Eastern Affairs.&nbsp; A native of New York, Ambassador Vrooman graduated from Harvard College with a B.A. in Social Studies and earned an M.S. in National Resource Strategy from the National Defense University’s Industrial College of the Armed Forces, now known as the Eisenhower School for National Security and Resource Strategy.&nbsp; Prior to joining the Foreign Service, he worked as the special assistant to the President of the American University in Cairo.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on CDC Guidance</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-cdc-guidance/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When I ran for President, I promised to be straight with you about COVID—good news or bad. And I promised to follow the science. That strategy has worked: in my first six months in office, we’ve given out over 300 million shots—and have 60% of adults fully vaccinated and nearly 70% started on vaccinations. Cases are down, and deaths&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>When I ran for President, I promised to be straight with you about COVID—good news or bad. And I promised to follow the science. That strategy has worked: in my first six months in office, we’ve given out over 300 million shots—and have 60% of adults fully vaccinated and nearly 70% started on vaccinations. Cases are down, and deaths are down dramatically. One estimate suggests that our rapid deployment of the vaccine has saved 100,000 American lives—perhaps more.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement by the CDC—that new research and concerns about the Delta variant leads CDC to recommend a return to masking in parts of the country—is another step on our journey to defeating this virus.&nbsp;I hope all Americans who live in the areas covered by the CDC guidance will follow it; I certainly will when I travel to these areas.</p>



<p>Today, the CDC also reaffirmed that we can safely reopen schools this fall—full time.&nbsp;Masking students is inconvenient, I know, but will allow them to learn and be with their classmates with the best available protection.</p>



<p>Most importantly, today’s announcement also makes clear that the most important protection we have against the Delta variant is to get vaccinated.&nbsp;Although most U.S. adults are vaccinated, too many are not.&nbsp;While we have seen an increase in vaccinations in recent days, we still need to do better.</p>



<p>On Thursday, I will lay out the next steps in our effort to get more Americans vaccinated. Vaccinations are free, safe, and effective to every American.&nbsp;They’ve been available to every adult in this country for more than three months—at locations within 5 miles of 90% of the US population.</p>



<p>By following the science, and by doing our part by getting vaccinated, America can beat COVID.&nbsp;In the meantime, more vaccinations and mask wearing in the areas most impacted by the Delta variant will enable us to avoid the kind of lockdowns, shutdowns, school closures, and disruptions we faced in 2020. Unlike 2020, we have both the scientific knowledge and the tools to prevent the spread of this disease.&nbsp;We are not going back to that.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Peru to Attend the Inauguration of His Excellency José Pedro Castillo Terrones</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-republic-of-peru-to-attend-the-inauguration-of-his-excellency-jose-pedro-castillo-terrones/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 14:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Peru to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Pedro Castillo on July 28, 2021, in Lima, Peru. The Honorable Miguel Cardona, United States Secretary of Education, will lead the delegation. Members of the Presidential Delegation: The Honorable Lisa&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Peru to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Pedro Castillo on July 28, 2021, in Lima, Peru.<br><br>The Honorable Miguel Cardona, United States Secretary of Education, will lead the delegation.<br><br><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Members of the Presidential Delegation:</span></strong><br><br>The Honorable Lisa Kenna, United States Ambassador to the Republic of Peru</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>An Update from the Equitable Data Working Group</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/blog/2021/07/27/an-update-from-the-equitable-data-working-group/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 13:46:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[DPC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OMB]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[OSTP]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By Alondra Nelson and Clarence Wardell III, Equitable Data Working Group The Equitable Data Working Group was established on the first day of the Biden-Harris Administration under Executive Order 13985, Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government, as part of the President’s commitment to a whole-of-government approach to advancing equity.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">By Alondra Nelson and Clarence Wardell III, <br><strong>Equitable Data Working Group</strong></p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator"/>



<p>The Equitable Data Working Group was established on the first day of the Biden-Harris Administration under Executive Order 13985, <em><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/01/27/memorandum-on-restoring-trust-in-government-through-scientific-integrity-and-evidence-based-policymaking/">Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government</a></em>, as part of the President’s commitment to a whole-of-government approach to advancing equity. As the order notes, “a first step to promoting equity in Government action is to gather the data necessary to inform that effort.”</p>



<p>Because Federal data are often not available by race, ethnicity, sexual orientation and gender identity, disability, income, region, veteran status, or other crucial demographic variables, the Equitable Data Working Group is tasked with identifying inadequacies in our existing Federal data collection infrastructure and laying out a strategy for improving equitable data practices in the Federal government. Acquiring the necessary data, either through the collection of new data or by blending information from multiple data sources, is a critical step in ensuring equity is a central component of decision-making processes across the Federal government. Agencies have also begun to identify where data gaps are making it more difficult to conduct equity assessments of their policies, programs, and services.</p>



<p>The Equitable Data Working Group is a multi-disciplinary group, composed of government leaders in program policy, statistics, social science, data science, and information technology that is initially taking a case-study approach to the work, which will pave the way to lasting change. The end goal is regular systematic measurement of equity and inequities throughout the Federal government.</p>



<p>Our case study approach focuses our initial efforts on a set of well-defined questions that have historically been difficult to answer for lack of sufficient data. For instance, questions under consideration currently include:</p>



<ul><li>If we had data about the race, ethnicity, and gender of those using or not using unemployment benefits, could we better understand the impact of labor market cycles on underserved subpopulations?</li><li>Can we better understand the distribution of programs and services in underserved communities, particularly in response to climate-related crises?</li><li>What disaggregated data is needed to measure whether the CARES Act benefits and American Rescue Plan benefits were equitably distributed?</li></ul>



<p>In each instance, the group aims to focus on high-impact data collection and prioritize cases that could create immediate value for local communities, policymakers, and academic researchers, alongside broad impact across the Federal government. Our intent is for these initial case studies to highlight the specific challenges that need to be addressed to establish and sustain equitable data practices across the Federal government, and ultimately form the basis of broader recommendations for how these practices can illuminate equity considerations in program and policy design, implementation, and outcomes.</p>



<p>By exploring key policy questions dependent upon underutilized, inaccessible, or missing data, the Equitable Data Working Group will explore ways to leverage government data in order to measure and promote equity. For example, in some cases the data needed to respond to an issue may exist, but there are so many barriers that it is underutilized. Part of our charge is to look for ways to responsibly promote agency data sharing and matching, to the extent permitted by law, to create datasets needed to answer relevant questions. Accordingly, we may make recommendations requiring regulatory or legislative changes.</p>



<p>As the Equitable Data Working Group proceeds in our work, we recognize that it is necessary to consider challenges for unintentional disclosure of personal information and privacy protection. We must be able to collect and share data about underserved communities—including Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander; lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, and queer (LGBTQ+); and rural communities—in ways that do not exacerbate their vulnerability, particularly when using or providing public-use data with high levels of detail.</p>



<p>We will also highlight areas of particular importance to advancing equity outcomes where the Federal government needs to collect additional information, because the data needed to illuminate or respond to an issue are low-quality or do not exist. For instance, very few Federal surveys and datasets provide the ability to characterize the experiences and life outcomes of those who identify as LGBTQ+ Americans, making it challenging for Federal policymakers, researchers, and the American people to ensure equitable life outcomes for LGBTQ+ people. As a modest step toward ensuring Federal data practices reflect and include LGBTQ+ individuals and families, we worked with the Office of the Chief Statistician and the U.S. Census Bureau to begin the process of including questions about sexual orientation and gender identity for the first time in their Household Pulse Survey beginning this month. The Household Pulse Survey measures how the coronavirus pandemic is impacting households across the country from a social and economic perspective. By including questions about sexual orientation and gender identity, Federal agencies and researchers will gain critical new insights into the impacts that the COVID-19 pandemic and resulting economic crisis has had on LGBTQ+ Americans. Going forward, we intend to continue work with key Federal agencies to identify opportunities for appropriate and dignified data collection on sexual orientation and gender identity.</p>



<p>The Equitable Data Working Group will provide an initial report to Ambassador Susan Rice, Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy, by Fall 2021. The report will communicate specific barriers and gaps to equitable data identified through our case studies and direct consultation with agencies and external stakeholders. The report will also include recommendations as to how to address those barriers. In this vein, the Equitable Data Working Group is seeking to foster new partnerships between Federal agencies, academic and research partners, state, local, and tribal governments, community and advocacy groups, and other stakeholders, in order to leverage Federal data for new insights on the effects of structurally biased policies, and to advance capacity for multilayered, intersectional analysis of Federal datasets. We’re already seeing this happen across some agencies, including the <a href="https://www.dol.gov/agencies/oasp/evaluation/currentstudies/Department-of-Labor-Summer-Data-Challenge" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Department of Labor’s Summer Data Challenge on Equity and Underserved Communities</a>, and we hope to help replicate these promising approaches.</p>



<p>We plan to keep the public updated on our work and regularly share examples of how the Equitable Data Working Group is working across Federal agencies, in consultation with the Chief Data Officers Council, Evaluation Officer Council and Interagency Committee on Standards Policy, and in partnership with communities and other stakeholders outside the Federal government. We recognize that many have worked for years to advance this work, and we are both excited about the promise that this moment holds and clear-eyed about the challenges that have stalled progress in the past. Our approach is intended to assess systemic barriers and stimulate long-term change that seeks to go beyond a one-time project. Further, we hope agencies will be able to use what we learn as they develop and commit to ongoing efforts to advance equity in their Action Plans due in January 2022. We are eager to learn from how others have approached this issue in their own organizations and sectors, and welcome input into our approach. We have been pleased to hear feedback from the public via the recent <a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2021/05/05/2021-09109/methods-and-leading-practices-for-advancing-equity-and-support-for-underserved-communities-through" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Request for Information</a> on <em>Methods and Leading Practices for Advancing Equity and Support for Underserved Communities</em> through Government and we look forward to future engagement.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Blueprint for a Fair, Orderly and Humane Immigration System</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/27/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-blueprint-for-a-fair-orderly-and-humane-immigration-system/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25095</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States can have an orderly, secure, and well-managed border while treating people fairly and humanely. In January, the Biden-Harris Administration launched a broad, whole of government effort to reform our immigration system, including sending to Congress legislation that creates a new system to responsibly manage and secure our border, provide a pathway to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States can have an orderly, secure, and well-managed border while treating people fairly and humanely.</p>



<p>In January, the Biden-Harris Administration <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/01/20/fact-sheet-president-biden-sends-immigration-bill-to-congress-as-part-of-his-commitment-to-modernize-our-immigration-system/">launched</a> a broad, whole of government effort to reform our immigration system, including sending to Congress legislation that creates a new system to responsibly manage and secure our border, provide a pathway to citizenship, and better manage migration across the Hemisphere.</p>



<p>In the six months since, the Administration has made considerable <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/15/action-the-biden-harris-administration-has-taken-to-address-the-border-challenge/">progress</a> to build a fair, orderly, and humane immigration system while continuing to call on Congress to make long overdue reforms to U.S. immigration laws. We successfully processed over 12,500 people who had been returned to Mexico under the Migrant Protection Protocols. We expanded lawful pathways for protection and opportunity, including the Central American Minors (CAM) program to reunite children with their parents in the United States. We strengthened collaborative migration management with regional partners, including through a new Human Smuggling and Trafficking Task Force to disrupt and prevent migrant smuggling and human trafficking operations. And we continue to deter irregular migration at our Southern border.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has accomplished this and more while reckoning with the prior Administration’s cruel and reckless immigration policies, which exacerbated long-standing challenges and failed to securely manage our border. Case in point: the total number of unique encounters at the Southern border to date this fiscal year remains below the total number of unique encounters to date during fiscal year 2019 under the Trump Administration.</p>



<p>Today the Administration is releasing a blueprint that outlines the next steps Federal agencies will be taking to continue implementing the President’s transformative vision for a 21st century immigration system that secures the border, fairly and efficiently considers asylum claims, strengthens regional migration management efforts in North and Central America, and addresses the root causes of migration from Central America. Success in building this fair, orderly, and humane immigration system won’t be achieved overnight, especially after the prior Administration’s irrational and inhumane policies, but this Administration has a blueprint to get there and is making real progress.</p>



<p>We will always be a nation of borders, and we will enforce our immigration laws in a way that is fair and just. We will continue to work to fortify an orderly immigration system.</p>



<p><strong>ENSURING A SECURE, HUMANE AND WELL-MANAGED BORDER</strong></p>



<p>The United States can allow people to exercise their legal right to apply for asylum while also reducing irregular migration and maintaining an orderly, secure, and well-managed border.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Making better use of existing enforcement resources. </strong>Since fiscal year 2011, U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s (CBP) discretionary budget has grown from $9.9 billion to $15 billion in FY 2021. The President’s Budget redirects resources from a needless border wall to make robust investments in smarter border security measures, like border technology and modernization of land ports of entry, that are proven to be more effective at improving safety and security at the border. These investments will serve as a force multiplier to the over 19,500 Border Patrol Agents currently helping secure our Nation’s borders and the over 25,500 CBP Officers working at our land, air, and sea ports. The investments will also facilitate more robust and effective security screening to combat human smuggling and trafficking and the entry of undocumented migrants.</li><li><strong>Improving the expedited removal process for those who arrive at the border.</strong> The Administration is working to improve the expedited removal process at the border to fairly and efficiently determine which individuals have legitimate claims for asylum and other forms of protection. Asylum and other legal migration pathways should remain available to those seeking protection. Those not seeking protection or who don’t qualify will be promptly removed to their countries of origin.</li><li><strong>Facilitating secure management of borders in the region </strong>by providing training and technical assistance, supporting the improvement of border infrastructure and technology, and promoting collaborative migration and border management approaches.</li><li><strong>Strengthening anti-smuggling and anti-trafficking operations </strong>by working with regional governments to investigate and prosecute individuals involved in migrant smuggling, human trafficking, and other crimes against migrants. In April 2021, DHS announced Operation Sentinel, a new operation targeting organizations involved in criminal smuggling.</li><li><strong>Bolstering public messaging on migration </strong>by ensuring consistent messages to discourage irregular migration and promote safe, legal, and orderly migration.</li></ul>



<p><strong>IMPLEMENTING ORDERLY AND FAIR PROCESSING OF ASYLUM APPLICATIONS</strong></p>



<p>The Administration is committed to fairly and efficiently considering asylum claims. Asylum and other legal migration pathways should remain available to those seeking protection. But those not seeking protection or who don’t qualify will be returned to their country of origin.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Establishing a dedicated docket to consider asylum claims.</strong> The Administration has set up a special immigration court docket to promptly and fairly consider the protection claims of certain recent arrivals.</li><li><strong>Further improving the efficiency and fairness of the U.S. asylum system </strong>by authorizing asylum officers to adjudicate asylum claims for those arriving at the border and establishing clear and just eligibility standards that harmonize the U.S. approach with international standards. The Administration has already begun to rescind Trump administration policies and decisions that unjustly prevent individuals from obtaining asylum. On June 16, the Department of Justice reversed two of the former administration’s rulings severely restricting asylum protections for victims of domestic and gang violence.</li><li><strong>Maximizing legal representation </strong>and legal orientation programs by working closelywith pro bono legal service providers. The President’s FY 2022 Budget requests $15 million to provide representation to families and vulnerable individuals, as well as $23 million to support DOJ legal orientation programs.</li><li><strong>Reducing immigration court backlogs</strong> by ensuring priority cases are considered in a timely manner and hiring more immigration judges. The FY 2022 Budget requests an additional 100 immigration judges and provides support for additional court staff to ensure the efficient and fair processing of cases.  The Department of Justice also restored the discretion of immigration judges to administratively close cases in another step to ensure priority cases are considered in a timely manner.</li></ul>



<p><strong>STRENGTHENING COLLABORATIVE MIGRATION MANAGEMENT WITH REGIONAL PARTNERS</strong></p>



<p>The United States seeks to expand U.S. and multilateral efforts to address the dire humanitarian situation in Central America and strengthen regional collaborative migration management.  The United States believes that all individuals should be able to have a safe, stable and dignified life within their own countries, while ensuring that asylum and other legal migration pathways remain available to those who need them.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing humanitarian support to address the acute needs that pressure individuals to abandon their homes</strong>.  U.S. efforts will address food insecurity and malnutrition, mitigate the impacts of successive droughts and food shortages, promote protection for vulnerable individuals, and provide materials to support rebuilding of homes and schools damaged by the hurricanes.  The United States will also work with the United Nations to mobilize international support for the deteriorating situation in the Northern Triangle. As part of these efforts, the United States in April <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/apr-27-2021-united-states-announces-increased-assistance-people-of-el-salvador-guatemala-honduras">provided</a> $255 million in assistance to meet immediate and urgent humanitarian needs for people in El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras, refugees, other displaced people, and vulnerable migrants in the region.</li><li><strong>Expanding access to international protection</strong> to provide safety to individuals closer to their homes by building and improving national asylum systems, enhancing efforts to resettle refugees, and scaling up protection efforts for at-risk groups.</li><li><strong>Establishing Migration Resource</strong> <strong>Centers</strong> in the Northern Triangle countries with the support of international organizations and in coordination with governments in Central America to provide referrals to services for people seeking lawful pathways for migration and protection.  The centers also provide referrals to reintegration support for migrants returned from the United States and other countries.</li><li><strong>Restarting and expanding the Central American Minors (CAM) program </strong>to provide children the opportunity to receive protection and reunite with parents in the United States. In March 2021, the United States reopened the CAM program and, in June 2021, expanded it to additional categories of eligible U.S.-based relatives who can petition for their children.</li><li><strong>Expanding refugee processing in the region</strong>, including in-country processing in Northern Triangle countries, and helping international organizations and local non-governmental organizations to identify and refer individuals with urgent protection needs to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program and other resettlement countries. The U.S. Department of State and Department of Homeland Security have resumed interviewing individuals via the Protection Transfer Arrangement (PTA) to expand protection for vulnerable nationals of El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras.</li><li><strong>Expanding access to temporary work visas in the region.  </strong>DHS announced a supplemental increase of 6,000 H-2B visas for temporary non-agricultural workers from Honduras, Guatemala and El Salvador in FY 2021. The Administration is also exploring ways to enhance access to H-2A visas for temporary agricultural workers when there are insufficient qualified U.S. workers to fill these jobs, while ensuring strong labor protections for all workers.  The Administration will also encourage other governments to develop and expand regional labor migration programs that protect workers’ rights and allow access for individuals to find meaningful, temporary work.</li><li><strong>Reducing immigrant visa backlogs.  </strong>The United States aims to reduce the backlog of immigrant visa applications for Northern Triangle nationals as quickly as possible.</li></ul>



<p><strong>INVESTING IN CENTRAL AMERICA TO ADDRESS THE ROOT CAUSES OF MIGRATION</strong></p>



<p>We cannot solve the challenge at our border without addressing the lack of economic opportunity, weak governance and corruption, and violence and insecurity that compel people to flee their homes in the first place.  The impact of two major hurricanes in late 2020, a prolonged drought, and COVID-19 have aggravated these long-standing challenges.  The FY 2022 Budget requests $861 million to address the root causes of migration.    </p>



<ul><li><strong>Addressing economic insecurity and inequality </strong>by investing in programs that foster a business-enabling environment for inclusive economic growth; enhancing workforce development, health, and education; and building resilience to climate change and food insecurity so individuals can find economic opportunity at home. The U.S. will also work with stakeholders to increase trade and diversify industry, as well as with the private sector to build on the <em>Call to Action</em> to catalyze investments in the region and support economic development.</li><li><strong>Combatting corruption and strengthening democratic governance </strong>by working with governments, civil society, and independent media to improve government services, increase transparency, promote accountability and respect for human rights, sanction corrupt actors, and provide protection to at-risk youth, victims of violence, and other marginalized populations.</li><li><strong>Promoting respect for human rights, labor rights and a free press</strong> by working with governments and civil society to strengthen legal frameworks and build institutional capacity, hold perpetrators accountable, promote labor rights compliance, and ensure citizens have access to information from independent sources to inform their choices.</li><li><strong>Countering and preventing violence, extortion, and other crimes</strong> by strengthening accountable law enforcement, focusing on crime prevention, and encouraging regional cooperation to address shared criminal threats.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Combatting sexual, gender-based and domestic violence </strong>by working with governments and civil society to prevent and prosecute violence and support victims.</li></ul>



<p>While President Biden can implement significant parts of this strategy within his executive authority, <strong><u>Congress must also act.</u></strong>  Millions of noncitizens call our country home.  Immigrants are key a key part of our communities and make significant contributions to our economy.  Over the past year, millions of immigrants have risked their health to work side by side with other Americans to perform jobs that are essential to the functioning of the country.  They are Americans in every way but on paper.  The American public supports a path to citizenship and a fair and efficient legal immigration system that welcomes talent from around the globe and allows families to reunite and make a life in our country.</p>



<p><strong>Congress should pass </strong>through reconciliation or other means:</p>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">The U.S. Citizenship Act (H.R. 1177/S. 348)</span> that reunites families, gives businesses access to a workforce with full labor rights, and creates a path to citizenship for those already living and working in the United States.  These critical reforms, coupled with measures to address the root causes of migration from Central America, will relieve pressure at the border by dissuading irregular migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><span style="text-decoration: underline">The Dream and Promise Act (H.R. 6) and Farm Workforce Modernization Act (H.R. 1603)</span> to create a path to citizenship for Dreamers, TPS recipients, and farmworkers. Both bills passed the House with bipartisan support.  They will protect millions of families, children, and essential workers who live, work, study, and worship in our communities. </li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Meeting with Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi of Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/07/26/readout-of-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-meeting-with-prime-minister-al-kadhimi-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 00:53:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=25083</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi of Iraq to strengthen bilateral coordination under the Strategic Framework Agreement.&#160; Together they discussed expanded initiatives on climate, energy, education, and combatting the COVID-19 pandemic.&#160; They committed to a continued security partnership to ensure that ISIS can never resurge and to allow communities recovering&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi of Iraq to strengthen bilateral coordination under the Strategic Framework Agreement.&nbsp; Together they discussed expanded initiatives on climate, energy, education, and combatting the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; They committed to a continued security partnership to ensure that ISIS can never resurge and to allow communities recovering from terror to rebuild with dignity even as the United States shifts to a purely advisory role. The leaders reaffirmed their respect for Iraq’s democracy, the rule of law, and promoting a secure environment for Iraq’s upcoming elections in October. The leaders agreed on the vital importance of holding these elections on time, and welcomed the UN monitoring mission to support their full transparency and fairness.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Together, they discussed the important role of Iraq in the region and the significant diplomatic efforts led by Prime Minister Al-Kadhimi to improve and strengthen Iraq’s relationships in the region.&nbsp; They lauded the historic visit of Pope Francis to Iraq earlier this year, the trilateral summit with Egypt and Jordan, and the important role Iraq plays in promoting interfaith tolerance and the common bonds of humanity in the Middle East.&nbsp; They agreed that Iraq’s stability was central to the stability of the entire region.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
