<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 18:48:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Deputy Press Secretary Andrew Bates En Route Philadelphia,&#160;PA</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/11/press-gaggle-by-deputy-press-secretary-andrew-bates-en-route-philadelphia-pa/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 18:48:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48958</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 11:37 A.M. EST MR. BATES:&#160; I have a little bit for you at the top.&#160; So, today, after giving the keynote address at the House Democratic Issues Conference, President Biden will visit a Philadelphia-area, majority-Hispanic elementary school to highlight how the American Rescue Plan is delivering critical resources&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Philadelphia, Pennsylvania</p>



<p>11:37 A.M. EST</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; I have a little bit for you at the top.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, today, after giving the keynote address at the House Democratic Issues Conference, President Biden will visit a Philadelphia-area, majority-Hispanic elementary school to highlight how the American Rescue Plan is delivering critical resources to keep schools safe and open, combat learning loss, and address student mental health.</p>



<p>When the President entered office, only 46 percent of schools were open; today, over 99 percent are.&nbsp; That was not by accident; it was the product of his historic investments not just to get schools open, but ensure they have the resources to address the long-term impact COVID has had on schools and students.</p>



<p>Today’s visit will highlight how American Rescue Plan dollars are enabling this school to help students catch up, including hiring more school staff, providing tutoring, and providing afterschool programs that are supporting student mental health.&nbsp; And that is reflective of what has been achieved across the country on account of the American Rescue Plan, which, again, every single Republican in Congress voted against.</p>



<p>President Biden will also speak with students directly to hear candidly about the issues they are facing today.</p>



<p>And then, Judge Jackson just wrapped her second successful week of meetings with senators in both parties, all of whom have been gracious hosts and who have asked engaging questions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you know, the President chose her because she&#8217;s an extraordinarily qualified jurist with experience at all levels of our justice system; who’s devoted to the Constitution and the rule of law; and who assesses cases fairly, neutrally, based solely on the facts; and who has been confirmed three times on a bipartisan basis by the Senate already.</p>



<p>In fact, Senator McConnell said last week that there is, quote, “no question” she&#8217;s qualified to serve on the Supreme Court.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, Senator Cornyn highlighted her practical experience as a judge, a criterion he said is important.</p>



<p>And I want to just take a minute to appreciate the broad set of endorsements that have come in for her, including from law enforcement.&nbsp; Out of the gate, Fraternal Order of Police issued a statement saying, “From our analysis of Judge Jackson’s record and some of her cases, we believe she has considered the facts and applied the law consistently and fairly on a range of issues.&nbsp; There is little doubt that she has the temperament, intellect, legal experience, and family background to have earned this appointment.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>That was followed shortly after by the National Organization of Black Law Enforcement Executives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This week, a large group of law enforcement officials from across the country, including a number of police chiefs, wrote to the Senate urging that she have &#8212; that she be confirmed in a timely manner.&nbsp; We saw a group of former U.S. attorneys do the same.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday, a group of 83 former state attorneys general from both parties wrote to the Senate urging her confirmation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Retired D.C. Circuit Judge Thomas Griffith has urged her confirmation, as has retired Fourth Circuit Court of Appeals Judge J. Michael Luttig, both of whom are highly respected conservatives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Conservative attorney William Burck, who represented Trump White House Counsel Don McGahn and a number of other senior Trump officials in court, has said that she is as qualified as anyone can be. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And I just wanted to take a minute to take stock of that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then a quick preview of next week for you: The President will sign the bipartisan funding bill, which takes some time for Congress to process, get to his desk.&nbsp; In the meantime, he will sign the short-term continuing resolution to keep the government open until the bipartisan funding bill is signed.</p>



<p>On Monday, the President will address the National League of Cities Congressional City Conference.</p>



<p>On Tuesday, Equal Pay Day, the President, Vice President, First Lady, and Second Gentleman will participate in an event in the East Room to celebrate Women&#8217;s History Month.</p>



<p>And on Thursday, I think it is a decent bet that we will commemorate St. Patrick&#8217;s Day.</p>



<p>And with that, I’m happy to take you all’s questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Two questions for you, Andrew.&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; First, President Biden, just a few hours ago, said that Russia would face a severe price should they use chemical weapons against Ukraine.&nbsp; What exactly did he mean, especially when, after these waves of &#8212; waves of sanctions already implemented, it does not appear yet that President Putin has buckled under the pressure?</p>



<p>And then second, just yesterday, U.S. Ambassador to the U.N., Linda Thomas-Greenfield, she said that what Putin has done to Ukraine constitutes a war crime.&nbsp; But already twice, when asked, Vice President Harris hasn’t matched that language.&nbsp; So what does the White House believe?&nbsp; Does it believe that Russia&#8217;s actions against Ukraine constitute war crimes?</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; Well, like you just mentioned, you heard from the President clearly that if Russia uses chemical weapons, there will be severe consequences.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview on that front, but he&#8217;s his meaning was unmistakable.</p>



<p>And when it comes to chemical weapons specifically, as you know, one of the false flags or pretexts that Russia has been indicating they might attempt to employ here is chemical weapons.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve warned about that for some time.&nbsp; We decided to participate in the recent Security Council session about this, not just to forcefully debunk Russian gaslighting on this subject, but to further call Putin out, as we have during this entire episode successfully at each juncture, where we have reason to believe they are trying to fabricate another false justification for more violence.</p>



<p>The truth is: Russia is the only country in this equation with a chemical and biological weapons program in violation of international law.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re not going to be specific about intelligence, which the President also mentioned this morning.&nbsp; But look no further than Russia&#8217;s track record.&nbsp; They have used chemical weapons &#8212; which, again, they are the only country in the mix here who possesses those &#8212; in Syria.&nbsp; And time again, we have warned about this particular pretext.&nbsp; And so it is something that we are being attentive to.</p>



<p>When it comes to war crimes, we have all seen the devastating images coming out of Ukraine and are appalled<a> </a>by Russia&#8217;s brutal tactics.&nbsp; Pregnant women on stretchers, apartment buildings shelled, families killed while seeking safety from this terrible violence.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are also seeing reports of other types of potential abuses, including sexual and gender-based violence.&nbsp; These are disgusting attacks.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Civilian casualties are increasing.&nbsp; If Russia is intentionally targeting civilians, that would be a war crime.&nbsp; And as we are all seeing on live television, evidence is mounting.&nbsp; And we are documenting it as it takes place.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There are strong indications that this is occurring and that the heinous way Russia is prosecuting this war will result in war crimes.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We are supporting the important work of human rights activists, civil society, and independent media in Ukraine who are documenting, collecting, and exposing evidence of possible war crimes, human rights abuses, and violations of international humanitarian law.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We will share the evidence we gather with allies and partners and with those investigations &#8212; investigators to support accountability using every tool available, including criminal prosecutions when appropriate.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On the trade announcement today &#8212; are you seeking higher tariffs on all Russian imports to the U.S. or only certain ones?&nbsp; And are those tariff levels going to be coordinated with European allies?</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; So, what I&#8217;ve got there is, like you mentioned, we&#8217;re revoking Russia&#8217;s most-favored-nation status, which is going to mean that Russian imports to the United States face tariffs and other &#8212; and other barriers.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And &#8212; you know what?&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t we take a seat and continue?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Too late.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. BATES:&nbsp; Well, all right.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Never mind, I just didn&#8217;t want anybody to get &#8212; get hurt there.&nbsp; Just one second.</p>



<p>(Gaggle interrupted as Air Force One lands.)</p>



<p>But we are going to include seafood, spirits, vodka, non-industrial diamonds, in terms of the Russian imports that are banned.&nbsp; And we are also going to be restricting U.S. exports to Russia so that they are not receiving luxury items like high-end watches, luxury vehicles, high-end apparel, high-end alcohol, jewelry, other goods frequently purchased by Russian elites.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I want to underscore that the countries with whom we&#8217;re working in unison on this represent 50 percent of the global economy.&nbsp; It is going to take a significant toll on Russia, in addition to the steps we have already taken, which have resulted in the ruble being worth less than a penny, has resulted in their stock market being closed for an historic period of time.&nbsp;&nbsp; It has resulted in their credit rating being labeled “junk” by authorities.&nbsp;</p>



<p>(Gaggle interrupted as Air Force One crew deplanes.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Andrew, is the U.S. in touch with India and Pakistan about India having accidentally launched a missile into Pakistan?&nbsp; And are &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. BATES:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have updates for you on that.&nbsp; I can see if our national security team does a little bit later.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And do you have any updates on the status of the Iran talks?&nbsp; Russia is demanding that the agreement inclu- &#8212; preclude sanctions on &#8212; related to Ukraine, impacting their ability to trade with Iran.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. BATES:&nbsp; So, Russia has taken some public positions attempting to tie the JCPOA to unrelated issues like Ukraine, so we&#8217;re working through that with European allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the bottom line is: It is in our national security interest and the national security interest of everyone involved, including Russia, to prevent Iran from obtaining a nuclear weapon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is the endgame of the sanctions exactly, knowing that more have been imposed today?&nbsp; What does the U.S. believe needs to be done in order to resolve this war in Ukraine?</p>



<p>MR. BATES:&nbsp; Well, we have provided Putin with possible off-ramps from the beginning, and we will continue to do so.&nbsp; But he is the only one who can decide whether to take them.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So far, every time he has had an opportunity to take an off-ramp, he&#8217;s instead gone full speed ahead.&nbsp; And the longer he forces his abused troops to attack Ukraine, the more he broadcasts his own profound weakness as a leader.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Putin&#8217;s only strategy has been escalation at every turn, but it&#8217;s becoming increasingly clear that it&#8217;s escalation without an endgame.&nbsp; And his erratic brutality, which comes at the expense of the Russian people and, again, his own demoralized troops, is proving to be a disaster for his country.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He has a clear plan to be savage toward Ukraine, but to what end?&nbsp; His initial military plan to quickly capture Ukraine and force a capitulation has failed.&nbsp; Now he&#8217;s turning to a strategy of laying waste to population centers to try and break the will of the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; But that strategy will make effective long-term Russian control of Ukraine impossible.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Meanwhile, the world is rallying around the Ukrainians.&nbsp; And we are exacting an enormous and historic toll on Russians’ &#8212; Russia&#8217;s economy because of his war of choice.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What future off-ramps do you have in mind?<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MR. BATES:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything more to preview.&nbsp; But as today&#8217;s actions make clear, the more that this continues, not only is he losing people on the ground to whom he has lied about the cause for going into Ukraine unprovoked, but the Russian economy is in tatters.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; They have lost 30 years of economic progress when it comes to integrating their economy with the world in a matter of weeks.&nbsp; That is not going to stop until he stops.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then the last thing is: Yesterday, we heard President Biden accuse Republicans of playing games with oil prices amid a couple other accusations.&nbsp; Does this amount to a preview of the midterm messaging?&nbsp; And how are you guys going to weather both inflation and rising oil prices?</p>



<p>MR. BATES:  So I can&#8217;t speak to midterm messaging directly from here.  But, factually, I think it&#8217;s important to keep in mind, first of all, every action that we have taken to punish Russia for Putin&#8217;s unprovoked further invasion of Ukraine has had strong bipartisan support and buy-in.  And, of course, Russia&#8217;s destabilizing actions have played an important role in recent increases in gas prices. <br><br>     But I&#8217;m glad you raised this, because the New York Times had a very conclusive fact check yesterday.  The headline was: “Republicans Wrongly Blame Biden for Rising Gas Prices.”  And so I think it&#8217;s important to note that independent arbiters in the press have consulted experts and they have deemed that these attacks are disingenuous and that the rising gas prices you&#8217;ve seen all over the world, but beforehand, are due to the pandemic and pressures that has put on international supply. <br><br>     So, thank you all.  Sorry, we didn&#8217;t have more time. <br><br>  11:51 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris and President Iohannis of Romania in Joint Press&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/11/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-and-president-iohannis-of-romania-in-joint-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 18:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48842</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cotroceni PalaceBucharest, Romania 4:14 P.M. EET PRESIDENT IOHANNIS:&#160; (As interpreted.)&#160; Good afternoon.&#160; I’m pleased to welcome to Bucharest Vice President of the United States of America, Her Excellency, Madam Kamala Harris.&#160; Dear Madam Vice President, welcome to Romania. I would like to thank Madam Vice President for her presence in Romania in this challenging moment&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Cotroceni Palace<br>Bucharest, Romania</em></p>



<p>4:14 P.M. EET<br><br>PRESIDENT IOHANNIS:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; I’m pleased to welcome to Bucharest Vice President of the United States of America, Her Excellency, Madam Kamala Harris.&nbsp;<br><br>Dear Madam Vice President, welcome to Romania.<br><br>I would like to thank Madam Vice President for her presence in Romania in this challenging moment for the democratic community and for the Euro-Atlantic security.<br><br>Your visit, Madam Vice President, reflects once more the strength and solidity of the bilateral strategic partnership and the firm commitment of the United States for the security of Romania and NATO Allies from the eastern flank.<br><br>I have conveyed to Madam Vice President the appreciation of Romania for the efforts and leadership of the United States, of President Biden, of Madam Vice President, and of the entire Washington administration in this very complicated context.<br><br>The continuous dialogue and the close coordination of the United States with Romania and with all the Allies and partners had an essential contribution to delivering a unified and strong message of the international community to the actions of Russia.<br><br>Together, we have come up with a firm and prompt response, both from the point of view of assistance in multiple areas, both for Ukraine and for the individuals affected by the conflict, both when it comes to the sanctions applied to Russia and to the measures for adopting the Allied posture in its entirety, especially on the eastern flank.<br><br>Madam Vice President has reconfirmed as part of our &#8212; today’s discussions the full commitment of the United States of America for the Article 5 regarding the collective defense of the NATO Washington Treaty.&nbsp; This Article contains the essence and spirit of NATO and guarantees that any attempt to impact the security of one NATO state will receive a firm, prompt response of the entire Alliance.<br><br>I’m saying it with a great responsibility: NATO will act without hesitation to defend each and every Allied state, including obviously Romania.&nbsp; It is a scenario that all of us want to avoid.&nbsp; But we, as Allies &#8212; and I’m saying it while I stand next to our most important strategic partner &#8212; will defend every inch when it comes to respecting the commitments that bind us.<br><br>I have conveyed my gratitude for these unshakeable security guarantees as the Romanian society has never had in its history, and thanks to which every citizen of Romania can be confident about his own safety and the safety of his family.</p>



<p>I have also conveyed my gratitude for the consolidation of the United States military presence in Romania.&nbsp; We have also discussed about the need within this tense context to keep increasing the American and Allied presence in Romania in the long run as an additional measure to ensure the security of our country and of the entire region.</p>



<p>I have conveyed that, in turn, Romania understands that the security starts at home.&nbsp; And from this point of view, I have recently decided to increase the defense expenses from 2 percent, where it stands now, to 2.5 percent of GDP.&nbsp; And this is greatly appreciated by the American side.</p>



<p>Together with Madam Vice President, we have assessed the long-term implications of the aggression that is taking place in Ukraine, as well as the Russian military presence in Belarus and the Euro-Atlantic.</p>



<p>We have agreed to cooperate to further consolidate the defense measures and deterrence on the eastern flank with a focus on the southern part.</p>



<p>I have highlighted the fact that, in this context, it is necessary to operationalize as soon as possible the NATO battle group on the territory of Romania.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Overall, Romania’s strategic assessment is that it becomes necessary to fundamentally rethink the concept, the structure, and the constituent elements of the NATO posture on the eastern flank, taking into account the fact that the current circumstances are considerably different compared to the moment when the current approach concerning the eastern flank was projected.</p>



<p>We need a united forward presence and a coherent one as soon as possible.&nbsp; We have discussed today about our common approach in order to come up with a common response to these unprecedented challenges, especially when it comes to the humanitarian area.</p>



<p>Romania, the United States, along with its Allied and partner countries, have offered assistance in different domains to Ukraine and its people that fights with heroism, courage, and determination.</p>



<p>As you know, I have decided the operationalization in Suceava of a humanitarian logistics facility &#8212; so-called hub &#8212; that, thanks to the support of the European Union, has the role to collect and transport the international donations in the area of humanitarian assistance for Ukrainian citizens.&nbsp; I have invited the United States to support the activity of this hub.</p>



<p>We have also discussed about the support that is so necessary to the Republic of Moldova.&nbsp; The situation of the neighboring country is unique from the point of view of a very high ratio between the number of refugees and population.&nbsp; This pressure overlaps with the economic and energy-related difficulties that the Republic of Moldova has to face.</p>



<p>Together with Madam Vice President, we have analyzed the energy security prospects.&nbsp; We agreed that this crisis can represent a historic opportunity to switch &#8212; to reach a true European energy independence from the Russian gas through investments in renewable sources in the civilian nuclear sector; through diversifying sources, imports of liquefied natural gas; and, obviously, through increased interconnectivity.<br><br>As you probably remember, within the context of COP26 Glasgow Summit, the common Romania-USA project to include small modular reactors in the Romanian national system &#8212; we agreed to continue and to intensify our cooperation in this strategic domain.</p>



<p>Last but not least, a fundamental aspect for the success of our efforts and to ensure &#8212; ensuring our common security is represented by the maintenance and consolidation of the transatlantic relationship by ensuring the unity and coordination of the European Union, United States, NATO, and G7.</p>



<p>Romania brought its own contribution in this regard by promoting the Bucharest Nine format, which was very efficient, even in this context.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This year, we celebrate 25 years from the launch of our strategic partnership that continuously developed during the last years and is currently at its highest level in its history.</p>



<p>In addition to the consolidated cooperation in the area of defense and security, and of the ambitious initiatives in the energy sector, I have discussed with Madam Vice President to continue expanding all the dimensions of the strategic partnership, from the economic one, including through the development of regional priorities, strategic projects related to the interconnectivity and that are of interest for Romania, and up to the consolidation of scientific cooperation and of, obviously, interhuman relationships.</p>



<p>We also discussed about visa waiver topic in regards to Romania, and we hope to have some results in this area as well.</p>



<p>Once again, I would like to thank Vice President Harris for coming to Romania.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure that the substantive discussions that we had will be followed up by concrete measures and adequate &#8212; appropriate decisions for the unprecedented context in which we currently find ourselves in.<br><br>Thank you, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; You have the floor.<br><br>&nbsp;VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you, President Iohannis, for the warm welcome to Romania and for your steadfast friendship to the partnership that we have that is longstanding and enduring.&nbsp;<br><br>I also want to recognize and thank Prime Minister Ciucă for the conversation that we had last week.<br><br>If I may, Mr. President, I&#8217;d like to speak directly to the Romanian people for one moment, to thank you, on behalf of the United States.<br><br>Under the leadership of President Iohannis, Romania has been extraordinary in the generosity and the courage that you have shown in this moment.&nbsp; Around the world, we have watched as you have received refugees.&nbsp; Around the world, and I will speak for the United States, we know of the particular challenges that you face geographically, yet you have shown so much courage.<br><br>The meeting that the President and I had today was a very productive meeting to reaffirm the strength of the relationship and friendship between the United States and Romania.&nbsp;<br><br>I&#8217;ve said many times, including this afternoon with the President and the President&#8217;s leadership, but around the world, and I will say it here: America&#8217;s commitment to Article 5 is ironclad.&nbsp; We take very seriously our role and the relationships that we have within the NATO Alliance.&nbsp;<br><br>We take seriously and are prepared to act on the words we speak when we say an attack against one is an attack against all.&nbsp; We are firm in our commitment &#8212; when I say and we say over and over again, President Joe Biden says: We will defend every inch of NATO territory.<br><br>So I am present in Romania today to reaffirm that commitment, in addition to thanking the president, your leadership, and the people of Romania.&nbsp;<br><br>The strength of our Alliance has endured and is now bigger and stronger than ever.&nbsp; The strength of our Alliance includes our mutual commitment to stand on the principles that we hold dear and share, that include the defense of the sovereignty and territorial integrity of independent states &#8212; and in this case, Ukraine.<br><br>We are clear that the work that is to be done in response to Putin&#8217;s war includes standing strong within the Alliance to support the needs of our partners.&nbsp; To that end, and to demonstrate our commitment as the United States, in recent weeks we sent a 1,000-member Stryker squadron.&nbsp; That creates a total force of 2,000 American troops who are prepared to stand in defense of our commitment to the NATO Alliance and the eastern flank.<br><br>We have reinforced our recent commitments, all with the mention and with the meaning of strengthening our deterrence and our collective defense.<br><br>I want to thank you, President Iohannis, for your leadership on NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.&nbsp; I want to thank you for in addition to doing all that you have been doing in your role of leadership, to modernizing and to increasing the resources that are available.<br><br>You and I talked about the importance of running a government in a way that we modernize and are efficient and effective with the resources we have.&nbsp; You have been a model in that regard, and I thank you.<br><br>In terms of our mutual support for the people of Ukraine &#8212; in Washington, in the United States Congress, we have taken recent action, including a commitment of $13.6 billion<br>for Ukraine and the region in terms of security assistance and humanitarian assistance.&nbsp;<br><br>The President &#8212; Iohannis and I talked extensively, and I was very moved, Mr. President, by the stories you shared with me of the time you spent with refugees, and the heart-wrenching experience that they are having.<br><br>So we stand together, Romania and the United States, in ensuring that we will do all that is required to put resources into the humanitarian piece of this, understanding that the needs are significant and immediate.<br><br>To the extent that we are offering humanitarian assistance, in addition to the $13.6 billion package from the United States Congress, $4 billion of that will be directly committed to humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; That is on top of the $53 million that I announced yesterday that, through the U.N., the United States will give to the World Food Programme.<br><br>But I must say, when we are talking about humanitarian assistance, Romania has been a hub of humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; And that is yet another reason that we are here to thank the President and the people of this great country for what you are doing based on the needs of this region.&nbsp; You have been welcoming tens of thousands of refugees, and doing it with such compassion and such grace.<br><br>So I&#8217;ll conclude my remarks by saying that this is a strong and enduring relationship. &nbsp;It is an important relationship.&nbsp; And the importance of this relationship is being highlighted at this very moment.&nbsp; But it is a relationship that will continue over the years.<br><br>And again, I thank you, Mr. President, and the people of this beautiful country for all you do and all you represent.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>PRESIDENT IOHANNIS:&nbsp; Thank you so much, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; We have a couple of questions.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Roxana Zamfirescu, State TV.&nbsp; I have a question for both officials.&nbsp; I would like to ask you if the United States plans to increase the number of troops and to create here a permanent presence.&nbsp; I&#8217;m asking this in the context of which 150 kilometers away from the Romanian frontieră take &#8212; bombardments take place.&nbsp; And I would like to ask you as well if &#8212; what are the chances of the war extending towards Romania and Republic of Moldova?<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; I cannot repeat frequently enough that the United States is committed to our friendship and alliance with Romania.&nbsp; And to that end, we have a continuous and rotating commitment of U.S. troops to this country, most recently with the deployment of the 1,000-member Stryker squadron.<br><br>And as the people of Romania know, we also know that this is a dynamic situation, and we will, on a daily basis, assess the needs that we have to maintain stability in this region.<br><br>As it relates to what might be the future conduct of Putin, I cannot speculate.&nbsp; But we are clear in our position, which is that as a member of NATO, an attack against one is an attack against all.<br><br>PRESIDENT IOHANNIS:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; I believe that the first part received a very clear response from Madam Vice President.&nbsp;<br><br>As for the second part, I can highlight the fact that we do not have information that would indicate that Romania would represent a target of an aggression.&nbsp; On the other hand, it is very clear that this Russian action, this war started against Ukraine, definitely created, definitely produced a result &#8212; a visible, a firm, a clear result.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s represented by the unity of NATO and the determination of NATO Allies to stand together and to defend itself &#8212; each other.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Nancy &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp;<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; &#8212; from Bloomberg.&nbsp;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Madam Vice President, the humanitarian crisis is growing and the violence only seems to be getting worse.&nbsp; The White House and British government have both offered dire warnings about the possibility of the chemical weapons being deployed by Russia, and diplomatic efforts seem to have failed.&nbsp; Is there any discernible pathway out of the crisis?&nbsp; And what is the off-ramp?<br><br>And to the President of Romania: I&#8217;m curious if you think that there are any specific economic sanctions that you&#8217;d like to see the U.S. pursue that they have not done so already.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; In terms of your question about off-ramp: You know, from the beginning, the United States has been attempting sincerely to engage in diplomacy &#8212; actively.&nbsp; And from everything that we know and have witnessed, Putin shows no sign of engaging in serious diplomacy.<br><br>As many of you know, I gave a speech in Munich three weeks ago, before the in- &#8212; the reinvasion of Ukraine started.&nbsp; And I said then what we have maintained all along: We&#8217;re witnessing a playbook &#8212; the Russian playbook &#8212; and it includes lies, misinformation, and the acts of aggression that we are now witnessing.<br><br>We maintain that diplomacy is the way to resolve these issues that coexists with our commitment to ensure that our Allies are strong and that there must be serious consequence and accountability for what Russia is doing, which is why we have &#8212; to the other point of your question &#8212; engaged in historic sanctions and to the effect of basically a freefall of the ruble.&nbsp; The Russian stock market is still not open.&nbsp; Their credit rating is now “junk.”&nbsp;<br><br>And there will be more announcements about more action that we will take to ensure serious consequence for what is atrocious and outrageous conduct on behalf of the Russian people by Putin.<br><br>PRESIDENT IOHANNIS:&nbsp; The sanction packages have been discussed between the United States and the European Union.&nbsp; We worked very well together on this, and we will continue to work together on this.&nbsp; This is the economic side.<br><br>On the other hand, the two of us just stated that we stand strong together according to Article 5 of the NATO treaty, and we will continue this way.&nbsp; So, if new sanctions will be necessary, they will be discussed and applied.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; Good afternoon.&nbsp; Oana Bala, Radio Romania.&nbsp; Madam Vice President, Mr. President, we have seen as the Russian troops attacked a maternity as well as humanitarian convoys.&nbsp; A lot of civilians were killed, including &#8212; a lot of people were killed, including children, and this triggered a huge international response.&nbsp; Do you believe that Russia committed war crimes in Ukraine?<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; I think I’ve said it before and I’ll say it again: We are clear that any intentional attack or targeting of civilians is a war crime.&nbsp; Period.<br><br>PRESIDENT IOHANNIS:&nbsp; (As interpreted.)&nbsp; We have discussed these topics because the images are, of course, shocking.&nbsp; I have discussed about this with Madam Vice President, and yesterday we discussed this topic as part of the European Union summit.&nbsp;<br><br>And it is very clear to everyone that such situations must be documented in such a way that when the right moment comes, the authorities and the competent institutions would be able to follow up on these &#8212; on these facts and to establish in a correct manner on the international level whether or not they constitute war crimes, who committed them, and what should be the appropriate consequences for them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, it is unimaginable for all of us to see such images now in the 21st century, in a war that takes place in Europe.&nbsp; It’s outrageous.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Aamer Madhani from the Associated Press.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Vice President.&nbsp; I really appreciate it.&nbsp;<br><br>But may I ask, Mr. President, your country and many of your neighbors are enduring enormous cost aiding Ukrainian refugees, and you also face a really dire threat in the Black Sea.&nbsp; And I was just wondering if &#8212; what specifically you&#8217;ve asked the Vice President for.&nbsp; Particularly, do you need more U.S. troops here?&nbsp; Do you need any specific more materiel defense aid?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if I can ask you, Madam Vice President: President Biden has said that Americans will feel some pain for the sake of defending freedom and liberty, but there does seem to be no endgame in sight.&nbsp; How long should Americans expect &#8212; how long should we be bracing for this really, sort of, historic inflation and some unprecedented gas prices?<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; In terms of the discussions that the President Iohannis and I had, they ranged in subject, including the issue of the Black Sea, and I&#8217;ll let him explain in more detail as he would like.</p>



<p>But we are, again, fully aware and apprised because we are in constant communication with the President, with his administration here about the concerns that they have about the entire region and, frankly, the vulnerability.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All you have to do is look at the map and see that where Romania exists geographically &#8212; and as is the case for our Allies on the eastern flank &#8212; that there are potential vulnerabilities, which is why we say very clearly: We will dedicate &#8212; and have been especially enhancing, over the last few weeks &#8212; our support based on their current needs.</p>



<p>When we look at Putin&#8217;s actions &#8212; the previous question &#8212; there is &#8212; it is painful to watch.&nbsp; It is painful to watch what is happening to innocent people in Ukraine who just want to live in their own country and have pride in themselves as Ukrainians, who want to be home speaking the language they know, going to the church that they know, raising their children in the community where their families have lived for generations.&nbsp; And by the millions, now, are having to flee with nothing but a backpack.<br><br>And then you compound that with what happened a couple of days &#8212; the President talked about it today; I talked about it yesterday &#8212; in terms of a maternity hospital, pregnant women.&nbsp; We are &#8212; we have the unfortunate experience, all of us right now who are not in Ukraine, of witnessing horror.&nbsp;<br><br>So we are committed in everything we are doing.&nbsp; And, yes, then the President did say in the State of the Union,<br>there is a price to pay for democracy.&nbsp; Got to stand with your friends.&nbsp; And as everybody knows, even in your personal life, being loyal to those friendships based on common principles and values, sometimes it&#8217;s difficult.&nbsp; Often, it ain&#8217;t easy.&nbsp; But that&#8217;s what the friendship is about, based on shared values.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re doing.<br><br>PRESIDENT IOHANNIS:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Russia started its attack on Ukraine from the south, from the Black Sea area.&nbsp; This is<br>a scenario we have been warning about for many years now.&nbsp;<br><br>On the other hand, Romania has approximately 650 kilometers of land border with Ukraine.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the longest land border of all allies neighboring with Ukraine.&nbsp;<br><br>So, yes, we are concerned.&nbsp; We are concerned about the eastern flank.&nbsp; And this is why we are working on making the eastern flank stronger.<br><br>And, yes, we discussed with Vice President Harris about these issues.&nbsp; And I raised the issue of the eastern flank, that the eastern flank has to be strong, it has to be well balanced.&nbsp; Because if one part of the eastern flank is strong and the other part is weak, it&#8217;s obviously a weakness on the eastern flank.<br><br>So the eastern flank has to be strong to defend the entire NATO, to defend the Euro-Atlantic area.&nbsp;<br><br>And on the eastern flank, the Allies &#8212; and, in this case, we discussed specifically about U.S. and Romania &#8212; have to materialize a force that is strong enough to be deterrent.&nbsp; NATO relies on strength and deterrence.&nbsp; So to deter somebody, you have to be strong in that area.<br><br>So, yes, we discussed about the necessity of a NATO battlegroup in Romania.&nbsp; And, obviously, the United States play an important role in this.<br><br>We discussed about enhanced U.S. presence on the eastern flank, specifically, obviously, on our part of the eastern flank.&nbsp; And we discussed, obviously, about Article 5 of NATO and about the longstanding partnership between our troops, because soldiers from the United States have been in Romania for many years now, and they work very well together with the Romanian forces, and they are a real gain on the southern part of the eastern flank.&nbsp; And they are a significant reassurance for Romanians that we do not stand alone, that we stand with the United States and with all the other NATO Allies.<br><br>So, yes, we discussed all this, and we have a common approach, if I may say so.&nbsp; And this is what &#8212; specific for our partnership.&nbsp; We have &#8212; we enjoy a strategic partnership because we try to solve problems and we do solve problems together.<br><br>Thank you.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a specific number for the enhanced presence you would like to see?&nbsp; Is there a number of U.S. or NATO troops, additionally, you would like to see in Romania?<br><br>PRESIDENT IOHANNIS:&nbsp; Well, why don’t we let the military from the States and from Romania talk together, and then to NATO, and then all of this will be public after that.<br><br>VICE PRESIDENT HARRIS:&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>PRESIDENT IOHANNIS:&nbsp; No more questions?&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>Thank you so much.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 4:44 P.M. EET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden Announcing Actions to Continue to Hold Russia&#160;Accountable</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/11/remarks-by-president-biden-announcing-actions-to-continue-to-hold-russia-accountable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 18:25:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48955</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 10:31 A.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good morning.&#160; I’m sorry to keep you waiting.&#160; I’ve just spoken for some time with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine.&#160; I told him, as I have each and every time we’ve spoken, the United States stands with the people of Ukraine and their bravely &#8212; as they bravely&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>10:31 A.M. EST<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; I’m sorry to keep you waiting.&nbsp; I’ve just spoken for some time with President Zelenskyy of Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I told him, as I have each and every time we’ve spoken, the United States stands with the people of Ukraine and their bravely &#8212; as they bravely fight to defend their country.&nbsp; And they are doing that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as Putin continues his merciless assault, the United States and our Allies and partners continue to work in lockstep to ramp up the economic pressure on Putin and to further isolate Russia on the global stage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Later today, together with other NATO Allies and the G7 &#8212; Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, the United Kingdom &#8212; as well as the European Union &#8212; we’re going to jointly announce several new steps to squeeze Putin and hold him more &#8212; even more accountable for his aggression against Ukraine.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I want to speak to a few of those points today.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; First, each of our nations is going to take steps to deny most-favored-nation status to Russia.&nbsp; A most-favored-nation status designation means two countries have agreed to trade with each other under the best possible terms &#8212;&nbsp;low tariffs, few barriers to trade, and the highest possible imports allowed.</p>



<p>In the United States, we call this “permanent normal trade relations” &#8212; PNTR &#8212; but it’s the same thing.&nbsp; Revoking PNTR for Russia is going to make it harder for Russia to do business with the United States.&nbsp; And doing it in unison with other nations that make up half of the global economy will be another crushing blow to the Russian economy that’s already suffering very badly from our sanctions.</p>



<p>And I want to thank Speaker Pelosi, Leader McCarthy, Leader Schumer and McConnell, and Senators Wyden and Crapo, Representatives Neal and Brady for their bipartisan leadership on this in the Congress.</p>



<p>I would like to offer a special thanks to Speaker Pelosi</p>



<p>who has been a strong advocate for revoking PNTR and who agreed to hold off on that in the House until I could line up all of our key allies to keep us in complete unison.  Unity among our allies is critically important, as you all know, from my perspective, at least.<br><br>     Many issues divide us in Washington, but standing for democracy in Ukraine, <s>pushing</s> [punishing] Russia’s aggression should not be one of those issues.</p>



<p>The free world is coming together to confront Putin.&nbsp; Our two parties here at home are leading the way.&nbsp; And with that bipartisan cooperation, I’m looking forward to signing into law the bill revoking PNTR &#8212; which is, again, most people think of it as “most-favored-nations” status.</p>



<p>We’re also taking a further step of banning imports of goods from several signature sectors of the Russian economy, including seafoods, vodka, and diamonds.</p>



<p>And we’re going to continue to squeeze Putin.&nbsp; The G7 will seek to deny Russia the ability to borrow from leading multinational institutions, such as the International Monetary Fund and the World Bank.</p>



<p>Putin is an aggressor &#8212; is the aggressor.&nbsp; And Putin must pay the price.</p>



<p>He cannot pursue a war that threatens the very foundations &#8212; which he’s doing &#8212; the very foundations of international peace and stability and then ask for financial help from the international community.</p>



<p>The G7 is also stepping up pressure on corrupt Russian billionaires.&nbsp; We’re adding new names to the list of oligarchs and their families that we’re targeting.&nbsp; And we’re increasing coordination among the G7 countries to target and capture their ill-begotten gains.</p>



<p>They support Putin.&nbsp; They steal from the Russian people.&nbsp; And they seek to hide their money in our countries.&nbsp; They’re part of a &#8212; that kleptocracy that exists in Moscow.&nbsp; And they must share in the pain of these sanctions.</p>



<p>And while we’re going after these &#8212; their superyachts and their vacation homes worth hundreds of milli- &#8212; millions of dollars, we’re also going to make it harder for them to buy high-end products&nbsp;manufactured in our country.&nbsp; We’re banning the export of luxu- &#8212; luxury goods to Russia.&nbsp; They’re also the latest steps we’re taking, but they’re not the last steps we’re going to take.</p>



<p>And as I said at the beginning of all of these steps, we’re going to hit Putin harder because the United States and our closest Allies and partners are acting in unison.</p>



<p>The totality of our sanctions and export controls is crushing the Russian economy.</p>



<p>The ruble has lost more than half its value.&nbsp; They tell me it takes about 200 rubles to equal 1 dollar these days.&nbsp; The Moscow stock exchange has been closed for fully &#8212; for two weeks because they know the moment it opens, it will probably collapse.</p>



<p>Credit rating agencies has downgraded Russia’s government to “junk” status &#8212; its economy to “junk” status.</p>



<p>The list of businesses and international corporations leaving Russia is growing by the day.</p>



<p>We’re also continuing the close <s>corporations</s> [cooperation] with Allies and partners to make sure that the close cooperation we continue to have, the Ukrainian people are &#8212; are able to defend their own nation.</p>



<p>The United States has sent more than $1 billion in security assistance to Ukraine over the last year, including anti-armor and anti-air capabilities &#8212; taking out tanks and planes and helicopters &#8212; with new shipments arriving every day.</p>



<p>We, the United States, are also facilitating significant shipments of security assistance from our Allies and partners to Ukraine.</p>



<p>On the humanitarian front, we’re working closely with the U.N. and humanitarian organizations to support the people of Ukraine who have been displaced by the violence in Ukraine.</p>



<p>We’re providing &#8212; we’re providing tens of thousands of tons of human supplies &#8212; excuse me, humanitarian supplies &#8212; food, water, medicines &#8212; coming via truck and train every single day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Yesterday in Poland, Vice President Harrins &#8212; Harris announced an additional $53 million in additional humanitarian support to Ukraine.&nbsp; That brings the total humanitarian assistance to $107 million in just two weeks.</p>



<p>We’ve joined in this effort by more &#8212; with more than 30 other countries&nbsp;who are providing hundreds of millions more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And last night, to their great credit, the Congress passed a bipartisan spending bill that included an additional $13.6 billion in new assistance to the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; And I look forward to signing that immediately.</p>



<p>And I also want to be clear though: We will make sure Ukraine has weapons to defend against an invading Russian force.&nbsp; We will &#8212; we will send money and food and aid&nbsp;to save the Ukrainian people.&nbsp; And I will welcome the Ukrainian refugees.&nbsp; We should welcome them here with open arms if they need access.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’re going to provide more support for Ukraine.&nbsp; We’re going to continue to stand together with our Allies in Europe and send an unmistakable message: We will defend every single inch of NATO territory with the full might of a united and galvanized NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will not fight a war against Russia in Ukraine.&nbsp; Direct confrontation between NATO and Russia is World War Three, something we must strive to prevent.</p>



<p>But we already know Putin’s war against Ukraine will never be a victory.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He hoped to dominate Ukraine without a fight.&nbsp; He failed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He hoped to fracture European resolve.&nbsp; He failed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He hoped to weaken the transatlantic alliance.&nbsp; He failed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He hoped to split apart American democracies, in terms of our positions.&nbsp; He failed.</p>



<p>The American people are united.&nbsp; The world is united.&nbsp; And we stand with the people of Ukraine.&nbsp; We will not let autocrats and would-be emperors dictate the direction of the world.</p>



<p>Democracies are rising to meet this moment, rallying the world to the side of peace and the side of security.</p>



<p>We’re showing our strength, and we will not falter.</p>



<p>May God bless all of you.&nbsp; God bless Ukraine.&nbsp; And God bless our troops.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden, your White House has said that Russia may use chemical weapons or create a false-flag operation to use them.&nbsp; What evidence have you seen showing that?&nbsp; And would the U.S. have a military response if Putin does launch a chemical weapons attack?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I’m not going to speak about the intelligence.&nbsp; But Russia would pay a severe price if they used chemical weapons.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>10:40 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States Partnership with the African Union – Africa Centres for Disease Control and&#160;Prevention</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/fact-sheet-united-states-partnership-with-the-african-union-africa-centres-for-disease-control-and-prevention/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48939</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, the United States and African Union (AU) – Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC) renewed our partnership by signing an updated Memorandum of Cooperation (MOC) between His Excellency Moussa Faki Mahamat, Chairperson of the African Union Commission (AUC), and U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken. This strategic memorandum signifies a continued&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, the United States and African Union (AU) – Africa Centres for Disease Control and Prevention (Africa CDC) renewed our partnership by signing an updated Memorandum of Cooperation (MOC) between His Excellency Moussa Faki Mahamat, Chairperson of the African Union Commission (AUC), and U.S. Secretary of State Antony Blinken. This strategic memorandum signifies a continued and expanded commitment to this partnership by outlining our shared priorities for the a safer, healthier, and more equitable future. Together, we will continue efforts to achieve the Sustainable Development Agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the February 2022 AU Heads of State Summit, a resolution was approved to elevate Africa CDC’s status to an autonomous health agency of the African Union – a recognition of its global and regional leadership during the COVID-19 pandemic, Ebola outbreaks, and many other health events. In its support to Member States, Africa CDC serves as a platform to share and exchange knowledge and lessons from public health interventions. Since our partnership officially began in 2015, the U.S. government and Africa CDC have worked together to combat some of the world’s most pressing crises, including Ebola and COVID-19. We have continued to build on our strong relationship through technical assistance, embedded experts and deployed staff to work alongside the organization, and funding to support Africa CDC activities and staffing.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, we celebrate ongoing work and highlight&nbsp;key areas of future engagement, including:&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>National Public Health Institutes (NPHIs):&nbsp;</strong>National public health institutes (NPHIs) serve as a functional home for public health activities and the foundation of Africa CDC’s operating model. These science-based agencies monitor the population’s health and respond to disease outbreaks and other public health priorities. They provide leadership and coordination to focus on core public health functions, including surveillance, laboratory, workforce, and public health emergency management. There is natural synergy between Africa CDC and the United States in establishing NPHIs and strengthening their core functions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States has also supported Africa CDC’s three-tiered operational model by developing and strengthening NPHIs at the national level and at five Regional Collaborating Centers (RCCs). The RCCs help build capacity of, coordinate public health initiatives with, and coordinate resources among AU Member States. Current Africa CDC initiatives, in partnership with the United States, can address capacity needs of NPHIs, including surveillance networks, health information exchange, early warning systems, and development of testing and diagnostics capacity. Our partnership will help support Africa CDC’s ongoing efforts to expand health security throughout the continent, and help countries reach the goals and target of the Global Health Security Agenda.</p>



<p><strong>Public Health Workforce:&nbsp;</strong>The United States and Africa CDC share the perspective that the public health and healthcare workforce plays a critical role in strengthen health systems, including preparing for and responding to pandemics while continuing to address health needs. The United States works with Africa CDC in building Africa’s public health workforce through supporting global human resources for health, expanding the Field Epidemiology Training Program (FETP), and partnering with Africa CDC’s Institute for Workforce Development (IWD) on other capacity building efforts.</p>



<p><strong>COVID-19:</strong>&nbsp;As part of President Biden’s commitment to leading an international and coordinated vaccine effort, the United States has shared over 166 million COVID-19 vaccine doses with 48 countries in Africa, as of February 2022, with plans for sending more.&nbsp;&nbsp;Africa CDC, in partnership with the African Union, the African Vaccine Acquisition Trust and COVAX, has helped guide allocations of those doses. The United States is supporting updates to regulatory structures and is facilitating engagement with private sector and international organizations that will help expand vaccine manufacturing and enable African public health institutions to produce and supply vaccines for the continent. The U.S. government has partnered with Africa CDC to enhance surveillance and laboratory capacity to identify, detect, and respond to COVID-19 outbreaks and variants of concern. The United States has also deployed staff to support and collaborate with Africa CDC in its leadership of COVID-19 response in Africa.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Critical Medical Commodities:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;Through the United States Government’s Initiative for Global Vaccine Access (Global VAX), we are expanding efforts to work with international partners like Africa CDC to support infrastructure and capacity in vaccine delivery. While we currently work together on COVID-19 vaccine development, these efforts lay the foundation for accelerating the development of vaccines, therapeutics, and other critical medicals tools for a range of diseases.&nbsp;&nbsp;This complements existing work and technical partnerships across Africa for similar efforts to meet immediate and long-term health needs.</p>



<p><strong>Advanced Molecular Detection</strong>: Advanced technologies such as next-generation sequencing and bioinformatics are essential public health tools to help prevent and respond to emerging health threats. Genomics is an increasingly important tool in emerging potential in global public health. The United States, Africa CDC, and other partners have worked together to launch Africa CDC&#8217;s Pathogen Genomics initiative to strengthen laboratory systems and enhance disease surveillance by equipping the continent’s public health institutions with the tools, training, and data infrastructure to fully leverage critical genomic sequencing technologies.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 960 and H.R.&#160;3419</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/bills-signed-h-r-960-and-h-r-3419/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 16:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48943</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[H.R. 960, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 3493 Burnet Avenue in Cincinnati, Ohio, as the John H. Leahr and Herbert M. Heilbrun Post Office. Thank you to Representative Wenstrup, the Ohio delegation, and Senators Portman and Brown for their leadership. H.R. 3419, which designates the facility of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>H.R. 960, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 3493 Burnet Avenue in Cincinnati, Ohio, as the John H. Leahr and Herbert M. Heilbrun Post Office.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representative Wenstrup, the Ohio delegation, and Senators Portman and Brown for their leadership.</p>



<p>H.R. 3419, which designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 66 Meserole Avenue in Brooklyn, New York, as the Joseph R. Lentol Post Office.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representative Maloney and Senators Gillibrand and Schumer for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Zelenskyy of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-zelenskyy-of-ukraine-7/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 16:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine to underscore his support for the Ukrainian people as they continue to defend their country against Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack. President Biden highlighted how the United States is continuing to surge security, humanitarian, and economic assistance to Ukraine. He also updated President Zelenskyy&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine to underscore his support for the Ukrainian people as they continue to defend their country against Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified attack. President Biden highlighted how the United States is continuing to surge security, humanitarian, and economic assistance to Ukraine. He also updated President Zelenskyy on the actions the United States is taking today in coordination with the G7 and the EU to further raise the costs on Russia.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Statement by the G7 Announcing Further Economic Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/joint-statement-by-the-g7-announcing-further-economic-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 16:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48924</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We the Leaders of the Group of Seven (G7) remain resolved to stand with the Ukrainian people and government who heroically resist Russian President Vladimir Putin’s military aggression and war of choice against their sovereign nation. This unprovoked and unjustified attack is causing enormous suffering and a tragic loss of life, including through the increasingly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We the Leaders of the Group of Seven (G7) remain resolved to stand with the Ukrainian people and government who heroically resist Russian President Vladimir Putin’s military aggression and war of choice against their sovereign nation. This unprovoked and unjustified attack is causing enormous suffering and a tragic loss of life, including through the increasingly indiscriminate bombing and shelling of civilians in schools, homes, and hospitals.</p>



<p>We are united in our determination to hold President Putin and his regime accountable for this unjustified and unprovoked war that has already isolated Russia in the world. The world should join together in calling on President Putin and his regime to immediately stop its ongoing assault against Ukraine and withdraw its military forces. We stand in solidarity with those who are bravely opposing the invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>We urge Russia to ensure safe and unhindered humanitarian access to victims of its assault in Ukraine, and to allow safe passage for civilians wishing to leave. We call for, and commit to provide, humanitarian, medical and financial support to refugees from Ukraine.</p>



<p>Since President Putin launched the Russian Federation’s invasion on February 24, our countries have imposed expansive restrictive measures that have severely compromised Russia’s economy and financial system, as evidenced by the massive market reactions. We have collectively isolated key Russian banks from the global financial system; blunted the Central Bank of Russia´s ability to utilise its foreign reserves; imposed sweeping export bans and controls that cut Russia off from our advanced technologies; and targeted the architects of this war, that is Russian President Vladimir Putin and his accomplices, as well as the Lukashenko regime in Belarus.</p>



<p>In addition to announced plans, we will make further efforts to reduce our reliance on Russian energy, while ensuring that we do so in an orderly fashion and in ways that provide time for the world to secure alternative and sustainable supplies. In addition, private sector companies are leaving Russia with unprecedented speed and solidarity. We stand with our companies that are seeking an orderly withdrawal from the Russian market.</p>



<p>We remain resolved to isolate Russia further from our economies and the international financial system. Consequently, we commit to taking further measures as soon as possible in the context of our ongoing response and consistent with our respective legal authorities and processes:</p>



<p>First, we will endeavor, consistent with our national processes, to take action that will deny Russia Most-Favoured-Nation status relating to key products.&nbsp;This will revoke important benefits of Russia’s membership of the World Trade Organization and ensure that the products of Russian companies no longer receive Most-Favoured-Nation treatment in our economies. We welcome the ongoing preparation of a statement by a broad coalition of WTO members, including the G7, announcing their revocation of Russia’s Most-Favoured-Nation status.</p>



<p>Second, we are working collectively to prevent Russia from obtaining financing from the leading multilateral financial institutions, including the International Monetary Fund, the World Bank and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development. Russia cannot grossly violate international law and expect to benefit from being part of the international economic order. We welcome the IMF and World Bank Group’s rapid and ongoing efforts to get financial assistance to Ukraine. We also welcome the steps the OECD has taken to restrict Russia’s participation in relevant bodies.</p>



<p>Third, we commit to continuing our campaign of pressure against Russian elites, proxies and oligarchs close to President Putin and other architects of the war as well as their families and their enablers. We commend the work done by many of our governments to identify and freeze mobile and immobile assets belonging to sanctioned individuals and entities, and resolve to continue this campaign of pressure as a matter of priority. To that end, we have operationalised the task force announced on February 26, which will target the assets of Russian elites close to President Putin and the architects of his war. Our sanctions packages are carefully targeted so as not to impede the delivery of humanitarian assistance.</p>



<p>Fourth, we commit to maintaining the effectiveness of our restrictive measures, to cracking down on evasion and to closing loop-holes. Specifically, in addition to other measures planned to prevent evasion, we will ensure that the Russian state and elites, proxies and oligarchs cannot leverage digital assets as a means of evading or offsetting the impact of international sanctions, which will further limit their access to the global financial system. It is commonly understood that our current sanctions already cover crypto-assets. We commit to taking measures to better detect and interdict any illicit activity, and we will impose costs on illicit Russian actors using digital assets to enhance and transfer their wealth, consistent with our national processes.</p>



<p>Fifth, we are resolved to fighting off the Russian regime’s attempts to spread disinformation. We affirm and support the right of the Russian people to free and unbiased information.</p>



<p>Sixth, we stand ready to impose further restrictions on exports and imports of key goods and technologies on the Russian Federation, which aim at denying Russia revenues and at ensuring that our citizens are not underwriting President Putin’s war, consistent with national processes. We note that international companies are already withdrawing from the Russian market. We will make sure that the elites, proxies and oligarchs that support President Putin’s war are deprived of their access to luxury goods and assets. The elites who sustain Putin’s war machine should no longer be able to reap the gains of this system, squandering the resources of the Russian people.</p>



<p>Seventh, Russian entities directly or indirectly supporting the war should not have access to new debt and equity investments and other forms of international capital. Our citizens are united in the view that their savings and investments should not fund the companies that underpin Russia’s economy and war machine. We will continue working together to develop and implement measures that will further limit Russia’s ability to raise money internationally.</p>



<p>We stand united and in solidarity with our partners, including developing and emerging economies, which unjustly bear the cost and impact of this war, for which we hold President Putin, his regime and supporters, and the Lukashenko regime, fully responsible. Together, we will work to preserve stability of energy markets as well as food security globally as Russia’s invasion threatens Ukraine’s capacity to grow crops this year.</p>



<p>We continue to stand with the Ukrainian people and the Government of Ukraine. We will continue to evaluate the impacts of our measures, including on third countries, and are prepared to take further measures to hold President Putin and his regime accountable for his attack on Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Executive Order on Prohibiting Certain Imports, Exports, and New Investment with Respect to Continued Russian Federation&#160;Aggression</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/11/executive-order-on-prohibiting-certain-imports-exports-and-new-investment-with-respect-to-continued-russian-federation-aggression/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 16:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48920</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.), and section 301 of title 3, United&#160;States Code,&#160; I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) (IEEPA), the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.), and section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code,<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, in order to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024 of April&nbsp;15, 2021, relied on for additional steps taken in Executive Order 14039 of August&nbsp;20, 2021, and expanded by Executive Order 14066 of March 8, 2022, hereby order:<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Section 1.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; The following are prohibited:<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; the importation into the United States of the following products of Russian Federation origin:&nbsp; fish, seafood, and preparations thereof; alcoholic beverages; non-industrial diamonds; and any other products of Russian Federation origin as may be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp;&nbsp; the exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United States person, wherever located, of luxury goods, and any other items as may be determined by the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury, to any person located in the Russian Federation;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iii)&nbsp; new investment in any sector of the Russian Federation economy as may be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, by a United States person, wherever located;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(iv)&nbsp;&nbsp; the exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United States person, wherever located, of U.S. dollar-denominated banknotes to the Government of the Russian Federation or any person located in the Russian Federation; and<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(v)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; any approval, financing, facilitation, or guarantee by a United States person, wherever located, of a transaction by a foreign person where the transaction by that foreign person would be prohibited by this section if performed by a United States person or within the United States.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; The prohibitions in subsection (a) of this section apply except to the extent provided by statutes, or in regulations, orders, directives, or licenses that may be issued pursuant to this order, or pursuant to the export control authorities implemented by the Department of Commerce, and notwithstanding any contract entered into or license or permit granted prior to the date of this order.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Any transaction that evades or avoids, has the purpose of evading or avoiding, causes a violation of, or attempts to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; Any conspiracy formed to violate any of the prohibitions set forth in this order is prohibited.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; Nothing in this order shall prohibit transactions for the conduct of the official business of the Federal Government or the United Nations (including its specialized agencies, programs, funds, and related organizations) by employees, grantees, or contractors thereof.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 4.&nbsp; For the purposes of this order:<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(a)&nbsp; the term &#8220;entity&#8221; means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; the term &#8220;person&#8221; means an individual or entity;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; the term &#8220;Government of the Russian Federation&#8221; means the Government of the Russian Federation, any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality thereof, including the Central Bank of the Russian Federation, and any person owned, controlled, or directed by, or acting for or on behalf of, the Government of the Russian Federation; and<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(d)&nbsp; the term &#8220;United States person&#8221; means any United&nbsp;States citizen, lawful permanent resident, entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States (including foreign branches), or any person in the United States.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 5.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, are hereby authorized to take such actions, including the promulgation of rules and regulations, and to employ all powers granted to the President by IEEPA, as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this order.&nbsp; The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Commerce may, consistent with applicable law, redelegate any of these functions within the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Commerce, respectively.&nbsp; All executive departments and agencies of the United&nbsp;States shall take all appropriate measures within their authority to implement this order.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sec. 6.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this order shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(b)&nbsp; This order shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p>(c)&nbsp; This order is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>



<p>THE WHITE HOUSE,</p>



<p>March 11, 2022.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and President of the Senate on Prohibiting Certain Imports, Exports, and New Investment with Respect to Continued Russian Federation&#160;Aggression</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-president-of-the-senate-on-prohibiting-certain-imports-exports-and-new-investment-with-respect-to-continued-russian-federation-aggression/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 16:10:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), the National Emergencies Act (50&#160;U.S.C. 1601 et seq.), and section 301 of title 3, United&#160;States Code, I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order in order to take additional steps with respect to the national&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>Pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1701 <em>et seq</em>.), the National Emergencies Act (50&nbsp;U.S.C. 1601 <em>et seq</em>.), and section 301 of title 3, United&nbsp;States Code, I hereby report that I have issued an Executive Order in order to take additional steps with respect to the national emergency declared in Executive Order 14024 of April 15, 2021, with respect to the unusual and extraordinary threat to the national security, foreign policy, and economy of the United States posed by specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The order prohibits the following:  (i) the importation into the United States of the following products of Russian Federation origin: fish, seafood, and preparations thereof; alcoholic beverages; non-industrial diamonds; and any other products of Russian Federation origin as may be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce; (ii) the exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United States person, wherever located, of luxury goods, and any other items as may be determined by the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury, to any person located in the Russian Federation; (iii) new investment in any sector of the Russian Federation economy as may be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, by a United States person, wherever located; (iv) the exportation, reexportation, sale, or supply, directly or indirectly, from the United States, or by a United States person, wherever located, of U.S. dollar-denominated banknotes to the Government of the Russian Federation or any person located in the Russian Federation; and (v) any approval, financing, facilitation, or guarantee by a United States person, wherever located, of a transaction by a foreign person where the transaction by that foreign person would be prohibited by this section if performed by a United States person or within the United States.</p>



<p>I am enclosing a copy of the Executive Order I have issued.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States, European Union, and G7 to Announce Further Economic Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/11/fact-sheet-united-states-european-union-and-g7-to-announce-further-economic-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 15:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48911</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden and G7 Leaders from Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, and the United Kingdom as well as the European Union will announce new economic actions to hold Putin accountable for his continued assault on Ukraine and further isolate Russia from the global financial system. Each partner will implement actions consistent with their national&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden and G7 Leaders from Canada, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, and the United Kingdom as well as the European Union will announce new economic actions to hold Putin accountable for his continued assault on Ukraine and further isolate Russia from the global financial system. Each partner will implement actions consistent with their national processes.</p>



<p>These actions will collectively ramp up pressure on Putin and build on the unprecedented package of economic sanctions and export controls the United States and over 30 countries have already imposed on Russia. Today, the ruble is trading at its weakest level ever and is worth less than a penny; the Russian stock market is closed for the longest time in history; the Russian government’s credit rating has been downgraded to “junk” status, and we’re seeing a mass exodus from Russia by the private sector – the result of our historic, multilateral coordination and commitment to ensure that Putin’s war of choice is a strategic failure. Russia has now become a global economic and financial pariah. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Today’s announcements include:</p>



<p><strong>Revoking Russia’s Most-Favored Nation Status.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden will work closely with Congress to deny Russia the benefits of its WTO membership and ensure that Russian imports do not receive most favored nation treatment in our economy. The United States Congress has demonstrated bipartisan leadership to revoke Permanent Normal Trade Relations for Russia, and President Biden looks forward to signing a bill into law. Together with similar actions by the G7, following our respective national processes, this collective action by more than half of the global economy will deliver another serious economic blow to Russia.</p>



<p><strong>Denying Borrowing Privileges at Multilateral Financial Institutions.&nbsp;</strong>The G7 Leaders will agree to ensure Russia cannot obtain financing from the leading multilateral financial institutions, such as the International Monetary Fund and the World Bank. Russia cannot grossly violate international law and expect to benefit from being part of the international economic order.</p>



<p><strong>Full blocking Sanctions on Additional Russian Elites and their Family Members</strong>. This includes Yuri Kovalchuk, executives of banks we have sanctioned, and Duma members who sponsored legislation to recognize the so-called “Donetsk People’s Republic” and “Luhansk People’s Republic.” This action will follow up on multiple efforts, along with those of our allies and partners, to target Russian elites and their family members who are profiting from this war of choice, and cuts them off from the U.S. financial system, freezes any assets they hold in the United States and blocks their travel to the United States. We will work through the international task force announced on February 26 to pursue the ill-gotten gains of these elites.<br><br><strong>Ban Export of Luxury Goods to Russia.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden will sign an Executive Order (E.O) that will end the exportation of luxury items to any person located in the Russian Federation. This will ensure that U.S. persons are not providing luxury items, such as high end-watches, luxury vehicles, high-end apparel, high-end alcohol, jewelry, and other goods frequently purchased by Russian elites. The U.S. export value of the products covered by today’s luxury goods restrictions is nearly $550 million per year. The elites who sustain Putin’s war machine should no longer be able to reap the gains of this system and squander the resources of the Russian people.</p>



<p><strong>Ban U.S. Import of Goods from Several Signature Sectors of Russia’s Economy.&nbsp;</strong>President Biden’s E.O. will also prohibit the import of goods from several signature sectors of Russia’s economy – including seafood, spirits/vodka, and non-industrial diamonds. This will deny Russia more than $1 billion in export revenues and ensure U.S. citizens are not underwriting Putin’s war. The United States retains the authority to impose additional import bans as appropriate.</p>



<p><strong>New guidance by the Department of Treasury to Thwart Sanctions Evasion, including through Virtual Currency.</strong>&nbsp;The Department of the Treasury, through new guidance, will continue to make clear that Treasury’s expansive actions against Russia require all U.S. persons to comply with sanctions regulations regardless of whether a transaction is denominated in traditional fiat currency or virtual currency. Treasury is closely monitoring any efforts to circumvent or violate Russia-related sanctions, including through the use of virtual currency, and is committed to using its broad enforcement authorities to act against violations and to promote compliance. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Create the Authority to Ban New Investment in Any Sector of the Russian Federation Economy</strong>. President Biden has already banned new U.S. investments in the Russian energy sector. This E.O. will establish the legal authority for future investment restrictions in any sector of the Russian economy, as may be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, by a United States person.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
