<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:58:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Small Business Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-small-business-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For generations, small businesses across America have shaped and embodied our Nation&#8217;s entrepreneurial spirit and driven our economy forward.  Today, more than 32 million small businesses employ almost half of America&#8217;s workforce and represent the heart and soul of countless communities.  During National Small Business Week, we celebrate America&#8217;s small businesses and their enormous contributions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For generations, small businesses across America have shaped and embodied our Nation&#8217;s entrepreneurial spirit and driven our economy forward.  Today, more than 32 million small businesses employ almost half of America&#8217;s workforce and represent the heart and soul of countless communities.  During National Small Business Week, we celebrate America&#8217;s small businesses and their enormous contributions to American life and prosperity.<br><br>When I first took office, the pandemic had devastated America&#8217;s small business community.  Hundreds of thousands of small businesses had closed, main streets were shuttered, and millions more Americans were out of work through no fault of their own.  Even with the creativity and resilience of small business owners and workers, COVID-19 took an incalculable toll on so many lives and livelihoods.  That is why I made it a top priority to provide substantial, immediate relief to our Nation&#8217;s small businesses, giving them the tools, resources, and support they needed to reopen, rehire, and rebuild.<br><br>My American Rescue Plan and other emergency relief programs distributed hundreds of billions of dollars to millions of small businesses to keep the lights on and keep workers on the payroll.  My Administration also removed historic barriers to level the playing field for businesses across rural and urban America, especially businesses owned by veterans, women, and people of color.  These efforts have helped millions of small businesses not only weather the pandemic, but thrive.<br><br>My Administration is committed to unlocking new opportunities to help small businesses grow and compete.  Through the American Rescue Plan, our State Small Business Credit Initiative provides States, territories, and Tribal governments with resources to establish loan and equity capital programs to support entrepreneurs.  In addition, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law has created unprecedented contracting opportunities for small businesses in every community.  Already, more than 4,000 projects have been announced to upgrade America&#8217;s infrastructure, creating significant opportunities for small businesses to grow.  The law is delivering affordable high-speed internet access to every community &#8212; urban, rural, suburban, and Tribal &#8212; so every small business can use digital technologies and gain new customers across the country and around the world.  The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law makes the Minority Business Development Agency within the United States Department of Commerce a permanent entity &#8212; seeded with a record amount of funding &#8212; so minority-owned businesses can receive tailored assistance for their unique challenges and access the capital they need to grow.<br> <br>I firmly believe that equal opportunity is the bedrock of our democracy.  That is why my Administration is committed to using Federal procurement dollars to support firms owned by underrepresented people and to help small businesses build generational wealth.  Last year, I announced a set of reforms to increase contracting opportunities for underserved businesses by up to 50 percent by 2025.  We are also capitalizing on our historic investments in supply chain resilience and &#8220;Made in America&#8221; manufacturing so small businesses can innovate, compete, and build the products of tomorrow.  To position small businesses for success in the long term, the United States Small Business Administration&#8217;s Community Navigator Pilot program is forging stronger partnerships with local organizations to get resources to underserved small businesses.<br><br>Thanks to these initiatives and the resilience of the American people, America&#8217;s entrepreneurial spirit has never been stronger.  New business applications grew by more than 30 percent over the course of the pandemic, with almost 5.4 million new applications in 2021 alone.  More Americans than ever before &#8212; including more women and people of color &#8212; are following their dreams and starting new enterprises.  My Administration will continue to support them, build upon this remarkable resurgence, and strengthen the foundation of our economy with America&#8217;s small businesses at the forefront.<br><br>This National Small Business Week, let us renew our commitment to supporting our Nation&#8217;s small businesses.  From local &#8220;mom and pop&#8221; shops to innovative start-ups, small businesses are pillars of our communities and the engine of our economy.  By rebuilding our economy from the bottom up and middle out, we can maintain our global competitiveness and build a stronger Nation where everyone can succeed.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 1 through May 7, 2022, as National Small Business Week.  I call upon all Americans to recognize the contributions of small businesses to the American economy, continue supporting them, and honor the occasion with programs and activities that highlight these important businesses.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Foster Care Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-foster-care-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:55:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52114</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every May, we renew our commitment to ensuring that all youth in foster care have the love, support, and resources they need to thrive.  We also celebrate the families who provide safe and loving homes for our Nation&#8217;s foster children.  We share our appreciation for the dedicated volunteers and professionals who help our Nation&#8217;s foster&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every May, we renew our commitment to ensuring that all youth in foster care have the love, support, and resources they need to thrive.  We also celebrate the families who provide safe and loving homes for our Nation&#8217;s foster children.  We share our appreciation for the dedicated volunteers and professionals who help our Nation&#8217;s foster youth find permanent homes and connect with their biological families when appropriate &#8212; many of whom are working hard to safely reunite with their children.<br><br>Today, nearly a third of children in foster care are being raised by kin &#8212; many of whom are grandparents.  This helps children retain family bonds and a sense of cultural identity, which are so important to a child&#8217;s resilience and well-being.  As children and families of color are disproportionately overrepresented in foster care, it is essential that we invest in culturally supportive services to nurture all children and families who are impacted by the child welfare system.<br><br>The COVID-19 pandemic has had a disproportionate impact on young people in foster care.  That is why my Administration implemented the Supporting Foster Youth and Families through the Pandemic Act &#8212; helping foster youth aging out of the system access services to stay in school, participate in job training programs, pay rent and other bills, and transition to adulthood.  My Administration also funded grants that help agencies connect kinship caregivers and foster parents to programs and services for children in their care and we continue to promote best practices that identify and notify relatives when a child has been placed into foster care.<br><br>This month, we also recognize the history of injustice in America&#8217;s foster care system &#8212; particularly against Black and Native Americans.  Relative to their white peers, Black and Native American children stay in foster care longer and are less likely to be adopted or reunited with their birth parents.  Furthermore, foster care systems do not provide children with disabilities or LGBTQI+ youth with the individualized support, resources, and safety measures they need and deserve.  My Administration stands with transgender youth in foster care and with all families that love and care for their children.<br><br>To improve our foster care system, I have proposed a significant funding increase and a package of reforms to expand prevention services so more children can remain safely in their own homes.  For children who need to be placed into foster care, my proposal provides States with incentives to place more children with relatives or adults with whom they are emotionally bonded, when appropriate.  It will also increase resources for youth who are aging out of foster care.  In addition, I have called for competitive grants for States to advance racial equity, expand prevention services, and improve education outcomes in our child welfare system.  My proposal would also help more low- and moderate-income families afford the costs of adoption and legal guardianship of children who would otherwise be in foster care.<br>   <br>National Foster Care Month is an opportunity for us to celebrate foster youth and the people who provide them with love and support.  It is our duty to help vulnerable children, and child welfare professionals and the families they serve.  Through education, volunteering, and partnerships, we can strengthen our communities and ensure that youth in foster care have the support they need for a future they deserve.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as National Foster Care Month.  I call upon all Americans to observe this month by reaching out in their neighborhoods and communities to the children and youth in foster care and their families, to those at risk of entering foster care, and to kin families and other caregivers.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Mental Health Awareness Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-mental-health-awareness-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52111</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Each May we raise awareness about the importance of mental health and its impact on the well-being of all Americans, including children, adults, families, and communities across our Nation.  We also give thanks to the dedicated mental health providers whose service and support improve the lives of so many Americans.  We stand in solidarity with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Each May we raise awareness about the importance of mental health and its impact on the well-being of all Americans, including children, adults, families, and communities across our Nation.  We also give thanks to the dedicated mental health providers whose service and support improve the lives of so many Americans.  We stand in solidarity with those who are experiencing mental health conditions, renewing our commitment to providing them with the support they need and deserve. <br><br>Even before the pandemic, millions of Americans were experiencing stress, trauma, anxiety, and heightened levels of depression.  The COVID-19 pandemic exacerbated those conditions, creating an unprecedented mental health crisis across our country. Communities of color, frontline workers, health care workers, and individuals with eating disorders have been disproportionately impacted, and the rate of depression across the country has more than tripled compared to rates in 2019.<br><br>Mental health challenges among our youth have also been particularly acute due to disruptions in routines, increased social isolation, and learning loss.  Research has shown that social media plays a central role in increasing mental health challenges among young people &#8212; especially young women.  Emergency department visits for attempted suicide among girls in 2021 increased by more than 50 percent compared to 2020.  American Indians, Alaska Natives, Black youth, and LGBTQI+ youth also face a disproportionate risk of suicide.<br><br>Despite these disturbing trends, less than half of Americans struggling with mental illness receive the treatment they need &#8212; even fewer within Black and Brown communities. A variety of factors contribute to this problem. For example, too many communities lack sufficient numbers of mental health providers.  Even where there are enough mental health providers, our fragmentated system makes it difficult for people to access them.  Tragically, too, many Americans feel ashamed to reach out for help, or are stigmatized for seeking care.<br><br>My Administration is committed to transforming mental health care for all Americans. The American Rescue Plan laid the groundwork for this effort, investing nearly $5.5 billion nationwide to strengthen mental health and substance use care. It also invested billions of dollars in our Nation&#8217;s schools, including mental health treatment for students and staff.<br><br>But far more needs to be done. That is why in this year&#8217;s State of the Union Address, I outlined my vision for bolder investments to address our national mental health crisis. My strategy includes actions that will broaden the pipeline of behavioral health professionals in areas of greatest need, integrate mental health and substance use treatment into primary care, and expand access through more virtual care options.<br><br>In addition, last year the Surgeon General released an Advisory on Protecting Youth Mental Health that underscored the growing harms of digital technologies &#8212; especially social media &#8212; on the mental health of our youth.  It is time to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children, and demand that technology companies stop collecting the personal data of our children.  We must also continue researching the impact of social media on the mental health of our children, expand services in school to promote their well-being, and set them up for success so they can thrive as adults.<br><br>As my Administration works to expand suicide prevention and strengthen crisis care infrastructure within our communities, those who need immediate assistance can call the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline at 1-800-273-TALK &#8212; which will transition to a simple three-digit number, 988, in July.<br>Each of us has an important role to play in supporting our fellow Americans who are living with mental health conditions.  Learn the warning signs of emotional distress and suicide.  Engage affected loved ones in supportive dialogue.  Fight the prejudice and negative attitudes that discourages those in need from seeking mental health support.  Above all, let us collectively ensure that all children and adults experiencing mental health challenges are treated with the compassion, respect, and understanding they deserve.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as National Mental Health Awareness Month.  I call upon citizens, government agencies, private businesses, non-profit organizations, and other groups to join in activities and take action to strengthen the mental health of our communities and our Nation.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Jewish American Heritage Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-jewish-american-heritage-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52104</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 1654, a small ship carrying 23 Jewish refugees sailed into the port of present-day New York City.  Fleeing oppression and discrimination, these courageous women and men faced resistance from the colony&#8217;s leaders.  Nevertheless, they secured the right to remain and became the first Jewish communal presence to settle on American soil.  In so doing,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In 1654, a small ship carrying 23 Jewish refugees sailed into the port of present-day New York City.  Fleeing oppression and discrimination, these courageous women and men faced resistance from the colony&#8217;s leaders.  Nevertheless, they secured the right to remain and became the first Jewish communal presence to settle on American soil.  In so doing, they expanded the frontier of religious freedoms that would help define the bedrock principles upon which this Nation was built.  During Jewish American Heritage Month, we honor these 23 refugees and the centuries of successive generations of Jewish Americans, who &#8212; shaped by their own encounters with prejudice, persecution, and the promise of a better tomorrow &#8212; have emboldened our Nation to stand up for justice, equality, and freedom.</p>



<p>The story of America was written, in part, by Jewish Americans who, through their words and actions, embraced the opportunity and responsibility of citizenship knowing full well that democracy is not born, nor sustained, by accident.  Inspired by Jewish American communal leadership, our Nation&#8217;s first President pledged that our Government will &#8220;give to bigotry no sanction, to persecution no assistance.&#8221;  Inspired by Jewish American poetry, our shores have welcomed millions with the words &#8220;Give me your tired, your poor, your huddled masses yearning to be free.&#8221;  Throughout our country&#8217;s history, Jewish Americans have proudly served our Nation in uniform, in elected office, and on our Nation&#8217;s highest courts.  They have made enormous contributions to America&#8217;s cultural, scientific, artistic, and intellectual life, and they have marched, petitioned, and boarded buses to demand civil and political rights for all &#8212; from women&#8217;s rights to voting rights to workers&#8217; rights.</p>



<p>Today, we continue to strive to live up to our founding ideals.  As the scourge of white supremacy and antisemitic violence rises, my Administration remains committed to ensuring that hate has no safe harbor.  That is why we have created new laws that give us more tools to combat hate crimes; developed the first-ever National Strategy for Countering Domestic Terrorism; provided assistance to religious organizations, places of worship, and nonprofits to protect their facilities and members; and named a new Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Antisemitism.  My Administration will use the full force of our judicial system to confront bigotry and antisemitism wherever and whenever it surfaces.</p>



<p>The Jewish American story, and the story of our Nation as a whole, is fueled by faith, resilience, and hope.  It is a story defined by a firm belief in possibilities, the resolve to make real the promise of America for all Americans, and a commitment to perfecting our Union, heeding the timeless words of Rabbi Tarfon, the first-century scholar who taught &#8220;It is not your duty to finish the work, but neither are you at liberty to neglect it.&#8221;</p>



<p>Three-hundred and sixty-eight years after those 23 brave Jewish refugees arrived in America, Jewish Americans continue to help our country thrive and prosper.  This month, we honor the timeless traditions, heritage, and contributions of Jewish Americans that drive our progress as a Nation each and every day.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as Jewish American Heritage Month.  I call upon all Americans to visit JewishHeritageMonth.gov to learn more about the heritage and contributions of Jewish Americans and to observe this month with appropriate programs, activities, and ceremonies.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Asian American, Native Hawaiian, And Pacific Islander Heritage Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-asian-american-native-hawaiian-and-pacific-islander-heritage-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:50:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Heritage Month, our Nation recognizes the innumerable contributions, vibrant cultures, and rich heritage of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders (AA and NHPIs).  As some of the fastest-growing racial and ethnic groups in the Nation, AA and NHPI communities represent a multitude of ethnicities, languages, and experiences&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>During Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Heritage Month, our Nation recognizes the innumerable contributions, vibrant cultures, and rich heritage of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders (AA and NHPIs).  As some of the fastest-growing racial and ethnic groups in the Nation, AA and NHPI communities represent a multitude of ethnicities, languages, and experiences that enrich America and strengthen our Union.<br><br>AA and NHPIs have long played an essential role in writing the American story.  From serving our country in uniform, advocating for civil rights, starting new businesses, and winning Olympic medals, the contributions of the AA and NHPI community touch the lives of Americans every day.  AA and NHPIs serve with distinction at the highest levels of Federal, State, and local government.  I am proud to have Vice President Kamala Harris, the first person of South Asian descent to serve as Vice President, and Katherine Tai, the first Asian American United States Trade Representative, in my Administration.<br><br>As we celebrate AA and NHPI communities, we must also redouble our commitment to combating the surge of anti-Asian hate crimes.  The First Lady and I shared the Nation&#8217;s outrage as we witnessed these crimes increase by 339 percent last year compared to the year before in cities across America.  Many other incidents of anti-Asian bias, xenophobia, and harassment that surfaced throughout the COVID-19 pandemic were not even reported.  We cannot allow these horrific acts to continue threatening the safety of AA and NHPI Americans &#8212; especially women, girls, and the elderly.  These acts are wrong; they are un-American; and they must stop. <br><br>In my first week in office, I directed all executive departments and agencies to combat xenophobia, hate, and discrimination against AA and NHPI communities.  I also signed into law last May the COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act to provide law enforcement with resources to identify, investigate, and report hate crimes and ensure that hate crimes information is more accessible to AA and NHPI communities.<br><br>As we work to ensure that hatred has no safe harbor in America&#8217;s future, we must confront shameful chapters in our history.  That is why, for example, I signed into law the Amache National Historic Site Act &#8212; to memorialize the 10,000 Japanese Americans who were unjustly imprisoned at Amache during World War II.  And we will continue to root out racial injustices of our past and advance equity for all Americans as we move forward.<br><br>Toward that aim, my Administration is making long-overdue investments in AA and NHPI communities.  I reestablished and expanded the President&#8217;s Advisory Commission and the White House Initiative on Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders.  The American Rescue Plan helped reduce poverty among AA and NHPI families by approximately 26 percent.  We have increased access to capital, training, and counseling for AA and NHPI entrepreneurs so their businesses can thrive.  We are also working to ensure that healthcare resources are available to AA and NHPI communities.  And we are rebuilding our immigration system so everyone is treated fairly and humanely &#8212; including AA and NHPI communities.<br><br>This month, we celebrate our fellow Americans from AA and NHPI communities and pay tribute to all they have done to help fulfill the promise of America for all.  Together, let us recommit ourselves to building a country in which every American &#8212; regardless of who they are, where they come from, or what they look like &#8212; has an equal opportunity to thrive.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Heritage Month.  I call upon all Americans to learn more about the history of AA and NHPIs, and to observe this month with appropriate programs and activities.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Physical Fitness and Sports Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-physical-fitness-and-sports-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52102</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout the pandemic, Americans have found creative ways to maintain their physical fitness through sports or other forms of physical activity.&#160; During National Physical Fitness and Sports Month, we renew our commitment to staying active and encourage all Americans to participate in activities that improve their well-being and lead to healthier lifestyles. Thanks to our&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Throughout the pandemic, Americans have found creative ways to maintain their physical fitness through sports or other forms of physical activity.&nbsp; During National Physical Fitness and Sports Month, we renew our commitment to staying active and encourage all Americans to participate in activities that improve their well-being and lead to healthier lifestyles.<br><br>Thanks to our dedicated health care professionals and millions of Americans who have gotten vaccinated and boosted, schools, gyms, and businesses across the country have reopened.&nbsp; Stadiums are, once again, filled with fans cheering on their favorite sports teams and athletes.<br><br>But for the past few years, rates of physical activity have decreased &#8212; especially among groups at high risk for COVID-19. &nbsp;Socioeconomic disparities, including a lack of opportunities to participate in sports and fitness programs, have exacerbated the problem.&nbsp;&nbsp;The environments where people live, learn, work, and play also affect physical activity.&nbsp;&nbsp;Other barriers to regular physical activity, such as time, money, safety, and accessibility, impact the health and well-being of children and adults in every community. &nbsp;We must seek out equitable solutions to ensure that all Americans can live a more active, healthier lifestyle.<br><br>Fitness and sports are not only good for our physical health, they also improve the quality of our lives overall.&nbsp; Experts agree that even small amounts of physical activity can make a significant difference in a person&#8217;s physical and mental health. &nbsp;For example, it can reduce the risk of chronic diseases, blood pressure, and anxiety while improving sleep &#8212; among other health benefits.<br><br>Every sector has a role to play in removing barriers and increasing opportunities for Americans to participate in physical activities.&nbsp; That is why I issued an Executive Order to renew the President&#8217;s Council on Sports, Fitness &amp; Nutrition, focusing on the importance of mental health related to physical fitness and nutrition.&nbsp; Through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&#8217;s &#8220;Active People, Healthy Nation&#8221; initiative, we are providing an evidence-based blueprint to help 27 million Americans become more physically active by 2027.&nbsp; Additionally, the Department of Health and Human Services&#8217; &#8220;Move Your Way&#8221; campaign is informing Americans about activities they can do to stay healthy through the Physical Activity Guidelines for Americans.<br><br>This month, let us all find ways to become more physically active in our daily lives.&nbsp; Take a walk, hike in your favorite park, try a new fitness class, join a local sports team, or volunteer at a community race.&nbsp;Whatever physical activity you choose, fitness will lead to better and healthier lives for all Americans.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as National Physical Fitness and Sports Month. &nbsp;I call upon the people of the United States to make daily physical activity a priority, to support efforts to increase access to sports opportunities in their communities, and to pursue physical fitness as an essential part of healthy living.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Loyalty Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-loyalty-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52099</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Loyalty Day, we reaffirm our allegiance to the Nation we share and to the principles of freedom, justice, equality, and dignity enshrined in the Declaration of Independence and the United States Constitution. Our unity and common purpose as Americans &#8212; not hindered but strengthened by our differences &#8212; is and has always been the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Loyalty Day, we reaffirm our allegiance to the Nation we share and to the principles of freedom, justice, equality, and dignity enshrined in the Declaration of Independence and the United States Constitution.<br><br>Our unity and common purpose as Americans &#8212; not hindered but strengthened by our differences &#8212; is and has always been the source of our limitless potential.&nbsp; The weaving together of diverse cultures, heritages, religions, backgrounds, and ideals across generations has sparked our capacity to build the strongest, freest, and most prosperous country the world has ever known. &nbsp;And though we have not always fully lived up to our founding promise of equality and justice for all, we have never fully walked away from that promise either.&nbsp; It is up to each of us to heed the call of our Constitution &#8212; to do all that we can to form a more perfect Union, coming together around the values and ideals that make us one united people.<br><br>Today, we salute the Americans whose hard work and sacrifice have strengthened our Nation in common cause &#8211;including veterans who have defended our country in uniform; abolitionists, suffragists, activists, and advocates who have helped deliver the full promise of America to more Americans; workers and entrepreneurs whose ingenuity and vision have helped expand the possibilities of life in our Nation; and countless others who have made America a beacon of hope for people throughout the world.<br><br>We also extend our deep and abiding gratitude to the members of our Armed Forces, as well as to their families, caregivers, and survivors.&nbsp; We thank our dedicated educators for their essential work lifting up the next generation of Americans, and we applaud our first responders and other essential workers for their selflessness and determination every day &#8212; especially throughout these past 2 years, as they have carried our Nation on their backs.&nbsp; May 1 is also International Workers&#8217; Day &#8212; and today, we honor the workers of every age and background who built this country and who continue to help build a better America today.&nbsp; Today and every day, we are grateful to all of the workers who have organized and fought to improve our Nation and create a fairer and more just society for all.<br><br>To celebrate our shared American spirit and the sacrifices so many of our fellow citizens have made, the Congress, by Public Law 85-529, as amended, has designated the first day of May each year as Loyalty Day.&nbsp; On this day, let us reaffirm our commitment to the values that bind us together and honor all those who have defended our freedom and ideals.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim May 1, 2022, as Loyalty Day.&nbsp; This Loyalty Day, I call upon the people of the United States to join in this national observance, display the American flag, and pledge allegiance to our Republic for which it stands.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Building Safety Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-national-building-safety-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During National Building Safety Month, we renew our commitment to strengthening our buildings so that all Americans are safe.  As our Nation continues to mourn the loss of those who perished in the Surfside condominium collapse and other building disasters, it is clear that the quality and resiliency of our infrastructure has never been more&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>During National Building Safety Month, we renew our commitment to strengthening our buildings so that all Americans are safe.  As our Nation continues to mourn the loss of those who perished in the Surfside condominium collapse and other building disasters, it is clear that the quality and resiliency of our infrastructure has never been more important.  This month we also show our appreciation to the dedicated professionals who work tirelessly to create affordable, sustainable, and structurally sound buildings for our communities.<br> <br>The impact of climate change and the increasing frequency and severity of natural hazard incidents &#8212; injuring people and damaging property and the environment &#8212; pose significant challenges for our infrastructure.  Increasing our energy efficiency plays an important role in keeping Americans safe.  Residential and commercial buildings account for more than one-third of the climate-altering carbon pollution that America releases each year &#8212; directly affecting our climate.  Although hurricanes, floods, extreme heat, and wildfires impact communities across the Nation, they disproportionately impact communities of color and low-income communities that cannot necessarily afford to modernize their buildings or prepare for and recover from climate hazards.<br><br>The historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law tackles these challenges head on. It enables us to repair our Nation&#8217;s aging infrastructure, modernize and electrify our buildings, and advance our climate resiliency. By investing in infrastructure, we are investing in opportunities and quality jobs for Americans &#8212; particularly in disadvantaged and underserved communities. To further support these communities, we are also providing grant funds for equitable disaster recovery.<br><br>This year&#8217;s National Building Safety Month theme &#8212; &#8220;Safety for All: Codes in Action&#8221; &#8212; is an important reminder that modern building code adoption and enforcement is essential to keeping our homes, businesses, schools, and other facilities safe.  By investing in our infrastructure, modernizing our buildings, and adopting building codes, our buildings will contribute less to climate change, protect more Americans, and be better positioned to withstand extreme natural hazards in the future.<br><br>As we recommit to effective safety standards this month, let us pay tribute to building professionals nationwide &#8212; architects, engineers, construction workers, inspectors, building officials, and others &#8212; who help safeguard our communities.  Let us strengthen our collaboration within and across the public, private, and non-profit sectors to address building safety needs today so we can meet the infrastructure challenges of tomorrow.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as National Building Safety Month.  I encourage citizens, government agencies, businesses, nonprofits, and other interested groups to join in activities that raise awareness about building safety.  I also call on all Americans to learn more about how they can contribute to building safety at home, work, and in their communities.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Older Americans Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-older-americans-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During Older Americans Month, we honor our Nation&#8217;s seniors and the tremendous impact they have made in helping build a more perfect Union. &#160;Older Americans contribute their time and wisdom to make our communities stronger, more informed, and better connected.&#160; They are our loved ones, friends, mentors, essential workers, volunteers, and neighbors.&#160; We celebrate their&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>During Older Americans Month, we honor our Nation&#8217;s seniors and the tremendous impact they have made in helping build a more perfect Union. &nbsp;Older Americans contribute their time and wisdom to make our communities stronger, more informed, and better connected.&nbsp; They are our loved ones, friends, mentors, essential workers, volunteers, and neighbors.&nbsp; We celebrate their achievements and recommit to providing our elders with the support and services they need to thrive and age with dignity.<br><br>Older adults have always been a vital source of strength and resilience in America.&nbsp; During the pandemic, many seniors came out of retirement to serve their communities in health care and education roles, filling job vacancies in critical shortage areas. &nbsp;Moving forward, we must ensure that older Americans have the appropriate resources to maintain their independence and stay connected to their communities.<br><br>My Administration is committed to keeping older Americans safe and healthy as they age.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan allocated $1.4 billion to providing older adults with services for nutrition, health promotion, disease prevention, caregiver support, and long-term care.&nbsp; It also provided additional Medicaid funding to support millions of older adults with disabilities and to help States improve the quality of caregiving jobs.&nbsp; My Administration is also dedicated to improving the safety and quality of care in nursing homes &#8212; ensuring that they have sufficient staff, that families have the&nbsp;necessary information to support their loved ones, and that poorly performing nursing homes are held accountable.<br><br>This year, we celebrate the 50th anniversary of the Older Americans Act Nutrition Program &#8212; the first Federal program to&nbsp;support the well-being of older Americans through meal deliveries, nutrition services, educational programs, and counseling.&nbsp; We also celebrate the 10th anniversary of the National Plan to Address Alzheimer&#8217;s Disease and recommit to building upon this important work.<br><br>During Older Americans Month, let us pay tribute to the seniors who raised and guided us throughout our lives, and let us renew our commitment to honoring their contributions by giving them the fullest care, support, and respect they deserve.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 2022 as Older Americans Month.&nbsp; This month and beyond, I call upon all Americans to celebrate older adults for their contributions, support their independence, and recognize their unparalleled value to our Nation.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Public Service Recognition Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/04/29/a-proclamation-on-public-service-recognition-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 16:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52090</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[America&#8217;s dedicated public servants are the lifeblood of&#160;our democracy. &#160;Every day, millions of public workers at all levels of government do extraordinary things to make our lives better and our country stronger.&#160; During Public Service Recognition Week, we honor the dedicated Federal, State, Tribal, and local public servants who embody the spirit of service and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>America&#8217;s dedicated public servants are the lifeblood of&nbsp;our democracy. &nbsp;Every day, millions of public workers at all levels of government do extraordinary things to make our lives better and our country stronger.&nbsp; During Public Service Recognition Week, we honor the dedicated Federal, State, Tribal, and local public servants who embody the spirit of service and endless possibilities that define America.<br><br>Public servants make crucial contributions in every community in America.&nbsp; They educate our children, keep our communities safe, defend our country, deliver our mail, maintain our roads and bridges, develop cures for diseases, improve sustainability, and care for our veterans &#8212; among countless other essential services that keep our country safe and propel us forward.&nbsp; Public servants reflect the full diversity of this Nation, and deliver the promise of a Government by and for the people.<br><br>Our public servants have displayed remarkable resilience and dedication throughout the COVID-19 pandemic. &nbsp;They have led&nbsp;vaccination efforts to keep our communities safe, provided relief to small businesses, supported natural disaster recovery efforts, and safely reopened schools so that our students can learn.&nbsp; I am proud that my Administration&#8217;s American Rescue Plan provided $350 billion to State, Tribal, and local governments so that they could retain and re-hire vital public servants &#8212; educators, police officers, firefighters, public works employees, and countless others.&nbsp; The American Rescue Plan also provided $122 billion for our public schools, equipping them with the resources they need to operate safely and support our students.&nbsp; Every day, public servants continue to put these funds to work in ways that transform our communities for the better.<br><br>My Administration is committed to protecting, empowering, and rebuilding the career Federal workforce so they can bring more resources to bear in service of the American people. &nbsp;To&nbsp;recruit and retain the best career civil service employees, I&nbsp;directed executive departments and agencies to increase the&nbsp;minimum wage for Federal employees to $15 per hour to make Government jobs more competitive.&nbsp; I established a White House Task Force on Worker Organizing and Empowerment, led by Vice President Harris, which has already put forward nearly 70 recommendations to strengthen the right to unionize among Federal Government workers.&nbsp; I have also taken steps to protect Federal employees against discrimination on the basis of gender identity or sexual orientation.&nbsp; I established a government-wide initiative to advance diversity, equity, and inclusion in the Federal workforce &#8212; because when public servants reflect the full diversity of the communities they serve, governments are more effective and successful.<br><br>I am proud that my Administration has delivered significant relief to public servants who have Federal student loans. &nbsp;It is crucial that student loans create a pathway to opportunity, not a lifelong burden. &nbsp;In October, my Administration announced a series of actions to make it easier for borrowers to receive loan forgiveness. &nbsp;Since then, more than 100,000 public servants have received nearly $6.2 billion in student loan debt relief. &nbsp;We will continue to build a student loan system that provides borrowers the relief they need.<br><br>This week, we recognize the indispensable contributions of our Nation&#8217;s public servants.&nbsp; We honor all our public workers who perform critical roles across our country and around the globe.&nbsp; I have the greatest honor of serving alongside these workers every day, and I am humbled by their commitment to building a better America.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim May 1 through May 7, 2022, as Public Service Recognition Week.&nbsp; I call upon all Americans to celebrate public servants and their contributions this week and throughout the year.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-ninth day of April, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
