<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 19:11:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The White&#160;House Announces Guest List for the First Lady’s Box for the 2022 State of the Union&#160;Address</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/the-white-house-announces-guest-list-for-the-first-ladys-box-for-2022-state-of-the-union-address/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 19:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48091</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON, D.C. –&#160;&#160;First Lady Jill Biden will welcome&#160;selected&#160;guests from across the United States to join her in the viewing box for President Biden’s State of the Union Address this evening, Tuesday, March 1, 2022.&#160;Each&#160;of these individuals,&#160;with&#160;their resilience, innovation,&#160;service,&#160;and courage,&#160;were&#160;chosen&#160;by the White House&#160;because they&#160;represent&#160;policies&#160;or themes to be addressed by the President in his speech.&#160;&#160;&#160; The Second&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON, D.C. –&nbsp;&nbsp;First Lady Jill Biden will welcome&nbsp;selected&nbsp;guests from across the United States to join her in the viewing box for President Biden’s State of the Union Address this evening, Tuesday, March 1, 2022.&nbsp;Each&nbsp;of these individuals,&nbsp;with&nbsp;their resilience, innovation,&nbsp;service,&nbsp;and courage,&nbsp;were&nbsp;chosen&nbsp;by the White House&nbsp;because they&nbsp;represent&nbsp;policies&nbsp;or themes to be addressed by the President in his speech.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The<strong> </strong>Second Gentleman,<strong>&nbsp;Mr. Douglas&nbsp;Emhoff</strong>,<strong>&nbsp;</strong>the President’s sister,&nbsp;<strong>Valerie Biden Owens</strong>,&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<strong>Ambassador of Ukraine to the United States,&nbsp;Oksana&nbsp;Markarova</strong>,&nbsp;will also join the First Lady in the viewing box.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>The following&nbsp;Americans, listed in alphabetical order,&nbsp;will be seated in the box&nbsp;with&nbsp;the First Lady and Second Gentleman:&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Joseph “JoJo”&nbsp;Burgess&nbsp;</strong>(Washington,&nbsp;Pennsylvania)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><strong>New Employee Organization Trainer, United Steelworkers Local 1557&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br>Burgess is a 20-year member of the United Steelworkers and works at the U.S. Steel Clairton Coke Works facility, where he assists with training new hires&nbsp;and inspires future generations of steelworkers.&nbsp;The son of two former steelworkers, Burgess&nbsp;graduated high school in 1988 and promptly joined the U.S. Army, where he spent seven years in the military, including a tour during Operation Desert Storm. Upon his transition from the U.S. Army, he began his career in manufacturing. Burgess is an active member of the NAACP Washington branch.&nbsp;&nbsp;His son recently became a third-generation steelworker in the Pittsburgh&nbsp;area.&nbsp;&nbsp;Burgess introduced President Biden&nbsp;recently at an event at Mill 19 in Pittsburgh&nbsp;about&nbsp;the importance of investing in infrastructure, manufacturing, and&nbsp;making more in America.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Joshua Davis</strong>&nbsp;(Midlothian, Virginia)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><strong>7th&nbsp;Grade, Swift Creek Middle School, Diabetes Advocate&nbsp;</strong><br>Davis is a 13-year-old from Midlothian, VA, who was diagnosed with Type 1 diabetes when he was 11 months old. When he was four years old, he advocated for the Virginia General Assembly to pass a bill making school safer for kids with Type 1 diabetes. The Davis family, including his father Brian, who also has Type 1 diabetes, has&nbsp;continued to raise awareness about the importance of lowering prescription drug costs for American families. Davis and his mother, Shannon, introduced President Biden at an event on prescription drug costs at Germanna Community College in Culpeper, VA on February 10, 2022.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Refynd&nbsp;Duro</strong>&nbsp;(Galloway,&nbsp;Ohio)&nbsp;<br><strong>Progressive Care Unit Nurse, The Ohio State Wexner Medical Center&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br>Duro&nbsp;has been treating patients with COVID-19 since the beginning of the pandemic, and at times has had to quarantine away from her family because of her job, including her four-year-old son. She serves as a bedside nurse and advocate for bedside nurses and patient safety, a role she has held for 19 years. Her career started in a Neuro Intermediate Care Unit and in an outpatient dialysis unit. She then transferred to a level 1 trauma center at The Ohio State Wexner Medical Center, where she has been working for the last 12 years.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Patrick “Pat”&nbsp;Gelsinger</strong>&nbsp;(Santa Clara, California)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><strong>Chief Executive Officer, Intel&nbsp;</strong><br>Gelsinger&nbsp;serves as the CEO of Intel, where he spent the first 30 years of his career and served as Intel’s first Chief Technology Officer. He is a member of the National Security Telecommunications Advisory Committee. On January 21, 2022,&nbsp;Gelsinger&nbsp;announced&nbsp;one of the largest investments in a semiconductor manufacturing facility in recent U.S. history.&nbsp;Construction on a $20 billion Intel facility near Columbus, Ohio, will begin this year built by union labor, creating over 7,000 construction jobs and another 3,000 jobs running the high-tech facility.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Frances Haugen</strong>&nbsp;(Iowa City, Iowa)&nbsp;<br><strong>Former Facebook Lead Product Manager on Civic Misinformation&nbsp;</strong><br>Haugen is a specialist in algorithmic product management, having worked on ranking algorithms at Google, Pinterest, Yelp and Facebook. Haugen was recruited to Facebook to be the lead Product Manager on the Civic Misinformation team, which dealt with issues related to democracy and misinformation, and, later, worked on counter-espionage. She is an advocate for more&nbsp;humanity and transparency across the tech and social media industry, especially as it relates to teen mental health.<br><br><strong>Melissa Isaac&nbsp;</strong>(Mt. Pleasant, Michigan)&nbsp;<br><strong>Gizhwaasod&nbsp;(“Protector of the Young”) at the Michigan Department of Education’s Indigenous Education Initiative and Founder of Saginaw Chippewa Indian Tribe (SCIT)’s Project AWARE Program&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong><br>Isaac is an enrolled member of the Saginaw Chippewa Indian Tribe and serves her community through her role at the Michigan Department of Education. Most recently, Isaac worked as the Director of Education for the Saginaw Chippewa Indian Tribe. As an elementary school teacher at Saginaw Chippewa Academy (SCA), Isaac recognized the need to support the mental health of her students and their families. She later successfully applied for a Project AWARE grant from the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. Using this grant, Isaac expanded mental health services for children at SCA and two public school districts, which included services for Native American children. Previously, First Lady and U.S. Surgeon General Dr. Vivek Murthy met Melissa Isaac on October 24, 2021, when they hosted a listening session focused on youth mental health with members of the Saginaw Chippewa Indian Tribe, educators, and families in Mt. Pleasant, Michigan.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Danielle Robinson&nbsp;</strong>(Columbus, Ohio)&nbsp;<br><strong>Surviving Spouse of Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson&nbsp;</strong><br>Danielle Robinson is the widow of Sergeant First Class Heath Robinson, who deployed to Camp Bondsteel in Kosovo and the Camp Liberty/Victory complex in Iraq. SFC Robinson was&nbsp;serving on&nbsp;active duty as a combat engineer in the Ohio National Guard when he was diagnosed with a rare autoimmune disorder and stage 4 lung cancer.  He passed away in May of 2020.  Robinson&nbsp;is&nbsp;an advocate for helping service members and veterans who have been exposed to&nbsp;environmental hazards&nbsp;and burn pits while&nbsp;serving.  Robinson, the mother of an 8-year-old daughter named Brielle, has a Doctorate in Physical Therapy and has been practicing for 10 years. She works with patients who have orthopedic injuries and neurological disorders. &nbsp;<br><br><strong>Kezia&nbsp;Rodriguez&nbsp;</strong>(North Bergen, New Jersey)&nbsp;<br><strong>Student-Parent at Bergen Community College&nbsp;</strong><br>Rodriguez is a full-time student at Bergen Community College and mother of twin daughters. She enrolled her children in Bergen’s tuition-free child care program, an initiative made possible by the American Rescue Plan. Rodriguez is on track to graduate Bergen with an&nbsp;associate’s&nbsp;degree in&nbsp;general&nbsp;science and aims to transfer to a four-year institution for a bachelor’s degree in nursing. Having access to high-quality, affordable child care supports Rodriguez as she completes her education. Originally from Queens, New York, she is a first-generation American and the daughter of parents from Brazil. Rodriguez introduced the First Lady at Bergen Community College on January 20, 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###&nbsp; </p>



<p>Additional information about the State of the Union, including the livestream, is available at:&nbsp;WhiteHouse.gov/SOTU.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of Vice President Harris’s Calls with European&#160;Leaders</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/readout-of-vice-president-harriss-calls-with-european-leaders/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 18:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48088</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Kamala Harris today had five separate calls with European leaders from NATO’s eastern flank to discuss our collective response to Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked invasion of Ukraine. The Vice President spoke individually with: Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia; Prime Minister Krisjanis Karins of Latvia; Prime Minister Ingrida Simonyte of Lithuania; Prime Minister&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Vice President Kamala Harris today had five separate calls with European leaders from NATO’s eastern flank to discuss our collective response to Russia’s unjustified and unprovoked invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>The Vice President spoke individually with: Prime Minister Kaja Kallas of Estonia; Prime Minister Krisjanis Karins of Latvia; Prime Minister Ingrida Simonyte of Lithuania; Prime Minister Mateusz Morawiecki of Poland; and Prime Minister Nicolae Ciuca of Romania.</p>



<p>Throughout each of the calls, the Vice President underscored the strength and unity of our Alliance and welcomed each of her counterparts’ leadership and coordination on robust response measures, including sanctions and other economic measures through the European Union. They also discussed the robust NATO response. Following the February 25 extraordinary NATO summit, the Vice President and the European leaders reviewed recent and upcoming U.S. and NATO force posture adjustments in Europe, including the deployment of thousands of U.S. troops and critical capabilities to reinforce our deterrence posture and collective defense. In each call, the Vice President reaffirmed our ironclad commitment to NATO’s Article 5.</p>



<p>The Vice President also reiterated our ongoing support for the people of the Ukraine, including through economic, security, and humanitarian assistance, and commended each Ally’s assistance to Ukraine. The Vice President noted that we will continue to support Ukraine and Ukraine’s neighbors as they deal with refugee flows and other humanitarian needs. She welcomed steps already taken to offer refuge to those fleeing violence.</p>



<p>Lastly, the Vice President reaffirmed U.S. support for the international rules and norms that have brought peace and security in Europe since World War II and that have served as the foundation of the NATO Alliance. She noted that we will be steadfast and united with our Allies in defense of these principles.</p>



<p></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Zelenskyy of&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-zelenskyy-of-ukraine-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 18:44:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48085</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine to discuss the United States’ continued backing for Ukraine as it defends itself against Russian aggression.  President Biden underscored the United States’ sustained help for Ukraine, including ongoing deliveries of security assistance, economic support, and humanitarian aid.  The leaders discussed how the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Volodymyr Zelenskyy of Ukraine to discuss the United States’ continued backing for Ukraine as it defends itself against Russian aggression.  President Biden underscored the United States’ sustained help for Ukraine, including ongoing deliveries of security assistance, economic support, and humanitarian aid.  The leaders discussed how the United States, along with Allies and partners, is working to hold Russia accountable, including by imposing sanctions that are already having an impact on the Russian economy.  The leaders discussed Russia’s escalation of attacks on sites used by civilians in Ukraine, including today’s bombing near Babyn Yar Holocaust memorial.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on Maximizing Assistance to Respond to&#160;COVID-&#8288;19</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/01/memorandum-on-maximizing-assistance-to-respond-to-covid-19-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 17:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48079</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY               THE ADMINISTRATOR OF THE FEDERAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, 42 U.S.C. 5121–5207 (the &#8220;Stafford Act&#8221;), I hereby&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE SECRETARY OF HOMELAND SECURITY</p>



<p>              THE ADMINISTRATOR OF THE FEDERAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT AGENCY</p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, 42 U.S.C. 5121–5207 (the &#8220;Stafford Act&#8221;), I hereby order as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1.&nbsp; Policy.&nbsp; It is the policy of my Administration to combat and respond to the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic with the full capacity and capability of the Federal Government to protect and support our families, schools, and businesses, and to assist State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments to do the same, including through emergency and disaster assistance available from the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and through Federal support of the Governors&#8217; use of the National Guard.</p>



<p>Sec. 2.&nbsp; Assistance for Category B COVID-19 Emergency Protective Measures.&nbsp; FEMA shall provide a 100 percent Federal cost share for all work eligible for assistance under Public Assistance Category B, pursuant to sections 403 (42 U.S.C. 5170b), 502 (42 U.S.C. 5192), and 503 (42 U.S.C. 5193) of the Stafford Act, including work described in section 3(a) of the Presidential Memorandum of January 21, 2021 (Memorandum to Extend Federal Support to Governors&#8217; Use of the National Guard to Respond to COVID-19 and to Increase Reimbursement and Other Assistance Provided to States), and in section 2 of that memorandum on the Governors&#8217; use of the National Guard, performed from January 20, 2020, through July 1, 2022.</p>



<p>Sec. 3.&nbsp; General Provisions.&nbsp; (a)&nbsp; Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>(i)&nbsp;&nbsp; the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>(ii)&nbsp; the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (b)&nbsp; This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (c)&nbsp; This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United&nbsp;States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (d)&nbsp; The Administrator of FEMA is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the <em>Federal Register</em>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Supporting Veterans Experiencing Financial Hardship and Addressing the Harmful Effects of Military Environmental&#160;Exposures</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-supporting-veterans-experiencing-financial-hardship-and-addressing-the-harmful-effects-of-military-environmental-exposures/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President believes that our Nation has a sacred obligation– to properly prepare and equip the troops we send into harm’s way, and to care for them and their families when they return home. Far too often military service comes with a cost, and we owe it to our veterans and their families to address&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President believes that our Nation has a sacred obligation– to properly prepare and equip the troops we send into harm’s way, and to care for them and their families when they return home. Far too often military service comes with a cost, and we owe it to our veterans and their families to address the consequences comprehensively. This means helping veterans build lives of opportunity when they leave military service by helping them to find employment, providing pathways to home ownership, and providing financial support and relief for those who are struggling.</p>



<p>Our veterans are the best of America and supporting the women and men who wear the uniform is a commitment that unites all of us. Throughout history, Democrats and Republicans have been working together to ensure access to world-class health care and benefits for our veterans. And, while our nation’s longest war is over, our commitment to support our veteran continues.</p>



<p>To honor those who have worn the uniform of the United States, and to ensure we address the needs of veterans in financial hardship or those who have encountered environmental hazards, the Biden-Harris Administration is:</p>



<p><strong><u>Reducing Financial Hardship</u></strong></p>



<p>The President’s American Rescue Plan provided $17 billion to help veterans, ensuring the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) had funding to provide health care services for veterans, including funding for homelessness programs, and to implement a rapid retraining assistance program to help veterans impacted by the pandemic. The American Rescue Plan also eliminated all out-of-pocket medical cost for veterans and provided much needed financial relief to veterans experiencing economic hardship during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>



<p>Veterans in financial hardship who get treatment through VA are entitled to get their medical debt forgiven. But currently, they can only apply for that medical debt relief through a complex, paper form with complicated eligibility requirements. Veterans may be deterred from applying for much-needed relief because the application process is too confusing and time-consuming. To address this barrier, today the President is announcing that VA is:</p>



<p><strong>Simplifying the process for claiming medical debt forgiveness. </strong>VA will streamline the request process and set a simple income threshold for receiving medical debt relief. The request process will include an online option for veterans and reduce the effort required by veterans to access relief. These changes will go into effect in the next 90 to 120 days. This change comes on top of the approximately $1 billion in medical debt the VA has already forgiven for veterans under the American Rescue Plan, which eliminated all out-of-pocket medical cost for veterans and provided much needed financial relief to veterans experiencing economic hardship during the COVID-19 pandemic. It also comes on top of a <a href="https://www.va.gov/opa/pressrel/pressrelease.cfm?id=5758">final rule</a> VA issued in February 2022, under which it will virtually cease reporting unfavorable debt, including medical debt, to consumer reporting agencies.</p>



<p><strong><u>Addressing Harmful Effects of Environmental Exposures</u></strong></p>



<p>Too often, military service results in increased health risks and other consequences for our veterans. Some of these injuries and illnesses may take years to manifest. Some are visible and some are invisible. This can make it difficult for veterans to prove in-service exposure and establish a direct connection for disabilities resulting from military environmental exposures such as burn pits.</p>



<p>To mitigate the difficulty in establishing entitlement to benefits, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) has established the presumption of exposure and service connection for various chronic conditions when the evidence of a military environmental exposure and the associated health risks are strong in the aggregate but hard to prove on an individual basis.</p>



<p>To further advance efforts to address the harmful effects of exposures during military service, the Biden-Harris Administration is:</p>



<p><strong>Proposing to establish presumption for rare respiratory cancers.</strong> Based on a focused review of scientific and medical evidence related to exposure to fine particulate matter and the subsequent development of rare respiratory cancers, the Secretary of VA plans to propose a rule that will add presumptive service connection for several rare respiratory cancers for certain veterans. These cancers under consideration include squamous cell carcinoma (SCC) of the larynx, SCC of the trachea, adenocarcinoma of the trachea, salivary gland-type tumors of the trachea, adenosquamous carcinoma of the lung, large cell carcinoma of the lung, salivary gland-type tumors of the lung, sarcomatoid carcinoma of the lung and typical and atypical carcinoid of the lung.</p>



<p><strong>Supporting legislation to better care for veterans with environmental exposures</strong>. TheAdministration strongly supports ongoing legislative efforts to expand access to health care services and benefits for veterans impacted by environmental exposures. We are committed to ensuring we are able to quickly and fairly recognize additional presumptions of service-connected disabilities by modernizing the processes for evaluating the relationship between exposure and health outcomes. The President looks forward to signing legislation that addresses the toxic legacy of environmental exposures sustained by veterans during their military service.</p>



<p>These actions build on ongoing efforts the Administration is taking to ensure timely access to services and benefits for veterans who experience service connected disabilities from military environmental exposures, including:</p>



<p><strong>Processing claims for new presumptive conditions.</strong>&nbsp;In August, VA began processing disability claims for asthma, rhinitis, and sinusitis based on presumed exposure to particulate matter. Veterans who served in the Southwest Asia theater of operations and other areas and who developed these conditions within 10 years of military service are now eligible to apply for disability benefits and access to VA health care. This rulemaking was based upon application of the new presumptive model and involved careful review of a study conducted by the National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine, as well as other evidence assessed by VA subject matter experts.<strong> </strong>Since August, VA has completed 16,537 claims, granting over 12,000 veterans and their survivors benefits for one or more conditions, leading to over $36 million in retroactive benefit payments. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Applying a new model to review evidence of service connection for constrictive bronchiolitis</strong>. VA continues to test and refine a new decision-making framework to determine whether to establish presumptions of service connection based on exposure to military environmental hazards during active military service and other purposes. The new model is evidence-based, transparent, and allows VA to make faster policy decisions on crucial exposure issues. This new model will fundamentally change how VA makes decisions on environmental exposures. VA continues to test the model, solicit feedback from internal and external stakeholders, and evaluate its effectiveness. <strong></strong></p>



<p><strong>Raising awareness of VA benefits related to military exposures.&nbsp;</strong>Many veterans were unaware of their eligibility for benefits and services related to potential military exposures. In addition, some claims adjudicators may not have up-to-date awareness of recent policies related to conditions newly presumed to be service-connected.&nbsp;Beginning in November 2021, VA launched a proactive campaign to inform and encourage veterans to file claims related to military environmental exposures. In December 2021, military environmental exposures were featured in the VA Benefits Newsletter, reaching nearly 5 million subscribers. VA continues to share information via its social media platforms weekly.</p>



<p><strong>Requiring training for VA and non-VA providers. </strong>Veterans often find that their providers and compensation and pension examiners are not well-trained to understand or treat veterans’ exposure concerns. To address this, VA directed compensation and pension providers and Veterans Health Administration clinicians to complete a training module on assessing deployment related to environmental exposures. This is the first module in a series of five essential trainings. VA is also encouraging all providers who care for veterans outside of VA through the Community Care Network contract to complete training on the TRAIN Learning Network, VA’s publicly available training site. Furthermore, VA employees and community care providers have been directed to utilize the Exposure Ed App to help providers provide information to Veterans on health effects associated with certain exposures during military service. More information on the app is available <a href="https://mobile.va.gov/app/exposure-ed">here</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Implementing a network of specialized providers and call center.</strong> Veterans with concerns about the health outcomes of military exposures experience inconsistent care to address these specific issues, especially outside of VA. Earlier this year, VA launched VET-HOME, The Veterans Exposure Team-Health Outcomes of Military Exposures. VA plans to hire a total of 73 health professionals, including physicians, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants who will specialize in conducting patient assessments regarding the health effects of military exposures. By January 2023, VA expects to have a fully operational call center and network of experts to help veterans concerned about environmental exposure and provide consultative services to veterans in primary care clinics.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Read Across America Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/01/a-proclamation-on-read-across-america-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 16:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48075</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reading ignites imagination, insight, and inspiration.  It nourishes a child&#8217;s creativity and curiosity, and inspires a passion for lifelong learning.  Books can challenge and inspire.  They can teach important lessons, reveal new worlds, and enrich our understanding of our own &#8212; of different people, perspectives, and cultures.  On Read Across America Day, we celebrate the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Reading ignites imagination, insight, and inspiration.  It nourishes a child&#8217;s creativity and curiosity, and inspires a passion for lifelong learning.  Books can challenge and inspire.  They can teach important lessons, reveal new worlds, and enrich our understanding of our own &#8212; of different people, perspectives, and cultures.  On Read Across America Day, we celebrate the joy of learning and give thanks to the parents, caregivers, educators, librarians, authors, and community members who invest in our Nation&#8217;s children. </p>



<p>For many young Americans, the path to literacy begins with treasured and timeless traditions:&nbsp; being read to at bedtime, gathering in classrooms for story time, and attending events at local libraries with family and friends.&nbsp; Children&#8217;s classics such as Dr. Seuss&#8217; &#8220;Green Eggs and Ham&#8221; and &#8220;Oh, the Places You&#8217;ll Go!&#8221; have inspired a passion for reading and endless creativity that spans generations. &nbsp;Today&#8217;s stories and adventures are as diverse as the world in which we live, and by reading them, we come to more fully understand the vibrant diversity of our Nation &#8212; and the world.&nbsp; This is especially important as young people learn and grow and engage with their own sense of identity.&nbsp; Books build each child&#8217;s sense of belonging and can help inculcate respect and empathy for others.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The First Lady, a lifelong educator, has said, &#8220;reading is the foundation of all education.  It affects every aspect of our society.&#8221;  This has never been truer than today.  It is one of the many reasons why my Administration is committed to advancing educational excellence for every child and literacy for every American.  It is why I have proposed making 2 years of high-quality preschool available to every child in America.  It is one of the reasons why safely reopening schools for in-person instruction was a priority for my Administration from day one &#8212; so that children could get back to learning in the classroom with their peers &#8212; and why the American Rescue Plan included $122 billion to keep schools open safely and help address the learning loss and mental health impacts of missing school.  School districts across the country are already using these funds to support literacy efforts by updating curricula and hiring specialists.</p>



<p>My Administration is also committed to supporting volunteer and literacy programs that help young people and adults master reading.&nbsp; This work is crucial, as half of adults in the United&nbsp;States are unable to read a book written for the eighth-grade level, and nearly a quarter of American adults have not read a book over the last year.</p>



<p>I often say that children are the kite strings that keep our National ambitions aloft.&nbsp; On Read Across America Day, we dedicate ourselves to helping each new generation of readers and thinkers become the leaders who will write a more hopeful chapter in the American narrative and in the story of our shared world.&nbsp; As the great American writer Toni Morrison reminds us:&nbsp; &#8220;If you find a book you really want to read but it hasn&#8217;t been written yet, then you must write it.&#8221;</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2, 2022, as Read Across America Day.&nbsp; I call upon children, families, educators, librarians, public officials, and all the people of the United States to observe this day with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this first day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on Coordinated IEA Release to Support Global Energy&#160;Security</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-coordinated-iea-release-to-support-global-energy-security/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 16:47:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s announcement is another example of partners around the world condemning Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and working together to address the impact of President Putin’s war of choice. President Biden was clear from the beginning that all tools are on the table to protect American businesses and consumers, including from rising prices&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s announcement is another example of partners around the world condemning Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine and working together to address the impact of President Putin’s war of choice. President Biden was clear from the beginning that all tools are on the table to protect American businesses and consumers, including from rising prices at the pump.<br> <br>After intensive around-the-clock coordination and consultation by President Biden, the Administration and our Allies and partners, the International Energy Agency (IEA) Member countries, supported by the European Commission, agreed to a collective release of an initial 60 million barrels of crude oil from our strategic petroleum reserves. As part of this agreement, President Biden will authorize the Department of Energy to release 30 million barrels from the U.S. Strategic Petroleum Reserve.<br> <br>IEA Member countries also agreed to continue monitoring markets and consider further releases as necessary. We are prepared to use every tool available to us to limit disruption to global energy supply as a result of President Putin’s actions. We will also continue our efforts to accelerate diversification of energy supplies away from Russia and to secure the world from Moscow’s weaponization of oil and gas.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Announce Strategy to Address Our National Mental Health Crisis, As Part of Unity Agenda in his First State of the&#160;Union</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-announce-strategy-to-address-our-national-mental-health-crisis-as-part-of-unity-agenda-in-his-first-state-of-the-union/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In his first State of the Union, the President will outline a unity agenda consisting of policy where there has historically been support from both Republicans and Democrats, and call on Congress to send bills to his desk to deliver progress for the American people.&#160; As part of this unity agenda, he will announce a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>In his first State of the Union, the President will outline a unity agenda consisting of policy where there has historically been support from both Republicans and Democrats, and call on Congress to send bills to his desk to deliver progress for the American people.&nbsp; As part of this unity agenda, he will announce a strategy to address our national mental health crisis.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our country faces an unprecedented mental health crisis among people of all ages. Two out of five adults <a href="https://www.kff.org/report-section/the-implications-of-covid-19-for-mental-health-and-substance-use-issue-brief/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">report </a>symptoms of anxiety or depression. And, Black and Brown communities are <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2767308">disproportionately</a><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2767308" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"> </a>undertreated – even as their burden of mental illness has continued to rise. Even before the pandemic, rates of depression and anxiety were inching <a href="https://www.apa.org/pubs/journals/releases/abn-abn0000410.pdf">higher</a>. But the grief, trauma, and physical isolation of the last two years have driven Americans to a <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2021/12/24/collective-trauma-public-outbursts/">breaking point</a>.<br>&nbsp;<br>Our youth have been particularly impacted as losses from COVID and disruptions in routines and relationships have led to increased social isolation, anxiety, and learning loss.&nbsp; More than half of parents <a href="https://www.psychiatry.org/newsroom/news-releases/new-apa-poll-shows-sustained-anxiety-among-americans-more-than-half-of-parents-are-concerned-about-the-mental-well-being-of-their-children">express</a> concern over their children’s mental well-being. An <a href="https://www.mckinsey.com/industries/education/our-insights/covid-19-and-education-the-lingering-effects-of-unfinished-learning">early study</a> has found that students are about five months behind in math and four months behind in reading, compared with students prior to the pandemic. In 2019, one in three high school students and half of female students <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchhstp/dear_colleague/2020/dcl-102320-YRBS-2009-2019-report.html">reported</a> persistent feelings of sadness or hopelessness, an overall increase of 40 percent from 2009. Emergency department <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/12/07/science/pandemic-adolescents-depression-anxiety.html">visits</a> for attempted suicide have risen 51 percent among adolescent girls.<br>&nbsp;<br>This youth mental health crisis has been accentuated by large social media platforms, which for years have been conducting a national experiment on our children and using their data to keep them clicking—with enormous consequences. While technology platforms have improved our lives in some ways, there is <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/surgeon-general-youth-mental-health-advisory.pdf">mounting evidence</a> that social media is harmful to many kids’ and teens’ mental health, well-being, and development. As the Surgeon-General has <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/surgeon-general-youth-mental-health-advisory.pdf">said</a>, “when not deployed responsibly and safely, these tools can pit us against each other, reinforce negative behaviors like bullying and exclusion, and undermine the safe and supportive environments young people need and deserve.” In the State of the Union, the President will call on Congress to strengthen privacy protections, ban targeted advertising to children, and demand technology companies stop collecting personal data on our children.<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden is laying out a vision to transform how mental health is understood, perceived, accessed, treated, and integrated – in and out of health care settings. The American Rescue Plan laid the groundwork, providing critical investments to expand access to mental health services. Now, far more is needed to ensure that everyone who needs help can access care when and where they seek it.<br>&nbsp;<br>The President is announcing a national mental health strategy to strengthen system capacity, connect more Americans to care, and create a continuum of support –transforming our health and social services infrastructure to address mental health holistically and equitably.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong><u>Strengthen System Capacity</u></strong><br>At the center of our national mental health crisis is a severe <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/best-states/articles/2021-06-10/northeastern-states-have-fewest-mental-health-provider-shortages">shortage</a> of behavioral health providers. More than one-third of Americans live in designated <a href="https://data.hrsa.gov/topics/health-workforce/shortage-areas">Mental Health Professional Shortage Areas</a>, communities that have fewer mental health providers than the minimum their level of population would need. Even outside of these shortage areas, the fragmentation of the current system makes it hard for mental health providers to meet people where they are. We must dramatically expand the supply, diversity, and cultural competency of our mental health and substance use disorder workforce – from psychiatrists to psychologists, peers to paraprofessionals – and increase both opportunity and incentive for them to practice in areas of highest need.&nbsp; Our crisis response infrastructure must also be strengthened to ensure that those facing acute behavioral health challenges can be seamlessly connected to necessary services.&nbsp; We will:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Invest in proven programs that bring providers into behavioral health.</strong>&nbsp; The President’s FY23 budget will invest $700 million in programs – like the National Health Service Corps, Behavioral Health Workforce Education and Training Program, and the Minority Fellowship Program – that provide training, access to scholarships and loan repayment to mental health and substance use disorder clinicians committed to practicing in rural and other underserved communities. These major new investments will both expand the pipeline of behavioral health providers and improve their geographic distribution to target areas with the greatest unmet need.</li><li><strong>Pilot new approaches to train a diverse group of paraprofessionals</strong>.&nbsp; Doctors, nurses, and other clinicians cannot do this work alone.&nbsp; In the fall of 2022, HHS expects to award over $225 million in training programs to increase the number of community health workers and other health support workers providing services, including behavioral health support, in underserved communities. The President’s FY23 budget will also propose major new multi-year funding to develop provider capacity and support mental health transformation.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Build a national certification program for peer specialists.&nbsp; </strong>The Biden-Harris Administration will convene stakeholders, launch development, and support implementation of a national certified peer specialist certification program, which will accelerate universal adoption, recognition, and integration of the peer mental health workforce across all elements of the health care system.<br></li><li><strong>Promote the mental well-being of our frontline health workforce. </strong>Three-quarters of frontline health care workers <a href="http://https:/mhanational.org/pandemic-taking-dangerous-toll-mental-health-frontline-healthcare-workers">report</a> burnout, while more than half say they lack adequate supports to cope. The Administration has already <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/07/16/hhs-announces-103-million-arp-funding-to-address-health-workforce-burnout.html">dedicated</a> $103 million in American Rescue Plan funding to address burnout and strengthen resiliency among health care workers. The President will strengthen this commitment by signing the bipartisan Dr. Lorna Breen Health Care Provider Protection Act into law, which will invest $135 million over three years into training health care providers on suicide prevention and behavioral health while launching an awareness campaign to address stigmatization, promote help-seeking and self-care among this workforce. In addition, HHS will continue grant programs to support health systems and provider groups to prevent burnout, relieve workplace stressors, administer stress first aid, and increase access to high-quality mental health care for the frontline health care workforce.<br></li><li><strong>Launch the “988” crisis response line and strengthen community-based crisis response.</strong>&nbsp; This summer, HHS will launch the <a href="https://suicidepreventionlifeline.org/current-events/the-lifeline-and-988/">988</a> mental health crisis service hotline, which will create a national network of local crisis centers fortified by national back up centers to answer calls and texts. Through the American Rescue Plan, the Administration has provided $180 million to support local capacity to answer crisis calls, and establish more community-based mobile crisis response and crisis stabilizing facilities to minimize unnecessary emergency department visits. The President’s FY23 budget will build on this investment with an additional nearly $700 million to staff up and shore up local crisis centers while also building out the broader crisis care continuum: someone to call, someone to respond, and somewhere for every American in crisis to go.<br></li><li><strong>Expand the availability of evidence-based community mental health services.</strong> The American Rescue Plan invested millions of dollars to expand Certified Community Behavioral Health Clinics (CCBHCs), a proven model of care that has been <a href="https://aspe.hhs.gov/reports/preliminary-cost-quality-findings-national-evaluation-certified-community-behavioral-health-clinic-0">shown</a> to improve health outcomes while lowering costs, by delivering 24/7 mental health and substance use care to millions of Americans, no matter who they are or whether they’re able to pay. The President’s FY23 budget will build on this down payment, by proposing to make this program permanent while granting states funding to expand CCBHCs for the communities that need them most. The President’s budget will also permanently extend funding for Community Mental Health Centers, which provide essential mental health services to vulnerable communities that would otherwise lack access.<br></li><li><strong>Invest in research on new practice models</strong>.&nbsp;&nbsp; New scientific and technological innovation has the opportunity to expand our capacity to meet American’s mental health needs, but there is a pressing need for research to validate what works and build a robust evidence base. The President’s FY23 budget will call for investing $5 million in research into promising models for treating mental health conditions.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Connect Americans to Care</strong><br>Less than half of Americans with mental health conditions <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/05/10/cost-and-accessibility-of-mental-health-care-in-america.htm">receive</a> treatment. The average delay from the onset of mental health symptoms to treatment is <a href="https://www.nami.org/mhstats">11 years</a>.&nbsp; Too often, <a href="https://www.apa.org/monitor/2020/07/datapoint-care">costs</a> prevent people from accessing care far. At the same time, those with mental illness are <a href="https://www.psychiatry.org/patients-families/stigma-and-discrimination">often</a> misunderstood, mistreated, mislabeled, and misdirected to services. It is imperative that we promote better pathways to care and make it as easy as possible for all Americans with behavioral health needs – including common and pervasive conditions like anxiety and depression – to access the resources that will improve their well-being. We must fight to ensure that every American can access mental health and substance use disorder care through their insurance coverage, while integrating mental health services and supports into a variety of other settings, online and in the community. The Biden-Harris Administration will: &nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Expand and strengthen parity</strong>. The <a href="https://www.cms.gov/CCIIO/Programs-and-Initiatives/Other-Insurance-Protections/mhpaea_factsheet">2008 Mental Health Parity and Addiction Equity Act</a> called for mental health care benefits to be covered at the same level as physical health care benefits. The President’s fiscal year 2023 (FY23) budget will propose that all health plans cover robust behavioral health services with an adequate network of providers, including three behavioral health visits each year without cost-sharing.</li><li><strong>Integrate mental health and substance use treatment into primary care settings</strong>. Equipping primary care providers with the tools to identify, treat, and manage behavioral health conditions is a <a href="https://bipartisanpolicy.org/download/?file=/wp-content/uploads/2021/03/BPC_Behavioral-Health-Integration-report_R03.pdf">proven</a> approach for delivering quality mental health and substance use care, particularly for individuals with depression. To facilitate adoption of these models, the President’s FY23 budget will double funding for primary and behavioral health integration programs. In addition, using existing authority, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) will test payment models that support the delivery of whole-person care through behavioral health integration and authorize Medicaid reimbursement of inter-professional consultations so that primary care providers can consult with a specialist and provide needed care for patients.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Improve veterans&#8217; access to same-day mental health care. </strong>Veterans are at <a href="https://www.rand.org/pubs/research_briefs/RB10087.html">higher</a> risk for mental health and substance use challenges than the general population. Increasing their access to quality mental health care is the first step to closing this disparity. The Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) will reduce barriers to mental health access by fully implementing their Primary Care Mental Health Integration and Behavioral Health Interdisciplinary Program, which connect veterans to same-day mental health care and improve the integration of these services into primary care settings.<br></li><li><strong>Expand access to tele- and virtual mental health care options. </strong>&nbsp;The use of telehealth to address mental health and substance use needs <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2021/12/03/new-hhs-study-shows-63-fold-increase-in-medicare-telehealth-utilization-during-pandemic.html">rose</a> dramatically during the height of the pandemic and has remained above pre-pandemic levels even where COVID has waned. These tele-mental health services have proven both <a href="https://www.commonwealthfund.org/blog/2020/using-telehealth-meet-mental-health-needs-during-covid-19-crisis">safe and effective</a>, while reducing barriers to care. To maintain continuity of access, the Administration will work with Congress to ensure coverage of tele-behavioral health across health plans, and support appropriate delivery of telemedicine across state lines. At the same time, the HHS will create a learning collaborative with state insurance departments to identify and address state-based barriers, like telehealth limitations, to behavioral health access. And the United States Office of Personnel Management will facilitate widespread, confidential, and easy access to telehealth services, in part by strongly encouraging Federal Employees Health Benefits Program carriers to sufficiently reimburse providers for telehealth services, and to eliminate or reduce co-payments for consumers seeking tele-mental service.<br></li><li><strong>Expand access to mental health support in schools and colleges and universities. </strong>&nbsp;The President has committed to doubling the number of school-based mental health professionals. The Department of Education (ED) will continue to support states, school districts, colleges and universities, in using relief funds – including the more than $160 billion invested by the American Rescue Plan in the Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief (ESSER) and Higher Education Emergency Relief Fund (HEERF) – to address the mental health needs of students, including by training, recruiting, and retaining more school- and college and university-based mental health professionals. With the help of ESSER funds, schools have already seen a 65% increase in social workers, and a 17% increase in counselors. To help schools sustain these roles, the Department of Health and Human Services will make it easier for school-based mental health professionals to seek reimbursement from Medicaid, and the President’s FY23 budget will propose $1 billion to help schools hire additional counselors and school psychologists and other health professionals.<br></li><li><strong>Embed and co-locate mental health and substance use providers into community-based settings</strong>. Expanding pathways to care also means creating new, low-barrier access points, in settings where Americans already live, work, and play. To that end, the President’s FY23 budget will include $50 million to pilot models that embed and co-locate mental health services into non-traditional settings like libraries, community centers, schools, and homeless shelters.<br></li><li><strong>Increase behavioral health navigation resources. </strong>Finding the right care or an available provider can be a frustrating experience. We need to make it easier for Americans both to find help, and to receive it. To meet this need, the Administration will build new easy-to-access, user-friendly online treatment locator tools – starting with a redesigned and refurbished mentalhealth.gov – so Americans can find care when they need it, where they need it, with the click of a button. The Department of Defense will also create a one-stop online resources for service members and their families to access mental health information and locate mental health providers.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Support Americans by Creating Healthy Environments</strong></p>



<p>We cannot transform mental health solely through the health care system. We must also address the determinants of behavioral health, invest in community services, and foster a culture and environment that broadly promotes mental wellness and recovery. This crisis is not a medical one, but a societal one. In December 2021, the Surgeon-General released an <a href="https://www.hhs.gov/sites/default/files/surgeon-general-youth-mental-health-advisory.pdf">Advisory on Protecting Youth Mental Health</a> that outlined a wide range of causes for the national youth mental health crisis and underscored growing concern about the harms of digital technologies, particularly social media, to the mental health and well-being of young people, as well as calling for practical action from technology companies to address these concerns.</p>



<p>We need a whole-of-society effort to address these concerns: to expand prevention programs and actions that improve mental health at every age and across settings; and to enhance programs that support recovery, especially for populations at increased risk during vulnerable transition periods. The Biden-Harris Administration will:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li><strong>Strengthen children’s privacy and ban targeted advertising for children online.</strong><br>The online platforms have <a href="https://wearesocial-cn.s3.cn-north-1.amazonaws.com.cn/common/digital2021/digital-2021-global.pdf">billions</a> of users worldwide, many of whom use the platforms for <a href="https://datareportal.com/reports/digital-2022-united-states-of-america">hours a day</a>. These companies know everything from <a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/states-file-new-suits-against-google-over-location-tracking-11643037890">where users are physically located</a> at any moment, to how many seconds they spend reading a particular post, to intimate personal data like what medical symptoms they have been researching. Children are also subject to the platforms’ intensive and excessive data collection vacuum, which they use to deliver sensational and harmful content and troves of paid advertising to our kids. <a href="https://neweconomics.org/uploads/files/i-Spy__NEF.pdf">By one estimate</a>, online advertising firms hold 72 million data points on the average child by the time they reach the age of 13. The President is calling on Congress to ban excessive data collection on and targeted advertising online for children and young people.<br></li><li><strong>Institute stronger online protections for young people, including prioritizing safety by design standards and practices for online platforms, products, and services. </strong>Social media platforms are designed to be addictive, too often deliver age-inappropriate content, promote unhealthy social comparisons, and enable harassment, child sexual exploitation, stalking, and cyber-bullying. Children, adolescents and teens are uniquely vulnerable to harmful and dangerous content online. Other democratic countries have been acting to prevent and reduce the online harms to their children. The President believes not only that we should have far stronger protections for children’s data and privacy, but that the platforms and other interactive digital service providers should be required to prioritize and ensure the health, safety and well-being of children and young people above profit and revenue in the design of their products and services.<br></li><li><strong>Stop discriminatory algorithmic decision-making that limits opportunities for young Americans. </strong>When a girl searches for jobs online, platforms will too often push her away from fields like engineering that historically have excluded women. Searches for “Black girls,” “Asian girls,” or “Latina girls” too often return harmful content, including pornography rather than role models, toys, or activities. Platforms shape how our kids understand what is possible and access opportunities. When young people are treated unfairly, it can have mental health impacts including anxiety and depression. We must ensure that platforms and other algorithmically-enhanced systems do not discriminatorily target our kids.<br></li><li><strong>Invest in research on social media’s mental harms.</strong> Ample research has now emerged that social media is <a href="https://www.usnews.com/news/health-news/articles/2021-07-20/social-media-is-a-public-health-crisis">associated</a> with negative mental health outcomes, particularly among <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/health/mental-health/social-media-linked-rise-mental-health-disorders-teens-survey-finds-n982526">young people</a>, and that children under 18 are disproportionately <a href="https://www.apa.org/news/apa/2022/social-media-children-teens">vulnerable</a> to the dangerous and harmful content that they might encounter online. More research, however, is needed to understand why and how these harms occur – and how they can be prevented and treated. To meet this need, the President&#8217;s FY23 budget will dedicate at least $5 million toward advancing research on social media&#8217;s harms, as well as the clinical and societal interventions we might deploy to address them. Over the next year, the Department of Health and Human Services will also launch a national Center of Excellence on Social Media and Mental Wellness, which will develop and disseminate information, guidance, and training on the full impact of adolescent social media use, especially the risks these services pose to their mental health.      <br></li><li><strong>Expand early childhood and school-based intervention services and supports</strong>. Half of all mental disorders begin <a href="https://www.samhsa.gov/data/sites/default/files/report_1973/ShortReport-1973.html">before</a> the age of 14. And when systems act to promote well-being at early developmental stages, youth reap the mental and emotional benefits for <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamapediatrics/fullarticle/2766307">years</a> to come. The American Rescue Plan dedicated millions of dollars to youth mental health. The President’s FY23 budget builds on this investment and proposes to make historic investments in youth mental health services, including more than $70 million in infant and early childhood mental health programs. For example, Project LAUNCH works to ensure that the systems that serve young children have the resources and knowledge to foster their social, emotional, cognitive, and behavioral development. The FY23 budget will also continue funding for the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program of the Department of Health and Human Services, which supports new families by teaching positive parenting skills, conducting developmental and mental health screenings, promoting school readiness, and linking to community resources and supports. Additionally, the President&#8217;s FY23 budget will propose to dramatically expand funding for community schools by increasing funding for the Full-Service Community School program by over $400 million dollars relative to current levels – a more than ten-fold increase. Community schools provide a range of wraparound supports to students and their families, including mental health services and other integrated student supports.<br></li><li><strong>Set students up for success. </strong>When students struggle in school, it impacts their well-being. A comprehensive strategy to support student wellness must also include efforts to address the impact of the pandemic on student learning, particularly on students most impacted by the pandemic, and create supportive learning environments. ED will continue to help states and school districts use the $122 billion in ARP ESSER funds for this purpose. Specifically, the Department will help states and districts use the funds to provide more individual and small group instruction, hire instructional and other critical staff, launch high-impact tutoring programs, provide high-quality afterschool and summer learning and enrichment programs, and invest in other evidence-based strategies that will help our students recover from the pandemic. Districts nationwide are already using ARP ESSER funds to invest in these strategies. To support this work, we need more caring adults taking on roles supporting students. The President is calling on Americans nationwide to take on roles as tutors and mentors to help our students recover. Those looking to return to the workforce, who are just out of school, or changing careers, should consider the rich, rewarding job opportunities in our schools and with our young people. The investments the President will propose in his FY23 budget will support and sustain efforts that set up students for success. This includes more than doubling funding for Title I, a ten-fold increase for the Full-Service Community School program, and an historic $3.3 billion increase for Individuals with Disabilities Education Act grants that support PK-12 children with disabilities and $450 million for IDEA PART C, which supports early intervention services for infants and toddlers.<br></li><li><strong>Increase mental health resources for justice-involved populations</strong>. In too many communities, jails and other correctional facilities have become the <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/health-shots/2018/04/25/605666107/insane-americas-3-largest-psychiatric-facilities-are-jails">largest</a> provider of mental health care. Approximately <a href="https://www.prisonpolicy.org/research/mental_health/">40 percent</a> of incarcerated individuals have a mental illness, yet merely <a href="https://bjs.ojp.gov/content/pub/pdf/imhprpji1112.pdf">one-third</a> receive treatment. The President believes that we have both a moral and a public health obligation to increase access to comprehensive mental health care for the justice-involved. To this end, the Department of Justice will expand funding and technical assistance to local communities and corrections systems to provide behavioral health care, case management services, family services, and other transitional programming for adults returning from incarceration into the community. <br></li><li><strong>Train social and human services professionals in basic mental health skills. </strong>It’s not enough to train health care providers to deliver mental health care; social and human services providers must also be equipped to identify, understand, and respond to signs of mental illness and addiction among those they serve. To this end, the Department of Housing and Urban Development will launch a national effort to train housing counselors, housing-based services coordinators, and Fair Housing grantee staff to recognize the signs of emotional distress and to connect residents with mental health resources. The U.S. Department of Agriculture will provide training on mental health resources and communication strategies to Farm Production and Conservation Mission Area field employees, who serve farmers and ranchers, as well as incorporate updated mental health information into its online resource center for State, local and clinic staff administering the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC). ED will continue to highlight the effectiveness of Mental Health First Aid training for educators, so that they can better support their students and one another. And the Department of Health &amp; Human Services will provide additional training support to Head Start, Early Head Start, and home visiting grantees to spot and address mental health challenges among children.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Women’s Health Protection&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-womens-health-protection-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48057</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At a time when women’s access to reproductive health care is under increased assault in states across the country,&#160;it is extremely disappointing that&#160;Senate Republicans&#160;blocked passage of&#160;the Women’s Health Protection Act,&#160;which&#160;would strengthen health care access and codify constitutional rights affirmed half a century ago by&#160;Roe v. Wade&#160;and in subsequent Supreme Court precedent. Today, we mark six&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>At a time when women’s access to reproductive health care is under increased assault in states across the country,&nbsp;it is extremely disappointing that&nbsp;Senate Republicans&nbsp;blocked passage of&nbsp;the Women’s Health Protection Act,&nbsp;which&nbsp;would strengthen health care access and codify constitutional rights affirmed half a century ago by&nbsp;<em>Roe v. Wade</em>&nbsp;and in subsequent Supreme Court precedent.</p>



<p>Today, we mark six months since Texas law SB8 went into effect,&nbsp;brazenly&nbsp;violating Texans’ constitutional rights and empowering private citizens to act as&nbsp;bounty hunters against&nbsp;their neighbors.&nbsp;Now, a number of other states&nbsp;are also&nbsp;considering&nbsp;passing laws&nbsp;in open defiance of the U.S. Constitution,&nbsp;threatening&nbsp;the&nbsp;reproductive freedom&nbsp;of all&nbsp;Americans.&nbsp;These restrictions&nbsp;are particularly devastating for&nbsp;communities of color,&nbsp;rural Americans, and all those faced with&nbsp;fewer options and fewer resources.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As dangerous new laws proliferate in states across the country, the Biden-Harris Administration will continue to explore the measures and tools at our disposal to stand up for women’s equality. This is a moment for us to recommit to strengthening access to women’s health care, defend the constitutional right affirmed by <em>Roe</em>, and protect the freedom of all people to build their own future. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter from President&#160;Biden to the Dedicated Members of the Federal&#160;Workforce</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/01/letter-from-president-biden-to-the-dedicated-members-of-the-federal-workforce/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To the Dedicated Members of the Federal Workforce: Tonight, I will deliver my State of the Union address to the Congress and the American people. Before I do, I want to thank each of you for your dedication in service to our Nation. Thanks to your tireless work this past year, America is on the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>To the Dedicated Members of the Federal Workforce:</p>



<p>Tonight, I will deliver my State of the Union address to the Congress and the American people. Before I do, I want to thank each of you for your dedication in service to our Nation.</p>



<p>Thanks to your tireless work this past year, America is on the move again. Together, we have made significant progress confronting the pandemic, fueling our economy’s historic recovery, tackling the climate crisis, advancing racial equity, and protecting our national security. While our work is not finished, and deep challenges remain, this progress would not have been possible without you.</p>



<p>The strength of any organization rests in its people. Your capabilities and dedication are what make the Federal Government strong and ensure we deliver the basic needs for everyday Americans. As we look to the year ahead, we must build on the innovations and technologies that we put to work serving the American people throughout the pandemic, making our government more efficient, resilient, and effective. And because of our progress combatting the pandemic, we can safely increase in-person work, while continuing to protect your health and safety. Together, we can lead by example and show our country a way forward—not only by what we do, but by how we do it.</p>



<p>Thank you for your service and sacrifices, and that of your family. Your talents could have taken you many places, but you chose to serve our country. I am forever grateful, and with your continued dedication and leadership, I have never been more optimistic for the future of America.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">Joe Biden</p>



<p>To view a signed copy of President Biden&#8217;s letter, visit: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Letter-from-President-Biden-to-the-Dedicated-Members-of-the-Federal-Workforce_20220301.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Letter-from-President-Biden-to-the-Dedicated-Members-of-the-Federal-Workforce_20220301.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
