<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 14:58:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden on Unemployment Insurance&#160;Claims</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-unemployment-insurance-claims-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49642</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Americans are getting back to work at a historic pace, with fewer Americans on unemployment insurance today than at any time in the last half century. This morning, we received news that the number of Americans on unemployment insurance fell to its lowest level since 1970 and the number of Americans filing new claims fell&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Americans are getting back to work at a historic pace, with fewer Americans on unemployment insurance today than at any time in the last half century. This morning, we received news that the number of Americans on unemployment insurance fell to its lowest level since 1970 and the number of Americans filing new claims fell to its lowest one-week level since 1969. This historic progress is no accident: it’s the result of an economic strategy to grow the economy from the bottom up and middle out, starting with the American Rescue Plan. And, it’s the result of effective management of emergency pandemic resources that resulted in 75% of adult Americans vaccinated and 99% of schools re-opened.  We have more work to do to cut costs for families, but today’s data are a reminder that the U.S. economy is uniquely well positioned to deal with the global challenge of inflation. We will continue the fight to lower costs with every tool at our disposal, from making more here in America and rebuilding our supply chains, to lowering costs that have held back Americans for decades, to promoting competition to ensure markets can operate effectively and consumers are protected.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President&#160;Biden on the Extraordinary NATO&#160;Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/statement-from-president-biden-on-the-extraordinary-nato-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49637</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NATO leaders met today on the one-month anniversary of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine to reiterate our strong support for the Ukrainian people, our determination to hold Russia accountable for its brutal war, and our commitment to strengthening the NATO Alliance. We had the privilege of hearing directly from President Zelenskyy, and we&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NATO leaders met today on the one-month anniversary of Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine to reiterate our strong support for the Ukrainian people, our determination to hold Russia accountable for its brutal war, and our commitment to strengthening the NATO Alliance. We had the privilege of hearing directly from President Zelenskyy, and we will continue to support him and his government with significant, and increasing, amounts of security assistance to fight Russian aggression and uphold their right to self-defense.</p>



<p>In the past few weeks, the United States has announced $1 billion in new security assistance to Ukraine — anti-aircraft systems, anti-armor weapons, drones, and millions of rounds of ammunition. I welcome the steps by many other Allies to provide defensive support to Ukraine and together, we are committed to identifying additional equipment, including air defense systems, to help Ukraine.</p>



<p>We also discussed our work to bolster NATO’s collective defense, particularly on the Eastern flank. Our joint statement today makes clear that NATO is as strong and united as it has ever been. Immediately after Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, we activated NATO’s defensive plans and the NATO Response Force. The United States has surged thousands of forces and additional capabilities to Europe, and we have welcomed the new deployments made by our Allies. Today’s establishment of four new battle groups in Slovakia, Romania, Bulgaria, and Hungary is a strong signal that we will collectively defend and protect every inch of NATO territory. Between now and the NATO summit in June, we will develop plans for additional forces and capabilities to strengthen NATO’s defenses. We will adopt an updated Strategic Concept to ensure NATO is ready to meet any challenge in the new and more dangerous security environment.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Meetings at&#160;NATO</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/24/background-press-call-on-president-bidens-meetings-at-nato/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49631</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Via Teleconference 11:53 A.M. CET MODERATOR:&#160; Well, good morning, everyone.&#160; And thank you for joining the White House background call on the President&#8217;s trip to Europe.&#160; As a reminder of the ground rules, this call will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” For your awareness but not for your reporting, the three officials&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"> Via Teleconference</p>



<p>11:53 A.M. CET</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Well, good morning, everyone.&nbsp; And thank you for joining the White House background call on the President&#8217;s trip to Europe.&nbsp; As a reminder of the ground rules, this call will be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”</p>



<p>For your awareness but not for your reporting, the three officials joining us on our call today are [senior administration officials].&nbsp;</p>



<p>We will have two sections of the call today.&nbsp; The first will be a recap of the President&#8217;s time at NATO, which will be embargoed until the call concludes.&nbsp; The second section, which previews the G7 and EU meetings, will be embargoed until this afternoon at 2:15 p.m. Central European Time, or 9:15 a.m. Eastern Time.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to our first speaker, [senior administration official], for the first section of the call.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; And good morning, almost good afternoon, to everyone.&nbsp; I just stepped out of the listening room where I have been for the last hour or so, and I&#8217;m happy to share a little bit of color from what&#8217;s been happening in the meeting.</p>



<p>So, Secretary General Stoltenberg opened the meeting.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sure all of you saw his open remarks, which were open to press. Then the leaders went into a closed session.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As I think everyone is tracking, President Zelenskyy was beamed in via video link from Ukraine to address the group.&nbsp; He spoke very eloquently, as he has to a number of national parliaments in recent weeks, with a message very much focused on the efforts of the Ukrainian military and people to defend their country, to defend their citizens, and also to defend our shared democratic values.</p>



<p>He repeated his requests for continued and increased Western security assistance.&nbsp; But notably, there was not a request for a no-fly zone.&nbsp; There was also not a request for NATO membership in his remarks.</p>



<p>Following his intervention, he departed on the video link, and the members moved into a closed session among the Alliance.</p>



<p>After him, the President was the first speaker.&nbsp; He set out the three-pronged approach that we have taken throughout this this crisis, noting that today marks the one-month anniversary of the launch of Russian military aggression against Ukraine.</p>



<p>First, he talked about everything that we have done to impose costs on Russia, including the very significant package of sanctions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, he reiterated our strong support for Ukraine, both in terms of security assistance &#8212; increased and continued security assistance, as well as humanitarian assistance that we were continuing to provide to those both in Ukraine and to those fleeing the violence.</p>



<p>And third, a very strong message of support for NATO &#8212; reaffirming the U.S. commitment to Article 5 and the steps that the United States, in partnership with other Allies, had taken in recent weeks to reinforce the security of the eastern flank.<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of that, speaking more generally: In terms of the Alliance, he talked about force posture adjustments, as I mentioned.&nbsp; He welcomed the similar moves that we have seen from a number of countries to strengthen NATO&#8217;s eastern flank.&nbsp; He welcomed the increased defense spending pledges that we have seen from a number of countries, as well as the ongoing robust exercises that are continuing.</p>



<p>Finally, he looked ahead to the Madrid summit, which will be in about two and a half months in late June, and laid out a number of issues that the Alliance is going to have to grapple with in advance of that summit, given the changed security context that we see ourselves in and as the Alliance is finalizing the strategic concept that will be addressing a number of these changes in security architecture.</p>



<p>By the time I left the room, I think about six leaders had spoken.&nbsp; So, just to give you a sense of the mood: First, there was a very strong sense that we are facing a significant, historical moment, and very strong support from all of the leaders who spoke about the need to defend our democracy, the need to defend our shared values, and a strong sense that NATO was appropriately poised to be able to do that.</p>



<p>Second and relatedly, there was a very strong message of unity &#8212; notes of how united the NATO Alliance was, notes of unity across the transatlantic alliance; very strong support for NATO, for its Article 5 commitments; a number of leaders speaking about increases in their own defense spending; and also notes about changes that various countries have made in terms of force posture, particularly with what we&#8217;ve seen in the last couple of weeks with a significant movement of NATO forces to NATO&#8217;s eastern flank to defend the security of Allies there.</p>



<p>Third, very strong admiration for the Ukrainian military and the Ukrainian people in terms of everything they are doing to defend their country from Russian aggression.</p>



<p>There was also very strong pledges of support from across the Allies that I heard speak about their readiness to continue, as well as increase, their security assistance to Ukraine.</p>



<p>Related to that, many of the leaders also spoke about the importance of economic sanctions and the need for us to continue imposing robust economic costs on Russia in response to its aggression.</p>



<p>Related to that: On the Ukrainian people, very strong support for refugees; a lot of appreciation to the eastern flank Allies that have been bearing the brunt of the crisis; and continued pledges by Allies to continue contributing financially to the humanitarian assistance, as well as, of course, a number of these countries taking in refugees themselves.</p>



<p>And just a final note: There was also a reference by many of the speakers to China and a recognition that China needs to live up to its responsibilities within the international community as a U.N. Security Council member, that we need to continue to call on China not to support Russia in its aggression against Ukraine, and that we need China to call for a peaceful end to the conflict as a responsible member of the international community.</p>



<p>So the mood overall has been sober, it&#8217;s been resolute, and it&#8217;s been incredibly united.&nbsp;<br>So let me stop there with my opening comments.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; With that, we&#8217;ll open it up to a couple of questions on the NATO portion before we move on to the second portion of the call, which will be EU and G7 specific.</p>



<p>If I can ask everyone who has a question to please indicate you have one using the “raise hand” feature.</p>



<p>Josh Wingrove from Bloomberg.&nbsp; I saw your hand up first.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Hello from the travel pool.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Can you give me a sense of what President Zelenskyy did ask for if he didn’t mention NATO membership and didn’t mention the closure?&nbsp;<br>And also, NBC is reporting that 100,000 refugees &#8212; the U.S. will announce a pledge to take in 100,000 refugees.&nbsp; Is there anything you can tell us on that in particular that we could publish before any later embargo?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you for that.</p>



<p>So, on your question about refugees, I don’t want to steal any thunder from my colleague, so let me defer that to the later part of the call where [senior administration official] is going to have more information specifically on some of our refugees and humanitarian assistance.</p>



<p>In terms of President Zelenskyy’s comments, I will let the Ukrainian government speak for themselves in terms of what specifically Zelenskyy conveyed to leaders in what was a closed, private session to leaders.</p>



<p>What I can say is that President Biden was very clear in his remarks about the security assistance that the U.S. has continued to provide, underscoring the $2 billion that we have provided over the last year, underscoring the billion dollars in new security assistance to Ukraine that we have just announced; talked in some specifics, as he has done previously, about the additional types of assistance that we have been providing to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>And then, just more broadly, I would say that we have started consulting with Allies on providing anti-ship missiles to Ukraine.&nbsp; There may be some technical challenges with making that happen, but that is something that we are consulting with Allies and starting to work on.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next, we go to Kevin Liptak with CNN.</p>



<p>Q &nbsp;Hi. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;Yesterday, Jake said that discussion of Russia’s potential use of chemical or biological or nuclear weapons would come up in all these discussions. &nbsp;I wonder if you could say whether that came up at NATO today and what the leaders &#8212; what was &#8212; if there was a consensus among the leaders about whether NATO would be obliged to respond to the use of those kinds of weapons should that take place.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, there were some references to that.&nbsp; I think there is a recognition that NATO needs to continue a lot of the good, ongoing work to be prepared to respond to various contingencies.&nbsp; It&#8217;s something that NATO, as a military alliance, is already postured to do, and it&#8217;s something that they recognize that they need to continue to do given the various scenarios that could emerge as part of this conflict.<br>&nbsp;<br>The United States is already taking steps both nationally, as well as through NATO, to enhance the readiness and capability of our defense forces to respond to chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear incidents.&nbsp; Frankly, for NATO, this is an important part of strengthening our longer-term defense and deterrence postures.<br>&nbsp;<br>NATO has a Combined Joint CBRN Defence Task Force, which is an element of the NATO Response Force, which is prepared to deploy at SACEUR’s direction.&nbsp; This includes specially trained and equipped forces who are able to deal with these types of incidents if there are attacks against NATO populations, territory, or forces.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And NATO Allies are also continuing to consult, as well as to take national decisions, to be able to provide on a bilateral basis protective equipment and medical countermeasures to help Ukraine detect, identify, and respond to these types of threats.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, in sum, yes, it was a subject that came up in discussion today and I assume is a continuing part of the ongoing discussion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second, there are broader conversations within NATO about how to respond to these types of incidents.<br>&nbsp;<br>And third, some NATO Allies are already taking national decisions to be able to respond to, potentially, Ukrainian needs on these threats as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And then we&#8217;ll do one more question from Chris Megerian with AP.&nbsp; After that, we&#8217;ll move on to the second portion.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; I wanted to see if you could talk any more about force posture adjustments.&nbsp; What specifically are we speaking about?<br>&nbsp;<br>And then on China, when you said that China needs to do more, what specifically do you want to see them do more or see them stop doing?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks for that.&nbsp; So, in terms of force posture, there was considerable discussion by leaders about the number of changes that have already been made across the Alliance.&nbsp; I think what we&#8217;ve seen within the last couple of weeks with NATO Allies acting with great unity and speed to deploy additional defensive forces and capabilities in response to renewed Russian aggression against Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>NATO activated its response plans.&nbsp; It deployed the NATO Response Force.&nbsp; It increased NATO&#8217;s readiness.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s now approximately 40,000 Allied forces under direct NATO command with particular emphasis on the eastern flank.<br>&nbsp;<br>As part of that, the United States has already deployed thousands of additional forces to Europe.&nbsp; There&#8217;s now approximately 100,000 U.S. forces on land, in the air, at sea, training, exercising, and ready to defer &#8212; or to deter and defend against any threat.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, in the parts of the meeting that I was in, there was a lot of recognition about the steps that the U.S. has taken and, frankly, that a large number of other Allies have taken to move their forces to the eastern flank as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>And in terms of China, I would refer to what I had said earlier in terms of similar messages that Stoltenberg himself actually has given within the last couple of days as well: that there is a desire for China to live up to its responsibilities within the international community, clearly a strong desire for Russia [China] not to provide economic or military assistance to Russia in furtherance of its aggression against Ukraine, and for China to join with other responsible members of the international community in calling on Russia to end its violence.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And with that, that concludes the first portion of the call, which, as a reminder, is embargoed until this call concludes.<br>&nbsp;<br>12:08 P.M. CET</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Biden Administration Announces New Humanitarian, Development, and Democracy Assistance to Ukraine and the Surrounding&#160;Region</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/fact-sheet-the-biden-administration-announces-new-humanitarian-development-and-democracy-assistance-to-ukraine-and-the-surrounding-region/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is proud to be the largest single donor of humanitarian, democracy, and human rights assistance to Ukraine, working closely with our European partners. We remain committed to ensuring those affected by President Putin’s war of aggression, especially vulnerable populations such as women, children, lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and intersex (LGBTQI+) persons, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States is proud to be the largest single donor of humanitarian, democracy, and human rights assistance to Ukraine, working closely with our European partners. We remain committed to ensuring those affected by President Putin’s war of aggression, especially vulnerable populations such as women, children, lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender and intersex (LGBTQI+) persons, and persons with disabilities, are able to access food, clean water, shelter, and medical care. In addition to assisting people in need within Ukraine, we are supporting the efforts of Ukraine’s neighbors and the European Union to welcome and host millions of refugees. And we will do our part to welcome Ukrainians to the United States.<br>&nbsp;<br><strong>Today, the United States is announcing that we are prepared to provide&nbsp;more than $1 billion in new funding towards humanitarian assistance for those affected by Russia’s war in Ukraine and its severe impacts around the world, including a marked rise in food insecurity,&nbsp;over the coming months. This funding will provide food, shelter, clean water, medical supplies and other forms of assistance. We are also announcing an additional $320 million in democracy and human rights funding to Ukraine and its neighbors.</strong> Since 2021, the United States has provided over&nbsp;$1.1 billion in economic, health, democracy and human rights, and humanitarian assistance to the Europe and Eurasia region.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to our humanitarian assistance, the United States continues to support public health initiatives in Ukraine and the region to tamp down the spread of communicable diseases like polio, tuberculosis, and COVID, and to help ensure patients continue to have access to medical care. And we remain committed to defending and strengthening democratic governance, human rights, and the fight against corruption in Ukraine and its neighbors, as together we reject autocracy and aggression.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Providing refuge to Displaced Ukrainians.</strong> While we expect many Ukrainians will choose to remain in Europe close to family and their homes in Ukraine, today, the United States is announcing plans to welcome up to 100,000 Ukrainians and others fleeing Russia’s aggression through the full range of legal pathways, including the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.&nbsp;In particular, we are working to expand and develop new programs with a focus on welcoming Ukrainians who have family members in the United States.&nbsp;The United States and the European Union are also coordinating closely to ensure that these efforts, and other forms of humanitarian admission or transfers, are complementary and provide much-needed support to Ukraine’s neighbors.<br></li><li><strong>Supporting humanitarian assistance in Ukraine.</strong> Today, the Biden Administration is announcing that we are prepared to provide more than $1 billion in new funding towards humanitarian assistance to support people within Ukraine and assist those affected by the global impacts of Russia’s war.&nbsp;This support builds on the 25-person humanitarian response team the United States has deployed to the region to assess needs, provide assistance, and coordinate closely with the United Nations, NGOs, and the Government of Ukraine, including the State Emergency Services of Ukraine.&nbsp;With the support of the United States and Allies and partners, the World Food Programme is working to reach 3.1 million people in Ukraine with ready-to-eat rations, canned goods, bread, wheat, flour, and oil.&nbsp;U.S.-funded humanitarian organizations in Ukraine are operating mobile medical teams and delivering emergency health supplies and medicine to public health care centers, enabling continued primary health services, trauma care, and vaccinations.&nbsp;In collective shelters in places like Mariupol or Lviv, humanitarian organizations are distributing blankets, water containers, and hygiene kits containing soap, toothpaste, diapers, and toilet paper to help thousands of internally displaced persons and mitigate the spread of disease.&nbsp;Mobile teams are also providing psychological support, ensuring especially vulnerable populations have access to services and are protected from risks, including gender-based violence, child-trafficking, and landmines.<br></li><li><strong>Helping those who have fled in the region.</strong>&nbsp;Since February 24, the United States has already provided more than $123 million to complement the work of neighboring countries and the European Union to receive and host millions of refugees, including $48 million in Poland, $30 million in Moldova, $10 million in Romania, $9 million in Hungary, and $4 million in the Slovak Republic.&nbsp;U.S.-funded humanitarian organizations are working in partnership with host governments to launch cash programs that provide refugees with temporary assistance for food, accommodations, and medical care until they can work or receive social support.&nbsp;In addition to counselling, legal aid, and mental health and psychological support, U.S. partners are providing health support for refugees including infection prevention and control, and sexual and reproductive health assistance, as well as providing safe drinking water, strengthening sanitation infrastructure, and providing refugees with basic household items and shelter materials.&nbsp;The U.S. has deployed refugee coordinators to the region to work with the governments of neighboring countries, the UN, and other humanitarian organizations, and donors. Additionally, the U.S. has allocated $5.5 million to facilitate the safe and orderly return of up to 20,000 third-country nationals to return home from Ukraine.<br></li><li><strong>Bolstering democracy and human rights in Ukraine and neighboring states. </strong>In line with President Biden’s commitment to support democracy and human rights globally, the United States is launching the European Democratic Resilience Initiative (EDRI), which is intended to provide at least $320 million in new funding to support societal resilience and defend human rights in Ukraine and neighboring countries. The EDRI is expected to support media freedom and counter disinformation, increase the safety and security of activists and vulnerable groups including LGBTQI+ persons,&nbsp;build resilience to strategic corruption and kleptocracy, strengthen democratic and anti-corruption institutions and the region’s rule of law, and support accountability for human rights abuses and violations of international law.&nbsp;Implementation of the EDRI will be closely coordinated with the European Union and other partners.<br></li><li><strong>Advancing accountability for Russian war crimes in Ukraine. </strong>An important component of EDRI will be support for efforts to document and preserve evidence of potential war crimes being committed in Ukraine. The United States is already supporting several such initiatives. New lines of effort, including the establishment of a conflict observatory, will gather information that can be shared with a range of accountability efforts at the national and international level designed to hold Russia accountable for its actions.<br></li><li><strong>Protecting children and other vulnerable populations.</strong> Russia’s unprovoked further invasion of Ukraine poses an immediate and growing threat to the lives and well-being of the country’s 7.5 million children who face attacks on schools, injuries from mines and explosives, and child trafficking.&nbsp;In response, in both Ukraine and surrounding countries, the United States has been supporting Children and Family Protection Support Hubs where professional case workers, mental health professionals, and legal aid providers are available to assist children, female heads of household, those with disabilities, older persons and other vulnerable populations.&nbsp;These centers offer safe spaces for psychosocial support, hygiene, health and nutrition; provide family tracing for unaccompanied children; as well as protection from sexual exploitation and abuse.&nbsp;With support to nine different organizations, the United States is also supporting 55 mobile protection teams to prevent family separation, mitigate gender-based violence, communicate the risks of mines and war remnants, and address the psychological effects of war.<br></li><li><strong>Strengthening public health.</strong> Since February 24, the U.S. government has rapidly accelerated support to the Ukrainian health system and systems in the region, on top of previously funded programs.&nbsp;Inside Ukraine, U.S. government partners are providing critical medical commodities, expanded immunization support to areas experiencing an influx of internally displaced persons, and supporting continuity of tuberculosis and HIV/AIDS treatment services to ensure patients do not lose access to lifesaving treatments – including through procuring $6.1 million worth of antiretroviral drugs, re-purposing of mobile HIV testing vans, and expanded support to patients and home delivery of medicines. The U.S. government is also supporting the Ministry of Health and World Health Organization with technical assistance on issues such as immunization, outbreak response, blood safety, and overall emergency response coordination. The U.S. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention is also supporting the Ministry of Health to consolidate medicine needs from over 5,000 public, private, and academic institutions in order to guide and prioritize humanitarian assistance efforts, while helping the Ministry of Health to shift and expand warehousing and medicines delivery capacity.&nbsp;The U.S. government is also working with the Public Health Center of Ukraine to roster all CDC-trained graduates of the Field Epidemiology Training Program (FETP) in-country and support relocation of critical public health equipment and personnel within Ukraine, to mitigate the impacts of the Russian invasion on public health infrastructure.&nbsp;These teams are augmenting the humanitarian response by monitoring the health conditions of the Ukraine population, including refugees and internally displaced persons with focus on COVID-19, HIV, TB, measles, polio, mental health, non-communicable diseases, and maternal and child health.<br></li><li><strong>Defending global food security.</strong> Russia’s war of aggression threatens to disrupt the supply of critical agricultural commodities from the Black Sea region, jeopardizing global food security, particularly for vulnerable populations in the Middle East and Africa.&nbsp;The United States, through the Feed the Future initiative and our nutrition commitments, will be providing over $11 billion over the next five years to address food security threats and malnutrition across the globe &#8211; with programming in many of the countries vulnerable to increases in food and fertilizer prices. Ongoing activities within the initiative that help buffer food systems against macroeconomic shocks like the Russian invasion of Ukraine include: increasing the productivity of smallholder farmers, including women, through access to improved agricultural technologies and inputs, financing, and markets; strengthening agricultural market systems by building a vibrant local private sector; and improving people’s access to higher quality diets and safer food for improved nutrition. Additionally, the United States will remain one of the top providers of humanitarian food and nutrition assistance globally, having contributed approximately $4.6 billion in humanitarian food and nutrition assistance in 2021.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States and Allies and Partners Impose Additional Costs on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/fact-sheet-united-states-and-allies-and-partners-impose-additional-costs-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49597</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[United States sanctions over 400 Russian elites, Duma members, and defense companies in coordination with the European Union and G7; U.S. has now sanctioned over 600 targets&#160;G7 and EU announce sanctions evasion initiative to prevent circumvention and backfilling of our unprecedented sanctions; continue to blunt Central Bank of the Russian Federation’s ability to deploy international&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><em>United States sanctions over 400 Russian elites, Duma members, and defense companies in coordination with the European Union and G7; U.S. has now sanctioned over 600 targets</em></strong><br>&nbsp;<br><strong><em>G7 and EU announce sanctions evasion initiative to prevent circumvention and backfilling of our unprecedented sanctions; continue to blunt Central Bank of the Russian Federation’s ability to deploy international reserves including gold</em></strong></p>



<p>President Biden is in Europe to continue our historic coordination with allies and partners on all aspects of our response to Russia’s war against Ukraine, including imposing further severe costs on those enabling President Putin’s war of choice. Today, the United States is sanctioning over 400 individuals and entities comprised of Russian elites, the Duma and more than 300 of its members, and defense companies, aligning and strengthening our sanctions in close coordination and partnership with the EU and G7.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our sanctions on Russia are unprecedented — in no other circumstance have we moved so swiftly and in such a coordinated fashion to impose devastating costs on any other country. The ruble has depreciated substantially, and is expected by markets to weaken further. The Moscow Stock Exchange closed for weeks. The Central Bank of the Russian Federation has doubled interest rates to 20 percent and companies are being forced to turn over foreign exchange for rubles to provide the Russian Government hard currency. The economy is forecast to contract as much as 15 percent or more in 2022. This economic collapse of Russia’s GDP will wipe out the past 15 years of economic gains in Russia, according to the Institute for International Finance. Inflation in Russia is already spiking, with analysts projecting it to rise up to 15 percent on a year-over-year basis, and the Russian Government has been downgraded to “junk” status by major credit rating agencies. More than 400 multinational companies have left Russia in a mass exodus by the private sector.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As long as President Putin continues this war, the United States and allies and partners are committed to ensuring the Russian government feels the compounding effects of our current and future economic actions.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Today’s actions include:&nbsp;<br><br><strong>Full blocking sanctions on more than 400 individuals and entities, including the Duma and its members, additional Russian elites, and Russian defense companies that fuel Putin’s war machine.</strong>&nbsp;This includes:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>328 Duma members and sanctioning the Duma as an entity.</li><li>Herman Gref,&nbsp;the head of Russia’s largest financial institution Sberbank and a Putin advisor since the 1990s.&nbsp;</li><li>Russian elite Gennady Timchenko, his companies and his family members.</li><li>17 board members of Russian financial institution Sovcombank.</li><li>48 Large Russian defense state-owned enterprises that are part of Russia’s defense-industrial base and produce weapons that have been used in Russia’s assault against Ukraine’s people, infrastructure, and territory, including Russian Helicopters, Tactical Missiles Corporation, High Precision Systems, NPK Tekhmash OAO, Kronshtadt. We are targeting, and will continue to target, the suppliers of Russia’s war effort and, in turn, their supply chain.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Establishment of an initiative focused on sanctions evasions. </strong>G7 leaders and the European Union today announced an initiative to share information about and coordinate responses related to evasive measures intended to undercut the effectiveness and impact of our joint sanctions actions. Together, we will not allow sanctions evasion or backfilling. As part of this effort, we will also engage other governments on adopting sanctions similar to those already imposed by the G7 and other partners. <br> <br><strong>Continuing to blunt the Central Bank’s ability to deploy international reserves, including gold, to prop up the Russian economy and fund Putin’s brutal war. </strong>G7 leaders and the European Union will continue to work jointly to blunt Russia’s ability to deploy its international reserves to prop up Russia’s economy and fund Putin’s war, including by making clear that any transaction involving gold related to the Central Bank of the Russian Federation is covered by existing sanctions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with NATO Secretary General Jens&#160;Stoltenberg</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-nato-secretary-general-jens-stoltenberg-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 11:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) ahead of the extraordinary NATO Summit to address Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. They discussed the unity and strength of the alliance and NATO’s ongoing efforts to deter and defend against any aggression, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) ahead of the extraordinary NATO Summit to address Russia’s unprovoked and unjustified invasion of Ukraine. They discussed the unity and strength of the alliance and NATO’s ongoing efforts to deter and defend against any aggression, and they welcomed the support of Allies for the government and people of Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: Biden-&#8288;Harris Administration Releases Report on Native American Voting&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-releases-report-on-native-american-voting-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Vice President Harris Announces Additional Steps in Response to the to the President’s Executive Order to Promote Access to Voting&#160; Since their first days in office, President Biden and Vice President Harris have prioritized strengthening our democracy and taken steps to protect voters from the current efforts to suppress the vote and subvert our electoral&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Vice President Harris Announces Additional Steps in Response to the to the President’s Executive Order to Promote Access to Voting&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Since their first days in office, President Biden and Vice President Harris have prioritized strengthening our democracy and taken steps to protect voters from the current efforts to suppress the vote and subvert our electoral process.&nbsp;&nbsp;The unprecedented nature and scale of the present attacks on voting rights must be met with federal legislation, which is why the President and Vice President have repeatedly called for the Senate to pass the Freedom to Vote Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act. The President and Vice President have also forcefully called for changing Senate rules to prevent a minority of Senators from blocking action on this fundamental right from which all other rights flow.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Congress still has the responsibility to act, but the President is committed to using every tool at his disposal to protect the sacred right to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;On March 7, 2021, the 56th anniversary of Bloody Sunday, he signed an Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting, directing an all-of-government effort to promote information about the voting process and to further the ability of all eligible Americans to participate in our democracy.&nbsp;&nbsp;That work is ongoing, and agencies will continue to develop ways to deliver non-partisan election information and enable eligible Americans to register and to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>A key provision of the Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting highlighted the unique trust responsibility that the Federal government has for Tribal Nations and Native communities.&nbsp;&nbsp;In light of this responsibility, President Biden directed the creation of an Interagency Steering Group on Native American Voting Rights, whose mission is to study the barriers Native voters face in casting their ballot and having those votes counted, and to recommend steps to mitigate or eliminate these barriers.&nbsp;&nbsp;For far too long, members of Tribal Nations and Native communities have faced unnecessary burdens when they attempt to exercise their sacred right to vote.&nbsp;&nbsp;Native voters often have to overcome language barriers, a lack of accessibility for voters with disabilities, cultural disrespect and outright hostility, geographically remote residences, and persistent poverty — conditions that have only been exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp;&nbsp;State laws and local practices also present too many Native voters with undue impediments to full and fair exercise of the franchise, including barriers in receiving information about the voting process, discriminatory redistricting, and burdens in voter registration, voter identification, voting in person, and voting by mail.</p>



<p>The Steering Group held consultations with Tribal leaders and Native Americans across the country, and engaged in listening sessions with Native Hawaiians, organizations advocating for improved Tribal voting rights, and state and local election officials in jurisdictions with sizable Native populations.  These sessions revealed recurring, unnecessary, and unacceptable impediments to the franchise. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Tribal-Voting-Report-FINAL.pdf">The report released today </a>chronicles the barriers Native voters face and recommends actions for policymakers at every level to help break these barriers down.  To live up to the recommendations of the report, the Department of the Interior is taking the unique step of translating it into six Native languages that reflect the regional consultation structure: Navajo, Yup&#8217;ik, Ojibwe, Cherokee, Lakota, and Native Hawaiian.  The translations will be available in writing and by audio.  </p>



<p>A few key recommendations from the report include:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>Congress should pass the Freedom to Vote Act and the John Lewis Voting Rights Advancement Act, which includes the Native American Voting Rights Act.&nbsp;&nbsp;States do not need to wait for Congress to take this action— they can and should pass legislation incorporating and building upon the protections in the Native American Voting Rights Act, as several states since 2017 have already done.</li><li>Federal, state, and local policymakers should institutionalize engagement of Tribal leaders and Native communities, including in ensuring that county and municipal election officials locate offices and polling places serving Native communities for convenience to Native voters, and staff those sites with well-trained, bilingual members of those communities.</li><li>The U.S. Postal Service should evaluate whether it can add routes, offices, and staff hours or personnel in areas serving Native communities, and should prioritize assigning postal addresses to homes on Tribal lands.</li><li>Government offices with significant presence serving Native communities should expeditiously offer their programs for state designation under the National Voter Registration Act, and state officials should accept those requests for designation.</li><li>Jurisdictions serving Native voters should ensure that they offer effective language assistance through adequate translation of materials in appropriate media, even when no statutory mandate compels them to do so.</li></ul>



<p>This important report is the product of an extensive effort across the Administration — and it is also just a beginning.&nbsp;&nbsp;There will be more to come in the weeks and months ahead, as agencies work with partners and allies to implement the report’s recommendations.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Agencies have also been working to implement other provisions of the President’s Executive Order on Promoting Access to Voting, offering nonpartisan information and opportunities to help eligible Americans participate.&nbsp;&nbsp;Those efforts will continue across the whole of government, with new actions rolling out as they are ready for release.&nbsp;&nbsp;A selection of recent developments from individual agencies follows:&nbsp;</p>



<ul><li>The <strong>U.S.</strong> <strong>Small Business Administration</strong> formally requested designation by Michigan as a voter registration agency under the National Voter Registration Act, becoming the first federal agency to request designation in any state.  Designation would ensure that Americans seeking service from a designated District Office are offered convenient one-stop opportunities to register to vote at the same time.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Veterans Affairs </strong>launched a survey to over 12 million Veterans in a first-of-its-kind effort to better understand Veterans’ experience with the voter registration process, and to better assist Veterans in addressing and overcoming any challenges.  The Department also developed a website for Veterans with nonpartisan information about voter registration and elections at va.gov/vote: <a href="https://www.va.gov/initiatives/vote/?msclkid=4ee33ffaa97111ecaf6453e6663908f9">How Veterans Can Register To Vote | Veterans Affairs (va.gov)</a>.  And the Department announced that, by summer, it would launch a pilot program for VA Medical Centers and other offices in six states, with an eye to the geographic and demographic diversity of the Veteran population, seeking designation as a voter registration agency under the National Voter Registration Act.</li><li>The <strong>Department of the Interior</strong> announced that it is working with states to formally designate the Department-operated post-secondary Tribal institutions — Haskell Indian Nations University in Kansas and the Southwestern Indian Polytechnic Institute (SIPI) in New Mexico — as voter registration agencies under the National Voter Registration Act, facilitating voter registration opportunities for enrolled students and members of the community.  </li><li>With <strong>Treasury Department</strong> and IRS support, Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) sites throughout the country are assisting taxpayers with access to voting opportunities.  The VITA centers provide assistance to low-income taxpayers with their returns.  This year, over 450 VITA centers in 40 states have reported that they will provide information about voting opportunities.  The IRS has also placed voter registration information referring taxpayers to vote.gov in the Form 1040 Instructions both online and in print.</li><li>The <strong>National Institute of Standards and Technology</strong> at the Department of Commerce released a <a href="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.1273.pdf">report</a>examining barriers across the voting process for people with disabilities.  The report offers recommendations for state and local election officials, the federal government, and other non-governmental organizations to eliminate or mitigate those barriers.</li><li>The <strong>Office of Personnel Management</strong> issued <a href="https://chcoc.gov/content/executive-order-promoting-access-voting">guidance</a> to agencies to offer paid time off that will ensure that the thousands of federal employees in every state have time to vote and to serve in nonpartisan election-related capacities, including as volunteer poll workers.  The guidance amounts to a significant step in fulfilling the directive in the President’s Executive Order that the federal government should serve as a model employer in facilitating employees’ civic participation.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Justice</strong> is offering information and resources to individuals in federal custody to promote access to voting for those who remain eligible to vote while incarcerated or who will regain eligibility to vote upon their release. The Department also created an online resource for the public that connects them with state-specific information about registering and voting, details the Department’s enforcement of federal voting rights laws, and explains how to report potential violations.</li><li>The <strong>Department of Health and Human Services </strong>Health Resources and Services Administration issued <a href="https://bphc.hrsa.gov/programrequirements/scope/voter-requirements">guidance</a>for nearly 1,400 federally funded community health centers, with more than 14,000 service delivery sites providing primary care to nearly 29 million patients in underserved areas in every state across the country, clarifying the ways in which those health centers may support voter registration efforts.</li><li>At the <strong>Department of Housing and Urban Development</strong>, the Office of Public and Indian Housing <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/PIH/documents/PIH_announcement020922.pdf">wrote</a> to more than 3,000 public housing authorities managing approximately 1.2 million public housing units, explaining the ways in which grantees may support voter registration and information about the electoral process. The Office of Multifamily Housing <a href="https://www.hud.gov/sites/dfiles/PIH/documents/AllVotingCommunications.pdf">reminded</a> multifamily owners and agents of HUD-assisted properties about residents’ voting rights and opportunities to support their exercise of the franchise. And the Office of Field Policy and Management connected with local election officers and placed voter registration materials in all 10 HUD Regional Offices across the country. </li><li>The <strong>U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness</strong> released best practices election checklists—in five different languages—to be distributed to <a href="https://www.usich.gov/tools-for-action/step-by-step-voting-guide-for-people-experiencing-homelessness"><a href="https://www.usich.gov/tools-for-action/step-by-step-voting-guide-for-people-experiencing-homelessness">voters experiencing homelessness</a> and to <a href="https://www.usich.gov/tools-for-action/step-by-step-guide-for-homeless-service-providers-to-help-people-vote">service providers</a> who can help them register and vote. </a></li></ul>



<ul><li>The&nbsp;<strong>Department of Labor</strong>&nbsp;is providing guidance to state and local workforce officials on how they can work with state elections officials to designate American Job Centers, which provide employment, training, and career services to workers in every state, as voter registration agencies under the National Voter Registration Act. The Department’s guidance also clarifies which programs receiving federal workforce development funds could support nonpartisan voter registration efforts.</li><li>The&nbsp;<strong>Department of Agriculture</strong>&nbsp;Food and Nutrition Service issued letters to state agencies administering nutrition assistance programs to encourage the promotion of voter registration and non-partisan voting information.&nbsp;&nbsp;For state SNAP and WIC agencies, the letters remind states of their responsibilities under the National Voter Registration Act.</li><li>The&nbsp;<strong>Department of Education</strong>&nbsp;will send a letter next week to institutions of higher education highlighting their responsibilities under the Higher Education Act to make a good faith effort to distribute voter registration forms to the more than 19 million students enrolled in these institutions.&nbsp;&nbsp;The Department last reminded institutions of this requirement in 2013.&nbsp;&nbsp;The letter will also explain the conditions under which work-study funds may be used to support nonpartisan community service activity related to the electoral process.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki on the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea’s Ballistic Missile&#160;Launch</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/statement-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki-on-the-democratic-peoples-republic-of-koreas-ballistic-missile-launch/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States strongly condemns the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea (DPRK) &#160;for its test of a long-range ballistic missile. On March 10th, the United States Government publicly released information that the DPRK’s tests on February 26 and March 4, 2022 EST involved an Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) system. We noted that there would likely&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States strongly condemns the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea (DPRK) &nbsp;for its test of a long-range ballistic missile. On March 10<sup>th</sup>, the United States Government publicly released information that the DPRK’s tests on February 26 and March 4, 2022 EST involved an Intercontinental Ballistic Missile (ICBM) system. We noted that there would likely be further tests in the future. The President and his national security team are assessing the situation in close coordination with our allies and partners.&nbsp; This launch is a brazen violation of multiple UN Security Council resolutions and needlessly raises tensions and risks destabilizing the security situation in the region. This action demonstrates that the DPRK continues to prioritize its weapons of mass destruction and ballistic missile programs over the well-being of its people.&nbsp; We urge all countries to hold the DPRK accountable for such violations and call on the DPRK to come to the table for serious negotiations.&nbsp; The door has not closed on diplomacy, but Pyongyang must immediately cease its destabilizing actions.&nbsp;The United States will take all necessary measures to ensure the security of the American homeland and Republic of Korea and Japanese allies.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by Deputy National Security Advisor for International Economics Daleep Singh on Russia’s Plans to Partially Re-Open Stock&#160;Market</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/24/statement-by-deputy-national-security-advisor-for-international-economics-daleep-singh-on-russias-plans-to-partially-re-open-stock-market/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 06:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What we’re seeing is a charade: a Potemkin market opening. After keeping its markets closed for nearly a month, Russia announced it will only allow 15% of listed shares to trade, foreigners are prohibited from selling their shares, and short selling in general has been banned. Meanwhile, Russia has made clear they are going to&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>What we’re seeing is a charade: a Potemkin market opening. After keeping its markets closed for nearly a month, Russia announced it will only allow 15% of listed shares to trade, foreigners are prohibited from selling their shares, and short selling in general has been banned. Meanwhile, Russia has made clear they are going to pour government resources into artificially propping up the shares of companies that are trading. This is not a real market and not a sustainable model—which only underscores Russia’s isolation from the global financial system. The United States and our allies and partners will continue taking action to further isolate Russia from the international economic order as long it continues its brutal war against Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan En Route Brussels,&#160;Belgium</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/23/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-en-route-brussels-belgium/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 22:30:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49593</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[1:43 P.M. EDT&#160;MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Hi, everybody.&#160; Okay.&#160; We have National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan here.&#160; And he’s going to say a few words, take a couple of questions, and then I’ll take over after that and take any other questions you might have.&#160;&#160;Go ahead, Jake.&#160;MR. SULLIVAN:&#160; Hey, guys.&#160; So, we’re heading into a full day&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>1:43 P.M. EDT<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We have National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan here.&nbsp; And he’s going to say a few words, take a couple of questions, and then I’ll take over after that and take any other questions you might have.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Go ahead, Jake.<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Hey, guys.&nbsp; So, we’re heading into a full day tomorrow in Brussels.&nbsp; The President will start by meeting with the Secretary General to check signals, you know, get on the same page in terms of the agenda for the NATO Summit.&nbsp; And then he’ll be at the NATO Summit for three hours with his 29 fellow Allied leaders.&nbsp; So, it’ll be NATO with 30.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>NATO itself has not, as institution, been involved in the coordination or facilitation of security assistance to Ukraine.&nbsp; It’s been individual members, individual Allies who have done that.&nbsp; The United States, obviously, providing a really significant amount of military equipment and weapons to Ukraine and also coordinating the supplies of Allies as well to facilitate their delivery.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, it will be a subject of discussion at the summit &#8212; even though, institutionally, NATO is not engaged in it, how we make sure that we’re continuing to support Ukraine in its effort to defend itself, you know, will be a topic of conversation among the leaders while the President is in Brussels.<br>&nbsp;<br>They will also discuss the question of NATO’s force posture on the eastern flank.&nbsp; The leaders will ratify some of the decisions taken by defense ministers last week.&nbsp; We’ll have more to say on that tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But they’ll also task the military and political instruments of NATO to set out a longer-term game plan for what forces and capabilities are going to be required in those eastern flank countries &#8212; to be, ultimately, agreed at the Madrid Summit this summer &#8212; so that we’ve got a long-term footprint that is matched to the new security reality that’s been created both by Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine and by what’s happening in Belarus, including the fact that we’re seeing Russian forces and projecting Russian forces ending up in a posture where there is more of them more frequently on the territory of Belarus, and perhaps other capabilities as well.<br>&nbsp;<br>So that’ll be the NATO Summit piece of it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The President will then have opportunity to meet with the G7 leaders, and they’ll issue a statement.&nbsp; And it will cover a range of issues.&nbsp; The G7 has been a central locus for sanctions coordination.&nbsp; It’s where many of the key elements of the sanctions architecture were agreed and have been &#8212; have been &#8212; the details have been worked through.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the G7 leaders tomorrow will agree on an initiative to coordinate on sanctions enforcement so that Russian efforts to evade the sanctions or other countries’ effort to help Russia evade the sanctions can be dealt with effectively and in a coordinated fashion.&nbsp; And there’ll be, you know, a specific example of what that means discussed at the meeting and rolled out tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition, we, the United States, will announce a package of sanctions designations tomorrow that relate both to political figures, oligarchs &#8212; so, individual designations as well as entities &#8212; and that’ll be released tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>The G7 will also cover a number of other critical issues, including the global energy picture and the global food security picture, and some of the other knock-on and spillover effects of the conflict in Ukraine on the global economy and on the livelihoods of the citizens of our countries and people all around the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>And then the President will have the opportunity to have a signals check with President Michel, the President of the European Council, before he goes into a European Council meeting where he will have the opportunity to discuss the refugee and humanitarian situation that has been fast evolving over the course of the past month since Russia&#8217;s latest military action got underway.<br>&nbsp;<br>He&#8217;ll have the chance to talk about next steps on sanctions with the European Union.&nbsp; He&#8217;ll have the chance to talk about democratic resilience and supporting civil society and journalists and other instruments of strong democracies in many of the partner countries of the European Union in the east.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there will be a few other elements to the discussion that he will have with European leaders, including China and how we get coordinated on our approach vis-à-vis China, especially as it relates to China&#8217;s involvement in the crisis in Ukraine &#8212; because the EU has a summit with China coming up on April 1st, so just a few days after the President will be engaging them in in Brussels.<br>&nbsp;<br>The last thing is, throughout the day, the President will obviously consult on potential contingencies: the possibility of cyberattacks by Russia against the United States or other Allied and partner countries, the possibility of the use of chemical or biological weapons in Ukraine, the possibility of escalation in the conflict in other ways.&nbsp; And as I discussed yesterday at the podium, how to deal with the rhetoric and the commentary coming out of Russia on this whole question of the potential use of nuclear weapons.<br>&nbsp;<br>I said yesterday that we haven&#8217;t seen anything that&#8217;s made us adjust our posture &#8212; our nuclear posture, but it&#8217;s, of course, something that we will have to continue to stay in close consultation with Allies and partners on, as well as communicate directly to the Russians on.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, let me stop there in terms of what tomorrow looks like, and I&#8217;m happy to take your questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q &nbsp;Can I ask, on energy sanctions or energy actions, what &#8212; you mentioned this yesterday &#8212; what is on the table in terms of some sort of deal or anything between the U.S. and the EU to try to reduce reliance on Russian energy?<br>&nbsp;<br>Of course, European partners have been more hesitant to enact the same measures that the UK, the U.S., Canada, and others have because they rely more heavily on it, in particular on natural gas.&nbsp; Is there anything you&#8217;re going to discuss or announce on that?&nbsp; Is there deal in place?&nbsp; What can you tell us?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, this is a substantial topic of conversation.&nbsp; A major priority for both the President and his European allies is to reduce the dependence of Europe on Russian gas.&nbsp; Full stop.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the practical roadmap for how to do that &#8212; what steps have to be taken, what the United States can contribute, what Europe has to do itself &#8212; this has been the subject of intense back-and-forth over the course of the past few days and weeks.&nbsp; And we will have more to say on this subject specifically on Friday, particularly with the European Commission and the European Commission President, von der Leyen.&nbsp; So he&#8217;ll discuss it tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But in terms of further things to say publicly on the subject, I&#8217;m not going to preview it today.&nbsp; But you can zero in on Friday morning for more news on that, so stay tuned.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say what the U.S. will tell its European partners what it wants to see from China or what it hopes Europe will seek from China?&nbsp; In other words, what is the latest in terms of what you&#8217;re &#8212; what you perceive to be China&#8217;s involvement or lack of involvement in Russia&#8217;s war and the trajectory, I guess?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, as I said yesterday, we have not actually seen or do not have evidence of the actual provision of military equipment for use in Ukraine from China to Russia.&nbsp; But we are monitoring that closely and, of course, our European allies are as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we&#8217;ve sent a clear message to China about the implications and consequences of any such provision of military equipment.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re on the same page with our European allies on that, and we expect that they will convey similar messages in their dealings at the highest levels with the Chinese government.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>The same thing goes for systematic efforts to undermine, weaken, or circumvent the sanctions regime that we have put in place.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ve communicated on that as well to China, and we expect similar communication by the European Union and individual European countries.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re also on the same page in that regard.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And the G7 sanctions enforcement initiative ensuring that there isn&#8217;t systematic sanctions busting, that&#8217;s not specifically about China, but it will apply to every significant economy and the decisions that any of those economies take to try in an intentional and active way to undermine or weaken the sanctions that we put in place.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just follow up on the energy issue?&nbsp; The idea of reducing energy dependence sounds like a medium- to long-term question.&nbsp; Is the United States &#8212; is the President going to be pressing the &#8212; his European allies to do more in the immediate term &#8212; a ban on oil, a ban on gas?&nbsp; A ban on coal has been raised.&nbsp; I mean, is &#8212; and understanding that their reluctance is because of their greater dependence, is the message from the United States going to be, “You guys need to act now”?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, first, I think it&#8217;s important to note that the United States itself is acting now to help Europe on the issue of Russ- &#8212; dependence on Russian gas, diverting cargoes to help increase the supply of gas &#8212; U.S. LNG &#8212; to Europe in the immediate term.&nbsp; And I think you can expect that the U.S. will look for ways to increase LNG supplies, surge LNG supplies to Europe not just over the course of years, but over the course of months as well.&nbsp; Of course, that amount will grow over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, our focus now is not on &#8212; over the course of the next couple of days &#8212; is not on a particular sanctions move we&#8217;re asking Europe to make on this.&nbsp; It is, rather: How do we put in place a strategy that is not just a long-term strategy but is a short-term strategy to help reduce dependence and to create more freedom and flexibility then for different policy choices by the Europeans?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I put a finer point on the China question?&nbsp; You &#8212; they have a preexisting economic relationship &#8212; China and Russia.&nbsp; Are your concerns about an incremental growth in that relationship as a financial relationship?&nbsp; Is status quo okay? Could you maybe elaborate a little bit more about those concerns?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; What do you mean?&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, I&#8217;m not sure I fully &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; China and Russia have a preexisting financial relationship: trade.&nbsp; Is it okay if that trade continues as is? Or are you concerned about incremental change in that &#8212; or growth in that kind of trade to avoid sanctions?&nbsp; Can you put a little finer point on that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I mean, just three sort of examples that I think will give a little bit more flavor to the kinds of things we&#8217;re looking out for.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>One is attempting to backfill in response to the export controls that we have imposed &#8212; Chinese companies or companies from other countries choose to backfill.&nbsp; We obviously have tools available to us to ensure that backfilling can&#8217;t happen.&nbsp; That&#8217;s one.<br>&nbsp;<br>Second is, from the point of view of payment settlements and financial sanctions, systematic efforts, industrial-scale efforts to try to reorient the settlement of financial payments and so forth.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that, in coordination with our G7 allies, we will look at and respond to.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then third, of course, is the kinds of non-steady state, new efforts to try to seize opportunities that have been created by the reduction in commerce between Europe, Japan, and other countries because of the sanctions not just with China but across the board.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that we will look at as well.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, I&#8217;ve been clear that we&#8217;re not going to lay out in specifics the particular countermeasures we would take, the particular steps we’d impose.&nbsp; We&#8217;re communicating that privately to countries.&nbsp; You know, I don&#8217;t want to use the microphone to threaten; I just want to say this is something we&#8217;re vigilant about and that we have tools at our disposal to deal with in coordination with the G7 and with other countries.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A question on chemical and biological.&nbsp; Has the U.S. seen evidence that Russia has moved or deployed any of these weapons in a way to threaten Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have any intelligence to share with you today on this subject.&nbsp; The main thing that we&#8217;re looking at right now is the deliberate drumbeat of misinformation, propaganda, and lies on this subject that has all the markers of a precursor to them actually using these weapons.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So is the U.S. assessment based entirely on that drumbeat of propaganda, or is it also based on movements of weapons?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; It&#8217;s a very fair question.&nbsp; All I can tell you right now is I can&#8217;t comment further on the intelligence picture on this today.&nbsp; To the extent that I&#8217;m in a position to share further information related to our intelligence, I&#8217;ll be sure to do so.&nbsp; But right now, I don&#8217;t have anything else to share.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, was there anything in your conversations with Chinese officials last week or President &#8212; or the President&#8217;s conversations with President Xi that left you at all reassured that the Chinese would not provide weapons or other assistance to the Russians?&nbsp; Or do you &#8212; are you more concerned after those conversations?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, I will beg your forgiveness in advance by being sort of intentionally vague in my answer to your question. &nbsp;And the reason is because this is not the kind of circumstance where you just kind of feel reassurance.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to require constant vigilance, constant monitoring.&nbsp; We will have to see what happens.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, all I can really say to you is that coming out of that conversation, we have not seen the Chinese government move forward on the supply of weapons, but it&#8217;s something we&#8217;re watching every day.&nbsp; And I really can&#8217;t characterize my level of comfort with that out one way or the other; it&#8217;s something we just have to maintain vigilance about.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a question on the EU.&nbsp; Do you want to see the European Union &#8212; does the administration want to see the European Union spend more on defense &#8212; such as what President Macron has suggested, that they should become &#8212; you know, borrowing more money, spending more, bolstering its defense spending to this point?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; When President Biden and President Macron met in Rome in October, they put out a joint statement.&nbsp; And one of the points in that statement was support across the board for increased European capability and investment in the strength of their defense tools and the modernization of their defense establishments with one very important principle underlying that, and that is complementarity with NATO.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, all of this work that&#8217;s being done by individual European countries, by the European Union, this is something that contributes overall to the health and strength of the transatlantic Alliance so long it is &#8212; it is done in complementarity with NATO.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Should Russia still be part of the G20?&nbsp; Any concern, any talk about that?&nbsp; There are some countries that have voiced some &#8212; some opinions on that.&nbsp; I know there&#8217;s a financial leadership meeting in Washington of the G20 come maybe April.&nbsp; Should Russia be a &#8212; should Russia representatives attend that?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So what I said yesterday, which I&#8217;ll repeat today, is that we don&#8217;t believe it can be business as usual with Russian international institutions.&nbsp; But in terms of specific answers to that kind of question for the G20 or other international organizations, we want to have the opportunity to consult with our Allies and partners around the world, including our G20 partners before I opine on that question publicly.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A couple.&nbsp; On &#8212; if you&#8217;re looking at the sanctions and the upcoming planned sanctions that you plan to announce, on &#8212; say, on like a scale of 1 to 10, or do it on however measure you would like to &#8212; like, what do you have left?&nbsp; Like, where would you be at if 10 were ratcheted up to the highest degree?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And what else could you do?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yeah, how much room to grow do you have?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So I &#8212; I would ask you guys, I guess, two &#8212; two questions &#8212; two things.&nbsp; The first is: In terms of an analysis of the macroeconomic impact of what we have done and then, you know, what additional tools are in the toolkit, Daleep &#8212; who is on the trip, and we&#8217;ll get you with him in a backgrounder so you have the opportunity to speak with him directly on this &#8212; is the expert and then to speak also with the Treasury Department.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s one thing.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Because I think this is one where really getting down granularly into what hit has the Russian economy taken, in what way, and then, you know, what are other things that we could do over time.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But the second thing I would ask you is to consider this not just like we&#8217;re firing bullets out of the chamber of a gun and we fired X number and there&#8217;s Y number left.&nbsp; I think it’s the wrong way to think about it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>What we&#8217;ve done on the financial sanctions and the export controls is create a vise that is squeezing harder and harder with each passing day and week.&nbsp; And then, as we see the impact and we see efforts to evade, we think about adjustments we need to make to ensure that vise continues to tighten.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So our theory on this was never: Every three days we fire another bullet.&nbsp; It was: Put the major pieces in place, look for ways to continue to tighten the screws, and then consider other means as we go forward.&nbsp; And, of course, we will do that.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So I can&#8217;t characterize this question of what we&#8217;ve done and what we have left precisely, in part because we don&#8217;t think of it quite in the terms that your question posed.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; But on &#8212; on the kind of macro picture, which is a kind of &#8212; the way to back into an answer to your question, I&#8217;d ask you to speak with Daleep.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you talk a little bit about Friday?&nbsp; There&#8217;s obviously a big gaping hole in the President&#8217;s schedule.&nbsp; Is he going to go close to the border?&nbsp; Is he going to meet with &#8212; is he going to tour refugees &#8212; with refugees?&nbsp; What &#8212; what else can you tell us about Friday?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I&#8217;ll let Karine talk to you about Friday when &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; When do you think we may see &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; &#8212; when the time is right.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; JCPOA updated?&nbsp; And to what extent that will be discussed on this trip during this week?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So he&#8217;ll have the chance to talk to our E3 European partners &#8212; UK, France, Germany; four members of the P5+1; as well as the European Union, which plays this important coordinating role in the P5+1.<br>&nbsp;<br>Where things stand now is we’ve made progress over the course of the past several weeks.&nbsp; There are still some issues left.&nbsp; We&#8217;re working on those issues.&nbsp; It&#8217;s unclear whether this will come to closure or not.&nbsp; But, you know, we&#8217;re diligently trying to drive the diplomacy to a place where we have put Iran&#8217;s nuclear program back in a box.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you sure that a deal could put more money or more freedom to use money in the hands of Iran, and that, in turn, could be a lifeline to Russia&#8217;s economy?&nbsp; Can you talk about the sort of triangulation of that here?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; First, Russia posed both publicly and privately this proposition that Iran should somehow be entirely carved out of the sanctions regime, which was not accepted by any of the parties.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So the only question of sanctions as it relates to Russia in the context of the JCPOA is about sanctions on Iran being able to, for example, cooperate with the Russian Atomic Energy authorities to ship out their enriched uranium.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So we feel confident that if we were to get back into the JCPOA on a compliance-for-compliance basis.&nbsp; It would not create a significant economic opportunity for Russia.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we would take whatever necessary enforcement steps to ensure that that was the case.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake, how much visibility do you have into the status of Russian-Ukrainian negotiations right now?&nbsp; And how much faith do you have in the Russians being a trustworthy negotiation partner in the first place?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Well, I will point out that Russia has not been trustworthy in its public statements about its intentions with respect to Ukraine for months.&nbsp; So, we take everything that they say at the negotiating table or from their podiums with a very large grain of salt.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We are in very consistent communication with our Ukrainian friends.&nbsp; And President Biden speaks to President Zelenskyy on this issue. &nbsp;President Biden also speaks with the Presidents of France and Germany, the Prime Minister of Israel, the President of Turkey, others who have been actively engaged in discussions with President Putin and President Zelenskyy.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;re actively engaged in monitoring the ongoing diplomacy, though the United States is not directly at the table or directly playing any kind of mediating or brokering role.&nbsp; And we will see how things unfold.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Our basic principle is: This is about Ukraine&#8217;s future, Ukraine&#8217;s destiny, and therefore it is up to Ukraine and the Ukrainian leadership, the Ukrainian people to make their own judgments about any agreement that they would reach with the Russians.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you comment on the transfer of air defense systems to Ukraine.&nbsp; Is that moving forward?&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve talked about the S-300 system &#8212; things like that.&nbsp; There’s a large shuffle going on.&nbsp; What&#8217;s the latest on that?&nbsp; When could Ukraine expect to see those systems in their country?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We feel good about the progress that we are making with respect to air defense systems.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not going to get into further details on that because I don&#8217;t want to compromise the ongoing effort to ensure that Ukraine gets the tools it needs to protect itself from the sky.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you confirm that NATO &#8212; NATO Allied countries want to extend the contract of the Secretary General, Stoltenberg, and what the President&#8217;s view &#8212; possibly through September of 2023 &#8212; and what the President&#8217;s view on that might be?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; The President thinks very highly of Secretary General Stoltenberg.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve developed a relationship of trust.&nbsp; And Pres- &#8212; Secretary General Stoltenberg has played an instrumental role in helping secure the powerful unity you&#8217;ve seen at NATO through this crisis.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t have anything for you on the question of his tenure.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say whether he wants to see continuity there and not sort of breaking this up in the middle of this conflict?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, all I will say is: We think that Jens Stoltenberg has been doing a fantastic job and, day in and day out, has played a critical leadership role for NATO.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you&#8217;ll forgive me if for today, on this plane flight, I will add nothing to that other than our unreserved view that that Stoltenberg is a real asset to the Alliance.&nbsp; And then, you know, the leaders will have the chance to talk tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President plan to send additional U.S. troops to Eastern Europe?&nbsp; And if so, how many?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, we don&#8217;t have any plans for announcements of specific additional units to move to Eastern Europe at this time.&nbsp; But the President is constantly reviewing plans for near-term adjustments to our force posture in all the eastern flank countries, depending on how things develop.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s not a today thing or a tomorrow thing, but it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s a matter of consistent reassessment.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know if any additional troop deployments will be announced on this trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that’s &#8212; but what about the broader &#8212; the long-term of NATO force deployment along the eastern &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yes, we have &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; that &#8212; that could involve U.S. troops to &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Two aspects of this will be discussed tomorrow.&nbsp; One is the immediate need to shore up on a rotational basis those Allies on the southern end of the eastern flank, and that will be discussed tomorrow.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then the second is, across the entire eastern flank, as we head to the Madrid Summit, what decisions does NATO have to take for longer-term force posture adjustments?&nbsp; And of course, some of those will involve U.S. forces.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On this trip, what are you looking to hear from other EU and the UK leaders?&nbsp; You’ve talked about trying to reduce Europe&#8217;s energy &#8212; energy dependence on Russian oil and gas.&nbsp; What else would you like to hear from the leaders that the President will be meeting?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think what we would like to hear is that the resolve and unity that we&#8217;ve seen for the past month will endure for as long as it takes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s at a topline.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Then how that translates specifically: that countries follow through on the commitments they&#8217;ve made with respect to the supply of military equipment and add to those commitments as Ukraine&#8217;s needs evolve over time; that countries remain fully committed to enforcing the sanctions on the books and, to the extent we find additional targets that can help impose pressure on Putin, we do &#8212; we move in a joint way on that; that we all work together to do our part on the humanitarian element of this crisis, both the suffering inside Ukraine and the refugee crisis outside Ukraine &#8212; here, Europe has really stepped up in a huge way, and it&#8217;s the United States that will be coming with additional commitments on both humanitarian assistance and refugees tomorrow; and that NATO, as an Alliance, puts its money where its mouth is when it comes to actually defending every inch of NATO territory, and that means following through on the necessary capabilities and contributions to defend the eastern flank and to defend the whole Alliance.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>That&#8217;s what tomorrow is all about across an integrated set of three meetings.&nbsp; And we think that we will have a substantial set of outcomes that will emerge by the end of the day when, after many hours, the President will emerge to address all of you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does President Biden plan to have a short bilat with Turkish President Erdoğan on the sidelines of NATO?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have a bilat scheduled with President Erdoğan.&nbsp; But you know how these things go.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll be hanging out at NATO Headquarters, and I expect he&#8217;ll have the chance to have brief conversations with a number of leaders.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the U.S. position on giving planes to Ukraine &#8212; remains the same?&nbsp; Or are you looking to discuss that if the Polish, for instance, bring it up?&nbsp; Is it still your belief that it should not be NATO giving planes to Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; There’s been no change in our position on the MiG-29s.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And have you guys formally shot down the idea of a peacekeeping force that the Poles have raised?&nbsp; Or is that something that is still at least open for discussion from the U.S. perspective?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; President Biden&#8217;s been very clear that we&#8217;re not sending U.S. soldiers to fight Russian soldiers in Ukraine.&nbsp; I have not, myself, had the opportunity, nor has President Biden had the opportunity to consult with his Polish counterpart, or I with mine, on exactly what they have in mind.&nbsp; So, we&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;ll have that conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But our position, with respect to deployment of U.S. forces in Ukraine, has been clear from the start, and it remains unchanged.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; There’s a difference between saying U.S. forces shouldn&#8217;t be deployed and NATO forces should not be deployed into Ukraine.&nbsp; Do you have the same red line about forces under a NATO banner from other NATO countries going into Ukraine?<br>&nbsp;<br>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; I think before I opine on what is a hypothetical or theoretical question like that, I think it&#8217;s important for us to get the opportunity to hear more about something we&#8217;ve just seen in the press, and then we can speak to it.<br>&nbsp;<br>All right.&nbsp; Thank you, guys.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you, Jake.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Thanks, Jake.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Now you get to tell us all about the refugees in the Friday schedule.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Is that what you want me to talk about?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jake &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; No, Jake did a great job laying out tomorrow &#8212; NATO, EU, G7 meetings that the President will be &#8212; will be part of.<br>&nbsp;<br>I mean, look, what I &#8212; what I can do is &#8212; you guys already have all of this &#8212; is say what happens when he leaves Brussels &#8212; right? &#8212; in a more broad stroke &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right, just because &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; and say what happens after Brussels in a more broad &#8212; broad stroke.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as you guys already know, he&#8217;s going to meet with President Duda once he leaves Brussels and goes to Poland to thank him for everything the people of Poland are doing and to discuss our coordinated humanitarian response to support the many Ukrainians who have been impacted by Putin&#8217;s war.<br>&nbsp;<br>I think Jake also talked about the President &#8212; where he will engage with U.S. troops who are now &#8212; who are now helping to defend NATO territory yesterday.&nbsp; He talked about that.&nbsp; And he will meet with experts involved in a humanitarian response.<br>&nbsp;<br>We talked about the speech that the President will be giving, but I won&#8217;t give any more further &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; His speech?&nbsp; I’m sorry, which?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; We talked about that.&nbsp; The President is going to be giving a speech in Poland.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; In Poland?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah, we announced that probably a day or two ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so those are kind of &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; Michael, you got to keep up.&nbsp; You got to keep up.&nbsp; So, we talked &#8212; I’m just going to, like I said, talk about the broader strokes of things that he’s going to do tomorrow.<br>&nbsp;<br>Clearly, we’ll give more guidance on what Friday will look like.&nbsp; But for security purposes, we just want to keep it more broad and not go into details.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us an update on whether the President tested before this trip since Monday and what his most recent COVID test result was?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just any general update of other people who tested positive in the White House.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, the President ha- &#8212; was tested yesterday, as Josh just mentioned, and as part of his regular testing cadence.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no change to the President&#8217;s testing cadence during his travel because he was not a close contact.<br>&nbsp;<br>He will be tested throughout the trip in alignment with the various entry and departure requirements for the countries he will be visiting.<br>&nbsp;<br>For example, for context here, there&#8217;ll be no testing entry requirement for Brussel &#8212; testing requirement.&nbsp; There&#8217;ll be testing requirement for a Warsaw exit requirement for return to the U.S.<br>&nbsp;<br>As far as your question, so, since &#8212; when we&#8217;re talking about staff and all of those things that you just asked &#8212; so, since July, because of our commitment to transparency, we provide updates when any White House official tests positive for COVID-19 and with White House Medical Unit deems them as having had close contact with the President, Vice President, First Lady, and &#8212; or Second Gentleman.&nbsp; That will be up to the White House Medical Unit based on the criteria of the CDC.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, Jen, for example, shared her positive case yesterday, as she did in October, out of an abundance of transparency.<br>&nbsp;<br>If an individual does not meet this criteria that I just laid out, meaning they are not a close contact of our four principals, it would be up to the individual.&nbsp; This has been our policy since July.&nbsp; It hasn&#8217;t changed.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us an update on whether you&#8217;re still considering any further releases of the SPR to deal with the current gas price?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything new to share on that, on any new actions.&nbsp; But as the President has said previously, we&#8217;re going to continue to assess, and our government will take action as needed as evidenced &#8212; as evidenced by recent Strategic Petroleum Reserve releases that we announced not too long ago, and the &#8212; and announced International Energy Agency agreement &#8212; those two things that we announced probably, I don’t know, about a month ago &#8212; a couple weeks ago.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And acknowledging that there are other things on the go, has he made any decisions on when you will name a new Fed nominee?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview for you on the new Fed nominee.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Forgive me for having to ask.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; No, it’s a fair &#8212; it’s a &#8212; not a surprising ask.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President have any further reaction to yesterday here on the Sup- &#8212; on Ketanji Brown Jackson?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; So, as we noted, the President did watch some of &#8212; some of the &#8212; did watch some of the portions of yesterday&#8217;s hearing with Judge Jackson.<br>&nbsp;<br>And again, he couldn&#8217;t be more proud of her intellect, her grace, character, and the value of her experience.&nbsp; The country is seeing just how qualified Judge Jackson is and how she determines cases fairly based solely on the facts and the law, which is what the American people expect in a Supreme Court justice.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why she is endorsed by conservative judges, the Fraternal Order of Police, the International Association of Chiefs of Police, dozens of police chiefs, sheriffs, and 83 bipartisan former State Attorney Generals.&nbsp; Just today, 43 former federal prosecutors in Florida endorsed Judge Jackson.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, like we said yesterday, the President was also impressed with how she dismantled bad-faith conspiracy theories and that have &#8212; that have been fact checked by major media outlets and experts, like some of you all here, and moderates in both parties are now dismissing them for the fringe smears that they are.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>She thoughtfully and thoroughly answered questions from senators for nearly 12 hours, as you all know, demonstrating the temperament required for a Supreme Court justice and showing the strength of her intellect and character.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I guess &#8212; I just wanted to follow up really quickly. Does he have any reaction to the kind of questioning that Senator Cruz, Senator Hawley, Senator Cotton &#8212; I mean, you know, a range of them &#8212; did?&nbsp; What did he think of their questions?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just to piggyback on that &#8212; just the critical race theory as well &#8212; you know, theory and all of that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Let me talk more broadly about your point, Michael, about the overall attacks.&nbsp; Look &#8212; so, you know, we&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re focused on the full Senate.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; She&#8217;s been working hard to earn support since day one.&nbsp; She has &#8212; since the day she was &#8212; the President named her, she&#8217;s met with 45 senators, and she&#8217;s going to meet with more after.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you&#8217;ve heard Republicans react well to her qualifications and her neutral methodology based in the facts of law &#8212; law and facts &#8212; based in the law and facts.&nbsp; And so, I want to be really clear: Our strategy doesn&#8217;t depend on Josh Hawley or any of the other senators who attacked her.<br>&nbsp;<br>On the critical race theory, you know, she actually spoke to this yesterday as well &#8212; Judge Jackson.&nbsp; And to quote her, she said, when it comes to critical race theory, “never been something I&#8217;ve studied or relied on.”&nbsp; She applies the facts and the law when making decisions on the bench, not academic theory.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And I also saw PolitiFact already found an attack about base &#8212; about &#8212; based on this “false” after a senator claims she considered it when judging cases.&nbsp; In comments to students about academic subjects that may &#8212; that they may find interesting, she mentioned critical race theory in a list of other academic topics such as administrative law, constitutional law, negotiations, and contracts.<br>&nbsp;<br>But again, I would refer you back to what she said herself about that.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But I guess the questions is: Did he think the questions from the senators that we mentioned about critical race theory and the other issues &#8212; the, you know, pornography, and whatever &#8212; did he think those questions were inappropriate, racist, whatever &#8212; however you want to say?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, it’s basically what I said, Michael.&nbsp; He&#8217;s very proud &#8212; he&#8217;s very proud of how she handled herself yesterday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That doesn’t answer &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I mean, I think &#8212; I think it does.&nbsp; We &#8212; I just told you he watched &#8212; he watched yesterday, and I just told you his reaction.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to go &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to break it down &#8212; break it down specific to details.&nbsp; I just laid out how he felt and why she was chosen and her bipartisan support that she&#8217;s getting.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us more of a preview of the humanitarian assistance that we might expect to see?&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to go to Poland.&nbsp; Polish leaders have been pretty clear about their breaking point.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to presumably see some evidence of that.&nbsp; I know you&#8217;re not going to get ahead of the President, but can you give us some &#8212; should Americans expect a more open-door policy to get these &#8212; some of these folks into the U.S.?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look &#8212; you know, again, he&#8217;s going to announce further American contributions to respond to the growing flow of refugees and to the coordinated humanitarian response to ease the suffering of civilians inside Ukraine, but I don&#8217;t have anything further to preview.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Look, we are surging humanitarian assistance to countries neighboring Ukraine who are providing them with support.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve kind of laid out what we&#8217;ve done in the past &#8212; these past couple weeks.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And with Poland, to help them &#8212; some kind of relief package for Poland to help them deal with &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Again, I&#8217;m not &#8212; I mean, you even said it in your question.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President, but this is something that&#8217;s coming forward.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just &#8212; last time on this one, to follow up on Michael&#8217;s point.&nbsp; You know, he&#8217;s served on this panel for many years, like many of these confirmation fights.&nbsp; Like just generally &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t want to respond to any specific senator &#8212; how does he think that these Republican senators have comported themselves?&nbsp; Not her reaction to that, but the senators themselves.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Look, I&#8217;m not going to get into specifics on that at all.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just going to lay out what I said already and how he saw her performance, which is what is the most important thing is &#8212; how Judge Jackson performed yesterday.&nbsp; He&#8217;s very proud of her.&nbsp; We feel very confident in her being the next justice on the Supreme Court.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything further to read out to you.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have any lists of bilats or anything you can share on what meetings he might have during this trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that last part.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you &#8212; can you share anything about what bilateral meetings he might have on this trip?<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No.&nbsp; Jake just talked about that.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t have anything &#8212; at least when he was asked about Turkey &#8212; we don&#8217;t have anything else to preview on a bilat meeting.&nbsp; And just to reiterate what Jake said &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; which is, you know, at these type of events &#8212; the NATO in particular and the EU and G7 &#8212; you never know what might happen.&nbsp; But we &#8212; I don&#8217;t have anything else to preview on a bilat.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.<br>&nbsp;<br>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp; Appreciate you all.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>2:24 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
