<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 20:42:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Republic of the Philippines to Attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Ferdinand Romualdez Marcos,&#160;Jr.</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/26/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-republic-of-the-philippines-to-attend-the-inauguration-of-his-excellency-ferdinand-romualdez-marcos-jr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 20:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Ferdinand Romualdez Marcos, Jr. on June 30, 2022, in Manila, Republic of Philippines.&#160; Mr. Douglas Emhoff, Second Gentleman of the United States, will lead the delegation.&#160; Members of the Presidential Delegation: Ms. Heather Variava, Chargé&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Ferdinand Romualdez Marcos, Jr. on June 30, 2022, in Manila, Republic of Philippines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Mr. Douglas Emhoff, Second Gentleman of the United States, will lead the delegation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</p>



<p>Ms. Heather Variava, Chargé d’Affaires, ad interim, U.S. Embassy Manila</p>



<p>The Honorable Bobby Scott, Chairman of the Committee on Education and Labor, United States Representative (D), Virginia</p>



<p>The Honorable Nani A. Coloretti, Deputy Director, Office of Management and Budget</p>



<p>Admiral James “Sandy” A. Winnefeld, Jr. (Ret.), Former Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Honorable Edgard D. Kagan, Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for East Asia and Oceania, National Security Council&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Honorable Chantale Y. Wong, U.S. Director of the Asian Development Bank</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Launch of the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and&#160;Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/26/remarks-by-president-biden-at-launch-of-the-partnership-for-global-infrastructure-and-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 16:58:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56314</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Schloss ElmauKrün, Germany 5:19 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you very much.&#160; Well, good afternoon, folks.&#160; Our nations and our world stand at a genuine inflection point in history.&#160; Technology has made our world smaller, more immediate, and more connected.&#160; It’s opened up incredible opportunities, but also accelerated challenges that impact on all of us:&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Schloss Elmau<br>Krün, Germany</p>



<p>5:19 P.M. CEST<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you very much.&nbsp; Well, good afternoon, folks.&nbsp;<br><br>Our nations and our world stand at a genuine inflection point in history.&nbsp; Technology has made our world smaller, more immediate, and more connected.&nbsp; It’s opened up incredible opportunities, but also accelerated challenges that impact on all of us: managing global energy needs, taking on the climate crisis, dealing with the spread of diseases.<br><br>And the choices we make now, in my view, are going to set a direction of our world for several generations to come.<br><br>These challenges are hard for all of us, even nations with resources of the G7.&nbsp; But developing countries often lack the essential infrastructure to help navigate global shocks, like a pandemic.&nbsp; So they feel the impacts more acutely, and they have a harder time recovering.<br><br>In our deeply connected world, that’s not just a humanitarian concern, it’s an economic and a security concern for all of us.&nbsp;<br><br>That’s why, one year ago, when this group of leaders met in Cornwall, we made a commitment: The democratic nations of the G7 would step up &#8212; step up and provide financing for quality, high-standard, sustainable infrastructure in developing and middle-income countries.<br><br>What we’re doing is fundamentally different because it’s grounded on our shared values of all those representing the countries and organizations behind me.&nbsp; It’s built using the global best practices: transparency, partnership, protections for labor and the environment.<br><br>We’re offering better options for countries and for people around the world to invest in critical infrastructure that improves the lives &#8212; their lives, all of our lives &#8212; and delivers real gains for all of our people, not just the G7 &#8212; all of our people.<br><br>Today, we officially launch the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment.&nbsp; We collectively have dozens of projects already underway around the globe.<br><br>And I’m proud to announce the United States will mobilize $200 billion in public and private capital over the next five years for that Partnership.<br><br>We’re here today because we’re making this commitment together as a G7 in coordination with one another to maximize the impact of our work.<br><br>Collectively, we aim to mobilize nearly $600 billion from the G7 by 2027.&nbsp;<br><br>These strategic investments are areas of &#8212; critical to sustainable development and to our shared global stability: health and health security,&nbsp;digital connectivity, gender equality and equity, climate and energy security.<br><br>Let me give you some examples of the kinds of projects that are underway in each of these areas.<br><br>First, health.&nbsp; Two years ago, COVID-19 &#8212; didn’t need any reminders about how critical investments in healthcare systems were and health sec- &#8212; and health security is, both to fight the pandemic and to prepare for the next one, because it will not be the last pandemic we under- &#8212; we have to deal with.<br><br>That’s why the United States, together with the G7 partners and the World Bank, are investing in a new industrial-scale vaccine manufacturing facility in Senegal.&nbsp; When complete, it will have the potential to produce hundreds of millions of doses of vaccines annually for COVID-19 and other diseases.<br><br>It’s an investment that will enhance global vaccine supplies as well as improve access and equity for developing countries.<br><br>Second, in the digital area.&nbsp; Our economies’ future increasingly depends on people’s ability to connect to secure information and communications technologies.&nbsp; And we need to strengthen the use of trusted technologies so that our online information cannot be used by autocrats to consolidate their power or repress their people.<br><br>That’s why the Digital Invest Program is mobilizing $335 million in private capital to supply secure network equipment in Africa, Asia, and Latin America.<br><br>And the U.S. government also supported the successful bid by an American company, SubCom, for a $600 million contract to build a global subsea telecommunications cable.&nbsp; This cable will stretch from Southeast Asia, through the Middle East and the Horn of Africa, to Europe.<br><br>This will be essential to meeting the growing demand for reliable security, high-tech connectivity in three key regions of the world.<br><br>Third, gender.&nbsp; When women and girls have the ability and the opportunity to parcia- &#8212; to participate more fully in those societies and economies, we see positive impacts not only in their communities but around the board &#8212; across the board.<br><br>We have to increase those opportunities, though, for women and girls to thrive, including practical steps to make childcare more accessible and affordable as we continue the vital work to protect and advance women’s fundamental rights.<br><br>The United States is committing $50 million over five years to the World Bank’s global Childcare Incentive Fund.&nbsp; This public-private partnership supported by several G7 partners will help countries build infrastructure that makes it easier for women to participate equally &#8212; equally &#8212; in the labor force.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Fourth and very important, climate and energy.&nbsp; We’re seeing just how critical this is every day.&nbsp; The entire world is feeling the impact of Russia’s brutal war in Ukraine and on our energy markets.<br><br>We need worldwide effort to invest in transformative clean energy projects to ensure that critical infrastructure is resilient to changing climate.&nbsp;<br><br>Critical materials that are necessary for our clean energy transition, including the production of batteries, need to be developed with high standards for labor and the environment.<br><br>Fast and reliable transportation infrastructure, including railroads and ports, is essential to moving inputs for refining and processing and expanding access to clean energy technologies.&nbsp;<br><br>For example, the U.S. government just facilitated a new partnership between two American firms and the government of Angola to invest $2 billion in building new solar projects in Angola.&nbsp; It’s a partnership that will help Angola meet its climate goals and energy needs while creating new markets for American technologies and good jobs in Angola and, I suspect, throughout Africa.<br><br>And in Romania, the American company, NuScale Power, will build a first-of-its-kind small modular reactor plant.&nbsp; This will help bring online zero-emission nuclear energy to Europe faster, more cheaply, and more efficiently.<br><br>The U.S. government is helping to advance the development of this groundbreaking American technology, which will strengthen Europe’s energy security and create thousands of jobs in Romania and the United States.<br><br>These deals are just some of what’s in store.&nbsp; And we’re ready.&nbsp; We’re ready to get to work, together, all of us.<br><br>To lead efforts &#8212; to lead U.S. efforts, in my case &#8212; appointed &#8212; I appointed Amos Hochstein, my Special Presidential Coordinator, to deal with the rest of our colleagues.&nbsp; <s>I’ll</s> [He’ll] lead the U.S. whole-of-government approach to drive a coalition and a collaboration with the G7 and our partners around the world, including private sector and multilateral development banks.<br><br>I want to be clear: This isn’t aid or charity; it’s an investment that will deliver returns for everyone, including the American people and the people of all our nations.&nbsp; It’ll boost all of our economies, and it’s a chance for us to share our positive vision for the future and let communities around the world see themselves &#8212; and see for themselves the concrete benefits of partnering with democracies.<br><br>Because when democracies demonstrate what we can do, all that we have to offer, I have no doubt that we’ll win the competition every time.<br><br>Thank you.&nbsp; And now I invite President von der Leyen to the podium.<br><br>5:28 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum on the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and&#160;Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/26/memorandum-on-the-partnership-for-global-infrastructure-and-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES SUBJECT:    Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment  By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and to establish my Administration&#8217;s policy and approach to executing the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment (PGII), it&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>MEMORANDUM FOR THE HEADS OF EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENTS AND AGENCIES</p>



<p>SUBJECT:    Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment </p>



<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and to establish my Administration&#8217;s policy and approach to executing the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment (PGII), it is hereby ordered as follows:</p>



<p>Section 1. &nbsp;Policy. &nbsp;Infrastructure is critical to driving a society&#8217;s productivity and prosperity. &nbsp;When done well, infrastructure connects workers to good jobs; allows businesses to grow and thrive; facilitates the delivery of vital services; creates opportunities for all segments of society, including underserved communities; moves goods to markets; enables rapid information-sharing and communication; protects societies from the effects of climate change and public health crises or other emergencies; and supports global connection among nations. &nbsp;Infrastructure comes in many forms and sizes, from the large-scale energy systems that power inclusive economies, to the local healthcare networks that contribute to global health security, to the range of innovative infrastructure developed through investments from financial institutions and small- and medium-sized enterprises. &nbsp;My Administration is making an urgent, once-in-a-generation investment in domestic infrastructure that will create jobs, help address the climate crisis, and help the Nation recover from the coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) pandemic –– and the same focus is needed around the globe.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Internationally, infrastructure has long been underfunded, with over $40 trillion in estimated need in the developing world –– a need that will only increase with the climate crisis and population growth. &nbsp;Many low- and middle-income countries lack adequate access to high-quality financing that meets their long-term infrastructure investment needs. &nbsp;Too often, financing options lack transparency, fuel corruption and poor governance, and create unsustainable debt burdens, often leading to projects that exploit, rather than empower, workers; exacerbate challenges faced by vulnerable populations, such as forced displacement; degrade natural resources and the environment; threaten economic stability; undermine gender equality and human rights; and put insufficient focus on cybersecurity best practices &#8212; a failure that can contribute to vulnerable information and communications technology networks.</p>



<p>The underinvestment in infrastructure is not just financial, but also technical. &nbsp;Delivering high-quality infrastructure in low- and middle-income countries must include helping to establish and improve the necessary institutional and policy frameworks, regulatory environment, and human capacity to ensure the sustainable delivery of services to communities; defining strong engineering, environmental, social, governance, and labor standards; and structuring projects to attract private investment. &nbsp;Through the PGII, the United States and like-minded partners will emphasize high-standards and quality investments in resilient infrastructure that will drive job creation, safeguard against corruption, guarantee respect for workers&#8217; organizations and collective bargaining as allowed by national law or similar mechanisms, support inclusive economic recovery, address risks of environmental degradation, promote robust cybersecurity, promote skills transfer, and protect American economic prosperity and national security. &nbsp;The PGII will also advance values-driven infrastructure development that is carried out in a transparent and sustainable manner &#8212; financially, environmentally, and socially &#8212; to lead to better outcomes for recipient countries and communities.</p>



<p>There is bipartisan support for international infrastructure development. &nbsp;The Congress passed the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (BUILD Act) (Division F of Public Law 115-254, 132 Stat. 3485) with bipartisan support to mobilize private-sector dollars to support economic development in low- and middle income countries, which can include support for projects to build infrastructure, creating first-time access to electricity, starting businesses, and creating jobs. &nbsp;The BUILD Act institutionalized the United States&#8217; commitment to private sector–funded development by establishing the United States International Development Finance Corporation (DFC), authorized a higher exposure cap for the DFC than the exposure cap for the former Overseas Private Investment Corporation, and provided new tools to engage entrepreneurs and investors to help low- and middle-income countries access private resources to generate economic growth. &nbsp;These investments help ensure that our partners are stronger, create opportunities for people around the world, and reduce the need for future United States foreign aid.</p>



<p>In a similar spirit, in 2018 the Congress passed the AGOA and MCA Modernization Act (Public Law 115-167, 132 Stat. 1276), authorizing the Millennium Challenge Corporation (MCC) to make concurrent regional compacts under specified conditions, which can include investments in regional infrastructure. &nbsp;This new authority builds on the MCC&#8217;s record of delivering complex infrastructure projects that result in the delivery of vital services for communities and sustainable, inclusive economic growth. &nbsp;In addition, recognizing the need for access to high-quality, fair, and transparent financing for United States exporters and foreign buyers, the Congress also reauthorized the Export-Import Bank of the United States (EXIM) for 7 years in 2019. &nbsp;The EXIM&#8217;s reauthorization legislation also took steps to advance American leadership in transformational exports, which can include support for goods and services necessary for open, secure, reliable, and interoperable information and communications technology.</p>



<p>The United States and its partners have a long history of providing high-quality financing and technical support for infrastructure projects throughout the world. &nbsp;However, the lack of a comprehensive approach for coordinating infrastructure investments with like-minded partners often leads to inefficiencies and missed opportunities for coordinated investments to deliver at scale. &nbsp;Greater flexibility, speed, and resources, combined with expanded internal coordination within the United States Government, will provide opportunities for the United States Government and United States companies to better meet the infrastructure needs of low- and middle-income countries around the world. &nbsp;At the same time, greater coordination with G7 and other like-minded partners will increase efficiency and catalyze new financing to advance a shared vision of values driven, high-quality, and sustainable infrastructure around the world.</p>



<p>Four key priorities relating to infrastructure will be especially critical for robust development in the coming decades: &nbsp;climate and energy security, digital connectivity, health and health security, and gender equality and equity. &nbsp;Economic prosperity and competitiveness will largely be driven by how well countries harness their digital and technology sectors and transition to clean energy to provide environmentally sustainable and broadly shared, inclusive growth for their people. &nbsp;Countries not only will need new and retrofitted infrastructure, secure clean energy supply chains, and secure access to critical minerals and metals to facilitate energy access and transitions to clean energy, but also will need significant investments in infrastructure to make communities more resilient to diverse threats, from pandemics to malicious cyber actors, to the increasing effects of climate change. &nbsp;Further, the COVID-19 pandemic has highlighted the unequal infrastructure needs in the developing world and has disproportionately affected low- and middle-income countries and regions, particularly with respect to the health sector. &nbsp;In the developing world, the pandemic has also set back the economic participation of women and members of underserved communities and has reversed decades of progress toward ending poverty, with global extreme poverty rising for the first time in more than 20 years due to COVID 19. &nbsp;The pandemic has highlighted the need for expanded investments in and high-quality financing for strengthened health systems to both fight the current pandemic and prepare for future health crises.</p>



<p>It is therefore the policy of the United States to catalyze international infrastructure financing and development through the PGII, which is designed to offer low- and middle-income countries a comprehensive, transparent, values-driven financing choice for infrastructure development to advance climate and energy security, digital connectivity, health and health security, and gender equality and equity priorities. &nbsp;The PGII will mobilize public and private resources to meet key infrastructure needs, while enhancing American competitiveness in international infrastructure development and creating good jobs at home and abroad. &nbsp;In this effort, the United States is working in close partnership with G7 and other like-minded partners toward infrastructure financing and infrastructure development that are sustainable, clean, resilient, inclusive, and transparent, and that adhere to high standards.</p>



<p>Sec. 2. &nbsp;Approach. &nbsp;In order to meet the enormous infrastructure needs in the developing world, a new approach to international infrastructure development that emphasizes high-standards investment is needed. &nbsp;To meet this challenge and seize this opportunity, the PGII should:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (a) &nbsp;partner with low- and middle-income countries to finance infrastructure across key sectors that advances the four key priorities critical to sustainable, inclusive growth: &nbsp;climate and energy security, digital connectivity, health and health security, and gender equality and equity;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (b) &nbsp;promote the execution of projects in a timely fashion in consultation and partnership with host countries and local stakeholders to meet their priority needs and opportunities, balancing both short- and longer-term priorities;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (c) &nbsp;pursue the dual goals of advancing prosperity and surmounting global challenges, including the climate crisis, through the development of clean, climate-resilient infrastructure that drives job creation, accelerates clean energy innovation, and supports inclusive economic recovery;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (d) &nbsp;support the policy and institutional reforms that are key to creating the conditions and capacity for sound projects and lasting results and to attracting private financing;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (e) &nbsp;boost the competitiveness of the United States by supporting businesses, including small- and medium-sized enterprises in overseas infrastructure and technology development, thereby creating jobs and economic growth here at home;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (f) &nbsp;advance transparency, accountability, and performance metrics to allow assessment of whether investments and projects deliver results and are responsive to country needs, are financially sound, and meet a high standard;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (g) &nbsp;mobilize private capital from both the United States private sector and the private sector in partner countries;&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (h) &nbsp;build upon relationships with international financial institutions, including the multilateral development banks (MDBs), to mobilize capital;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (i) &nbsp;focus on projects that can attract complementary private-sector financing and catalyze additional market activity to multiply the positive impact on economies and communities;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (j) &nbsp;coordinate sources of bilateral and multilateral development finance to maximize the ability to meet infrastructure needs and facilitate the implementation of high standards for infrastructure investment;</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (k) &nbsp;uphold high standards for infrastructure investments and procurement, which safeguard against bribery and other forms of corruption, better address climate risks and risks of environmental degradation, promote skills transfer, generate good jobs, mitigate risks to vulnerable populations, and promote long-term economic and social benefits for economies and communities; and</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (l) &nbsp;align G7 and other like-minded partners to coordinate our respective approaches, investment criteria, expertise, and resources on infrastructure to advance a common vision and better meet the needs of low- and middle-income countries and regions.</p>



<p>Sec. 3. &nbsp;Execution. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;A whole-of-government approach is necessary to meet the challenge of international infrastructure development, with executive departments and agencies (agencies) working together with like minded partners. &nbsp;The Special Presidential Coordinator for the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment shall be responsible for overseeing the whole-of-government execution of these efforts and serving as the central node for United States coordination among the G7, as well as with other like-minded partners, the private sector, and other external actors. &nbsp;While specific lines of effort and initiatives may each have agency leads, such as on sourcing critical minerals or identifying trusted 5G and 6G vendors, whole-of-government policies should be addressed through the Coordinator.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (b) &nbsp;Agencies shall, consistent with applicable law and available appropriations, prioritize support for the PGII and make strategic investments across the PGII&#8217;s key priorities of climate and energy security, digital connectivity, health and health security, and gender equality and equity.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (c) &nbsp;The PGII shall be executed through the following key implementation efforts:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (i) &nbsp; &nbsp; The Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs (APNSA), through the interagency process identified in National Security Memorandum 2 of February 4, 2021 (Renewing the National Security Council System) (NSM-2), shall submit a report to the President within 180 days of the date of this memorandum. &nbsp;The report shall include recommendations on United States Government actions to boost the competitiveness of the United States in international infrastructure development, and to improve coordination on international infrastructure development across relevant agencies.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (ii) &nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), and the heads of other relevant agencies shall prioritize programming consistent with the policy and approach described in sections 1 and 2 of this memorandum to support timely delivery of international infrastructure development, particularly across the PGII&#8217;s four key priorities, as appropriate and consistent with their respective authorities. &nbsp;The Chief Executive Officer (CEO) of MCC, the CEO of DFC, the President of EXIM, the Director of the Trade and Development Agency (TDA), and the heads of other relevant independent agencies are encouraged to follow this same line of effort, as appropriate and consistent with their respective authorities.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (iii) &nbsp; The Secretary of State shall direct Chiefs of Mission to use all appropriate tools and to develop coordination mechanisms –– including through Embassy Deal Teams –– to address host country strategic infrastructure needs within the PGII&#8217;s four key priority areas.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (iv) &nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of USAID, the CEO of MCC, the CEO of DFC, the President of EXIM, and the Special Presidential Coordinator, shall develop a strategy for using Embassy Deal Teams to identify potential priority infrastructure projects for the PGII and refer promising opportunities to relevant agencies for consideration, based on each agency&#8217;s strengths and authorities.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (v) &nbsp; &nbsp; The Secretary of State, through the Special Presidential Coordinator and in consultation with the heads of other relevant agencies, shall coordinate diplomatic engagements to expand the PGII beyond the G7 to bring greater resources and opportunities for partnership.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (vi) &nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of State, through the Special Presidential Coordinator and in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Administrator of USAID, the CEO of MCC, and the CEO of DFC, shall lead interagency efforts regarding international coordination on infrastructure development standards and metrics, including on labor and environment, and certification mechanisms, including through the Blue Dot Network.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (vii) &nbsp; The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the President of EXIM, the Director of TDA, and the Special Presidential Coordinator, shall develop and implement a strategy to boost the competitiveness of the United States and promote the use of United States equipment and services in international infrastructure development.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (viii) &nbsp;The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the CEO of MCC, the CEO of DFC, and the Special Presidential Coordinator, shall develop and implement a strategy to catalyze private-sector investment and support low- and middle income countries across the PGII&#8217;s four key priority areas.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (ix) &nbsp; &nbsp;The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Administrator of USAID, and the Special Presidential Coordinator shall develop a plan for engaging the MDBs to foster high-quality infrastructure investment and increased private-capital mobilization for low- and middle-income countries, and shall coordinate with like-minded partners in the plan&#8217;s execution. &nbsp;The CEO of DFC, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Administrator of USAID, and the Special Presidential Coordinator, is encouraged to develop a plan to enhance engagement with national and international development finance institutions to increase private-capital mobilization.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (x) &nbsp; &nbsp; The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the heads of other relevant agencies, shall develop and implement a strategy to promote high-quality, sustainable, and resilient transportation infrastructure in low- and middle-income countries, including through the launch of a comprehensive toolkit for national, subnational, and multilateral partners that emphasizes best practices in planning, finance, project delivery, safety, and maintenance.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (xi) &nbsp; &nbsp;The APNSA, through the interagency process identified in NSM-2 and in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall identify potential legislative and administrative actions that could improve the ability of United States economic development and assistance, development finance, and export credit tools to meet international infrastructure development needs.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (xii) &nbsp; The APNSA, through the interagency process identified in NSM-2, shall lead biannual reviews to monitor the progress, metrics, and outcomes of the PGII&#8217;s investments and projects; identify strategic opportunities across the PGII&#8217;s four key priorities; and ensure that the execution of the PGII aligns with, and supports, broader strategic United States national security and economic objectives and values, including by supporting United States companies in international infrastructure development.</p>



<p>Sec. 4. &nbsp;Definition. &nbsp;For purposes of this memorandum, &#8220;agency&#8221; means any authority of the United States that is an &#8220;agency&#8221; under 44 U.S.C. 3502(1), other than one considered to be an independent regulatory agency, as defined in 44 U.S.C. 3502(5). &nbsp;&#8220;Agency&#8221; also means any component of the Executive Office of the President.</p>



<p>Sec. 5. &nbsp;General Provisions. &nbsp;(a) &nbsp;Nothing in this memorandum shall be construed to impair or otherwise affect:</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (i) &nbsp; the authority granted by law to an executive department or agency, or the head thereof; or</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (ii) &nbsp;the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (b) &nbsp;This memorandum shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (c) &nbsp;This memorandum is not intended to, and does not, create any right or benefit, substantive or procedural, enforceable at law or in equity by any party against the United States, its departments, agencies, or entities, its officers, employees, or agents, or any other person.</p>



<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; (d) &nbsp;The Secretary of State is authorized and directed to publish this memorandum in the Federal Register.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden and G7 Leaders Formally Launch the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and&#160;Investment</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/26/fact-sheet-president-biden-and-g7-leaders-formally-launch-the-partnership-for-global-infrastructure-and-investment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment will deliver game-changing projects to close the infrastructure gap in developing countries, strengthen the global economy and supply chains, and advance U.S. national security  President Biden will announce new flagship projects and lay out the Administration&#8217;s comprehensive effort to execute the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment. At the 2021 G7&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment</em> <em>will deliver game-changing projects to close the infrastructure gap in developing countries, strengthen the global economy and supply chains, and advance U.S. national security </em><br> <br><em>President Biden will announce new flagship projects and lay out the Administration&#8217;s comprehensive effort to execute the Partnership for Global Infrastructure and Investment.</em></p>



<p>At the 2021 G7 Summit, President Biden and G7 leaders announced their intent to develop a values-driven, high-impact, and transparent infrastructure partnership to meet the enormous infrastructure needs of low- and middle-income countries and support the United States’ and its allies’ economic and national security interests. Over the past year, members of the Administration have traveled to hear directly from countries on how we can meet their infrastructure needs, deepened our coordination across the U.S Government and with the G7, honed our infrastructure investment tools, and closed game-changing deals.<br> <br>At the G7 Leaders’ Summit in Schloss Elmau, Leaders will formally launch the <strong>Partnership for Global Infrastructure (PGII) </strong>to mobilize hundreds of billions of dollars and deliver quality, sustainable infrastructure that makes a difference in people’s lives around the world, strengthens and diversifies our supply chains, creates new opportunities for American workers and businesses, and advances our national security.<br> <br><strong>Today, President Biden will announce that the U.S. aims to mobilize $200 billion for PGII over the next 5 years through grants, Federal financing, and leveraging private sector investments.</strong> Together with G7 partners, we aim to mobilize $600 billion by 2027 in global infrastructure investments. And this will only be the beginning. The United States and its G7 partners will seek to mobilize additional capital from other like-minded partners, multilateral development banks, development finance institutions, sovereign wealth funds, and more.<br> <br><strong>President Biden will release a Presidential Memorandum to execute the PGII across four priority pillars that will define the second half of the 21<sup>st</sup> century.</strong><br><br>This includes:</p>



<ul><li>Tackling the climate crisis and bolstering global energy security through investments in climate resilient infrastructure, transformational energy technologies, and developing clean energy supply chains across the full integrated lifecycle, from the responsible mining of metals and critical minerals; to low-emissions transportation and hard infrastructure; to investing in new global refining, processing, and battery manufacturing sites; to deploying proven, as well as innovative, scalable technologies in places that do not yet have access to clean energy.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Developing, expanding, and deploying secure information and communications technology (ICT) networks and infrastructure to power economic growth and facilitate open digital societies—from working with trusted vendors to provide 5G and 6G digital connectivity, to supporting access to platforms and services that depend upon an open, interoperable, secure, and reliable internet and mobile networks with sound cybersecurity.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Advancing gender equality and equity—from care infrastructure that increases opportunities for economic participation by women, to improved water and sanitation infrastructure that addresses gender gaps in unpaid work and time use – in order to boost the global economic recovery by ensuring that half the population is not forced to sit on the sidelines.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>Developing and upgrading the infrastructure of health systems and contributing to global health security through investments in patient-centered health services and the health workforce; vaccine and other essential medical product manufacturing; and disease surveillance and early warning systems, including safe and secure labs. Addressing the current pandemic and preventing and preparing for the next one is crucial to U.S. economic and national security.</li></ul>



<p><strong>President Biden will announce flagship projects of PGII, </strong><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/06/Other-PGII-projects.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">along with additional projects that have been undertaken over the past year.</a><strong> PGII will demonstrate how millions of dollars can mobilize tens or hundreds of millions in further investments and tens or hundreds of millionscan mobilize billions.</strong></p>



<ul><li>With support from the U.S. Department of Commerce and the Export-Import Bank of the United States (EXIM), U.S. firm AfricaGlobal Schaffer (Washington, DC), in collaboration with U.S. project developer Sun Africa (Miami, FL), signed a contract with the Government of Angola to develop a $2 billion solar project in four southern Angola provinces. The project will include solar mini-grids, solar cabins with telecommunications capabilities, and home power kits. In addition to supporting up to $1.3 million in U.S. exports, the project will help Angola meet their climate commitments, including generating 70% carbon-free power by 2025.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>In collaboration with G7 members as well as the European Union and multilateral organizations, the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation (DFC) is disbursing a $3.3 million technical assistance grant to Institut Pasteur de Dakar (IPD) for early-stage project development for an industrial-scale flexible multi-vaccine manufacturing facility in Senegal with potential annual capacity of millions of doses of COVID-19 and other vaccines, potentially using both viral vector and mRNA technologies. DFC’s grant is part of a $14 million grant financing package that also includes $3.3 million from the International Finance Corporation, $2 million from the Agence Française de Développement, and $5.2 million from the European Investment Bank (EIB). DFC, along with other development finance institutions, is currently evaluating a loan to support IPD’s expansion to supplement EIB’s recent announcement of a nearly $80 million sovereign loan financing package.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>U.S. telecommunications company SubCom (Eatontown, NJ), awarded a $600 million contract, to build the Southeast Asia–Middle East–Western Europe 6 submarine telecommunications cable that will connect Singapore to France through Egypt and the Horn of Africa. The submarine cable will stretch over 17,000 km and connect countries across the region with high-speed, reliable connectivity. The U.S. Government, including through the U.S. Department of State, Commerce’s Advocacy Center, EXIM, and the U.S. Trade and Development Agency’s (USTDA) commitment of nearly $4 million in additional capacity building to support five countries using SubCom’s technology, collectively helped secure the award of the construction and deployment of the undersea fiber optic cable for SubCom.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The U.S. Government with U.S. firm NuScale Power LLC (Tigard, OR) will provide $14 million in support for the Front-End Engineering and Design study for Romania’s deployment of a first-of-its-kind small modular reactor (SMR) plant. Building on U.S. Government efforts, including advocacy support from Commerce and technical assistance from State and USTDA, this investment is meant to mobilize a multi-billion-dollar effort and showcase U.S. ingenuity in the advanced nuclear sector, accelerate the clean energy transition, create thousands of jobs, and strengthen European energy security while upholding the highest standards for nuclear safety, security, and nonproliferation.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) will aim to commit up to $50 million over five years to the World Bank’s new global Childcare Incentive Fund – $200 million public-private partnership to address the gap in suitable childcare infrastructure; boost women’s employment opportunities, productivity and income, and broader economic growth; and promote human capital and early learning for children. Other partners include the Governments of Canada and Australia, the Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation, the Conrad N. Hilton Foundation, Echidna Giving, the Ford Foundation, the William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, and the LEGO Foundation.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>DFC will invest up to $25 million in the Uhuru Growth Fund I-A, which will provide needed growth capital to small-and medium-sized enterprises in West Africa – including women-led businesses. Some of the largest economies in Africa, including Nigeria, Ghana, and Cote d’Ivoire, are facing a shortage of growth capital. Uhuru has committed to investing at least 30 percent of capital in eligible portfolio companies that support DFC’s 2X women’s economic empowerment initiative, and over 40 percent of the Uhuru team members are women. In addition to U.S. support, like-minded partners are investing including $35 million from the German Development Finance Institution, $30 million from the European Investment Bank, and $15 million from British International Investment, among others. Through this investment, DFC expects to mobilize $78 million in private capital.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>The Digital Invest program will leverage $3.45 million in State and USAID funding to mobilize up to $335 million in investment capital for internet service providers and financial technology companies in Africa, Asia, and Latin America that use secure network equipment and advance competition and choice in emerging markets. This new blended finance program for fund managers and project developers through the Digital Connectivity and Cybersecurity Partnership will promote the growth of resilient, secure digital ecosystems in developing countries.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>USAID will invest $40 million in the Southeast Asia’s Smart Power Program to decarbonize and strengthen the region&#8217;s power system by increasing regional energy trade, accelerating the deployment of clean energy technologies, and actively engaging private sector leaders and key development partners in shared priorities. The program is expected to mobilize $2 billion in financing as a result of U.S. Government assistance, increase regional energy trade by five percent, and result in 2 gigawatts of advanced energy systems deployed.<br>&nbsp;</li><li>DFC will invest up to $30 million in&nbsp;<a>Omnivore Agritech and Climate Sustainability Fund 3,&nbsp;</a>an impact venture capital fund that invests in entrepreneurs building the future of agriculture, food systems, climate, and the rural economy in India.&nbsp;The Fund seeks to invest in companies that increase food security and promote both climate resilience and climate adaptation in India, as well as improve the profitability and agricultural productivity of smallholder farms.&nbsp;The Fund is targeting a $65 million first close in September 2022 and a final close in 2023 to reach its target capitalization of $130 million.&nbsp;Through this investment, DFC expects to mobilize $30 million in private capital.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</li><li>ABD group (Philadelphia, PA), a project development company, was awarded a $320 million healthcare infrastructure project to renovate or construct over 100 hospitals and clinics across Côte d’Ivoire and has already begun work on 10 locations. ABD Group credits the Memorandum of Understanding for commercial cooperation between the U.S. Government and the Government of Côte d’Ivoire with providing the necessary foundation of partnership for this deal to come to fruition. With the support of Commerce, the project has already received $160 million in closed financing with another $160 million nearing completion.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&nbsp;###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s First Day in&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/26/background-press-call-on-president-bidens-first-day-in-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 8:04 A.M. CEST MODERATOR:&#160; All right, so in the interest of time, we’re going to go ahead and get started.&#160; Thanks for your patience.&#160; Just some logistical things we were dealing with this morning. So we’re &#8212; thanks for coming.&#160; Thanks for joining the background call today.&#160; This call is on background, attributable&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>8:04 A.M. CEST<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; All right, so in the interest of time, we’re going to go ahead and get started.&nbsp; Thanks for your patience.&nbsp; Just some logistical things we were dealing with this morning.</p>



<p>So we’re &#8212; thanks for coming.&nbsp; Thanks for joining the background call today.&nbsp; This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And it&#8217;s to preview day one in Germany today.</p>



<p>So for your awareness, not for reporting, the speakers on the call are [senior administration official] and [senior administration official].&nbsp; They&#8217;re both going to just give some quick remarks at the top, and then we&#8217;re going to try to take as many questions as we can, given the time limitations that we&#8217;re going through today.</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re going to start with [senior administration official], and then we&#8217;ll go to [senior administration official].&nbsp; So, [senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thanks.&nbsp; Good morning, everybody.&nbsp; And welcome to Bavaria.&nbsp; Sorry for running a little bit late this morning; was getting through security on the way up to the Schloss.</p>



<p>The President is looking forward to kicking off his Europe trip with a meeting with the German Chancellor.&nbsp; The administration has been investing very heavily in our bilateral relationship with Germany since he took office, including engagements last summer with former Chancellor Merkel.&nbsp; And the President has developed a very close and effective working relationship with Chancellor Scholz, who took office&nbsp;on December 8th.</p>



<p>The President, just to remind, spoke to him two days after that and then hosted him for an Oval Office meeting in February.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve since had a number of bilateral calls, as well as broader calls with other transatlantic and G7 leaders, particularly around the crisis in Ukraine.&nbsp; So this meeting is going to provide a good opportunity to affirm the deep and enduring ties between our two countries.</p>



<p>In terms of the meeting agenda, expect that Russia and Ukraine are going to be at the top of the list, including our continued close coordination on the political and diplomatic front; ongoing conversation about the security assistance that we, as well as other allies and partners, are providing to Ukraine; financial supports; and as well as continued efforts on sanctions to impose economic costs on Russia.</p>



<p>But it&#8217;s a full agenda, as it is our bilateral relationship.&nbsp; So I would expect there will also be discussion of transatlantic defense issues, especially in anticipation of the NATO Summit, which we’ll be heading to from here.&nbsp; This meeting will be a good opportunity for them to check signals on the G7 under the German presidency, and given the next couple of days of meetings that we have here with the G7, and then also an opportunity to discuss our shared interest in a range of other global challenges, including climate change and energy.</p>



<p>I would expect that the President will be thanking Chancellor Scholz for his leadership of the G7 during what&#8217;s been a truly unprecedented time in Europe over the last number of months.</p>



<p>In addition to coordinating the G7 response on Ukraine, the President will undoubtedly recognize the Chancellor&#8217;s leadership on other shared challenges, including climate change and economic resilience.</p>



<p>Many of the priorities that Germany has chosen for its G7 dovetail very closely with the administration&#8217;s focus, including on issues such as health, climate, economic resilience, and COVID.</p>



<p>So let me leave it there for now on the bilateral side, and then happy to answer any other questions after [senior administration official] is done.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], over to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [moderator].&nbsp; So, after his bilateral meeting with Chancellor Scholz, the President will participate in the G7 Summit.&nbsp; The first session will be on the global economy.&nbsp; And I think you can expect that leaders will be focused on discussing some of the core problems that are at the top of mind for all of us across the board, things like energy security challenges, the food security challenge globally, the disruptions generally that are emanating from Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.</p>



<p>Even as the leaders, including President Biden, will be focused on the challenges and disruptions of the moment, while &#8212; we should also recognize that the U.S. is positioned to weather those challenges because of the strong economic leadership of President Biden and the policies and investments he is putting in place.</p>



<p>The President obviously passed historic rescue legislation last year, has achieved significant bipartisan infrastructure legislation.&nbsp; These have put the United States in a position both to respond to the crisis that the President inherited economically and put the United States in a strong position, as well as to invest in our resilience and ongoing economic strength looking ahead.</p>



<p>Of course, the President has also taken significant steps to address the energy crisis, including &#8212; including historic releases from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve, and rallying the world through intensive diplomacy to make that a coordinated action across a number of different partners globally.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important to note that it&#8217;s not just the United States that&#8217;s in a strong position to address the challenges and the headwinds that the globe faces, the G7 as a whole is collectively in a strong place.</p>



<p>The unemployment rate, to take one example, is as low across the G7 as a whole as it&#8217;s been at any time in the last 40 years.</p>



<p>So even as the United States, the G7 as a whole faces significant challenges, disruptions, headwinds as a result of Putin&#8217;s war, we should also recognize that the United States and the G7 are collectively in a strong position to address and manage those challenges.</p>



<p>I would expect that after the session on the global economy, you&#8217;ll hear leaders move on to talking about the ways in which we can help, in the G7, to invest in global infrastructure, in particular in the emerging and developing world.</p>



<p>That is going to be the topic of the second session that leaders meet around.&nbsp; Last year, G7 leaders agreed to explore offering positive alternatives to the infrastructure model that sell debt traps to low- and middle-income countries.&nbsp; That positive alternative from the G7 will also advance U.S. economic competitiveness and our national security.</p>



<p>You will hear how the President is moving forward this line of effort, along with announcements on new flagship product &#8212; projects.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll have a press call later on today that will offer more details on that effort, and not just the session that leaders will be having, but also the side events between the President and other leaders to announce those steps forward.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, the President and other G7 leaders will continue to work to hold Putin accountable.&nbsp; Today, the U.S. and the UK are announcing that G7 leaders will ban imports of Russian gold.&nbsp; The official announcement will come on Tuesday.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The U.S. has rallied the world in imposing swift and significant economic costs to deny Putin the revenue he needs to finance his war.&nbsp; In this case, gold, after energy, is the second-largest export for Russia and a source of significant revenue for Putin and Russia.</p>



<p>The United States Treasury will issue a determination to prohibit the import of new gold into the United States on Tuesday, which will further isolate Russia from the global economy by preventing its participation in the gold market.</p>



<p>So, between the session on the global economy, the session on global infrastructure and the side event, as well, of course, as the bilateral meeting that [senior administration official] spoke to, it&#8217;s going to be a very action-packed day here and one that the President is looking forward to.</p>



<p>I’ll go ahead and pause there and hand it back to [moderator] to take questions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if I said this, but just a reminder: This call is &#8212; the embargo on this call is going to lift after this call ends.</p>



<p>So if you have a question, could you just please raise your hand and I will do my best to get to as many as we can in the limited time that we have.&nbsp; So let&#8217;s go first to Sebastian Smith from AFP, please.</p>



<p>&nbsp;Sebastian, are you there?</p>



<p>&nbsp;[Senior administration official], can you still hear me?&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, I can hear you, [moderator].</p>



<p>&nbsp;MODERATOR:&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; So maybe Sebastian might be having some trouble, so let&#8217;s go to Tamara Keith from NPR.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tamara, can you unmute yourself, please?<br><br>Hey, Angela, are you making sure that people can unmute themselves?&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure what’s going on here.</p>



<p>Hey, guys, give us just one minute to figure out what’s going on.</p>



<p>&nbsp;Hey, Angela, were you able to fix people&#8217;s un-muting problem?</p>



<p>Guys, sorry.&nbsp; Just give us a couple of minutes.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Is that Tamara?</p>



<p>&nbsp;Q &nbsp; &nbsp;This is Tam, yes.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Okay, sorry.&nbsp; Okay, go ahead, Tam.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It&#8217;s a muting miracle.&nbsp; Thank you for taking my question.&nbsp; I know that you are announcing the gold export limitations.&nbsp; Are you expecting there to be anything on sanctions with regards to further punishing Russia?&nbsp; Or is this gold thing, sort of, the primary pushback on Russia out of the G7?</p>



<p>And just a quick question about the Global Infrastructure Partnership.&nbsp; The event is happening on the margins.&nbsp; Should we read anything into it being on the margins and not part of the main program, or not?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the first question, Tamara &#8212; this is [senior administration official] &#8212; I think you should expect to see a series of steps that are designed to increase pressure in an ongoing way on Putin and Russia.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>We think that the step forward that&#8217;s being taken with gold is a very important illustration of the additional steps that we expect to be taken now and in the weeks ahead.</p>



<p>This is a key export, a key source of revenue, a key alternative for Russia, in terms of their ability to transact in the global financial system.&nbsp; Taking this step cuts off that capacity and, again, is an ongoing illustration of the types of steps the G7 can take collectively to continue to isolate Russia and cut it off from the global economy.</p>



<p>To your second question, I would &#8212; I would say, you know &#8212; and we&#8217;ll have more to say about this later&nbsp;this afternoon&nbsp;in the background call &#8212; you know, what you&#8217;re going to see is leaders speaking together in one of the plenary sessions of the G7 to global infrastructure, to the global infrastructure challenge, to what the G7 can do to provide an alternative, to provide a high-road, transparent alternative for low- and middle-income countries around partnering in their common future and in infrastructure together.</p>



<p>You know, what&#8217;s going to happen after they leave that session where they speak privately about that initiative and that priority is to go join together to talk about formally launching this joint infrastructure partnership.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I think far from the margins, this is a moment when leaders are going to speak privately to this core priority.&nbsp; Then they&#8217;re going to join together to speak about the action that they&#8217;ve collectively taken since last year&#8217;s declaration of intent in Carbis Bay, and now what it means to launch this with a year&#8217;s worth of work under their belts and to take the steps forward from here.</p>



<p>So I think, again, far from being on the margins, this is a very, I think, compelling choreography that you&#8217;re going to see with leaders reviewing together privately the steps that have been taken and the steps they intend to take, and then to describe those steps to the world at a joint event.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great, thanks.&nbsp; And also just add on to [senior administration official]’s, it&#8217;s just &#8212; I would not read into it.&nbsp; This is just how G7 and other G20 and other summits work.&nbsp; There&#8217;s, like, the plenary sessions, and then everything else is a side event.&nbsp; So I wouldn&#8217;t read anything into it at all.<br><br>All right, I think &#8212; so the muting problem should be fixed.&nbsp; So, Sebastian Smith from AFP, can you hear us and can you ask your question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, can you hear me now?</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perfect.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; I’m out of the purgatory there.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I wanted to ask about the gold measure.&nbsp; Is there a reason that the other members of the G7 didn&#8217;t sign up to this, if I understand it right &#8212; the European ones.<br><br>And another question related: Given the way the Russians seem to have found a workaround on their oil exports, how confident is the U.S. that gold won&#8217;t find another, you know, an alternative route to going through London, for example?&nbsp; Like, say, could it go via South Africa instead?&nbsp; Is it going to become a smuggler’s delight?<br><br>Just lastly, (inaudible), again related, if you could zoom out, (inaudible) out the summit &#8212; and it’s (inaudible) needed to review their progress on this whole campaign.&nbsp; How do they see it going in terms of pressuring Russia?&nbsp; Because, if I remember, the very first briefing for you guys ever did on &#8212; when you first announced sanctions, the language was things like, you know, “we&#8217;re going to cripple the ruble,” and it was pretty much “bring the Russian economy to its knees.”&nbsp; That, obviously, hasn&#8217;t happened and neither has the war really slacked off.&nbsp; So, is there something more to this that we should be thinking about thinking about?&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So perhaps we’ll take the last question first.&nbsp; I think that the collective efforts the G7 has taken with (inaudible) sanctions, export controls, and other measures against Russia is having a dramatic effect on the Russian economy.&nbsp;<br><br>The Russian economy is expected to shrink by double digits this year, and that&#8217;s just looking at headline GDP.&nbsp; If you look at things like imports, those have fallen off a cliff, likely to decline this year by 40 percent or more.&nbsp; Those are very substantial changes in the underlying economic conditions of the Russian economy.&nbsp; And those dramatic changes are attributable to the actions the G7 has taken collectively.<br><br>The other thing I&#8217;d observe is: The sanctions effort is intended to be cumulative, not just in the moment.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re already seeing the extent to which sanctions are degrading the productive capacity of the Russian economy, particularly in sectors like technology, like defense, like other key important industries.<br><br>And those impacts only accumulate over time, such that Russia’s ability to produce, Russia’s ability to wage war are going to decline over time as a result of the collective steps that the G7 has taken.<br><br>With respect to your question on gold, I would say, you know, I think one of the ongoing focuses of the sanctions effort has been to identify places where Russia, where others are seeking to evade the steps that have been taken.&nbsp; This is an ongoing area of focus by the G7 and an ongoing place where the G7, the United States, other partners &#8212; where we take steps forward to block off areas where evasion risk is becoming more prominent.<br><br>And, in fact, I think one way of thinking about the measure on gold is: To the extent that so many other avenues, with respect to Russia&#8217;s ability to interact with the global financial system, have been cut off, taking this step on gold is just yet another way to block off paths between the Russian economy and the broader global financial system.&nbsp;<br><br>So we will continue to identify places where evasion is a risk, continue to take steps to block off those paths.&nbsp; And the measure on gold in some ways is, in fact, another step forward to block off ways that Russia might seek to engage with the financial system by virtue of all the other ways that have now been cut off to them.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; And, sorry, I lost service.&nbsp; [Senior administration official], you answered the question about whether &#8212; if the G7 announcing the gold thing on Tuesday?&nbsp; Right?<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yes, this is &#8212;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp; Correct.&nbsp;<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; You will &#8212;&nbsp; exactly.&nbsp; So the U.S. and the UK have &#8212; are announcing today, but &#8212; when the G7 takes steps collectively, and you&#8217;ll see that on Tuesday. This will be a &#8212; this will be a G7 principle that is articulated.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; All right, so we only have time for one more, unfortunately.&nbsp; So we&#8217;re going to go to Francesca Chambers from USA Today.&nbsp; Can you hear us?&nbsp; And can you ask your question, please?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I can.&nbsp; And I had difficulty at the beginning (inaudible) can attribute these before I get into the substance of the question?<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yeah, of course.&nbsp; So this is &#8212; this call is on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.” And the contents of the call embargo will lift after this call is over.&nbsp; Does that help?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; And we appreciate you having this, as always. However, it would facilitate greater public trust in our reporting if this information were attributable to named officials.&nbsp;<br><br>But again, as to the substance of the call, this question is for [senior administration official].&nbsp; The U.S. has unsuccessfully pushed the EU to enact a full embargo on Russian oil and gas.&nbsp; For what new incentive or new information is President Biden prepared to offer his counterparts this week to entice them to support the sanctions?&nbsp;<br><br>And then I have a second question.&nbsp; Are there any additional measures or steps that the U.S. is preparing to take to try to speed up getting grain out of Ukraine faster?&nbsp; Poland says that construction of the silos that President Biden proposed will take three to four months to build.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; On the first, what I would say is: In fact, this is a place where the G7 has taken significant steps forward.&nbsp; At this stage, each of &#8212; the United States, Canada, the United Kingdom, the EU &#8212; has taken steps to ban the importation of Russian oil into their economies.&nbsp; So, far from a measure of &#8212; far from (inaudible), of course, that’s what the G7 has taken together.&nbsp; At this stage, again, you know, the U.S., the EU, Canada, the UK have all taken steps to embargo imports of Russian oil.<br><br>To you second question around food security, around speeding the facilitation of grain exports from Ukraine: Obviously, this is something that G7 leaders are focused on.&nbsp; But the thing I would start by saying is: There is a reason that there is a crisis in global food markets, why there is a crisis of global food security, and that is Russia&#8217;s invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; This is their invasion, their blockade of Ukrainian ports, the inability of Ukrainian grain to reach global markets.&nbsp; This is why, at core, global food markets are under stress.&nbsp;<br><br>And G7 leaders are focused on what can be done to get that grain out of Ukraine, recognizing that that is &#8212; that is, at root, one of the key sources of this broader set of challenges.&nbsp; So, yes, I expect this to be a (inaudible) of discussions on the food security challenge (inaudible).<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, Francesca, for raising your point.&nbsp; You know, we’re endeavoring here to give you guys as many background and on-the-record opportunities as we can.&nbsp; And, of course, we&#8217;ll always try to do our best in that regard.&nbsp;<br><br>So as a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And the contents of this call &#8212; the embargo will lift after this call is over.<br><br>Thanks for bearing with us with the logistical problems in the beginning.&nbsp; Hopefully it&#8217;ll only (inaudible).<br><br>Thanks, guys.&nbsp; And talk to you later tonight.</p>



<p>8:31 A.M. CEST&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. on International Day in Support of Victims of&#160;Torture</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/26/statement-by-president-joseph-r-biden-jr-on-international-day-in-support-of-victims-of-torture-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Torture remains a moral stain on the world’s collective conscience. That is why today, 35 years after the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment came into effect, I am proud to re-affirm that the United States stands unequivocally against this barbaric act. As one of the original&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Torture remains a moral stain on the world’s collective conscience. That is why today, 35 years after the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment came into effect, I am proud to re-affirm that the United States stands unequivocally against this barbaric act. As one of the original drafters of the Convention, the United States remains committed to eradicating torture throughout the world.<br> <br>Any instance of torture is one too many, and yet every year countless victims suffer this brutal violation of their human rights and dignity. This year we have been shocked by the horrific acts committed by Russian forces in Ukraine, including multiple, credible reports of torture such as beatings, electric shocks, and mock executions. In Mali and Burkina Faso, terrorist groups have been documented to have massacred and tortured local populations, while in Mali and Central African Republic, Kremlin-aligned Wagner mercenaries have reportedly employed similar cruel and unlawful tactics. In the Americas, transnational crime organizations, including cartels and gangs, have been reported as torturing journalists, activists, and minorities, including LGBTQI+ individuals, as a tactic to sow fear and intimidation. In Burma, reports document security forces torturing and killing those who support democracy, including through electrocution, rape, and other forms of sexual violence. Each of these examples tears at our humanity.<br> <br>Today, I reaffirm the United States’ dedication to eliminating torture and supporting its victims. The United States has legally prohibited torture in all of its forms, without exception. We also remain the top contributor to the United Nations Voluntary Fund for Victims of Torture, which helps nearly 50,000 victims and their families receive medical, psychological, legal, social, and other assistance necessary to rebuild their lives. And this year, I submitted to Congress a budget that requests the largest ever funding amount for the U.S. Survivors of Torture Program in HHS’s Office of Refugee Resettlement.<br> <br>When a government commits torture, it surrenders its moral authority and undermines its own legitimacy. And, critically, when torture is committed in the name of national security, it only emboldens and multiplies enemies, fuels unrest, and leaves governments isolated internationally.<br> <br>Today, and every day, let us stand in solidarity with survivors of torture, while calling on all nations to end this inhuman practice.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Meeting with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/26/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-chancellor-olaf-scholz-of-germany-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 10:23:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56291</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany ahead of the G7 Leaders’ Summit. President Biden expressed appreciation for the Chancellor’s leadership of the G7, and the importance of coordinating responses to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, climate, and economic and democratic resilience. The leaders underlined their commitment to Ukraine’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany ahead of the G7 Leaders’ Summit. President Biden expressed appreciation for the Chancellor’s leadership of the G7, and the importance of coordinating responses to Russia’s further invasion of Ukraine, climate, and economic and democratic resilience. The leaders underlined their commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity, as well as their continued provision of military, economic, humanitarian, and diplomatic support to help Ukraine defend its democracy against Russian aggression. The leaders also discussed efforts to alleviate the impacts of Russia’s war in Ukraine on global food and energy security. The President welcomed Germany’s historic commitment to significantly boost defense spending and meet its NATO commitments, which will strengthen the Alliance’s long-term deterrence and defense posture. Finally, the leaders also discussed the challenges posed by China and our shared commitment to provide transparent and high-standard solutions to address global gaps in key infrastructure.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Chancellor Scholz of the Federal Republic of Germany Before Bilateral Meeting &#124; Krün,&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/26/remarks-by-president-biden-and-chancellor-scholz-of-the-federal-republic-of-germany-before-bilateral-meeting-krun-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56293</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[10:46 A.M. CEST&#160;CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&#160; So, it’s very good to have you here.&#160; (Inaudible) we can really do important things (inaudible) special time.&#160;PRESIDENT BIDEN:&#160; Well, there’s a lot to do.&#160; And I want to compliment you on stepping up as you did when you became chancellor and moving in the way that you &#8212; had a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>10:46 A.M. CEST<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; So, it’s very good to have you here.&nbsp; (Inaudible) we can really do important things (inaudible) special time.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; Well, there’s a lot to do.&nbsp; And I want to compliment you on stepping up as you did when you became chancellor and moving in the way that you &#8212; had a great impact on the rest of Europe to move, particularly as it related to Ukraine.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And you’re &#8212; you’re one of our fastest and closest allies in the world, and we got to make sure we have this &#8212; us all staying together.&nbsp; You know we’re going to continue working on the economic challenges we face, but I think we can get through all this &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; and come out stronger.<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; And the good message is that we all made it to stay united, which obviously Putin never expected.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; And that was in no small part because of you &#8212; no small part because of you.&nbsp; Seriously.&nbsp; Because there was a lot of discussion of whether or not, in the transition &#8212; how it was going to work.&nbsp; But you’ve done an incredible job.&nbsp; I want to thank you for it.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>We have to stay together &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Yeah.<br>&nbsp;<br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:&nbsp; &#8212; because Putin has been counting on, from the beginning, that somehow NATO would &#8212; and the G7 would splinter.&nbsp; And &#8212; but we haven’t, and we’re not going to.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, we can’t let this aggression take the form it has and get away with it.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>CHANCELLOR SCHOLZ:&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>10:49 A.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre and NSC Coordinator for Strategic Communications John Kirby En Route Munich,&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/25/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-and-nsc-coordinator-for-strategic-communications-john-kirby-en-route-munich-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 18:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Munich, Germany 11:21 A.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Welcome to our trip to Europe &#8212; G7 and NATO. I’m going to pass it over to John Kirby, who is going to lay out what we’re going to be doing tomorrow and on this trip, and take any questions that you all&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Munich, Germany</p>



<p>11:21 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Welcome to our trip to Europe &#8212; G7 and NATO. I’m going to pass it over to John Kirby, who is going to lay out what we’re going to be doing tomorrow and on this trip, and take any questions that you all may have. And then he’ll depart and then I’ll take over and take whatever other questions you have.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Hey, everybody. Just a couple of things right at the top here.</p>



<p>Obviously, we’re all horrified by the mass shooting in Oslo today, targeting the LGBTQI+ community there. And our ho- &#8212; our hearts, obviously, go out to all the families of &#8212; of the victims; the people of Norway, which is a tremendous ally; and of course the LGBTQI+ community there and around the world, quite frankly. And we stand in solidarity with our close ally, Norway, and the community in Norway and all who have been devastated by this senseless act.</p>



<p>I do want to add that we’ve been in touch with the Norwegian government to offer our condolences and &#8212; and also to offer any support that they might need as they continue to investigate this.</p>



<p>Now, for the G7, just &#8212; I just want to go over tomorrow, just the broad brushstrokes. I know you guys have been informed on background about all the things that we’re going to be doing.</p>



<p>But the President has got a very busy day. Before the summit starts, he’ll have a bilateral meeting with German Chancellor Olaf Scholz. They&#8217;ll do a signals check before the summit, and they&#8217;ll continue to closely coordinate, as they have been, on supporting Ukraine, holding Russia accountable, and, of course, other important priorities between the two of us.</p>



<p>President Biden obviously appreciates Germany&#8217;s close partnership. They are a strong NATO Ally. You saw us all come together when it come to &#8212; when it came to putting in place significant sanctions against Russia, making Putin pay cons- &#8212; cons- &#8212; costs for his invasion, and, of course, providing security assistance to Ukraine. And Germany very recently, as you know, stepped up in providing lethal weapon systems to Ukraine. So they have been very, very important in that.</p>



<p>After that bilat, the President will participate in the actual summit. The first session is going to be focused on the global economy. And you can be sure that leaders are going to be talking about core problems that are on the top of mind for all of us across the board, like rising prices, supply chain disruptions, all exacerbated by this war in Ukraine and by Mr. Putin&#8217;s decision.</p>



<p>But we should also recognize the U.S. is positioned to weather these challenges because of the strong economic leadership in the United States &#8212; President Biden specifically &#8212; and the policies and investments that he is putting in place.</p>



<p>The second session of the day is going to be on global infrastructure. And right after that, the President and other G7 leaders will formally launch their Global Infrastructure Partnership.</p>



<p>As we said before, and I spoke about this from the podium the other day, the G7 leaders have agreed to explore, last year, an alternative to infrastructure models that sell debt traps to low- and middle-income partner countries, and advance U.S. economic competitiveness and our national security.</p>



<p>So you’ll hear about how the President is moving forward on that line of effort tomorrow, along with other announcements on some new flagship pro- &#8212; projects. I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of them specifically today.</p>



<p>So, again, a very full day for the first day in &#8212; in Germany. And the President is very much looking forward to it.</p>



<p>Q John, looking ahead to the rest of the trip, can you read out any other bilats the President is expected to have? Will he meet with President Erdoğan of Turkey, particularly as the NATO accession issue comes up later in the week?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I think you can expect that the President will have multiple bilateral discussions. I mean, obviously, he&#8217;s starting out with the Chancellor &#8212; German Chancellor tomorrow. But I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the schedule. And we&#8217;ll &#8212; we&#8217;ll let you know as they come up and, of course, read them out to you. But I don&#8217;t have anything specific with any other leader today to talk about.</p>



<p>Q And then in terms of the economic meeting, are you expecting any deliverables out of that, particularly as we’ve seen rising inflation in the United States and around the world? Any agreements from the G7 leaders on that?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: You know, I think you will see some announcements coming out of these meetings. Again, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the specifics here. But as I mentioned right at the top, I mean, a large focus of the G7 and the leaders are going to be, you know, how to not only manage the challenges in the global economy as a result of Mr. Putin&#8217;s war, but how to also continue to hold Mr. Putin accountable and to make sure that &#8212; that they&#8217;re &#8212; that he is &#8212; and he &#8212; that &#8212; that he is being subjected to cost and consequences for what he&#8217;s doing.</p>



<p>So there will be some announcements. There will be some &#8212; some muscle movements. But I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of that right now.</p>



<p>Q Hey, John, on &#8212; on the &#8212; another topic in the global economy session: China &#8212; which you guys have said there will be strong language condemning their non-market practices. Should we expect any deliverables there or any actions taken? Or will this be essentially just the G7 condemning what has been condemned many times before?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Well, again, without getting ahead of deliverables &#8212; you&#8217;re going to get tired of hearing me say that, but it’s true &#8212;</p>



<p>Q Will there be any deliverables?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: But, look, China will be a significant focus here for the G7, and the impact that China&#8217;s coercive, economic practices, use of forced labor, intellectual theft &#8212; all those are front and center for the nations of the G7. And I think you&#8217;re going to see China very much at the forefront as the G7 goes on. But I don’t &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of anything specific.</p>



<p>Q On &#8212; there is one thing you haven&#8217;t mentioned so far, which is climate change. Climate change is a big topic for the G7.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Yes.</p>



<p>Q But at the same time, so are rising energy costs. So how are you going to articulate those two, you know, challenges without watering down some climate commitments?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Well, there&#8217;s no watering down of climate commitments. I just talked about day one. I mean, climate is clearly going to be age- &#8212; on the agenda here at the G7. And the President has been a leader here on the search for clean energy solutions, because we&#8217;ve all seen, just in the last three months, the &#8212; the impact of &#8212; of reliance on fossil fuel and &#8212; and Russia&#8217;s weaponizing of that fossil fuel on &#8212; on the global economy.</p>



<p>Obviously, Americans are feeling this at home too, which is exactly why the President not only wants to, in the moment we&#8217;re in, hold Russia accountable for what he&#8217;s doing in Ukraine and try to find some relief &#8212; immediate relief. That&#8217;s why he pushed so hard and is an advocate for a federal gas tax holiday &#8212; to find some immediate relief &#8212; but also to move towards clean energy solutions that reduce the dependence on fossil fuel and reduce the dependence on Russia.</p>



<p>And so, even as we&#8217;re looking at long-term clean energy solutions, we&#8217;re also doing all we can to increase supply globally of things like natural gas and &#8212; and oil.</p>



<p>Q German Chancellor Scholz has signaled that he wants to roll back the G7’s commitment to end investment in fossil fuels overseas. Is that something that the United States would support on a temporary basis?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Yeah, I &#8212; I’m not going to get ahead of the discussions here at the G7. Our position last May was &#8212; and the President was clear &#8212; that &#8212; that he &#8212; he did not feel like these &#8212; these investments were the right course of action. I know of no such change to that policy.</p>



<p>Q And on the infrastructure initiative that&#8217;s clearly aimed at countering China&#8217;s Belt and Road Initiative, which is quite large in volume, do you have dollar figure in mind for how much you can &#8212; how much, you know, the United States and other allies can produce in terms of infrastructure?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I think you&#8217;ll hear more about this as the G7 goes on. And tomorrow is the day that they&#8217;re going to get together and talk about the global infrastructure partnership.</p>



<p>Again, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President here. But there are &#8212; I think you can expect them to explore a range of different opportunities and initiatives to allow low- and middle-income countries to address their own infrastructure and development problems better. And it&#8217;ll be a range; it&#8217;ll be a mix of federal funding, as well &#8212; as well as grants, as well as private-sector investments.</p>



<p>Again, I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the President, but I do think you&#8217;ll &#8212; tomorrow you&#8217;ll be able to get a much clearer picture of just how many opportunities there are and how many &#8212; how much resour- &#8212; how much resource &#8212; how many resources &#8212; let me try that again &#8212; G7 leaders are going to be willing to apply to that problem.</p>



<p>Q Can I follow up on the GIP and then move us over to the Mideast? So, first of all, on the GIP, the Global Infrastructure Partnership, what is the difference between that and Build Back Better World, other than the name? Are there any tangible differences?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: This is a months-long effort here by the administration to work with leaders around the world to try to come up with, again, more innovative and creative alternatives for these low- and middle-income countries to foster their own economic development and their infrastructure needs.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re much less worried about what it&#8217;s called than we are about what it does for these countries.</p>



<p>Q On Iran, Josep Borrell says talks might begin in, quote, “coming days.” Do we know when that might happen? And now that Iran is enriching uranium, are you worried that this round of talks might be like a make-or-break?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Well, we still &#8212; we still believe in getting back into the JCPOA. And I can&#8217;t speak to the status of where the negotiations are right now, but there&#8217;s &#8212; nothing has changed about our position that a nuclear deal is the best way to prevent Iran from achieving nuclear weapons status. And we want to get them back into compliance.</p>



<p>Q And then finally, on the Mideast trip, is Saudi-Israeli normalization a goal of this trip? And if so, what does that roadmap look like?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: Let&#8217;s not get ahead of ourselves. That trip is not until next month. But the United States has been very clear that we support normalization between Israel and Arab countries in the region, that these are obviously discussions that these sovereign nations have to have, but we&#8217;re fully in support of the Abraham Accords and normalization efforts.</p>



<p>Q John, on Chinese &#8212; on the Chinese buying Russian oil and gas, will there be any discussion of that at the G7? And will there be any sort of acknowledgement of concern that President Putin still seems to be able to fund his war machine?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I think a big focus tomorrow is going to be &#8212; at least the first session &#8212; dedicated to the global economic issues here caused by the war in Ukraine.</p>



<p>And again, without getting ahead of ourselves here, I think leaders are going to be looking for ways to do two things: one, continue to hold Mr. Putin accountable and to increase the costs and consequences of his war on him and his economy; and, two, minimizing as much as possible the effect of these rising oil prices and the way he has weaponized energy on nations, particularly on the continent but also around the world.</p>



<p>Q India is also participating at the invitation of Germany. India is another one of the countries that is purchasing cheap Russian oil. Is there &#8212; are you at all &#8212; you know, are you seeing any movement on the part of India to sort of be more supportive of the global effort to hold Putin accountable?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: We’re glad that India is coming. There’s lots to discuss on the agenda with India. We have a very deep partnership with them, even in the defense world.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ll let Indian leaders speak for themselves here, but obviously, what President Biden is focused on, what the administration is focused on is making sure that the costs keep rising for Mr. Putin, that it&#8217;s harder for him to wage war. And obviously, we want to see all nations participate in those kinds of efforts.</p>



<p>Q John, we know this is coming on the heels of the Dobbs decision. You know, Macron, Trudeau both put out statements. The Secretary of State put out a statement. Obviously, there&#8217;s interest outside of America in this decision. Is the President worried at all that this is going to take away or overshadow at all the G7? And what&#8217;s his message going to be to leaders that are wondering what, you know, America is doing in that decision?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: The President is not worried about that at all. There is, as I just said, just on day one alone &#8212; I mean, there is a robust agenda of issues here to talk about at the G7 and then follow on at the NATO Summit.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s real national security issues here that have to be discussed. And the President is not at all concerned that that the Supreme Court&#8217;s decision is going to take away from that at all.</p>



<p>And I think his message to leaders around the world is exactly the same message that he gave to the American people yesterday.</p>



<p>Q Can I go back to Russian oil for a second, though? That price cap on Russian oil that Secretary Yellen has been negotiating or pushing for &#8212; I know you don&#8217;t want to get ahead of deliverables, but maybe you can give us a hint of how confident you are that the leaders will endorse &#8212; all the leaders, because there was some, you know, holdouts &#8212; all leaders will endorse this at the summit.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I think what I can tell you is that all leaders are &#8212; we believe all leaders are going to be committed to those two things that I mentioned before: one, continuing to hold Mr. Putin accountable and make it even more painful for him to prosecute this war, as well as looking for ways to minimize the effect of rising oil prices and the profits that Mr. Putin continues to get from those oil prices on other nations around the world, including the United States.</p>



<p>Q John, are you satisfied with the amount of weapons that countries that have stocks of older-generation weapons have been giving to Ukraine? I mean, the U.S. is drawing down its stocks of weapons that can be transferred to Ukraine, on which they can be trained, but other countries have more stocks.</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: So, a couple of things there. Two weeks ago, the Secretary of Defense held another Ukraine Contact Group, this time in Brussels &#8212; 50 nations. That&#8217;s the most that we&#8217;ve ever done, and we&#8217;ve had three iterations. Fifty nations showed up &#8212; not just from Europe, not just NATO Allies, but from around the world &#8212; Middle East and the Indo-Pacific.</p>



<p>And a large number of those nations are contributing security assistance, weapons, to Ukraine. Now, they&#8217;re doing what they can. Every nation has to make a decision about what they can afford to provide because they have their own national security needs. But I think &#8212; you know, I&#8217;d point you back to what Secretary Austin said at the end of that. I mean, it was impressive to see how many nations are willing to pull down from their own inventories or even to contract for additional systems.</p>



<p>Now, look, in the very early weeks of the war, there was a significant and, I think, right focus on making sure that Ukraine was getting systems that they were trained on, knew how to use, had them in their inventory already &#8212; ex-Soviet stuff. There&#8217;s still a need for that. I mean, they still are using those systems.</p>



<p>And so, Secretary Austin is &#8212; why he’s doing the Contact Group is to continue to talk to nations around the world to see what else they can provide.</p>



<p>But also now, because the war is now stretched into its third month, it&#8217;s becoming much more about artillery in the Donbas, the long-range fires. The United States has been willing to step up and provide other Western or American systems to Ukraine, to allow them to carry on in the Donbas. And that requires a little bit of training, right? That means you got to take some Ukrainian soldiers out of the fight.</p>



<p>So we want to make sure that we strike the right balance here, that they&#8217;re getting systems that they&#8217;re used to as well as systems that they need, without unnecessarily decrementing their combat readiness in the field.</p>



<p>But every nation that&#8217;s providing stuff, they&#8217;ve got to do it in accordance with their own national security interests as well. And I would say the short answer to your question is: Yes. We&#8217;re impressed, we&#8217;re grateful, we&#8217;re satisfied that nations around the world, not just &#8212; not just in the region, are coming forward and providing Ukraine as much as they can.</p>



<p>And there&#8217;s &#8212; and look, this is going to be an iterative, ongoing conversation. We&#8217;re going to continue to have these contact groups. We&#8217;re going to continue to talk to nations. We&#8217;re obviously going to continue to talk to Ukrainians about what they need every day.</p>



<p>Q A question on natural gas, maybe. Gazprom has started reducing its supply to Europe and Germany. And Germany has warned that it could, you know, interfere with their plans to replenish the reserve before winter.</p>



<p>So, two questions. First, do you believe the Russians when they say this is &#8212; this cuts are for technical reasons? And second question: Is there anything the United States can do right now or in the coming weeks to help the Europeans?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I won&#8217;t &#8212; well, on the first question, we think this is just a piece of Mr. Putin’s willingness to weaponize now energy. And I don&#8217;t think we take any Russian claim at face value here with respect to what&#8217;s going on.</p>



<p>And I &#8212; again, I think &#8212; I won&#8217;t get ahead of where we&#8217;re going on G7, but, clearly, alternative energy is going to be on the docket here for the next couple of days.</p>



<p>I got to go. I’m going to let Karine finish.</p>



<p>Q John, (inaudible) food security?</p>



<p>Q A follow-up on landmines?</p>



<p>Q Food security obviously a huge &#8212; food security &#8212; getting the grain out. Are you expecting any &#8212; what’s the nature of the conversations between the U.S. government and Russian counterparts about trying to secure ways of getting that grain out? Does that place at the U.N.? Is that taking place bilaterally?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: So, I know of no bilateral discussions with the Russians on food security. But we are obviously &#8212; it will be on the agenda here at the G7. We’re working very hard with allies and partners to try to get that grain out of Ukraine. We’ve been able to increase shipments of it through the West by rail. But, obviously, that&#8217;s not the most efficient way to do this. It&#8217;s a perishable commodity.</p>



<p>We&#8217;d like to see the blockade, which is essentially in place by the Russians in the Black Sea, lifted. We know that Turkey is talking to Russia about some options there. We welcome those efforts.</p>



<p>But, you know, it&#8217;s &#8212; it&#8217;s very much on President Biden’s mind.</p>



<p>Q A landmine question. Just very quickly: With the U.S. &#8212; the new U.S. policy on landmines, does this change the weapons that are going to be sent to Ukraine? Because you were sending a number of Claymore mines. And are you satisfied that those munitions have been used responsibly and in accordance with the law by Ukrainian soldiers?</p>



<p>MR. KIRBY: I know of no shipments of U.S. Claymore mines to Ukraine. But separate and distinct, the Claymore mines are not covered by the Ottawa Convention because they have to be triggered with a person. They’re &#8212; they’re &#8212; the way they&#8217;re constructed is they have to be manually triggered by an operator, so they are not subject to the Ottawa Convention.</p>



<p>Okay? Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>Q Thank you.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: All right. I don&#8217;t have anything else. I don&#8217;t have anything as a topper, so shoot away. Go.</p>



<p>Q Karine, the White House has talked a lot in the last six months, longer, about preparing for the fall of Roe. On the Supreme Court ruling yesterday, the President didn&#8217;t announce any executive actions. He didn&#8217;t announce any specific plans or proposals on his part to try to protect women&#8217;s rights to abortion, both &#8212; so, why is there a seeming lack of urgency from the President on this issue?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So, I &#8212; Zeke, I have to tell you, I disagree with the premise of your question there. There’s been a lot of urgency from this President and from this White House on how &#8212; on the next steps of &#8212; especially now that we know that the decision was made yesterday.</p>



<p>Look, the President &#8212; two hours after we learned about the decision, the President gave a &#8212; gave remarks &#8212; powerful, passionate remarks to the American public and laid out two concrete steps on how to move forward &#8212; how to move forward and really fight for women&#8217;s rights and women&#8217;s freedom.</p>



<p>And those two concrete steps that he laid out &#8212; one had to deal with HHS and making sure that we make FDA-approved medication available to women and protect that right; the other one was he gave his executive authority to the Department of Justice to make sure that we defend women who travel to &#8212; as they make decisions on their own healthcare.</p>



<p>And those two are very concrete, big steps. I know those &#8212; that&#8217;s using his executive authority. I know people are asking about executive actions. The President is going to continue to find solutions. He&#8217;s going to continue to talk to leading groups. He&#8217;s going to continue to talk to legal experts on what he can do from his &#8212; you know, his own executive perch, if you will.</p>



<p>And so that&#8217;s going to &#8212; the conversation is going to continue to happen. That&#8217;s not going to stop.</p>



<p>I do want to share what the group &#8212; the offices are in the White House and who&#8217;s been involved with this, because it&#8217;s been around-the-clock type of response in looking into how to move forward.</p>



<p>So, the White House senior officials, including from the Gender Policy Council, Office of Public Engagement, Office of Intergovernmental Affairs, Office of Political Strategy and Outreach, and the Office of the Vice President engage in dozens of formal meetings and private conversations on reproductive rights with over 200 stakeholders, including the leadl- &#8212; leading national organizations fighting to protect women&#8217;s constitutional right to keep her &#8212; her healthcare decisions to herself and doctors.</p>



<p>We have met with patients, medical providers, policy and legal experts, as I just mentioned, women&#8217;s rights groups and reproductive rights advocates, state legislators, faith leaders, political figures, and private sectors. And we have been doing that since we learned about the leaked document.</p>



<p>So, this has been a priority for this administration. And we will continue to see what else we can do.</p>



<p>Q Karine, just to follow up on that real quick: The challenge of that &#8212; the President yesterday announced that the administration will fight for those things &#8212; traveling across state lines and the FDA-approved medication for abortion &#8212; except, right now, in a number of states, those actions are punishable by civil or lega- &#8212; or criminal penalties, depending on the specific states and if the law is there.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s not &#8212; does the President believe that his sort of saying that HHS or the Department of Justice will fight for it means these women should do it? If women were to take those drugs right now, (inaudible) if somebody were to help them travel across state lines in some states, that could expose them to significant liability today. What’s the President doing to protect them right now?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So that’s why he’s asked the Department of Justice to step in. Look, this is not &#8212;</p>



<p>Q (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So, you know, state laws restricting the right to travel will undoubtedly be challenged &#8212; right? &#8212; in court. So that is &#8212; we understand. So, the DOJ will look to support the right to travel in appropriate cases.</p>



<p>Look, the Attorney General’s statement yesterday made it clear that the &#8212; that bedrock of constitutional principles support women’s freedom to seek care in states where abortion remains legal. So, they &#8212; they are going to step in where they can to defend women who may have to make decisions for themselves &#8212; should be making decisions for theirselves on their health.</p>



<p>So that is the executive authority that the President used, and that is what the Department of Justice laid out in a very long statement that they did yesterday on how they’re going to go about that.</p>



<p>Look, this is &#8212; you know, this is a scary time. We understand that. What happened yesterday with the decision from the Supreme Court is un- &#8212; is extreme. That decision is extreme.</p>



<p>This is about a constitutional right that was provided by the Supreme Court almost 50 years ago. And &#8212; and it was done &#8212; the judge that wrote that decision almost 50 years ago &#8212; it was a 7-2 decision &#8212; that was done by a judge who was appointed by President Nixon.</p>



<p>So, this &#8212; this constitutional right has been around, you know, with Democratic presidents and Republican presidents. And the President understands that we got to continue to fight.</p>



<p>So, the other part that we are trying to say as well is, yes, the President can use executive authority. We can look to see what other &#8212; what executive action we can take.</p>



<p>But the reality is we have to get Congress to act to restore Roe, to make it law of the land.</p>



<p>And if that can&#8217;t happen, the American public has to use their voice. And in light of this decision, they have to use their voice at the ballot box. And this is how we can turn this around.</p>



<p>But yesterday, again, he laid out two concrete solutions &#8212; or two concrete steps, I should say &#8212; to move forward. And we&#8217;re going to continue to see what else we can do.</p>



<p>Q A lot of people watching this ruling are concerned that it could be a slippery slope leading to limited access to contraception and to other rights that &#8212; that Americans currently enjoy. Is the White House concerned about that? And if so, how are you preparing and what are you going to do?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: We are concerned about that. If you look at what &#8212; what Justice Thomas said &#8212; he wrote expli- &#8212; explicitly that “In future cases, we should reconsider all of this Court&#8217;s substantive due process precedents.”</p>



<p>So make no mistake: Congressional &#8212; congressional Republicans have &#8212; have made it clear; Republican leaders &#8212; national Republican leaders have made it clear they are going to go after &#8212; they&#8217;re going to go after women&#8217;s reproductive healthcare across the country and beyond. That&#8217;s what we heard from them yesterday.</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;re going to continue to stand up. We&#8217;re going to continue to fight against that. We&#8217;re going to continue to tell people to use their voice.</p>



<p>And so, look, the way that we &#8212; again, the way that we get to a solution here, the way that we get to really resolving this is for Congress to act.</p>



<p>Yes, the President is going to continue to look at solutions. He&#8217;s going to continue to figure out what else we can do, continue to talking to groups, getting that legal &#8212; legal expertise on what he can do from &#8212; from his executive authority.</p>



<p>But we have to make sure that &#8212; the American public has to make sure that they use their voice. And not only that, the decision that &#8212; that they made &#8212; the decision that the Court made on Roe v. Wade is out of step. It’s out of step with majority of the American public. A majority of the American public support Roe &#8212; support Roe v. Wade.</p>



<p>Q Karine, the President &#8212; you know, you talk about bringing the President out on the road, taking him on the road; he likes to connect with the American people. Will he dedicate some travel specifically to this issue, to reach out to young voters, to women who are outraged and &#8212; and frustrated? Where will he go? What are &#8212; you know, what are some of the messages that he could be bringing? And how soon could we see him start to take those kinds of trips?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I don&#8217;t have anything to read out to you specifically on a strategy &#8212; a strategic strategy around the decision that was made by the Court yesterday. But what I can say, and the President spoke about this very forcefully: He vehemently disagrees with the decision that the Court made yesterday.</p>



<p>He&#8217;s going to continue to fight for women&#8217;s rights. He&#8217;s going to continue to fight for freedom &#8212; for their freedom. And also, even when we heard the leaked decision &#8212; this is kind of to your question &#8212; a couple of weeks ago, he had warned that it wouldn&#8217;t &#8212; they would not just stop at women&#8217;s &#8212; women&#8217;s reproductive rights. He warned that.</p>



<p>And now, what we saw from Judge Thomas should be chilling. It should be very chilling to people. But this is an opportunity to take action. And that&#8217;s what the President did yesterday. He did a call to action for the American public.</p>



<p>Q (Inaudible) &#8212; I mean, I was asking about trips, travel. Any trips, travel?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I don&#8217;t have &#8212; I just don&#8217;t have anything to &#8212; to lay out for you at this time. Clearly, we&#8217;re going to the G7 and NATO. It&#8217;s going to be for the next five days. We&#8217;ll get back on Thursday. And ma- &#8212; hopefully after that, we&#8217;ll have more to share on specific travel. Just right now, I don&#8217;t have anything to lay out.</p>



<p>Q Karine, you just said that the decision of the Supreme Court does not reflect what the American &#8212; the majority of Americans want. And polls also show that, you know, the &#8212; the credibility of the &#8212; the opinion that Americans have after the Supreme Court is now very poor. So is it time, in the President&#8217;s view, to think about reforming the Court? And if so, what changes would he like to see?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So, I know I&#8217;ve &#8212; I’ve been asked &#8212; I was asked this question yesterday, and I&#8217;ve been asked it before &#8212; and I think the President himself &#8212; about doing &#8212; about expanding the Court. That is something that the President does not agree with. That is not something that he wants to do.</p>



<p>There was a commission that was put together about how to potentially move forward with the Court &#8212; reform the Court. I don&#8217;t have anything more to share from any &#8212; any final decision that the President has made.</p>



<p>I do want to say, though &#8212; you know, we talk about the popul- &#8212; I was talking about the popularity of how much Americans support Roe v. Wade. Never &#8212; this is the &#8212; this is the most support that Roe &#8212; Roe v. Wade has gotten ever.</p>



<p>I mean, it is &#8212; it has such a majority popularity. And so for the Court to have made this extreme ruling is so out of step. It’s so out of step not only with this decision, but it&#8217;s also so out of step with the Constitution.</p>



<p>Q Karine, the fact that you haven&#8217;t yet identified, even after this leaked decision, executive actions that you could take, does that sort of just reflect that there isn&#8217;t anything more, even after more talks with legal scholars, that you can do on this?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I think the way &#8212; I think the way to look at this &#8212; he did use executive authority. And that matters &#8212; right? &#8212; because he&#8217;s the President of the United States and using executive authorities to protect, you know, contraception for women and make sure they have that accessible to them &#8212; FDA-approved medication &#8212; is very important. I think that is something that&#8217;s going to be meaningful for many, many women across the country.</p>



<p>And secondly, to be able to have the DOJ defend women who are going to have to now travel to get &#8212; you know, after they make decisions on their own &#8212; their own health decision, I think, is actually really important. And again, we talked to legal experts about this.</p>



<p>We talked to other leading &#8212; leading groups in the &#8212; reproductive rights organizations. And so, these are two things that we thought were two concrete steps.</p>



<p>And so, you know, this is, again, a &#8212; first steps. We&#8217;re going to continue to see what else we can do.</p>



<p>But I guess what I&#8217;m trying to say about the executive actions is that nothing could make &#8212; could fill the hole that this decision has made with now upending Roe, which is what the Court did. The only way to make that whole again is for Congress to act, is Congress to restore Roe and make it a &#8212; you know, a law of the land. That is actually the best way to do that.</p>



<p>Q And on that, what is the President&#8217;s reform on &#8212; position on filibuster reform? He says, you know, “Elect more Democrats.” Let&#8217;s say he got two more Democrats in the Senate who would be okay with killing the filibuster on this issue so he had 50. Would he then support that stance?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, look, if we got more &#8212; more members of Congress, more &#8212; more members of Congress who support Roe, then the thinking would be that we would be able to pass a law to get that done. I don&#8217;t think the &#8212; I don&#8217;t think the filibuster would play a role there.</p>



<p>But that&#8217;s what we have to do. We got to make sure that we elect more members, or we have more members come in to &#8212; come in to Congress that can actually make a difference here.</p>



<p>I’ve got to be careful, because I can&#8217;t talk about &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; elec- &#8212; as you know. So I’ve got to be careful of what I say.</p>



<p>But the point that I&#8217;m making is: I hear &#8212; I hear you &#8212; I hear your point about the filibuster. But I think if &#8212; if we&#8217;re able to &#8212; if Americans are able to use their voice at the ballot box, bring in more members into Congress that support this issue, then there is movement that we can make. There is a way that we can restore Roe. And that is the most important thing that we can do.</p>



<p>Yes, can the President use &#8212; continue to use executive authority? We will see what else he can do. But, honestly, to fill that hole, we got to &#8212; we got to take action. And that&#8217;s what the President was trying to do.</p>



<p>Q Karine, can I ask you an Afghanistan question? Sorry. So the earthquake there has caused so much damage. And there&#8217;s some movement, again, for people to &#8212; to please release some of those funds, some of the central bank currency funds. Can you say what the U.S. position is on that and whether there&#8217;s any movement on that in light of the humanitarian catastrophe?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Are you talking about the &#8212; the assets in Ukraine? Yeah.</p>



<p>Q The assets &#8212; yeah. Not in Ukraine, in Afghanistan.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I’m sorry, I meant to say Afghanistan. There&#8217;s so much going on in the world. I apologize.</p>



<p>So, in signing an executive order several months ago, the President took a significant step to preserve these funds and ensure they go toward benefiting the people of Afghanistan.</p>



<p>If the President hadn’t taken this action, the funds would have remained tied up for years. So we are energized across the U.S. government &#8212; energized across the U.S. government to get these funds moving.</p>



<p>We are urgently working to address complicated questions about the use of these funds to ensure they benefit the people of Afghanistan and not &#8212; not the Taliban. So that is a focus of ours.</p>



<p>But the President is not going to wait to help the people of Afghanistan recover and rebuild their &#8212; from their devastating earthquake, as I mentioned much earlier in the week.</p>



<p>USAID and our partner humanitarian organizations are already providing immediate assistance on the ground where it&#8217;s needed the most.</p>



<p>Q Karine, if I could, back on the abortion issue, what do you think the decision means for the standing of the U.S. overseas, particularly in parts of the world where you&#8217;re trying to promote women&#8217;s rights?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, it&#8217;s a very good question, because what we saw &#8212; again, what we saw yesterday was extreme. It was an extreme decision on &#8212; on the American public&#8217;s constitutional right &#8212; a right that was given by that same Court almost 50 years ago.</p>



<p>You know, the &#8212; the administration has restored its commitment to advance women&#8217;s health both at home and abroad, revoking harmful global gag rule, as you know, and restoring funding to the United Nations Population Fund.</p>



<p>This administration will continue its work to advance women&#8217;s health and reproductive rights around the world, consistently with existing law. So we are going to continue to have those relationships, those leader-leader relationships that the President has.</p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;ve heard from a lot of the leaders already. I know some of them have put out statements &#8212; very vocal &#8212; about what they have seen from this decision in the last 12 &#8212; I’m losing track of time &#8212; 12, 24 hours &#8212; and &#8212; and giving &#8212; offering support to the American people.</p>



<p>But this is not going to &#8212; I don&#8217;t think this stops the work that the President is going to do or wants to do or looking to do with leaders.</p>



<p>Q But is it harder to get the message across if other parts of the world are going to turn around and say, “Well, look what&#8217;s happening in your own backyard”?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I &#8212; I mean, I don’t think it’s &#8212; I don’t think it’s necessarily harder. The President &#8212; the President has his own career and reputation to stand on. Right? He has been a senator, he has been a Vice President, and he has been a President that has been able to unify the country &#8212; not the country, the world, especially as we look at what is happening in Ukraine with Russia&#8217;s invasion.</p>



<p>So, you know, we&#8217;re going to G7. We&#8217;re going to NATO. People have said that NATO is the &#8212; is the most unified that they&#8217;ve ever seen, at least in modern times, in most recent times. And a lot of that was due to this &#8212; due to this President. I don&#8217;t think that goes away. I don&#8217;t think that does at all.</p>



<p>So, if anything, it just highlights the work that needs to continue to be done.</p>



<p>Q The DNC Chairman yesterday called the Supreme Court “illegitimate” after the decision. One, is that something that the President agrees with? And two, does he think that that&#8217;s a winning message for the Democrats going into 2022?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: So I can&#8217;t speak for the DNC. I can only speak for the President. And the President &#8212; you know, when the President commented about the decision, about the Court&#8217;s ruling, it was about the decision. He sees the Court, obviously, as legitimate. And he respects the Court.</p>



<p>He does believe that this particular ruling that they &#8212; that they made yesterday is extreme and is out of step. And he is going to continue to call that out.</p>



<p>But, you know, this is a President that was the Chair of the Judiciary Committee for &#8212; for many, many years when he was a senator. He oversaw many &#8212; many nominations for the Supreme Court. It is a court that he highly respects, but it is &#8212; it should be &#8212; right? &#8212; this is America &#8212; we should be able to speak out or speak &#8212; or have a &#8212; you know, have a disagreement.</p>



<p>And this is not just a disagreement, obviously, but this is what we saw. That decision was indeed stunning, and it was extreme and incredibly unfortunate. It is going to devastate so many lives, taking that constitutional right away for so many people across the country.</p>



<p>Q Karine, you said a couple of times that the Court gave the right to an abortion to women 50 years ago.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: But what I mean is that &#8212; what I mean is that they gave that constitutional right. Right? When that seven &#8212; 7-2 decision, Roe v. Wade, it was a constitutional right. Roe v. Wade was a constitutional right that was provided almost 50 years ago, and they took that constitutional right away.</p>



<p>Q So the President doesn&#8217;t believe that a right to abortion is in &#8212; is sort of &#8212; is built on the right to privacy enshrined in the Constitution, and ratification is only &#8212; it only came about at Roe?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, the President believes in pri- &#8212; in women’s privacy. He believes in a woman&#8217;s consti- &#8212; in a woman&#8217;s right to make their own choice. He believes that they should have their own freedoms to make their own decision.</p>



<p>What we&#8217;re saying is that decision that was made is going to &#8212; with that decision, things are going to, across the country, change so quickly because of that decision in states. And that is unacceptable.</p>



<p>If you think about, in some states, women&#8217;s &#8212; women will not be able to make a decision on how to protect their own lives. If you are a woman or a girl and you are raped, you will have to bear your child&#8217;s rapist [rapist’s child]. If you are a doctor, you could be criminalized for providing care. I mean, that is &#8211;those are the things that he spoke to himself directly in his speech.</p>



<p>And so he&#8217;s going to continue to fight for women&#8217;s rights. He&#8217;s going to continue to fight for their freedom. And he&#8217;s going to see what else he can do, as an executive authority, to see what other steps that we can do to move forward in protecting women.</p>



<p>Q Karine, you mentioned that the President has managed to rally NATO Allies and create unity overseas, but he clearly hasn’t in the United States. Is he frustrated by that? Is he going to be trying anything new ahead of the midterms?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: No, that’s a &#8212; that&#8217;s a good question. Look, when the President decided to run in 2019 &#8212; of April of 2019, he talked about redeeming the soul of this nation. Right? And two years prior to that, we saw what happened in Charlottesville. We saw the ugliness that was marching down the streets of Charlottesville. And he wrote &#8212; he wrote an op-ed and talked about that very personally. And when there was an opportunity for him to do something about that in a real profound way, he decided to run for President.</p>



<p>And in many ways &#8212; you know, he won with 81 million votes. Many people elected him because they believed he could bring the country together. And I think what the President understands is that we are in a very divided, politicized political environment at this time, and it&#8217;s going to take a lot more work. We are just not there yet.</p>



<p>Q Does he have any new strategies to achieve that? Or &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Well, he&#8217;s going to &#8212; I think he&#8217;s going to &#8212; look, let me &#8212; let&#8217;s step back for a second. We were able &#8212; this morning, the President was able to do something that hadn&#8217;t been done in almost 30 years, which is sign a bipartisan gun reform legislation.</p>



<p>So both sides were able to come together and really address an epidemic in this country. That matters, I think. And so he signed that into law. And it’s &#8212; and it’s &#8212; and then, hopefully, it will save lives.</p>



<p>And so, you know, when it comes to, you know, other &#8212; other issues that we see around the country, yeah, there&#8217;s going to be a lot of work that needs to be done. There&#8217;s going to be still &#8212; we still need to figure out how we&#8217;re going to bring the country together. This is not something that he&#8217;s not aware of; he&#8217;s very clearly aware of that.</p>



<p>And so he&#8217;s going to continue to have to do the work as President.</p>



<p>Q Karine, there&#8217;s evidence showing that states are starting to segregate along political lines. Are you concerned that this decision could accelerate that move; that, in essence, the trigger states and states that follow on &#8212; I mean, there&#8217;s talk about something like 26 states could eventually pass such laws. Are you concerned that we could see a country that is geographically divided along these lines, where, basically, states that ban abortion and punish women are fundamentally more Republican and that you see an outflow, a kind of a great migration out of people who are more progressive and liberally minded?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, look, the President said this yesterday: We are &#8212; we are going to see some nightmare scenarios. These &#8212; we&#8217;re going to see some devastating consequences because of the decision that the Court made.</p>



<p>That is not hypothetical. That is just the facts as you look across the states and also the legislation that have been coming out, the bills have been coming out, out of the state &#8212; the state houses.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s why the President made it very clear yesterday that he&#8217;s going to continue to fight. He&#8217;s going to continue to call for action as it relates to Congress, as it relates to the American public using their voice at the ballot box. And he&#8217;s going to continue to talk to leading organizations &#8212; and not just him, but also his team. I laid out offices that have been working since day one of the leaked document. And we&#8217;re going to see what else we can do.</p>



<p>But we believe &#8212; we put forward two concrete steps. You know, we&#8217;re going to try to see what else we can do. But, you know, the President talked about this: We are going to see some nightmare scenarios, sadly, because of this decision. I mean, this is a 50 &#8212; almost 50-year &#8212; almost five-decade decision that has been overturned and upended.</p>



<p>Q Karine?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: Yeah.</p>



<p>Q One more on the gas tax holiday. Since the President called on Congress on Wednesday, has there been any movement or indication whatsoever that Congress is going to prioritize that when they&#8217;re back from recess? It doesn&#8217;t really seem like the important folks on the Hill are where you are on this. So I&#8217;m just trying to figure out how you&#8217;re going to try to get this done.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, let &#8212; just let me just reiterate: The President &#8212; you know, the President called for the suspension of federal gas tax, a gas tax &#8212; gas tax holiday, because he felt that this was the most simplest, easiest way to deal with a &#8212; an issue for the American public of high gas prices at the pump. And he felt &#8212; he felt that 90 days was, you know, an easy thing to do, because the American public &#8212; you know, this is the time that they drive the most: during the summer.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re still talking to &#8212; to answer your question, we’re still talking to Congress. I don&#8217;t have anything more to share with you as &#8212; as far as a priority for them. We&#8217;re going to have this conversation.</p>



<p>But the President made very clear what he believed this could do and giving that little bit of breathing room for the Americans as they travel, as they go to work, as they are trying to live their lives every day, especially this summer when it&#8217;s incredibly active.</p>



<p>Q Don&#8217;t you risk missing that window, I mean, given that, you know, Congress is out now? And &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, here’s the thing: Look, Congress can act on this anytime. It&#8217;s actually very simple to do.</p>



<p>Q If they want to.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: If &#8212; well, we&#8217;re going to continue to have that conversation and, you know, see if we can make that a priority. But this is not a difficult thing to do. That&#8217;s why we keep saying it&#8217;s straightforward and easy. It is actually not a difficult thing to do, and we&#8217;re going to continue to call on them to do (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q Just one on abortion &#8212;</p>



<p>Q The President’s Sherpa is &#8212;</p>



<p>Q Sorry. Karine, just some activists are pushing for abortion clinics to be built on federal lands in conservative states. Is this an option that the administration is considering?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I just don&#8217;t have anything else to share. We&#8217;re going to continue to look at what other options we have. I don&#8217;t have anything to share on that specific question.</p>



<p>Q Karine, one last one &#8212;</p>



<p>Q The President’s &#8212;</p>



<p>Q When the President went to the G7 a year ago, he came with ambitious COVID vaccine donation goals for the rest of the world. The U.S. is falling short on that because it doesn&#8217;t have the money to help countries administer and transport and store those vaccines safely.</p>



<p>Is the President worried that by failing to meet those commitments &#8212; in part because of Congress, in part because of other reasons &#8212; that U.S. credibility on the global stage around public health will be called into question?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: I mean, look, I’d have to look into where we are specifically on our international assistance on COVID. I know that we have been the country that&#8217;s provided the most &#8212; a leader &#8212; than any other country. It is a commitment. It has come up in every international trip that he&#8217;s had. COVID has always been a part of the agenda.</p>



<p>But I would disagree with &#8212; with your premise of the question.</p>



<p>Look, the President has &#8212; if you look at where we are currently as a country and the economic strengths that we have, a lot of &#8212; a lot of that is because of what the President did on day one, which is present a comprehensive strategy to get people vaccinated.</p>



<p>And now we have more than 200 million people who are vaccinated. We&#8217;re getting zero to five vaccinated. It&#8217;s about 18- &#8212; you know, there’s, zero to five, 18 million young people. The hope is to do everything that we can to get vaccinated.</p>



<p>So, if anything, he has shown leadership right here in this country on everything that he has done to make sure that &#8212; that folks &#8212; that the American public have access to vaccines and boosters. And so, we have shown our leadership here.</p>



<p>I can see what else I have for you on where we are with conversations at the G7 and our deliverables on this subject particularly. But this has always been part of an agenda in every &#8212; every trip that he&#8217;s done. And I think the President, we believe, and I don&#8217;t &#8212; and I would argue others across the globe believe, that we have been a leader in this.</p>



<p>Thanks, everybody.</p>



<p>12:11 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Oslo&#160;Shooting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/25/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-oslo-shooting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 18:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=56278</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The horrific shooting in Norway this morning has been felt around the world. The United States strongly condemns this act of terror. We stand in solidarity with the families of the victims, the diverse and strong LGBTQI+ community of Oslo, our close NATO ally Norway, and all who have been devastated by this senseless act. The United States&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The horrific shooting in Norway this morning has been felt around the world. The United States strongly condemns this act of terror. We stand in solidarity with the families of the victims, the diverse and strong LGBTQI+ community of Oslo, our close NATO ally Norway, and all who have been devastated by this senseless act. The United States has been in touch with the Norwegian government and offered to provide assistance. We remain committed to continuing to partner with Norway to advance a more equitable and just world for all, free from violence and discrimination.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
