<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 20:07:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on President Biden&#8217;s Meetings at the G7 Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/12/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-president-bidens-meetings-at-the-g7-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 20:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20559</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 7:00 P.M. BST&#160;MODERATOR:&#160; Good evening, everyone.&#160; Thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing.&#160; This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&#160; We’ll, of course, have time for Q&#38;A at the end. Not for reporting or attribution, but just for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>7:00 P.M. BST<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing.&nbsp; This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials,” and embargoed until the conclusion of the call.&nbsp; We’ll, of course, have time for Q&amp;A at the end.</p>



<p>Not for reporting or attribution, but just for your knowledge, on today&#8217;s call we have joining us [senior administration official].&nbsp; And with that, I&#8217;m going to pass it off to our speaker.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks, everybody, for joining.&nbsp; I thought I&#8217;d just give you an update on what we observed over the last couple of days and heading into the last day tomorrow, after which we’ll release the communiqué.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what is really striking to me is the amount of convergence we&#8217;ve seen, both &#8212; that&#8217;s true both in terms of the direction of convergence and also the speed with which it&#8217;s happening.</p>



<p>Now, I had a chance to look back, and, three years ago, if you look back to the communiqué in 2018, China wasn&#8217;t even explicitly mentioned, even though you could find whole paragraphs devoted to countries like North Korea, Russia.&nbsp; Back then, they couldn&#8217;t reach consensus on anything as it related to China.</p>



<p>And, you know, this year, what is &#8212; what is striking is the very strong and shared foundation for a joint approach.&nbsp; And I don’t want to get ahead of specifics in the communiqué, but I can give you at least some of the areas of convergence, because I think they&#8217;re all profound and really important to highlight.<br>&nbsp;<br>So I’ll give you a few examples: First, working together to respond to China&#8217;s non-market economic practices that are harmful and distorted to the global economy.&nbsp; Being willing to speak out on human rights abuses, including in Xinjiang.&nbsp; And more than just speaking out, taking action, responding to forced labor in supply chains, again, including from Xinjiang.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, this is something we talked about yesterday &#8212; some of us at least &#8212; (inaudible) infrastructure initiative that is high standards, values-driven, transparent, and multilateral.&nbsp; And, you know, today, in fact, there was quite a bit of discussion about coordination on supply chain resilience and coming up with technology standards that are suited for the 21st century so that, as democracies, we’re aligned and we&#8217;re supporting each other.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, you know, I could go on, actually.&nbsp; But if that&#8217;s not a common approach, I don&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t know what is.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just a huge move forward in three years, and, you know, I&#8217;m quite encouraged by what we heard.<br>&nbsp;<br>So let me just stop there and see if there are questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; So, now, everyone, if you&#8217;ve got a question, please use the “raise hand” function on the Zoom interface, and we&#8217;ll try to take some questions.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let&#8217;s start with Anne Gearan from The Washington Post.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you very much for doing this.&nbsp; This is, kind of, logistics, but can you let us know when you think we will see the communiqué and in what form?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, Anne.&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; I can at least give you a ballpark sense.&nbsp; So there are a couple of sessions planned for tomorrow for the leaders in the communiqué, but (inaudible).&nbsp; So I would say sometime around (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, you broke up.&nbsp; Sometime around what time?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; (Inaudible) digital technology is a little bit choppy.&nbsp; I said sometime around midday would be my expectation.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; We’re actually probably going to be on a bus or a plane.&nbsp; So we’re, like &#8212; (laughs) &#8212; and (inaudible) it looks like there’s going to be news in it, so we’re trying to figure out how best to do that.&nbsp; And, you know, anything you guys can do to make sure that we have it in real time would be a huge help.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well taken.&nbsp; And will do.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Next we will go to Josh Wingrove at Bloomberg.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; This morning there was a dis- &#8212; or the indications were, earlier today, that there was sort of a discussion between some people who wanted China more explicitly named, including President Biden, and others who were less keen on that, including Chancellor Merkel.&nbsp;Can you give me an update on that? &nbsp;And can you specify: Is &#8212; is the word &#8220;China&#8221; going to be in the communiqué? &nbsp;Because that, too, was uncertain as of a day ago. &nbsp;Thank you. &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I would say there was unanimity in terms of a willingness to call out human rights abuses and violations of fundamental freedoms that invoke our shared values.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, so this was &#8212; there has been, yesterday, and there certainly was today, a tremendous (inaudible) this together, and what forges the G7 partnership.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s very much about our shared (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, there was a willingness to speak out &#8212; not just a willingness; I think there was unanimity in terms of our (inaudible) to speak out and (inaudible) and to be specific (inaudible), and (inaudible) and with a commitment to take action in response to what we&#8217;re seeing.&nbsp; And, you know, again, that was &#8212; that was a &#8212; that&#8217;s a dramatic change from where we were only three years ago.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I&#8217;m sorry &#8212; we&#8217;re perhaps near our Zoom &#8212; the end of our Zoom era, but you did cut out a few times there.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, I&#8217;m sorry, Josh.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; I don&#8217;t know when I cut out.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Perhaps I would just suggest: If there was a point you felt particularly strongly about, if it came in the middle, we might not have heard it in full.&nbsp; So, if you wanted to sum up &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay, I&#8217;ll just summarize.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Okay, Josh, is this better now?&nbsp; Can you hear me?<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Yes, sir.&nbsp; I can.&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll give it another shot.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, what I was saying was that, again, I heard from everyone that what binds us together as a G7 partnership, more than anything else, are the shared values of democracies.&nbsp; And that, because of that partnership, you know, it&#8217;s our obligation to call out human rights abuses and other &#8212; other violations of fundamental freedoms that calls us into &#8212; that really invoke our shared values.<br>&nbsp;<br>And more than just &#8212; more than just calling out those abuses, which are &#8212; that&#8217;s important &#8212; there was a (inaudible) to take action.&nbsp; And (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s go to Steve Holland with Reuters.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Just to be specific about what&#8217;s going to be in the communiqué: You&#8217;re saying it&#8217;s going to cite &#8212; it&#8217;s going to criticize China&#8217;s non-market policies and China&#8217;s human rights treatment in Xinjiang.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I don’t want to get ahead of what &#8212; I can&#8217;t get ahead of what&#8217;s in the communiqué because it hasn&#8217;t (inaudible) and leaders have to sign off.&nbsp; But I&#8217;m just trying to reflect the conversation.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, I think you mentioned the word &#8220;criticize.&#8221;&nbsp; And certainly there&#8217;s a strong convergence in terms of a willingness to call out human rights abuses.&nbsp; But I would say, with respect to non-market economic practices, my reference there was to work together collaboratively within the G7 to find ways to confront those practices and to offer a better choice and affirmative path.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And there was a lot of discussion about what that could mean in terms of (inaudible); in terms of cooperation on technology standards; in terms of things we can work together to bolster our supply chain resilience, ways we could come (inaudible) &#8212; ways we could come (inaudible) to provide support to low-income countries with the resources (inaudible) and through the (inaudible) that we&#8217;ve built.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>There&#8217;s a long list of items that were discussed, (inaudible) a positive agenda, while also being clear about what we don&#8217;t tolerate.&nbsp; And all of those actions and that agenda, again, flow from shared values that everyone &#8212; everyone &#8212; held up as the reason (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; Next, let&#8217;s go to Franco Ordoñez with NPR.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I wanted to just kind of follow up on that.&nbsp; It sounds like, from the conversations, the &#8212; that the leaders are ready to be more specific about addressing these human rights (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But you also mentioned being committed to taking action.&nbsp; I wanted to ask: Will that be &#8212; do you anticipate that will be outlined in the communiqué, not only calling out the human rights, but outlining some of the steps to take action?&nbsp; And if it doesn&#8217;t outline some of those steps, do you feel like that would be falling short in any way?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I don&#8217;t, again, (inaudible) communiqué, but (inaudible) communiqué (inaudible) &#8212;&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; You&#8217;re coming out a little garbled.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; There&#8217;s a commitment here about how our (inaudible) in terms of our actions, and that&#8217;s both being (inaudible) and also what we&#8217;re for.&nbsp; So you’ll see strong elements of both tomorrow.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t get into specifics again, Franco, just because, you know, the doc is not final.<br>&nbsp;<br>If you want to go back &#8212; you already have heard about (inaudible) important (inaudible) actions we’ve taken together.&nbsp; The pandemic response means our contributions &#8212; the unprecedented amount that the G7 has agreed to provide without conditions, without any strings attached, both for this (inaudible).&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And (inaudible) to deal with (inaudible).&nbsp; Because that’s the spirit in which the discussion have taken place (inaudible) &#8212; why our model is still the single best way to deliver for our people, but also to meet the biggest challenges and (inaudible), supply chain resilience, (inaudible) competition.&nbsp; And, yes, (inaudible).<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Much of that answer was very unclear and garbled.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you want to try again, but that came across as about 80 percent choppy.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, boy.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, Franco, can you hear me any better?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes, that was a little clearer.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay, well, I mean, I started off by saying I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of any specifics in the communiqué.&nbsp; You are going to see a very clear commitment on a number of fronts in which &#8212; (phone line drops).<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Our speaker just dropped.&nbsp; Give us one second while we try to get him back on.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>[Senior administration official], are you there?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey, it&#8217;s [senior administration official].&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Hey there.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hey.&nbsp; I know [senior administration official] is experiencing some tech issues.&nbsp; So why don&#8217;t I just close this out with a little bit of &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That&#8217;s perfect.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; &#8212; again, sort of &#8212; yeah.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll close it out with an overview of how we&#8217;re seeing today.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And as [senior administration official] said at the top of the call, I mean, the &#8212; not just today, but the G7 writ large, we&#8217;ve seen &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve seen and felt and been encouraged by a growing convergence.&nbsp; And you look at where the G7 was three years ago &#8212; with China not even explicitly mentioned, though entire paragraphs were devoted to North Korea and Russia &#8212; I think it just underlines that the &#8212; where the G7 has come from there, and the fact that we have a strong, common foundation on our approach to issues that matter.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And, you know, as [senior administration official] said, in terms of where we are right now, we&#8217;ve reached consensus on a number of points that are reflective of that shared approach.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>We&#8217;re working together to respond to non-market economic practices that are objectionable in a global economy; speaking out on human rights abuses; responding to forced labor in supply chains; pursuing an affirmative infrastructure initiative that&#8217;s high standards and transparent; and coordinating on supply chain resilience and technology standards so that democracies are aligned and supporting each other.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And so, you know, as we close out the day, that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re seeing and that&#8217;s where we are.&nbsp; I appreciate folks bearing through some of the audio difficulties.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll be back with one of these very soon.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much for joining us again, everyone.&nbsp; Again, this call is on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and embargoed until the call concludes, which will be momentarily.&nbsp; Thank you so much again.</p>



<p>7:15 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President Biden’s Meeting with President Emmanuel Macron of France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-of-president-bidens-meeting-with-president-emmanuel-macron-of-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 17:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20555</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Emmanuel Macron on the margins of the G7 Summit. The two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to deepening our bilateral ties and to the Transatlantic alliance. They highlighted their dedication to ending the pandemic, including through participation in the G7 commitment to donate COVID-19 vaccines to countries&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. met today with President Emmanuel Macron on the margins of the G7 Summit. The two leaders reaffirmed their commitment to deepening our bilateral ties and to the Transatlantic alliance. They highlighted their dedication to ending the pandemic, including through participation in the G7 commitment to donate COVID-19 vaccines to countries in need, and to build back better global health security for the future. They reaffirmed their commitment to reform the international tax system to address some of the inequities created by globalization. President Biden expressed his appreciation for France’s leadership on climate issues through the Paris Agreement, and both leaders underscored their dedication to achieve ambitious outcomes at the COP26 Summit in Glasgow in November. President Biden and President Macron discussed our work to strengthen and modernize NATO, and our close cooperation on counter terrorism cooperation, including in the Sahel, and other shared foreign policy priorities such as China and Russia.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden and President Macron of the French Republic Before Bilateral Meeting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/remarks-by-president-biden-and-president-macron-of-the-french-republic-before-bilateral-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:50:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20549</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Carbis Bay Hotel &#38; EstateSaint Ives, United Kingdom 3:01 P.M. BST Q    How are you, sir? PRESIDENT MACRON:  How are you?   PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I&#8217;m well.  The sun is shining.  We&#8217;re almost on the beach.  I&#8217;m well.  And I&#8217;m with the President of France; that makes me even feel better.  (Laughs.) AIDE:  We&#8217;re on. PRESIDENT BIDEN:  We&#8217;re on.  Okay.  We&#8217;re on. &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Carbis Bay Hotel &amp; Estate<br>Saint Ives, United Kingdom</p>



<p>3:01 P.M. BST<br> <br>Q    How are you, sir?<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  How are you?  <br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I&#8217;m well.  The sun is shining.  We&#8217;re almost on the beach.  I&#8217;m well.  And I&#8217;m with the President of France; that makes me even feel better.  (Laughs.)<br> <br>AIDE:  We&#8217;re on.<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  We&#8217;re on.  Okay.  We&#8217;re on.  Did you know that?  (Laughter.)  Well, we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re just having a &#8212; we&#8217;ve had a good couple days so far.  I&#8217;ve had a chance to spend some time with President Macron, get to know him.  And we &#8212; we have some things we&#8217;ve got to talk about a little bit later, but things are going, I think, well.  And we&#8217;re &#8212; we&#8217;re, as we say in &#8212; back in the States, &#8220;We&#8217;re on the same page.&#8221;  So, thank you.<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Yeah.  Thank you.  Thank you, Mr. President.  We had a &#8212; I want to thank you for our discussion yesterday and the working sessions we had, indeed. <br> <br>We have to &#8212; to deal with this pandemic and the COVID-19.  We have to face a lot of challenges, a lot of crisis &#8212; climate change.  And for all these issues, what we need is cooperation.  And I think it&#8217;s great to have the U.S. President part of the club and very willing to cooperate.  And I think that what you &#8212; what you demonstrate is that leadership is partnership. And &#8212; and we do appreciate it, and I think we can deliver great things for that.<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  I think we can do a lot, too.  We &#8212; the United States, I&#8217;ve said before &#8212; we&#8217;re back.  The U.S. is back.  We feel very, very strongly about the cohesion of NATO. <br> <br>And I, for one, think that the European Union is an incredibly strong and vibrant entity that has a lot to do with the ability of Western Europe to not only handle its economic issues, but provide the backbone and the support for NATO. <br> <br>And so I &#8212; we&#8217;re very supportive &#8212; very supportive.<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Thank you. <br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Thank you. <br> <br>Q    Mr. President, are you convinced that your allies in the United States are back?<br> <br>PRESIDENT BIDEN:  Ask him.<br> <br>Q    Is America back?<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Yeah.  Definitely.<br> <br>Q    Do you believe America is back?<br> <br>PRESIDENT MACRON:  Definitely.<br> <br>3:03 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White House Roundtable with LGBTQ+ and Gun Violence Prevention Leaders on the Fifth Anniversary of the Pulse Nightclub Mass Shooting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-lgbtq-and-gun-violence-prevention-leaders-on-the-fifth-anniversary-of-the-pulse-nightclub-mass-shooting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 16:17:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20543</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Public Engagement Director and Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond hosted a virtual roundtable with LGBTQ+ leaders and&#160;gun violence survivors and advocates to recognize the fifth anniversary of the mass shooting at the Pulse Nightclub in Orlando, Florida. Together, they observed a moment of silence to honor&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, Domestic Policy Advisor Susan Rice and White House Public Engagement Director and Senior Advisor Cedric Richmond hosted a virtual roundtable with LGBTQ+ leaders and&nbsp;gun violence survivors and advocates to recognize the fifth anniversary of the mass shooting at the Pulse Nightclub in Orlando, Florida. Together, they observed a moment of silence to honor the 49 individuals who lost their lives in the Pulse tragedy and the traumatic impact that the mass shooting had on LGBTQ+ and Latino communities across the country.</p>



<p>During the meeting, three courageous LGBTQ+ gun violence survivors discussed the impact that gun violence has had on their lives. Participants shared their perspectives on the ongoing public health crisis of gun violence in America and the burden that this crisis has on LGBTQ+ communities across our nation. They discussed the epidemic levels of violence faced by transgender people, especially transgender women of color, and the impact of firearms in the crisis of anti-transgender homicides. Participants also discussed the intersection of gun safety and the movement to prevent and end suicide among LGBTQ+ youth.</p>



<p>Ambassador Rice and Congressman Richmond expressed gratitude for the participants’ courageous leadership in addressing acts of anti-LGBTQ+ violence, and for their persistent advocacy to tackle the gun violence epidemic. They reiterated President Biden’s commitment to advancing full equality for every LGBTQ+ person and family, including his urging for the Senate to pass the Equality Act to ensure that LGBTQ+ Americans can live free of discrimination and without fear of who they are or whom they love. Finally, they underscored President Biden’s deep commitment to ending the gun violence public health epidemic in America and reiterated his call for the Senate to pass bipartisan legislation to reduce gun violence that has already passed the House.</p>



<p>Participants in yesterday’s roundtable included:</p>



<ul><li>Jason Lindsay, Pride Fund to End Gun Violence</li><li>Elle Moxley, The Marsha P. Johnson Institute</li><li>Destini Philpot, Students Demand Action Baltimore &amp; Good Kids Mad City Baltimore</li><li>Casey Pick, The Trevor Project</li><li>Andrea Pino-Silva, Community Justice Action Fund</li><li>Bamby Salcedo, The TransLatin@ Coalition</li><li>Nadine Smith, Equality Florida</li><li>Beverly Tillery, New York City Anti-Violence Project</li><li>Brandon Wolf, Survivor of the Pulse Nightclub Mass Shooting, and Advocate for LGBTQ+ Equality and Gun Violence Prevention</li><li>Christopher Zoeller, March for Our Lives Florida</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the 5th Anniversary of the Pulse Nightclub Shooting</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-5th-anniversary-of-the-pulse-nightclub-shooting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 15:57:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Five years ago today in Orlando in the middle of Pride Month, our nation suffered the deadliest attack affecting the LGBTQ+ community in American history, and at the time, the deadliest mass shooting by a single gunman. Within minutes, the Pulse nightclub that had long been a place of acceptance and joy turned into a&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Five years ago today in Orlando in the middle of Pride Month, our nation suffered the deadliest attack affecting the LGBTQ+ community in American history, and at the time, the deadliest mass shooting by a single gunman.</p>



<p>Within minutes, the Pulse nightclub that had long been a place of acceptance and joy turned into a place of unspeakable pain and loss. Forty-nine people were there celebrating Latin night were murdered, even more injured, and countless others scarred forever – the victims were family members, partners and friends, veterans and students, young, Black, Asian and Latino – our fellow Americans.</p>



<p>A few days later, I traveled with President Obama to pay respects to them and their families, to thank the brave first responders and the community who found strength and compassion in each other, and to pledge that what happened would not be forgotten.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Over the years, I have stayed in touch with families of the victims and with the survivors who have turned their pain into purpose, and who remind us that we must do more than remember victims of gun violence and all of the survivors, family members, and friends left behind; we must act.</p>



<p>In the coming days, I will sign a bill designating Pulse Nightclub as a national memorial, enshrining in law what has been true since that terrible day five years ago: Pulse Nightclub is hallowed ground.</p>



<p>But there is more we must do to address the public health epidemic of gun violence in all of its forms – mass shootings and daily acts of gun violence that don’t make national headlines.</p>



<p>It is long past time we close the loopholes that allow gun buyers to bypass background checks in this country, and the Senate should start by passing the three House-passed bills which would do exactly that. It is long past time we ban assault weapons and high capacity magazines, establish extreme risk protection orders, also known as “red flag” laws, and eliminate gun manufacturers’ immunity from liability.</p>



<p>We must also acknowledge gun violence’s particular impact on LGBTQ+ communities across our nation. We must drive out hate and inequities that contribute to the epidemic of violence and murder against transgender women – especially transgender women of color. We must create a world in which our LGBTQ+ young people are loved, accepted, and feel safe in living their truth.&nbsp;And the Senate must swiftly pass the Equality Act, legislation that will ensure LGBTQ+ Americans finally have equal protection under law.</p>



<p>In the memory of all of those lost at the Pulse nightclub five years ago, let us continue the work to be a nation at our best – one that recognizes and protects the dignity and safety of every American.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: G7 to Announce Joint Actions to End Public Support for Overseas Unabated Coal Generation by End of 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/fact-sheet-g7-to-announce-joint-actions-to-end-public-support-for-overseas-unabated-coal-generation-by-end-of-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20523</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is rallying the world’s democracies to deliver for our people, meet the world’s biggest challenges, and demonstrate our shared values Today, President Biden and fellow G7 Leaders agreed to a set of concrete actions to accelerate the global transition away from coal generation as part of our efforts to combat the climate&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The United States is rallying the world’s democracies to deliver for our people, meet the world’s biggest challenges, and demonstrate our shared values</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden and fellow G7 Leaders agreed to a set of concrete actions to accelerate the global transition away from coal generation as part of our efforts to combat the climate crisis. <br><br><strong><em>Accelerating Decarbonization and Transition from Unabated Coal: </em></strong>Confronting the climate crisis presents a historic opportunity to drive our economic recovery, create millions of good-paying union jobs, and build back better as we invest in a more resilient, prosperous, equitable, and secure future. Recognizing that unabated coal power generation is the single biggest source of greenhouse gas emissions globally, and consistent with President Biden’s domestic leadership, G7 Leaders will commit to an end to new direct government support for unabated international thermal coal power generation by the end of this year. To support key developing countries in their transitions away from unabated coal, Canada, Germany, the UK, and the United States will also include a new collective commitment to provide up to $2 billion to support the work of the Climate Investments Funds focused on accelerating the transition from coal for key developing countries while investing in technology, job training, and infrastructure to enable the transition to a more reliable and prosperous clean energy economy.<br><br>Hard-to-abate heavy industrial sectors like cement and steel will play a key role in this transition. Therefore, Leaders are launching the G7 Industrial Decarbonization Agenda, a first-of-its-kind platform to accelerate innovation, deploy decarbonization technology, and harmonize standards. The Leaders also will emphasize sectoral decarbonization in power, transport, agriculture, and buildings.<br><br><strong><em>Aligning to Confront the Climate Crisis:</em></strong> Additionally, for the first time in history, all G7 Leaders will align their long-term and short-term climate goals in a manner consistent with keeping the 1.5 degrees Celsius global warming threshold within reach. Leaders will also resolve to strengthen adaptation and resilience to protect people from the impacts of climate change and to halt and reverse biodiversity loss, as well as to mobilize finance and leverage innovation to reach these goals.<br><br>To fully address the climate crisis, we also must recognize and focus on the role of conservation. This is why the United States supports the G7 goal of conserving or protecting at least 30 percent of global land and marine areas by 2030 – a commitment grounded in scientific evidence that has shown increasing conservation is critical for maintaining the health and productivity of our ecosystems for generations to come.<br><br>Domestically, President Biden is advancing policies that will achieve carbon-pollution free energy in electricity generation by 2035. These policies will support scale up of technology that captures carbon and then permanently sequesters or utilizes that captured carbon, which includes lowering the cost of carbon capture retrofits for existing power plants — all while ensuring that overburdened communities are protected from increases in cumulative pollution.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official After G7 Plenary Session Two</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/12/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-after-g7-plenary-session-two/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 15:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 12:47 P.M. BST MODERATOR:  Good afternoon, everybody.  Thanks so much for joining us for a quick background briefing following G7 Session Two: &#8220;Building Back Resilient &#8211; Winning the Future.&#8221;  Apologies for the delay and appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility.  We&#8217;ll do this on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;  Not for reporting or attribution, but with us&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>12:47 P.M. BST<br> <br>MODERATOR:  Good afternoon, everybody.  Thanks so much for joining us for a quick background briefing following G7 Session Two: &#8220;Building Back Resilient &#8211; Winning the Future.&#8221; <br> <br>Apologies for the delay and appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility.  We&#8217;ll do this on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials.&#8221;  Not for reporting or attribution, but with us we have [senior administration official].  And I will pass it over to them to kick us off, and we&#8217;ll take some brief questions and answers at the end. <br> <br>[Senior administration official], go ahead.<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Great.  Well, good afternoon.  I apologize for being a little bit late.  Just to give a little bit of the optics: They &#8212; today was the second session of the G7 &#8212; the plenary sessions.  And this was done in a more secure format.  They &#8212; it was the first of two of the foreign policy sessions.  This was focused on &#8220;Winning the Future.&#8221;  It, kind of &#8212; the way the G7 leaders have committed, in February 19th, in the virtual meeting, to do more coordination around China, and then had some discussions in the interim about some ways to do that. <br> <br>This session focused on some of those opportunities and coordination efforts, and was done in a session where they ended up kind of closing off a lot of the Internet connections.  So it&#8217;s been a little bit tough for the &#8212; to communicate from the &#8212; after the session. <br> <br>But it was about a 90-minute session.  The Prime Minister kicked it off.  He then passed it to &#8212; I think, in the order &#8212; sorry, I can&#8217;t access my &#8212; the full notes right now, but the &#8212; it was a mix of &#8212; I think first was &#8212; I believe it was some combination of Merkel, Macron, and &#8212; I&#8217;m trying to get this right here &#8212; Merkel, Macron, Suga.  President Biden spoke for a bit. <br> <br>There was a little bit of the session back and forth, but, basically, the &#8212; kind of the key takeaways and topics were just, kind of, the opportunities and the different perspectives on how to turn, I think, some of the ideas and efforts around both the cooperative elements, the competitive elements, the adversarial elements of the relationship with China, and turn those into something more than just words and, kind of, like-minded efforts around democratic values of the G7 members, but, kind of, a way of translating that into more concrete actions. <br> <br>There was discussions around the &#8220;Build Back Better World&#8221; efforts to be able to create and offer some greater opportunity to the developing world around infrastructure.  And I think, hopefully, you all have or will receive the &#8212; a factsheet that goes into a bit more detail around that. <br> <br>There was also a little discussion within that of the UK&#8217;s efforts around the &#8212; something focused a little more intently on climate that, I think, fits within the larger &#8220;Build Back Better World&#8221; effort.  I think we&#8217;re going with &#8220;B3W&#8221; as a shorthand. <br> <br>There was discussion &#8212; I think some good discussion around &#8212; from Prime Minister Draghi to Chancellor Merkel, and a little bit from the EU &#8212; around, kind of, the cooperative nature of the relationship versus, I think, (inaudible) side of Prime Minister Trudeau, President Biden, and a couple of others &#8212; Prime Minister Johnson &#8212; wanting to really show, I think, our positions and values through a little bit more action-oriented efforts and coordination. <br> <br>There was discussion of possibly working towards a &#8212; some sort of working group or task force that would draw out some of the coordination efforts in more detail.  This is something that the Prime Minister floated to the group and, I think, seemed to have some warm responses to. <br> <br>And then, I think there was agreement on the larger infrastructure efforts of turning values and efforts into more concreteness in terms of trying to figure out exactly the more nuances and detail of what the &#8220;Build Back Better World&#8221; &#8212; that also encompasses something &#8212; the clean green initiative that the Prime Minister has talked about, focusing more on climate, in the near future. <br> <br>So that&#8217;s something, I think, that will probably come off of this with potential for further coordination and action among G7 countries, and possibly through the sherpa channel, but we&#8217;ll see exactly how that &#8212; how that ends up looking.<br> <br>I guess any immediate kind of questions around areas that might be helpful to touch on &#8212; and I&#8217;ll see, also, if I can pull up &#8212; we&#8217;re still under a bit of a lockdown, in terms of access to a lot of our notes and connections, but I can see if I can fish a couple more things if it&#8217;s helpful.<br> <br>MODERATOR:  Thanks.  Yeah, we&#8217;ll dive right into some brief Q&amp;A.  For those of you that are on the Zoom interface, please use the &#8220;raise hand&#8221; function, and we&#8217;ll try to get through a few questions.<br> <br>First, why don&#8217;t we go to Josh Wingrove of Bloomberg.<br> <br>Q    Hi.  Thank you so much for doing this.  These calls are very helpful.  (Loud noises disrupt the call.)  Thank you, also, whoever just muted.  (Laughs.)  Can you &#8212; you mentioned that the EU and Draghi and Merkel were talking about the cooperative nature of the relationship.  Can you just expand on that?  Are you referring to the &#8212; to the China-G7 relationship or the relationship within the G7 bloc? <br> <br>And if you could speak a little bit more about the action-oriented measures that you said Prime Ministers Trudeau, Johnson, and President Biden were favoring.  Thank you. <br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Sure.  Yeah.  No, I think &#8212; I mean, I don&#8217;t know if you &#8212; if you all had a readout yet from last night as well, but I&#8217;ll say, as someone who&#8217;s worked here at the &#8212; at the White House for a &#8212; for across (inaudible) the changes across administrations, that just &#8212; to say that I think the environment inside the room and being able to see the leaders from the G7 &#8212; the warm looks, the embraces, the sense of, I think, real agreement around the values and the purpose of gathering and trying to, kind of, set the tone of rallying the democracies of the world to take concrete actions in a meaningful way, I think, is very much apparent. <br> <br>In that, I think, context &#8212; and I think, last night, you saw a lot of &#8212; for the first opening session and the welcome pieces, you kind of saw that &#8212; those relationships, I think, in action.  And I think President Biden, who knows many of these leaders over the years &#8212; and the ones who he&#8217;s met, I think, very much looking forward to kind of shaping and being much more aligned from a value perspective. <br> <br>I think that, first and foremost, was, I think, set as an initial placeholder last night.  And then this morning was to go a little bit deeper on some of the, I think, the more challenging elements within the G7 positioning on how hard to push and to call out some of the actions that China is taking. <br> <br> And I think that that was some of the space where there was some interesting discussions and a little bit of a differentiation of opinion on not whether, kind of, the threat is there, but on how strong, from an action perspective, I think different G7 members are willing to take things. <br> <br>And I think President Biden really was leading the charge in his remarks this morning.  And I would say Prime Minister Johnson was very close behind him &#8212; and Prime Minister Trudeau and President Macron.  And there is a little differentiation, I think I would say, within &#8212; within, I think, the spectrum of how hard they would push on some of these issues, but there was &#8212; there was widespread agreement on the ideas of doing something in the infrastructure space that was focused on the positive offer to the developing world. <br> <br>That could be something that, I think, could provide a more positive offer, but not a &#8212; not a choice between the &#8212; what I think (inaudible) economies where China is offering to some of those developing countries in more of a values-driven, high-standards, equity lens. <br> <br>But there is some &#8212; I think, as you all probably are very well aware and in depth in, kind of, the different perspectives of just how hard and much of the relationship is willing to focus on the potential competitive and adversarial elements of the relationship and, kind of, call those out, whether it&#8217;s forced labor in Xinjiang that the President really, kind of, made a forceful &#8212; some forceful comments about kind of putting values and actions by at least be willing &#8212; a willingness to kind of call that &#8212; call some of those things out publicly, but also, I think, kind of, the understanding that there are different facets and elements of that relationship for other countries in the EU as a whole &#8212; and I think just kind of trying to see where the G7, as a whole, is right now and where they could be. <br> <br>And I think you&#8217;re going to see a communiqué that&#8217;s going to come out on Sunday.  And I think at the President&#8217;s press conference, I think, he&#8217;ll have a chance to &#8212; to really talk about this in a lot more depth. <br> <br>MODERATOR:  Thanks.  Next, why don&#8217;t we go to Jonathan Lemire with the Associated Press. <br> <br>Q    Hey, there.  Thanks for doing the call.  I was actually hoping you could elaborate just on that final point about the forced labor in China.  Could you talk a little bit more about what the President said and how it was received in the room by others?  And is there an agreement that could be mentioned in the communiqué, which I know White House officials had previously said was a hope?<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah, I think the communiqué is still being negotiated, as I think &#8212; as I think these things often are up until the final &#8212; the final day, which is tomorrow. <br> <br>There are certainly discussions around that issue of forced labor.  It&#8217;s a &#8212; I think it&#8217;s a representation of democratic values (inaudible) in action that I think the President certainly feels strongly about &#8212; a willingness to call out, if possible &#8212; there&#8217;s consensus from the G7. <br> <br>So there&#8217;s certainly &#8212; I think there are a number of areas that you&#8217;ll see in the communiqué where some of our &#8212; I think the values element of the &#8212; of this grouping of democratic, like-minded allies, where we&#8217;re trying to show those values in concrete ways and in concrete actions. <br> <br>And I think &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if they&#8217;ve shared some of the thoughts on some of the deliverables that may emerge from &#8212; or at least, kind of, live issues that are being discussed.  But, you know, kind of, there are some other efforts around the &#8220;Build Back Better World,&#8221; and what exactly that looks like. <br> <br>You heard the announcements around the vaccines, which I think is also kind of a values component of, I think, the G7 really showing a shared commitment on an incredibly important issue, not just the kind of &#8220;vaccinate their own &#8212; the people in their own countries,&#8221; but kind of really make a concrete commitment to be there for the rest of the world and show, I think, what democratic leadership can look like in practice. <br> <br>The Build Back Better World &#8212; which, I think, again, was talked about a little further here &#8212; again, offers what I think is a more positive way forward in the development (inaudible) space and something that could be, I think, really meaningful for many countries that won&#8217;t have to take on incredible debt or some of the, I think &#8212; some of the challenges that has arisen so far and some of the deals that have been put together through the BRI in the past. <br> <br>There&#8217;s the element of forced labor in Xinjiang and just kind of the belief in &#8212; I think, in human rights and dignity of people that I think carries over to other areas, such as the global minimum tax and whether something may emerge there that, I think, also is connected to a sense of values and belief in the dignity of workers and avoiding the race to the bottom and some of the some of the issues in that regard as well. <br> <br>So there&#8217;s a whole slew.  And then also ransomware.  There&#8217;s also been some very interesting discussions in, kind of, the recognition that, I think, a lot of these global challenges are things that are across borders, whether it&#8217;s the vaccine or ransomware.  Issues that, I think, countries &#8212; if they&#8217;re able to kind of come on the same page and tackle together &#8212; are going to be a lot stronger as a bloc.  Whether they pay ransoms or not, I think, can have some meaningful input and kind of having a collective stance there.<br> <br>Anti-corruption is another thing that&#8217;s being discussed as a live issue and, kind of, really trying, again, to, kind of, put values in action. <br> <br>So that&#8217;s just kind of a snapshot.  And I think the China issue, as a whole &#8212; the coordination on China is one of the more complicated and thorny ones, where there is a greater spectrum of &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s agreement across the board that there needs to be greater coordination and action taken and a willingness to call out some of the challenges that exist. <br> <br>But I think there is that spectrum of how far different countries are willing to go, and I think that was certainly a little bit evident.  But, I think, also, with, kind of &#8212; taking a step back, with a sense that these leaders really seem to like each other and to respect one another and to, kind of, want to work through and find, kind of, where that sweet spot might be. <br> <br>And I think our hunch is that the leaders communiqué, as a whole &#8212; and that that will come out tomorrow &#8212; will have some meaningful points in that regard.  And I think that it should be an exciting, exciting press conference that will follow tomorrow&#8217;s (inaudible) as well.  <br> <br>And there&#8217;s a foreign policy session that comes next.  I think it&#8217;s starting very quick &#8212; very shortly.  And that&#8217;s going to cover, I think, a lot of the more live foreign policy issues outside of the &#8212; of the past discussion and, I think, touch on the spectrum of challenges from Russia and the Russian &#8212;<br> <br>(The call is interrupted by an audio drop.)<br> <br>(The call resumes.)<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  …the President&#8217;s Climate Summit in Washington, just the road to COP 26 in upping the ambition in the road ahead with potential new commitments and some areas of extra focus and attention that the G7 has been discussing (inaudible) as well and some discussions over potential outputs that could emerge in the Leaders&#8217; Communiqué. <br> <br>And (inaudible) closing press conference that would then follow where, I think, it will be a chance to reflect on the six plenary discussions and sessions, and then also to talk a bit about some of the outputs and potential deliverables that have hopefully reached consensus through the communiqué and the negotiations that have been happening around the periphery of the &#8212; of the Leaders&#8217; Summit and the plenary sessions themselves.<br> <br>MODERATOR:  Thanks so much.  I know [senior administration official] is between sessions, so we&#8217;ll try to continue to get through as many questions as we can. <br> <br>Next, let&#8217;s go to Yamiche Alcindor with PBS.<br> <br>Q    Hi.  Thanks so much for taking my question.  I&#8217;m wondering if you could talk a little bit more about what exactly President Biden wants to see when it comes to actions on China and what the most contentious disagreements are on what actually should happen.  What does he want to see?  And what maybe are other countries saying they want to see that&#8217;s different?  If you could give more details on that. <br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah.  No, it&#8217;s a good question.  I mean, I think the &#8212; again, I think the two, kind of, top-of-mind, hot-button issues that was discussed this morning, at least, in some depth was the issue around forced labor and, kind of, that being just, I think, one example, I think, of a larger willingness to call out some of the human rights practices, some of the &#8212; a kind of an unwillingness to play by the same set of rules as the rest of the international community. <br> <br>And I think, kind of, that being &#8212; the February 19th Leaders &#8212; there was a statement that was released at &#8212; in the virtual meeting.  And it was the first time, I think, that China was, kind of, called out as &#8212; for a willingness for the G7, as whole, to do more coordination around issues that are emanating from that &#8212; the way they are engaging in the international system. <br> <br>So, I think that the labor &#8212; forced labor being one issue.  The Build Back Better World &#8212; I think it&#8217;s a really ambitious initiative and idea that had stemmed from a conversation with Prime Minister Johnson and President Biden, where, I think, they both, you know, had kind of talked about that Build Back Better framing and slogan, and had wanted to kind of do something that was ambitious in practice and, kind of, in alignment on recognizing a lot of partners in the developing world, kind of, being taken advantage of in some ways, through investments that they received with the Belt and Road and other financing deals.  And I think offering &#8212; trying to figure out there was a more values-driven &#8212; just something else that could be offered. <br> <br>Not that, I think, it &#8212; the hope is that, you know, potentially if China ultimately would sign up or kind of want to be part of the Build Back Better World, I don&#8217;t think that that is something that would be off the table, as long as they&#8217;re willing to up their standards and to kind of take on some of the infrastructure space and the more values &#8212; higher-standard way. <br> <br>There was also discussions on &#8212; a little bit of discussion around some of the international institutions and just the way China, I think, is engaging itself at the WTO, for example, or within other IOs.  And just how, as a &#8212; you know, a bloc of leading democracies, how they &#8212; and how forcefully they need to call out some of the &#8212; some of the efforts that are causing some real harm for both relationships bilaterally with the G7, I think, as a grouping, and then, just as importantly, for other countries around the globe who, I think, are being strong-armed in some way on some of the policies that are being put into practice. <br> <br>MODERATOR:  Great.  Thank you. <br> <br>Next, let&#8217;s go to Franco Ordoñez with NPR. <br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  And I think I&#8217;m going to have to run in soon because I think they&#8217;re &#8212; they&#8217;re going to start the next session, I believe &#8212; <br> <br>MODERATOR:  So, this will be last question. <br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Okay. <br> <br>Q    Hey, thanks so much for doing this.  I&#8217;ll try to be &#8212; I&#8217;ll try to be quick with the question.  You know, this &#8212; President Biden is, you know, not the first to try to do &#8212; you know, meet this need and offer an alternative to Belt and Road.  And less-developed countries have also said they would rather work with the United States and the West; they have, you know, many common, shared goals. <br> <br>But they&#8217;ve also, you know, struggled and have a lot of needs &#8212; and very short-term needs &#8212; to have jobs, build infrastructure projects.<br> <br>I was hoping you could share a little bit more concrete about what you think the Allies can do.  I mean, how big do you think this fund could be?  Because, so far, China has been able to do this in ways that the United States could not.  I mean, what &#8212; I mean, how &#8212; how big do you think this fund could be &#8212; need to be to make this actually work so that the United States and the Allies could actually compete in a concrete way?<br> <br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:  Yeah.  No, that&#8217;s a great &#8212; that&#8217;s a good question.  I think that, kind of, the way folks are viewing this is that they want to be able to provide, you know, some sort of a credible offer to the developing world, not necessarily, again, in contrast to &#8212; in direct contrast (inaudible) forcing countries to make a choice between, I think, what a &#8220;Build Back Their World&#8221; infrastructure or opportunity might look like &#8212; or offer might look like, or something else.<br> <br>I think it&#8217;s more, kind of, a recognition that there remains a huge infrastructure gap globally &#8212; just as there does, I think, in the United States, as well.  And, kind of, an opportunity to do something meaningful in a way that is different than, kind of, the current options &#8212; or leading option, I think, that many countries are resorting to. <br> <br>So I think that &#8212; certainly a credible number that at least shows that there could be some &#8212; some real, meaningful efforts that could be funded in that regard &#8212; in, kind of, doing the funding in a &#8212; in a more value-driven; hopefully more of, kind of, an equity- versus debt-financed type way. <br> <br>But, again, a lot of the concrete details are still being &#8212; would be worked through.  It would be, I think, more of a decentralized structure of sorts.  It would kind of tap into some of the development finance institutions among G7 members and some of the efforts that currently are happening and &#8212; with different priorities of different sectors. <br> <br>Certainly, from the U.S. perspective, there&#8217;s a heavy emphasis on climate &#8212; the climate infrastructure space, the health infrastructure space, the digital technology infrastructure space, and the gender equality/gender equity infrastructure space as well &#8212; and, kind of, finding ways to, I think, help partners around the globe invest in some of those areas and do it in a credible, high-standard, values-driven way. <br> <br>MODERATOR:  Thanks so much.  And thanks so much, everybody, for joining us today.  We&#8217;ll do another couple of these today, and so just keep an eye out on your emails for registration and Zoom links, and appreciate everyone&#8217;s flexibility on time. <br> <br>Have a good day. <br> <br>1:13 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President Biden and G7 Leaders Launch Build Back Better World (B3W) Partnership</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/12/fact-sheet-president-biden-and-g7-leaders-launch-build-back-better-world-b3w-partnership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is rallying the world’s democracies to deliver for our people, meet the world’s biggest challenges, and demonstrate our shared values Today President Biden met with G7 leaders to discuss strategic competition with China and commit to concrete actions to help meet the tremendous infrastructure need in low- and middle-income countries. Build Back&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>The United States is rallying the world’s democracies to deliver for our people, meet the world’s biggest challenges, and demonstrate our shared values</em></p>



<p>Today President Biden met with G7 leaders to discuss strategic competition with China and commit to concrete actions to help meet the tremendous infrastructure need in low- and middle-income countries.<br><br><strong>Build Back Better World: An Affirmative Initiative for Meeting the Tremendous Infrastructure Needs of Low- and Middle-Income Countries. </strong>President Biden and G7 partners agreed to launch the bold new global infrastructure initiative Build Back Better World (B3W), a values-driven, high-standard, and transparent infrastructure partnership led by major democracies to help narrow the $40+ trillion infrastructure need in the developing world, which has been exacerbated by the COVID-19 pandemic.<br><br>Through B3W, the G7 and other like-minded partners with coordinate in mobilizing private-sector capital in four areas of focus—climate, health and health security, digital technology, and gender equity and equality—with catalytic investments from our respective development finance institutions.<br><br>B3W will be global in scope, from Latin America and the Caribbean to Africa to the Indo-Pacific. Different G7 partners will have different geographic orientations, but the sum of the initiative will cover low- and middle-income countries across the world. <br><br>In announcing this partnership, the United States and its G7 partners are expressing a unified vision for global infrastructure development. As a lead partner in B3W, the United States will seek to mobilize the full potential of our development finance tools, including the Development Finance Corporation, USAID, EXIM, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, and the U.S. Trade and Development Agency, and complementary bodies such as the Transaction Advisory Fund. In doing so, the Biden Administration aims to complement domestic infrastructure investments in the American Jobs Plan and create new opportunities to demonstrate U.S. competitiveness abroad and create jobs at home.<br><br>In addition to the billions of dollars which the United States mobilizes in overseas infrastructure financing through existing bilateral and multilateral tools, we will work with Congress to augment our development finance toolkit with the hope that, together with the private sector, other U.S. stakeholders, and G7 partners, <strong>B3W will collectively catalyze hundreds of billions of dollars of infrastructure investment for low- and middle-income countries in the coming years</strong>.<br><br>Together with leaders of the G7, the Biden Administration fully endorses the guiding principles of B3W:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Values-Driven. </strong>Infrastructure development carried out in a transparent and sustainable manner—financially, environmentally, and socially —will lead to a better outcome for recipient countries and communities. We will offer countries a positive vision and a sustainable, transparent source of financing to meet their infrastructure needs.</li><li><strong>Good Governance and Strong Standards</strong>. High standards have become ever more important at a time when governments are grappling with complex decisions on how to tackle climate change, build back local economies, direct scarce financing, and boost employment in an inclusive way. We are committed to providing citizens of recipient communities with the long-run benefits they expect and deserve from infrastructure projects. Our efforts will be guided by high standards and principles, such as those promoted by the updated Blue Dot Network, relating to the environment and climate, labor and social safeguards, transparency, financing, construction, anticorruption, and other areas.</li><li><strong>Climate-Friendly. </strong>The investments will be made in a manner consistent with achieving the goals of the Paris Climate Agreement.</li><li><strong>Strong Strategic Partnerships. </strong>Infrastructure that is developed in partnership with those whom it benefits will last longer and generate more development impact. Infrastructure created under the B3W will be developed through consultation with communities and assessing local needs as a true partners. We will establish a taskforce together as a G7, and with others, to coordinate, harmonize our efforts, and increase our impact and reach<strong>.</strong></li><li><strong>Mobilize Private Capital Through Development Finance. </strong>Status quo funding and financing approaches are inadequate to address the tremendous infrastructure gap in low- and middle-income countries. We are committed to augmenting the development finance tools at our disposal to support and catalyze a significant increase in private capital to address infrastructure needs. Infrastructure investment by a responsible and market-driven private sector, paired with high standards and transparency in public funding, is crucial for long-run development effectiveness and sustainability.</li><li><strong>Enhancing the Impact of Multilateral Public Finance.  </strong>Multilateral development banks and other international financial institutions (IFIs) have developed rigorous standards for project planning, implementation, social and environmental safeguards, and analytical capability. The United States will incorporate these standards and safeguards to help ensure that U.S. taxpayer resources are used appropriately and effectively. We will work with the IFIs to enhance their catalytic impact and increase the mobilization of capital—both public and private—needed for impactful and sustainable infrastructure investment.</li></ul>



<p>More detail will be included in the G7 Leaders’ Communique.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials Previewing the Second Day of the G7 Summit</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/12/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-previewing-the-second-day-of-the-g7-summit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[June 11, 2021 7:13 P.M. BST MODERATOR:&#160; Good evening, everyone.&#160; Thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing, and apologies for running a few minutes behind.&#160;In today&#8217;s background briefing, we&#8217;re going to preview tomorrow&#8217;s G7 working session on China.&#160; This call will be on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and under&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">June 11, 2021</p>



<p>7:13 P.M. BST</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Good evening, everyone.&nbsp; Thank you so much for joining us for this background briefing, and apologies for running a few minutes behind.<br>&nbsp;<br>In today&#8217;s background briefing, we&#8217;re going to preview tomorrow&#8217;s G7 working session on China.&nbsp; This call will be on background, attributable to &#8220;senior administration officials,&#8221; and under embargo until Saturday, June 12th, 7:00 a.m. British Summer Time.&nbsp; We, of course, will have some time for Q&amp;A at the end.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Not for reporting or attribution, but just for your knowledge, on today&#8217;s call we have joining us [senior administration officials].<br>&nbsp;<br>With that, I&#8217;ll pass it off to [senior administration official] to kick us off.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks very much.&nbsp; So, first, I&#8217;ll do a quick roundup of today.&nbsp; Today was the first G7 working session on the global economy, where President Biden and G7 leaders discussed ways to forge a more fair, sustainable, inclusive global economy.<br>&nbsp;<br>We also announced that President Biden will welcome German Chancellor Angela Merkel to the White House on July 15th &#8212; a visit that will affirm the deep bilateral ties between the U.S. and Germany.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And following on the President’s speech last night, the G7 and guest countries agreed to provide more than 1 billion additional COVID-19 vaccines for the world, starting, effectively, now.<br>&nbsp;<br>Looking ahead to tomorrow, I wanted to give some context and subtext.&nbsp; We are obviously not looking to make China the overriding issue while we&#8217;re in Europe.&nbsp; It isn’t the focus or the headline of many of the deliverables my colleague will go through in a minute.<br>&nbsp;<br>But many of them also happen to be in service of positioning the United States and our partners to better compete with China, just as is the case with some of our most important domestic steps, like those concerning getting our economy back in line and getting our arms around the pandemic &#8212; steps that have allowed the United States to reengage with the world from a position of strength.<br>&nbsp;<br>This is not about making countries choose between us and China; this is about offering an affirmative, alternative vision and approach that they would want to choose.&nbsp; So, what we are promoting is a confident, positive agenda focused around rallying other countries that share our values on the issues that matter most.<br>&nbsp;<br>What does that mean?&nbsp; On vaccines: As we’ve said, we and our G7 partners are providing more than a billion additional COVID-19 vaccine doses for the world, of which the U.S. will contribute half a billion doses to the developing world.&nbsp; For us, this is about saving lives and ending the pandemic.&nbsp; This is not about coercion or transactional political or economic favors.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>On infrastructure, we’ll be announcing a bold, new global infrastructure initiative with our G7 partners that will be values-driven, transparent, and sustainable.&nbsp; There is, by some estimates, a $40 trillion infrastructure gap in parts of the world that this would be intended to help other countries fill.&nbsp; My colleague will be saying more about this in a moment, but we believe that it stands in stark contrast to the way that some other countries have handled efforts around infrastructure.<br>&nbsp;<br>At NATO, which will be next on the President&#8217;s agenda after the G7 wraps up &#8212; this will be the first time that the NATO countries will be addressing the security challenge from China directly in a communiqué.<br>&nbsp;<br>At the EU Summit, which will also take place in Brussels, we will be addressing the trade and technology and other challenges in the U.S.-EU relationship and also the opportunities those issues present so that we can focus on writing the rules of the road on these issues together as democracies, and not leave that work to the autocracies of the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>So we are doing the careful hard work of diplomacy, of rallying our friends and allies.&nbsp; We’re not looking to simply score a bunch of rhetorical points on China.&nbsp; And this is how we believe our endeavors will be most successful.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the contrast between approach and China&#8217;s, on these and other issues, is really &#8212; should speak for itself.&nbsp; As the President likes to say, &#8220;It&#8217;s never a good bet to bet against America,&#8221; and I think that we are proving that point already in the context of G7 and the other meetings I described.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So with that, I will turn it over to my colleague to talk about tomorrow&#8217;s G7 session.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, thanks.&nbsp; Can everybody hear me?&nbsp; Just to do a soundcheck.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Yes, go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; So as [senior administration official] mentioned, tomorrow&#8217;s morning session at the G7 will be on China.&nbsp; I want to give you a heads up on two specific areas of focus: one, a new G7 infrastructure partnership called &#8220;Build Back Better for the World&#8221;; and, second, to give you an update on what we&#8217;re saying and what we&#8217;re doing about forced labor.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, first, on the infrastructure initiative, the United States and many of our partners and friends around the world have long been skeptical about China&#8217;s Belt and Road Initiative.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen the Chinese government demonstrate a lack of transparency, poor environmental and labor standards, and a course of approach that&#8217;s left many countries worse off.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But until now, we haven&#8217;t offered a positive alternative that reflects our values, our standards, and our way of doing business.&nbsp; So, tomorrow, we&#8217;ll be announcing &#8220;Build Back Better for the World,&#8221; an ambitious, new global infrastructure initiative with our G7 partners that won&#8217;t just be an alternative to the BRI, but we believe will beat the BRI by offering a higher-quality choice.&nbsp; And we&#8217;ll offer that choice of self-confidence about our model that reflects our shared values.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, as we come together on this partnership, our G7 partners have agreed that our real purpose here is to demonstrate that democracies and open societies can come together and deliver a positive choice to meet some of the biggest challenges of our time, not just for our people, but for people all over the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And let&#8217;s be clear, as [senior administration official] alluded to: The needs in the developing world for high-quality infrastructure &#8212; whether it&#8217;s physical infrastructure, digital infrastructure, health infrastructure, or a way to deal with gender disparities &#8212; are large and growing, and made especially worse after the pandemic.<br>&nbsp;<br>The World Bank estimates there&#8217;s a cumulative $40 trillion of infrastructure needs in the developing world through 2035.&nbsp; And &#8220;Build Back Better for the World,&#8221; or B3W, is an affirmative way to meet that need while meeting the highest labor and environmental standards, providing transparency, and mobilizing the private sector to invest with us.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;ll be happy to say more if you have questions.&nbsp; But let me turn now to forced labor.&nbsp; And so, President Biden in tomorrow&#8217;s session will also be pressing his fellow leaders for concrete action on forced labor to make clear to the world that we believe these practices are an affront to human dignity and an egregious example of China&#8217;s unfair economic competition.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I&#8217;m not going to get ahead of the discussions tomorrow, but I can share a little bit more about the U.S. perspective and how we view the issue.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, when we think of forced labor &#8212; and, look, we &#8212; it&#8217;s an expression of our shared values to make clear what we won&#8217;t tolerate as the United States and as a G7.&nbsp; So we think it&#8217;s critical to call out the use of forced labor in Xinjiang and to take concrete actions to ensure that global supply chains are free from the use of forced labor.<br>&nbsp;<br>And the point is to send a wakeup call that the G7 is serious about defending human rights and that we need to work together to eradicate forced labor from our products.<br>&nbsp;<br>Let me pause there.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp; So now we’ve got some time for some Q&amp;A, so if you have a question, please use the “raise hand” function on the Zoom interface, and we’ll try to get through as many questions as we can.&nbsp; So, again, please use the “raise hand” function on the Zoom interface, and we’ll call on as much as we have time for.</p>



<p>Let’s first go to Anne Gearan of The Washington Post.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, could you talk a little bit more about the China piece of this and describe for us what the other G7 countries, to the best of your knowledge, are willing to do in terms of taking on China more frontally?&nbsp; Obviously, a lot of these other countries have different trading relationships and, in some cases, far deeper trading relationships than even the United States.&nbsp; What are they willing to do, and how confident can you be that, in this context, they’re going to be with you in confronting China?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Anne.&nbsp; So, I mean, I guess, as I said, this is not just about confronting or taking on China.&nbsp; This is about providing an affirmative, positive, alternative vision for the world than that that is presented by China and, in some similar ways but also in some different ways, Russia.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, the President talks often about this contest of democracies and autocracies.&nbsp; And for him, that is not an abstract question of political science or even purely a moral or values-based question &#8212; although I think he does have strong feelings about the values element of democracy.&nbsp; It is actually, first and foremost, about whether the democratic system can continue to deliver for its own people, for the people of our partner democracies, and for the citizens of the world.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so what this G7 meeting is, first and foremost, about is proving that point: that democracies &#8212; the leading democracies &#8212; when they come together, can deliver.&nbsp; I think we’re seeing that in the context of the vaccines announcement.&nbsp; We’re going to see that in the context of the infrastructure announcement that we’ve described, and some of the other steps they’re going to be taking during the course of this week.<br>&nbsp;<br>But, in many ways, that’s going to be the most important work.&nbsp; It’s not a confrontation, but basically a presentation of a model that we believe, to this day, remains more appealing.&nbsp; There are other contexts in which, you know, we will talk about taking China on more directly, but this meeting is really focused on an affirmative vision.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next, we’ll go to Andrea Mitchell with MSNBC.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you all so much.&nbsp; Regarding Vladimir Putin, as you head into Geneva &#8212; NATO first, of course; the G7; and then to Geneva &#8212; has his crackdown on Navalny’s operation, calling them “extremists,” indicated to you that having a stable and predictable relationship with Vladimir Putin, as the President had said (inaudible) he wants to, is going to be very difficult to achieve?&nbsp; And does that change your posture going into this summit?&nbsp; Thank you.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Andrea.&nbsp; You know, we’re under no illusions that this is going to be an easy relationship; it is going to be an extremely challenging relationship.&nbsp; And I think we’ve been quite clear about that.</p>



<p>And the President has been very clear in two phone calls now with President Putin that, perhaps unlike some of his predecessors, he is not going to simply elide or gloss over the differences that we have; he’s going to take them on with candor and directly.&nbsp; And that where Russia crosses lines that we consider to be unacceptable, we will impose costs on Russia for doing that.<br>&nbsp;<br>You know, he has said that directly to the Russian president, and then he has lived by that in some of the steps that we’ve rolled out, including with regard to the poisoning of Aleksey Navalny.<br>&nbsp;<br>So, I think that &#8212; without getting ahead of the conversation that has yet to take place between the two leaders &#8212; I think the conversation that &#8212; that the meeting in Geneva will be held in a very similar vein to what I’ve just described.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next, we’ll go to Steve Holland with Reuters.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This is actually Andrew Restuccia with the Wall Street Journal.&nbsp; We’re all sitting together by the pool listening to the call on speaker.&nbsp; But, I just wanted to ask if you would &#8212; if you expect, in the G7 communiqué, to name China specifically, or if it will be sort of a more subtle reference to China?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And then, separately, how much do you expect the G7 to put toward this global infrastructure proposal?&nbsp; Is there an overall number?&nbsp; And how far will it go to closing this $40 trillion infrastructure gap?&nbsp; Thanks.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, do you want the first, and I can take the second?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I think you probably should take both, given that you&#8217;re &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; &#8212; directly involved in this.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, so, you know, we&#8217;re in the middle of these negotiations.&nbsp; The communiqué doesn&#8217;t actually get finalized until Sunday.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>But suffice it to say that China has been an animating topic throughout these discussions, and, you know &#8212; and it&#8217;s very much &#8212; as [senior administration official] described, the conversation is very much about this contest that President Biden speaks of between those who think that autocracy is the best path forward and those, like us, who understand that democracies and our shared values provide the best path for delivering for our people and also meeting the biggest challenges in the world.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, the communiqué reflects those conversations as it&#8217;s taking shape.&nbsp; And, look, we&#8217;re pushing for being specific on areas like Xinjiang, where forced labor is taking place and where we have to express our values as a G7.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>It&#8217;s too early to say what will end up in the final.&nbsp; But certainly that&#8217;s our position, and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;ve been advocating for.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the second question, in terms of the size &#8212; the potential size of this infrastructure initiative: Let me just say that, in addition to the billions of dollars which the U.S. already mobilizes in overseas infrastructure financing through our bilateral tools and also our multilateral institutions, our plan is to work with Congress to augment our development finance toolkit with the hope that &#8212; together with G7 partners, the private sector, and other stakeholders &#8212; we’ll soon be collectively catalyzing hundreds of billions of dollars in infrastructure investment for low- and middle-income countries that need it.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>So, that&#8217;s a credible scale.&nbsp; There&#8217;s no real way to estimate how large some of the other large &#8212; some of the other major infrastructure programs are in the world, including the BRI, that don&#8217;t have the same degree of transparency.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re aiming for an ambitious and credible scale.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Next, we&#8217;ll go to David Sanger with the New York Times.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Two questions related to the next couple of days.&nbsp; All of you and President Biden have made it pretty clear that you want to put together some rules of the road, or guardrails, on cyber, similar to what some of the summits have done in the past in other areas &#8212; terrorism, nuclear, and so forth.&nbsp; Can you tell us how that&#8217;s going to play out at G7 and NATO?&nbsp; And then, if there are any specific proposals for Mr. Putin?&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And we hear there have been some developments in the effort about whether or not the President and Mr. Putin will be speaking publicly together in any form in Geneva, if you could give us an update on that.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Did we lose you, [senior administration official]?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; Sorry.&nbsp; I muted myself.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry about that.&nbsp; So, David, on cyber, I think you&#8217;re going to see that this is featured prominently in every single one of the key meetings on this overseas trip.&nbsp; It&#8217;s going to be featured prominently in the G7 conversations.&nbsp; We can say more about that if you want.&nbsp; I think in the EU Summit and at the NATO Summit, you&#8217;re going to see a discussion around the recent spate of ransomware attacks and the threats to critical infrastructure.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>And certainly, in the conversation with President Putin, you can expect &#8212; as it has been raised in the past in the conversations between the two leaders &#8212; for the President to raise it very directly and make clear our expectations of the government of Russia to address the threat that is emanating from its territory.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>Whether these ransomware attackers are state actors or not, they are present on Russian soil, in many cases, and we believe it’s the responsibility of the Russian government to address that, as it would be for any state that has criminals acting inside its territory.<br>&nbsp;<br>And so that will be made very clear to President Putin.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of outcomes or the conversation in any more detail than that.<br>&nbsp;<br>You asked also about the public dimension of that meeting, and I don&#8217;t think we&#8217;ve got more to say about that at this point, but I know that there&#8217;s a lot of interest in it, and I expect we&#8217;ll have more to say about that soon.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And just a &#8212;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Go ahead.<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Just to pick up on [senior administration official]’s comment about ransomware and the discussion about cyber within the G7 context: And I would just say &#8212; I mean, there&#8217;s uniform recognition that ransomware and the abuse of virtual currencies is an urgent threat, it’s an escalating threat.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s been a productive discussion, I would say, in terms of how we can share information to support prosecutions, how we can hold criminal networks to account, and also how we can modernize our cyber defenses.<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; I think we, unfortunately, have time for one last question, so let&#8217;s go to Betsy Klein with CNN.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, this is Kaitlan Collins.&nbsp; Just to follow up on David&#8217;s question: When Biden&#8217;s predecessor met with Putin, no staff was in the room, with the exception of interpreters.&nbsp; So, can you confirm who from the U.S. side will be in the room when they meet next week?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, I think the answer to that is: We can&#8217;t yet.&nbsp; You know, I suspect that the meeting will take place with some multiple formats &#8212; maybe some small or maybe some larger &#8212; but we do not have the information to confirm yet exactly who is going to be in the meeting.&nbsp; But we know, as I said, that there&#8217;s a lot of interest in that question, and I expect we&#8217;ll have more to say about it soon.<br>&nbsp;<br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you at least confirm that there will be staff in the room beyond just translators?<br>&nbsp;<br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I mean, again, I&#8217;m not going to confirm any of the format information.&nbsp; I think, well before the summit, you will hear more from us on this.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Alrighty.&nbsp; Thanks so much, everyone, for joining us this evening.&nbsp; Again, this call is on background attributable to “senior administration officials,” embargoed until 7:00 a.m. British Summer Time, tomorrow, June 12th.&nbsp; We&#8217;ll talk to you all again very soon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>7:33 P.M. BST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Memorandum for the Secretary of State on Unexpected Urgent Refugee and Migration Needs</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/11/memorandum-for-the-secretary-of-state-on-unexpected-urgent-refugee-and-migration-needs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 21:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=20497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&#160;2(c)(1) of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 (22 U.S.C. 2601(c)(1)) (MRAA), I hereby determine, pursuant to section&#160;2(c)(1) of the MRAA, that it is important to the national interest to furnish assistance&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including section&nbsp;2(c)(1) of the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 (22 U.S.C. 2601(c)(1)) (MRAA), I hereby determine, pursuant to section&nbsp;2(c)(1) of the MRAA, that it is important to the national interest to furnish assistance under the MRAA in an amount not to exceed $46&nbsp;million from the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund for the purpose of meeting unexpected urgent refugee and migration needs, including through contributions to international organizations by the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration of the Department of State, related to the humanitarian needs of vulnerable refugees and migrants in Central America and third countries in the region.<br><br>You are authorized and directed to submit this determination to the Congress, along with the accompanying Justification, and to publish this determination in the <em>Federal Register.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
