<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 13:00:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png</url>
	<title>Briefing Room &#8211; The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Juneteenth Day of Observance, 2021</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/06/18/a-proclamation-on-juneteenth-day-of-observance-2021/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 13:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21365</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On June 19, 1865 &#8212; nearly nine decades after our Nation&#8217;s founding, and more than 2 years after President Lincoln signed the Emancipation Proclamation &#8212; enslaved Americans in&#160;Galveston, Texas, finally received word that they were free from bondage. &#160;As those who were formerly enslaved were recognized for the first time as citizens, Black Americans came&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On June 19, 1865 &#8212; nearly nine decades after our Nation&#8217;s founding, and more than 2 years after President Lincoln signed the Emancipation Proclamation &#8212; enslaved Americans in&nbsp;Galveston, Texas, finally received word that they were free from bondage. &nbsp;As those who were formerly enslaved were recognized for the first time as citizens, Black Americans came to commemorate Juneteenth with&nbsp;celebrations across the country, building new lives and a&nbsp;new tradition that we honor today. &nbsp;In its celebration of freedom, Juneteenth is a day that should be recognized by all Americans. And that is why I am proud to have consecrated Juneteenth as our newest national holiday.</p>



<p>Juneteenth is a day of profound weight and power.</p>



<p>A day in which we remember the moral stain and terrible toll of slavery on our country –- what I&#8217;ve long called America&#8217;s original sin. &nbsp;A long legacy of systemic racism, inequality, and inhumanity.</p>



<p>But it is a day that also reminds us of our incredible capacity to heal, hope, and emerge from our darkest moments with purpose and resolve.</p>



<p>As I said on the 100th Anniversary of the Tulsa Race Massacre, great nations don&#8217;t ignore the most painful chapters of their past. Great nations confront them. &nbsp;We come to terms with them.</p>



<p>On Juneteenth, we recommit ourselves to the work of equity, equality, and justice.&nbsp; And, we celebrate the centuries of&nbsp;struggle, courage, and hope that have brought us to this time&nbsp;of progress and possibility. &nbsp;That work has been led throughout our history by abolitionists and educators, civil&nbsp;rights advocates and lawyers, courageous activists and&nbsp;trade unionists, public officials, and everyday Americans who have helped make real the ideals of our founding documents for all.</p>



<p>There is still more work to do. &nbsp;As we emerge from the long, dark winter of the COVID-19 pandemic, for example, racial equity remains at the heart of our efforts to vaccinate the Nation and beat the virus. &nbsp;We must recognize that Black Americans, among other people of color, have shouldered a disproportionate burden of loss &#8212; while also carrying us through disproportionately as essential workers and health care providers on the front lines of the crisis.</p>



<p>Psalm 30 proclaims that &#8220;weeping may endure for a night, but joy cometh in the morning.&#8221;&nbsp; Juneteenth marks both the long, hard night of slavery and discrimination, and the promise of a&nbsp;brighter morning to come.&nbsp; My Administration is committed to&nbsp;building an economy &#8212; and a Nation &#8212; that brings everyone along, and finally delivers our Nation&#8217;s founding promise to Black Americans.&nbsp; Together, we will lay the roots of real and lasting justice, so that we can become the extraordinary country that was promised to all Americans.</p>



<p>Juneteenth not only commemorates the past.&nbsp; It calls us to action today.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in&nbsp;me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim June 19, 2021, as Juneteenth Day of Observance.&nbsp; I call upon the people of the United States to acknowledge and celebrate the end of the Civil War and the emancipation of Black Americans, and commit together to eradicate systemic racism that still undermines our founding ideals and collective prosperity.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this eighteenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-one, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-fifth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President Biden at Signing of the Juneteenth National Independence Day Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/17/remarks-by-president-biden-at-signing-of-the-juneteenth-national-independence-day-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 3:51 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT: Thank you, thank you, thank you. Well, thank you, Madam Vice President. One hundred and fifty-six years ago &#8212; one hundred and fifty-six years &#8212; June 19th, 1865 &#8212; John, thanks for being here &#8212; a major general of the Union Army arrived in Galveston, Texas, to enforce&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>3:51 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>Well, thank you, Madam Vice President.<br><br>One hundred and fifty-six years ago &#8212; one hundred and fifty-six years &#8212; June 19th, 1865 &#8212; John, thanks for being here &#8212; a major general of the Union Army arrived in Galveston, Texas, to enforce the Emancipation Proclamation and free the last enslaved Americans in Texas from bondage. A day, as you all know &#8212; I’m going to repeat some of what was said &#8212; that became known as Juneteenth. You all know that. A day that reflects what the Psalm tell us: “Weeping may endure for a night, but joy cometh in the morning.”<br><br>Juneteenth marks both the long, hard night of slavery and subjugation, and a promise of a brighter morning to come. This is a day of profound &#8212; in my view &#8212; profound weight and profound power.<br><br>A day in which we remember the moral stain, the terrible toll that slavery took on the country and continues to take &#8212; what I’ve long called “America’s original sin.”<br><br>At the same time, I also remember the extraordinary capacity to heal, and to hope, and to emerge from the most painful moments and a bitter, bitter version of ourselves, but to make a better version of ourselves.<br><br>You know, today, we consecrate Juneteenth for what it ought to be, what it must be: a national holiday. As the Vice President noted, a holiday that will join the others of our national celebrations: our independence, our laborers who built this nation, our servicemen and women who served and died in its defense. And the first new national holiday since the creation of Martin Luther King Holiday nearly four decades ago.<br><br>I am grateful to the members of Congress here today &#8212; in particular, the Congressional Black Caucus, who did so much to make this day possible.<br><br>I’m especially pleased that we showed the nation that we can come together as Democrats and Republicans to commemorate this day with the overwhelming bipartisan support of the Congress. I hope this is the beginning of a change in the way we deal with one another.<br><br>And we’re blessed &#8212; we’re blessed to mark the day in the presence of Ms. Opal Lee. As my mother would say, “God love her.” (Applause.)<br><br>I had the honor of meeting her in Nevada more than a year ago. She told me she loved me, and I believed it. (Laughter.) I wanted to believe it. (Laughs.) Ms. Opal, you’re incredible. A daughter of Texas. Grandmother of the movement to make Juneteenth a federal holiday.<br><br>And Ms. Opal is &#8212; you won’t believe it &#8212; she’s 49 years old. (Laughter.) Or 94 years old, but I &#8212; (laughter). You are an incredible woman, Ms. Opal. You really are.<br><br>As a child growing up in Texas, she and her family would celebrate Juneteenth. On Juneteenth, 1939, when she was 12 years old, the white &#8212; a white mob torched her family home. But such hate never stopped her any more than it stopped the vast majority of you I’m looking at from this podium.<br><br>Over the course of decades, she’s made it her mission to see that this day came. It was almost a singular mission. She’s walked for miles and miles, literally and figuratively, to bring attention to Juneteenth, to make this day possible.<br><br>I ask, once again, we all stand and give her a warm welcome to the White House. (Applause.)<br><br>As they still say in the Senate and I said for 36 years, &#8220;if you excuse me there for a point of personal privilege,&#8221; as I was walking down, I regret that my grandchildren aren’t here because this is a really, really, really important moment in our history.<br><br>By making Juneteenth a federal holiday, all Americans can feel the power of this day, and learn from our history, and celebrate progress, and grapple with the distance we’ve come but the distance we have to travel, Jim.<br><br>You know, I said a few weeks ago, marking the 100th anniversary of the Tulsa Race Massacre, great nations don’t ignore their most painful moments. Great nations don’t ignore their most painful moments. They don’t ignore those moments of the past. They embrace them. Great nations don’t walk away. We come to terms with the mistakes we made. And in remembering those moments, we begin to heal and grow stronger.<br><br>The truth is, it’s not &#8212; simply not enough just to commemorate Juneteenth. After all, the emancipation of enslaved Black Americans didn’t mark the end of America’s work to deliver on the promise of equality; it only marked the beginning.<br><br>To honor the true meaning of Juneteenth, we have to continue toward that promise because we’ve not gotten there yet. The Vice President and I and our entire administration and all of you in this room are committed to doing just that.<br><br>That’s why we’ve launched an aggressive effort to combat racial discrimination in housing &#8212; finally address the cruel fact that a home owned, to this day, by a Black American family is usually appraised at a lower rate for a similar home owned by a white family in a similar area.<br><br>That’s why we committed to increasing Black homeownership, one of the biggest drivers of generational wealth.<br><br>That’s why we&#8217;re making it possible for more Black entrepreneurs to access &#8212; to access capital, because their ideas are as good; they lack the capital to get their fair &#8212; and get their fair share of federal contracts so they can begin to build wealth.<br><br>That’s why we’re working to give each and every child, three and four years of age, not daycare, but school &#8212; in a school. (Applause.)<br><br>That’s why &#8212; that&#8217;s why we’re unlocking the incredibly creative and innovation &#8212; innovation of the history &#8212; of our Historical Black Colleges and Universities, providing them with the resources to invest in research centers and laboratories to help HBCU graduates prepare and compete for good-paying jobs in the industries of the future.<br><br>Folks, the promise of equality is not going to be fulfilled until we become real &#8212; it becomes real in our schools and on our Main Streets and in our neighborhoods &#8212; our healthcare system and ensuring that equity is at the heart of our fight against the pandemic; in the water that comes out of our faucets and the air that we breathe in our communities; in our justice system &#8212; so that we can fulfill the promise of America for all people. All of our people.<br><br>And it’s not going to be fulfilled so long as the sacred right to vote remains under attack. (Applause.)<br><br>We see this assault from restrictive laws, threats of intimidation, voter purges, and more &#8212; an assault that offends the very democracy &#8212; our very democracy.<br><br>We can’t rest until the promise of equality is fulfilled for every one of us in every corner of this nation. That, to me, is the meaning of Juneteenth. That’s what it’s about.<br><br>So let’s make this June- &#8212; this very Juneteenth, tomorrow &#8212; the first that our nation will celebrate all together, as one nation &#8212; a Juneteenth of action on many fronts.&nbsp;<br><br>One of those is vaccinations. Tomorrow, the Vice President will be in Atlanta on a bus tour, helping to spread the word, like all of you have been doing, on lifesaving vaccines.<br><br>And across the country this weekend, including here in Washington, people will be canvassing and hosting events in their communities, going door-to-door, encouraging vaccinations.<br><br>We’ve built equity into the heart of the vaccination program from day one, but we still have more work to do to close the racial gap in vaccination rates. The more we can do that, the more we can save lives.</p>



<p>Today also marks the sixth anniversary of the tragic deaths of &#8212; at Mother Emanuel Church in Charleston, South Carolina. A killer motivated by hate, intending to start a race war in South Carolina. He joined his victims in a Bible study class, then he took their lives in the house of worship.<br><br>It’s a reminder that our work to root out hate never ends &#8212; because hate only hides, it never fully goes away. It hides. And when you breathe oxygen under that rock, it comes out.<br><br>And that’s why we must understand that Juneteenth represents not only the commemoration of the end of slavery in America more than 150 years ago, but the ongoing work to have to bring true equity and racial justice into American society, which we can do.<br><br>In short, this day doesn’t just celebrate the past; it calls for action today.<br><br>I wish all Americans a happy Juneteenth. I am shortly going to &#8212; in a moment, going to sign into law, making it a federal holiday.<br><br>And I have to say to you, I’ve only been President for several months, but I think this will go down, for me, as one of the greatest honors I will have had as President, not because I did it; you did it &#8212; Democrats and Republicans. But it’s an enormous, enormous honor.<br><br>Thank you for what you’ve done. And, by the way, typical of most of us in Congress and the Senate, I went down to the other end of the hall first and thanked your staffs because I know who does the hard work. (Laughter and applause.) They’re down there. They’re at the other end, but I thanked them as well.<br><br>May God bless you all. And may God protect our troops. Thank you. (Applause.)<br><br>Now, I’d like to invite up, while I sign, Senator Tina Smith, Senator Ed Markey, Senator Raphael Warnock, Senator John Cornyn, Whip <s>John</s> [Jim] Clyburn, Representative Barbara Lee, Representative Danny Davis, Chair Joyce Beatty, and Sheila Jackson Lee, and Ms. Opal.<br><br>(The act is signed.) (Applause.)<br><br>4:06 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: S. 475</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/17/bill-signed-s-475/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 20:39:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21347</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Thursday, June 17, 2021, the President signed into law: S. 475, the “Juneteenth National Independence Day Act,” which designates Juneteenth National Independence Day as a legal public holiday.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Thursday, June 17, 2021, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S. 475, the “Juneteenth National Independence Day Act,” which designates Juneteenth National Independence Day as a legal public holiday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations Sent to the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/17/nominations-sent-to-the-senate-21/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 20:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Sandra D. Bruce, of Delaware, to be Inspector General, Department of Education, vice Kathleen S. Tighe, resigned. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Margaret A. Burnham, of Massachusetts, to be a Member of the Civil Rights Cold Case Records Review Board.&#160; (New Position) &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Clayborne Carson, of California, to be a Member of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sandra D. Bruce, of Delaware, to be Inspector General, Department of Education, vice Kathleen S. Tighe, resigned.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Margaret A. Burnham, of Massachusetts, to be a Member of the Civil Rights Cold Case Records Review Board.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Clayborne Carson, of California, to be a Member of the Civil Rights Cold Case Records Review Board.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Carlos Del Toro, of Virginia, to be Secretary of the Navy, vice Kenneth J. Braithwaite.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Gabrielle M. Dudley, of Georgia, to be a Member of the Civil Rights Cold Case Records Review Board.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Henry Klibanoff, of Georgia, to be a Member of the Civil Rights Cold Case Records Review Board.&nbsp; (New Position)</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Michael D. Smith, of Virginia, to be Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, vice Barbara Stewart.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Damon Y. Smith, of Maryland, to be General Counsel of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, vice J. Paul Compton, Jr.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>On-the-Record Press Call by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on the President&#8217;s Trip to Europe</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/17/on-the-record-press-call-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-the-presidents-trip-to-europe/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 20:16:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 12:48 P.M. EDT MS. HORNE:&#160; Thank you, Operator.&#160; Hi, everyone, and thanks for joining us on short notice.&#160; Today&#8217;s call will be on the record, and our speaker will be National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan.&#160; Jake, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you for some opening comments, and then we&#8217;re happy to take your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>12:48 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. HORNE:&nbsp; Thank you, Operator.&nbsp; Hi, everyone, and thanks for joining us on short notice.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s call will be on the record, and our speaker will be National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Jake, I&#8217;ll turn it over to you for some opening comments, and then we&#8217;re happy to take your questions.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks, Emily.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; The main purpose here is to get the opportunity to answer some questions.&nbsp; But before we get to that, I thought I would just take a couple of minutes to review, from our perspective, the outcomes of this trip and where we go from here.</p>



<p>The bottom line is that Joe Biden confidently and skillfully donned the mantle of leader of the free world on this trip.&nbsp; The previous president had ceded that mantle, and this president has now emphatically reclaimed it.&nbsp; And as the foundational outcome for the trip, I think that is the most significant.</p>



<p>But it goes way beyond that.&nbsp; This was an unusually productive, substantive set of summits with real, tangible outcomes.&nbsp; And the combined impact of those has laid the groundwork for proving out the case that democracies can deliver for their own people and for people around the world, as the President discussed on multiple of his stops during the trip.</p>



<p>I’ll just say a word about five significant areas of progress on this trip.&nbsp; The first is action on COVID.&nbsp; The President both made a historic and monumental commitment of 500 million &#8212; half a billion &#8212; Pfizer vaccines that the U.S. will provide to the 100 lowest-income countries around the world.&nbsp; And this also galvanized commitments from the other G7 members, as well as helped form the core of a broader action plan to end the pandemic before the end of 2022, which we will now move forward smartly to execute on, both in terms of securing the production of the pledged doses, distributing them effectively, and dealing with all the other aspects of support that are required to end this pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The second is convergence among likeminded countries, among the world&#8217;s democracies, on China.&nbsp; We have &#8212; the G7 &#8212; embraced a new infrastructure initiative, Build Back Better World &#8212; B3W &#8212; that will be a high-standards, transparent, climate-friendly alternative to the Belt Road Initiative.</p>



<p>We had NATO tackling China in its communiqué for the first time, truly taking the security challenge posed by China seriously, and also a tasking for a new strategic concept that would deal with China where the last Strategic Concept did not even mention China.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have the U.S.-EU Trade Technology Council launched, which will address a wide range of trade and technology issues, both in terms of the affirmative agenda between the U.S. and Europe, and also taking on, in a coordinated fashion, the non-market economic practices that China has pursued over many years to the detriment of market economies in both Europe and the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, in fact, the G7 spoke to this issue of coordination and alignment on standing up to countering and pushing back on China&#8217;s non-market economic practices as part of a broader economic competition.</p>



<p>A specific, tangible example of that on this trip was the agreement to end a 16-year-long dispute between Airbus and Boeing.&nbsp; And that dispute &#8212; and that agreement involved not just a five-year suspension of tariffs but, critically, explicit alignment on the U.S. and the EU working together on inbound and outbound investment related to China&#8217;s large aircraft &#8212; large passenger aircraft industry so that the U.S. and the EU will be working together to protect jobs and protect technology in Europe and the United States against China&#8217;s predatory practices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The third major area of progress was delivering for workers and families, and this Airbus-Boeing deal, I think, is a significant example of that because, in the end, it will help secure and grow jobs in our own aviation industry by relaxing the tariffs and by protecting against predatory competition from China.</p>



<p>And, of course, the G7 agreement on global minimum tax will, once implemented, provide hundreds of billions of dollars over time into the U.S. FISC that can be invested in American workers and communities that currently are being lost because of the race to the bottom on corporate taxation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fourth area of progress was President Biden and the United States standing up for our values in an emphatic, affirmative, and positive way alongside and in chorus with our allies and partners.&nbsp; This included, of course, the Atlantic Charter &#8212; the new Atlantic Charter that the U.S. and the UK &#8212; Prime Minister Johnson and President Biden &#8212; signed in the opening phase of the trip.&nbsp; It included the G7 speaking out with one collective voice on human rights abuses in Xinjiang, as well as making a series of commitments on forced labor, particularly in those sectors that are prevalent in Xinjiang.</p>



<p>It included Joe Biden directly challenging Putin on a range of human-rights-related issues, including the unjust detention of Aleksey Navalny, the effort to suppress Radio Free Europe/ Radio Liberty, and then his extensive public comments yesterday about how an American president has to stand up and speak out on human rights and democracy; that it is stamped in America&#8217;s DNA.&nbsp; And that put, I think, an exclamation point on an entire trip centered around placing values back at the core of America&#8217;s foreign policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then the fifth area was driving progress on cyber.&nbsp; From the G7 commitments around ransomware, to NATO adopting a new cyber defense policy for the first time in seven years, to the extensive conversations as part of the summit yesterday between President Biden and President Putin on critical infrastructure in particular, we feel like we have emerged from this trip with a common strategy with our allies, and as well as having laid down some clear markers with Russia, some clear expectations, and also communicated to them the capacities that we have should they choose not to take action against criminals who are attacking our critical infrastructure from Russian soil.</p>



<p>Cyber also relates to this broader effort at standing up a strategic stability dialogue that will address arms control, but also touch on issues related to both cyber and space as we move forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, there were other critical elements to this trip &#8212; from the work that President Biden did with President Macron of France to come to an agreement around increased funding for NATO for new capabilities between now and 2030; to his meeting with President Erdoğan of Turkey on enduring presence in Afghanistan and how we ensure the security of that presence; to his meeting with President Ramaphosa of South Africa on how the United States can support vaccine manufacturing on the African continent; and much more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But those five areas in particular, I think, are where we feel like we made meaningful progress and have set ourselves up from a position of strength to be able to deal both with the transnational challenges of our time and with competition with China and Russia on a going-forward basis.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I said I wanted to get to your questions.&nbsp; I took a little time there &#8212; probably longer than I should have.&nbsp; But thank you for a hearing the add on all of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Hi, Jake.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the NATO discussions on the Afghanistan withdrawal and the President&#8217;s meeting with President Erdoğan.&nbsp; Turkey has offered to secure and operate the international airport provided it receives what its defense minister called political, financial, and logistical support.</p>



<p>As you also know, the Taliban has issued a statement saying it will consider any remaining foreign troops, including Turkey’s, to be occupying forces and will treat them accordingly.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I wanted to ask how seriously you take the Taliban threat.&nbsp; And did the President have any sense of what exactly Turkey would need to fulfill this task?&nbsp; And what is the United States and other partners willing to give in terms of support?</p>



<p>And secondarily, a separate question on the bilat with Turkey: There didn&#8217;t seem to be any give in Turkey&#8217;s position on the S-400.&nbsp; What does that mean in terms of Turkey’s continuing participation in NATO?&nbsp; Is everybody just going to coexist with Turkey operating this system?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Thanks, Karen.&nbsp; So, on your first question, President Biden and President Erdoğan had a detailed discussion of a potential Turkish mission to secure the airport once the Resolute Support Mission has ended.&nbsp; The President and President Erdoğan agreed that they would work together to make this happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Erdoğan indicated he would need, as you said, certain forms of support to do that.&nbsp; And President Biden committed that that support would be forthcoming.&nbsp; President Erdoğan expressed satisfaction with that, and the two of them tasked their teams just to work out the final details.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the clear commitment from the leaders was established that Turkey would play a lead role in securing Hamid Karzai International Airport, and we are now working through how to execute against that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, we take seriously the concern that the Taliban or other elements in Afghanistan will attack the Western &#8212; or the international presence &#8212; diplomatic presence or security presence in and around Kabul.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we are putting together a detailed and effective security plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We do not believe that what the Taliban has said publicly</p>



<p>should or will deter the efforts underway right now to establish that security presence, which in turn will enable international missions &#8212; diplomatic missions to operate.</p>



<p>On the S-400, they discussed it.&nbsp; There was not a resolution of the issue.&nbsp; There was a commitment to continue the dialogue on the S-400.&nbsp; And the two teams will be following up on that coming out of the meeting.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Actually, Karen asked my question.&nbsp; But I just wondered if, Jake, you could elaborate a little bit on what plan B is if the Turks decide that it&#8217;s not going to be in their interest or &#8212; to provide the security there in the end, and how confident you are that that plan can go forward.&nbsp; What&#8217;s plan B, though, if it doesn&#8217;t?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; We are feeling good about where we are in terms of the planning with the Turks on this issue.&nbsp; But, of course, we are obviously also conducting contingency planning in the event that either Turkey can’t proceed &#8212; although we have every expectation they will &#8212; or can only proceed in a more limited fashion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And without going into too much detail at this point because of the sensitivity of that contingency planning, I will say that it focuses on security contractors who have extensive experience in both static and dynamic security in Afghanistan.&nbsp; And that is what we are looking at as the alternative.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have scoped out what would be necessary to be able to confidently secure the airport in Kabul.&nbsp; And we feel that we would have an alternative, although we are very much focused right now on converting the President&#8217;s commitments to each other &#8212; President Erdoğan and President Biden &#8212; into an action plan that sees the Turks taking the lead at HKIA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, Jake.&nbsp; Thanks for taking this call.&nbsp; I was wondering, since you mentioned the G7 countries aligning on China, if you can elaborate a little bit more if that sort of means now that you had the G7 meeting, aligning, clearing the decks, meeting with Putin, if that now means you can go on to a bilateral discussion with President Xi and how you&#8217;re taking that on.</p>



<p>And if you could comment on, specifically, the human rights portion of that: What concretely will the G7 &#8212; the other G7 countries do on forced labor supply chain issues, since you guys were the first one to take action?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Yeah, thank you.&nbsp; So, on the first question, the answer is that what the President said about there being no substitute for leader-level dialogue as a central part of why he held the summit with Putin yesterday also applies to China and to President Xi Jinping.&nbsp; He will look for opportunities to engage with President Xi going forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We don&#8217;t have any particular plans at the moment, but I would note that both leaders are likely to be at the G20 in Italy in October.&nbsp; So I will leave it at that for now, because I &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re not coming off of this trip &#8212; the last thing we&#8217;re doing on Thursday is planning the next thing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But soon enough, we will sit down to work out the right modality for the two presidents to engage.&nbsp; Now, it could be a phone call; it could be a meeting on the margins of an international &#8212; another international summit; it could be something else.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, no decisions have been made on that score.&nbsp; But the notion that President Biden will engage in the coming month with President Xi in some way to take stock of where we are in the relationship and to ensure that we have that kind of direct communication that we found valuable with President Putin yesterday, we&#8217;re very much committed to that.&nbsp; It&#8217;s now just a question of when and how.&nbsp; And we will work through that and have more to report.</p>



<p>On forced labor, what we &#8212; you know, the G7 identified three sectors in particular: the garment sector; the agriculture sector, with cotton being one of the aspects of agriculture we&#8217;re particularly focused on; and the polysilicon sector and solar sector.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, what we expect is that other G7 partners will look at various forms of restrictions on goods that are proven to be produced with forced labor.&nbsp; The precise form of those restrictions will vary country by country; the timing on them will vary country by country.&nbsp; But our expectation is that we will align in a broad approach to take tangible action against or related to the supply chains emerging from forced labor jurisdiction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there, Jake.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; I had a couple of questions just about, kind of, some of the more practical results of the Putin-Biden summit.&nbsp; I know that there was discussion of sending ambassadors back.&nbsp; Can you expand on that?&nbsp; Are there, sort of, any talks of having the United States continue to hire local staff in Moscow?&nbsp; Any interest in reopening consulates?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then a somewhat, I guess, not exactly related question: But there&#8217;s talk about the UN voting and whether or not to keep the last remaining aid route into Syria open.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m curious if there were discussions on Syria.&nbsp; Did you all get any conversations about whether or not &#8212; just essentially where Russia would vote on that particular issue?</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; Sure, thank you.&nbsp; So, first, the two presidents agreed that they would return their ambassadors to capitals.&nbsp; So, Ambassador Sullivan will go back to Moscow; Ambassador Antonov will come back to Washington.&nbsp; And this is an effort to regularize the diplomatic engagement following the steps that the United States took in response to various harmful actions by Russia earlier this year.&nbsp; So, that has happened.&nbsp; That’s point one.</p>



<p>Point two, on the question of locally employed staff in Russia, the two presidents did discuss it.&nbsp; President Biden made the point that we each need effectively functioning diplomatic missions in our respective capitals in order to manage this relationship, both the difficulties in the relationship and the areas where we can make practical progress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in that regard, he encouraged President Putin to be practical and flexible about the implementation of Russian regulations on locally employed staff.&nbsp; And President Putin indicated that he would take measures to ensure that our mission was properly staffed, whether it&#8217;s through some &#8212; through the provision of visas for Americans to be able to fill those roles or through some other adjustment and regulations within Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the next step on that is that our teams will meet to follow up to try to work out details so that our mission in Moscow, in particular, but also throughout the rest of Russia, is not hamstrung.&nbsp; And President Putin was forward-leaning in that regard, and we will see how that translates into actual decisions here and in the weeks ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the question &#8212; now I&#8217;m forgetting what the other &#8212; oh, Syria.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Syria, yes.</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN.&nbsp; Yeah, on Syria.&nbsp; So, they did have a discussion on Syria, and in particular, focused on the question of humanitarian access.&nbsp; President Biden made the point that you&#8217;ve got millions of hungry people, people in need, in northeast and northwest Syria.&nbsp; And having those humanitarian crossings administered by the United Nations, particularly the one that is currently open and slated for renewal in July, is vital to ensuring that aid gets to the people who need it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Putin did not make a commitment as to how the Russians were going to vote on the resolution at the United Nations in July, but it was a constructive conversation.&nbsp; And we believe that there is scope for the U.S. and Russia to work together on a positive outcome so that resolution gets passed, that crossing gets sustained, and that other measures to alleviate the suffering of the people of Syria are also adopted with the U.S. and Russia working together on that issue.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, Jake.&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; The President said yesterday that we&#8217;ll find out within the next six months to a year whether or not there is actually a strategic dialogue that matters with Russia.&nbsp; How will you measure progress towards improving U.S.-Russia relations in the coming months?&nbsp; And if you don&#8217;t see that progress, what is the alternative?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then a quick question as well on the comments that Congressman Kevin McCarthy made: He said that he believes the President should have used this summit to “stand up for our national interests.”&nbsp; And he says, “Unfortunately, President Biden gave Vladimir Putin a pass.”&nbsp; I’m wondering if you have a response to that?&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MR. SULLIVAN:&nbsp; So, on Representative McCarthy&#8217;s comments, I think they are &#8212; his assertion is belied by the voluminous evidence that President Biden challenged President Putin on a range of issues that the previous President, who Representative McCarthy supported strongly, gave President Putin a pass on.</p>



<p>He challenged him on Aleksey Navalny.&nbsp; He challenged him on Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty.&nbsp; He challenged him on the detained Americans &#8212; unjustly detained Americans in Russia.&nbsp; He challenged him on Russia&#8217;s harmful cyber activities.&nbsp; He challenged him on election interference.&nbsp;</p>



<p>He didn&#8217;t side with Putin against the intelligence community on that &#8212; quite the contrary.&nbsp; And in a number of other areas, President Biden was clear, direct, straightforward in explaining to President Putin what American expectations are, what American capabilities are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he indicated that there are areas where we can work together, but he also was direct in saying if Russia chooses to continue various harmful activities, harmful to the national interests of the United States, the United States would take action, would respond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you heard that publicly from him yesterday, where he was clear and direct in where he was standing up and pushing back against Putin.&nbsp; And what you heard publicly was very much a reflection of what President Biden conveyed privately over the course of the summit.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s on your second question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On your first question: There are, I think, three or four different areas where we will be able to see, in the months ahead, whether progress is possible or whether we will simply have to take action to safeguard our interests because progress hasn&#8217;t occurred.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of those areas is in the cyber domain and, in particular, on critical infrastructure.&nbsp; And President Biden passed a list of the 16 sectors of critical infrastructure that are enshrined in Presidential Policy Directive 21, and indicated that he was particularly focused on those sectors, in terms of Russia both refraining from state-related cyber disruptions and preventing cyber disruptions by criminals operating from Russian soil.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s one.</p>



<p>Two, whether we actually are seeing tangible progress in the strategic stability dialogue around arms control and risk reduction measures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Three, whether we are seeing progress on regional issues, from Afghanistan to Syria to Iran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, four &#8212; going back to a previous question &#8212; whether or not practical steps are being taken to ensure that each of our embassies can operate in a unencumbered, effective way so that we can manage this difficult relationship in both Washington and Moscow.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, those are some of the areas in which we will be able to determine whether we made progress or not.&nbsp; And the President was very clear yesterday that “the proof of the pudding is in the eating”; that we&#8217;re not asserting any kind of “mission accomplished”; that we felt yesterday was productive, effective in creating a pathway to progress on some of these hard issues and a clear set of next steps for our two countries to work on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But it by no means is the end of the story; it is the start of the story.&nbsp; And how the story ends will unfold here over the course, as he said, of the next six months to a year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, let me just close on this call with where I started, which is &#8212; and it comes back a little bit to the McCarthy point &#8212; which is, I think &#8212; I really do not believe that it is hyperbole to say that Joe Biden returns from this trip as the clear and the consensus leader of the free world; that you&#8217;ve got the French president, when asked if America was back, saying, “Definitely.”&nbsp; You&#8217;ve got the leaders of democracies from both Europe and Asia extremely positive about Joe Biden&#8217;s personal presidential leadership and about American leadership writ large under his presidency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And whether it&#8217;s standing with friends or engaging with difficult competitors like Vladimir Putin, Joe Biden showed throughout this trip that he is striding across the world stage with confidence and purpose and a singular focus on defending American interests and values and those of our allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, we just &#8212; we really do feel good about it.&nbsp; It may be &#8212; it&#8217;s &#8212; these trips, you kind of finish them and you&#8217;re like, “All right, well that&#8217;s great.&nbsp; Now we got work to do.”&nbsp; And there&#8217;s an enormous amount of work to do, but we&#8217;re all ready for it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, sorry to go on for so long at the end, but really appreciate it.&nbsp; Thanks, guys.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. HORNE:&nbsp; All right, thanks, everyone, so much for joining.&nbsp; That concludes our call.&nbsp; Friendly reminder: We are on the record today and there is no embargo.&nbsp; Have a good afternoon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:18 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Briefing by White House COVID-19 Response Team and Public Health Officials</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2021/06/17/press-briefing-by-white-house-covid-19-response-team-and-public-health-officials-41/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 19:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference  11:11 A.M. EDT MR. ZIENTS:  Good morning, and thank you for joining us.  Today, Dr. Fauci will discuss the latest science, including an important announcement on next-generation treatments in our long-term fight against COVID-19. Dr. Walensky will give an update on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Murthy will discuss our public education&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference </p>



<p>11:11 A.M. EDT<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Good morning, and thank you for joining us.  Today, Dr. Fauci will discuss the latest science, including an important announcement on next-generation treatments in our long-term fight against COVID-19.<br><br>Dr. Walensky will give an update on the state of the pandemic, Dr. Murthy will discuss our public education and outreach efforts, and then we’ll have time for Q&amp;A.<br><br>We are making significant progress in our fight against COVID-19 in the U.S. and around the world.  Let’s remember where the country was before President Biden took office.<br><br>In mid-January, the United States had more than 185,000 new COVID-19 cases a day, and more than 3,300 Americans were dying each day from the virus.  Kids were out of school, people were out of work, and businesses were closed.<br><br>The President committed to marshalling a whole-of Government wartime response to meet this historic challenge.  That’s exactly what he has done by building an unparalleled vaccination program.<br><br>The results are clear: More than 175 million Americans have already gotten at least one shot, including 87 percent of seniors, those 65 and over; 74 percent of adults 40 and over; and nearly 2 out of 3 of all adult Americans.<br><br>In 14 states and the District of Columbia, at least 70 percent of adults have received at least one shot. And just this morning, we learned that 86 percent of K-through-12 educators and school staff had already been vaccinated by the end of May.<br><br>What does this all mean?  As a result of our success vaccinating Americans, cases and deaths are down more than 90 percent since the President took office on January 20th.<br>In fact, cases and deaths are at the lowest levels since the start of the pandemic.  Instead of heading into a summer, like last summer &#8212; of isolation, uncertainty, and loss &#8212; we’re headed into a summer of joy, celebration, and increasing freedom from the virus.<br><br>However, for all the progress we’re making as a country, too many communities remain at risk because of low vaccination levels.  In fact, we’re seeing the communities with the highest vaccination rates have lower rates of new cases and hospitalizations, and communities with the lowest vaccination rates have higher new cases and hospitalizations.<br><br>As the President says, we do not want our country, that is already too divided, become divided in a new way &#8212; between places where people live free from fear of COVID-19 and places that remain at risk.<br><br>The low vaccination rates in some communities is an even bigger concern now that we face the threat of a new, more dangerous variant, including specifically the Delta variant.<br><br>The good news is that the best way to protect yourself against these variants, including the Delta variant, is to get fully vaccinated.  So, if you’re fully vaccinated, you’re protected.  But if you’re unvaccinated, you’re at risk of getting seriously ill or spreading the disease to others.  This is why we are pushing so hard to get more Americans vaccinated.<br><br>During our National Month of Action, we’re mobilizing an all-of-America effort, including the “We Can Do This” National Vaccination Tour, led by the Vice President, to key communities across the country to reach millions of Americans who still need protection against the virus, and to energize and mobilize grassroots vaccine education and outreach efforts.<br><br>Vice President Harris kicked off the tour on Monday in Greenville, South Carolina, followed by EPA Administrator Regan returning to his home state, visiting Raleigh and Charlotte, North Carolina.  Yesterday, the Second Gentleman in Memphis, Tennessee.  Today, VA Secretary McDonough in Birmingham, Alabama.  And to cap off the first week, the Vice President will be in Atlanta, Georgia, tomorrow.<br><br>As the outlook on the virus gets brighter and brighter by the day here at home, we’re increasingly focused on driving progress to help end the pandemic around the globe.  Last week, the President took a historic step by announcing that the United States will purchase a half billion doses of Pfizer vaccines and donate them to nearly 100 low-income countries around the world.  This is by far and away the largest-ever donation of COVID-19 vaccines by a single country.<br><br>And these half billion doses are on top of the 80 million doses the President committed to sharing with the world by the end of June, and the $2 billion the U.S. has donated to COVAX to support its efforts to vaccinate the world.<br><br>We’ve already started shipping doses.  On Tuesday, doses landed in Mexico, and today, doses land in Canada.  And we’ll allocate all the initial 80 million doses in the coming days with shipments going out as soon as countries are ready to receive the doses.<br><br>So, in total, we’ve have already committed to sharing 580 million doses.  And we expect to do more and more over the summer months as we help lead the fight to end the pandemic across the globe.<br><br>Now I want to turn to Dr. Fauci for an important announcement on how we are mobilizing our whole-of-government effort to develop next-generation treatments to prevent severe COVID-19 illness or death.<br><br>This pioneering work of American ingenuity and innovation is essential to our long-term response to the pandemic, and is funded by the American Rescue Plan.<br><br>With that, over to Dr. Fauci.<br><br>DR. FAUCI:  Thank you very much, Jeff.  Can I have that first slide?  So, today, the Biden administration announced their investment of $3.2 billion from the American Rescue Plan as part of the COVID-19 Antiviral Development Strategy.  It&#8217;s a whole-of-government effort aimed at developing the next generation of COVID-19 treatments, as well as preparing us for future threats. <br><br>Next slide. <br><br>The program is called the Antiviral Program for Pandemics, and it aims to catalyze the development of new medicines to combat COVID-19 and, importantly, to prepare for other pandemic threats.  And what do I mean by that latter statement?<br><br>Next slide. <br><br>There are few treatments that exist for many of the viruses that have what we call “pandemic potential.”  I&#8217;m showing on this slide family of viruses that do, in fact, have potential to evolve into a pandemic, such as the paramyxovirus with Nipah; the bunyaviruses with hemorrhagic fevers; we&#8217;re very familiar with the coronavirus &#8212; what we&#8217;re dealing with right now. <br><br>Next slide. <br><br>So what is the rationale and the goals for this program?  Of course, as we&#8217;ve heard so often now over the last several briefings, vaccines clearly remain the centerpiece of our arsenal against COVID-19.  However, antivirals can and are an important complement to existing vaccines, especially for individuals with certain conditions that might put them at a greater risk.  For those who vaccines may not be as protective, we know that there are many people who are immunosuppressed, in which vaccines, at least initially, may not give an optimum response. <br><br>And it also adds a line of defense against other unexpected emerging things, like variants of concern that we are currently dealing with, including the variants that we&#8217;ll be discussing a little bit later. <br><br>This program is going to bring together leading scientists from academia, as well as industry, to accelerate the development of new antivirals.  And as I mentioned, it&#8217;s also going to target other viruses of pandemic potential.<br><br>Can I have the next slide? <br><br>It has two major pillars to the program: development and discovery.  The development is the more immediate activity; in other words, it’s going to accelerate the clinical testing of promising antiviral medicines that are already in various stages of development, including clinical trial, things like the Pfizer protease inhibitor; the Atea-Roche RNA polymerase inhibitor; the Merck mutagenic nucleoside, Molnupiravir; and others that are in that pipeline.  So it&#8217;s to be accelerating things that are already in process. <br><br>The other pillar is “discovery.”  And this is very important because this is modeled after the highly successful program developed decades ago for the targeted development of antiretroviral drugs for HIV, which has led to transforming therapies to control HIV, namely discovering new antiviral medications. <br><br>Next slide.<br><br>The program looks like this: It&#8217;s a total, as I mentioned, of $3.2 billion.  There&#8217;ll be $500 million for fundamental research and laboratory support; a billion for preclinical and clinical evaluation; $700 million for the development and manufacturing through NIH, in our usual partnership with BARDA; and $1 billion to support the creation of a program which we are calling the Antiviral Drug Discovery Centers for Pathogens of Pandemic Concern, meaning not only COVID-19, but some of the families I showed you on a prior slide. <br><br>And on the last slide: What are the next steps?  We&#8217;re going to continue engaging with manufacturers in the development part of it to accelerate the testing and authorization of promising meds, which are in later-stage development. <br><br>In this regard, we&#8217;re going to continue to identify and evaluate additional candidates for this program support.  With regard to discovery, we&#8217;re going to support academic industry partnerships aimed at discovering new molecules. <br><br>So we have a great deal of optimism that this program will ultimately be as successful as the highly successful program that we had implemented both for HIV and for hepatitis C. <br><br>With that, I&#8217;ll hand it over to Dr. Walensky.<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:  Thank you, Dr. Fauci.  And good morning, everyone.  Let&#8217;s begin with an overview of the data.  Yesterday, CDC reported 12,322 new cases of COVID-19.  Our seven-day average is 12,190 cases per day.  This represents a decrease of about 16 percent from the prior seven-day average and is the lowest seven-day average since March 27, 2020. <br><br>To put this in context: On January 10, 2021, the seven-day average was 252,000 cases per day.  We&#8217;ve seen a 95 percent decline in just the past five months.  The seven-day average of hospitalizations is about 2,000 per day, a decrease of about 10 percent from the prior seven-day period.  And the seven-day average of daily deaths has also declined to 286 per day, the first time that average daily deaths have been below 300 since March 27, 2020. <br><br>These numbers make it clear: Getting vaccinated gets us back to normal.  It&#8217;s the best way we have to defeat this virus and to get everyone back to gathering together safely at weddings, sports events, and travel. <br><br>Everyone in the United States ages 12 and older is eligible to get vaccinated.  It&#8217;s never been easier or more convenient.  Vaccines are free and available at a location near you.  Remember, visit VaccineFinder.gov to find a site near you.  We know that vaccination prevents the vast majority of serious COVID-19 illness, hospitalizations, and deaths. <br><br>As far as we have come in our vaccination efforts, with over half of those who are eligible being fully vaccinated, and many cities and states reaching our goal of over 70 percent of people with at least one dose, it&#8217;s understandable that some people still have questions.  What&#8217;s the science behind the vaccines?  How were they developed so quickly?  How do we know they are safe, especially for adolescents and teens?<br><br>Answering those questions remains a critical part of our efforts, especially when it comes to safety.  I&#8217;m the mother of three myself; I understand that parents want to make sure their children are safe.  We don&#8217;t want our children to be sick from anything, particularly a preventable illness. <br><br>The COVID-19 vaccine saves lives.  COVID-19 has resulted in more than 320 deaths in children under age 18 in the United States during this pandemic.  And hospitalization rates among adolescents who got COVID-19 were two and a half to three times higher than they are during a typical influenza season. <br><br>In addition to preventing hospitalizations, the vaccine also reduces the risk of COVID-19 and therefore reduces the risk of MISC, a serious condition of multisystem inflammation in children, which has affected over 4,000 children in the United States during the pandemic, including 36 children whose deaths were associated with MISC. <br><br>My own children received the COVID-19 vaccine because vaccination is the best way to protect our adolescents, teens, and young adults from COVID-19 and its complications.<br><br>Tomorrow, CDC’s Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, or ACIP, will meet to review data on reports of myocarditis and pericarditis, or inflammation of the heart and surrounding tissue.<br><br>These cases are rare, and the vast majority have fully resolved with rest and supportive care.  CDC will present details about more than 300 confirmed cases of myocarditis and pericarditis reported to CDC and FDA among the over 20 million adolescents and young adults vaccinated in the United States.<br><br>Over the last several months, we have been asking clinicians to be on the look-out for and report patients with symptoms of myocarditis or pericarditis following vaccination.<br><br>CDC has been collecting these reports, including obtaining detailed medical records to confirm the diagnosis and reviewing them to ensure, in real time, the safety of our vaccines.<br><br>Our team has also been in regular contact with the American Academy of Pediatrics, who share CDC’s recommendation for all teens to get the COVID-19 vaccine.<br><br>Tomorrow, in a meeting open to the public, the ACIP will hear a risk-benefit analysis regarding COVID-19 vaccination versus the potential rare side effects across all age groups.<br><br>I look forward to hearing this important discussion, which is yet another demonstration of our ongoing efforts to keep safety central to everything we do. <br><br>Getting vaccinated is our way out of this pandemic.  If you have questions about vaccination, please contact your health care provider, your state or local health department, or your local pharmacist. <br><br>Thank you.  I&#8217;ll now turn things over to Dr. Murthy. <br><br>DR. MURTHY:  Well, thank you so much, Dr. Walensky.  And it&#8217;s good to be with all of you again today. <br><br>Our COVID 19 vaccine public education efforts have continued in earnest and, in fact, with even greater urgency given the spread of the Delta variant, which is significantly more transmissible, may be more dangerous than prior variants, and which serves as a stark reminder that if you are vaccinated, you are protected; if you are not, the threat of variants is real and growing. <br><br>In the last two weeks alone, our door-knocking and phone-banking efforts have generated hundreds of thousands of conversations in all 50 states. <br><br>Our mayor&#8217;s challenge has mobilized mayors in cities and towns across America to push toward our 70 percent goal, often in friendly competition with each other. <br><br>And we focused our broader efforts on three key groups in particular: parents, youth, and clinicians.  We&#8217;ve held town halls and press calls with parents, and publications and blogs focused on parenting.  We&#8217;ve reached out directly to young people by launching our Student Community Corps yesterday by hosting town halls with organizations like the Boys and Girls Club of America, and by working with young influencers on YouTube and other social media platforms. <br><br>Recognizing how essential doctors, nurses, and other healthcare professionals are as trusted messengers, we&#8217;ve also built partnerships with medical organizations and health systems across the country who have committed to reaching out to patients and their staff.  And we&#8217;ve also reached out directly to clinicians, including through a town hall last week with more than 1,500 pediatricians, and a national clinician town hall with more than 1,000 participants. <br><br>We&#8217;ve talked before about how clinicians are the number one source of trusted information about the vaccines.  Today, I also want to talk about something we don&#8217;t discuss as often, which is the mental health and wellbeing of our clinicians. <br><br>Recent data indicates more than 50 percent of clinicians are experiencing burnout during this pandemic.  But even before COVID, more than one third of nurses and doctors experienced substantial symptoms of burnout, with doctors experiencing a suicide rate double that of the general population.  COVID-19 made this much worse, as clinicians have been forced to push through new levels of fatigue. <br><br>Among the many stories that I have heard from clinicians, one that sticks out is an account from a nurse practitioner who said he stopped counting how many patients he’d lost after his 146th patient died from COVID-19. <br><br>Clinicians have gone through trauma of their own during this pandemic.  And if burnout isn&#8217;t addressed, it won&#8217;t just hurt our health care workers, but it will hurt our ability to provide routine care that people need every day. <br><br>Now, the administration is responding to clinician burnout.  The Health Resources and Services Administration has secured $120 million in funding through the American Rescue Plan.  This funding will support an expansion of training and wellness programs to reduce burnout and to promote resiliency. <br><br>In addition, the CDC’s National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health has received $20 million for an education and awareness campaign to improve the wellbeing of the nation&#8217;s healthcare workforce.<br><br>My office will continue to focus on clinician wellbeing in the coming months.  It&#8217;s why we started the dialogue with healthcare organizations and with the National Academy of Medicine’s Action Collaborative on Clinician Well-Being and Resilience, which is a network of more than 200 organizations committed to addressing clinician burnout and improving clinician wellbeing. <br><br>Our nation owes our healthcare workers a debt of gratitude, but also a debt of action.  They&#8217;ve had our back during this pandemic, and now we will continue to strive to care for the people who care for all of us. <br><br>Thank you so much.  And I&#8217;ll pass it back to you, Jeff. <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Thank you, Dr. Murthy.  Let&#8217;s open it up for a few questions. <br><br>MODERATOR:  Thanks, Jeff.  First question, we will go to Tamara Keith at NPR. <br><br>Q    Thank you very much.  The question I have is about boosters.  I know you&#8217;ve been asked about this many times before, but the question is whether you have a plan to buy vaccines to be used as boosters, or whether you already have enough purchased.  And what specifically is the plan to determine if boosters will be needed?  How much of this is relying on the pharmaceutical companies?  And how much of it is, you know, CDC process?  Or how is that going to work?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Why don&#8217;t we first go to your question on the plan for whether we need and when we would need boosters, if we do need them. <br><br>Dr. Fauci?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:  Jeff.  Well, whether or not one needs it is going to depend on two things.  It&#8217;s going to depend on the durability of the protection.  And I want to emphasize, by “durability,” I don&#8217;t mean that the vaccines now are not affective.  We&#8217;re talking about the length of the protection, which we know is very high right now.  That can be determined either by looking at the correlates of immunity and making sure that an individual &#8212; a cohort of individual, who are in &#8212; who are vaccinated, that that level of a correlate does not go below a critical baseline. <br><br>Also, you might see &#8212; and we hope we don&#8217;t get to that point; we&#8217;ll know about it before &#8212; that there are more breakthrough infections. <br><br>So, right now, what we are doing is that we are doing clinical trials with boosters &#8212; boosters against wild type and boosters against what we call “variant-specific” boosts.  And the determination is not made by drug companies; the determination is made by the public health need of individuals who&#8217;ve been vaccinated, whether or not we&#8217;re going to have a durable immunity.<br><br>With regard to projections, we don&#8217;t know what that is.  That could be a year.  That could be 18 months.  That could be much longer.  We&#8217;re going to have to follow it.  And we will act according to the information that we get from the parameters that I just mentioned. <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  So, the approach on supply is going to be the same approach that we have followed since day one, which is to be prepared for any contingency or any scenario.  So, we will have ample supply if indeed boosters are needed down the road. <br><br>DR. WALENSKY:  And maybe I&#8217;ll just chime in and say: Among the topics on tomorrow&#8217;s ACIP meeting will be a discussion about vaccine effectiveness and when boosters might be needed and how we will use science to inform that.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Wonderful.  Next question. <br><br>MODERATOR:  Let’s go to Shefali Luthra at The 19th. <br><br>Q    Hi, thanks for taking my question.  I wanted to hear a bit more about how we&#8217;re thinking about the treatments being developed for COVID and other coronaviruses, and in particular, what pricing might look like, given what a big discussion we’re all having right now about high drug prices. <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Dr. Fauci?<br><br>DR. FAUCI:  You know, well, I&#8217;m not really sure I can address pricing right now.  We don&#8217;t have the drugs that we&#8217;re talking about.  As I mentioned, there&#8217;s both development and discovery.  And right now, obviously, you&#8217;d want a price that would be affordable for people who would need it.  But I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m in a position right now, at this point in the plan, to talk about the pricing of the products that will come out of that. <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Was there a first part of the question?<br><br>Okay, let&#8217;s go to the next question. <br><br>MODERATOR:  Let’s go to Sheryl Stolberg at the New York Times. <br><br>Q    Hi, thank you for taking my question; it has to do with vaccination rates.  Right now, for people receiving the first dose, the seven-day average is about 200,000.  And that is down from roughly 500,000 at the outset of the month when the President announced his month of action. <br><br>So, I am wondering, do you expect that we will meet the 70 percent threshold that the President has set out for July 4th?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Well, I’ll start by saying: Getting vaccinated is as important as it&#8217;s ever been.  Those who are vaccinated are protected.  Those who are not, are not protected.  And the Delta variant just reminds us all that we need to not only get the first dose, but, for those who only have one dose and they’re on a two-dose regimen, to complete their vaccination as soon as possible. <br><br>We&#8217;ve made tremendous progress.  Today, more than 175 million Americans have gotten at least one shot: as I said, 87 percent of seniors, 74 percent of people over the age of 40.  And we&#8217;re now nearly 2 in 3 adult Americans &#8212; hundreds of thousands of people &#8212; are continuing to get their first shot each day. <br><br>And we are going to get to 70 percent.  And we&#8217;re going to continue across the summer months to push beyond 70 percent.  For the reasons that I just talked about, you have to get vaccinated in order to be protected against COVID-19, the Delta variant, and any other variants that might come down the road. <br><br>Next question. <br><br>MODERATOR:  Let’s go to Raquel at TV Globo Brazil. <br><br>Q    Thank you so much.  Can you hear me?<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Yes. <br><br>Q    Thank you so much, Kevin.<br><br>About the 80 million doses of COVID that will be shared with the other countries by the end of the month: Only 25 million were announced; still, 55 million need to be announced and sent by the end of the month. <br><br>Two questions: Will the administration be able to achieve this goal?  And when can we expect an announcement for the next 55 million?  Are they going to be distributed the same way as 25 million?  How and when are they being allocated?  And also, I&#8217;m curious to know about &#8212; is it going to be shared the same way to Brazil?  We know that Brazil is still like &#8212; the numbers are still very high; 2,000 people dying every day.  So, I wonder what amount Brazil would be receiving.  Thank you so much. <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  So, we will be allocating those &#8212; the full 80 million &#8212; so, the remaining 55 million, given that 25 million has already been allocated &#8212; in the coming days, with shipments going out as soon as countries are ready to receive the doses. <br><br>There are complex logistics here &#8212; coordinating with medical agencies in the host countries, regulatory bodies.  Obviously, we want to make sure that when the doses arrive, that the ancillary supplies are in place &#8212; the needles, the syringes, the alcohol pads &#8212; so that we can make sure that we get needles into arms right away. <br><br>There&#8217;ll be an increasing number of shipments each and every week as we ramp up these efforts.  The process to export the 80 million takes partnership in coordination with the receiving governments.  But that&#8217;s well underway now.<br><br>On Tuesday, doses landed in Mexico.  Today, doses are landing in Canada.  And, yes, importantly, doses will be shipped to Brazil in the coming weeks. <br><br>Next question. <br><br>MODERATOR:  All right, last question.  We’ll go to Cheyenne Haslett, ABC News. <br><br>Q    Hi, guys.  Thanks for taking my question.  Community groups say they&#8217;re worried about putting marginalized groups at risk again as we reopen.  Less vaccinated pockets &#8212; the Bronx, for example, has around 40 percent vaccination but makes up many of New York’s front-facing workers.  I wonder if you think reopening puts areas like that at risk.<br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Dr. Walensky?<br><br>DR. WALENSKY:  Yeah, I would say we know how to protect ourselves against this virus.  The first line is vaccination, of course.  And then, prior to vaccination, we knew that and know that masking and distancing work.  So, what we&#8217;re really trying to do, as you note, is to get into those communities with trusted messengers to ensure that they know that that vaccine is available to them, to inform them and understand where they might be hesitant so that we can get them vaccinated.  And then, if not, to ensure that they&#8217;re working towards the mitigation strategies that they know work. <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Dr. Murthy, anything to add there? <br><br>DR. MURTHY:  Yeah, I completely agree with Dr. Walensky.  And I would also say that this is why our partnership with employers is so important, especially for those employers who have workers who are on the front lines, you know, whether in grocery stores or in healthcare settings.  We want them to do everything they can to help their staff get vaccinated, whether that&#8217;s providing them with information, whether that&#8217;s setting up access to the vaccine on site. <br><br>So, we&#8217;re going to continue to work with employers because, as Dr. Walensky said, getting vaccinated remains the best way to protect ourselves, our workers, our neighbors, and our friends. <br><br>DR. FAUCI:  Yeah, and also, opening up is not synonymous with stopping the push to vaccinate people.  So, I think people should not misinterpret that because a city or a state is opening up, that they&#8217;re done.  No, they&#8217;re not. <br><br>We&#8217;re going to continue to push vaccination beyond the Fourth of July, into the summer, so to get as many people vaccinated as we possibly can, whether you&#8217;re open as a state or a city, or not.  That&#8217;s the goal. <br><br>MR. ZIENTS:  Well, thank you, everybody.  We look forward to next week&#8217;s briefing.  Thank you. </p>



<p>11:41 A.M. EDT</p>



<p>To view the COVID Press Briefing slides, visit&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/COVID-Press-Briefing_17June2021_-for-transcript.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/COVID-Press-Briefing_17June2021_-for-transcript.pdf</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe Biden on the U.S. Supreme Court Decision Upholding the Affordable Care Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/17/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-the-u-s-supreme-court-decision-upholding-the-affordable-care-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 16:55:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Affordable Care Act remains the law of the land.&#160; Today’s U.S. Supreme Court decision is a major victory for all Americans benefitting from this groundbreaking and life-changing law. It is a victory for more than 130 million Americans with pre-existing conditions and millions more who were in immediate danger of losing their health care&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Affordable Care Act remains the law of the land.&nbsp;<br><br>Today’s U.S. Supreme Court decision is a major victory for all Americans benefitting from this groundbreaking and life-changing law. It is a victory for more than 130 million Americans with pre-existing conditions and millions more who were in immediate danger of losing their health care in the midst of a once-in-a-century pandemic.&nbsp;<br><br>It is a victory for every American who, prior to the Affordable Care Act, stayed up at night staring at the ceiling, wondering whether they would lose everything if they or a loved one got sick. Because of this law, they don’t have to worry about being denied coverage due to a pre-existing condition like diabetes or watching their coverage being capped during a cancer treatment. Because of the law, they are able to get free preventive screenings that can save their lives and improve their health. Today’s victory is also for all the young people who can stay on their parents’ insurance plan until they turn 26 years old, and for the millions of low-income families and people with disabilities receiving health care because their states expanded Medicaid under this law.</p>



<p>After more than a decade of attacks on the Affordable Care Act through the Congress and the courts, today’s decision – the third major challenge to the law that the U.S. Supreme Court has rejected – it is time move forward and keep building on this landmark law.<br><br>That is what we are doing thanks to the American Rescue Plan, which has lowered health care costs and expanded coverage for millions of&nbsp;Americans through the Affordable Care Act. More than 1.2 million Americans signed up for coverage under the law through a special enrollment period I established during this pandemic, which people can still sign up for through August 15<sup>th</sup>. And&nbsp;I look forward to working with the Congress to build on this law so that the American people will continue to have access to quality and affordable health care.<br><br>Today’s decision affirms that the Affordable Care Act is stronger than ever, delivers for the American people, and gets us closer to fulfilling our moral obligation to ensure that, here in America, health care is a right and not a privilege.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris in a Meeting with Members of the Texas State Senate and Texas House of Representatives</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/16/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-in-a-meeting-with-members-of-the-texas-state-senate-and-texas-house-of-representatives/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:51:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room  11:18 A.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So let me begin today by saying thank you to all of you.  You are courageous leaders and you&#8217;re American patriots.  And so, I&#8217;m very pleased to welcome you &#8212; and for many of you, welcome you back &#8212; to the White House to have yet another&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Roosevelt Room </em></p>



<p>11:18 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  So let me begin today by saying thank you to all of you.  You are courageous leaders and you&#8217;re American patriots. <br><br>And so, I&#8217;m very pleased to welcome you &#8212; and for many of you, welcome you back &#8212; to the White House to have yet another very important conversation, and this time about one of the most important pillars of our democracy, which is about the fundamental right to vote.  <br><br>And when we look at what has happened in Texas, we look at what&#8217;s happening around the country, I think it&#8217;s important to remember: We talk about the right to vote, and the right to vote is a given.  All citizens have the right to vote.  Constitutionally, it is their right.<br><br>What we are seeing are examples of an attempt to interfere with that right and attempt to marginalize and take from people a right that has already been given.  We are not asking for the bestowal of a right; we are talking about the preservation of a right that is the right of citizenship.  And it&#8217;s that fundamental.  It is that fundamental. <br><br>And so, when I look at that and the fact that Americans are at risk of losing their access to their right &#8212; they still have the right, but losing access to that right &#8212; we know we have a great challenge in front of us, and therefore, a fight, which is to fight for every American’s right &#8212; meaningful right to vote.<br><br>And so that&#8217;s where we are.  And, of course, since 2013 and the gutting of Shelby &#8212; in the Shelby v. Holder case, we have seen exactly what we fear when that case came down in 2013. Because that case was an opening of a door to allow states to do what otherwise we have protected against, which is states putting in place laws that are designed, in many cases quite intentionally, to make it difficult for people to vote. <br><br>And so this is what we&#8217;ve seen over and over again, and what&#8217;s happening right now in Texas is, of course, a very clear and current example of that.  So, to the &#8212; to the point of what we must do collectively to ensure that every American retains their right to vote, our administration &#8212; President Biden and myself and our administration are here to make very clear that we will do everything in our power as an administration to lift up the voices of those who seek to preserve the right of the people to vote. <br><br>We&#8217;re not telling people how to vote.  And, frankly, this is not a Democratic or a Republican issue; this is an American issue.  This is an American issue. <br><br>When we look at these attempts to infringe on people&#8217;s access to voting, we know that it is going to impact people &#8212; Americans with disabilities, seniors, students, people of every walk of life. <br><br>When we look at these laws that are designed to interfere with poll workers &#8212; well, let&#8217;s think about that for a moment.  I have voted and been &#8212; and visited with these wonderful American volunteers, the poll workers, when I&#8217;ve gone to vote at the local elementary school, when I&#8217;ve gone to vote at the local church.  This is who we&#8217;re talking about, and interfering with them in what they are doing as part of their civic duty. <br><br>These are some of the issues that are at play.  And so, I welcome you.  I welcome you on behalf the President and myself.  As you know, he&#8217;s in Europe right now.  But we wanted to greet you here in the Roosevelt Room as an extension of the importance of the work you are doing, not only on behalf of the people of Texas, but the people of our country and our nation as a whole. <br><br>And while we will meet, we will also talk about the administration&#8217;s absolute commitment to seeing Congress &#8212; the United States Congress &#8212; pass the John Lewis Voting Rights Act and to pass the For the People Act to, again, put back in place the protections that existed before and to ensure, as we go forward, that as there are new attacks on the access to the polls and voting, that we head them off in a way that ensures again that the people retain their right to vote however they choose, but unimpeded.  <br><br>So with that, I want to thank all of you, and we will talk about Senate Bill 7 and how it clearly has been written in a way that will make it difficult for people and what you all are doing as courageous leaders that, again, speak up for the people.  And that is what you are doing.  <br><br>So, thank you all, and I look forward to our discussion.  And let us begin.  Let us begin.  So, thank you. <br><br> 11:24 A.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement From Senior Advisor and Chief Spokesperson Symone Sanders on Vice President Kamala Harris’s Meeting with Texas State Legislators on Voting Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/06/16/statement-from-senior-advisor-and-chief-spokesperson-symone-sanders-on-vice-president-kamala-harriss-meeting-with-texas-state-legislators-on-voting-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:49:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21205</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The right to vote is fundamental to our democracy—and defending that fundamental right is the most important work we can do as a nation. Today Vice President Harris met with 16 members of the Texas State Senate and Texas House of Representatives, who in May blocked passage of legislation that would have made it significantly&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The right to vote is fundamental to our democracy—and defending that fundamental right is the most important work we can do as a nation. Today Vice President Harris met with 16 members of the Texas State Senate and Texas House of Representatives, who in May blocked passage of legislation that would have made it significantly harder for the people of Texas to vote. They discussed the restrictive voting measures that already exist in Texas, the measures that would have been added under Texas Senate Bill 7 (SB7), and the path forward to make voting more accessible.</p>



<p>Members spoke about the real impact and effects of denying people the right to vote – including that it could lead to denial of health care, underfunding education, and failure to prepare the state to address emergency situations such as when the state had a power outage.</p>



<p>Members also spoke about the strength of building diverse coalitions around common values such as faith, education, and economic opportunity.</p>



<p>Members thanked the Vice President for lifting up the work to protect the right to vote and to make it more accessible to all Texans – and by extension – all Americans.</p>



<p>Over the last few weeks, the Vice President has spoken with a number of local and national leaders. On Monday, the Vice President held her first meeting on the ground regarding voting rights while she was in Greenville, South Carolina. Today’s meeting continued that work. The Vice President’s work moving forward will focus on educating the American people about voting rights attacks, building a coalition to bring together Americans concerned about their right and ability to vote, advancing federal legislation, registering voters per the President&#8217;s Executive Order on March 7th, and advocating for democratic principles worldwide.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration will protect the fundamental right to vote for all Americans regardless of where they live—by working to make voting accessible for all Americans and make sure every vote is counted through a transparent process.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title> Remarks by President Biden Before Air Force One Departure </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2021/06/16/remarks-by-president-biden-before-air-force-one-departure-4/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Jun 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=21193</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Geneva AirportGeneva, Switzerland 8:21 P.M. CEST THE PRESIDENT:  I owe my last question an apology.  I shouldn’t have &#8212; I shouldn’t have been such a wise guy with the last answer I gave. Anyway, thanks for being here.  And most of you have been here the whole route.  I really do think &#8212; not me, but I&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Geneva Airport<br>Geneva, Switzerland</p>



<p>8:21 P.M. CEST<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I owe my last question an apology.  I shouldn’t have &#8212; I shouldn’t have been such a wise guy with the last answer I gave.<br> <br>Anyway, thanks for being here.  And most of you have been here the whole route.  I really do think &#8212; not me, but I think we, the country, has put a different face on where we&#8217;ve been and where we&#8217;re going.  And I feel good about it.  I feel &#8212;<br> <br>You know, one of things that I think, understandably, there was a good deal of skepticism about: would the G7 sign on and give America back it&#8217;s, sort of, leadership role.  I think it did.  It wasn’t me, but it meant they&#8217;re glad America is back.  They&#8217;re glad America is back, and they acted that way. <br> <br>And then, when we went to NATO, I think it was the same thing.  We had really good meetings there and real response, as well as the EU.  I didn’t get one single person &#8212; not one of the world leaders said to us anything other than thanking me for arranging a meeting with Putin.  And I thought, quite frankly, I was in a much better position to represent the West, after the previous three meetings with Putin, that &#8212; knowing that the rest of the West was behind us.  And so, I think &#8212; so I owe them all a debt of gratitude.<br> <br>Q    Mr. President, since you&#8217;re now heading home, can I just ask you briefly about two domestic issues?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I&#8217;m not sure I can answer them, but &#8212;<br> <br>Q    If you could.  First would be this fate of the infrastructure bill.  There&#8217;s now a bipartisan group that has a new offer.  Have you had time to review it?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  I haven’t seen it.  No, I &#8212; I&#8217;m not being &#8212; I honestly haven’t seen it.  I don’t know what the details are.  I know that my Chief of Staffs thinks there’s some room that there may be a means by which to get this done.  And I know that Schumer and Nancy have moved forward on a reconciliation provision as well.  So I&#8217;m still hoping we could put together the two bookends here.<br> <br>Q    And the second issue is: Yesterday &#8212; or earlier this week, Mitch McConnell said that if Republicans were to take back the Senate in 2022, he did not see a way that you could get a Supreme Court justice confirmed.  Do you have a response to that?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Uh &#8212;<br> <br>Q    This would be next year.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, I know.  I know.  The answer is: Mitch is &#8212; Mitch has been nothing but &#8220;no&#8221; for a long time.  And I&#8217;m sure he means exactly what he says, but we&#8217;ll see.<br> <br>Q    Mr. President, did you talk with President Putin about the Iran nuclear deal? <br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Yes.<br> <br>Q    Did you make &#8212; find a way?  What did you discuss, and did you find a way to make some progress?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  It was about how we would jointly work, and I&#8217;m not going to discuss what we discussed.<br> <br>Q    Mr. President, Kaitlan&#8217;s question that you answered at the very end there, that you came over to talk about, I think at the heart of it was this question of whether or not you seem overly optimistic, given that &#8212; what we all listened to President Putin essentially say the same, old things that he’s said forever.  He &#8212; you know, rejecting all responsibility for all that stuff. <br> <br>And I guess the question that she was trying to get, and maybe you could take another stab at it, is: What concrete evidence do you have from these three &#8212; three plus hours that suggest that any movement has been made?<br> <br>And I don’t &#8212; I don’t mean that to be &#8212; I’m not &#8212; it’s not meant to be a &#8212; (inaudible) &#8212;<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, no, no.  No.  I know, but you’re all &#8212;<br> <br>Q    &#8212; (inaudible) question.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Look, to be a good reporter, you got to be negative.  You got to have a negative view of life &#8212; okay? &#8212; it seems to me, the way you all &#8212; you never ask a positive question. <br> <br>Why, in fact, having agreement &#8212; we’ll find out.  We have an agreement to work on a major arms control agreement. <br> <br>I started on working on arms control agreements back all the way during the Cold War.  If we could do one when the Cold War, why couldn’t we do one now?  We’ll see.  We will see whether or not it happens. <br> <br>But what do you &#8212; I mean, the thing that always amazes me about the questions &#8212; and I apologize for having been short on this before.<br> <br>If you were in my position, would you say, “Well, I don’t think, man, anything is going to happen.  This is going to be really rough.  I think it’s going to really be bad”?  You’d guarantee nothing happens.  You’d guarantee nothing happens.<br> <br>And so, so far &#8212;<br> <br>Q    So, there’s a value to &#8212;<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  There’s a value to being realistic and put on an optimistic front, an optimistic face.<br> <br>Look, you all said the same thing about the, you know, what was going to happen when we had the first meeting of the &#8212; of &#8212; of the seven.  “Oh, Biden &#8212; they’re not going to &#8212; they’re not going to buy Biden’s stuff.  They’re really not really…”<br> <br>Any of you find that?  Did that happen?  Any of it?  A little bit?  Just a little sliver of it? <br> <br>When I went to meet with NATO &#8212; “Oh boy, they’re not going to be happy.  They’re all going to be against Biden meeting with Putin.  They’re not going to want that.”  Did you hear a single, solitary syllable?<br> <br>Now, what would have happen if I had said, before I went into those negotiations, “You know, I think it’s going to be really hard.  I think it’s going to be really difficult.  I’m not so optimistic about &#8212; I don’t see anybody really changing”? <br> <br>And the same way when I met with the EU.  “The EU is not going to like the way Biden is operating.” <br> <br>Q    But this is Vladimir Putin.  I mean, can you be optimistic about his change?<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Sure, it’s Vladimir Putin.  But, look, it was also &#8212; I don’t want to compare him to Putin, but it was &#8212; the French President said he will never go for more money for NATO.  Guess what?  He’s agreed. <br> <br>Every &#8212; I mean, look, guys, I’m going to drive you all crazy because I know you want me to always put a negative thrust on things, particularly in public, and negotiate in public. <br> <br>I don’t have to trust somebody &#8212; we didn’t have to trust somebody to get START II.  It wasn&#8217;t a about our trust &#8212; “Well, I trust the Russians.  I can tell, man, they&#8217;re really &#8212; they&#8217;re &#8212; I can look in his eye, and they&#8217;re really very, very truthful.”  It&#8217;s not that at all. <br> <br>You have to figure out what the other guy&#8217;s self-interest is.  Their self-interest.  I don&#8217;t trust anybod- &#8212; look, I&#8217;ve got to get in the plane, but I&#8217;ll say it &#8212; you&#8217;ll hear me say this more than once.<br> <br>Q    It’s your plane.  You can go when you want.  (Laughter.)<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  Yeah, no, but &#8212; no, but here’s the thing: Folks, I &#8212; I don&#8217;t see any benefit ever to begin a negotiation as &#8212; and, I mean, you&#8217;re the brightest people in the country.  You&#8217;re the most informed people on detail.  I&#8217;m not being solicitous; you are.  But it makes no sense for me to negotiate with you.  It makes no sense for me to tell you what I&#8217;m about to do.  It makes &#8212; not because I want to hide anything from you.  Why would I telegraph that?<br> <br>Q    Did he do anything that surprised you, sir?<br> <br>AIDE:  Sir, we need to go.  Sir, we really have to go. <br> <br>Q    Was there any moment that you were really surprised by?<br> <br>AIDE:  Sir &#8212; thank you, guys.  Thank you, guys.<br> <br>THE PRESIDENT:  No, I wasn’t surprised because I was convinced that &#8212; let me choose my words.  Russia is in a very, very difficult spot right now.  They are being squeezed by China.  They want desperately to remain a major power.  You all are writing about, not illegitimately, “Biden already gave Putin what he wants: legitimacy, standing in the world stage with the President of the United States.”  They desperately want to have &#8212; be relevant. <br> <br>They have &#8212; and they don&#8217;t want to be known as, as some critics have pointed and said, you know, the &#8220;Upper Volta with nuclear weapons.&#8221;  It matters.  And I found it matters to almost every world leader &#8212; no matter where they&#8217;re from &#8212; how they&#8217;re perceived, their standing in the world.  It matters to them.  It matters to them in terms of their support at home as well. <br> <br>And so I think that there is &#8212; I&#8217;m trying to think how to shorten this so I can get in the plane. <br> <br>I&#8217;m of the view that, in the last three to five years, the world has reached a fundamental inflection point about what it&#8217;s going to look like 10 years from now.  I mean it literally.  It&#8217;s not hyperbole.  It&#8217;s not like I&#8217;m trying to pump it up.  I think it&#8217;s a genuine reality. <br> <br>And so each of the countries in &#8212; around the world, particularly those who had real power at one time or still do, are wondering: What &#8212; how do I maintain and sustain our leadership in the world?  That&#8217;s what the United States is going through right now.  How do we sustain us being the leading, the most powerful, and most democratic country in the world?  A lot is going on. <br> <br>I don&#8217;t know about you, I never anticipated, notwithstanding no matter how persuasive President Trump was, that we&#8217;d have people attacking and breaking down the doors of the United States Capitol.  I didn&#8217;t think that would happen.  I didn&#8217;t think we’d &#8212; I&#8217;d see that in my lifetime.  But it&#8217;s reinforced what I&#8217;ve always known and what I got taught by my political science professors and by the senior members of the Senate that I admired when I got there: that every generation has to re-establish the basis of its fight for democracy.  I mean, for real, literally have to do it. <br> <br>And I&#8217;ve never seen, including during &#8212; since the Civil War, such an outward assault on voting rights.  I mean, just a flat assault.  I didn&#8217;t anticipate that happening four years ago, but it&#8217;s happening now. <br> <br>So, there&#8217;s a lot at stake.  Each of the countries, we have our own concerns and problems, but we still &#8212; as long as I&#8217;m President, we are going to stick to the notion that we&#8217;re open, accountable, and transparent.  And I think that&#8217;s an important message to send the world. <br> <br>Thank you all so much.<br> <br>8:31 P.M. CEST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
