<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 15:37:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: White&#160;House Calls on Congress to Provide Additional Support for&#160;Ukraine</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-white-house-calls-on-congress-to-provide-additional-support-for-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 15:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51950</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The assistance the Biden-Harris Administration has provided to Ukraine to date has made a significant difference on the battlefield, helping Ukrainians defend their country and win the battle for Kyiv. Now, as the war shifts to and intensifies in Ukraine’s eastern front, the Biden-Harris Administration is calling on Congress to provide additional resources to help&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The assistance the Biden-Harris Administration has provided to Ukraine to date has made a significant difference on the battlefield, helping Ukrainians defend their country and win the battle for Kyiv. Now, as the war shifts to and intensifies in Ukraine’s eastern front, the Biden-Harris Administration is <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-on-fiscal-year-2022-emergency-supplemental-funding/">calling on</a> Congress to provide additional resources to help ensure Ukraine’s democracy prevails over Putin’s aggression.<br><br>The supplemental resources Congress provided on a bipartisan basis in March have been critical to bolstering security in Eastern Europe, countering Russia’s malign activities in the region, and delivering critical humanitarian and economic assistance to Ukraine and neighboring partners. Almost all of the $3.5 billion in drawdown authority Congress provided in March has been exhausted as the Biden-Harris Administration has surged military assistance to Ukraine, which they have used to great effect. U.S. supplied weapons and ammunitions – including anti-tank and anti-air systems, helicopters, drones, grenade launchers, and more than 50 million rounds of ammunition – have been flowing into Ukraine daily, and the United States has been working with allies and partners to facilitate deliveries of additional weapons capabilities. The Defense Department has also used $1 billion in supplemental resources to reinforce NATO’s eastern flank and bolster NATO’s security posture to deter Russian aggression.</p>



<p>At the same time, the Administration is delivering humanitarian, economic, food, and other security assistance to Ukraine and the region. This includes roughly $1.7 billion to ensure continuity of Ukraine’s democratic operations and provide other macroeconomic assistance to the region. It also includes $650 million in military assistance to Ukraine, eastern flank countries, and other partners in the region, as well as hundreds of millions of dollars in food, shelter, and other humanitarian aid to help Ukrainians who have been displaced by Russia’s war. Supplemental resources are also supporting efforts to hold Putin and his cronies accountable for their war of choice, helping the United States seize billions in assets and holdings.</p>



<p>Continued bipartisan support in Congress is vital to ensuring that the Ukrainian people have the resources they need to win this war, and this Administration is committed to working with lawmakers and our global allies and partners to keep aid flowing to Ukraine uninterrupted and to support those devastated by the food crisis that Putin’s war has exacerbated.<br><br>The $33 billion in security, economic, and humanitarian aid requested today will:<br><br><strong><em>Help Ukraine Defend Itself Over the Long-Term</em></strong><br><br>The Administration is requesting $20.4 billion in additional security and military assistance for Ukraine and for U.S. efforts to strengthen European security in cooperation with our NATO allies and other partners in the region. This includes $5 billion in additional drawdown authority, $6 billion for the Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative, and $4 billion for the State Department’s Foreign Military Financing program. These resources will put urgently needed equipment into the hands of Ukraine&#8217;s military and police, as well as help NATO deter and defend against Russian aggression over the long-term. These additional resources will be used to provide Ukraine and Eastern flank allies with:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Additional artillery, armored vehicles, anti-armor and anti-air capabilities </strong>flowing into Ukraine uninterrupted<strong>.</strong><br></li><li><strong>Accelerated cyber capabilities and advanced air defense systems</strong>, improved production capabilities for munitions and strategic minerals, and increased intelligence support.<br></li><li><strong>Assistance to clear landmines, improvised explosive devices, and other explosive remnants of war </strong>and for the Government of Ukraine in securing and addressing threats related to chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear materials.<br></li><li><strong>A stronger NATO security posture </strong>through support for U.S. troop deployments on NATO territory, including transportation of U.S. personnel and equipment, temporary duty, special pay, airlift, weapons system sustainment, and medical support.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Additional Economic Aid to Support Democracy in Ukraine</em></strong><br><br>The Administration is calling on Congress to provide an additional $8.5 billion in economic assistance to help the Government of Ukraine respond to the immediate crisis and continue to provide basic citizen services. This includes funds to:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Ensure Ukraine’s democratic government continues functioning; </strong>support food, energy, and health care services for the Ukrainian people; and assist the Ukrainian government in responding to operational challenges as businesses shutter and revenue collection plummets.<br></li><li><strong>Counter Russian disinformation and propaganda narratives</strong>, promote accountability for Russian human rights violation, and support activists, journalists, and independent media to defend freedom of expression.<br></li><li><strong>Support small- and medium- sized agrobusinesses during the fall harvest and for natural gas purchases</strong> by the Ukrainian state energy company in order to address critical food security, energy, and other emerging needs in Ukraine.</li></ul>



<p><em><strong>Address Humanitarian Needs due to Russia’s War<br></strong></em><br>The $3 billion in additional humanitarian assistance will provide critical resources to address food security needs around the globe, provide wheat and other commodities to people in need, build countries&#8217; resilience to global food supply and price shocks, and provide lifesaving aid to people displaced by or otherwise impacted by Putin’s War in Ukraine. This funding will mean:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Direct food support, including wheat and flour, for individuals in developing countries </strong>impacted by Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, as well as helping countries build more resilient agricultural systems.<br></li><li><strong>Medical supplies, high thermal blankets, emergency health kits, safe drinking water, shelter materials</strong>, and other lifesaving humanitarian assistance for Ukrainians displaced by Russia’s war.<br></li><li><strong>Job training, trauma-informed mental health services, and resources for local school districts to support Ukrainians arriving in the United States, </strong>including the new Uniting for Ukraine program.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Bolster Sanctions Enforcement</em></strong><br><br>Resources will also bolster the Department of Justice’s KleptoCapture Task force efforts to pursue high value asset seizures from sanctioned individuals related to Russian actions in Ukraine. The Administration is also proposing legislation to streamline the process to recoup proceeds from seized and forfeited assets and use them to remediate the harm caused in Ukraine.<br><br><strong><em>Addressing Economic Disruptions at Home and Around the World Due to Putin’s Aggression</em></strong><br><br>An additional $500 million in domestic food production assistance will support the production of U.S. food crops that are experiencing a global shortage due to the war in Ukraine, for example, wheat and soybeans. Through higher loan rates and crop insurance incentives the request provides greater access to credit and lowers risk for farmers growing these food commodities, while lowering costs for American consumers.<br><br>Additional funding will also allow use of the Defense Production Act to expand domestic production of critical minerals and materials that have been disrupted by Putin’s war in Ukraine and that are necessary to make everything from defense systems to automobiles.  This will help address economic disruptions and reduce price pressures at home and around the world.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives on Fiscal Year 2022 Emergency Supplemental&#160;Funding</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-on-fiscal-year-2022-emergency-supplemental-funding/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 15:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51956</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker:&#160;I am writing to provide you with my request for fiscal year (FY) 2022 emergency supplemental funding for critical security and economic assistance to Ukraine.&#160;I appreciate the Congress&#8217; continued bipartisan support for Ukraine, NATO, and other partner countries affected by Russia&#8217;s War in Ukraine.&#160; My Administration is committed to providing the Ukrainian people&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker:<br>&nbsp;<br>I am writing to provide you with my request for fiscal year (FY) 2022 emergency supplemental funding for critical security and economic assistance to Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>I appreciate the Congress&#8217; continued bipartisan support for Ukraine, NATO, and other partner countries affected by Russia&#8217;s War in Ukraine.&nbsp; My Administration is committed to providing the Ukrainian people the assistance they need.&nbsp; Our assistance to date has made a difference on the battlefield, helping Ukraine win the battle for Kyiv.&nbsp; This $33.0 billion request for&nbsp;additional funding and authority builds on the Congress&#8217; supplemental appropriation of $13.6&nbsp;billion on March 15, 2022, and seeks to address immediate and near-term security and economic needs.&nbsp; Additional security assistance will put urgently needed equipment into the hands of Ukraine&#8217;s military and police, including ammunition, armored vehicles, small arms, demining assistance, and unmanned aircraft systems.&nbsp; Economic assistance will provide Direct Budget Support to provide rapid, flexible funds to assist the Government of Ukraine in responding to the immediate crisis and continue to provide basic citizen services.&nbsp; Additional food security and humanitarian assistance will provide wheat and other commodities to people in need, build countries&#8217; resilience to global food supply and price shocks, and provide lifesaving aid to people displaced by or otherwise impacted by Russia&#8217;s War in Ukraine. &nbsp;Additionally, the request includes funding to support the production of United&nbsp;States food crops that are experiencing a global shortage due to the war in Ukraine, for example, wheat and soybeans helping to address rising food prices here at home and around the world.&nbsp; The request also would help increase domestic production for strategic minerals and materials produced in Russia or Ukraine and respond to global shortfalls and reduce price pressures.&nbsp; The request also outlines a number of authorities needed to support Ukraine, our European allies and&nbsp;partners, and address other emergent global needs.&nbsp; The details of this request are set forth in an enclosed addendum.<br>&nbsp;<br>Though we expect our NATO allies and EU partners will be making even larger collective contributions than the United States, there is no doubt that continuing to support Ukraine in this war against Russian aggression will require a substantial additional investment on our part.&nbsp; What I want to make clear to the Congress and the American people is this:&nbsp; the cost of failing to stand up to violent aggression in Europe has always been higher than the cost of standing firm against such attacks.&nbsp; That is as it always has been, and as it always will be.&nbsp; America must meet this moment, and do its part.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>In addition to the legislative proposals in this package, my Administration is also sending a proposal to the Congress to enhance the United States&#8217; ability to hold Russia accountable financially for its ongoing invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; These proposals would strengthen our whole-of-government approach &#8212; along with those of our international partners &#8212; by providing for expanded and expedited measures for investigating, prosecuting, and forfeiting assets of Russian oligarchs to&nbsp;be&nbsp;used for the benefit of Ukraine.<br>&nbsp;<br>Finally, I also appreciate the Congress&#8217; bipartisan support for ensuring we can continue to provide the American people with the tools they need to protect themselves from COVID-19, and again urge the Congress to act promptly to provide the $22.5 billion I&nbsp;requested on March 2, 2022.&nbsp; Without additional funding, we are unable to purchase additional life-saving treatments for the American people, and we are losing our spot in line to other countries for vaccines that may provide better and more durable protection against multiple variants.&nbsp; We also must stop the spread of possible new variants from around the world as every COVID variant has emerged from overseas.&nbsp; We have to keep vaccinating the world to save lives here at home and protect our&nbsp;economy from further supply chain disruptions, but we need funding to help get shots into arms. &nbsp;To avoid needless deaths in the United States and around the world, I urge the Congress to include this much needed, life-saving COVID funding as part of this supplemental funding request.&nbsp; &nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I urge the Congress to address these critical and urgent needs promptly.&nbsp; The amounts included in this request are requested to&nbsp;be designated by the Congress as being for an emergency requirement pursuant to section 4001(a)(1) and section 4001(b) of S. Con. Res. 14 (117th Congress), the concurrent resolution on the budget for FY 2022.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President Joe&#160;Biden on Gross Domestic&#160;Product</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/statement-by-president-joe-biden-on-gross-domestic-product/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 13:57:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51945</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The American economy — powered by working families — continues to be resilient in the face of historic challenges. Last quarter, consumer spending, business investment, and residential investment increased at strong rates. The number of Americans on unemployment insurance remains at the lowest level since 1970. Later this morning, I will meet with small business&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The American economy — powered by working families — continues to be resilient in the face of historic challenges. Last quarter, consumer spending, business investment, and residential investment increased at strong rates. The number of Americans on unemployment insurance remains at the lowest level since 1970. Later this morning, I will meet with small business owners who are creating and growing their businesses at a historic rate. While last quarter’s growth estimate was affected by technical factors, the United States confronts the challenges of COVID-19 around the world, Putin’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, and global inflation from a position of strength.</p>



<p>We need to keep making progress — cutting costs for working families, making more in America, and creating good-paying jobs you can raise a middle-class family on. Congressional Republicans, led by Senator Scott, believe the way to fight these global challenges is by raising taxes on middle class families, including half of small business owners. I have a different approach. Congress should send to my desk a bipartisan innovation bill to bolster our supply chains and make more in America. And Congress needs to pass legislation to lower costs and lower the deficit, reducing families’ prescription drug and utility bills and restoring fairness to our tax code — without raising taxes on anyone making less than $400,000 per year. That’s how we grow our economy and strengthen the middle class.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: U.S. Agencies Are Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the&#160;World</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-u-s-agencies-are-advancing-the-human-rights-of-lgbtqi-persons-around-the-world/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51934</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We’re… making equality the centerpiece of our diplomacy around the world.  We believe LGBTQ+ rights are human rights.  In February, I signed a presidential memorandum establishing that it’s the policy of the United States to pursue an end to violence and discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity. – President Joe Biden&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>We’re… making equality the centerpiece of our diplomacy around the world.  We believe LGBTQ+ rights are human rights.  In February, I signed a presidential memorandum establishing that it’s the policy of the United States to pursue an end to violence and discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation or gender identity.</em></p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">– President Joe Biden</p>



<p>Today, the U.S. Government released a first of its kind progress <a href="https://www.state.gov/lgbtqi-human-rights/">report</a> on implementation of President Biden’s <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2021/02/04/memorandum-advancing-the-human-rights-of-lesbian-gay-bisexual-transgender-queer-and-intersex-persons-around-the-world/">Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World</a>. &nbsp;The progress demonstrates the U.S. commitment to promoting and protecting the human rights of LGBTQI+ people around the world through our diplomacy and foreign assistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Federal agencies are:   <br><br><strong>Combating Criminalization of LGBTQI+ Status or Conduct Abroad</strong>:  The Department of State and the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), together with U.S. embassies and USAID missions, are taking innovative and bold steps to leverage diplomatic engagement and foreign assistance to promote the human rights of LGBTQI+ people, including through elevating concerns about criminalization of LGBTQI+ status or conduct with local officials, in collaboration with like-minded partners.  U.S. embassies and USAID missions also continue to welcome decisions of governments that decriminalize LGBTQI+ status or conduct.  As documented in the report, the scope and breadth of U.S.  engagement in this critical area continues to increase and strengthen.     <br><br><strong>Protecting Vulnerable LGBTQI+ Refugees and Asylum Seekers:</strong>  In December 2021, the Department of State announced a package of new pledges to support LGBTQI+ refugees, including enhanced training for the staff of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees.  The Department of State is also working to increase resettlement for LGBTQI+ persons and members of other vulnerable groups through new and expanded referral programs with NGOs and other organizations to the U.S. Refugee Admissions Program.  U.S. embassies also continue to support LGBTQI+ refugee needs through highlighting gaps in services and supporting civil society partners.  In February, the Department of Homeland Security issued revised guidance to recognize informal same-sex marriages for the purposes of obtaining refugee or asylee status, even if they are not officially recognized by officials in countries of origin.  The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) is providing resources for LGBTQI+ refugees and their allies, including intensive case management for refugees who are vulnerable to discrimination.<br><br><strong>Ensuring Foreign Assistance Protects Human Rights and Advances Non-discrimination:  </strong>In FY2021, the Department of State increased its support to the Global Equality Fund to $10 million annually.  The Fund now supports programs in over 100 countries in all global regions.  The Department of Health and Human (HHS) Services also supported new initiatives to increase access to health services for LGBTQI+ persons, including a new health and resource center for transgender persons in India.  USAID released new guidance outlining how to integrate the needs of LGBTQI+ persons into <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/External_Draft_-_Integrating_LGBTQI_Considerations_into_RFSs_Programming_Sectors-508.pdf">food security</a> and <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/sites/default/files/documents/_External_Draft_Integrating_LGBTQI_Considerations_In_Education_Programming_210601-508.pdf">education</a>-related development programming.  To advance non-discrimination in foreign assistance, the Department of Labor added new terms, definitions, and requirements related to advancing LGBTQI+ human rights in its guidance for its overseas grant solicitations and contracts, and HHS developed a similar equity appendix for the annual update to the Notice of Funding Award Guidance.  The Department of State’s U.S. Fulbright Student and Teacher Programs also updated its applications to include non-binary gender options for the first time.  And the Peace Corps undertook steps to recruit more diverse applicants, including by holding a panel on “Translating Transgender Identity Abroad” to specifically recruit transgender applicants.  To coordinate these efforts and facilitate resource and experience sharing, USAID convenes a thirteen-agency working group to discuss policy, programming, and inclusive data priorities.<br><br><strong>Taking Swift and Meaningful Responses to Human Rights Abuses of LGBTQI+ Persons Abroad:</strong>  The Department of State’s Global Equality Fund provides emergency funding to LGBTQI+ activists through the Dignity for All program to respond to active human rights violations and crises globally.  USAID programs build in flexibility and support for rapid response programming in the countries where they operate.  And across the globe, U.S. diplomats and U.S. development professionals are at the forefront of highlighting LGBTQI+ human rights attacks and abuses.  For example, in Poland, U.S. Embassy Warsaw supported “Words Matter,” a <a href="https://pl.usembassy.gov/wordsmatter_eng/">video</a> featuring members of the Polish LGBTQI+ community reading and reacting to homophobic comments posted in response to the Embassy’s social media campaign for Pride Month.  The &#8220;Words Matter&#8221; video reached over 12 million Poles and was widely covered by both Polish and international media.  In Guatemala, following murders of Guatemalan leaders in the transgender community in June 2021, U.S. Embassy Guatemala City issued a <a href="https://twitter.com/usembassyguate/status/1403573244112867331?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1403573244112867331%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.washingtonblade.com%2F2021%2F06%2F17%2Fus-condemns-murder-of-prominent-transgender-activist-in-guatemala%2F">statement</a> condemning the murders and urging full investigations. <br><br><strong>Building International Coalitions:</strong>  At the UN General Assembly’s Third Committee in November, the U.S.-led resolution on democracy and elections included for the first time a call for states to eliminate discrimination in the right to participate in public affairs based on “sexual orientation and gender identity.”  The U.S. Mission to the United Nations led the lobbying campaign to include this important new language.  The U.S. also advanced LGBTQI+ human rights together with like-minded partners in the Organizing for Security and Cooperation in Europe and the Organization of American States, and in the Equal Rights Coalition, which recently released statements with U.S. support focused on<a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/aggression-against-ukraine-and-the-protection-of-lgbti-persons-and-refugees-equal-rights-coalition-statement"> protection of LGBTQI+ persons in Ukraine</a>, and on <a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/nexus-between-democracy-and-the-human-rights-of-lgbti-people-equal-rights-coalition-statement-december-2021">democracy and LGBTQI+ human rights</a>. <br><br><strong>Rescinding Inconsistent Polices:</strong>  This Administration continues to update polices that are inconsistent with the President’s Memorandum on Advancing the Human Rights of LGBTQI+ Persons Around the World.  USAID, for example, reinstated a reporting mechanism to track overall foreign assistance which advances LGBTQI+ human rights and inclusive development.  In collaboration with HHS, the Department of State withdrew from the “Geneva Consensus Declaration,” and requested its removal from the UN document system in February 2021.  The Geneva Consensus Declaration opposes abortion and related reproductive health and rights and is widely viewed as undermining LGBTQI+ human rights. <br><br><strong>Advancing Inclusive Democracy</strong>:  During the Summit for Democracy, the U.S.  supported a <a href="https://equalrightscoalition.org/publications/erc-statement-on-the-nexus-between-democracy-and-the-human-rights-of-lgbti-persons/">statement</a> from the Equal Rights Coalition on Democracy and LGBTQI+ rights which affirms that promoting and protecting the human rights of LGBTQI+ persons is essential for democratic renewal.  As part of the Presidential Initiative for Democratic Renewal, the State Department also committed up to $5 million to launch the <a href="https://www.state.gov/statements-of-interest-requests-for-proposals-and-notices-of-funding-opportunity/drl-fy2021-global-lgbtqi-inclusive-democracy-and-empowerment-glide-fund/">Global LGBTQI+ Inclusive Democracy and Empowerment (GLIDE) Fund</a>, a new program under the Global Equality Fund that will facilitate the participation and leadership of LGBTQI+ community members in democratic institutions.  Also, during the Summit for Democracy, USAID committed to launch a new Global Development Alliance to support LGBTQI-led civil society organizations to respond to the COVID-19 crisis, engage in democratic processes, and build networks of allies.  USAID intends to commit $5M USD over five-years to this program involving substantial capacity building opportunities and direct grantmaking to LGBTQI+ and transgender-led organizations around the world.<br><br><strong>Reducing Bias-Motivated Violence:  </strong>Agencies continue to take steps to reduce bias motivated violence and hate crime targeting LGBTQI+ persons.  For example, the Department of Justice, in coordination with the Department of State, has Resident Legal Advisor (RLA) programs in Albania, Croatia, Kosovo, and North Macedonia which advance LGBTQI+ human rights and assist foreign counterparts with managing cases, including of including LGBTQI+ individuals.  Additionally, the RLA program in the Baltics assists investigators, prosecutors, and judges with investigating, prosecuting, and adjudicating hate crimes, including crimes motivated by a victim’s gender identity or sexual orientation.  To strengthen knowledge on patterns of violence, discrimination, and appropriate responses, in September 2021, the Department of State launched a new partnership with the Library of Congress to evaluate existing academic research for linkages between bias, discrimination, and violence, including against LGBTQI+ persons.  The goal is to better understand which criminal justice interventions can prevent escalations in violence.  An inter-agency review committee will review the research findings and provide recommendations for future actions.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden’s Comprehensive Proposal to Hold Russian Oligarchs and Elites&#160;Accountable</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-president-bidens-comprehensive-proposal-to-hold-russian-oligarchs-accountable/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51917</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, in concert with his supplemental request to Congress to support Ukraine, President Biden will send a proposal for a comprehensive legislative package that will enhance the United States Government’s authority to hold the Russian government and Russian oligarchs accountable for President Putin’s war against Ukraine. The proposals were crafted in close consultation with interagency&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, in concert with his supplemental request to Congress to support Ukraine, President Biden will send a proposal for a comprehensive legislative package that will enhance the United States Government’s authority to hold the Russian government and Russian oligarchs accountable for President Putin’s war against Ukraine. The proposals were crafted in close consultation with interagency partners, including the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Justice, the Department of State, and the Department of Commerce. The Biden Administration looks forward to working closely with Members of Congress as a whole to implement this package of proposals.</p>



<p>This package of proposals will establish new authorities for the forfeiture of property linked to Russian kleptocracy, allow the government to use the proceeds to support Ukraine, and further strengthen related law enforcement tools.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Establishing a Streamlined Administrative Authority to Seize and Forfeit Oligarch Assets:</strong> This proposal aims to streamline the process for seizure of oligarch assets, expand the assets subject to seizure, and enable the proceeds to flow to Ukraine. It would:</p>



<ul><li>Create a new, streamlined administrative process involving the Departments of the Treasury and Justice, for the forfeiture of property in the United States that is owned by sanctioned Russian oligarchs and that has a connection to specified unlawful conduct. A forfeiture decision would be reviewable in federal court on an expedited basis.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Create a new criminal offense, making it unlawful for any person to knowingly or intentionally possess proceeds directly obtained from corrupt dealings with the Russian government.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Enabling the Transfer of the Proceeds of Forfeited Kleptocrat Property to Ukraine to Remediate Harms of Russian Aggression.</strong> This proposal would improve the United States’ ability to use forfeited oligarch funds to remediate harms caused to Ukraine by Russian aggression. Under the proposal, the Departments of Justice, Treasury, and State will work together to use forfeited funds related to corruption, sanctions and export control violations, and other specified offenses to remediate harms of Russian aggression toward Ukraine.</p>



<p><strong>Clamping Down on Facilitation of Sanctions Evasion: </strong>This proposal would allow for the forfeiture of property that Russian oligarchs use to facilitate the evasion of sanctions.&nbsp;Under current law, the United States can forfeit the proceeds of sanctions violations, but it cannot forfeit property used to facilitate sanctions violations.&nbsp;This proposal closes that gap.</p>



<p><strong>Modernizing Racketeering to Include Sanctions Evasion: </strong>This proposal would strengthen the United States’ ability to investigate and prosecute sanctions evasion by adding the crime of sanctions evasion to the definition of “racketeering activity” in the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations (RICO) Act. This proposal would give the Department of Justice a powerful forfeiture tool used against racketeering enterprises to dismantle organizations that enable violations of U.S. sanctions.</p>



<p><strong>Expanding the Time Limit to Follow the Money: </strong>This proposal would improve the United States’ ability to pursue money laundering prosecutions (and post-conviction forfeitures) based on foreign offenses by extending the statute of limitations from five years to ten years.&nbsp;Criminal investigations of oligarchs can be complicated because sophisticated criminals use intricate schemes that may cut across multiple jurisdictions. The United States often works with international partners on these cases. Extending the statute of limitations would provide additional time for investigators and prosecutors to hold oligarchs criminally accountable.</p>



<p><strong>Leveraging Foreign Partners’ Ability to Freeze and Seize Oligarch Wealth: </strong>This proposal would improve the United States’ ability to work with international partners to recover assets linked to foreign corruption.&nbsp;This proposal would make several amendments to improve our ability to enforce foreign restraint and forfeiture orders in the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>The United States has already been working with allies and partners to track down assets all over the world:</strong></p>



<ul><li>In March, the U.S., led by the Department of the Treasury and Department of Justice, launched the Russian Elites, Proxies, and Oligarchs Task Force with international partners to coordinate the freezing and seizing of Russian assets around the world.</li><li>So far, member states in the European Union have reported freezing over $30 billion in assets, including almost $7 billion in boats, helicopters, real estate, and artwork.</li><li>Dozens of yachts have been seized by REPO Task Force member countries. The U.S. Treasury has sanctioned and blocked vessels and aircraft worth over $1 billion, as well as frozen hundreds of millions of dollars of assets belonging to Russian elites in U.S. bank accounts.</li><li>Last week, in the wake of criminal charges, Treasury designated a global sanctions evasion network associated with Konstantin Malofeyev, crack downing on the movement of illicit assets.</li><li><a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/90-million-yacht-sanctioned-russian-oligarch-viktor-vekselberg-seized-spain-request-united">Earlier this month</a>, the Department of Justice announced that Spain seized a 255-foot, $90 million yacht of sanctioned Russian Oligarch Viktor Vekselberg at the request of United States.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on the Declaration for the Future of the&#160;Internet</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/28/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-the-declaration-for-the-future-of-the-internet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference (April 27, 2022) 4:06&#160;P.M. EDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&#160; So, this call is going to be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&#160; The contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow, Thursday, April 28th, 7:00 a.m. Eastern. You all should have gotten the Declaration under embargo in your&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">(April 27, 2022)</p>



<p>4:06&nbsp;P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining.&nbsp; So, this call is going to be on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow, Thursday, April 28th, 7:00 a.m. Eastern.<br><br>You all should have gotten the Declaration under embargo in your inboxes.&nbsp; If you didn&#8217;t, please email me.&nbsp; And there&#8217;s a factsheet that is also coming your way soon.<br><br>So, with that, I&#8217;m going to &#8212; and &#8212; sorry, and just for your awareness but not for your reporting, the speakers on this call are [senior administration official] and then [senior administration official].<br><br>So, I&#8217;m going to start with [senior administration official] to kick us off with some remarks.&nbsp; Thank you.<br><br>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Hi, everybody.&nbsp; And thank you for joining the call.<br><br>It goes without saying that the Internet has enabled extraordinary benefits for the country and also the world, but it has also created new policy challenges, both domestically and internationally.</p>



<p>On the international front &#8212; what we’re talking about today &#8212; we have seen a trend of rising digital authoritarianism, where some states have been acting to repress freedom of expression, to censor independent news sources, to interfere with elections, promote disinformation around the world, and deny their citizens other human rights.</p>



<p>The last two months have provided an extreme example of such behavior in connection with Russia’s invasion of Ukraine.<br><br>Russia has aggressively promoted disinformation at home and abroad, censored Internet news sources, blocked or shut down legitimate sites, and gone so far as to physically attack the Internet infrastructure in Ukraine.</p>



<p>Russia, however, is hardly alone but just one of the leaders in a dangerous new model of Internet policy along with the People’s Republic of China and some of the other most censorial states in the world.</p>



<p>In response to these alarming trends, the United States is launching the Declaration for the Future of the Internet &#8212; otherwise known as the “DFI” &#8212; jointly with more than 50 partners, 50 other states from around the world, including &#8212; on the morning of April 28th, 2022.&nbsp; And U.S. National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan will be hosting the launch with endorsing partners.<br><br>In fact, I think I can say more.&nbsp; We have more than 55 partner countries from around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I will note that this effort takes into account and is complementary to existing processes in the United Nations, the G7, the G20, the OECD, WTO, ICANN, the Freedom Online Coalition, and other relevant multilateral and multi-stakeholder fora.&nbsp; We will use this Declaration and the principles to fortify existing institutions.</p>



<p>Now I’m going to turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk more about the Declaration itself.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks to all of you for joining this afternoon.&nbsp; We are tremendously excited about the launch tomorrow of the DFI, which represents, obviously, something a number of us have been working on across the administration, joined by dozens of countries around the world &#8212; as [senior administration official] says, more than 55 at this point &#8212; for quite some time.&nbsp; And just really excited to get it &#8212; get it out there.<br><br>You know, as [moderator] said, and as I hope you all have in your inboxes &#8212; you have the Declaration text itself, so I’m going to keep my summary brief.<br><br>But, basically, the Declaration affirms fundamental principles regarding how countries should comport themselves with respect to the Internet and to the digital ecosystem, the digital economy.&nbsp; It commits governments to promoting an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable, and secure Internet for the world.</p>



<p>This includes defending the Internet &#8212; an Internet that is governed through a multi-stakeholder approach that works with and through existing institutions and processes; an Internet that fosters the protection and promotion of basic human rights online; and an Internet that advances these goals across relevant economic policies and regulatory activities.</p>



<p>I want to point out the significance of the timing of the Declaration.&nbsp; What you’re seeing with the launch of the DFI is democratic governments and other like-minded partners from around the world rising to the challenge at this critical moment in history.<br><br>Over the last year, the U.S. has worked extensively and intensively with partners from all over the world &#8212; with civil society, with industry, with academics, and other stakeholders &#8212; to try to reverse the current trajectory of the Internet, including through the development of this Declaration.</p>



<p>The DFI has not been a “U.S. effort” to which others are joining, but a truly joint effort with America’s allies and partners.&nbsp; The U.S. and partners endorsing this Declaration will work together in the weeks, months, and years ahead to implement these principles and to promote this vision globally, while respecting each other’s regulatory autonomy within our own jurisdictions and in accordance with our respective domestic laws and international legal obligations.<br><br>The Declaration will also remain open after the launch to all partners who are willing to endorse its vision and uphold its principles.&nbsp; And so, we’re excited to have more than 55 countries join tomorrow.&nbsp; We’re also excited to see other counties come on &#8212; come on board as this goes forward.</p>



<p>Efforts like this take work and time, but we believe the DFI will advance a positive vision for digital technologies anchored by democratic values.&nbsp; We look forward to working with governments, the private sector, international organizations, the technical community, academia and civil society, and other relevant stakeholders worldwide to promote, foster, and achieve this shared vision.</p>



<p>[Moderator], let me turn it back over to you for a few questions.<br><br>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Could we cue up the directions, please, to ask a question?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello.&nbsp; Thanks so much for this.&nbsp; Can you maybe address why you aren’t doing this through the U.N. framework at the OEWG, and if this is any kind of indictment of that process?<br><br>And I noticed India and New Zealand are not on the list.&nbsp; Have you asked them?&nbsp; And what is the significance of getting their buy-in?<br><br>And finally, can you talk a little bit about the risks you see of splinternet and whether this is about more disinformation or physical attacks on infrastructure?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to start with those?&nbsp; Well, maybe I’ll start with one point, which &#8212; the good news is New Zealand has, in fact, joined the Declaration slightly (inaudible).&nbsp; And we &#8212; you know, the hope remains that time isn’t fully passed yet for India to join.&nbsp; But we&#8217;ve been engaged in &#8212; in very intensive efforts to have all of these &#8212; all of these countries join.&nbsp;<br><br>And we&#8217;ve been very &#8212; frankly, as [senior administration official] said, you know, we&#8217;re not at the end of this; the Declaration remains open.&nbsp; And, you know, for some people, it takes time (inaudible) think about it or, frankly, even just see who else has joined.&nbsp; And we remain confident that like-minded countries around the world will &#8212; will sign up.<br><br>[Senior administration official], I don&#8217;t know if you want to address anything else that was in the question.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, I just wanted to echo, [senior administration official], the points you made on membership.&nbsp; You know, it&#8217;s been growing by the day, which is terrific, and I think you&#8217;re going to continue to see it grow going forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, in terms of the splinternet issue &#8212; look, I think the reality is that what we&#8217;re seeing as we look out over the world is a, you know, trend by some countries, and particularly some of the authoritarian countries, to try to create a splinternet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, I mean, you look at what Russia is doing, some of the steps that China has been taking &#8212; and I think we actually see this as, in many ways, a response to these kind of splinternet tendencies by a number of the authoritarian countries around the world.&nbsp; Because what we&#8217;re really doing is taking a big-tent approach, laying out a broad &#8212; you know, and as I say, you know, more than 55 countries &#8212; broadly-shared vision of the future of the Internet.&nbsp; And we think that kind of galvanizing the world behind a shared vision is a very important part of pushing back on these splinternet tendencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then, on a more technical level, I think you&#8217;ll see &#8212; see in the text of the Declaration, you know, one of the principles we are committing to &#8212; all the countries are committing to &#8212; is kind of a reaffirmation of, you know, the multistakeholder approach to governance of the Internet &#8212; the idea that, you know, going back to its creation decades ago, it has been governed by a multi-stakeholder approach.&nbsp; And, you know, we view this as an opportunity to kind of reaffirm a commitment to that at a time when not every country is on board.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; You know, let me double-down on that.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not &#8212; we and our allies are not here to splinter the Internet but, frankly, to save it from splintering.&nbsp; You know, there has been a determined effort, as you said, to try and set up the two multiple Internets, each &#8212; each different.&nbsp; And we are &#8212; and our allies &#8212; reaffirming the vision of one Internet for the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Internet was originally a network of networks designed to interconnect everyone, and we think there&#8217;s extraordinary value in that.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re here to try to restore that vision.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next question, please.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, everyone, thank you so much for your time.&nbsp; I want to dig in a little bit on &#8212; you said, you know, in the coming weeks, months, years, they&#8217;re going to be implementing these principles.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m wondering if you can &#8212; like, more specifically, what does that mean?</p>



<p>And part of the reason I ask is that I think we can look at how China has approached these questions.&nbsp; It has often been by really kind of pushing products to countries in terms of telecom equipment, undersea cables, like, that provide them sort of &#8212; sort of material support, if they bring their countries online and their infrastructure up to date.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, principles are one thing, but how do you counter &#8212; how do you plan to counter sort of an on-the-ground offensive, that is often about sort of more material, in line with this document you&#8217;re going to put out tomorrow?&nbsp; Thanks so much.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So I think this is a great question, David, and thanks for it.&nbsp; And I should &#8212; maybe we should have made clear off the &#8212; you know, right off &#8212; right off the top: Obviously, what we&#8217;re doing with the DFI tomorrow is one important part, but only one important part of a kind of comprehensive set of tools and policies we, as the United States, have to promote our vision of the Internet and of global digital connectivity.</p>



<p>You know &#8212; and, for example, you know, our State Department colleague who&#8217;s on &#8212; on with us, you know, works for a new bureau the State Department just set up a couple of weeks ago in order to &#8212; in order to help make the U.S. more effective, both at a diplomatic level but also, as you say, at pushing out, like, tangible, concrete things.</p>



<p>And I think we could give you a whole, you know, separate interview on all the things we are doing to promote Open RAN 5G technologies around the world to help, you know, get the DFC to try to finance trusted telecommunications networks in developing countries around the world, you know, in competition with Huawei and other Chinese providers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Obviously, we&#8217;ve been doing a ton &#8212; both through DHS, CISA, also through various other mechanisms, modalities &#8212; to share cybersecurity, you know, operational information; how to have Shields Up posture, to provide that kind of practical assistance, as well.</p>



<p>And then, of course, we&#8217;ve been, through our State and AID colleagues, doing things to sort of tangibly promote the Internet freedom agenda, right?&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been, you know, providing, sort of, material support &#8212; you know, encryption technologies and things like that to NGOs around the world and in repressive societies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then you&#8217;ve seen us, kind of at a policy level &#8212; I think you will see us through the IPEF and the digital provisions of the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework and through the work we&#8217;re doing at TTC, kind of at a regulatory level, drive that agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we see here is a way to kind of, as we&#8217;re taking, you know, tangible steps in the assistance space, in the help the NGOs space, in the kind of global regulatory space &#8212; you know, this is a way of really re-energizing, at a principles-driven level, what the vision is that will then help build global support and drive all of these &#8212; drive further all of these kinds of individual, practical workstreams across the different areas of the vision that we&#8217;re pulling together and laying out tomorrow.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; I think we can do the next question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks for taking my question.&nbsp; I was wondering if you could talk a little bit about, I guess, what&#8217;s changed since December when you all were working on the Alliance for the Future of the Internet and, sort of, what lessons you all have learned and who you’ve talked to since then.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So I’ll be happy to discuss that.&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;ve been using the time since December to &#8212; essentially in recruitment and working with other countries &#8212; to sort of improve things.&nbsp; And I think that has really paid off.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I think that there&#8217;s now, as I said, more than 55 countries.&nbsp; You know, it takes time to sort of socialize an idea.&nbsp; Sometimes two steps is better than one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I think if you look carefully at the &#8212; I shouldn&#8217;t &#8212; I don&#8217;t think I want to encourage you to compare it with leaked versions &#8212; but I think that, you know, we talked to a lot of partners.&nbsp; We recognize the importance of civil society and stakeholders in this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, some of the feedback that we got &#8212; as you&#8217;ve probably noticed, most obviously, the name has changed from “alliance” to “declaration.”&nbsp; So that&#8217;s one area which changed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we&#8217;ve envisioned things.&nbsp; You know, I think the underlying thinking is similar, but we envisioned this declaration as a useful tool for multiple other fora.&nbsp; And I made it just very clear, I think, that this works in harmony with and is a complement to existing fora.</p>



<p>So, you know, it&#8217;s a reaffirming and an updating of the visions that anchored and powered some of the original Internet freedom work in the &#8212; from &#8212; over the last 20 years or so.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, yeah, I think that the delay has actually helped us quite a bit.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; I think we can do our next question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, folks.&nbsp; I wonder if you might just briefly address what, if any, outreach you may have done on this initiative to Russia and China and what you may have heard back from them, if anything.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not going to be in a position to get into specific diplomatic conversations with specific countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would say is we&#8217;ve obviously &#8212; in addition to the countries that have joined and that might be joining, you know, if not tomorrow, in the coming weeks &#8212; we have &#8212; I guess I wouldn’t say &#8212; I don’t think this will come as a surprise to any countries, even countries that we always thought were unlikely to join this, but I&#8217;m not going to comment on specific diplomatic discussions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; I think we have time for one more, so let’s do our last question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, yeah, Ina with Axios.&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Two things.&nbsp; One, some have called for something akin to a Geneva Convention governing what types of cyber warfare are and aren’t permissible.&nbsp; I&#8217;m guessing this is largely adjacent to that push, although there&#8217;s a little bit of discussion, I think, about protecting Internet infrastructure.&nbsp; But I want to make sure I have that correct.</p>



<p>And then also, I&#8217;m curious: What role, if any, do the big tech companies play in this?&nbsp; Were they &#8212; were you outreaching to them?&nbsp; Do you see them as not &#8212; this is really about nation states, not companies?&nbsp; So if you could clarify those two.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I’ll take a stab.&nbsp; So, on the first: Yeah, this is not a &#8212; this is not about cyber warfare.&nbsp; I mean, I guess you&#8217;re right to say at the edge &#8212; you know, at the edge, there may be some overlap.&nbsp; We have principles related to cyber ransoms, electoral interference.&nbsp; Some people consider electoral interference to be the edge.&nbsp; So I think it&#8217;s compatible with some of the developing principles in cyber warfare, but it&#8217;s not a cyber warfare treaty or anything &#8212; or agreement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But you know what this does have in common is this increasing sense that there needs to be almost constitutional principles for countries that “it shalt and shall not” &#8212; things that should be off limits.&nbsp; And, you know, some people call for that in cyber warfare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here we&#8217;re calling for it &#8212; or we&#8217;re agreeing on it, politically, more directly and in all kinds of areas, whether it&#8217;s unlawful surveillance of your citizens, whether it&#8217;s blocking legitimate news sources, whether it&#8217;s shutting down the Internet, and whether &#8212; or whether it&#8217;s, what I would say, interfering with elections of other countries.</p>



<p>You know, I think there is a need.&nbsp; And this is the first &#8212; I&#8217;ll emphasize that this is the first document to bring all these concepts together and put them in one place in this fashion, be agreed to by so many countries, and then to sort of stand on it &#8212; to stand on its own.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the question &#8212; the related question is whether big tech is involved.&nbsp; I mean, they’re obviously stakeholders in this, and we&#8217;ve consulted, like any other stakeholder or any other member of civil society.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the primary impetus here was to get at this question of state behavior and to meet what we have seen is a very negative trajectory, what we&#8217;ve seen as an effort to fundamentally change the Internet &#8212; the nature of the Internet &#8212; from something that is an instrument of commerce and culture to something that is an instrument of state power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, we believe that winning this particular struggle is, frankly, key to &#8212; the key part of the overall struggle between democracies and authoritarian governments.&nbsp; So that&#8217;s the kind of &#8212; that&#8217;s the focus of this effort.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; And, [senior administration official], you didn&#8217;t have anything to add, right?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; I think [senior administration official] was &#8212; nothing to add to [senior administration official]’s comments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Okay, great.&nbsp; So, everyone, thanks for joining us today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; The contents of this call are embargoed until tomorrow, Thursday, April 28th, 7:00 a.m. Eastern.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m about to send around the factsheet as well.&nbsp; Again, if you did not get the materials, please email NSC Press or email me.&nbsp; Thanks again, everyone, for joining.&nbsp;</p>



<p>4:28 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: United&#160;States and 60 Global Partners Launch Declaration for the Future of the&#160;Internet</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-united-states-and-60-global-partners-launch-declaration-for-the-future-of-the-internet/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51899</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Internet has been revolutionary. It provides unprecedented opportunities for people&#160;around&#160;the world to connect and to express themselves, and continues to transform the global economy,&#160;enabling&#160;economic opportunities&#160;for&#160;billions of people. Yet it has also created&#160;serious policy challenges. Globally, we&#160;are witnessing a&#160;trend of rising digital authoritarianism&#160;where&#160;some states act to repress freedom of expression, censor independent news sites, interfere&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The Internet has been revolutionary. It provides unprecedented opportunities for people&nbsp;around&nbsp;the world to connect and to express themselves, and continues to transform the global economy,&nbsp;enabling&nbsp;economic opportunities&nbsp;for&nbsp;billions of people. Yet it has also created&nbsp;serious policy challenges. Globally, we&nbsp;are witnessing a&nbsp;trend of rising digital authoritarianism&nbsp;where&nbsp;some states act to repress freedom of expression, censor independent news sites, interfere with elections, promote disinformation, and deny their citizens other human rights.&nbsp;At the same time, millions of&nbsp;people still face barriers to access&nbsp;and cybersecurity risks and threats undermine the trust and reliability of networks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Democratic governments and other partners are rising to the challenge.&nbsp;Today, the United States with 60&nbsp;partners from around the globe launched the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/Declaration-for-the-Future-for-the-Internet_Launch-Event-Signing-Version_FINAL.pdf">Declaration for the Future of the Internet</a>. Those endorsing the Declaration include&nbsp;Albania, Andorra, Argentina, Australia, Austria, Belgium, Bulgaria, Cabo Verde, Canada, Colombia, Costa Rica, Croatia, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Denmark, Dominican Republic, Estonia,&nbsp;the European Commission,&nbsp;Finland, France, Georgia, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Iceland, Ireland, Israel, Italy, Jamaica, Japan, Kenya, Kosovo, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Maldives, Malta, Marshall Islands, Micronesia,&nbsp;Moldova, Montenegro, Netherlands, New Zealand, Niger, North Macedonia,&nbsp;Palau,&nbsp;Peru, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Senegal, Serbia, Slovakia, Slovenia, Spain, Sweden,&nbsp;Taiwan, Trinidad and Tobago, the United Kingdom, Ukraine,&nbsp;and&nbsp;Uruguay.</p>



<p>This Declaration&nbsp;represents&nbsp;a&nbsp;political commitment among Declaration partners to&nbsp;advance apositive&nbsp;vision for the Internet and digital technologies.&nbsp;It&nbsp;reclaims the promise of the Internet in the face of the global opportunities and challenges presented by the 21<sup>st</sup>&nbsp;century.&nbsp;It also&nbsp;reaffirms and recommits its partners to a single global Internet – one that is truly open and fosters competition, privacy, and respect for human rights.&nbsp;The Declaration’s principles includecommitments to:&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Protect human rights and fundamental freedoms of all people;&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Promote a global Internet that advances the free flow of information;&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Advance inclusive and affordable connectivity so that all people can benefit from the digital economy;&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Promote trust in the global digital ecosystem, including through protection of privacy; and&nbsp;</p>



<p>•&nbsp;Protect and strengthen the&nbsp;multistakeholder&nbsp;approach to governance that keeps the Internet running for the benefit of all.</p>



<p>In signing this Declaration, the United States and partners will work together to promote this vision and its principles globally, while respecting each other’s regulatory autonomy within our own jurisdictions and in accordance with our respective domestic laws and international legal obligations.</p>



<p>Over the last year, the United States has worked with partners from all over the world – including civil society, industry, academia, and other stakeholders&nbsp;to reaffirm the vision of an open, free, global, interoperable, reliable, and secure Internet&nbsp;and reverse negative trends in this regard. Under this vision, people everywhere will benefit from an Internet that is&nbsp;unifiedunfragmented; facilitates global communications and commerce; and supports freedom, innovation,&nbsp;education&nbsp;and trust. &nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: The Small Business Boom Under the Biden-&#8288;Harris&#160;Administration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/28/fact-sheet-the-small-business-boom-under-the-biden-harris-administration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51910</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Through the American Rescue Plan and the equitable implementation of emergency relief programs, President Biden and Vice President Harris fostered the strongest recovery for Main Street on record. In 2021, Americans applied to start 5.4 million new businesses—more than 20 percent higher than any previous year on record. The boom in new business creation has been&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Through the American Rescue Plan and the equitable implementation of emergency relief programs, President Biden and Vice President Harris fostered the strongest recovery for Main Street on record. In 2021, Americans applied to start 5.4 million new businesses—more than 20 percent higher than any previous year on record.</p>



<p>The boom in new business creation has been particularly strong for entrepreneurs of color. In 2021, Hispanic Americans started new businesses at the fastest rate in more than a decade and 23 percent faster than pre-pandemic levels.</p>



<p>And, in the three-quarters of 2021, small businesses with fewer than 50 employees created 1.9 million jobs, the fastest start to small business job growth in any year on record.</p>



<p>This new White House report details the historic recovery for America’s small businesses and demonstrates how the Biden-Harris agenda laid the foundation for this small business boom. By focusing on combatting the pandemic, providing Americans with greater financial security, and delivering more than $450 billion in emergency relief to small businesses, the Biden-Harris Administration has helped create the conditions for unprecedented business and job creation.</p>



<p>The Biden-Harris strategy to rescue and revitalize Main Street contrasts sharply with the latest tax plan from Republicans in Congress. The Congressional Republican proposal put forward by Senator Rick Scott to impose a minimum tax on middle-class families would increase taxes on small businesses across the country. In addition to detailing the historic economic progress the Biden-Harris Administration has made to date, the Appendix includes a new state-by-state analysis of the Congressional Republican tax plan. The analysis finds that this tax plan would raise taxes on nearly half of small business owners (6.1 million people), including 82 percent of small business owners making less than $50,000 per year. Under the Congressional Republicans’ plan, the typical small business owner would see their taxes increased by almost $1,200.</p>



<p>President Biden rejects Congressional Republicans’ plan to increase taxes on half of small business owners. His four-pillar economic strategy for small businesses will lower costs and level the playing field for families and small businesses. The plan is focused on:</p>



<p>1.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Expanding access to capital,</p>



<p>2.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Making historic investments in helping small businesses navigate available resources,</p>



<p>3.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Leveraging federal spending to support small businesses, and</p>



<p>4.     Leveling the playing field for small business owners by reforming the tax code.</p>



<p>Read the full report here: <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/President-Biden-Small-Biz-Boom-full-report-2022.04.28.pdf">https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/04/President-Biden-Small-Biz-Boom-full-report-2022.04.28.pdf</a></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the 2022 National and State Teachers of the Year&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/27/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-2022-national-and-state-teachers-of-the-year-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51904</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[East Room 4:35 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thank you, Kurt.&#160; Thank you, thank you, thank you. Secretary &#8212; Secretary Cardona, thank you.&#160; And &#8212; and I want to thank Jill.&#160; Jill is the nation’s first First Lady to work full time as a professor &#8212; as a teacher.&#160; She taught high school and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">East Room</p>



<p>4:35 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, Kurt.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>Secretary &#8212; Secretary Cardona, thank you.&nbsp; And &#8212; and I want to thank Jill.&nbsp; Jill is the nation’s first First Lady to work full time as a professor &#8212; as a teacher.&nbsp; She taught high school and she teaches at a community college for a long time now.<br><br>We made a deal that &#8212; she was so &#8212; teaching is not what Jill does, it’s who she is, like most of you &#8212; who you are, what you believe.&nbsp; And so when we got elected &#8212; the presidency and as Vice President, as well &#8212; I suggested and she agreed fully that she should continue to teach.&nbsp; And people said, “What?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Well, she teaches 14 credits a semester at community college full time, and she does her job.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And, you know, I’m very, very supportive of teachers for a number of reasons &#8212; some of them are personal.&nbsp; But if I didn’t support teachers, I’d be sleeping alone in one of these bedrooms up here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>You know, before I begin the formal comments, one of the things that Jill reminded me of when she spoke &#8212; and I’ll bet all of you can give examples as well &#8212; I &#8212; I had &#8212; I got lucky.&nbsp; I won the &#8212; I won the lottery, in terms of parents; my mother and father were wonderful people.&nbsp; I had one of those moms that everybody wished had been their mom, for real.&nbsp; Everybody hung at my house.</p>



<p>But I also was a bit of a runt, in terms of my size.&nbsp; And I used to ta- &#8212; ta- &#8212; ta- &#8212; talk like this.&nbsp; I stuttered badly.&nbsp; And when you stutter, everyone thinks you have to be either stupid or totally incompetent.</p>



<p>And if you notice, it&#8217;s the only infirmity a child can talk about &#8212; an adult can talk about having had that people &#8212; you didn&#8217;t because you’re teachers &#8212; think they can laugh, think it&#8217;s funny.</p>



<p>If you saw the movie “The King&#8217;s Speech,” you understand.&nbsp; You understand.</p>



<p>We went to see it, Jill and I, and right as the King was standing at the racetrack making the speech, she reached over &#8212; I guess I tightened up somehow; it brought back all &#8212; all the memories.&nbsp;<br><br>And I look back on it now and I wonder, besides I really got lucky with my parents &#8212; my mother would say, “Look at me, Joey.&nbsp; Look at me.&nbsp; You&#8217;re smarter than anybody.&nbsp; You&#8217;re this.&nbsp; You&#8217;re that.&nbsp; So, stop.&nbsp; You can do this.”<br><br>My point is this: that I had teachers &#8212; I can name the ones through grade school, high school, and even college.&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t really beat my stuttering, and still occasionally I do, until I was &#8212; took speech and debate class in college just to force myself to be able to stand up.<br><br>When they sent me the copy &#8212; the guy who wrote “The King&#8217;s Speech” found the original speech and made a copy of it and sent it to me &#8212; no, I mean, from the movie.</p>



<p>And he does his speeches exactly like I did, which a nun taught me.&nbsp; If you took a look at my speech, you&#8217;ll see that there&#8217;s all these slash marks in the speech.&nbsp; Because, you know, an awful lot of people who are &#8212; I can&#8217;t sing worth a damn, but the people &#8212; entertainers and singers can sing like a nightingale but can&#8217;t talk, can&#8217;t speak.</p>



<p>And I look back on my life, and I think, beyond my family &#8212; my sister, my brother, my mom, my dad &#8212; the people who made a difference in my life, in a fundamental way, were teachers.</p>



<p>I remember &#8212; I was talking on the way over.&nbsp; This &#8212; my staff is going, “Why aren’t you giving the speech we wrote?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>But I remember &#8212; I truly remember &#8212; and we were talking about it on the way over &#8212; what got me involved in politics.&nbsp; I got into politics &#8212; involved in politics because I think the greatest sin that anyone can commit is the abuse of power, whatever that power is &#8212; the power of a teacher, the power of a doctor, the power of a leader.&nbsp; When someone who is relying on you or you cannot &#8212; just the abuse of power.<br><br>And I got involved because my state was the only state in the Union, when Dr. King was murdered, that was occupied by the National Guard for 10 months with drawn bayonets in every corner because we had a very conservative governor who ordered the National Guard and &#8212; because my state has the eighth-largest Black population in America as a percent of population.</p>



<p>And I had a job with the &#8212; one of the oldest law firms in the state.&nbsp; And I quit and became a public defender; that’s what got me involved.</p>



<p>But again, where teachers come in: I was &#8212; I had no intention of running for public office.&nbsp; Everybody thought Biden knew he wanted to be President at the time he was in sixth grade or something.&nbsp; I love these biographies.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But here&#8217;s the deal: What I did do &#8212; I wanted to get engaged.&nbsp; And so, we had a very, very conservative Democratic Party in my state.&nbsp; And I thought it was &#8212; I thought it was wrong on civil rights.&nbsp; The more &#8212; the more progressive party was the Republican Party because we were a southern Democratic Party.&nbsp; We&#8217;re a slave state to our great shame, early on.&nbsp; We fought on the side of the North, like Maryland did, and four &#8212; two other states, but we were a border state.</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what got me going.&nbsp; And so, I was asked by a group of senior lawyers whether or not I’d join a thing called a “New Democratic Coalition.”&nbsp; And the reason I bother to tell you that was how to reform the party, how to bring it into the &#8212; into the &#8212; you know, the 21st century &#8212; the 20th century, at the time.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and one day after being asked to see if I can help recruit someone to run for the United States Senate against a very popular Republ- &#8212; Democ- &#8212; Republican senator, a group of senator &#8212; a former senator, a former congressman, and two former governors came to me and said, “We want you to run.”&nbsp; And I wasn&#8217;t even old enough.&nbsp; I was 29 years old.</p>



<p>And I thought, “This is crazy.”&nbsp; But I remember going home from that convention, and the first stop I made was to speak to a professor in Dr. Ingersoll, who was one of those professors who was my &#8212; my &#8212; my philosophy professor in political science.&nbsp; And I stopped him, and I told him what was going on.&nbsp; And he looked at me, and I&#8217;ll never forget what he said.&nbsp; He said, “You should do it.”&nbsp; I said, “I can&#8217;t do that.”&nbsp; I never even knew anybody who was in the Senate.</p>



<p>And he looked at me; he said, “Remember what Plato said.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll paraphrase it,” he said.&nbsp; “The penalty good people pay for not being involved in politics is being governed by people worse than themselves.”</p>



<p>But my generic point is this: He gave me the confidence,</p>



<p>as a 29-year-old kid with no money, to run.&nbsp; He gave me the confidence.&nbsp; Just like the nun would tell me, “Joey, Joey, you can do this.”&nbsp; It gave me the confidence.</p>



<p>And I think about it.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to think about, 20 years from now, how did you end up standing on the podium in the White House?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, you didn&#8217;t ever expect that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I wonder how I got here.&nbsp; I got here because of my parents and my teachers.&nbsp; My teachers.</p>



<p>And so, folks, you know, that idea is exemplified by the National Teacher of the Year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Kurt, you have and I have something in common though.&nbsp; I&#8217;m &#8212; I was an adjunct professor in law school for years teaching an advanced course in separation of powers.&nbsp; And I taught to get &#8212; to get money when I was at Syracuse Law School.&nbsp; To get through law school, I was a substitute teacher.&nbsp; You should be nicer to them.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)</p>



<p>But that’s not what Kurt and I have in common.&nbsp; What we have in common is we both married women who are smarter than we are.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>This is an assistant dean at Oberlin College, one of the finest colleges in the country.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Kurt teaches history; he taught 25 years.&nbsp; In fact, he teaches in the same town, in the same district he grew up in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, when I left the vice presidency, I had a chance to do a number of things.&nbsp; But I became a professor at the University of Pennsylvania, and &#8212; presidential politics.&nbsp; And I &#8212; it was &#8212; I enjoyed it, but it&#8217;s hard.&nbsp; That&#8217;s another thing people don&#8217;t realize: It&#8217;s hard.&nbsp; How much you prepare.</p>



<p>I had a three-credit course I taught in law school.&nbsp; I would literally, every single &#8212; I didn&#8217;t want to do it during the week because I didn&#8217;t want people to say I’m taking away from my job as a senator, so I did it on Saturdays at Delaware Law School.</p>



<p>I would prepare &#8212; Jill will tell you &#8212; three to four hours every single &#8212; before every class.&nbsp; And it was what &#8212; not only I taught, but &#8212; what I did as Chairman of the Judiciary Committee.&nbsp; I taught about separation of powers.&nbsp; It was what I did my whole life.&nbsp; And it took me all that time.</p>



<p>But the point is: It really mattered.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know &#8212; you know, I love what this guy said in his classroom about &#8212; he said his classroom &#8212; he said, “We listen to each other and respect people&#8217;s opinion.”</p>



<p>Well, part of this is all about fundamentally teaching respect.&nbsp; While we might be in the opposite sides of hot topics, we&#8217;re on the same side in terms of having respect for one another.</p>



<p>Well, Kurt, I understand you wanted to go back home to be a teacher because your teachers inspired you.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll bet every one of you can name one or two teachers who fundamentally impacted your lives.</p>



<p>Well, you know, I think you&#8217;ve paid it forward many times over, old buddy, and &#8212; transforming the lives of your students in Oberlin, Ohio, helping students see themselves in you.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what happens, I think.&nbsp; And helping all your students not only learn history, but see &#8212; see what they &#8212; that they have a role in shaping history &#8212; I mean in a literal sense. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And to the Delaware Teacher of the Year, where &#8212; where were you, Jahsha?&nbsp; Where’s the Delaware Teacher of the Year?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I got to admit, we&#8217;re the second-smallest state, but I&#8217;m a little prejudiced on behalf of the state of Delaware.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know there are a lot of eighth graders at Brandywine who are feeling confident and more comfortable because of your help.&nbsp; Jill taught at the same school when she was in Delaware, at Brandywine school &#8212; high school.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And even though Teacher Appreciac- &#8212; Appreciation Week officially starts next week, I wanted to get us started earlier.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s an honor for me and the First Lady and Secretary Cardona to recognize the Teachers of the Year from 50 different states.&nbsp; And it really is something we look forward.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>I had &#8212; I did a eulogy today for a brilliant woman, the former Secretary of State.&nbsp; And I sat in the front row with two other presidents who were also there to honor her.&nbsp; And I told them what I was doing.&nbsp; And they all talked about how much they enjoyed the years they were here with the Teacher of the Year event.</p>



<p>Over &#8212; over the past two years, though, the entire country has witnessed the extraordinary dedication and resolve of our nation&#8217;s teachers.</p>



<p>Early in the pandemic, teachers and teachers’ aides had to &#8212; had to do &#8212; not just be educators, you had to be tech support, you had to be moral support, you had to be &#8212; you had to be health support.&nbsp; I mean, you had to take care of your own children in addition.</p>



<p>And I watched how hard it was &#8212; how really hard.&nbsp; There was so much heroic work to help kids connect, get connected to schools, and just the socialization that they were missing in so many places for so long.&nbsp; It&#8217;s estimated they&#8217;re five to seven months behind in their education right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The American people saw it.&nbsp; Because guess what?&nbsp; When you&#8217;re taught remotely from home, the moms and dads understood what you were doing.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And that &#8212; no, and they know they realized how damn hard it is.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m serious.</p>



<p>I think it was &#8212; you know, my mother used to say, “Out of everything bad, something good will happen if you look hard enough for it.”&nbsp; I think that was the upside.&nbsp; The American people became, “Whoa.&nbsp; My goodness.”&nbsp; And they understand what you’ve been saying for years.&nbsp; That you are professionals &#8212; all of you.&nbsp; All of you have a responsibility to make sure you have what you need, and we have a responsibility to make sure we have what you need to educate our children safely so they have a chance &#8212; a chance to achieve their dreams &#8212; dreams they don’t even know they have &#8212; they don’t even know they have.</p>



<p>That’s why I made it a priority to get educators vaccinated and re-open our schools quickly.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We made a historic commitment to our schools &#8212; $130 billion in the Rescue Plan &#8212; $130 billion.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>It helped us go from 50 percent of our schools being closed to 99 percent of schools open and safe &#8212; better heating, air conditioning, and ventilation systems, safer buildings.&nbsp; It isn’t a thriving building until it comes alive, though, with teachers and students.</p>



<p>With the help of the American Rescue Plan, local governments were able to &#8212; as the state officials here can tell you &#8212; in education &#8212; were able to add a record 279,000 new educators in 2021 &#8212; two hundred and sev- &#8212; 50,000 &#8212; another 50,000 jobs &#8212; teaching jobs in the first months of 2022.</p>



<p>In January, compared to the period before the pandemic, schools have increased their number of social workers by 65 percent and counselors by 17 percent.&nbsp; You&#8217;re expected to do everything.&nbsp; You&#8217;re expected to not only teach, you&#8217;re expected to be a guidance counselor yourself, but you&#8217;re also expected to deal with the problems that they have at home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You see it.&nbsp; You can see it in their faces when they walk into school and, as Jill said, just by the way they answer the questions &#8212; and questions about how they&#8217;re doing, how they’re feeling.&nbsp; And you need help.&nbsp; You need social workers.&nbsp; You need school psychologists and psychiatrists.&nbsp; You need that kind of help.</p>



<p>And the American Rescue Plan funds are especially important now that we see the impact that this pandemic exacted on our children.&nbsp; As I&#8217;ve said, students have lost months of learning, particularly reading and math.&nbsp; It’s not just academic skills they’ve fallen behind on, teachers are seeing young children struggle to interact in group settings, to manage conflict, to take turns.&nbsp; They’ve got a learning &#8212; a lot of learning to make up.&nbsp; And we’re doing everything we can to help you.&nbsp; I want to know &#8212; I want input from you as well, because we have a lot of teachers we seek their input.</p>



<p>Using funds from the American Rescue Plan, schools are providing and expanding summer learning &#8212; summer learning and tutoring programs to give students the extra time and attention they need to catch up and develop those fundamental math and reading skills.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You all know, if you get far behind in first, second, third, fourth, fifth, sixth, seventh grade, it takes a lot of time to make up.&nbsp; And if you lose your confidence, it even gets harder.</p>



<p>So, I urge more states, counties, and cities and towns to use their American Rescue Plan funding, which is in the billions of dollars, to hire more teachers, more tutors, more critical personnel in our schools.</p>



<p>Now we have an opportunity to make even more game-changing investments for educators, students, and families.</p>



<p>We’re in a competition for leading the 21st century.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; That’s what we&#8217;re &#8212; that&#8217;s where we are right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, parenthetically, if you think about it: What was the reason why we led the world &#8212; beginning around nineteen-five, -six, and -seven, and -eight?&nbsp; Because we became the first nation in the world to have universal education of 1 through 12, for everybody &#8212; no matter what, without cost.</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; If we were sitting down today, deciding we were going to set up an education system, raise your hand if any of you think 12 years is enough in the 21st century?&nbsp; Just 12 years.&nbsp; Things are moving too rapidly.&nbsp; They&#8217;re changing exponentially.</p>



<p>And as Jill said, any country that out-educates us is going to outcompete us.&nbsp; It&#8217;s that basic.&nbsp; So, we have to build a 21st century, because the rest of the world isn’t waiting.&nbsp; We have to build for it.</p>



<p>One of the tough images of the pandemic was children sitting in their cars with their mother or dad or older brother or sister in a McDonald&#8217;s parking lot because that’s the only way they could get on Wi-Fi to do their homework.&nbsp; This is the United States of America for God&#8217;s sake.&nbsp; The United States of America.</p>



<p>If we didn’t know it before, we know now: High-speed Internet is essential.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re spending tens of billions to make sure that we have high-speed Internet available to everyone &#8212; rural America, inner-city America, suburban America &#8212; throughout every single school system in America.&nbsp; That’s part of the whole legislation we passed in terms of infrastructure.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s starting now &#8212; it&#8217;s going to create millions of jobs as well.&nbsp; For real.&nbsp; But again, we got to get in the 21st century.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to move.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I &#8212; the budget I proposed supports schools, supports students, and supports you.</p>



<p>The bridge &#8212; to bridge the gap between under-resourced schools and their wealthier counterparts, we&#8217;re proposing a $19 billion increase in Title I schools &#8212; the most historically neglected and underfunded schools in our nation.&nbsp; We got to get &#8212; we got to let them catch up.&nbsp; That investment would more than double the current funding of Title I schools.</p>



<p>And also &#8212; also proposing the largest increase in special education funding in two decades.&nbsp; We made the promise; we&#8217;ve never filled &#8212; fulfilled it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to fulfill it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to add another billion-dollar commitment with the goal of doubling the number of social workers, school counselors, and school nurses in K through 12.</p>



<p>And, by the way, thanks to the American Rescue Plan, we’re making real progress towards that goal.</p>



<p>And to support you, the educators, my budget includes $610 million to increase teacher diversity, effectiveness, and retention.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; This is key.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because all of you know that it takes time to become a teacher &#8212; the teachers you are today.&nbsp; But nearly 1 in 10 teachers leave the profession every year, with the youngest teachers being the most likely ones to leave first.&nbsp; So, we’ve got to invest in ways to keep them in the profession.</p>



<p>This year, my administration helped over 150 public servants, including teachers, get &#8212; 150,000 &#8212; get school forgive &#8212; forgiveness loans for college loans through changes we made in the Public Service Loan Forgiveness Program.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The last team kind of messed it up.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve cleared it up.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, but I really mean it.&nbsp; Because if you go &#8212; if you &#8212; anyway, well, I won&#8217;t go into it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just go to that website.&nbsp; To learn how these changes can benefit you, and &#8212; I encourage you to go to StudentAid.gov, and you&#8217;re going to find you can have, in many of your cases, your entire student debt wiped out, because you are teaching and that&#8217;s considered a vital profession.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One more thing.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not enough to give teachers praise.&nbsp; We ought to give you a raise.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so &#8212; and I have to really listen to you, which I know Senator Cardona has been doing.&nbsp; And we should stand up for you.&nbsp; We should have your back.&nbsp; Teaching is one of the hardest jobs in this country to be able to do it well, and one of the most important.</p>



<p>Today, there are too many politicians trying to score political points, trying to ban books &#8212; even math books.&nbsp; I mean, did you ever think &#8212; even you younger teachers &#8212; did you ever think, when you&#8217;d be teaching, that you&#8217;d be worried about book burnings and banning books, all because it doesn&#8217;t fit somebody&#8217;s political agenda?</p>



<p>American teachers have dedicated their lives to teaching our children and lifting them up.&nbsp; We got to stop making them the target of the culture wars.&nbsp; That&#8217;s where this is going.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let me close with this, because I know &#8212; if I know anything about teachers, I know that some of you were probably grading papers on the way here.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, Jill traveled with me around the world.&nbsp; I&#8217;d say, &#8220;Jill, leave the binder.&nbsp; Leave the bag.&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, by the way, how many are math teachers?&nbsp; Raise your hand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She envies the hell out of you.&nbsp; She thinks your job is easier.&nbsp; You just have to check if they know the answer.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>She teaches writing.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But she gets off the plane &#8212; am I joking? &#8212; with up to 50, 60 papers she&#8217;s grading on Air Force One.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I mean, I said, &#8220;Jill&#8221; &#8212; she&#8217;s walking down the, you know &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; you think I&#8217;m kidding you?&nbsp; I&#8217;m not kidding with you.&nbsp; I &#8212; this is deadly earnest.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; and many of you are trying to figure out how you&#8217;re going to &#8212; if you have class tomorrow, you may not and you may be here for the &#8212; tomorrow.&nbsp; But on Monday, are you ready for your class?&nbsp; Are you prepared?&nbsp; Do you have your lesson plan together?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because you know &#8212; look, these aren&#8217;t &#8212; we always talk about &#8220;these children.&#8221;&nbsp; They&#8217;re not someone else&#8217;s children.&nbsp; They&#8217;re our children.&nbsp; And they are the kite strings that literally lift our national ambitions aloft in a literal sense.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you got to do one thing to make sure the nation succeeded in the next two generations, what would you do?&nbsp; You&#8217;d want &#8212; I would say, literally, have the best-educated public in the world.&nbsp; Have our students gain confidence enough to know what they can do, to reach in.&nbsp; We have an obligation.&nbsp; We have an obligation to help them teach and reach their potential.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You&#8217;ve heard me say it many times about our children, but it&#8217;s true: They&#8217;re all our children.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the reason you&#8217;re the Teachers of the Year is because you recognize that.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not somebody else&#8217;s children; they&#8217;re like yours when they&#8217;re in the classroom.&nbsp; You represent a profession that helps them gain the confidence &#8212; a confidence they believe they can do anything.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Again, think of your own lives.&nbsp; Think of where you gained the confidence beyond your family, God willing you&#8217;re able to.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you know what else we&#8217;re finding out?&nbsp; We&#8217;re having a big fight about it now, but I&#8217;m going to get it done eventually, or someone will.&nbsp; And that is that we&#8217;ve learned now &#8212; you all know those who &#8212; of you in the teaching profession know that if you come from a broken home or a home that has a single parent &#8212; and there may be a drug problem or something, from a very poor home &#8212; you&#8217;re going to end up hearing a million words &#8212; fewer words spoken by the time you get to first grade than from a kid coming from an average middle-class home.&nbsp; Not different words, just words spoken, because they&#8217;re not engaged in it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And also, we learned that if, in fact, you have kids go to school at three years old and four years old and five years old, you&#8217;ll increase exponentially &#8212; by 57 percent &#8212; the likelihood that they will make it no matter what their background, all the way through 12 years of school and probably beyond.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp; It matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for so &#8212; for that and so much more that you do, you believe in these kids.&nbsp; And I know some of them are really difficult.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I get it.&nbsp; But you believe in them.&nbsp; And you know: When they know you believe in them, they believe in you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So thank you for what you do.&nbsp; You are &#8212; if I get to have one profession that&#8217;s the best in the world &#8212; not a joke &#8212; it&#8217;s you who I want to be the best profession in the world, because you affect what this country looks like, what it&#8217;ll act like, what it&#8217;ll be like, its success or failure, more than any other group of Americans, period.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So thank you for what you do.&nbsp; Keep it going.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I promise you, Jill has your back &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and mine.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Thank you very much.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Mr. President, how did the release just happen, given the invasion and what’s going on?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Say again?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you surprised Trevor Reed was released by Russia, given the invasion?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I did it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I raised it.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How though?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; It was three months ago.</p>



<p>5:02 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Roundtable with Lesbian Leaders to Celebrate Lesbian Day of&#160;Visibility</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/27/readout-of-white-house-roundtable-with-lesbian-leaders-to-celebrate-lesbian-day-of-visibility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, in celebration of Lesbian Day of Visibility, the White House hosted a roundtable conversation with trailblazing lesbian and LGBTQI+ senior leaders from the White House and the broader Biden-Harris Administration. The roundtable included lesbian and queer advocates ,community leaders, leaders across the federal government, several of whom are the first out lesbians to hold&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, in celebration of Lesbian Day of Visibility, the White House hosted a roundtable conversation with trailblazing lesbian and LGBTQI+ senior leaders from the White House and the broader Biden-Harris Administration. The roundtable included lesbian and queer advocates ,community leaders, leaders across the federal government, several of whom are the first out lesbians to hold their position, including: Ambassador Chantale Wong, Director of the Asian Development Bank, who is the first out lesbian to be confirmed by the U.S. Senate to an ambassador post; Admiral Rachel Levine, Assistant Secretary for Health, who is a lesbian and the first openly transgender woman to achieve the rank the four-star admiral in any of the country’s uniformed services; White House Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre; and Deputy White House Communications Director Pili Tobar. The roundtable was convened by White House Gender Policy Council Director Jennifer Klein.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Participants discussed the unique barriers and challenges faced by lesbians and LGBTQI+ women, including barriers to health equity and reproductive justice; the impacts of anti-LGBTQI+ state legislation on the mental health and wellbeing of lesbian and LGBTQI+ girls; the effects of isolation and discrimination on lesbian older adults; and the economic justice and housing issues impacting lesbian women and couples. Participants highlighted that lesbians who are also women and girls of color, transgender women, women with disabilities, and older women face additional intersecting challenges to achieving economic security and full inclusion. Administration officials highlighted the actions the Biden Administration has taken to advance equity and visibility for lesbians and other LGBTQI+ women, and reaffirmed the President’s commitment to full equality for all lesbians and LGBTQI+ women and girls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>External participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Charlotte Clymer, Transgender Activist, Military Veteran, and Board Member, LPAC Action Network</li><li>Desireé Luckey, Director of Policy, Unite for Reproductive and Gender Equity (URGE)</li><li>Dr. Imani Woody, Founder and CEO, Mary’s House for Older Adults</li><li>Joanne N. Smith, President and CEO, Girls for Gender Equity (GGE)</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
