<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:17:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on New Economic Restrictive Measures on&#160;Russia</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/02/28/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-new-economic-restrictive-measures-on-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=48002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 7:04 A.M. EST &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And thanks, everyone, for joining us early this morning.&#160; This is a background press call to discuss an update on the Russia economic restrictive measures that we announced on Saturday with Allies and partners. &#160; This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” And&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>7:04 A.M. EST</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And thanks, everyone, for joining us early this morning.&nbsp; This is a background press call to discuss an update on the Russia economic restrictive measures that we announced on Saturday with Allies and partners. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This call is on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.” And the content of this call are embargoed until 7:30 a.m. Eastern.</p>



<p>For your awareness and not for reporting, the speakers on this call are [senior administration officials].&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to take &#8212; we&#8217;re going to have some remarks at the top and then just take a few questions at the end.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So with that, I&#8217;ll turn it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Good morning, everybody.&nbsp; I&#8217;ll kick off and then hand it over to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve been saying it as clearly as we can: This is an unjustified, unprovoked, and premeditated war of choice by Putin and that, alongside Allies and partners across the world, we would make this choice a strategic failure for Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We said if Putin continued to escalate, we would escalate.&nbsp; We said all options are on the table, including the most severe sanctions ever contemplated against Russia.&nbsp; We said that as we implement these costs, we would impose them in an historic and unprecedented show of coordination with countries across the world that wish to defend the core principles that underpin peace and security.</p>



<p>And so, that&#8217;s the context in which our actions to sanction the Russian Central Bank should be seen.&nbsp; We&#8217;re doing exactly what we said we’d do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I&#8217;ve mentioned before, no country is sanctions-proof when we act together.&nbsp; Our sanctioning of the Russian Central Bank, which we&#8217;re taking with Germany, France, the UK, Italy, Japan, Canada, the European Union, and others &#8212; with the culmination of months for planning and preparation across our respective governments; across technical, diplomatic, and political channels, including at the highest levels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We were ready, and that&#8217;s what allowed us to act within days, not weeks or months, of Putin’s escalation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I also want to emphasize the importance of relationships in taking this collective action.&nbsp; It takes trust and solidarity to sanction the central bank of a one and a half trillion-dollar economy, multiples larger than Iran’s or Venezuela’s.</p>



<p>We built that trust and solidarity over time in dozens of phone calls, meetings, and video conferences since November.</p>



<p>With respect to the impact this action will deliver:</p>



<p>As I mentioned, no &#8212; no country is sanctions-proof.&nbsp; Putin’s war chest of $630 billion in reserves only matters if he can use it to defend his currency, specifically by selling those reserves in exchange for buying the ruble.&nbsp; And after today&#8217;s actions, that will no longer be possible, and Fortress Russia will be exposed as a myth.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Already, you&#8217;ve seen the Russian Central Bank more than doubled its policy rate this morning to 20 percent.&nbsp; That’s the highest in almost two decades.&nbsp; The ruble is in freefall, and soon you’ll see inflation spike and economic activity contract.</p>



<p>This is a vicious feedback loop that&#8217;s triggered by Putin’s own choices and accelerated by his own aggression.&nbsp; <a>It&#8217;s a very raw deal Putin is giving to the Russian people as the world disconnects Russia from the global financial system and all its benefits, but it&#8217;s exactly what we said would be the consequences of his actions.</a></p>



<p>At the same time that we&#8217;re following through on our commitment to deliver overwhelming force, I want to emphasize that we and our Allies will continue to limit the impact back home.&nbsp; And in particular, we&#8217;ll continue to scope our measures to allow for steady energy supplies to global markets &#8212; [senior administration official] will say more on this.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And lastly, I want to remind everyone that, today, we’ll also fully block the Russian Direct Investment Fund and its CEO, Kirill Dmitriev.&nbsp; This fund and its leadership are symbols of deep-seated Russian corruption and influence peddling globally.&nbsp; Some of you may know it spun off from V.E.B. &#8212; Putin’s slush fund bank that we fully blocked last week &#8212; and it&#8217;s known to be intimately connected to kleptocracy at the highest levels of the Russian government.</p>



<p>This action will also limit RDIF’s ability to leverage corrupt ties to universities and organizations in the U.S. and the West more broadly.</p>



<p>Let me stop there and turn it to [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, all of you, for joining. I want to briefly walk through the impact of these actions and why we&#8217;re taking them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The steps we&#8217;re taking today are part of the strategy that the President asked Secretary Yellen to design in order to hold Russia accountable for an invasion in the Ukraine.</p>



<p>Our strategy, to put it simply, is to make sure that the Russian economy goes backwards as long as President Putin decides to go forward with his invasion of Ukraine.&nbsp; We&#8217;re accomplishing this objective by taking a variety of steps targeting Russia&#8217;s financial institutions, elites, and now the Russian Central Bank.</p>



<p>These are all sources of the wealth the Kremlin draws on to fund destabilizing activity.&nbsp; Today&#8217;s actions represent the most significant actions that the U.S. Treasury has taken against an economy of this size and assets of this size.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I would &#8212; I want to point out that what also makes this action significant is not just the amount of assets or the size of the country we&#8217;re targeting, but the speed at which our partners and Allies have worked with us to enact this response.</p>



<p>[Senior administration official] is right that we&#8217;ve been coordinating with these Allies since November on actions related to Russia.&nbsp; But since the beginning of President Biden&#8217;s term, we&#8217;ve been working closely with these Allies on various issues related to the international financial system, which built the trust that was necessary for us to take these actions today.</p>



<p><a>Now, a few things to note about the economic impact on Russia of today&#8217;s announcements: It&#8217;s clear that when Russia prepared for an invasion of Ukraine, they were counting on using their Central Bank assets to mitigate any economic hardship that came from sanctions.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Russia has hundreds of billions of dollars of assets in jurisdictions all over the world.&nbsp; And ever since the leaders made their announcement on Saturday, the Russian Central Bank has been attempting to bring those assets back to Russia or to safe havens so they can be used to support their economy and their currency.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today&#8217;s announcement to prohibit transactions with the Central Bank of Russia and the National Wealth Fund will significantly hinder their ability to do that and inhibit their access to hundreds of billions of dollars in assets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From our actions alone, they will not be able to access assets that are either in the United States or in U.S. dollars. And as you&#8217;ve seen, the EU has taken actions that prohibit Central Bank&#8217;s transactions in their jurisdiction as well, and we expect the rest of the &#8212; our G7 partners to take similar actions.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s important to note that with today&#8217;s actions, we&#8217;re also constricting Russia’s access of those they might turn to for a bailout since we&#8217;re also targeting its Ministry of Finance and its rainy-day fund, the National Wealth Fund.&nbsp; And our directive also makes clear that Russia can&#8217;t turn to other banks or companies and use them as agents to evade these prohibitions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a result of today&#8217;s coordinated announcement, Russia will experience even further economic consequences.&nbsp; They will be forced to deplete their limited domestic rainy-day fund far more quickly; experience a weakening of their currency, making funding their war of choice much more expensive; create a real squeeze on Russia&#8217;s ability to fund their priorities like invasion in Ukraine; constrict the Central Bank&#8217;s routine functions and make financing more difficult since it is locked out of using foreign reserves; and exacerbate liquidity issues.</p>



<p>As with our other actions, we&#8217;ve been calibrated and deliberate to ensure our sanctions cost maximum consequences for Russia, while mitigating harm to America and our partners.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President made very clear to us it was critical that we target our sanctions in a way that would impose costs on Russia if they continued the invasion, while mitigating those costs on the American people, on our Allies and partners.&nbsp; And consistent with that, Treasury will issue a general license to authorize certain energy-related transactions by exempting energy-related transactions for preventing unnecessary harm for consumers and preventing spikes in prices that would only pad the pockets of President Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I mentioned at the top, these are serious consequences for Russia&#8217;s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, and we wouldn&#8217;t hesitate to level more if necessary.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As I said in the beginning, our objective is to make sure that the Russian economy goes backwards if President Putin decides to continue to go forward with an invasion in Ukraine. And we have the tools to continue to do that.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll end my remarks and hand it back to our host.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Could we please queue up the directions to ask a question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, good morning.&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; Can you confirm that basically all the assets of the Central Bank, National Wealth Fund, the Finance Ministry are essentially frozen as a result of this action?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then can you say a word about the kind of coordination with the Allies?&nbsp; Did they move forward on this more quickly than you might have been expecting, or was this all already scripted ahead of time?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; [Senior administration official], do you want to take the first and I can &#8212; I can do the second?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I&#8217;m happy to do that.&nbsp; So what we&#8217;re doing today in the United States is that we are prohibiting transactions with the Russian Central Bank in dollars.&nbsp; So what that means is that if a U.S. financial institution has Russian Central Bank assets, they can&#8217;t do anything with them; they are stuck in that institution.&nbsp; If an institution outside of the United States has dollars for the Russian Central Bank, they can&#8217;t do anything with them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So those funds are immobilized.&nbsp; And the reality is that like any central bank around the world, the Russian Central Bank holds a great number of their assets in dollars.&nbsp; But in addition to dollars, they&#8217;re clearly diversified and they hold assets in euros, in yens, in pound sterling. &nbsp;And because of the work that we&#8217;ve done in coordinating, it means that those assets are also immobilized and unavailable for their use.</p>



<p>But let me turn it over to [senior administration official] to talk a little bit about the work we&#8217;ve done over the course of the last several months to coordinate with our Allies and partners so we&#8217;d be in a position to take an action like the one that we&#8217;re announcing today.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, and I&#8217;ll &#8212; I&#8217;ll touch on the first question as well, because we always thought of Russia&#8217;s Central Bank reserves &#8212; its $630 billion of foreign reserves &#8212; as an insurance policy for Russia.&nbsp; And that insurance policy was meant for exactly a circumstance like this.&nbsp; In other words, if their currency was plummeting, they could use those reserves to support the ruble and to defend it.&nbsp; And so, what this &#8212; what this action does is it removes, it negates, it nullifies that insurance policy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we&#8217;ve been talking about taking this action for months.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been conceiving of the circumstances in which it would get deployed, the mechanisms by which we could apply it, the coordination that will be required to give it force.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, as we saw the events unfold last week, we sent clear signals to the world about our willingness to take the most severe actions in our toolkit, and we deployed them.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks very much for doing this.&nbsp; I just wanted to ask if you could comment on anything related to, you know, action with Belarus &#8212; any future sanctions action &#8212; and reports that they&#8217;re preparing to get involved in this conflict.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Alan &#8212; [senior administration official], I&#8217;ll just start with this one &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re watching those events very carefully.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve said if &#8212; to the extent Belarus continues to aid and abet Russia&#8217;s aggression in Ukraine, they will also face consequences.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve already rolled out some of those measures.&nbsp; Those costs will continue to ratchet much higher.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, thanks so much.&nbsp; I&#8217;m just wondering if you could talk a little bit about the timing of this.&nbsp; You&#8217;re taking this action today.&nbsp; How quickly will it actually kick in?&nbsp; Is there any danger of Russia taking actions before these measures actually go into effect that would, you know, make these actions not as forceful and damaging to Russia?&nbsp; And how quickly do you expect that these measures will actually have an impact on the Russian economy and potentially start to change Putin&#8217;s calculus here?&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Let me just make this clear that these actions will be effective immediately.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking to you now because we wanted to put these actions in place before our markets opened, because what we learned over the course of the weekend from our Allies and partners was that the Russian Central Bank was attempting to move assets and there would be a great deal of asset flight starting on Monday morning from institutions around the world.</p>



<p><a>So, we took these ac- &#8212; we&#8217;re taking these actions in a way that they will be effective immediately.&nbsp; And I think the thing &#8212; to [senior administration official’s] earlier point, the Russian government, after the actions we took in 2014 &#8212; and I was here in 2014 when we took those actions &#8212; decided that they were going to try and build a war chest to try and defend against the actions that we may take if they were to take further actions in Ukraine or elsewhere in the world.</a></p>



<p>We knew that this existed and we knew that, ultimately, one of the things that we would need to do to ensure that our sanctions would be effective is at some point take &#8212; go after that war chest.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what we&#8217;ve done today.</p>



<p>And you &#8212; you asked a question as to how soon will this be effective, and we&#8217;re seeing the effect of that today: The Russian stock market isn’t open.&nbsp; The ruble has depreciated a great deal.&nbsp; Russia is taking unprecedented actions to try and support their economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what I would say is that we have always thought about how we would escalate as President Putin moved forward with the invasion in Ukraine.&nbsp; And we continue to have additional steps that we could take that will continue to have an impact on the Russian economy, because as they move forward with the invasion, we&#8217;re committed to working with our Allies and partners to make sure that their economy continues to move backwards so that they have less money to fund their projections of power going forward.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll just &#8212; I&#8217;ll just add a little bit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, as [senior administration official] said perfectly right, the &#8212; these actions are immediately effective, and the impact is also immediate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I think the ruble is already more than 30 percent weaker today<a>.&nbsp; The Central Bank already more than doubled its policy rate from 9 and a half percent </a>to 20 percent.&nbsp; There&#8217;s talk about Russia imposing capital controls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That &#8212; these choices that Russia has been forced into are a reflection of the fact that inflation is now very likely to spike, purchasing power is likely to plummet, investment is likely to plummet.&nbsp; These are &#8212; this is a negative and vicious feedback loop that Putin has triggered.</p>



<p>And as to whether it affects his calculus: I mean, all we can do is make sure this is a strategic failure.&nbsp; And the evidence of this failure is becoming more clear by each moment.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, there.&nbsp; Good morning.&nbsp; Can you say how much of the $630 billion is affected by the U.S. moves?&nbsp; In particular &#8212; in other words, how much of that 630 is either, I guess, linked to U.S. companies or held in U.S. dollars?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And can I ask &#8212; on a separate but related issue on the measures with regards to SWIFT: Can you give us an update on the latest on that and, in particular, whether you&#8217;re considering adding restrictions to new banks beyond those amounts previously?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Let me start with &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; What I can tell you is that &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Oh, do you want &#8212; I’ll take Central Bank, [senior administration official], and handover SWIFT to you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, great.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Well, what we know is that the Russian Central Bank, like all central banks around the world, has their assets diversified, with hundreds of billions of dollars located outside of Russia in central banks, in financial institutions around the world.</p>



<p>After the invasion of Crimea, Russia decided to move a great deal of its assets out of the United States &#8212; but to keep them in dollars but to move them into other jurisdictions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What we&#8217;ve done today is not only preventing them from using those dollars in the United States, but preventing them from being able to use those dollars in other places, like Europe or Japan, to defend their currency and prop up their institutions.</p>



<p>And our goal was to make sure that not only would they not have access to dollars, but also not have access to other currencies that would be critical to their ability to support their economy.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why doing this in a multilateral way with our Allies and partners is so important and is so crippling for the Russian Central Bank, which is now struggling to figure out ways to continue to support its economy in the face of these sanctions.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the SWIFT question: We’re &#8212; we remain in close consultations with our EU partners to finalize the list of banks that will be cut off from the SWIFT system.&nbsp; There are several banks that Europe and the U.S. have fully blocked; those will be the first ones considered.</p>



<p>Just as a regulatory matter, the list of banks will get finalized by the EU because SWIFT is under Belgian authority. And so, once the list is finalized, the Europeans will issue a directive that will go to Belgium for a vote of the SWIFT Board of Directors and then the de-SWIFTing will be complete.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, guys.&nbsp; Quick question is: Is the Bank for International Settlements part of this?&nbsp; And also, is the Swiss government part of this?</p>



<p>And as a broader question: Are you worried about any kind of ripple effects for the financial system?&nbsp; The &#8212; you know, are dollar funding markets likely to come under pressure from this?&nbsp; What are some of the possible kind of ripple effects and blowbacks?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; So, Neil, let me start with the second part of your question.&nbsp; I think one of the things that we&#8217;ve been doing in addition to coordinating and collaborating with our Allies and partners is telling &#8212; is telling our regulators the actions that we&#8217;ve been contemplating.</p>



<p>Since the end of last year, the Secretary and I have been spending time with regulators, both talking to them about the actions that the President is contemplating in order to better understand some of the impacts that you just mentioned and working with our team to make sure that we scenario plan for these actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With regard to the Bank of International Settlements and other institutions, our prohibition applies to &#8212; any U.S. dollar that exists in an institution around the world is now &#8212; cannot be transacted with the Russian Central Bank.&nbsp; That is applicable to international institutions, as well as foreign countries, as well as financial institutions &#8212; foreign financial institutions that have dollars.&nbsp; So, effective immediately as &#8212; when this directive goes out, transactions with the Russian Central Bank in dollars by anyone is prohibited.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thanks so much for doing the call.&nbsp; I guess this first one is for [senior administration official].&nbsp; On the carveouts, you know, including all the banks that are being sanctioned, can you share what percentage of the carveouts, particularly for energy &#8212; what percentage of those make up the overall transactions?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, I guess, for [senior administration official]: I wanted to ask &#8212; you mentioned again &#8212; or maybe it was [senior administration official]; I apologize &#8212; that, again, it will miti- &#8212; and energy impacts will be mitigated.&nbsp; Considering, you know, the moves in Germany and just support in Europe overall, is there potential or is it being considered to take a more stronger action against Russia&#8217;s energy sector?&nbsp;</p>



<p>But first, the percentage of the carveouts if you could.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;&nbsp; So the energy market is an important one, and it&#8217;s a place where Russia plays a major role.&nbsp; But the truth is that, for these financial institutions, that the &#8212; they are doing billions of transactions each day, many of which are not energy related.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And to be frank, the fact that it will take them time to figure out how to segregate those actions will lead to additional disruption of the Russian economy.</p>



<p>Look, while the carveout will make sure that people are able to get &#8212; to make energy payments, it&#8217;s not going to stop the &#8212; stop the impact that we&#8217;re seeing on the Russian economy.</p>



<p>Today, you&#8217;ve seen European headlines talking about the fact that there&#8217;s been a run on Sberbank, Russia’s European affiliate, which is under pressure because of deposit withdrawals.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, part of what we&#8217;ve done is, when we looked at the Russian financial system, we decided to take a variety of actions against the top 10 institutions.&nbsp; We did some &#8212; we did some debt and equity blocking.&nbsp; We did some full blocking.&nbsp; And we did some dollar-clearing blocking in order to make sure that the Russian Central Bank wasn’t in a position where they could find a one solution to each one of these challenges.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And for the full-blocked institutions, they&#8217;re not able &#8212; their assets have been frozen.&nbsp; For those where dollar clearing has been blocked, we&#8217;re starting to see runs on those institutions by depositors.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, in addition to the fact that we may have the energy carveout, which is providing the ability for energy to flow &#8212; energy to flow and to help mitigate some of the risks both to Europe but also to the global energy markets, the variety of actions we&#8217;ve taken are still ensuring that these &#8212; each one of these institutions are under a variety of different types of pressure, which, because of the actions we&#8217;re taking against the Central Bank today, the Central Bank is going to be unable to mitigate in a meaningful way.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; On the &#8212; on the second question, Franco: We have a &#8212; we have a collective interest in ensuring that the current supply of energy to the world remains steady, A, because we want to support the global economic recovery, but, B, because we don&#8217;t want prices to spike for the benefit of President Putin as a major energy exporter.</p>



<p>Over the long term, though &#8212; and this is important &#8212; we also have a collective interest to degrade Russia&#8217;s capacity to be a leading energy supplier over the long term.&nbsp; And over the long term, that requires critical technology inputs that allow &#8212; that would allow Russia to remain a leader in energy production.&nbsp; And there you&#8217;ve already seen some actions taken by the EU and a scenario we&#8217;re exploring actively.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, everybody, for joining today.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to “senior administration officials.”&nbsp; And the embargo lifts in about a minute.&nbsp; Have a good rest of your day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p>  7:30 A.M. EST</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Background on President&#160;Biden&#8217;s Remarks on the Economy During His First State of The Union&#160;Address</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-background-on-president-bidens-remarks-on-the-economy-during-his-first-state-of-the-union-address/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47998</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden ran for office with a new economic vision: to grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out, not the top down. On Tuesday, the President will make a strong case that the Biden-Harris economic strategy is producing historic results, and lay out his plan to tackle the economic challenges ahead.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden ran for office with a new economic vision: to grow the economy from the bottom up and the middle out, not the top down. On Tuesday, the President will make a strong case that the Biden-Harris economic strategy is producing historic results, and lay out his plan to tackle the economic challenges ahead. He will underscore that during his first year in office, due in large part to the American Rescue Plan, entrepreneurship and business investment rebounded, the economy achieved its fastest job growth in American history, the fastest economic growth in nearly 40 years, and a faster recovery than every other advanced economy. And, he will emphasize that this progress is occurring amidst an historic shift from the old, outdated trickle-down approach to one that centers on workers, families, and small businesses.</p>



<p>During his first State of the Union Address, the President will also make clear that there is more work to do to rebuild the economy towards resilience, security, and sustainability. Too many families continue to feel the squeeze of higher costs. The President will make clear that price increases that become entrenched are pernicious, and eat away at the economic progress the country is making. The President will lay out his plan to lower costs for American families while continuing an historically strong economic recovery by:<br><br></p>



<ul><li>Making more things in America, strengthening our supply chains, and moving goods faster and cheaper;<br><br></li><li>Reducing the cost of everyday expenses working families face and reducing the deficit;<br><br></li><li>Promoting fair competition to lower prices, help small businesses thrive, and protect consumers; and<br><br></li><li>Eliminating barriers to good-paying jobs for workers all across America.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Making more things in America, strengthening our supply chains, and moving goods faster and cheaper:</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden will make clear that he believes one of the best ways to lower costs over the long run is to increase the productive capacity of our economy—put simply, to make more things in America with more American workers contributing and earning a good living. He will describe the emerging manufacturing comeback, with American companies betting on America again because of the Administration’s commitment to domestic industrial revitalization and technological development. He will note that in just the last year, the economy added 375,000 manufacturing jobs and companies announced nearly $200 billion in investments for semiconductor, electric vehicle, battery, and critical mineral production and manufacturing in the United States. He will recount how Intel recently announced a new $20 billion factory outside of Columbus, Ohio that will create 7,000 construction jobs and another 3,000 permanent jobs – another sign of the strength of the American economy.</p>



<p>President Biden will also announce specific goals for implementation of his landmark Bipartisan Infrastructure law (BIL), a once-in-a-generation investment in our nation’s economic competitiveness that will strengthen supply chains and move goods to market faster and more efficiently, encouraging more companies to choose America. Over the next year:<br><br></p>



<ul><li>States, territories, Tribes and local governments will start to improve 65,000 miles of roads and 1,500 bridges with federal funding, representing a 44% and 50% increase respectively from average annual improvement levels over the past six years.<br><br></li><li>The Federal Aviation Administration will be able to invest in over 600 airport infrastructure projects, including preserving 400 pavement projects on taxiways and runways.<br><br></li><li>Communities will invest in an estimated 15,000 new buses, ferries and subway cars, improving commutes for working Americans, families, and students across the country and reducing greenhouse emissions.<br><br></li><li>The U.S. Army Corps of Engineers will advance over 500 projects across 52 states and territories to strengthen supply chains, improve waterways, and reduce flooding.<br><br></li><li>The Environmental Protection Agency will work with state and local governments to fund more than 400 new water projects from replacing lead service lines to improving drinking water systems.<br><br></li><li>States, Tribes, and other partners will use BIL funds to reclaim over 15,000 acres of abandoned mine lands, as well as launch new reclamation efforts that will ultimately address tens of thousands of additional acres across the country.<br><br></li><li>The Interior Department’s new Orphan Well Program will start work plugging, capping, and remediating over 8,000 abandoned oil &amp; gas well sites in communities across the country.<br><br></li><li>The Interior Department will increase its work to reduce the risk of wildfires to communities by more than 30 percent – removing over 300,000 acres of burnable fuels in the places where communities and wildlands meet – as well as the start of work to reduce wildfire risk on an additional 250,000 acres across the country.<br><br></li><li>The Department of Energy will take steps to launch a first-of-its kind $140 million demonstration facility to extract and separate rare earth elements and other critical minerals from coal ash, mine tailings, acid drainage, and other legacy fossil fuel waste to sustainably produce materials key to next-generation clean energy technologies.<br><br></li><li>The Department of Energy will make available nearly $3 billion to bolster domestic manufacturing of advanced batteries for electric vehicles and energy storage.</li></ul>



<p>To build on these investments and spur more private-sector investment in the United States, the President will also call on Congress to send him bipartisan competitiveness legislation like the COMPETES and USICA bills that have passed the House and the Senate to invest in innovation, manufacturing, and economic development capacity across all of America so America can outcompete China and the rest of the world in the industries of the future.</p>



<p><strong><u>Reducing the cost of everyday expenses working families face:</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden will call on Congress to send him legislation that lowers costs of everyday expenses working families face and lowers the deficit by rewarding work, not wealth. He will lay out specific, practical measures that would reduce costs for families right now, including prescription drug costs and health care premiums, child care and pre-k costs, and energy costs. He will point to the other ideas he has proposed on areas ranging from housing to care for seniors and people with disabilities to higher education affordability to direct tax relief for families. These efforts build on the support provided in the American Rescue Plan that has helped reduce the cost of health care, helped more than 5000 universities and community colleges make higher education more affordable, made work pay better for low-income workers through an expanded Earned Income Tax Credit, and provided historic middle class tax relief for tens of millions of working families through an expanded Child Tax Credit.</p>



<p>The President will make clear that we can lower costs while lowering the deficit by rewarding work, not wealth. He will outline proposals to make sure corporations and the wealthiest Americans pay their fair share, while making clear that no one making under $400,000 a year should see their taxes increased.</p>



<p>The President will call on Congress to send him a bill that lowers costs and lowers the deficit without delay. American families need relief from higher costs, and they need it now.</p>



<p><em><br></em><strong><u>Promoting fair competition to lower prices, help small businesses thrive, and protect consumers:</u></strong><em><u></u></em></p>



<p>President Biden will explain that we can also lower costs by promoting fair competition in the U.S. economy. The Administration has taken decisive actions in the first year to stop the trend of corporate consolidation, increase competition, and deliver concrete benefits to America’s consumers, workers, farmers, and small businesses. He will also announce new actions the Biden-Harris Administration is taking this year to tackle some of the most pressing competition and consumer protection problems across our economy. Specifically, he will announce new steps to:<br><br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Lower consumer prices and level the playing field for American businesses in ocean shipping.</strong> The President will explain that most traded goods—everything from the housewares you buy online to the agricultural products that American farmers market overseas—are transported by oceangoing vessels. However, the ocean shipping industry is now dominated by just a small number of giant, foreign-owned companies. Three global alliances—groups of ocean carriers that work together—now control 80% of global container ship capacity and 95% on the critical East-West trade lines. And, since the beginning of the pandemic, these carriers have been increasing shipping costs through higher rates and fees. The President will note that the foreign carriers are now seeing record profits, while prices for American consumers and businesses have risen. To combat this problem, the President will announce steps to lower consumer prices and level the playing field for American businesses in ocean shipping, including launching a new Federal Maritime Commission and Department of Justice initiative to promote competition in the ocean freight transportation system. He will also note that the Federal Maritime Commission is ramping up its oversight of the global shipping industry to address complaints about the unfair fees the carriers charge to American businesses. <em>Read the full Biden-Harris Plan to Lower Consumer Prices and Level the Playing Field in Ocean Shipping here.</em><strong><br><br></strong></li><li><strong>Protect seniors and other nursing home residents by cracking down on unsafe nursing homes. </strong>The President will explain that while the federal government spends tens of billions of taxpayer dollars on nursing homes annually, these federal funds too often flow to nursing homes with bad track records and dangerous conditions. He will explain that <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/over-200000-residents-and-staff-in-long-term-care-facilities-have-died-from-covid-19/">200,000 residents</a> and staff in nursing homes have died from COVID-19, representing nearly 23% of all COVID-19 deaths in the United States. He will also stress that despite well-documented, widespread health and safety violations, there has been little or no accountability. To protect seniors and crack down on unsafe nursing homes, President Biden will call on Congress to provide nearly $500 million to CMS Survey and Certification, a 24% increase, to support health and safety inspections at nursing homes. He will also announce that the Biden-Harris Administration will, among other new initiatives, establish a new minimum staffing ratio to protect residents, expand penalties for poor performing nursing homes and beef up scrutiny, improve transparency and Americans’ ability to comparison shop for the best home, strengthen value-based payment to ensure taxpayers pay for quality care, and continue to provide COVID-19 testing and vaccinations at nursing homes across the country.<em> Read the full Biden-Harris Plan to Protect Seniors by Cracking Down on Unsafe Nursing Homes here.</em><br><br></li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Eliminating barriers to good-paying jobs for workers all across America:</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden will reflect on one of the strongest labor market recoveries in American history. Specifically, the President will note that during his first year in office, the economy added more than 6.6 million jobs; the unemployment rate fell at its fastest pace on record; the number of number of workers filing for unemployment insurance declined by more than 70 percent; and millions of Americans have entered and reentered the labor force, with the largest increase in the labor force participation rate in more than 25 years. He will highlight the important role that the American Rescue Plan played in positioning employers to hire and workers to rejoin the labor force and find higher quality jobs. Earlier this year, he directed the Secretary of Labor to work with states to reinstate work search requirements for unemployment insurance recipients.<br><br></p>



<p>To further our economic recovery and increase the productive capacity of our economy, the President will announce his Administration’s plan to ensure everyone who wants to work should have the opportunity to find a high-quality job. Specifically, he will express his support for:<br><br></p>



<ul><li><strong>Enacting the Protecting the Right to Organize Act.</strong> President Biden will express his firm belief that every worker in every state must have a free and fair choice to organize or join a union, and the right to bargain collectively with their employer, without fear of intimidation, coercion, threats, and anti-union propaganda. He will reiterate that the middle class built America and unions built the middle class. And, he will emphasize that empowering workers is central to the Biden-Harris strategy to grow our economy from the bottom up and the middle out. The President will call on Congress to pass the Richard L. Trumka Protecting the Right to Organize (PRO) Act and the Public Service Freedom to Negotiate Act, ensuring that more private-sector workers and many more public-sector workers nationwide have a genuine right to organize and bargain collectively.<br><br></li><li><strong>Expanding skills-based hiring and increasing access to registered apprenticeships and training. </strong>President Biden will reiterate his commitment to creating pathways to the middle class for all Americans. He will stress that millions of Americans without a college degree are needlessly disadvantaged in the pursuit of good jobs, even when they have the skills and knowledge employers need. To support skills-based hiring, President Biden will announce that his Administration will explore using federal and procurement dollars to by hire based on skills rather than educational qualifications alone, , including through boosting hiring of people from Registered Apprenticeships and labor-management partnership training programs. Additionally, the Administration remains committed to strengthening the pipeline for more underserved communities to access these opportunities. As an example, the Administration has supported and increased access to quality trucking jobs by expanding Registered Apprenticeship programs for drivers; and developing more seamless paths for veterans and underrepresented communities, such as women, to access good driving jobs. He will state that the Administration is supporting and challenging employers to move towards skill-based hiring, including through a new budget proposal to invest in skills-based hiring research tools and technical assistance. This effort builds on the American Rescue Plan’s critical workforce investments in the past year – with more than half of states already committing Fiscal Recovery Funds to training and apprenticeships and efforts to hire and retain critical workers – and catalyzing investments in place-based regional workforce strategies through the Commerce Department’s Good Jobs Challenge.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding programs in high-demand fields at Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs), Tribal Colleges and Universities (TCUs), and Minority-Serving Institutions (MSIs).</strong> President Biden will explain that research has found that HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs are vital to helping underrepresented students achieve economic mobility, including in STEM fields. However, he will also stress that these institutions have significantly fewer resources than other top colleges and universities, undermining their ability to grow and support more students. To address this persistent problem, and building on the progress made by the American Rescue Plan providing the largest investment through the Department of Education ever in these institutions, the President will call on Congress to expand existing institutional aid grants to HBCUs, TCUs, and MSIs, which can be used by these institutions to strengthen their academic, administrative, and fiscal capabilities, including by creating or expanding educational programs in high-demand fields (e.g., STEM, computer sciences, nursing, and allied health).<br><br></li><li><strong>Providing up to more than $2,000 in additional assistance to low-income students by increasing the Pell Grant award. </strong>President Biden will note that broad access to education beyond high school is increasingly important for economic growth and competitiveness in the 21st century, but also remind us that higher education has become unaffordable for too many families. Over 6 million students depend on Pell Grants to finance their education, yet the amount of money in these grants has not kept up with the rising cost of college and DREAMers still do not have access. During his State of the Union Address, President Biden will call on Congress to increase the maximum Pell Grant award by more than $2,000.<br><br></li><li><strong>Supporting paycheck fairness. </strong>President Biden will note that women in the U.S. who work full-time, year-round are paid only 83 cents for every dollar paid to their male counterparts, on average. He will also express his belief that ensuring equal pay is essential to advancing America’s values of fairness and equity as well as our economic strength here at home and our competitiveness abroad. President Biden will use his State of the Union Address as an opportunity to call on Congress to pass the Paycheck Fairness Act, which will take important steps towards the goal of ending pay discrimination.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Raising the minimum wage to $15 per hour.</strong> President Biden will recount that throughout the pandemic, millions of American workers have put their lives on the line to keep their communities and country functioning, including the 40 percent of frontline workers who are people of color. The President will express his belief that hard-working Americans deserve sufficient wages to put food on the table and keep a roof over their heads, without having to work multiple jobs. The President already issued executive actions to ensure 370,000 federal employees and employees of federal contractors are paid a minimum of $15 per hour – because investing in workers also makes employers, including the government, work better and faster. The President will call on Congress to raise the minimum wage to $15 per hour, and end the tipped minimum wage and sub-minimum wage for people with disabilities so that workers across the country can have a little breathing room and provide opportunity for their families.<br><br></li><li><strong>Creating a national comprehensive paid family and medical leave program. </strong>President Biden will stress that nearly four of five private sector workers – and 90 percent of the lowest wage workers – have no access to paid family leave, which is a critical input for economic growth and competitiveness in the 21st century. He will call on Congress to pass comprehensive paid family and medical leave legislation so millions of American workers can take time to bond with a new child, care for a seriously ill loved one or heal from their own serious illness.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Protecting Seniors and People with Disabilities by Improving Safety and Quality of Care in the Nation’s Nursing&#160;Homes</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-protecting-seniors-and-people-with-disabilities-by-improving-safety-and-quality-of-care-in-the-nations-nursing-homes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47995</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[All people deserve to be treated with dignity and respect and to have access to quality medical care. And in no case should a health care facility be causing a patient harm. The President believes we must improve the quality of our nursing homes so that seniors, people with disabilities, and others living in nursing&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>All people deserve to be treated with dignity and respect and to have access to quality medical care. And in no case should a health care facility be causing a patient harm. The President believes we must improve the quality of our nursing homes so that seniors, people with disabilities, and others living in nursing homes get the reliable, high-quality care they deserve. That’s why he is announcing a set of reforms—developed by and implemented through the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS)—that will improve the safety and quality of nursing home care, hold nursing homes accountable for the care they provide, and make the quality of care and facility ownership more transparent so that potential residents and their loved ones can make informed decisions about care.</p>



<p>To do this, the reforms the President is announcing will ensure that:</p>



<ul><li>every nursing home provides a sufficient number of staff who are adequately trained to provide high-quality care;</li><li>poorly performing nursing homes are held accountable for improper and unsafe care and immediately improve their services or are cut off from taxpayer dollars; and</li><li>the public has better information about nursing home conditions so that they can find the best available options.</li></ul>



<p>The pandemic has highlighted the tragic impact of substandard conditions at nursing homes, which are home to many of our most at-risk community members. More than 1.4 million people live in over 15,500 Medicare- and Medicaid-certified nursing homes across the nation. In the past two years, more than <a href="https://www.kff.org/policy-watch/over-200000-residents-and-staff-in-long-term-care-facilities-have-died-from-covid-19/">200,000 residents</a> and staff in nursing homes have died from COVID-19—nearly a quarter of all COVID-19 deaths in the United States.  </p>



<p>Despite the tens of billions of federal taxpayer dollars flowing to nursing homes each year, too many continue to provide poor, sub-standard care that leads to avoidable resident harm. In fact, failure to comply with Federal guidelines at nursing homes is widespread. The Government Accountability Office found that, from 2013 to 2017, <a href="https://www.gao.gov/assets/gao-20-576r.pdf">82% of all inspected nursing homes</a> had an infection prevention and control deficiency, including a lack of regular handwashing, that was identified through Medicare and Medicaid surveys. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Without decisive action now, these unacceptable conditions may get worse. Private equity firms have been buying up struggling nursing homes, and research shows that private equity-owned nursing homes tend to have significantly worse outcomes for residents. Private equity firms’ investment in nursing homes has <a href="https://www.ineteconomics.org/uploads/papers/WP_118-Appelbaum-and-Batt-2-rb-Clean.pdf">ballooned</a> from $5 billion in 2000 to more than $100 billion in 2018, with about <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2772306">5</a>% of all nursing homes now owned by private equity firms. Too often, the private equity model has put profits before people—a particularly dangerous model when it comes to the health and safety of vulnerable seniors and people with disabilities. <strong>Recent research has found that resident outcomes are significantly worse at private equity-owned nursing homes</strong>:</p>



<ul><li>A <a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama-health-forum/fullarticle/2786442">recent study</a> found that residents in nursing homes acquired by private equity were 11.1% more likely to have a preventable emergency department visit and 8.7% more likely to experience a preventable hospitalization, when compared to residents of for-profit nursing homes not associated with private equity.</li><li><a href="https://www.nber.org/system/files/working_papers/w28474/w28474.pdf">One working paper</a> examining 18,000 nursing home facilities over a seventeen-year period found that private equity ownership increased excess mortality for residents by 10%, increased prescription of antipsychotic drugs for residents by 50%, decreased hours of frontline nursing staffing by 3%, and increased taxpayer spending per resident by 11%. That suggests an additional 20,150 lives lost as a result of private equity ownership.</li><li>Another <a href="https://ourfinancialsecurity.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/08/AFREF-NJ-Private-Equity-Nursing-Homes-Covid.pdf">study</a> found that private equity-backed nursing homes’ COVID-19 infection rate and death rate were 30% and 40% above statewide averages, respectively.</li></ul>



<p>Research also suggests that, <strong>despite depriving residents of quality care, private equity-owned nursing homes actually led to an </strong><a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama-health-forum/fullarticle/2786442"><strong>uptick in Medicare costs</strong></a><strong>, too.</strong>&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Today, the Biden-Harris Administration is announcing new steps by Department of Health &amp; Human Services (HHS) through its Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), to improve the quality and safety of nursing homes, to protect vulnerable residents and the health care heroes who care for them, and to crack down on bad actors. </strong>The Administration is committed to these urgent actions as first steps toward fulfilling a broader commitment to ensure taxpayer dollars go toward the safe, adequate, and respectful care seniors and people with disabilities deserve—not to the pockets of predatory owners and operators who seek to maximize their profits at the expense of vulnerable residents’ health and safety.</p>



<p><strong>Ensuring Taxpayer Dollars Support Nursing Homes That Provide Safe, Adequate, and Dignified Care</strong></p>



<p>CMS is launching four new initiatives to ensure that residents get the quality care they need—and that taxpayers pay for. These initiatives will help ensure adequate staffing, dignity and safety in their accommodations, and quality care.</p>



<ul><li><em>Establish a Minimum Nursing Home Staffing Requirement</em>. The adequacy of a nursing home’s staffing is the measure most closely linked to the quality of care residents receive. For example, a <a href="https://agsjournals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/jgs.16689">recent study</a> of one state’s nursing facilities found that increasing registered nurse staffing by just 20 minutes per resident day was associated with 22% fewer confirmed cases of COVID-19 and 26% fewer COVID-19 deaths. CMS intends to propose minimum standards for staffing adequacy that nursing homes must meet. CMS will conduct a new research study to determine the level and type of staffing needed to ensure safe and quality care and will issue proposed rules within one year. Establishing a minimum staffing level ensures that all nursing home residents are provided safe, quality care, and that workers have the support they need to provide high-quality care. Nursing homes will be held accountable if they fail to meet this standard.</li><li><em>Reduce Resident Room Crowding</em>. Most nursing home residents prefer to have private rooms to protect their privacy and dignity, but shared rooms with one or more other residents remain the default option. These multi-occupancy rooms increase residents’ risk of contracting infectious diseases, including COVID-19. CMS will explore ways to accelerate phasing out rooms with three or more residents and to promote single-occupancy rooms.</li><li><em>Strengthen the Skilled Nursing Facility (“SNF”) Value-Based Purchasing (“VBP”) Program. </em>The SNF-VBPprogram awards incentive funding to facilities based on quality performance. CMS has begun to measure and publish staff turnover and weekend staffing levels, metrics which closely align with the quality of care provided in a nursing home. CMS intends to propose new payment changes based on staffing adequacy, the resident experience, as well as how well facilities retain staff.</li><li><em>Reinforce Safeguards against Unnecessary Medications and Treatments</em>. Thanks to CMS’ National Partnership to Improve Dementia Care in Nursing Homes, the nation has seen a dramatic decrease in the use of antipsychotic drugs in nursing homes in recent years. However, inappropriate diagnoses and prescribing still occur at too many nursing homes. CMS will launch a new effort to identify problematic diagnoses and refocus efforts to continue to bring down the inappropriate use of antipsychotic medications.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Enhancing Accountability and Oversight</strong></p>



<p>Holding nursing homes accountable for their performance requires a robust compliance program—a program that has adequate funding to perform inspections and that imposes meaningful penalties when deficiencies are found. Federal taxpayer dollars should not flow to nursing homes that are unsafe.</p>



<ul><li><em>Adequately Fund Inspection Activities</em>. For over seven years, funding to conduct health and safety inspections has remained flat while the number of complaints about nursing homes has surged. To protect residents and crack down on unsafe nursing homes, President Biden will call on Congress to provide almost $500 million to CMS, a nearly 25% increase, to support health and safety inspections at nursing homes.</li><li><em>Beef up Scrutiny on More of the Poorest Performers</em>. CMS’s Special Focus Facility (SFF) program identifies the poorest-performing nursing homes in the country for increased scrutiny in an effort to immediately improve the care they deliver. The SFF program currently requires more frequent compliance surveys for program participants, which must pass two consecutive inspections to “graduate” from the program. The SFF program will be overhauled to more quickly improve care for the affected residents, including changes that will make its requirements tougher and more impactful. CMS will also make changes that allow the program to scrutinize more facilities, by moving facilities through the program more quickly. Facilities that fail to improve will face increasingly larger enforcement actions, including termination from participation in Medicare and Medicaid, when appropriate.</li><li><em>Expand Financial Penalties and Other Enforcement Sanctions</em>. CMS will expand the instances in which it takes enforcement actions against poor-performing facilities based on desk reviews of data submissions, which will be performed in addition to on-site inspections. In July 2021, CMS rescinded a Trump Administration change that lowered penalty amounts on bad actor nursing homes for harmful deficiencies by imposing only a one-time fine, instead of more aggressive per-day fines that charge for each day a facility is out of compliance. CMS will now explore making such per-day penalties the default penalty for non-compliance. CMS will also use data, predictive analytics, and other information processing tools to improve enforcement. President Biden is also calling on Congress to raise the dollar limit on per-instance financial penalties levied on poor-performing facilities, from $21,000 to $1,000,000.</li><li><em>Increase Accountability for Chain Owners of Substandard Facilities</em>. President Biden is calling on Congress to give CMS new authority to require minimum corporate competency to participate in Medicare and Medicaid programs, enabling CMS to prohibit an individual or entity from obtaining a Medicare or Medicaid provider agreement for a nursing home (new or existing) based on the Medicare compliance history of their other owned or operated facilities (previous or existing). He is further calling on Congress to expand CMS enforcement authority at the ownership level, enabling CMS to impose enforcement actions on the owners and operators of facilities even after they close a facility, as well as on owners or operators that provide persistent substandard and noncompliant care in some facilities, while still owning others.</li><li><em>Provide Technical Assistance to Nursing Homes to Help them Improve</em>. CMS currently contracts with Quality Improvement Organizations that help providers across the health care spectrum make meaningful quality of care improvements. CMS will ensure that improving nursing home care is a core mission for these organizations and will explore pathways to expand on-demand trainings and information sharing around best practices, while expanding individualized, evidence-based assistance related to issues exacerbated by the pandemic.</li></ul>



<p><br><strong>Increasing Transparency</strong></p>



<p>For too long, corporate owners and operators have not been held to account for poor nursing home performance. CMS will improve the public transparency of facility ownership and safeguard nursing home residents.<strong></strong></p>



<ul><li>. CMS will create a new database that will track and identify owners and operators across states to highlight previous problems with promoting resident health and safety. This registry will use information collected through provider enrollment and health and safety inspections to provide more information about prospective owners and operators to states. Giving the public a resource to better understand owners’ and operators’ previous violations will empower states to better protect the health and safety of residents.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Improve Transparency of Facility Ownership and Finances</em>. CMS will implement Affordable Care Act requirements regarding transparency in corporate ownership of nursing homes, including by collecting and publicly reporting more robust corporate ownership and operating data. It will also make this information easier to find on the Nursing Home Care Compare website.</li><li><em>Enhance Nursing Home Care Compare</em>: CMS will implement a range of initiatives to improve Nursing Home Care Compare, the rating website designed to help families pick a facility for their loved ones. Under the Biden-Harris Administration’s leadership, CMS has already published new measures on Care Compare, which allow users to consider nursing home staff turnover, weekend staffing levels, and other important factors in their decision-making process. &nbsp;When the new minimum staffing requirement comes online, Care Compare will also prominently display whether a facility is meeting these minimum staffing requirements. CMS will further improve Care Compare by improving the readability and usability of the information displayed—giving you and your family insight into how to interpret key metrics. Finally, CMS will ensure that ratings more closely reflect data that is verifiable, rather than self-reported, and will hold nursing homes accountable for providing inaccurate information. The President is calling on Congress to give CMS additional authority to validate data and take enforcement action against facilities that submit incorrect information.</li><li><em>Examine the Role of Private Equity. </em>As described above, private equity investors are playing a growing role in the nursing home sector, and published research increasingly indicates that facility ownership by investment groups leads to worse outcomes while costing taxpayers more—particularly as these owners have sought to cut expenses at the cost of patient health and safety, including during the COVID-19 pandemic. HHS and other federal agencies will examine the role of private equity, real estate investment trusts (REITs), and other investment ownership in the nursing home sector and inform the public when corporate entities are not serving their residents’ best interests. <strong></strong></li></ul>



<p><strong>Creating Pathways to Good-paying Jobs with the Free and Fair Choice to Join a Union</strong></p>



<ul><li><em>Ensure Nurse Aide Training is Affordable. </em>Lowering financial barriers to nurse aide training and certification will strengthen and diversify the nursing home workforce. CMSwill establish new requirements to ensure nurse aide trainees are notified about their potential entitlement to training reimbursement upon employment. CMS will further work with states to ensure reimbursement is being distributed and that free training opportunities are widely publicized.</li><li><em>Support State Efforts to Improve Staffing and Workforce Sustainability. </em>Strengthening the nursing home workforce requires adequate compensation as well as a realistic career ladder. CMS will develop a template to assist and encourage States requesting to tie Medicaid payments to clinical staff wages and benefits, including additional pay for experience and specialization.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Launch National Nursing Career Pathways Campaign. </em>CMS, in collaboration with the Department of Labor, will work with external entities—including training intermediaries, registered apprenticeship programs, labor-management training programs, and labor unions—to conduct a robust nationwide campaign to recruit, train, retain, and transition workers into long-term care careers, with pathways into health-care careers like registered and licensed nurses.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Ensuring Pandemic and Emergency Preparedness in Nursing Homes</strong></p>



<ul><li><em>Continued COVID-19 testing in long-term care facilities.</em> Throughout the pandemic, the Biden-Harris Administration has provided approximately 3 million tests per week to all Medicare- and Medicaid-certified nursing homes and thousands more assisted living facilities, supporting outbreak testing and regular testing of staff. HHS will continue to support this key mitigation strategy for vulnerable residents and the staff that care for them.</li><li><em>Continued COVID-19 vaccinations and boosters in long-term care facilities.</em> The Biden-Harris Administration has provided the full support of the federal government to states in ensuring that staff and residents across long-term care facilities have access to vaccinations and booster shots. Today, facilities are required to ensure staff are vaccinated and more than 87.1% of residents have received their primary series. CDC continues to offer all facilities the ability to be matched with a federal pharmacy partner to host an on-site vaccination clinic. CMS has reached out to thousands of these facilities directly to offer support, and the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality has made a wide set of tools available. HHS will continue to promote access to these clinics and efforts to integrate vaccinations into routine services, incentivize vaccinations through provider quality payment programs, and continue to provide a full range of resources to continue to build confidence in the vaccine.</li><li><em>Strengthen Requirements for On-site Infection Preventionists</em>. CMS will clarify and increase the standards for nursing homes on the level of staffing facilities need for on-site infection prevention employees, undoing the Trump Administration’s changes to these requirements to help improve resident health and safety.</li><li><em>Enhance Requirements for Pandemic and Emergency Preparedness</em>. Both the pandemic and the increase in natural disasters have demonstrated how critical proactive emergency preparedness is to keeping residents of nursing homes safe. CMS is examining and considering changes to emergency preparedness requirements and is working to bolster the resiliency of the health care sector as part of an Administration-wide effort to be ready for the next pandemic and the next weather-related emergencies.</li><li><em>Integrate Pandemic Lessons into Nursing Home Requirements. </em>The pandemic has underscored the need for resident-centered updates to nursing homes’ requirements of participation in Medicare and Medicaid. CMS will integrate new lessons on standards of care into nursing home requirements around fire safety, infection control, and other areas, using an equity lens<em>.</em></li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  Lowering Prices and Leveling the Playing Field in Ocean&#160;Shipping</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-lowering-prices-and-leveling-the-playing-field-in-ocean-shipping/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47990</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing an historic agreement between the Department of Justice and the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) to make sure that large ocean freight companies cannot take advantage of U.S. businesses and consumers. Right now, three global alliances, made up entirely of foreign companies, control almost all of ocean freight shipping, giving them power&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing an historic agreement between the Department of Justice and the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) to make sure that large ocean freight companies cannot take advantage of U.S. businesses and consumers. Right now, three global alliances, made up entirely of foreign companies, control almost all of ocean freight shipping, giving them power to raise prices for American businesses and consumers, while threatening our national security and economic competitiveness.</p>



<p>Most traded goods—everything from the housewares you buy online to the agricultural products American farmers market overseas—are transported by ocean freight companies. <strong>These companies have formed global alliances—groups of ocean carrier companies that work together—that now control </strong><a href="https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/docs/impact-alliances-container-shipping.pdf"><strong>80</strong></a><strong>%</strong><strong> of global container ship capacity and control </strong><a href="https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/docs/impact-alliances-container-shipping.pdf"><strong>95</strong></a><strong>%</strong><strong> of the critical East-West trade lines.</strong> This consolidation happened rapidly over the last decade. From 1996 to 2011, the leading three alliances operated only about <a href="https://www.itf-oecd.org/sites/default/files/docs/impact-alliances-container-shipping.pdf">30</a>% of global container shipping. Significant consolidation occurred in the years running up to the Pandemic. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Since the beginning of the pandemic, these ocean carrier companies have been dramatically increasing shipping costs through rate increases and fees. <strong>They increased spot rates for freight shipping between Asia and the United States by 100% since January 2020, and increased rates for freight shipping between the United States and Asia </strong><a href="https://fbx.freightos.com/freight-index/FBX01"><strong>by over 1,000%</strong></a><strong> over the same period.</strong> Oftentimes cargo owners are charged fees—known as “detention and demurrage” fees—even when they can’t get access to their containers to move them. The FMC estimates that from July to September of 2021, eight of the largest carriers charged customers fees totaling $2.2 billion—a 50% increase on the previous three-month period.</p>



<p>These historically large shipping price increases translate into higher prices for American consumers. Based on research by the <a href="https://www.kansascityfed.org/ten/2017-spring-ten-magazine/shipping/#:~:text=Kansas%20City%20Fed%20economists%20Nicholas,core%20inflation%20after%20one%20year.">Kansas City Fed </a>and the <a href="https://www.ecb.europa.eu/pub/economic-bulletin/focus/2021/html/ecb.ebbox202103_01~8ecbf2b17c.en.html">European Central Bank</a>, these shipping cost increases are expected to contribute to approximately a 1% increase in consumer prices over the next year.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, the ocean carrier companies are experiencing elevated profits and soaring profit margins. Estimates suggest that the container shipping industry made a record <a href="https://www.drewry.co.uk/news/is-it-time-for-investors-to-exit-the-container-shipping-space">$190</a> billion in profits in 2021, a <a href="https://fortune.com/2021/12/03/shipping-container-record-profit-supply-chain-breakdown/#:~:text=Container%20shipping%20pre%2Dtax%20profit,to%20The%20Journal%20of%20Commerce.">seven-fold increase</a> from the previous year and five times what it made over the <a href="https://phaata.com/en/logistics-market/container-shipping-lines-report-record-profits-in-the-third-quarter-of-2021-1096.html">entire period from 2010-2020</a>. Profit margins have increased by even larger amounts. <strong>In the third quarter of 2021, the average operating margin of the major carriers was about </strong><a href="https://globalmaritimehub.com/shipping-profit-margins-accelerate.html"><strong>56</strong></a><strong>%, compared to an average operating margin of 3.7% two years earlier</strong>:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="680" height="383" src="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-47993" srcset="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg 680w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg?resize=615,346 615w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg?resize=304,171 304w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg?resize=608,342 608w, https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Econ-image-1.jpg?resize=1200,675 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></figure>



<p>Beyond price increases, several specific business practices of many large ocean carrier companies are hurting American businesses and farmers. For example, because of their market power, these alliances are able to cancel or change bookings and impose additional fees without notice. These unpredictable practices undermine American business’ ability to deliver orders on time. <a href="https://www.agri-pulse.com/articles/17129-usda-to-boost-ag-export-capacity-at-port-of-oakland">All too often</a>, ocean carriers are effectively <a href="https://www.agri-pulse.com/articles/17129-usda-to-boost-ag-export-capacity-at-port-of-oakland">refusing</a> to take American exports altogether, preferring to <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2021/01/26/shipping-carriers-rejected-us-agricultural-exports-sent-empty-containers-to-china.html">speed back to China</a> with an empty ship to make a quick turnaround rather than transport American exporters’ cargo or dock at American ports. This is especially difficult to our farmers, who have spent decades building relationships internationally, only to find that now they can’t transport their agricultural products overseas with any reliability or predictability.</p>



<p>The carriers have also continued to pursue practices that directly contribute to port congestion, such as imposing “box rules” that require truckers to use only certain trailers to haul their containers—thus forcing truckers to wait for the “right” kind of trailer to become available. That leads to lower pay and longer wait times for our nation’s truck drivers, who get paid per box, and allows the ocean carriers to generate even higher detention and demurrage fees.</p>



<p>A century ago, in the original Ocean Shipping Act, Congress provided for utility-style regulation of ocean carriers, paired with antitrust immunity for ocean carrier alliance agreements only when the alliance was in the “public interest.” But Congress <a href="https://www.justice.gov/atr/file/823411/download">steadily deregulated</a> the industry—expanding the antitrust immunity while weakening ocean carriers’ obligations to publicly disclose prices and fees and treat businesses and their customers fairly. That is how we have arrived at the point where three alliances can dominate the market for ocean shipping and squeeze American businesses and consumers.</p>



<p><strong><u>The Biden-Harris Administration is taking steps to lower consumer prices and level the playing field in ocean shipping:</u></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Today, the FMC and the Department of Justice (DOJ) are </strong><a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-and-federal-maritime-commission-reaffirm-and-strengthen-partnership"><strong>announcing</strong></a><strong> a new joint initiative to promote competition in the ocean freight transportation system. </strong>Under the new initiative, DOJ will provide the FMC with the support of attorneys and economists from the Antitrust Division for enforcement of violations of the Shipping Act and related laws. The FMC will provide the Antitrust Division with support and maritime industry expertise for Sherman Act and Clayton Act enforcement actions. The agencies’ announcement explains that competition in the maritime industry is integral to lowering prices, improving quality of service, and strengthening the resilience of supply chains.</li></ul>



<p>This initiative grew out of the “whole of government” approach to competition established by the President’s July Executive Order on Promoting Competition. The FMC and the DOJ are both part of the White House Competition Council established by the Order. Their partnership builds on an information-sharing Memorandum of Understanding that the agencies <a href="https://www.justice.gov/opa/pr/justice-department-and-federal-maritime-commission-sign-memorandum-understanding-support">entered into in July</a>.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The FMC will continue ramping up oversight of the global ocean shipping industry. </strong>Since last summer, the FMC has established a <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/fmc-establishes-ocean-carriers-audit-program/">new audit program</a> backed by an audit team to address complaints about carriers charging unfair fees, <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/commission-questions-shipping-lines-about-surcharges/">demanded justification</a> from the carriers about their fees, launched 42 cases investigating port congestion charges, and took steps to <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/fmc-policy-statements-provide-guidance-on-complaints-process/">address barriers to filing complaints</a> at the FMC and to prevent retaliation against complainants. It also launched a <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/commissioner-bentzel-hosts-inaugural-meeting-of-fmc-data-initiative/">new data initiative</a> to identify data constraints that are adding to supply chain congestion. This month, the FMC also <a href="https://www.fmc.gov/commission-invites-comments-on-benefits-of-new-demurrage-detention-rule/">sought comments</a> on reforms to how carriers charge shippers fees.</li></ul>



<p>The Administration, led by Port Envoy John Porcari, has also worked with the Ports of Los Angeles and Long Beach to develop new fees on ocean carrier companies for letting cargo sit on the docks for over nine days. These long-dwelling import containers had been causing delays in getting goods to shelves while increasing port congestion. Since the announcement of the proposed fee, the number of long-dwelling containers on the docks has fallen more than 70 percent. Building on the success of the proposed carrier fee, the Administration is working with the ports on charging the carriers for long-dwelling empty containers that have been clogging the docks. There has been a more than 25 percent drop in the number of empty containers on the docks at the Port of Los Angeles since that announcement.</p>



<p>The need for reform to our ocean freight transportation system to improve fluidity and fairness, particularly for our agricultural exporters, was underscored last week in reports released by the <a href="https://www.transportation.gov/supplychains">Department of Transportation</a> and <a href="https://www.ams.usda.gov/supply-chain">the Department of Agriculture (USDA)</a> as part of the Administration’s six supply chain <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/24/the-biden-harris-plan-to-revitalize-american-manufacturing-and-secure-critical-supply-chains-in-2022/">industrial base reports</a> published on the one-year anniversary of the President’s supply chain executive order. <strong>The President is calling on Congress to pass robust reforms to the ocean shipping industry, including reforms that address the current antitrust immunity for ocean shipping alliances.</strong> In addition to the important administrative actions announced today, the President believes Congress should provide additional tools for the Administration to address problems in the ocean shipping industry. The President is encouraged by action in both Houses of Congress to address these problems. He is calling on Congress to also address the immunity of alliance agreements from antitrust scrutiny under current law.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET:  President&#160;Biden to Lay Out Bold Commitments on Rebuilding America&#8217;s Crumbling Infrastructure Over the Next&#160;year</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/fact-sheet-administration-announces-new-actions-to-address-the-needs-of-people-with-disabilities-and-older-adults-in-response-to-and-recovery-from-covid-19-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47980</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will rebuild crumbling road and bridges, replace lead pipes, help make available reliable, affordable high-speed internet to every family in America, and produce concrete results that change people’s lives for the better. It will also support American manufacturing jobs by making sure taxpayer dollars are spent purchasing American made goods.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The historic Bipartisan Infrastructure Law will rebuild crumbling road and bridges, replace lead pipes, help make available reliable, affordable high-speed internet to every family in America, and produce concrete results that change people’s lives for the better. It will also support American manufacturing jobs by making sure taxpayer dollars are spent purchasing American made goods. Rebuilding our infrastructure and supply chains here at home, and making more here in America, means we can create more good jobs, move what we make more efficiently, and ultimately lower prices for the American people. By reaching all communities all across the country – including rural communities and historically underserved populations – these once-in-a-generation investments will position the United States to win the 21st century.<br><br>In the first 106 days since President Biden signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the White House Infrastructure Implementation Team has&nbsp;<a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/23/fact-sheet-biden-%e2%81%a0harris-administration-delivering-results-100-days-into-infrastructure-implementation/">hit the ground running</a>&nbsp;to deliver concrete results for the American people. Nearly $100 billion of dedicated funding has been announced and is headed to states, territories, Tribes and local governments, with another nearly $50 billion of notices of funding opportunity released. To date, over 4000 projects have been announced, from airport improvements to port upgrades to superfund cleanup sites. Over 90 percent of Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding will be spent by non-federal partners, meaning the Biden-Harris administration will be partnering with states, territories, Tribes, local governments and others to deliver the crucial infrastructure projects and the good-paying jobs created by these investments.<br><br><strong>In his first State of the Union Address, President Biden will highlight how our historic federal investments in infrastructure will create a visible impact in the lives of American families&nbsp;this year&nbsp;by committing to start repair on 65,000 miles of roads and 1,500 bridges.</strong>&nbsp;The President will also commit to rapid progress across every facet of the law.<br><br><strong>TRANSPORTATION</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Roads &amp; Bridges:</strong>&nbsp;As a result of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, the Department of Transportation announced $52.5 billion for highways and more than $5.3 billion for bridges for fiscal year 2022. Over the next year, states, territories, Tribes and local governments will start to improve 65,000 miles of roads and 1,500 bridges with federal funding, representing at 44% and 50% increase respectively from average annual improvement levels over the past six years.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Airports:</strong>&nbsp;In December, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) at USDOT announced $3 billion for 3,075 airports across the country that can use investments to upgrade critical infrastructure. Over the next year, FAA will be able to invest in over 600 airport infrastructure projects, including preserving 400 pavement projects on taxiways and runways.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Transit:&nbsp;</strong>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law includes the largest Federal investment in public transit in history<strong>.&nbsp;</strong>Over the next year, communities will be investing in an estimated 15,000 new buses, ferries and subway cars, improving commutes for working Americans, families, and students across the country and reducing greenhouse emissions.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Rail:</strong>&nbsp;The Federal Railroad Administration and Amtrak are transforming the nation’s transportation system. In the next year, Amtrak is investing Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding in 75 new, Made-in-America locomotives, at least 73 Made-in-America Intercity Trainsets, and major improvements to facilities in the Northeast Corridor.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ports, Waterways, and Flood Mitigation:&nbsp;</strong>With $14 billion in funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and other appropriations, the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers will advance over 500 projects across 52 states and territories to strengthen supply chains, improve waterways, and reduce flooding. Additional projects will be funded by the Port Infrastructure Development Program.</li></ul>



<p><strong>HIGH-SPEED INTERNET</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Broadband Access &amp; Deployment:&nbsp;</strong>In the next year, the Department of Commerce will issue final guidance and notices of funding opportunity for the Broadband Equity, Access and Deployment Program and the Middle Mile Broadband Infrastructure Program, which together will distribute more than $43 billion in broadband funding. The Department of Agriculture will issue a new funding opportunity notice for the ReConnect program which will provide nearly $2 billion in funding for rural broadband deployment.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Broadband Affordability:&nbsp;</strong>Over the next year, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) will build on the more than 10 million lower-income households already receiving subsidized internet service through the Affordable Connectivity Program. The FCC will also adopt rules requiring broadband providers to display easy-to-understand labels to allow consumers to more effectively comparison shop for broadband services.<br>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p><strong>CLIMATE, CLEAN ENERGY, AND ENVIRONMENT</strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Clean Water:&nbsp;</strong>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) announced $7.4 billion for Fiscal Year 2022 in Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding will be available to states to upgrade America’s aging water infrastructure, sewerage systems, lead pipes and service lines, and more through their State Revolving Fund programs. By this time next year, using Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funding alone, EPA will have worked with state and local governments to fund more than 400 new water projects from replacing lead service lines to improving drinking water systems.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Abandoned Mine Lands:&nbsp;</strong>The Department of the Interior (DOI) announced nearly $725 million in Fiscal Year 2022 funding for 22 states and the Navajo Nation to create good-paying union jobs and catalyze economic opportunity by reclaiming abandoned mine lands. Over the next year, DOI expects states, Tribes, and other partners to reclaim over 15,000 acres of abandoned mine lands, as well as launch new reclamation efforts that will ultimately address tens of thousands of additional acres across the country using Bipartisan Infrastructure Law funds. This investment delivers on President Biden’s historic commitment to investing in the revitalization of the energy communities that have powered our country for generations.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Orphan Wells:&nbsp;</strong>The first $1.15 billion in funding is now available to 26 states to create good-paying jobs cleaning up orphaned oil and gas wells across the country. Over the next year, we expect the DOI’s new Orphan Well Program will start work plugging, capping, and remediating over 8,000 abandoned oil &amp; gas well sites in communities across the country.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Superfund:&nbsp;</strong>EPA announced $1 billion to initiate cleanup and clear the backlog of 49 previously unfunded Superfund sites and accelerate cleanup at dozens of other sites across the country, with work expected at more than 80 Superfund cleanup projects in the next year.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Great Lakes Restoration:&nbsp;</strong>EPA announced $1 billion for the Great Lakes Restoration Initiative, including $200 million in Fiscal Year 2022, to accelerate progress in the clean-up and restoration of the Great Lakes’ most environmentally degraded sites, securing clean water and a better environment for millions of Americans in the Great Lakes region. In the next year, EPA will work across more than 20 sites across the Great Lakes basin targeting open areas of concern.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Wildfire Resilience:&nbsp;</strong>In the next year, the DOI will increase its work to reduce the risk of wildfires to communities by more than 30 percent&#8211; removing over 300,000 acres of burnable fuels in the places where communities and wildlands meet – as well as the start of work to reduce wildfire risk on an additional 250,000 acres across the country. With BIL funding and existing appropriations, the US Forest Service at the Department of Agriculture also expects to execute hazardous fuels reduction work on more than 4 million acres over the next year, including reforesting up to 400,000 acres to create new carbon sinks on previously burned lands.<br>&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Critical Mineral Refinery:&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Energy (DOE) released a Request for Information for the construction and operation of a first-of-its kind $140 million demonstration facility to extract and separate rare earth elements and other critical minerals from coal ash, mine tailings, acid drainage, and other legacy fossil fuel waste to sustainably produce materials key to next-generation clean energy technologies. This facility will support good-paying manufacturing jobs and help secure a sustainable domestic supply chain to fight the climate crisis.<br>&nbsp;</li><li><strong>Battery Manufacturing:</strong>&nbsp;This Spring, DOE will make available nearly $3 billion to bolster domestic manufacturing of advanced batteries for electric vehicles and energy storage. This includes refining and production of battery materials, manufacturing of battery cells and packs, and end-of-life recycling to create good-paying manufacturing jobs and support growing demand for electric vehicles and energy storage to meet the Administration’s ambitious net-zero climate goals.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Amends Puerto Rico Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/02/28/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-amends-puerto-rico-disaster-declaration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47977</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for Public Assistance projects undertaken in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico as a result of earthquakes during the period of December 28, 2019, to July 3, 2020. Under&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. made additional disaster assistance available to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico by authorizing an increase in the level of Federal funding for Public Assistance projects undertaken in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico as a result of earthquakes during the period of December 28, 2019, to July 3, 2020.<br><br>Under the President’s major disaster declaration issued for the Commonwealth of Puerto on January 16, 2020, Federal funding was made available for Public Assistance, Hazard Mitigation, and Other Needs Assistance at 75 percent of the total eligible costs.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Under the President&#8217;s order today, the Federal share for Public Assistance has been increased to 90 percent of the total eligible costs.<br><br>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE&nbsp; FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on American Red Cross Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/28/a-proclamation-on-american-red-cross-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47974</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Throughout our history, Americans have always stepped up for each other in moments of crisis.&#160; This spirit is woven into the fabric of our Nation, and for more than 140 years it has been exemplified by devoted employees, volunteers, and supporters of the American Red Cross.&#160; This month, we honor the American Red Cross and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Throughout our history, Americans have always stepped up for each other in moments of crisis.&nbsp; This spirit is woven into the fabric of our Nation, and for more than 140 years it has been exemplified by devoted employees, volunteers, and supporters of the American Red Cross.&nbsp; This month, we honor the American Red Cross and the selfless Americans who serve our communities in need across our country and around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Since its founding in 1881 by Clara Barton, a nurse and educator, the American Red Cross has carried out its noble mission of preventing and easing human suffering.&nbsp; Today, in big cities and small towns across the country, hundreds of thousands of Red Cross workers &#8212; more than 90 percent of whom are volunteers &#8212; continue to carry out that mission by selflessly giving blood, making donations, and teaching first aid in local communities.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Support from the American Red Cross has provided hope to people in their darkest hours &#8212; in the face of armed conflict, climate-related disasters, and the COVID-19 pandemic.&nbsp; Red Cross volunteers are on the front lines of recovery, providing emergency shelter to families impacted by devastating floods, tornadoes, fires, and other disasters; donating lifesaving blood to meet the rising demand of hospital patients; supporting our Nation&#8217;s service members, veterans, and their families; and providing medical care and essential resources to combat diseases worldwide.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; During American Red Cross Month, Americans who can are encouraged to answer the call to donate blood and serve communities in need.&nbsp; You are encouraged to learn more about eligibility and the steps involved to donating blood.&nbsp; Let us renew our commitment to Clara Barton&#8217;s timeless ideal of caring for one another in times of hardship and uncertainty.&nbsp; Let us take part in this proud tradition of lending a helping hand to those in need.&nbsp; Let us live up to the duty of care we owe each other through acts of compassion every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America and Honorary Chair of the American Red Cross, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2022 as American Red Cross Month.&nbsp; I encourage all Americans to observe this month with appropriate programs, ceremonies and activities, and by supporting the work of service and relief organizations.</p>



<p>                IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-eighth day of February, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">                             JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Women&#8217;s History Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/28/a-proclamation-on-womens-history-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:13:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47971</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Every March, Women&#8217;s History Month provides an opportunity to honor the generations of trailblazing women and girls who have built our Nation, shaped our progress, and strengthened our character as a people.&#160; Throughout our history, despite hardship, exclusion, and discrimination, women have strived and sacrificed for equity and equality in communities across the country. &#160;Generations&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Every March, Women&#8217;s History Month provides an opportunity to honor the generations of trailblazing women and girls who have built our Nation, shaped our progress, and strengthened our character as a people.&nbsp;<br><br>Throughout our history, despite hardship, exclusion, and discrimination, women have strived and sacrificed for equity and equality in communities across the country. &nbsp;Generations of Native American women were stewards of the land and continue to lead the fight for climate justice. &nbsp;Black women fought to end slavery, advocate for civil rights, and pass the Voting Rights Act. &nbsp;Suffragists helped pass the 19th Amendment to the Constitution so that no American could be denied a vote on the basis of sex.<br><br>Standing on the shoulders of the heroines who came before them, today&#8217;s women and girls continue to carry forward the mission of ensuring our daughters have the same opportunities as our sons. &nbsp;Women of the labor movement are achieving monumental reforms to help all workers secure the better pay, benefits, and safety they deserve. &nbsp;LGBTQI+ women and girls are leading the fight for justice, opportunity, and equality &#8212; especially for the transgender community. &nbsp;Women and girls continue to lead groundbreaking civil rights movements for social justice and freedom, so that everyone can realize the full promise of America.<br><br>But despite the progress being made, women and girls &#8212; especially women and girls of color &#8212; still face systemic barriers to full participation and wider gaps in opportunity and equality. &nbsp;The COVID-19 pandemic has exposed and exacerbated those disparities which have disproportionately impacted women&#8217;s labor force participation, multiplied the burden on paid and unpaid caregivers, and increased rates of gender-based violence. &nbsp;The constitutional right to abortion established in Roe v. Wade is facing an unprecedented assault as States pass increasingly onerous restrictions to critical reproductive health care and bodily autonomy. &nbsp;Workers contend with gender and racial wage gaps that can amount to hundreds of thousands of dollars denied over the course of their lifetimes. &nbsp;The Congress sent the Equal Rights Amendment to the States for ratification 50 years ago and it is long past time that the principle of women&#8217;s equality should be enshrined in our Constitution.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; My Administration has made this issue a top priority from day one. &nbsp;Through historic Executive actions, my Administration launched Government-wide efforts to advance gender equity and equality, racial equity, and LGBTQI+ equality.&nbsp; Through the American Rescue Plan, my Administration delivered immediate relief to women and families, funded domestic violence and sexual assault services, supported child care providers, and invested in care workers &#8212; who are disproportionately women of color.&nbsp; Through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we are working to ensure equitable access to good-paying jobs, particularly in sectors where women have historically been underrepresented. &nbsp;We have taken critical steps to end the scourge of gender-based violence and advocate for the long overdue reauthorization of the Violence Against Women Act &#8212; legislation that I was proud to author and champion as a United States Senator.&nbsp; We are confronting the epidemic levels of violence that transgender women and girls continue to face.&nbsp; We are working to expand access to health care, including reproductive health care for all people regardless of their gender, race, ethnicity, income, or zip code. &nbsp;We are fighting to lower the costs of child care and provide access to free preschool for all three- and four-year olds.&nbsp; We issued a call to action to eliminate racial disparities in maternal health care, which disproportionately impact Black and Indigenous women.&nbsp; And my Administration established a Gender Equity and Equality Action Fund to advance the rights and economic security of women and girls around the world.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;This work is being led by the most diverse and gender-balanced Cabinet in American history, including the first woman &#8212; and woman of color &#8212; to serve as Vice President, Kamala Harris; the first women ever to serve as Treasury Secretary and Director of National Intelligence; the first Native American woman to serve as a Cabinet Secretary; women leading the Departments of Commerce, Energy, Housing and Urban Development, along with the Small Business Administration and the Office of Management and Budget; and women of color representing America on the world stage as United States Ambassador to the United Nations and the United States Trade Representative as well as leading my Council of Economic Advisers in the White House.&nbsp; In addition, I&nbsp;established the first White House Gender Policy Council to advance gender equity across the Federal Government and released the first-ever national gender strategy to support the full participation of all people &#8212; including women and girls &#8212; in the United States and around the world.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; This Women&#8217;s History Month, as we reflect on the achievements of women and girls across the centuries and pay tribute to the pioneers who paved the way, let us recommit to the fight and help realize the deeply American vision of a more equal society where every person has a shot at pursuing the American dream. &nbsp;In doing so, we will advance economic growth, our health and safety, and the security of our Nation and the world.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2022 as Women&#8217;s History Month. &nbsp;I call upon all Americans to observe this month and to celebrate International Women&#8217;s Day on March 8, 2022, with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities.&nbsp; I also invite all Americans to visit www.WomensHistoryMonth.gov to learn more about the vital contribution of women to our Nation&#8217;s history.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this<br>twenty-eighth day of February, in the year of our Lord two&nbsp;thousand&nbsp;twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United&nbsp;States of&nbsp;America the two&nbsp;hundred and forty-sixth.<br>&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/28/a-proclamation-on-national-colorectal-cancer-awareness-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ Cancer is personal to nearly every family, including my own.  Each year, more than 50,000 families across the country lose a loved one to colorectal cancer &#8212; the fourth most common cancer and the second leading cause of cancer deaths in America.  The toll it exacts is immeasurable, but when we detect colorectal cancer early,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p> Cancer is personal to nearly every family, including my own.  Each year, more than 50,000 families across the country lose a loved one to colorectal cancer &#8212; the fourth most common cancer and the second leading cause of cancer deaths in America.  The toll it exacts is immeasurable, but when we detect colorectal cancer early, we can save lives and deliver hope.  During National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month, we raise awareness of this dreaded disease and renew our commitment to ending cancer as we know it.  <br><br>     While anyone can be afflicted by colorectal cancer, we know that this illness strikes at a disproportionate rate among Black Americans as well as Americans over the age of 50.  Getting regular screenings and identifying symptoms and risk factors are both pivotal to saving lives.  According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, symptoms such as blood in the stool, a change in bowel habits, stomach pain, bloating, cramps that do not go away, or weight loss without a known cause should be discussed with a health care provider.  However, early stages of colorectal cancer often emerge without symptoms, and it is important to begin regular screenings starting at the age of 45.<br><br>     In addition, people who smoke, consume alcohol, or are obese are more likely to be diagnosed with colorectal cancer.  Adopting healthy behaviors &#8212; including quitting the use of tobacco products, reducing alcohol consumption, and eating meals that include fruits, vegetables, and whole grains &#8212; can also reduce your risk.  For more information on risk factors, please visit <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=bf58d1fb1b&amp;e=dbfe791882">www.Cancer.gov</a>. <br><br>     I believe that it is within our power to end cancer as we know it.  That is why I have re-ignited the Cancer Moonshot and set new ambitious goals, to reduce the death rate from cancer by 50 percent over the next 25 years and to improve the lives of people and their families living with and surviving cancer.  I have called on the Congress to create the Advanced Research Projects Agency for Health (ARPA-H), which will invest billions of dollars to advance breakthroughs in the prevention, detection, and treatment of cancer and other deadly diseases.  As we continue to pursue game-changing scientific breakthroughs, my Administration also remains steadfast in our commitment to increasing colorectal cancer screenings, follow-ups, and referrals, with a particular focus on underserved populations.  On February 2, 2022, the First Lady and I launched a call to action on cancer screening and early detection.  Our goal is to jumpstart progress on potentially life-saving screenings that far too many Americans have missed as a result of the pandemic and help ensure that everyone in the United States benefits equitably from the tools we have to detect and diagnose cancer.  We are calling on every American to get back on track with their recommended screenings, including colorectal cancer screenings, and for the public and private sectors to increase access to early detection for individuals and communities.<br><br>     Ensuring that every American has access to quality, affordable health coverage is another critical way that we can win the fight against cancer.  Thanks to the Affordable Care Act, most health insurance plans must cover certain preventive services with no out-of-pocket costs.  This coverage now includes colorectal cancer screenings for adults over the age of 45, making it easier to get colorectal cancer screenings and helping improve access to earlier treatment.  Health coverage under the Affordable Care Act has never been more accessible and affordable than it is today, and I encourage all Americans to learn more by visiting <a href="https://whitehouse.us19.list-manage.com/track/click?u=c97630621baff8c44fe607661&amp;id=4cdbbe63ea&amp;e=dbfe791882">www.HealthCare.gov</a>.  <br><br>     During National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month, I urge every American to exercise vigilance around their own health and the health of their loved ones.  Early diagnosis and treatment save lives &#8212; and getting screened for colorectal cancer is vitally important as we continue our shared mission to end cancer as we know it.<br><br>     NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2022 as National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month.  I encourage all citizens, government agencies, private businesses, non-profit organizations, and other groups to join in activities that will increase awareness and prevention of colorectal cancer.<br><br>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this<br>twenty-eighth day of February, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.<br>                               </p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Irish-American Heritage Month,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/02/28/a-proclamation-on-irish-american-heritage-month-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 18:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=47963</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For centuries, Irish Americans have played a crucial role in helping define the soul of our Nation, and today, nearly 1 in 10 Americans proudly trace their roots back to the Emerald Isle.  With hope and faith in their hearts, the first immigrants from Ireland crossed the Atlantic in search of liberty and opportunity.  It&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>For centuries, Irish Americans have played a crucial role in helping define the soul of our Nation, and today, nearly 1 in 10 Americans proudly trace their roots back to the Emerald Isle.  With hope and faith in their hearts, the first immigrants from Ireland crossed the Atlantic in search of liberty and opportunity.  It was the dream of a better life that brought my ancestors &#8212; the Blewitts of County Mayo and the Finnegans of County Louth &#8212; and countless other Irish immigrants. <br><br>Like so many Irish American families, my grandparents carried the spirit and memory of Ireland in their hearts &#8212; a pride and passion they instilled in their home in Scranton, Pennsylvania.  Through the journeys of their own mothers and fathers and in the lessons they passed on to my mother, Catherine Eugenia Finnegan Biden, they joined Irish Americans in every corner of America in helping to write the next chapter of the American story.<br><br>The story of Irish Americans has always been one of strength and perseverance through adversity.  Many Irish immigrants arrived on America&#8217;s shores to escape the Great Famine, only to face discrimination, prejudice, and poverty.  Despite these hard times, they embraced their new homes in every corner of America &#8212; from the Atlantic to the Pacific, across the Midwest and through the Rocky Mountains &#8212; and helped build and fortify our Nation into what it is today.  <br><br>Irish Americans expanded the American middle class, building ladders of opportunity that future generations could climb.  They became teachers, firefighters, police officers, labor leaders, farmers, business owners, and more.  Along the way, Irish Americans contributed enormously to the American labor movement &#8212; championing safe working conditions, advocating for children&#8217;s rights, and fighting racism, prejudice, and income inequality.  They bravely answered the call to serve, defending our Union and its values in every battle.  They continue to work on behalf of the American people as public servants &#8212; serving in the Congress, the Supreme Court, Federal agencies, the White House, and in State and local offices across the country.  Irish Americans have enriched our culture and nourished our hearts and souls through the arts and humanities, earning recognition as Nobel and Pulitzer prize-winning poets and authors, award-winning musicians, storytellers, and dancers, and critically acclaimed actors.  They have blessed our Nation with their indomitable spirit, faith, and love for family that has been passed down through the generations.  This sense of community, hospitality, resilience, and passion are integral pieces of America&#8217;s cultural tapestry. <br><br>The United States and Ireland are deeply and forever intertwined:  linked in memory and imagination &#8212; in joy, sorrow, and resilience &#8212; by our common love and common dreams.  We share, in every heart, an unrelenting optimism &#8212; a flicker of hope that guides us through even the darkest of nights.<br><br>As we celebrate Irish-American Heritage Month, let us honor the journey and contributions of Irish Americans who helped shape this land of opportunity and define what it means to be American.  Let us reaffirm the legacy of friendship and strong family ties between the United States of America and Ireland &#8212; united by our common purpose, by our histories, and by our futures.<br><br>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 2022 as Irish-American Heritage Month.  I call upon all Americans to celebrate the achievements and contributions of Irish Americans to our Nation with appropriate ceremonies, activities, and programs.<br><br>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-eighth day of February, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
