<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 21:42:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by Senior Administration Officials on&#160;China</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/03/14/background-press-call-by-senior-administration-officials-on-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 21:42:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49087</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 2:59 P.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; MODERATOR:&#160; Great.&#160; Thank you.&#160; Thanks, everyone, for joining us today.&#160; So, this call is on background.&#160; It is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&#160; And the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call. For your reporting &#8212; sorry, for your awareness &#8212; oh, my&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>2:59 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone, for joining us today.&nbsp; So, this call is on background.&nbsp; It is attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; And the contents of this call are embargoed until the end of the call.</p>



<p>For your reporting &#8212; sorry, for your awareness &#8212; oh, my God &#8212; for your awareness, not for your reporting, the speaker on this call is [senior administration official].</p>



<p>So, again, as a reminder, this call is on background to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I’ll turn it over to you for some top remarks.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks so much.&nbsp; And thanks to everybody for hopping on.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry for keeping you all waiting just a little bit there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I think you all have seen the readout that went out from the White House just a little bit ago, so I won&#8217;t rehearse what was in there.&nbsp; You’ve got that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, you know, we just wrapped a meeting in Rome, of course between the National Security Advisor and his PRC counterpart.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two covered a range of issues of interest to the United States and the international community.&nbsp; It was an intense seven-hour session reflecting the gravity of the moment, as well as our commitment to maintaining open lines of communication.&nbsp;</p>



<p>While this meeting had been planned for some time, it was a timely and important conversation in this crisis moment.&nbsp; The two officials covered the whole range of issues in the U.S.-China relationship.&nbsp; <a>They had an extensive conversation on Russia/Ukraine, with the National Security Advisor laying out where we are, how we got here, and what the risks are that we see lying ahead. </a>&nbsp;</p>



<p>The two sides discussed DPRK because that is also an escalating situation that demands our attention.&nbsp; We agreed that officials with responsibility for this issue from the two sides will deepen their conversations in the near future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, they discussed crisis management and ways to manage strategic risk, following up on the discussion in November between President Biden and President Xi on the importance of doing so, toward the goal of managing the competition between our two countries to ensure that it does not veer into conflict.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The National Security Advisor also reiterated our One China policy based on the Taiwan Relations Act, Three Communiqués, and Six Assurances.&nbsp; And he underscored concerns about Beijing&#8217;s courses and provocative actions across the Taiwan Strait.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This meeting, of course, comes not only amid Russia&#8217;s intensifying invasion in Ukraine, but also the intense work in recent months with our allies and partners in Europe and Asia.</p>



<p>The National Security Advisor described to Yang the unity of the United States and its allies and partners, the unprecedented coordination with our European and NATO Allies in particular, as well as the intense and unprecedented engagement by Asia Pacific allies in bringing the cost on Russia for its actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The President, as you know, has been coordinating closely with our Indo-Pacific partners to support the solidarity.&nbsp; And, of course, just less than two weeks ago, President Biden convened a secure video meeting of the Quad leaders of Australia, India, Japan, and the United States to discuss the war against Ukraine and the implications for the Indo-Pacific.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that is what I&#8217;ve got on the meeting, and we&#8217;d be happy to take a couple of questions.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; Could we re-up the directions again to ask a question please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Can you tell us: What is the current financial situation between China and Russia?&nbsp; And was this call &#8212; this meeting so urgent, particularly because of the threat that Russia &#8212; the possibility Russia might default as soon as Wednesday?&nbsp; And is Russia seeking a bailout from China?&nbsp; And is that your prime concern more than weapons right now &#8212; to stop China from bailing out Russia?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, thanks so much, Andrea, for the question.&nbsp; So let me just clarify with a bit of context that, you know, this meeting had been planned for some time.&nbsp; In fact, discussions about planning this meeting started soon after the virtual meeting between the two leaders, which, of course, that meeting was in November.&nbsp; I believe the planning conversations for this meeting today took place &#8212; started in December.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So this was the date that had been agreed upon by the U.S. and China quite some time ago.&nbsp; But, of course, the context in which the conversation is taking place has shifted since the original conversations about this meeting.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>So I wouldn&#8217;t want to somehow convey that there was an urgency necessarily, or that this meeting was timed based on some particular events vis-à-vis Russia/Ukraine.&nbsp; Rather, again, this was a long-planned, long-discussed meeting where, in fact, the timing of it landed, we think, was a really timely and important moment in this crisis.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>So that&#8217;s kind of on the timing piece of it.</p>



<p>You know, on the question about, you know, the financial situation and what our concerns are and whatnot: I mean, number one, I&#8217;d have to sort of refer you to Russia and China, respectively, about what the situation actually is.&nbsp; But, you know, what I would just say, in general, is that we do have deep concerns about China&#8217;s alignment with Russia at this time, and the National Security Advisor was direct about those concerns and the potential implications and consequences of certain actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Can we do our next question, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thanks so much for doing this.&nbsp; I just want to follow on Andrea’s question.&nbsp; Does the U.S. have information that China has expressed an openness to providing Russia with the requested military and financial assistance that we&#8217;ve all reported on?&nbsp; And has any assistance been provided from China to Russia since the invasion of Ukraine started?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Kaitlan.&nbsp; I do not have any comments for you on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you say why you don’t have any comment?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; I &#8212;</p>



<p>OPERATOR:&nbsp; All right, our next ques- &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>OPERATOR:&nbsp; Sorry.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Let’s let [senior administration official] finish that thought.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Well, I’m not going to comment on the specific reports.&nbsp; You know, what I will say, in general, in terms of concerns vis-à-vis what China may be considering, or what kind of support it could provide: You know, the National Security Advisor was clear, I think, over the weekend.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But we&#8217;re not communicating via the press with the PRC.&nbsp; We are communicating directly and privately with China about our concerns, about the kinds of support that other countries might be providing to Russia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Next question, please.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, thank you.&nbsp; You said it was an intense seven-hour meeting.&nbsp; Why was it so intense?&nbsp; Why was it so long?&nbsp; What did you ask China to do?&nbsp; Was it a successful meeting?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; That was a lot of &#8212; a lot packed in there, so I&#8217;ll try and hit all of those, Steve.</p>



<p>You know, why was it intense?&nbsp; I would say, number one, you know, this was pretty &#8212; this is a &#8212; there&#8217;s a lot of gravity in this moment<a></a><a>.&nbsp; And I think the conversation reflected the intensity of that.&nbsp; And I think it was also a very candid conversation, which I &#8212; you know, I think is also important.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>Why was it so long?&nbsp; Well, you know, it had been planned as, you know, a relatively lengthy set of meetings &#8212; set of exchanges.&nbsp; We had several sessions throughout the day, including, you know, a one-on-one between the two officials, as they have done previously.&nbsp; And, you know, I think &#8212; I mean, there&#8217;s practical reasons there, which is, you know, the National Security Advisor and Director Yang flew great lengths to meet.&nbsp; So, important to take that opportunity to cover the wide range of issues, you know, not only in U.S.-China relations, but of, you know, international interest and import.&nbsp; So, I think that is the reason for the length.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, on the question of, you know, of a specific ask: You know, I would just say that this meeting was not about negotiating any specific issues or outcomes, but about a candid, direct exchange of views and articulation of those.&nbsp; And I would suppose it depends on how you define success.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, we believe that it is important to keep open lines of communication between the United States and China, especially on areas where we disagree.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s incredibly important to be able to have, you know, candid and direct conversations about those things.&nbsp; And so, I’m certain that that was what occurred today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hey, [senior administration official], thanks for doing this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m going to try to get you to say something on those reports on the assistance that Russia had requested from China.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll try a different way.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>When you guys say, you know, that there &#8212; that you&#8217;re looking for substantial and material support that could be provided, what do you define it as?&nbsp; Is there a red line that China could cross, but if they don&#8217;t, then there&#8217;s no consequences for them?&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>And then secondly, you know, this is a pretty high-stakes moment, as you’ve said &#8212; you know, also in the context of all of these reports.&nbsp; And I don&#8217;t know if your candid conversations necessarily always lead to the Chinese understanding exactly what you want from them.&nbsp; So, does it warrant a call between the leaders to follow up and really drive home the points you made today?</p>



<p>And then thirdly &#8212; sorry, because my line is still open &#8212; what did you take into this meeting from allies?&nbsp; And how concerned are they on these reports, on the intel that you shared with them?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks, Jenny.&nbsp; Love the &#8212; the, like, triple, quadruple questions we&#8217;ve got going here.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not too jet-lagged yet to lose track.</p>



<p>So, on the first question &#8212; look, I&#8217;m just going to reiterate that we do have deep concerns about China&#8217;s alignment with Russia at this time.&nbsp; And the National Security Advisor was direct about those concerns and the potential implications and consequences of certain actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But again, we&#8217;re not communicating via the press with China.&nbsp; We&#8217;re communicating directly and privately.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t have anything for you on the question about a call between the leaders, other than, again, we believe it&#8217;s important to maintain open lines of communication.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I said I was going to remember your last question, and now I can&#8217;t read my handwriting here.&nbsp; So, what was the third one?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I think it was concer- &#8212; are our allies and partners concerned about &#8212;</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp;&nbsp; Oh, our allies.&nbsp; Right.&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; Of course, of course, of course.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, again, not going to be able to confirm any reports or comment on any new reports that have been in the press.&nbsp; However, as I noted, we have been, you know, working closely, consulting closely with allies and partners over &#8212; you know &#8212; well, over the course of the entire administration, but certainly very intensively in recent months.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know &#8212; and I would refer you to other capitals to characterize their own views, other than to say that I know that, you know, the &#8212; much of the world is, you know, watching the decisions that various governments are taking in this incredibly important moment.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; I think we have time for just one more question, so could we queue that up, please?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Again this Hyeongjoo, VOA.&nbsp; Thank you for this opportunity.&nbsp; My question is about discussion on DPRK.&nbsp; So, could you be a little bit more specific on what Jake Sullivan’s message to his counterpart, especially, as you may know, the situation in Korean Peninsula is escalating by North Korea&#8217;s continuous provocation?</p>



<p>And also, we have a news report, citing South Korean officials, that North Korea intercontinental ballistic missiles launch might be imminent.&nbsp; So what did you ask China to do in dealing with the North Korea?&nbsp; Especially, did you discuss the Chinese continuous objection at the U.N. Security Council to respond the North Korean missile test?</p>



<p>And also, how would you respond if North Korea launched the intercontinental ballistic missile?&nbsp; How would you respond?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks for that question. &nbsp;So, obviously &#8212; oh, there&#8217;s a bit of an echo.&nbsp; Okay, it’s better now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, obviously &#8212; you know, we have serious concerns about the recent escalatory actions that we have seen from the DPRK.&nbsp; You know, the National Security Advisor was clear with Director Yang not only about those concerns, but also, you know, about the steps that we believe are necessary in this moment and the work that we hope to be able to engage with China on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We do think there is a history of the United States and China being able to work together on this issue, in addition to, obviously, the United States continuing our close work with our allies in Seoul and Tokyo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, that&#8217;s where the two sides &#8212; the National Security Advisor and Director Yang &#8212; discussed ensuring that there are follow-up conversations in the near future, building on recent discussions between, you know, our Special Representative Sung Kim and his Chinese Special Representative Liu Xiaoming in order to further discuss specific ways that the United States and China may be able to press the DPRK on a different path.</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Great.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&nbsp; That was our last question.&nbsp; As a reminder, this call was on background, attributable to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp; The embargo on the contents of this call have now lifted.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you have any more questions, please feel free to reach out to me and we&#8217;ll make sure to get back to you.&nbsp; Thanks, everyone.</p>



<p>3:18 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at the National League of Cities Congressional City&#160;Conference</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/03/14/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-national-league-of-cities-congressional-city-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 21:40:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49082</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Marriott MarquisWashington, D.C. 2:31 P.M. EDT &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Hello, hello, hello.&#160; (Applause.)&#160; It’s great to be back with you all, in person this time.&#160; Please, sit down.&#160; Please, sit down &#8212; if you have a seat.&#160; (Laughs.)&#160; (Applause.)&#160; &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; AUDIENCE MEMBER:&#160; We love you, Mr. Biden! &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Mr. President, Mayor Vince Williams,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Marriott Marquis<br>Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>2:31 P.M. EDT<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Hello, hello, hello.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s great to be back with you all, in person this time.&nbsp; Please, sit down.&nbsp; Please, sit down &#8212; if you have a seat.&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We love you, Mr. Biden!<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Mr. President, Mayor Vince Williams, thank you for your leadership of this organization and your leadership down in Union City, Georgia.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>I wanted to come here because you’re the people America looks to first for guidance and for leadership.&nbsp; And that’s not hyperbole.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; City managers, mayors, councilpersons &#8212; when you have a problem, they’re knocking on your doors.&nbsp; That’s because their quality of life depends on you more than anyone else.&nbsp; And I’m not trying to be solicitous; I know from personal experience.</p>



<p>When I was a 27-year-old kid, I got elected to the New Castle County Council, which &#8212; we’re like a miniature Illinois; one county has 60 percent of the population of the state.&nbsp; And so the Councilman represents a district seven times bigger than the state rep and three times bigger than a state senator.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, fortunately, after two years &#8212; I was elected for four years &#8212; after two years, my &#8212; the Republican party saw in me something I didn’t see; they &#8212; so they reapportioned me to a two-year term &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; from a district that was overwhelmingly Republican to over overwhelmingly Republican.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>So I got put in the position &#8212; that old saying goes &#8212; “up or out.”&nbsp; So I do appreciate what you all do.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You’re &#8212; you’re there &#8212; you can’t walk into a grocery store or gas station, you can’t go into a supermarket without &#8212; without someone having a question for you, and &#8212; because you’re the &#8212; you’re the people they know, you’re the people they depend on.&nbsp; You’re out there every day on the frontlines of public service.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And that’s why, when I took office last year in the midst of the worst health pandemic in a century, the worst economic crisis since the Great Depression, I knew we had to design a Rescue Plan with your partnership to meet your needs.</p>



<p>Three days ago marked the one-year anniversary I signed the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp; I’m &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I learned as a councilman I never have anything that’s intended to be shared by the cities and towns that has to go through state legislature.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; No, I mean it.</p>



<p>The most significant investment in local government in all of history was in that plan.&nbsp; And frankly, you couldn’t have gotten it done without your support and so many local officials around the country.</p>



<p>I don’t need to remind you the situation you all inherited in 2020 &#8212; the pain, the disruption, the stress of your local budgets requiring you to lay off cops, firefighters, teachers.&nbsp; So many people lost their jobs.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you remember the lines of cars stretching for miles in your communities, with families just waiting for a box of food to be put in the backseat or the trunk.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Because of this law, we were able to help 41 million Americans put food on the table for the better part of a year.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Because of this law, we helped keep a roof over 4 million people’s heads.&nbsp; And it gave what &#8212; families what my dad would call “just a little bit of breathing room” in a tough time.</p>



<p>And it worked.&nbsp; Because we took action, America added 6.7 million jobs last year &#8212; (applause) &#8212; more jobs created in one year than ever before in American history.&nbsp; And it hasn’t stopped.</p>



<p>We’re now well over 7 million jobs &#8212; 678,000 just last month.&nbsp; The unemployment rate is down to 3.8 percent.&nbsp; The economy grew at 5.7 percent last year &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the strongest growth in four decades.</p>



<p>A leading financial team on Wall Street, Moody’s, estimate that because of the Rescue Plan, 4 million more jobs were created and unemployment is lower by 2 percent than it would have been had we failed to act.</p>



<p>One year after signing this law, our cities, our towns, and our rural communities are roaring back.</p>



<p>Before this law, state and local governments were still down more than a million jobs from before the pandemic.</p>



<p>One year later, we had at least &nbsp;one year of state and local job growth &#8212; the largest in 20 years &#8212; adding 467,000 jobs.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Educators, firefighters, police officers back on the job.</p>



<p>Before this law, fewer than half our schools were open, putting an extraordinary strain on parents and teachers and students.&nbsp; One year later, more than 99 percent of our schools are open, and kids are back in the classroom.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, folks, you just had the strongest year of hiring teachers and educators on record.</p>



<p>But there’s more to the story than that.&nbsp; America has had many recoveries in the past.&nbsp; But underneath those recoveries there’s also been a lot of lasting pain.&nbsp; Lots of folks never get back on their feet when they’re knocked down so badly.&nbsp; And a whole lot of young people saw their futures dimmed from the previous recession.&nbsp; They never got back on their feet.</p>



<p>It’s what economists call “economic scarring”: chronic pain when the economy comes back but some folks are still left behind.&nbsp; Trapped in long-term unemployment.&nbsp; Eviction and foreclosure.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Research shows that when you’re stuck in that cycle, it has the worst impact on your emotional health than the loss of a family member &#8212; which sounds excessive, but it’s true.&nbsp; And it’s serious.</p>



<p>So when I came to office in the midst of this crisis, I was determined not to let that happen again.</p>



<p>This time around, with the American Rescue Plan, we made a choice to bring everyone along &#8212; every single person in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So, not only has the unemployment rate dropped at a record pace, we’ve also seen the biggest drop in long-term unemployment ever recorded in a 12-month span; nearly 2.5 million people breaking out of that cycle of long-term unemployment and depression.</p>



<p>Black unemployment fell by more than 30 percent.&nbsp; Hispanic unemployment fell from nearly 9 percent to 4.4 percent, the fastest drop ever recorded.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’ve seen &#8212; it was something we should be doing again, but I’m having trouble getting it passed again &#8212; and that is the Child Tax Credit.&nbsp; The lowest pov- &#8212; child poverty rate projected in 40 years &#8212; a 40-year decline.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Folks, we also have the lowest number of home foreclosures ever recorded, a record low of credit card delinquencies because families had more money in their pockets.</p>



<p>The list goes on.&nbsp; But you all know it better than I do: A big part of the reason we’re so successful is because the Rescue Plan went directly to you without having to pass “Go,” without having to go to the statehouses.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Folks, we allocated $350 billion to state and local budgets, but we made sure $130 billion of that went straight to local governments.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Straight to local government.</p>



<p>Six thousand local governments never got a dime of the earlier relief package exac- &#8212; enacted before I came to office.&nbsp; But we made sure that every one of you was dealt into the Rescue Plan.</p>



<p>As a former local official, I know that it matters &#8212; having that flexibility and control to meet both the short-term and the long-term challenges you face.</p>



<p>One year later, the Rescue Plan is still delivering.&nbsp; So I urge you all to use the flexibility we built into the law to spend these funds wisely: to reduce violence in your communities, like members are doing in Baton Rouge and Baltimore and in New York City; to address homelessness and affordable housing, like you’re doing in Tacoma and New York City; to expand high-speed Internet, like Brownsville, Texas; or to train people for good-paying jobs, like you’re doing in Oklahoma City.</p>



<p>And, by the way, there are a lot of jobs coming to people that you’re going to need to train up people, thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Bill.</p>



<p>Everybody knew &#8212; and you heard from my Secretary a little bit earlier &#8212; America was falling behind on infrastructure.&nbsp; We used to be number one in the world; we’re now number eight.&nbsp; But now, not only has Infrastructure Week finally arrived, we’re talking about infrastructure decade, not week.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, folks, we’ve already authorized 4,000 projects all across the country, including 1,500 bridges in disrepair, and they’re starting this year, not later &#8212; this year.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the law is going to create millions of jobs rebuilding America’s roads, bridges, highways, ports, and airports; getting rid of poisonous lead pipes in 10 million homes and 400,000 schools so kids and families can have clean drinking water.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And, folks, we’re investing $65 billion to deliver high-speed Internet everywhere in America: urban, rural, suburban, Tribal communities.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; We can’t be a country where a mother has to take her kid to the McDonald’s parking lot to do their homework over the Internet.&nbsp; This is the United States of America, for God’s sake.</p>



<p>And, folks, the law is going to put an end to that, obviously.&nbsp; And the only &#8212; it’s only the beginning.&nbsp; Hundreds of billions of new investments are on the way.</p>



<p>Today, Secretary Buttigieg announced $409 million in new grants, 70 new projects, 39 states &#8212; just the beginning; electric buses to make bus service safer and more reliable and environmentally sound, helping folks in big cities, small towns get to work and get to school.</p>



<p>Projects like a new $15 million bus maintenance facility serving Atlanta; $5 million to buy cleaner and more reliable hydrogen fuel cells for buses, replacing old diesel engines in south &#8212; in southern Nevada, and so much more.</p>



<p>It’s now time for cities and towns to get ready.&nbsp; You don’t have to wait until these infrastructure projects start.&nbsp; You’re going to need more welders, pipefitters, advanced manufacturers.</p>



<p>And it takes training to get the job done well.&nbsp; And that’s why all these programs &#8212; these apprenticeship programs, union programs &#8212; and, by the way, when people talk about an apprenticeship program, we’re talking like going to four years of college; it’s four years.&nbsp; That’s why they’re the best workers in the world when they finish.&nbsp; Projects are cheaper because they last longer and they’re better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You can’t &#8212; you can start by investing in those Rescue Plan funds now, in new pathways to better jobs through union-based apprenticeships and on-the-job training.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Build the strong, diverse workforce you need to take on these infrastructure jobs so the families in your communities can deal themselves into this booming economy.</p>



<p>Look, we have an incredible opportunity ahead of us.&nbsp; But despite the progress we’ve made, we know that families are still struggling with higher prices.</p>



<p>I grew up in a family where when the price of gas went up at the pump &#8212; a gas station &#8212; we talked about it at the kitchen table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But let’s be absolutely clear about why prices are high now.&nbsp; They’re high for two reasons. &nbsp;One was COVID.</p>



<p><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The way the global economy works: If a factory in Taiwan that makes computer chips shuts down due to a COVID outbreak, it causes a ripple effect to slow down auto manufacturing in Detroit &#8212; literally, not figuratively.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, because of the pandemic, we had significant dirupt- &#8212; disruptions in the supply chain.&nbsp; And our supply chain is so important with so many materials that come from other places.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the same time, because the Rescue Plan boosted the strength and speed of our recovery, Americans had more money in their pockets.</p>



<p>And during the pandemic, they wanted to spend that money not on restaurants and vacations &#8212; because of COVID &#8212; but on hard goods: home improvements, televisions, automobiles.</p>



<p>But the lumber factories weren’t open.&nbsp; They weren’t making two-by-fours.&nbsp; Plywood wasn’t available.&nbsp; I can go down the list.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The very products that we needed for the things they wanted to buy are slowed down by disruptions in the supply chain.</p>



<p>So what happens?&nbsp; Prices went up significantly.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just look at automobiles.&nbsp; Last year, automobiles &#8212; new automobiles accounted for one third of all the inflation in America.&nbsp; Because the auto companies couldn’t get the computer chips, the price of an automobile skyrocketed.</p>



<p>And now, the second big reason for inflation is Vladimir Putin &#8212; and gas prices.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; We’ve seen the price of gas go up over a dollar just since he put his troops on the border &#8212; on the border of Ukraine.&nbsp; It went up a dollar and five cents.&nbsp; A big part of that reason is Putin began amassing troops along the border and then crossed.</p>



<p>And guess what?&nbsp; The world took notice.&nbsp; The market anticipated; prices went up.&nbsp; And then Putin invaded.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Make no mistake: The current spike in gas prices is largely the fault of Vladimir Putin.&nbsp; It has nothing to do with the American Rescue Plan.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Back to Wall Street: Wall Street estimated that the &#8212; and the San Francisco Reser- &#8212; Federal Reserve said &#8212; analyzed it &#8212; said the Rescue Plan contributed only 0.3 percent to inflation &#8212; 0.3 percent.&nbsp; That&#8217;s coming from the Fed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Rescuing our economy didn&#8217;t cause this problem, but we’re working to fix it.&nbsp; We’re building this economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; And something incredible is happening: We&#8217;re seeing a manufacturing revival like never before &#8212; the pride that comes from stamping products “Made in America.”</p>



<p>If they’d hold a minute &#8212; one of the things you should be aware of &#8212; there is a law I was unaware of when I was a senator, to be honest with you.&nbsp; It&#8217;s called “Made in America.”&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; As President of the United States, I get to allocate over $600 billion in spending on federal projects.&nbsp; Any federal project, the President for &#8212; since 1939 has been able to say, “That entire product has to be made in America before I&#8217;m going to pay for it.”&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; Fifty-three perc- &#8212; if it was 55 percent of the product was made in America, it was thought to be made in America.&nbsp; I&#8217;m changing that.&nbsp; I&#8217;m changing that.&nbsp; It has to be a minimum of 75 percent and then &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and then &#8212; because where in the hell is it written saying we can&#8217;t manufacture things in America again?&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know where that&#8217;s written.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And so, guess what?&nbsp; Intel came to me.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yeah!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; They&#8217;re going in- &#8212; yes.&nbsp; By the way, yes. &nbsp;The chairman of the board came.&nbsp; They&#8217;re going to invest $20 billion to build a factory in Ohio to manufacture computer chips &#8212; (applause); semiconductors that will power the world and our everyday lives &#8212; smartphones, the Internet, technology that doesn&#8217;t even exist today.&nbsp; And they&#8217;re prepared to increase that investment from $20 billion to $100 billion in the suburb of Cleveland.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So now it’ll create over 12,000 jobs &#8212; some of them just building the facilities, but the rest &#8212; blue-collar workers making an average of $135,000 a year in these factories.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And as soon as the Congress sends me the Bipartisan Innovation Bill &#8212; a bill that will invest another $52 billion in computer chips &#8212; I might add, by the way, we invented the computer chip here in America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We advanced the computer chip here in America.&nbsp; Then we stopped making the computer chip here in America.&nbsp; And that’s going to bring down prices of automobiles, appliances, and so much more.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s not just Intel; look at Ford.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I had a long discussion with Ford and General Motors and the Detroit factories.&nbsp; Ford has committed $11 billion to build electric vehicles in America &#8212; the biggest investment they&#8217;ve ever made.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>GM has committed $7 billion to build electric vehicles.&nbsp; Just a few years ago, these pompl- &#8212; these companies might have built these factories elsewhere; not now.&nbsp; They&#8217;re building it right here in the United States of America again.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>But look, we also know there&#8217;s much more than one way to increase people&#8217;s standard of living.&nbsp; You can reduce the cost.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, right now, what &#8212; what&#8217;s the problem?&nbsp; Again, my dad used to say, “People just need a little bit of breathing room.”&nbsp; My dad was a &#8212; a &#8212; not &#8212; my dad was just a wonderful, decent gentleman whose greatest regret was he never went to college.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My dad &#8212; my dad used to talk about how middle-class folks, whenever given a chance, they&#8217;d never, ever, ever let the country down.&nbsp; Never let the country down.&nbsp; When they do well, everybody does well.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>But look &#8212; so, gasoline prices, home heating oil prices are going to continue to go up because of these &#8212; these embargoes on Russian oil and other things that he&#8217;s brought on.&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; But what happened?&nbsp; There&#8217;s other ways &#8212; they used &#8212; my dad used to talk about the standard of living.&nbsp; It costs a lot more money if you have to pay five bucks at a pump for a gallon of gasoline, and that affects families big time &#8212; or to heat your home.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But guess what?&nbsp; If you lower the cost of childcare, it affects your standard of living.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re going to make sure no one has to pay more than 7 percent of their income on childcare.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are over 200,000 kids in America and many more adults with Type 1 diabetes<a> needing insulin every day.&nbsp; It costs 10 bucks to make a vial of insulin.&nbsp; The average cost: $647 a month, up to $1,000.&nbsp; Not going to happen on my watch.&nbsp; No one is going to be able to charge more than $35 a month for insulin.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; They’ll still make a big profit.</a></p>



<p>The average family, when we passed the provision allowing for tax credit for homeowners to winterize their homes, can save an average of 500 bucks a month just by having doors that don’t leak, windows that don’t leak, and so on.</p>



<p>So, look, let me be clear: None of this will increase inflation.&nbsp; Seventeen Nobel Prize winners in economics wrote to me saying it would ease inflationary presence &#8212; pressures.</p>



<p>We can also do it without raising a single penny on tax of anybody making under $400,000 a year.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; If you make less than 400, you’re not going to pay a penny in tax.&nbsp; We have to do this by asking the top and the biggest corporations to pay a little more.</p>



<p>Look, I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; If you can a million or a billion bucks, good for you.&nbsp; But pay your fair share!&nbsp; Pay a little bit.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>By the way, whether you’re Democrats or Republicans, raise your hand if you think the tax structure is fair now.</p>



<p>Look, 55 &#8212; I come from the corporate capital of the world.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Delaware!</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You got it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, you think I’m kidding.&nbsp; There are more corporations incorporated in Delaware than every other state in the union combined.</p>



<p>And I got elected seven times in Delaware, notwithstanding the fact that I’m so “anti-corporate America.” &nbsp;Give me a break.&nbsp; How long would I last if &#8212;</p>



<p>But here’s the deal: Fifty-five of the largest corporations of Fortune 500 paid zero in federal taxes last year, and they made $40 billion in profits.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Booo &#8212;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Look, I said, “I’m a capitalist.&nbsp; That’s not about punishing anybody.”&nbsp; But why in God’s name should a billion-dollar corporation pay a lower tax rate than a teacher or a firefighter?&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So, folks &#8212; I really mean it.&nbsp; We could raise the standard of living for hardworking families without raising tax, without raising inflation, without raising the deficit.</p>



<p>And let me remind everybody: I actually, last year, cut the budget $360 billion &#8212; cutting the budget.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And we’re on track now to be the first President in history to have a lower deficit by over $1 trillion in one year.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Look, folks, we can tackle these challenges, but we can’t do it without you.&nbsp; You understand what families are up against every time you walk down the street in your neighborhoods.&nbsp; You understand the cost if we fail to act.</p>



<p>We need your voices &#8212; the voices of local officials who understand what your communities need.&nbsp; Your senators and congressperson will listen to you all.</p>



<p>If you can get this done &#8212; we can get it done, there’s no limit to what America can achieve.</p>



<p>So let’s give working people the quality they deserve &#8212; the quality of life.&nbsp; Let’s face the challenge ahead and let’s keep building a better America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>We can do this!&nbsp; Thank you for taking the time.&nbsp; Love you all.&nbsp; Keep at it.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Thanks, everybody.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; Every time I’d walk out of my grandpop’s house up in Scranton, Pennsylvania &#8212; his name was Ambrose Finnegan &#8212; he’d yell, “Joey, keep the faith.”&nbsp; And my grandmother would yell, “No, Joey, spread it.”</p>



<p>Go spread the faith.&nbsp; Let’s get it done.&nbsp; Thank you. &nbsp;(Applause.)</p>



<p> 2:56 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 3665 and S.&#160;854</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/14/bills-signed-h-r-3665-and-s-854/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 21:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49086</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, March 14, 2022, the President signed into law: H.R. 3665, which designates the medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in San Diego, California, as the Jennifer Moreno Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center, and to support the designation of a component of such medical center in honor of Kathleen Bruyere. Thank&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, March 14, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>H.R. 3665, which designates the medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in San Diego, California, as the Jennifer Moreno Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Center, and to support the designation of a component of such medical center in honor of Kathleen Bruyere.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Mike Levin, Juan Vargas, Sara Jacobs, Darrell Issa, Scott Peters, and Julia Brownley for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 854, the &#8220;Methamphetamine Response Act of 2021,&#8221; which designates methamphetamine as an emerging drug threat and requires the Office of National Drug Control Policy to develop, implement, and make public a national response plan that is specific to methamphetamine.</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives  Scott Peters (D-CA-52), John Curtis (R-UT-03), Diana Harshbarger, Cindy Axne, and Josh Harder and Senators Dianne Feinstein and Chuck Grassley for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Alaska Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/14/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-alaska-disaster-declaration-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 21:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49076</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Alaska and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by the severe winter storm and straight-line winds during the period of January 1 to January 4, 2022. Federal funding is available&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Alaska and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by the severe winter storm and straight-line winds during the period of January 1 to January 4, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storm and straight-line winds in the Matanuska-Susitna Borough.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named Thomas J. Dargan as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments.</p>



<p>FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE  FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on National Equal Pay Day,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/03/14/a-proclamation-on-national-equal-pay-day-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 18:27:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49063</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Equal pay is a matter of justice, fairness, and dignity &#8212; it is about living up to our values and who we are as a Nation.&#160; For over 25 years, Equal Pay Day has helped draw attention to gender-based pay disparities by highlighting how far into a new year a woman must work, on average,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Equal pay is a matter of justice, fairness, and dignity &#8212; it is about living up to our values and who we are as a Nation.&nbsp; For over 25 years, Equal Pay Day has helped draw attention to gender-based pay disparities by highlighting how far into a new year a woman must work, on average, to earn what a man did in the previous year.</p>



<p>This year, Equal Pay Day falls on March 15, the earliest we have ever marked the occasion.  The earlier that Equal Pay Day arrives, the closer our Nation has come to achieving pay fairness.  But while we should celebrate the progress we have made, as I have said in the past, we should not be satisfied until Equal Pay Day is no longer necessary at all.</p>



<p>In 2020, the average woman working full-time, year-round, for wages or a salary earned 83 cents for every dollar paid to their average male counterpart.  And once again, the disparities are even greater for Black, Native American, Latina, and certain subpopulations of Asian women when compared to white men.  Disabled women also continue to experience significant disparities and make 80 cents for every dollar compared to men with disabilities.  The pay gap reflects outright discrimination as well as barriers that women face in accessing good-paying jobs and meeting caregiving responsibilities &#8212; including a lack of affordable child care, paid family and medical leave, and fair and predictable scheduling &#8212; which often prevent women from joining and staying in the workforce.</p>



<p> Over the course of a career, the pay gap can add up to hundreds of thousands of dollars in lost earnings, particularly for women of color, significantly impacting retirement savings and uniquely burdening households led by single mothers.</p>



<p> The Biden-Harris Administration has moved quickly to deliver results for women and working families and to dismantle the barriers that women face in the workplace.  In our first full year in office, we saw the largest calendar year decline in unemployment.  We also saw the strongest economic growth in nearly 4 decades, rising wages, and an estimated nearly 40 percent decline in child poverty.  We have turned the tide on women&#8217;s labor force participation, which the COVID-19 pandemic had pushed to a more than 30-year low.  In addition, my Administration has taken key steps to address pay discrimination, including issuing an Executive Order directing the Office of Personnel Management to take appropriate steps to advance equal pay at Federal agencies.  And I have raised the minimum wage for Federal contractors, which has significantly benefitted women &#8212; especially women of color &#8212; who are disproportionately represented in minimum-wage and low-wage jobs.</p>



<p>We can be proud of that progress &#8212; but there is more we need to do.  My Administration is fighting to ensure that women have the free and fair choice to organize and collectively bargain for the wages and benefits they deserve and to access training for good-paying jobs in sectors where they have historically been underrepresented.  We are working to eliminate anticompetitive barriers that keep women from bargaining for better pay and demanding dignity and respect in the workplace.  I have continued to call on the Congress to pass the Paycheck Fairness Act, which would help mitigate sex-based pay discrimination while ensuring greater transparency and reporting of disparities in wages.  And I am continuing to work with the Congress to pass critical legislation that would lower the cost of child care, elder care, home-based health care, and other major barriers to working families, while raising compensation for care workers, who are disproportionately women of color and who have been underpaid and undervalued for far too long.</p>



<p>If we are going to continue our record-breaking recovery and build a truly strong and competitive economy for the future, we have to address the barriers that have long held women back from full participation and fair treatment in the workforce.  The founding promise of our Nation is that all people are created equal &#8212; and my Administration is committed to ensuring that all Americans have a fair and equal opportunity to get ahead, so that one day soon we can render Equal Pay Day a relic of the past.</p>



<p>NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and the laws of the United States, do hereby proclaim March 15, 2022, as National Equal Pay Day.  I call upon all Americans to recognize the full value of women&#8217;s skills and their significant contributions to the labor force, acknowledge the injustice of wage inequality, and join efforts to achieve equal pay.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this fourteenth day of March, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Politburo Member Yang&#160;Jiechi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/14/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-politburo-member-yang-jiechi-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 18:26:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi in Rome, Italy. Their meeting followed up on the November 15, 2021 virtual meeting between President Biden and President Xi. Mr. Sullivan raised a range of issues in U.S.-China relations, with&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi in Rome, Italy. Their meeting followed up on the November 15, 2021 virtual meeting between President Biden and President Xi. Mr. Sullivan raised a range of issues in U.S.-China relations, with substantial discussion of Russia’s war against Ukraine. They also underscored the importance of maintaining open lines of communication between the United States and China.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bills Signed: H.R. 2545 and S.&#160;321</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/14/bills-signed-h-r-2545-and-s-321/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 16:17:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49059</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Monday, March 14, 2022, the President signed into law:&#160;H.R. 2545, which clarifies the roles and pay of doctors of podiatric medicine in the VA system.&#160; Thank you to Representatives Wenstrup, Mrvan, Suozzi and Schakowsky and Senators Cassidy and Sinema for their leadership. S. 321, the &#8220;Six Triple Eight&#8221; Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2022,&#8221;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Monday, March 14, 2022, the President signed into law:<br>&nbsp;<br>H.R. 2545, which clarifies the roles and pay of doctors of podiatric medicine in the VA system.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you to Representatives Wenstrup, Mrvan, Suozzi and Schakowsky and Senators Cassidy and Sinema for their leadership.</p>



<p>S. 321, the &#8220;Six Triple Eight&#8221; Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2022,&#8221; which provides for the award of a Congressional Gold Medal to the members of the Women’s Army Corps who were assigned to the 6888th Central Postal Directory Battalion, known as the &#8220;Six Triple Eight&#8221;.</p>



<p>Thank you to and Senators Jerry Moran and Jacky Rosen and Representatives Gwen Moore and Jake LaTurner for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at the 2022 International Women of Courage Award&#160;Ceremony</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/14/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-the-2022-international-women-of-courage-award-ceremony/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 15:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S. Department of State Washington, D.C. From soft lullabies to battle cries for justice, women nurse and nurture, teach and build, lead and dream our world forward—each and every day.&#160; Women have never been silent, but women have been silenced:&#160;with violence, with hate, discrimination, and isolation, with work and care that is never done. Women&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">U.S. Department of State</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">Washington, D.C.</p>



<p>From soft lullabies to battle cries for justice, women nurse and nurture, teach and build, lead and dream our world forward—each and every day.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Women have never been silent, but women have been silenced:&nbsp;with violence, with hate, discrimination, and isolation, with work and care that is never done.</p>



<p>Women have been told that they are dangerous. And that’s because they are—dangerous to corruption and injustice. When we raise our voices, we have the power to shatter the shields of oppression.</p>



<p>That’s why cowardly men stop girls from learning. It’s why women’s bodies become casualties of war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Like all of us, my heart has ached watching videos of Ukraine. Sick kids fleeing on makeshift medical trains, the unthinkable bombing of a maternity ward. Parents weeping over their children’s broken bodies in the streets. The senselessness is staggering.<br><br>We also know that there are horrors happening around the globe that never make the evening news. There are children’s broken bodies and women who bear the scars of war all around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there are women everywhere whose voices need to be heard — because stories are powerful. They shape our lives —defining the shades of our joy and sorrow, dividing what matters from the rest. They’re how we understand and connect to each other—beyond language, and distance, and time. They foster empathy and compel each of us to act.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I continue to teach writing at a nearby community college, and in my classes, I watch students find confidence when they lay their lives down on paper. I’ve seen them draw closer to one another when they share, realizing that their differences are precious and their similarities infinite. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The stories we tell matter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My husband, our President, knows that. He knows how the stories he heard from survivors of abuse kept him up at night, how they inspired him to write and champion the Violence Against Women Act.</p>



<p>He knows that women’s voices have been the heart of resistance to tyranny, and that no country that oppresses half of its population can thrive.</p>



<p>And he knows that the United States must lead a global community dedicated to stopping the corruption, and injustice, and brutality that silences women. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Because there can be no true democracy, no true peace, no true prosperity without women’s voices. There can be no history without our stories.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That’s why what we do here resonates far beyond these walls.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For 16 years, these awards have lifted up the voices of women around the world. It has shined light on the struggles and strength of women in the global North, South, East, and West. It has declared to all: The United States stands with these heroes. They are not alone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today, we honor twelve women—and we go further, giving them a platform to speak their truth in their own words. We recognize the power that they hold—to take on the most dire challenges of our time and move us all to do more.</p>



<p>When you hear their words, hold them close to your heart. Share them with your daughters and sons, and with everyone you know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tell their stories because they can inspire our world to rise to their courage.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tell them because women warriors everywhere need to hear what’s possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tell them because there is a sisterhood of girls who hold a universe of possibility within themselves, who need to know that the future belongs to them, too.&nbsp;</p>



<p>To all Women of Courage—those fighting injustice in Latin America or hoping to learn in the Middle East, working for democracy and stability in Europe, protecting their families in sub-Saharan Africa, or speaking out against gender violence in Asia—we will continue to work with passion and persistence, with development and democracy, to stop those who wish to silence you.</p>



<p>And we will tell your stories, even when you cannot.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan on Iran Missile Attack on Kurdistan Region of&#160;Iraq</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/13/statement-by-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivan-on-iran-missile-attack-on-kurdistan-region-of-iraq/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 01:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49045</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States condemns in the strongest terms Iran’s missile attack on the Kurdistan Region of Iraq. This attack targeted a civilian residence in Erbil, the Kurdistan Region’s capital city, without any justification. The United States stands with Prime Minister Kadhimi and the leaders of the Kurdistan Region, President Nechirvan Barzani, and Prime Minister Masrour Barzani,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The United States condemns in the strongest terms Iran’s missile attack on the Kurdistan Region of Iraq. This attack targeted a civilian residence in Erbil, the Kurdistan Region’s capital city, without any justification. The United States stands with Prime Minister Kadhimi and the leaders of the Kurdistan Region, President Nechirvan Barzani, and Prime Minister Masrour Barzani, in condemning this assault on the sovereignty of Iraq and its Kurdistan region. We will support the Government of Iraq in holding Iran accountable, and we will support our partners throughout the Middle East in confronting similar threats from Iran. The United States of America stands behind the full sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of Iraq. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with President Macron of&#160;France</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/03/13/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-president-macron-of-france/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:22:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=49042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France to discuss Russia’s war against Ukraine. They reviewed recent diplomatic engagements and underscored their commitment to hold Russia accountable for its actions and to support the government and people of Ukraine. ###]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with President Emmanuel Macron of France to discuss Russia’s war against Ukraine. They reviewed recent diplomatic engagements and underscored their commitment to hold Russia accountable for its actions and to support the government and people of Ukraine.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
