<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 19:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Press Secretary Jen&#160;Psaki￼</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/05/06/press-gaggle-by-press-secretary-jen-psaki%ef%bf%bc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 19:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Cincinnati, Ohio 12:31 P.M. EDT MS. PSAKI:&#160; So, welcome to our trip to Cincinnati.&#160; This is my last gaggle on Air Force One, so I have a lot of things to get off my chest.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; I’m just kidding. Okay, I wanted to give you guys a sense of the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Cincinnati, Ohio</p>



<p>12:31 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; So, welcome to our trip to Cincinnati.&nbsp; This is my last gaggle on Air Force One, so I have a lot of things to get off my chest.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’m just kidding.</p>



<p>Okay, I wanted to give you guys a sense of the week ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Sunday morning, the President will participate in a G7 virtual leaders meeting chaired by German Chancellor Scholz.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The leaders will be joined by President Zelenskyy of Ukraine.&nbsp; They will discuss the latest developments in Russia&#8217;s war against Ukraine, the global impact of Putin’s war, showing support for Ukraine and Ukraine&#8217;s future, and demonstrating continued G7 unity and our collective response, including building on our unprecedented sanctions to impose severe costs for Putin&#8217;s war.</p>



<p>On Monday, President Biden and Vice President Harris will deliver remarks from the Rose Garden on how the Biden-Harris administration is lowering the cost of high-speed Internet for millions of American families and expanding access through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.</p>



<p>Also Monday, the President will sign the Ukraine Democracy Defense Lend-Lease &#8212; Lend-Lease Act of 2022.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sorry.&nbsp; Next page.</p>



<p>On Tuesday, the President will welcome Prime Minister Mario Draghi of Italy to the White House.&nbsp; They will reaffirm the strong bilateral relationship between Italy and the United States.&nbsp; They will discuss their ongoing coordination with allies and partners on measures to support the people of Ukraine and impose economic costs on Russia for its unprovoked aggression.&nbsp; They will also discuss our close cooperation on promoting global economic prosperity, increasing Europe’s energy security, and combating climate change.</p>



<p>On Wednesday, the President will travel to Chicago, Illinois, to attend the 40th IBEW International Convention.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On Thursday, he will welcome the leaders of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, or ASEAN, to the White House for dinner.</p>



<p>On Friday, the President will participate in a summit with the ASEAN leaders at the State Department to recognize ASEAN’s central role in delivering sustainable solutions to the region&#8217;s most pressing challenges and commemorate 45 years of U.S.-ASEAN relations.</p>



<p>With that, let&#8217;s get to your questions.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just want to ask you: Congress has limited the President now on some of his &#8212; the administration’s biggest ideas.&nbsp; Build Back Better and the Voting Rights Act has been a frustration.&nbsp; And now, many in the base with &#8212; since the Alito leak &#8212; are eager for him to push for codifying Roe.&nbsp; But as you pointed out this week, easier said than done.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m just wondering: How is the President and the administration looking forward?&nbsp; Is there any sort of angst or frustration about the ability to deliver the big idea?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that the President is incredibly proud of what he has already accomplished to date in 15 months of his presidency.&nbsp; And not only did he get the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law passed, but 80 bills &#8212; bipartisan bills that he has helped lead the effort to move forward and sign into law.</p>



<p>And today he&#8217;s going to talk about the Bipartisan Infrastructure &#8212; or Innovation Act, and the need to move that forward in order to build more things in the United States, manufacture, make us more competitive here at home, and help address costs for the American people.</p>



<p>He was in the Senate for 36 years.&nbsp; He knows and understands it sometimes takes more time than he would like to get &#8212; to get his agenda forward, to get your agenda forward.&nbsp; He also understands that with such a slim majority in the Senate, it requires having either every single Democrat prepared to move forward on, say, the reconciliation package, which we&#8217;re still working to move forward, or it requires working in a bipartisan way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So while I&#8217;m not &#8212; while I’m not getting into politics here, I would just refer you and also point you to what the President said in his statement about the leaked document the other night, and how &#8212; and how having more senators and House members in Congress who support his agenda will help him move it forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, does the President want protesters to influence Supreme Court justices so that they uphold Roe?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; The President believes in peaceful protest.&nbsp; He believes that&#8217;s part of our democracy and part of the history of the United States and this country.&nbsp; But he also respects and understands the independence of the third branch of government, and &#8212; I mean, obviously, the Justice Department &#8212; but also the role of the Supreme Court and what they play.</p>



<p>So I wouldn&#8217;t say he has a view on that.&nbsp; He believes in peaceful protests, but they&#8217;re going to make decisions they make, and we&#8217;re not going to prejudge a final opinion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask a little bit about the Sunday meeting with the G7?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Sure.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is &#8212; sanctions are on &#8212; new sanctions are on the table.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us any sense of what kind of sanctions?&nbsp; Are these aimed at individuals, you know, big companies?&nbsp; Is it more about sort of clamping down on people evading the sanctions that are existing?&nbsp; What is the meeting about?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything to preview specifically on what&#8217;s next other than to say that all of those are steps that we&#8217;ve taken to date and we will continue to take to date.&nbsp; So, sanctioning additional individuals, additional companies, and also making sure we&#8217;re taking steps to prevent companies or others from evading the sanctions we&#8217;ve put in place.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I don&#8217;t have anything to preview at this point about what’s next.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does the President have a particular message to the rest of the G7 that he plans to deliver that was different from the previous meetings?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think it should not be lost &#8212; the significance &#8212; or on anyone &#8212; the significance of when the timeline &#8212; when his &#8212; when this G7 meeting is happening, which is the day before Russia&#8217;s Victory Day, which President Putin has certainly projected his desire to mark that day as a day where he is victorious over Ukraine.&nbsp; Of course, he&#8217;s not.&nbsp; While he expected to be marching through the streets of Kyiv, that’s obviously not what is going to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But certainly having this meeting and conversation on Sunday is an opportunity to not only show how unified the West is in confronting the aggression and the invasion by President Putin, but also to show that unity requires work; requires effort; requires blood, sweat, and tears sometimes.&nbsp; And the President is committed to continuing to engage to make sure people are unified &#8212; that these leaders are unified moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, finally, we understand many people are attending his speech to &#8212; or his event today.&nbsp; Representative Tim Ryan, who just won the nomination, is not planning on being here.&nbsp; Do you have any comment on that &#8212; his absence as the new Democratic nominee?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would just note they have been in touch.&nbsp; My understanding is Congressman Ryan has to attend a funeral and had other events he needed to attend.&nbsp; But the President remains in close touch with him; he’s obviously very supportive of him.&nbsp; And he&#8217;s looking forward to having both senators from Ohio there today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, does the President have a position on the &#8212; Senator Manchin’s efforts to do a bipartisan climate change bill?&nbsp; Is he aware of that specific bill and those efforts?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He&#8217;s certainly aware of them.&nbsp; And the President has long believed that there should be a bipartisan path forward for a range of his ideas, including the importance of addressing the climate crisis and doing more on that front.</p>



<p>We&#8217;re not going to prejudge those efforts.&nbsp; But at the same time, we&#8217;re not stalling or we&#8217;re not delaying our conversations with a range of members about attempting or working to move the reconciliation package forward.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And I know&nbsp;<a></a><a></a>that you’re not negotiating in public or with us but &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; can you give us any sense of where those talks stand with regard to climate in the reconciliation bill?&nbsp; It is the beginning of May.&nbsp; The window is closing.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Look, I would say that we made a decision, per the President’s direction, not to talk publicly about conversations he’s having or others are having on the Hill because we feel it’s more constructive that way.<br><br>What I can tell you is there is still a great deal of passion and engagement happening behind the scenes.&nbsp; The President is very focused on moving his climate agenda forward. And so he’s going to continue those conversations and continue working until we get it done.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And just one on abortion. &nbsp;Sorry, Franco.&nbsp; &nbsp;Can you give us a sense of whether or not the White House is in touch with women’s groups about this?&nbsp; What is your engagement?&nbsp; What is the level of, probably, both frustration and anger out there at the Supreme Court and perhaps at the White House about this?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I’m not aware of anger at the White House.&nbsp; Others could speak to that.&nbsp; Obviously, this is a leaked &#8212; not final &#8212; opinion from the Supreme Court.&nbsp; Right?&nbsp; So what our effort and our focus is on is on broadly engaging about the specifics on possible actions and preparing for the release of a final opinion when the &#8212; when that is released early this summer.<br><br>We are in conversations with a wide range of people, including women’s groups; including pro-choice activists; including folks inside of D.C., outside of D.C.; including business leaders; philanth- &#8212; philanthropy; members of Congress; state legislatures; governors; advocacy groups, across the board.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We’re using the convening power of the White House to talk to a broad range of groups.&nbsp; That effort is being led by the Gender Policy Council, which is coordinating work from the Department of Health and Human Services, from the White House Counsel’s Office, from a range of &#8212; from the &#8212; from the Domestic Policy Council, from a range of officials in the government, working to see what our options are and what levers we have in government.<br><br>I would note that we already took steps in reaction to S.B. 8 in Texas, and we will continue to build on them and prepare for a range of options.<br><br>I’d also note that today we saw &#8212; or yesterday, I should say &#8212; we saw that, in Connecticut, Governor Lamont signed a bill that will protect medical providers and patients seeking abortion care in Connecticut who may be traveling from other states that have outlawed abortion.&nbsp; And additionally, the law expands abortion access in Connecticut by expanding the type of practitioners eligible to perform certain abortion-related care.&nbsp;<br><br>So, we’re also here and available to states who are looking to take steps to protect women’s rights.&nbsp; Obviously, our pri- &#8212; our preference would be for Congress to codify Roe and, of course, for the final opinion not to look like the leaked opinion.<br><br>But we are also supportive of states.&nbsp; We’re going to work with a broad range of stakeholders as we prepare for a final opinion to be released.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Jen, can you talk a little bit more about the ASEAN Summit &#8212; what you hope to get out of that?&nbsp; Will that be &#8212; will one of the objectives be building the coalition against Moscow?&nbsp; How much of an objective will that be?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would note that there has been a broad response to the invasion of Ukraine by President Putin and the Russian military, including by a number of countries who are participating.&nbsp; So, certainly, the war in Ukraine will be a topic of discussion, but it’s also an opportunity to discuss security in the region; to discuss our fight against the pandemic, which is ongoing and important on the global front as well; and to discuss a broad range of issues &#8212; North Korea as well.&nbsp;<br><br>So it has a broad-ranging agenda.&nbsp; The President, as I noted earlier, will be participating in not just hosting a dinner on Thursday evening, but in a two-hour session on Friday afternoon to cover a range of topics.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On &#8212; more on Ukraine. &nbsp;There has been some discussion or some calls to cut, cancel, or reduce Ukraine’s foreign debt, kind of reduce their burden so they can put that money elsewhere.&nbsp; What’s the administration’s position on that?&nbsp; Does it have a position on whether or not there should be efforts to reduce Ukraine&#8217;s foreign debt?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It’s a good question.&nbsp; I’m happy to dig into it further.&nbsp; We’re very open to anything that would help the Ukrainians rebuild their country; obviously fight against the invasion of Russia.&nbsp; And we know that humanitarian and economic assistance that will take many forms &#8212; right?&nbsp;&#8212; is vital to them and to their success moving forward.&nbsp; And I can check if we have a specific view on the canceling of foreign debt.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And finally, from me, just &#8212; there’s language in the Ukraine supplementable [sic] &#8212; supplemental &#8212; excuse me &#8212; about Afghan adjustment for status.&nbsp; Can you talk &#8212; what’s the status of that?&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>This has been &#8212; this has been tried before and it didn’t make it in.&nbsp; Do you have the support?&nbsp; How important is that to the administration?&nbsp; What’s &#8212; what’s the status?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I don’t have an update on the status in Congress on it.&nbsp; I can also see if there’s an update we have from here.&nbsp; I’d really ask members &#8212;<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; How important is it for the White House to get it in now?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; As you noted, it’s something that we have supported in the past.&nbsp; But I &#8212; I can’t &#8212; there’s &#8212; there’s a lot of factors at play here, so I can’t &#8212; I can’t speak to that.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One the news that the House is voting on a resolution next week to &#8212; for congressional workers’ right to organize, does the White House have a position on that?&nbsp; Does the President take a position on that?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I can &#8212; I can check more into the specifics of it.&nbsp; I don’t think we&#8217;ve taken a specific position on it.&nbsp; Obviously, I haven&#8217;t looked at the details of it.&nbsp; The President has been a supporter of the right to organize, of collective bargaining for some time.&nbsp; But I&#8217;d have to look into more details of what the other components of it are.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On Ukraine, maybe, we&#8217;ve seen reports about how U.S.&nbsp;intelligence is helping the Ukrainians take out generals and ships.&nbsp; Is there a risk that those revelations could help the Russians in the sense that they go with the rhetoric of a proxy war and that this could lead to further escalation?<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, let me first say, to speak to the reports: They’re inaccurate.&nbsp; We did not provide Ukraine with specific targeting information for the Moskva.&nbsp; We were not involved in the Ukrainians’ decision to strike the ship or in the operation they carried out.&nbsp; We had no prior knowledge of Ukraine&#8217;s intent to target the ship.&nbsp; The Ukrainians have their own intelligence capabilities to track and target Russian naval vessels, as they did in this case.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And I&#8217;ve discussed this with both our National Security Advisor and the President, and the view is that, one, this is an inaccurate over-claiming of our role and an under-claiming of the role of the Ukrainians who, frankly, have a greater level of intelligence and access to intelligence than we do.<br><br>They take &#8212; we do provide a range of intelligence to help them understand the threat posed by Russian ships in the Black Sea and to help them prepare to defend themselves against potential sea-based assaults, but they take our intelligence and they combine that with what they have access to.&nbsp; And so, on this specific report, it’s just not an accurate depiction of how this happened.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Has the President tested in the last few days?&nbsp; There’s, sort of, such a surge post-White House Correspondents’ Association Dinner.<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; He is regularly tested, as you know.&nbsp; The last test I&#8217;m aware of was Tuesday.&nbsp; I can check if there has been an additional test.&nbsp; And he was obviously negative then.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What did we not ask you that you’re prepared to answer today, Jen?&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Oh, my gosh.&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; I don’t know, Jeff.&nbsp; What’s &#8212; what else is on your mind?<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can we ask you just on the job numbers &#8212;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.<br><br>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; today? &nbsp;You know, good job numbers, but with the Fed hike, are we seeing the end of the bump of, you know, just what the economy can do as a result of the Fed rate &#8212; pushing up the interest rates?&nbsp; And what’s the way forward from there?&nbsp;<br><br>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I’m not going to speak &#8212; I mean, the Fed and,&nbsp;obviously, Chairman Powell spoke to a lot of that earlier this week, so I&#8217;m going to let those comments stand.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>What I would note, though, is that, you know, the jobs numbers today &#8212; 428,000 jobs in April &#8212; bring the total number of jobs created by &#8212; under the President&#8217;s watch to 8.3 million.&nbsp; What he will talk about &#8212; which we are very encouraged by.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is also true that inflation is too high, that costs are too high.&nbsp; And what he will also talk about today is what we can do to address that.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And his view is that we need to do &#8212; take a couple of steps.&nbsp; One is, of course, lowering costs for families and taking steps like addressing the supply chain manufacturing goods in the United States, which the Bipartisan Innovation Act would help do.&nbsp; And launching the initiative he&#8217;s launching today &#8212; the administration is launching today &#8212; will help do &#8212; will help make sure that by manufacturing goods here, we&#8217;re lowering those costs.</p>



<p>Obviously, he&#8217;s taken a lot of steps to address energy costs, which we know is a major driver of inflation.&nbsp; And the other piece that he&#8217;s very focused on, that you&#8217;ve heard him talk about, is lowering the deficit.&nbsp; And he talked about, earlier this week, the revised Treasury &#8212; the data, which showed that we lowered the deficit &#8212; he lowered the deficit by $300 billion and on track to lower it by $1.5 trillion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you&#8217;ll hear him talk about all of that today.&nbsp; We know that&#8217;s on the minds of Americans.&nbsp; And we certainly understand that with an unemployment rate of 3.6 percent, that &#8212; you know, with that historically low number, that, you know, things will level.&nbsp; And we understand that and recognize that as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just a follow-up on &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; You said &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry, Aamer.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is there a sort of deadline/goal line for when the President wants to see the Bipartisan Innovation Act passed?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we know it&#8217;s in conference now, which is certainly a good sign.&nbsp; And he has been out there making the case in the country because he does believe that this is a piece of legislation that there is bipartisan support for it, there should be &#8212; because certainly manufacturing goods in the United States, making sure we&#8217;re not relying on the whims of a dictator, is to the advantage of all of the American people.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To follow-up on that topic broadly, is the White House concerned about the risk of recession?&nbsp; You hear more and more people using that word recently.&nbsp; Is that &#8212; to what extent is that on your radar, and is it a concern?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, we&#8217;re always looking at economic data, of course.&nbsp; But what we also look at is signs of strength in the economy, which is not just the jobs numbers and continued economic growth.&nbsp; It&#8217;s also &#8212; even in the GDP numbers earlier &#8212; was it earlier this week, or last week?&nbsp; It&#8217;s all running together. &nbsp;We saw business investment.&nbsp; We saw &#8212; we saw &#8212; the fact that the export numbers were down was actually because we are doing better than the rest of the world.</p>



<p>So, there is still a range of data that we look at and a lot of outside economists, frankly, look at to show where we are in the economy at this point in time.&nbsp; So, that&#8217;s not something we are predicting at this point.&nbsp; We know some people can make their own predictions on the outside, but we&#8217;re not assessing that or making that prediction at this point.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I ask you on the SPR? &nbsp;There was notice this week of the buybacks, but that&#8217;ll take some time.&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of the timeline on that?&nbsp; How quickly will the U.S. begin replenishing the barrels that it is drawing down over the next months?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah, that&#8217;s a good question.&nbsp; I mean, it was &#8212; as you noted, it was yesterday we announced the start of that process to replenish.&nbsp; So, we would have that ability to have the supply at a higher level so we could have it for the future.</p>



<p>I can check and see how &#8212; the length of time of that &#8212; what that will take.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The markets kind of jumped.&nbsp; They were thinking the U.S. was immediately buying it back, but it didn&#8217;t seem like that was the case.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s an overnight thing, but I will see if we have a timeline of that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Going back to COVID quickly: As someone referenced earlier, there&#8217;s been a spike of cases following the Correspondents’ Dinner.&nbsp; With the upcoming foreign trip, is the President taking any additional mitigation strategies to ensure that he can go on the trip, and, you know, make sure he doesn&#8217;t test positive before his next foreign trip?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I would first say that we have a range of strict protocols in the White House that go far beyond what the CDC requirements are, including the fact that everybody who is meeting with the President is tested, everybody who is traveling with him is tested.&nbsp; We take steps to make sure we&#8217;re socially distanced in meetings, and we wear masks in meetings with the President.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he, of course, is tested regularly.&nbsp; He went to the Correspondents’ Dinner to honor the work of all of you and your colleagues and made a decision &#8212; a risk assessment, like we all do every day, that that was important for him to do.</p>



<p>But beyond that, we&#8217;ll just continue the strict protocols we already have in place.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Speaking of international travel, is the U.S. considering lifting its testing requirements for people flying in?&nbsp; Other countries have started to pull back those sorts of measures.&nbsp; Is that on the table at all?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I&#8217;m not aware of a timeline for that.&nbsp; Obviously, we are &#8212; we are basing any decisions on the CDC and what their recommendations are.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The CDC said on May 3rd that they still recommend masking on airplanes.&nbsp; They did not say whether they would have extended that rule had the court not knocked it down.&nbsp; Because it would have &#8212; that would have been the sort of pivot point, regardless of the court ruling.</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you know whether they would have extended it regardless of that? &nbsp;And is there any update on the appeal that DOJ has stuck its foot in the door on?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I would really point at the Department of Justice.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve indicated their plans to appeal, and that has been the case for several weeks now.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t speak to what the CDC would or wouldn&#8217;t have done.&nbsp; Obviously, they made a decision, and we still have a masking require- &#8212; or recommendation in place.&nbsp; And &#8212; but, you know, it&#8217;s hard to get into a reverse hypothetical.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And, finally, can you give a sense: Does the President view the Roe v. Wade potential repeal, the issue more broadly, as a core message for Democrats heading into the midterms?&nbsp; And if so, or regardless, who does he think should be giving that message?&nbsp; Is it him?&nbsp; Is it the Vice President?&nbsp; Should, frankly, men be out in front on it?&nbsp; Should women be out in front on it?&nbsp; Does it matter?&nbsp; Who does he think &#8212; does he think Democrats should be leaning into this issue?&nbsp; And if so, who does he think should be leaning into it?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Well, I think you saw in his initial written statement that he spoke to, you know, the need to have more Democrats &#8212; pro-choice Democrats in Congress in order to codify Roe.&nbsp; And that spoke to his view of politics, without me getting into it too much.</p>



<p>I think his view is that it should be all of the above: him, the Vice President, any others.&nbsp; And, you know, as it relates &#8212; what was the last part of your question?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Does he think Democrats should make this a key issue, or is it sort of one of a range of issues?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yes, you heard the President, two days ago, talk about the Ultra-MAGA Agenda.&nbsp; And what he&#8217;s referring to there &#8212; yes, he spoke about Chairman Scott&#8217;s plan to raise taxes on people making less than $100,000 a year; he&#8217;s also talking about the advocacy by some in &#8212; elected officials, Republicans &#8212; to take away a woman&#8217;s right to make choices about her own body and make choices with their doctor.&nbsp; And his view is that is another example of the Ultra-MAGA Agenda as well.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is the timing of this trip just &#8212; you know, Tuesday, they had their primary.&nbsp; Is he going in part to also contrast the Democratic agenda versus what some of the people that may be coming in and what they&#8217;re offering?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; I think you will see him do a whole lot of that moving forward, but today is &#8212; his remarks are largely focused on making the case for the Bipartisan Innovation Act, how it would help us manufacture jobs in the United States, lower costs, make us more competitive.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One quick follow-up on Ukraine.&nbsp; Ukraine&#8217;s Ambassador to the U.S. told reporters yesterday that a definition of &#8220;victory&#8221; would include restoring sovereignty to Crimea and the Donbas region.&nbsp; Is that a definition the White House supports in terms of victory for Ukraine?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; We have long said that we would support the Ukrainians and their efforts through negotiations in a diplomatic process to determine what victory looks like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But I would say that, in our view, the victory or the definition of victory that President Putin outlined from the beginning &#8212; which was taking over Ukraine, taking over their territorial integrity, their sovereignty, dividing NATO, dividing the West &#8212; has been ineffective &#8212; has been ineffective. &nbsp;And, therefore, because President Putin will not be marching through the streets of Kyiv, we&#8217;ve already won in many ways.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President has also said he&#8217;s going to host his vaccine summit &#8212; his second vaccine summit on &#8212; next Thursday, the 12th.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; What is he hoping to get out of that?</p>



<p>MS. PSAKI:&nbsp; It&#8217;s an opportunity to lift up the need to continue to fight around the world to combat COVID, and the fact that our job is not done, there is great deal of work ahead.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States remains far and away the largest provider of vaccines and know-how to the global community.&nbsp; The world needs to continue to do more.&nbsp; It&#8217;s an opportunity to discuss that. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I think we should all sit down.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Thank you, everyone.</p>



<p>12:55 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-14/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52579</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve in key roles in his administration: Donald R. Cravins Jr., Nominee for Under Secretary for Minority Business Development, Department of Commerce David P. Pekoske, Nominee for Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, Department of Homeland Security Hugo F. Rodriguez Jr.,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>WASHINGTON – Today, President Biden announced his intent to nominate the following individuals to serve in key roles in his administration:</p>



<ul><li>Donald R. Cravins Jr., Nominee for Under Secretary for Minority Business Development, Department of Commerce</li><li>David P. Pekoske, Nominee for Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, Department of Homeland Security</li><li>Hugo F. Rodriguez Jr., Nominee for Ambassador to Nicaragua</li><li>Rosie Hidalgo, Nominee for Office on Violence Against Women Director, U.S. Department of Justice</li><li>Jonathan W. Burks, Nominee for Member, United States Institute of Peace</li><li>Michael K. Singh, Nominee for Member, United States Institute of Peace</li><li>Kathryn Wheelbarger, Nominee for Member, United States Institute of Peace</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Donald R. Cravins Jr., Nominee for Undersecretary of Commerce for Minority Business Development</u></strong></p>



<p>Donald R. Cravins, Jr. serves as the Executive Vice President and Chief Operating Officer at the National Urban League.&nbsp;Cravins graduated from LSU in 1994. Upon graduation, he attended&nbsp;the Southern University Law Center and obtained a juris doctorate in 1998. In 2004, he was elected to the Louisiana House of Representatives and inn 2006, he was elected to the Louisiana Senate. During his tenure in the Louisiana Senate, Cravins was heavily involved in post-Hurricanes Katrina and Rita business recovery issues as the Chair of the Insurance Committee.</p>



<p>In January 2009, Cravins left the Louisiana Legislature to serve as Staff Director and Chief Counsel for the United States Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. In that role, he was instrumental in the passage of the Small Business Jobs Act of 2010. In January 2013, he began serving as Chief of Staff for U.S. Senator Mary L. Landrieu of Louisiana.&nbsp;In addition to his duties at the National Urban League, Cravins is an adjunct professor at The George Washington University. He also serves as an officer in the District of Columbia Army National Guard. He is a Life Member of Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity, Inc. and a member of the 100 Black Men of Prince George&#8217;s County. Cravins’ honors include being inducted into the Southern University Law School Hall of Fame in 2018 and being named a&nbsp;Distinguished Alumnus of LSU in 2015. He and his family reside in Maryland.</p>



<p><strong><u>David P. Pekoske, Nominee for Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, U.S. Department of Homeland Security</u></strong></p>



<p>David Pekoske was confirmed by the U.S. Senate as the Transportation Security Administration’s seventh administrator in August 2017.&nbsp; He leads a workforce of over 60,000 employees and is responsible for security operations at nearly 440 airports throughout the United States.&nbsp; While serving as TSA Administrator, Pekoske also served at the Department of Homeland Security as Acting Secretary from January 20 to February 2, 2021, and as the Senior Official Performing the Duties of Deputy Secretary from April to November 2019 and again from February to June 2021.&nbsp; He was also a Commissioner on the Cyberspace Solarium Commission that developed a consensus on a strategic approach to defending the United States in cyberspace against attacks of significant consequence.</p>



<p>Before joining TSA, Pekoske was an executive in the government services industry, where he led teams that provided counterterrorism, security and intelligence support services to government agencies. Pekoske served as the 26th Vice Commandant of the U.S. Coast Guard, culminating a Coast Guard career that included extensive operational and command experience. As the Vice Commandant, Pekoske was second in command, also serving as Chief Operating Officer and Component Acquisition Executive of the Coast Guard. He is a recognized expert in crisis management, strategic planning, innovation and aviation, surface transportation and maritime security. In addition, he has been twice awarded the Homeland Security Distinguished Service Medal. Pekoske holds a Master of Business Administration degree from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, a Master of Public Administration degree from Columbia University and a Bachelor of Science degree from the U.S. Coast Guard Academy.</p>



<p><strong><u>Hugo F. Rodriguez, Jr., Nominee to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Nicaragua</u></strong></p>



<p>Hugo F. Rodriguez, Jr., a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as a Senior Advisor in the U.S. Department of State’s Bureau of Western Hemisphere Affairs.&nbsp; He was previously Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Western Hemisphere Affairs, and in 2021 assumed the role of Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary for the bureau.&nbsp; Before that, Rodriguez served as Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Asunción, Paraguay and as the Embassy’s Charge d’ Affaires a.i. from 2017 to 2018.&nbsp; Earlier, Rodriguez served as Consul General at the U.S. Embassy in Mexico City and as the Mission’s Acting Minister Counselor for Consular Affairs.&nbsp; He previously served as Deputy Director of the Office of Mexican Affairs, as Division Chief for the Western Hemisphere in the Bureau of Consular Affairs’ Overseas Citizen Services office, and as a Watch Officer and Senior Watch Officer in the Executive Secretariat’s Operations Center.&nbsp; Other overseas assignments include U.S. Embassies in Lima, Peru and Rome, Italy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A native of Pennsylvania, Rodriguez holds a Master’s degree in Business Administration from the Darden School of Business at the University of Virginia and a Bachelor of Arts degree in Economics from Hampden-Sydney College. The recipient of numerous State Department performance awards, Rodriguez speaks Italian and Spanish.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Rosie Hidalgo, Nominee for the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women, U.S. Department of Justice</u></strong></p>



<p>Rosie Hidalgo currently serves as Special Assistant to the President and Senior Advisor on Gender-Based Violence at the White House Gender Policy Council. She has worked in the movement to end gender-based violence for over 25 years as a public interest attorney and as a national policy advocate. Most recently, she was the Senior Director of Public Policy for Esperanza United, a national resource center with a focus on providing training, research, and policy advocacy to prevent and end domestic violence and sexual assault.&nbsp; Hidalgo previously served as the Deputy Director for Policy at the Office on Violence Against Women at the U.S. Department of Justice during the Obama-Biden Administration, and served on a detail to the Office of the Vice President, working with the White House Advisor on Violence Against Women.&nbsp; After law school, she worked as a Skadden Fellow providing direct legal services through non-profit organizations in New York and Virginia.&nbsp; Hidalgo also served on the Biden Foundation’s Advisory Council for Ending Violence Against Women, and on the American Bar Association’s Commission on Domestic and Sexual Violence.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Hidalgo received her Bachelor’s degree in Government and International Relations from Georgetown University and holds a J.D. from New York University School of Law, where she was a Root-Tilden Scholar.  She is married and has three children.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Johnathan W. Burks, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace</span></strong></p>



<p>Jonathan W. Burks is Vice President for Global Public Policy at Walmart, where he leads the global retailer’s efforts to analyze and develop positions on pressing public policy issues. Prior to joining Walmart, he was a partner at the global consultancy the Brunswick Group where he was the co-lead for the U.S. public affairs office. Before moving to the private sector, Burks served as the Chief of Staff to Speaker of the House Paul Ryan, a Policy Advisor on budget and appropriations issues to Senate Majority Leader Mitch McConnell, Policy Director of the House Budget Committee, Director of Legislative Affairs at the Securities and Exchange Commission, Senior Advisor to the Under Secretary of the Treasury for International Affairs, and Policy Advisor in the transition office of the newly created Director of National Intelligence. </p>



<p>Burks was the Deputy Policy Director on the 2012 Romney for President campaign. Earlier in his career, he served for four years at the White House, working first for Vice President Cheney and then for President Bush in a variety of positions, including as the Vice President’s Staff Secretary, Associate Staff Secretary to the President, and Special Assistant to the President for Policy in the Chief of Staff’s office.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Michael K. Singh, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace</span></strong></p>



<p>Michael K. Singh currently serves as Managing Director and Senior Fellow at the Washington Institute for Near East Policy, and Interim Director of the Institute’s Glazer Program on Great Power Competition and the Middle East.  Singh was Senior Director for Middle East Affairs at the National Security Council from 2007-2008, and a Director on the NSC staff from 2005-2007.  Earlier, he served as Special Assistant to Secretaries of State Colin Powell and Condoleezza Rice, and at the US Embassy in Tel Aviv.  He co-chaired the Congressionally-mandated Syria Study Group, and served on the Congressional Task Force on Extremism in Fragile States. In addition, Singh co-chaired Mitt Romney’s State Department transition team in 2012, and served as Middle East advisor to the Romney campaign.  Singh also serves on the “Welcome Council” of Welcome.US, a bipartisan initiative to empower Americans to welcome refugees.  Singh has been an adjunct fellow at the Belfer Center at Harvard’s Kennedy School of Government and an economics instructor at Harvard College. </p>



<p>Singh earned his bachelor’s degree in economics and Near Eastern studies from Princeton University and an MBA from Harvard Business School.&nbsp; He lives in Virginia with his wife, Kellie, and their two sons.</p>



<p></p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Kathryn Wheelbarger, Nominee for Member of the Board of Directors of the United States Institute of Peace</span></strong></p>



<p>Kathryn Wheelbarger is currently Vice President for Future Concepts at Lockheed Martin Government Affairs, where she leads a team focused on encouraging advanced technological solutions to global security challenges.  She previously served as Acting Assistant Secretary of Defense for International Security Affairs at the U.S. Department of Defense.  In that role, she was responsible for developing and advising the Secretary of Defense on defense policies related to the Middle East, Europe/NATO, Africa, the Western Hemisphere, and Russia and Eurasia.  For her service, she was awarded the Defense Distinguished Public Service Medal, the Defense Department’s highest civilian award.  Immediately prior to joining Lockheed Martin, she was a fellow with The Washington Institute. </p>



<p>From 2009 to 2017, Wheelbarger held several senior roles on Capitol Hill to include Policy Director on the Senate Armed Services Committee for Chairman McCain (R-AZ), Deputy Staff Director on the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence for Chairman Mike Rogers (R-MI), and Deputy Staff Director on the Energy and Commerce Committee for Ranking Member Joe Barton (R-TX).&nbsp; Earlier in her career, she served as Counsel to Vice President Dick Cheney and Associate General Counsel and Counselor to the Secretary at the Department of Homeland Security. Kathryn began her career clerking on the 9th Circuit Court of Appeals and litigating with two nationally recognized law firms.&nbsp; Raised in California, Wheelbarger &nbsp;graduated Summa Cum Laude from UCLA with a BA in Political Science and Cum Laude with a J.D. from Harvard Law School.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from President Joe&#160;Biden on the William T. Coleman, Jr. and Norman Y. Mineta Federal Building Act and Passing of Norman&#160;Mineta</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-the-william-t-coleman-jr-and-norman-y-mineta-federal-building-act-and-passing-of-norman-mineta/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This week, our nation lost an American hero and I lost a dear friend in Norman Mineta. Earlier today, I signed a bill to name the United States Department of Transportation headquarters in his honor, along with the late William T. Coleman, Jr. As a boy during World War II, Norm and his family were&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>This week, our nation lost an American hero and I lost a dear friend in Norman Mineta. Earlier today, I signed a bill to name the United States Department of Transportation headquarters in his honor, along with the late William T. Coleman, Jr.</p>



<p>As a boy during World War II, Norm and his family were cruelly confined in the Heart Mountain Relocation Center in Wyoming during America’s shameful period of Japanese Incarceration.&nbsp; Undaunted — and eternally hopeful — Norm was motivated by this early injustice to pursue a life of service.&nbsp; He was determined to ensure that the nation he loved lived up to its defining promise of liberty, equality, and justice for all — and he worked with grace and dignity to bring us closer to those ideals.</p>



<p>Norm will always be remembered for the many barriers he broke.&nbsp; He was the first Asian American to serve as Mayor of a major city — his beloved hometown of San Jose — as well as the first Asian American to serve in the Cabinet.&nbsp; Over two decades in the House of Representatives, Norm was a force of purpose and progress.&nbsp; He was the first chair of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus, and led passage of the landmark Civil Liberties Act of 1988 — legislation that, at long last, acknowledged and remunerated families like his own who had been incarcerated in camps during World War II.</p>



<p>But beyond his remarkable lifetime of accomplishments, I will remember Norm for his steadfast commitment to a belief he held dear: that America can accomplish anything when we come together.&nbsp; It is no accident that Norm was entrusted to lead Cabinet departments under both Democratic and Republican presidents — nor that some of his closest friendships in Congress were with members across the political spectrum.&nbsp; Norm treated everybody he met with equal dignity, and earned the respect of all who knew him.</p>



<p>Our thoughts are with Norm’s wife, Deni, his four children, his 11 grandchildren, and generations of constituents and staff who were inspired by the power of his example and who followed his lead in serving this nation.</p>



<p>May God bless Norman Mineta.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bill Signed: S.&#160;400</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/legislation/2022/05/06/bill-signed-s-400/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 15:16:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Legislation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52570</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Friday, May 6, 2022, the President signed into law: S. 400, the &#8220;William T. Coleman, Jr. and Norman Y. Mineta Department of Transportation Headquarters Act,&#8221; which designates the headquarters building of the Department of Transportation located at 1200 New Jersey Avenue, SE, in Washington, DC, as the William T. Coleman, Jr. and Norman Y.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On Friday, May 6, 2022, the President signed into law:</p>



<p>S. 400, the &#8220;William T. Coleman, Jr. and Norman Y. Mineta Department of Transportation Headquarters Act,&#8221; which designates the headquarters building of the Department of Transportation located at 1200 New Jersey Avenue, SE, in Washington, DC, as the William T. Coleman, Jr. and Norman Y. Mineta Federal Building.</p>



<p>Thank you to Senators Wicker, Cantwell, Carper, Capito, Tim Scott, Booker, Warnock, Inhofe, Duckworth and many others, and Representatives DeFazio and Carson for their leadership.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the April Jobs&#160;Report￼</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-april-jobs-report%ef%bf%bc/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 13:55:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52567</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, we learned that the economy created 428,000 jobs in April – bringing the total number of jobs created since I took office to 8.3 million: record setting job creation in my first 15 months in office.  Our plans and policies have produced the strongest job creation economy in modern times.  The unemployment rate now&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, we learned that the economy created 428,000 jobs in April – bringing the total number of jobs created since I took office to 8.3 million: record setting job creation in my first 15 months in office.  Our plans and policies have produced the strongest job creation economy in modern times.  The unemployment rate now stands at 3.6% —the fastest decline in unemployment to start a President’s term ever recorded. There have been only 3 months in the last 50 years where the unemployment rate in America is lower than it is now. This is a direct result of the American Rescue Plan, our COVID vaccination program, and my plan to grow our economy from the bottom up and middle out.  When I took office, there were around 20 million people relying on unemployment benefits to feed their families; today, that number is around 1 million – the lowest since 1970.   We are building an economy that values the dignity of work.<br> <br>There’s no question that inflation and high prices are a challenge for families across the country, and fighting inflation is a top priority for me. The continued strength of our job market and the savings that families have built up over the last year means that our economy faces the challenges of COVID-19, Putin’s unprovoked invasion of Ukraine, and global inflation from a position of strength. There’s more work to do. I encourage Congressional Republicans to join us in our efforts to lower prices for families across the country, by making more in America, strengthening our supply chains, and cutting the energy and prescription drug costs.<br> </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: Biden Administration Celebrates Launch of AM Forward and Calls on Congress to Pass Bipartisan Innovation&#160;Act</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/06/fact-sheet-biden-administration-celebrates-launch-of-am-forward-and-calls-on-congress-to-pass-bipartisan-innovation-act/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52357</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[AM Forward will help lower costs for American families by improving the competitiveness of America’s small-and-medium-sized manufacturers, creating and sustaining high-paying manufacturing jobs, and improving supply chain resilience through adoption of additive manufacturing President Biden’s top economic priority is to fight inflation by lowering costs that working families face, and lowering the federal deficit. One&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>AM Forward will help lower costs for American families by improving the competitiveness of America’s small-and-medium-sized manufacturers, creating and sustaining high-paying manufacturing jobs, and improving supply chain resilience through adoption of additive manufacturing</em></p>



<p>President Biden’s top economic priority is to fight inflation by lowering costs that working families face, and lowering the federal deficit.</p>



<p>One of the best ways to lower the cost of the goods and services that families rely on is to make more things in America, with more secure, resilient supply chains. We’ve learned this the hard way during this crisis – when brittle supply chains and hollowed out manufacturing resulted in backlogs, bottlenecks and higher prices for families.</p>



<p>President Biden’s plan to fight inflation addresses this problem head on. Thanks to the President’s leadership, we are in the midst of an American manufacturing boom with over $200 billion of investments in new manufacturing facilities and record-setting job creation. The Biden Administration has spurred unprecedented job growth and the fastest economic recovery in nearly four decades. Since taking office, President Biden’s actions have resulted in the creation of 7.9 million jobs, including 473,000 in manufacturing – more jobs in the first 14 months of any President’s term ever.</p>



<p>Companies are investing in America again, bringing good-paying manufacturing jobs back home. Whether it’s semiconductors, advanced batteries, or other leading sectors, companies are opening new facilities and announcing commitments to produce the world’s most cutting-edge technologies in the United States.</p>



<p>This is just the beginning of a broad revival of American industrial might. Continuing this momentum is key to easing price pressures throughout our economy and bringing inflation down. That is why the President is committed to making more in America, strengthening our supply chains, supercharging American leadership in the industries of the future, and lowering costs for families. That starts with the historic resources in the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which are rebuilding our roads, bridges, ports, airports, and making our businesses and workers more competitive globally. And we can take the next step by passing the Bipartisan Innovation Act, which will make generational investments in innovation, domestic manufacturing, and lowering prices through stronger supply chains.</p>



<p>AM Forward builds on that work and advances key Administration goals:</p>



<ul><li>More resilient and innovative supply chains, by investing in small and medium sized companies;</li><li>Growing industries of the future, overcoming coordination challenges that limit adoption of new technologies like additive manufacturing; and</li><li>Both inventing and making more in America, through investments in regional manufacturing ecosystems.</li></ul>



<p>Each of these goals is also advanced by the Bipartisan Innovation Act (BIA), which establishes a Supply Chain Office at the Department of Commerce, supports foundational technologies such as additive manufacturing, and invests in regional tech hubs as well as increasing funding for Manufacturing USA Institutes and the Manufacturing Extension Partnership.</p>



<p>Keeping pace with technological change should not be the capability of a few, or an over-the-horizon goal, out of reach for most of our manufacturing base. It should be a pillar of American industrial competitiveness – something that is broadly deployed and available to small and large companies alike. Enacting BIA will put important new technologies like additive manufacturing into the hands of entrepreneurs and companies across the country—raising the productivity and resilience of US manufacturers while lowering costs for American families. It is urgent that Congress acts quickly to pass the BIA, sending it to the President’s desk for his signature.</p>



<p>But not enough American companies are using 3D printing or other high-performance production technologies. That’s why President Biden is pleased to join several leading American companies to celebrate the launch Additive Manufacturing Forward (AM Forward), a voluntary compact between large, iconic manufacturers and their smaller U.S.-based suppliers. GE Aviation, Honeywell, Lockheed Martin, Raytheon, and Siemens Energy are the initial participants in AM Forward. These leading manufacturers will support their U.S.-based suppliers’ adoption of new additive capabilities, helping to transform shop floors across the country.</p>



<p>In additive manufacturing, producers transmit computer data to industrial 3D printers.&nbsp; In turn, these machines build parts on-demand, directly in suppliers’ own shops. Firms use this capability to reduce the number of parts required for an application, to make spare parts one at a time as needed, and design high-performing components in various industries ranging from aviation to medical devices</p>



<p>Through AM Forward, each of these iconic companies will make clear, <a href="https://www.astroa.org/amforward">public commitments</a> to purchase additively produced parts from smaller U.S.-based suppliers; train the workers of their suppliers on new additive technologies; provide detailed technical assistance to support their suppliers’ adoption of new capabilities; and engage in common standards development and certification for additive products.</p>



<p>Among other public commitments:</p>



<ul><li>GE Aviation will target small/medium sized suppliers to compete on 50% of the requests for quotes that are sent out on products made using additive or related technologies; and will target 30% of its total external sourcing of additively manufactured parts from U.S.-based SME suppliers.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Raytheon will seek SME manufacturers involvement in over 50% of its requests for quotes on products manufactured using additive technologies; the company will also seek to simplify and accelerate the procurement process of AM parts.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Siemens Energy will target to purchase 20-40% of total externally sourced AM parts and services from U.S.-based suppliers and partners. It will engage 10-20 U.S. SME suppliers to help improve their AM capability. And, it will also train 10-20 SME suppliers on inspection and post-processing best practices.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Lockheed Martin will work with its SME suppliers to conduct research to improve the performance of additive manufacturing AM techniques specifically focused on the use of 3D printing as an alternative to castings and forgings; and it will further participate in university and technical college programs for additive workforce development, including coursework and apprenticeship.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Honeywell will target U.S.-based SME suppliers to compete on request for quote packages sent out for products, machinery, manufacturing tooling, and/or manufacturing process development utilizing additive or related technologies. It will also offer technical assistance in part design, data generation, machine operation, post-processing, part inspection / quality management to its SME suppliers.</li></ul>



<p>AM Forward is a completely voluntary compact <a href="https://www.astroa.org/amforward">open to any OEM to participate</a>, provided they are willing to make public commitments to support their suppliers’ adoption of additive capabilities. It will be supported by Applied Science &amp; Technology Research Organization (ASTRO), a non-profit organization.</p>



<p>To support AM Forward, the Biden Administration has identified a range of federal programs that U.S. SME manufacturers can use to support their adoption of additive capabilities and increase their competitiveness. The Administration’s actions are focused on helping to overcome common challenges that have slowed the deployment of AM technologies, particularly among smaller manufacturers.</p>



<p>They include:</p>



<ul><li><em>Providing access to capital to our SME manufacturers: </em>Providing affordable financing to small manufacturers will support the installation of additive equipment by reducing its cost. To address this issue, the U.S. Department of Agriculture will make its Business and Industry program available to rural manufacturers to support the purchase of new additive machines, and the training necessary to upskill their workforce. The Export-Import Bank will highlight its new domestic lending program that can help SME manufacturers upgrade their existing production equipment. And the Small Business Administration will work with the participants of AM Forward on how its 504 Loan Program and Small Business Investment Company (SBIC) program can support the widespread deployment of new additive capabilities across U.S. industry.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Delivering </em><em>technical assistance from the federal government and OEMs to our SME manufacturers: </em>SME manufacturers have noted the need <a href="https://sites.lsa.umich.edu/stevensamford/wp-content/uploads/sites/552/2017/10/Samford-et-al-BAP-2017.pdf">for technical assistance</a> to utilize new production technologies like 3D printers to their fullest extent. To support AM Forward, the Department of Energy will make its Manufacturing Demonstration Facility at Oak Ridge National Laboratory available to SME manufacturers to test new additive techniques. The Manufacturing Extension Partnership will provide enhanced technical assistance; and the Department of Defense (DOD) will use its Mentor Protégé Program to reimburse the cost to the large OEM participants in AM Forward for providing technical assistance to their smaller U.S.-based suppliers owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals. DOD’s Manufacturing Technology Program Office will work with America Makes, a DOD-sponsored Manufacturing Innovation Institute, and AM Forward members on a pilot standardization project.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Investing in the additive manufacturing workforce</em>: To fully benefit from the use of additive capabilities, SME manufacturers must train their workforce differently to successfully deploy additive capabilities, including upskilling workers. America Makes will thus develop curriculum for workforce training with AM Forward participants; and, along with the U.S. Department of Labor, will assist manufacturers in launching apprenticeship programs in additive manufacturing.</li></ul>



<ul><li><em>Setting industry standards</em>: Finally, since 3D printing requires different standards and process certifications, the U.S. Department of Commerce – through the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) – will conduct measurement science research to overcome key barriers to widespread use of metals-based additive manufacturing, develop the technical basis for new high-priority standards, and disseminate these results to AM Forward participants through leadership of standards development within ASTM International, International Organization for Standardization (ISO), American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME), and other standards bodies.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vice President Harris Statement on the Passing of Norman&#160;Mineta</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/05/vice-president-harris-statement-on-the-passing-of-norman-mineta/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52538</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A son of California, Norm Mineta worked tirelessly to make America stronger, safer, and more just. Decades after experiencing the injustice of internment, he devoted his career to public service, serving in the U.S. Army and fighting for civil liberties for all.&#160;&#160;As the Mayor of San Jose, CA, Secretary Mineta saw the powerful role that&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>A son of California, Norm Mineta worked tirelessly to make America stronger, safer, and more just. Decades after experiencing the injustice of internment, he devoted his career to public service, serving in the U.S. Army and fighting for civil liberties for all.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>As the Mayor of San Jose, CA, Secretary Mineta saw the powerful role that infrastructure played in connecting individuals to economic opportunity and fought to get his community the resources they needed. This was a fight that he relentlessly continued through ten terms in Congress and as a Cabinet Secretary.<br>&nbsp;<br>Secretary Mineta laid the foundation for Asian American leaders across the nation and helped lead our nation&nbsp;through some of its most trying times. His leadership included the co-founding of the&nbsp;Asian Pacific American Institute for Congressional Studies and the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus, of which I was proud to be a member.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>I will cherish our conversations over the years. We all owe Secretary Mineta a debt of gratitude for his legacy of fighting to make this country live up to its promise.<br>&nbsp;<br>The Second Gentlemen and I are holding Secretary Mineta’s wife Danealia, and his entire family in our hearts.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks By President&#160;Biden and First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at a Cinco De Mayo&#160;Reception</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/05/remarks-by-president-biden-and-first-lady-jill-biden-at-a-cinco-de-mayo-reception/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 23:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[4:47 P.M. EDT THE FIRST LADY:&#160; Thank you.&#160; And welcome to the White House!&#160; (Applause.) AUDIENCE MEMBER:&#160;&#160;La Casa Blanca!&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; THE FIRST LADY:&#160; Yes! The Battle of Puebla, which Cinco de Mayo celebrates, lasted for only a single day.&#160; Defending the small town of central Mexico wasn’t a major strategic victory in the Franco-Mexican War.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>4:47 P.M. EDT<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; And welcome to the White House!&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp;&nbsp;<em>La Casa Blanca</em>!&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Yes!<br><br>The Battle of Puebla, which Cinco de Mayo celebrates, lasted for only a single day.&nbsp; Defending the small town of central Mexico wasn’t a major strategic victory in the Franco-Mexican War.&nbsp; But the fact that a rag-tag group of soldiers, outnumbered 3 to 1, could defeat Napoleon’s French Foreign Legion was a victory of the heart.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>It showed the determination and the backbone of the Mexican people.&nbsp; It inspired other cities to believe that they, too, could stand against the odds.<br><br>And the reverberations of that battle traveled north to the United States.<br><br>This holiday reminds us that the threads of our history and our heritage are woven together.&nbsp; We inspire one another.&nbsp; We shape each other.<br><br>Our relationship with Mexico is special.&nbsp; And I’m so grateful to be joined today by the First Lady of Mexico &#8212; (applause) &#8212; Dr. Gutiérrez &#8212; Beatriz.&nbsp; From our love of poetry and literature to our shared passion to education, we have so much in common.<br><br>You know, Joe always says that politics is personal, and I’m grateful to continue building our friendship.&nbsp; Actually, we already have plans for what we’re going to do next time we’re together.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Ooh.&nbsp; (Laughs.)<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know if you’re invited, Joe.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Don’t think I am.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; It’s not only our history that is tied to Mexico, but our future as well.&nbsp; We are stronger when we face the challenges of our modern world together.&nbsp;<br><br>And when we recognize our shared heritage, we can better understand and celebrate the true beauty and diversity of America.<br><br>A few years ago, at the National LULAC Conference, I met with a young group of Mexican Americans and other Latino leaders.<br><br>They told me about the issues that were on their minds: education, climate change, healthcare, and jobs &#8212; just like anyone their age.&nbsp; But what struck me was that they said that they didn’t often feel seen or heard.&nbsp;<br><br>And that touched my heart.&nbsp; Don’t we owe them better?<br><br>Since then, I’ve held conversations to hear from different generations of Latinos from across this country.<br><br>And again and again, I’ve seen the unique gifts of this community &#8212; the common threads that tie us together.<br><br>I’ve been reminded that our differences are precious and that our similarities infinite.<br><br>The former Poet Laureate of the United States and a proud Chicano &#8212; did I say that right?<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yeah!<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; Oh, I should ask you.&nbsp;<br><br>Juan Felipe Herrera once said: “Diversity really means becoming complete as human beings &#8212; all of us.&nbsp; We learn from each other.&nbsp; If you’re missing on that stage, [you] learn less.&nbsp; We all need to be on that stage.”&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>The White House &#8212;&nbsp;<em>Casa Blanca</em>&nbsp;&#8212; (laughter) &#8212; is the People’s House &#8212; your house.&nbsp; And the story of America is the story of you, the story of all of us.<br><br>So, thank you for helping us celebrate our nation’s Mexican American heritage today.&nbsp; And Happy Cinco de Mayo!&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And now, my husband, your President, and mine: Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; We love you, Joe!&nbsp; We really do.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I&#8217;m glad some woman in this crowd loves me.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>Well, thank you, Jill.&nbsp; I&#8217;m honored to welcome all of you to the White House, especially our distinguished guest, the First Lady. &nbsp;I&#8217;m going to go down and say hi.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>(The President shakes the hand of First Lady Gutiérrez Müller.)<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Jill doesn’t let me get in these conversations, so I want to &#8212; (laughter) &#8212;&nbsp;<br><br>And Secretary of Education Miguel Cardona. &nbsp;Where are you, Miguel?&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Yeah, where is my Mig- &#8212;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; He&#8217;s here.&nbsp; There he is.&nbsp; He&#8217;s educating people in the back.&nbsp; There you go.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Oh, hi!&nbsp; Hi, Miguel.&nbsp;<br><br>Did you see Naomi too?<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Did I &#8212;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Naomi.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I didn&#8217;t see Naomi.&nbsp;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; She&#8217;s over here.&nbsp; How can you miss her?&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, I &#8212; I&#8217;ll tell you what &#8212; hi, Naomi.&nbsp; How are you?&nbsp; That&#8217;s my granddaughter.&nbsp; My oldest &#8212; our oldest granddaughter and &#8212;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; And her fiancé.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; and her &#8212; I can&#8217;t see.&nbsp;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; And Peter.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And Peter.&nbsp;<br><br>You all have to know all this, you know?&nbsp; It&#8217;s really important.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>Secretary of Interior Deb Haaland.&nbsp; Where&#8217;s Deb?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; She&#8217;s here.&nbsp; Deb, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.<br><br>And one of my best buddies when we served together and, I think, probably one of the best ambassadors we&#8217;ve ever had to Mexico or anywhere else: Ken Salazar.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>Madam First Lady, we were campaigning &#8212; and this is off-script here, I know &#8212; but we were campaigning when I was seeking the vice presidency with President Obama, and we were in western &#8212; eastern Colorado.&nbsp; And we were about to walk out, and we were at a beautiful renovated railroad station and a railroad that is no longer functioned as a interstate railroad, but it was magnificent.&nbsp;<br><br>And he kept telling me &#8212; he said, &#8220;Now, look, Joe, there&#8217;s a couple of thousand people across the track.&#8221;&nbsp; And he said, &#8220;They’re Latinos, so you got to be get- &#8212; you got to be &#8212; you got to be respectful.&#8221;&nbsp; And I&#8217;m like, &#8220;I&#8217;m not going to respectful?&#8221;&nbsp; And &#8212; and I said &#8212; he said, &#8220;And you don&#8217;t understand about &#8212; about prejudice.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t unders- &#8212; you don&#8217;t get it.&#8221;&nbsp; And I listened to him and listened.&nbsp; And finally &#8212; then he pointed out &#8212; he said, &#8220;Look, my family has been here 400 years.&#8221;&nbsp; And I said, &#8220;Well, mine has not been here that long.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s any &#8212; anywhere…” &#8212; anyway, so, we talked a little bit longer.&nbsp; And he kept talking about, &#8220;Be careful.&#8221;&nbsp; Remember this?&nbsp;<br><br>In this beautifully renovated station.&nbsp; I mean, it was gorgeous.&nbsp; And it was about the size of &#8212; I don&#8217;t know &#8212; it’s is from here to the far hedge, and about halfway into the crowd &#8212; about 30, 40 feet wide.&nbsp; And there was nothing in there except there was linden wallpaper.&nbsp; And there were these brass plaques about every six or eight feet around the entirety of the &#8212; of the reception room.&nbsp; And I said, &#8220;I think…&#8221; &#8212; I said, &#8220;I genuinely understand.&#8221;&nbsp; He said, &#8220;No.&#8221; &nbsp;I said &#8212; I turn, I said, &#8220;Take a look what they say.&nbsp; It says, &#8216;No Irish allowed.'&#8221;&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; &#8220;No Irish allowed,&#8221; because it was renovated to exactly what it was in 1869.&nbsp;<br><br>So, I don&#8217;t really know, but anyway, I just wanted to remind &#8212;<br><br>But, Ken, you&#8217;re one of the best ambassadors I think we have anywhere in the world.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>You know, along with all the mayors &#8212; how many mayors are here today &#8212; American mayors?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; Wow.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; And how many diplomats are here from various parts of the world?&nbsp;&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You can raise your hand.&nbsp; It&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; You don&#8217;t want to be seen.&nbsp; It&#8217;s like, &#8220;You know, I don&#8217;t know.&#8221;&nbsp; I&#8217;m not sure he wants to &#8212; you know.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And how many advocates and community leaders are here?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; All right.&nbsp;<br><br>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Teachers!<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Oh, teachers.&nbsp; I &#8212; you know, I sleep with a teacher every night.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Same one.&nbsp; The same one.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; If I didn’t like teachers, I’d be sleeping alone.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I’d be &#8212;<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; You’re a teacher too.&nbsp;<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; &#8212; in a different place.&nbsp;<br><br>As Jill said: Cinco de Mayo is a day to celebrate freedom and resilience, and, you know, it’s also day to celebrate friendship.&nbsp;<br><br>And President López Obrador, when &#8212; he was kind enough to come up and see me here in the Oval and the White House in November.&nbsp; And he pointed to a patriot &#8212; a &#8212; excuse me, a portrait over the mantle of the &#8212; of the &#8212; in the White House, in the Oval Office.&nbsp; And it’s a picture of &#8212; it’s a big portrait of Franklin Delano Roosevelt hanging on the wall.&nbsp; And he told me that he liked Roosevelt because he was the President who initiated the Good Neighbor Policy between our two nations.&nbsp; We talked about that for a while.<br><br>And I told him that today the United States and Mexico are more than good neighbors; we’re genuine, true friends, partners.&nbsp; And there’s an unshakable bond strengthened by mutual respect and our shared commitment to the prosperity and security of both our nations.&nbsp;&nbsp;It’s not our backyard; it’s our front yard.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you very much, Madam<s>President</s>&nbsp;[First Lady].&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>Those bonds are further strengthened by our shared history and heritage &#8212; culture, pride, and countless contributions of Mexican Americans, and the heritage and culture of an essential part of the American culture.&nbsp; It’s just &#8212; it’s just part of American culture.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And that’s why I made it a priority to build a government that looks like America, including the most diverse Cabinet ever assembled &#8212; including, by the way, two Mexican Americans: Xavier Becerra, as &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the Department of Health and Human Services, as well as Isabel Guzman, who is leading the Small Business Administration.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; And many, many more folks throughout the administration.<br><br>Beyond &#8212; beyond representation, we’re also focused on delivering results for Latino families.&nbsp;<br><br>Through the American Rescue Plan, our vaccination effort and our &#8212; was centered on equity and ensured that Latinos were vaccinated at the same rate everyone else was.&nbsp; As a matter of fact, they’re vaccinated at a slightly higher rate than everyone else was.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>And to make sure relief checks were delivered to 1,400,000 spouses and nearly 3,700,000 children of mixed status families where mom or dad is a citizen.&nbsp; Because every family deserves food on the table, a roof over their head, and a little breathing room.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>We cut the Latino child poverty rate by an estimated 40 percent because of the Child Tax Credit.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>And we surged funding to community health centers, which disproportionately serve Latino communities.<br><br>And, by the way, I met last week at the White House with five incredible Latino entrepreneurs.&nbsp; They’re part of an amazing story &#8212; a boom of new small businesses in America.<br><br>In America today, there are more new small businesses being created and small business creation &#8212; more jobs than ever before.&nbsp; And Latino entrepreneurs are leading the way, starting new businesses last year at the fastest rate in more than a decade &#8212; 23 percent faster than the pre-pandemic levels.&nbsp;<br><br>The reason I mention this is it’s a big deal.&nbsp; The prosperity and jobs for Latino communities affects everybody.&nbsp;<br><br>And we’re working to fix our immigration system as well.&nbsp; As I said &#8212; (applause) &#8212; it’s important.&nbsp; As I said in my State of the Union Address, we can secure our borders and keep lit the torch of liberty.<br><br>On my first day in office, I sent an immigration bill to Congress that would provide a pathway to citizenship for immigrants contributing to our economy.&nbsp; That’s &#8212; we are &#8212; we &#8212; you know, we are an immigrant nation.&nbsp; I mean, we &#8212; we litera- &#8212; I mean, we say that, but people act like they don’t believe it.&nbsp; We are an immigrant na- &#8212; and that is our strength.&nbsp; That is our strength.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>But if Congress won’t act on broader reform, let’s pass the bills that have bipartisan support &#8212; for DREAMers and those&nbsp;Temporary Protected Status farm workers, essential workers.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; It’s not only the right thing to do but it’s, economically, the smart thing to do as well.<br><br>And most of all, we’re going to continue to fight for the rights and opportunities and dignity of Mexican Americans and all Latinos in America.&nbsp;<br><br>I might point out &#8212; and Jill and I talk about this: If we don’t get smart in this country, and the other team doesn’t understand what’s going on &#8212; you know, 25 out of every 100 children in grades kindergarten through senior in high school speak Spanish.&nbsp; Twenty-five out of every one hundred.&nbsp; It’s overwhelmingly in the interest not only of those kids, but of all Americans that we invest &#8212; we invest in the community.&nbsp; And we’ll conquer and honor and lift up all those folks who, in fact, are &#8212; have gotten in the way.<br><br>You know, Mexican American culture is a great contribution for &#8212; to America.&nbsp;<br><br>And soon we’ll also see the broader Latino community culture celebrated through the creation of the newest Smithsonian Museum &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the National Museum of the American Latino.&nbsp; It’s a big deal.&nbsp; And I look forward to seeing it take its rightful place here in Washington to help share the remarkable stories and incredible contributions our Latinos have contributed to this nation &#8212; the entire Latino community.&nbsp; And for now, though, let’s celebrate today.&nbsp; Let’s celebrate today.<br><br>And I just want you to know &#8212; I can’t tell you how much we’re looking forward to this day.&nbsp; I’m glad it held off.&nbsp; Thank you, God.&nbsp; (Laughter.)<br><br>But I hope &#8212; I hope you all have a good time today.&nbsp; And, again, Madam First Lady, you’re welcome here.&nbsp; And I want to take you in and show you my office too, if you’d come.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp; I’ll you show you Franklin Roosevelt, okay?&nbsp;<br><br>Well, thank you all.&nbsp; God bless you.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>5:01 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Presidential Delegation to the Republic of Costa Rica to Attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Rodrigo Alberto de Jesús Chaves&#160;Robles</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/05/president-biden-announces-presidential-delegation-to-the-republic-of-costa-rica-to-attend-the-inauguration-of-his-excellency-rodrigo-alberto-de-jesus-chaves-robles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 21:04:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52516</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to San José, Costa Rica to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Rodrigo Alberto de Jesús Chaves Robles as President of the Republic of Costa Rica on May 8, 2022. The&#160;Honorable Miguel Cardona, United States Secretary of Education,&#160;will lead the delegation. Members&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. today announced the designation of a Presidential Delegation to San José, Costa Rica to attend the Inauguration of His Excellency Rodrigo Alberto de Jesús Chaves Robles as President of the Republic of Costa Rica on May 8, 2022.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;Honorable Miguel Cardona, United States Secretary of Education,&nbsp;will lead the delegation.</p>



<p><strong><u>Members of the Presidential Delegation:</u></strong></p>



<p>The Honorable Cynthia Telles, United States Ambassador to the Republic of Costa Rica</p>



<p>The Honorable Uzra Zeya, Under Secretary for Civilian Security, Democracy, and Human Rights, U.S. Department of State</p>



<p>The Honorable Cristóbal Alex, Special Assistant to the President and White House Deputy Cabinet Secretary</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with Chancellor Scholz of&#160;Germany</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/05/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-chancellor-scholz-of-germany/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 20:32:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=52510</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany.  The leaders underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected by the violence.&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. spoke today with Chancellor Olaf Scholz of Germany.  The leaders underscored their commitment to continue holding Russia accountable for its brutal actions in Ukraine, and reviewed their ongoing efforts to provide security assistance to the government of Ukraine and humanitarian aid to the millions of Ukrainians affected by the violence. The President welcomed Germany’s provision of security assistance and recent pledge of additional humanitarian aid, as well as their close partnership throughout this crisis.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
