<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 17:20:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Readout of Senior Administration Travel to Hawaii, Fiji, Papua New Guinea, and Solomon&#160;Islands</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/22/readout-of-senior-administration-travel-to-hawaii-fiji-papua-new-guinea-and-solomon-islands/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 15:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On April 22, a high-level U.S. delegation – led by National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell, Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink, Deputy Commander INDOPACOM&#160;Lieutenant General&#160;Stephen Sklenka , and USAID Acting Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator for Asia Craig Hart – visited Honiara, Solomon Islands. The delegation met for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>On April 22, a high-level U.S. delegation – led by National Security Council Indo-Pacific Coordinator Kurt Campbell, Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs Daniel Kritenbrink, Deputy Commander INDOPACOM&nbsp;Lieutenant General&nbsp;Stephen Sklenka , and USAID Acting Senior Deputy Assistant Administrator for Asia Craig Hart – visited Honiara, Solomon Islands. The delegation met for ninety minutes with Prime Minister&nbsp;Manasseh&nbsp;Sogavare, along with two dozen members of his cabinet and senior staff. While there, the delegation also met with prominent religious leaders on the island and with key members of the political opposition.</p>



<p>This visit to&nbsp;Solomon Islands was the final leg of the delegation’s trip across the Pacific. It followed stops in Hawaii, where the delegation met with senior officials from Australia,&nbsp;Japan,&nbsp;and New Zealand; Fiji, where they met with Prime Minister&nbsp;Frank&nbsp;Bainimarama, as well as&nbsp;leadership of the Pacific Island Forum, and held the&nbsp;U.S.-Fiji Strategic Dialogue; and Papua New Guinea, where they met with Prime Minister James Marape and senior defense officials to discuss ways to enhance security ties. Across these engagements, the United States reiterated that it will seek to further deepen our enduring ties with&nbsp;the Pacific Islands&nbsp;and take tangible&nbsp;steps to advance a free, open, and resilient Indo-Pacific. The United States will do so by fulfilling and strengthening its commitments in the region, working to advance regional unity, coordinating with allies and partners on meeting twenty-first century challenges, and protecting the sovereignty of Pacific Island states.</p>



<p>In the meeting with Solomon Islands’ Prime Minister Sogavare, the delegation reiterated the key priorities animating the trip and also outlined specific steps&nbsp;the United States&nbsp;would take to advance the welfare of the people of&nbsp;Solomon Islands. The United States will expedite the opening of an embassy in&nbsp;Solomon Islands; advance cooperation on unexploded ordinance; launch a program on maritime domain awareness; dispatch the Mercy hospital ship to address public health; advance a dialogue on the return of the Peace Corps; deliver additional vaccines;&nbsp;and advance initiatives on&nbsp;climate, health,&nbsp;and people-to-people ties.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States respects the right of nations to make sovereign decisions in the best interests of their people. The two sides engaged in substantial discussion around the recently&nbsp;signed&nbsp;security agreement between&nbsp;Solomon Islands and the People’s Republic of China (PRC). Solomon Islands representatives indicated that the agreement had solely domestic applications, but the&nbsp;U.S. delegation noted&nbsp;there are potential regional security implications of the accord, including for the United States and its allies and partners. The U.S. delegation outlined clear areas of concern with respect to the purpose, scope, and transparency of the agreement.</p>



<p>If steps are taken to establish a de facto permanent military presence, power-projection capabilities, or a military installation, the delegation noted that the United States would then have significant concerns and respond accordingly. In response to these enumerated concerns, Prime Minister Sogavare reiterated his specific assurances that there would be no military base, no long-term presence, and no power projection capability, as he has said publicly. The United States emphasized that it will follow developments closely in consultation with regional partners.</p>



<p>At this critical juncture, the United States and Solomon Islands agreed to launch a high-level strategic dialogue, co-chaired on the U.S. side by the White House and the Department of State. Its purpose will be to enhance communication, address mutual concerns, and drive practical progress. In particular, both sides agreed to discuss in greater detail security issues of mutual concern, economic and social development, public health, and finance and debt. Each side committed to take the necessary steps in the intervening period to prepare for a successful engagement.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden Signs Executive Order to Strengthen America&#8217;s Forests, Boost Wildfire Resilience, and Combat Global&#160;Deforestation</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/22/fact-sheet-president-biden-signs-executive-order-to-strengthen-americas-forests-boost-wildfire-resilience-and-combat-global-deforestation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51591</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New actions will protect against wildfire threats, support local economies, and reduce climate pollution Today, on Earth Day, President Biden will sign an Executive Order to expand his Administration’s historic and bold efforts to tackle the climate crisis, make our nation more resilient to extreme weather, and strengthen local economies. The President will sign the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>New actions will protect against wildfire threats, support local economies, and reduce climate pollution</em></p>



<p>Today, on Earth Day, President Biden will sign an Executive Order to expand his Administration’s historic and bold efforts to tackle the climate crisis, make our nation more resilient to extreme weather, and strengthen local economies. The President will sign the Executive Order in Seattle, Washington—rounding out a trip across the West focused on lowering costs for families and protecting communities from intensifying climate impacts. Wildfires and extreme weather events are growing in frequency and ferocity, engulfing communities in the West and across the country and costing lives, homes, and money. Because President Biden knows the cost of inaction is too great, he is taking bold executive action and reaffirming his calls on Congress to address the climate crisis. &nbsp;</p>



<p>America’s forests are a key climate solution, absorbing carbon dioxide equivalent to more than 10% of U.S. annual greenhouse gas emissions. Federal lands are home to many of the nation’s mature and old-growth forests, which serve as critical carbon sinks, cherished landscapes, and unique habitats. However, these magnificent ecosystems are threatened by the climate impacts that are already here, with intensifying wildfires demanding urgent action to protect our forests and the economies that depend on them. The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides historic wildfire resilience funding and calls for prioritizing the restoration of old-growth forests.</p>



<p>Building on this directive and the Administration’s commitment to climate-smart forest stewardship, today’s Executive Order will:</p>



<ul><li><strong>Safeguard mature and old-growth forests on federal lands</strong>, as part of a science-based approach to reduce wildfire risk.</li><li><strong>Strengthen reforestation partnerships across the country</strong> to support local economies and ensure we retain forest ecosystems and sustainable supplies of forest products for years to come.</li><li><strong>Combat global deforestation</strong> to deliver on key COP26 commitments.</li><li><strong>Enlist nature to address the climate crisis</strong> with comprehensive efforts to deploy nature-based solutions that reduce emissions and build resilience.</li></ul>



<p>Across these efforts, the Administration will leverage historic investments from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and the FY 2022 budget, and work in partnership with states, Tribal Nations, communities, industry, NGOs, labor, scientists, and private landowners, to strengthen our forests while creating good-paying jobs.</p>



<p>Today’s Executive Order will advance the Biden-Harris Administration’s climate goals and economic agenda by:</p>



<p><strong><u>Reducing Wildfire Risk</u></strong></p>



<p>Under President Biden’s leadership, the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s (USDA) Forest Service has developed a <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/01/18/secretary-vilsack-announces-new-10-year-strategy-confront-wildfire">10-year strategy</a> to reduce wildfire risk through science-based fuels and forest health treatments, with a goal of treating an additional 50 million acres across federal and non-federal lands. The Department of the Interior (DOI) has also developed a <a href="https://www.doi.gov/pressreleases/interior-department-releases-five-year-monitoring-maintenance-and-treatment-plan">5-year plan</a> for monitoring, maintenance, and treatment efforts focused on fire-prone Interior and Tribal lands.</p>



<p>As a critical down payment, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides $8 billion to fund forest and land management activities, and the FY 2022 Omnibus provides $5.7 billion for wildland fire management and related risk mitigation and research. USDA and DOI are mobilizing $5 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law for hazardous fuels reduction and other mitigation programs, such as a $1 billion Community Wildfire Defense Grant program and $600 million for firefighter pay—providing about 1,500 additional firefighters and supporting the President’s commitment that no federal firefighter will make less than $15 an hour. Already, USDA has <a href="https://www.fs.usda.gov/news/releases/biden-administration-announces-bipartisan-infrastructure-law-wildfire-mitigation">announced</a> $131 million this year for wildfire risk reduction treatments in high-risk landscapes in Washington, Oregon, California, Idaho, Montana, Colorado, New Mexico, and Arizona.</p>



<p>The Bipartisan Infrastructure Law directs DOI and USDA to specifically prioritize the restoration of old-growth forests, taking into consideration their contributions to landscape fire adaptation. However, there is currently no inventory that identifies the location and condition of mature and old-growth stands.</p>



<p><strong><em>To strengthen America’s forests and advance a holistic, science-based approach to wildfire resilience and forest restoration, this Executive Order advances action on: &nbsp;</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Data Collection and Analysis:</strong> DOI and USDA will conduct the first-ever inventory of mature and old-growth forests on federal lands. This will be completed and made publicly available in a year and will establish consistent definitions, accounting for regional and ecological variation. The agencies will then analyze threats facing these forests, including from wildfires and other climate impacts.</li><li><strong>Climate-Smart Stewardship:</strong> After completing the inventory, DOI and USDA will develop new policies, with robust opportunity for public comment, to institutionalize climate-smart management and conservation strategies that address the threats facing mature and old-growth forests on federal lands.</li><li><strong>Enhanced Coordination: </strong>DOI and USDA will partner with other federal agencies, states, Tribal Nations, and any interested private landowners to better coordinate conservation and wildfire risk reduction efforts—leveraging investments from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and other sources.</li></ul>



<p>Going forward, the Administration will work with Congress to secure additional resources, by requesting $6.1 billion for wildfire risk reduction in the President’s FY 2023 Budget and continuing to pursue historic climate resilience investments in additional legislation.</p>



<p><strong><u>Strengthening Forests for Thriving Local Economies</u></strong></p>



<p>America’s forests provide millions of jobs and underpin local economies, particularly in rural communities. The Biden-Harris Administration is mobilizing historic resources to help these forests and communities thrive. For example, the Administration’s Building a Better America Rural Infrastructure Tour is <a href="https://www.usda.gov/sites/default/files/documents/usda-rural-fact-sheet.pdf">highlighting</a> wide-ranging support for healthy forest economies, including: planning assistance to boost outdoor recreation economies; support for Tribes, local governments, and conservation non-profits to establish community forests that create jobs; and grants to expand markets for innovative wood products and wood energy that support sustainable forest management.</p>



<p>Through the FY 2022 Omnibus, the Administration is also investing $162 million in cooperative forestry programs across State, municipal, and privately-owned forest landscapes. Additionally, the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law significantly expands reforestation projects on National Forest land—enough to plant an estimated 1.2 billion trees and sequester 75 million metric tons of carbon, all while supporting thousands of jobs.</p>



<p><strong><em>The Executive Order will build on these efforts by advancing:</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Economic Opportunities in Outdoor Recreation and Sustainable Forest Products: </strong>The Departments of Agriculture, Commerce, and the Interior will work with state, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, as well as the private sector, nonprofit organizations, labor unions, and the scientific community, to advance forest-related economic opportunities at the local and regional levels. These community-led opportunities will create and sustain jobs in outdoor recreation and in sustainable wood, paper, and other forest products, while supporting healthy, sustainably managed forests in timber communities.<br><br></li><li><strong>Reforestation Partnerships: </strong>The Administration will develop agency-specific 2030 targets for reforestation, including the use of partnerships to advance these goals beyond federal lands to enable our future forests to be more resilient to climate change and wildfire, while also supporting healthy forest economies for years to come.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Expanding Seed and Nursery Capacity:</strong><a> </a>USDA and DOI will address a longstanding seed shortfall by developing a plan, in partnership with states, Tribes, and the private sector, to boost federal cone and seed collection and seedling nursery capacity. These actions will support tree-planting efforts by a range of public and private partners. Expanding seed and nursery capacity is especially important for timberlands in the West that have been devastated by wildfire and need to be re-planted.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Combatting Global Deforestation</u></strong></p>



<p>President Biden has committed to help deliver on global goals to end natural forest loss by 2030, while restoring at least an additional 200 million hectares of forests and other ecosystems. At the COP26 international climate conference, President Biden announced the “<a href="https://www.state.gov/plan-to-conserve-global-forests-critical-carbon-sinks/">Plan to Conserve Global Forests: Critical Carbon Sinks</a>”—harnessing U.S. diplomatic, policy, and financing tools, in partnership with other countries, Indigenous and local forest communities, the private sector, and civil society, and with a focus on three critical areas of global importance: the Amazon, Congo, and Southeast Asian forests.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><em>To further advance these efforts and achieve the President’s international commitments, this Executive Order directs the Department of State, in coordination with other agencies, to prepare reports to the President on whole-of-government approaches to stopping global deforestation and restoring lands, including:</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Combat Commodity-Driven Deforestation:</strong> A major driver of global deforestation is forest clearing to produce agricultural commodities like beef, soy, and palm oil. To combat those practices, the Department of State will lead development of a report on whole-of-government approaches to reduce or eliminate U.S. purchases of agricultural commodities grown on illegally or recently deforested lands, including through public-private partnerships to incentivize sustainable sourcing. These efforts will not only protect forests and human rights abroad, but also provide a level playing field for responsible agricultural producers at home.</li><li><strong>Support Sustainable Forest Management Around the World:</strong> The Department of State will coordinate with other agencies to assess the broader use of foreign assistance, trade tools, finance, and international partnerships to combat deforestation and support sustainable forest management around the world, with special attention to the critical role played by Indigenous peoples and local communities and landholders in conserving and restoring forests.</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Enlisting Nature in the Fight Against Climate Change</u></strong></p>



<p>The Biden-Harris Administration has led the way on enhancing nature’s ability to support the health, wellbeing, and economic security of all Americans. President Biden launched the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2021/12/20/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-celebrates-expansion-of-locally-led-conservation-efforts-in-first-year-of-america-the-beautiful-initiative/">America the Beautiful initiative</a> to support his goal of conserving at least 30 percent of U.S. lands and waters by 2030. Interagency Working Groups reporting to the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/climate/">National Climate Task Force</a> are exploring nature-based solutions to address extreme heat, drought, wildfire, flood, and coastal threats. The Administration is also recognizing the value of and elevating <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2021/11/15/white-house-commits-to-elevating-indigenous-knowledge-in-federal-policy-decisions/">Indigenous Traditional Ecological Knowledge</a> across federal scientific and policy processes. The President’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law provides—as part of over $50 billion in historic resilience investments—funding for nature-based solutions, including $2.3 billion for the Forest Service and Interior to advance ecosystem restoration and resilience.</p>



<p>To facilitate use of these and other resources, today the National Climate Task Force’s<a href="https://www.noaa.gov/coastal-resilience-interagency-working-group"> Coastal Resilience Interagency Working Group</a>, co-led by the White House Council on Environmental Quality and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, is releasing a <strong><a href="https://www.noaa.gov/sites/default/files/2022-04/Nature-based-Solutions-Compendium.pdf">Compendium of Federal Nature-Based Solutions for Coastal Communities, States, Tribes, and Territories</a></strong>—streamlining access to more than 100 information resources and 48 federal programs that can support nature-based solutions in coastal areas.  </p>



<p><strong><em>To further amplify the power of nature, including its ability to absorb climate pollution and increase resilience in all communities, today’s Executive Order calls for the following:<br></em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Report on Nature-Based Solutions:</strong> As reaffirmed this year by the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/ostp/news-updates/2022/02/28/statements-from-the-white-house-office-on-science-and-technology-policy-ostp-on-the-intergovernmental-panel-on-climate-changes-working-group-ii-report/">Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change</a>, nature-based solutions will play a key role in achieving net-zero emissions and building resilience to climate impacts. Building on ongoing efforts, the White House Council on Environmental Quality, Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP), and Office of Domestic Climate Policy will work with agencies to develop a report to the National Climate Task Force on key opportunities for greater deployment of nature-based solutions—everything from restoring marshes, to planting shade trees, to promoting drought-resistant crops.</li><li><strong>Guidance on Valuing Nature: </strong>The Office of Management and Budget will issue valuation guidance to help agencies better account for services provided by ecosystems and the environment (such as pollinators supporting our crops, or forests cleaning our air and water). In support, OSTP and the Department of Commerce will continue leading an interagency initiative to improve and update baseline information on the economic value of our existing natural assets and new nature-based solutions.&nbsp;</li><li><strong>First U.S. National Nature Assessment:</strong> The United States lacks comprehensive knowledge of the state of our nation’s lands, waters, and wildlife and the specific benefits that they provide. To create this comprehensive picture, the 13-agency U.S. Global Change Research Program will develop the first-ever assessment of the condition of nature within the United States. The assessment will also allow us to look ahead at how nature might change in the future and identify opportunities for investments in nature to help achieve our climate, health, environmental justice, and economic goals.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris During a Tour of the William J. Rutter&#160;Center</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-during-a-tour-of-the-william-j-rutter-center/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 02:48:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51598</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UCSF Mission Bay Medical CenterSan Francisco, California THE VICE PRESIDENT: But I&#8217;m so looking forward to our conversations. But you all just have to know, we applaud and thank you. We are so grateful for what you all do. And you know, we were just talking about it &#8212; it takes a lot to do&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>UCSF Mission Bay Medical Center<br><em>San Francisco, California</em></em></p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT: But I&#8217;m so looking forward to our conversations. But you all just have to know, we applaud and thank you. We are so grateful for what you all do. And you know, we were just talking about it &#8212; it takes a lot to do the work that that you all do, and it can be quite painful because you see so much pain and you care so deeply.<br><br>And in spite of all of that, you all are about empowerment, about recognizing &#8212; not giving but recognizing the dignity and fighting for the rights.<br><br>And it&#8217;s extraordinary the gift that you have and that you give. And so, I wanted to come here today &#8212; and with the Administrator &#8212; so we could talk with you, we can visit with you so we can talk about you as we travel around the country.<br><br>Because, you know, we were talking earlier about it. When we&#8217;re fighting for the ability of women and their families and their community to receive all that they are entitled to receive, it&#8217;s important that we also let them know that they are not alone. And that&#8217;s part of telling the stories.<br><br>It is also about letting them know and see what the solution looks like so that they don&#8217;t have to ever have an experience of wondering whether it is even possible that they would be treated with dignity and receive what is necessary for them to have a joyful and healthy experience and be seen in the full totality of who they are.<br><br>So, by being here today and lifting up and sharing what you all are doing here, we&#8217;re going to be talking with women you all will never meet, will probably never even know your names or mine, but who will benefit from what you all are doing here on the ground. So, I just want to thank you all so very much.<br><br>And with that, why don’t we begin our conversation.<br><br>END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Democratic National Committee&#160;Fundraiser</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-democratic-national-committee-fundraiser-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Private ResidenceSeattle, Washington 6:29 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; First of all, every time I’m here, I don&#8217;t want to go home, Jay.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; My Lord.&#160; Look, first of all, Mary, Spencer, and Brad and Kathy, thank you.&#160; Thank you for hosting me.&#160; And almost every one of you has &#8212; or part of the reason&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Private Residence<br>Seattle, Washington</p>



<p>6:29 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; First of all, every time I’m here, I don&#8217;t want to go home, Jay.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; My Lord.&nbsp; Look, first of all, Mary, Spencer, and Brad and Kathy, thank you.&nbsp; Thank you for hosting me.&nbsp; And almost every one of you has &#8212; or part of the reason why I&#8217;m standing here in the first place as the President of the United States &#8212; you&#8217;ve all been an enormous help.</p>



<p>And the thing I want to mention is that, in all the help you give me, not one of you have ever called and asked for a favor.&nbsp; I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; Think about that.&nbsp; Not one of you have ever called and said, “Now you’re President.&nbsp; Can I get boom, boom, boom?”&nbsp; Not one.</p>



<p>And the way you do it with such honor, integrity.&nbsp; And so many of the philanthropies that some of you run &#8212; always doing this good, decent work for people.</p>



<p>You know, when I ran, I was &#8212; I won’t say “criticized” &#8212; people thought I wasn&#8217;t &#8212; my rationale for running was not one that would carry much weight in terms of the body politic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I said I was running for three reasons.&nbsp; One, to restore the soul of the country and to restore a sense of decency and honor to the &#8212; to the United States of America in terms of the presidency.&nbsp; Because the president and the White House was looked at by many people around the world as what America is about.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not; it&#8217;s much bigger &#8212; bigger &#8212; bigger than that.</p>



<p>But &#8212; and the second thing I said was that I wanted to rebuild the economy &#8212; the backbone of the economy, which I believe to be the middle class.&nbsp; Because if the middle class does well, the poor have a way up and the wealthy still do very well.&nbsp; Everybody does better when everybody is in on the deal.</p>



<p>And the third thing was &#8212; that’s turning &#8212; that I was roundly and justifiably criticized for was saying I want to unite the country.&nbsp; Because no democracy can be sustained without the informed consent of the American people.&nbsp; We’ve got to bring them together.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a tough thing.</p>



<p>And so, one of the things that I found is that I’m reminded every day why elections matter.&nbsp; And I just cite two generic examples of why I say that.&nbsp; Number one &#8212; and the press has heard me say this, so I apologize to the press for my repeating this, but I believe it &#8212; is that, Gov, I think, in the year 2020 and beyond, we&#8217;re in the battle between democracies and autocracies.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve had long discussions and over many, many hours &#8212; I mean, literally, over &#8212; I think it&#8217;s now up to 70-some hours with Xi Jinping.&nbsp; We traveled 17,000 miles.&nbsp; And he doesn’t have a democratic &#8212; with a small “d” &#8212; bone in his body.&nbsp; He’s a very smart and calculating guy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he&#8217;s just very straightforward with me.&nbsp; He doesn&#8217;t think that democracies can be sustained in the 21st century, in the second quarter of the century, because things are moving so rapidly, so incredibly fast that only &#8212; he doesn&#8217;t say “autocracy” &#8212; only autocracies are able to handle it.&nbsp; Because democracies require consensus, and it takes too much time, too much effort to get it together.&nbsp; And by that time, the event, the circumstance has gone beyond your ability to fix it.</p>



<p>And we see that &#8212; I &#8212; we talked about it.&nbsp; We mentioned democracies.&nbsp; One of the things that I did, I put together a worldwide effort, through a Zoom conference, with 142 heads of state on gathering up the democracies of the world to discuss where we go from here.&nbsp; And this was now two and a half months ago.</p>



<p>And as Freedom House will tell you, we have fewer democracies today than we did 15 years ago.&nbsp; Democracies are actually receding, not expanding.&nbsp; Just look around the world.&nbsp; Things are changing.</p>



<p>And so, when I got elected, one of the things I thought was critic- &#8212; critically important was that we stopped treating our allies and friends &#8212; my first discussion, Xi Jinping called me the night I was elected and the day after my &#8212;&nbsp; election &#8212; the next day after my election in 20- &#8212; whatever date it was.&nbsp; I can’t remember now.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, he called me to congratulate me.&nbsp; We ended up spending almost three hours on the telephone.&nbsp; And he &#8212; and it just amazed the Chinese experts who were on the phone with me, the things that he said.&nbsp; He remembered everything I had said to him.&nbsp; He said, “I remember you &#8212; asking you.”&nbsp; I said, “I know.”&nbsp; He said, “You shouldn&#8217;t be criticizing another country in terms of your &#8212; our human rights and our policy towards individuals.”</p>



<p>And I said, “You know, the United States is the most unique the country in the world not because we were born that way, but because we&#8217;re the only country ever organized based on an idea.”</p>



<p>I mean that sincerely.&nbsp; Think about it.&nbsp; An idea.&nbsp; We’re not based on ethnicity, race, religion, geography.&nbsp; It’s an idea. And what was the idea?&nbsp; “We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all women and men are created equal, endowed by their Creator with certain inalienable rights.”&nbsp; You know it.</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve never met it, but we never walked away from it.&nbsp; We’ve never walked away from, except for a very brief period of time in the last administration.</p>



<p>And so, I said, “For me not to be critical of your abuse of human rights would be like you deciding you didn&#8217;t think that China was any longer the center of the earth.&nbsp; You would be abandoning exactly what your country thinks it is and thought it was.”&nbsp; And I said, “So, I&#8217;m not going to stop being critical.”</p>



<p>My generic point was larger, though.&nbsp; If you &#8212; I said I was going to &#8212; he said, “What are you going to do?”&nbsp; And I said, “What I&#8217;m going to do is reestablish our alliances.”&nbsp; And by my implication, he said, “That&#8217;s &#8212; that’s because you&#8217;re trying to hurt China.”</p>



<p>I said, “No.&nbsp; It&#8217;s because we have to bring together the alliances we had before that have been treated like &#8212; our alliances, four years earlier, had been treated like…” &#8212; how can I say it?&nbsp; Anyway.&nbsp; Not well.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; I was going to say something I shouldn’t say (inaudible).</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, think about it.&nbsp; And so, what I did was, I immediately convened a meeting and &#8212; of the G7.&nbsp; And it was in London.&nbsp; I mean, excuse me, in suburban &#8212; it was down in the (inaudible) in England.</p>



<p>And everybody showed up.&nbsp; And the first thing I said, when I walked in, I said, “America is back.”&nbsp; And I will not, with the press here, say &#8212; went &#8212; two heads of state said the same thing: “For how long?&nbsp; For how long?”</p>



<p>And I also indicated to Xi Jinping that I was going to pull together the Quad: Australia, India, Japan, and the United States.&nbsp; He said, “You&#8217;re just doing that to affect us.”</p>



<p>I said, “No, it&#8217;s because we&#8217;re trying to put together those folks who have an opportunity to work together in the Indo-Pacific.”</p>



<p>The point being that one of the things that the autocrats fear the most &#8212; and India has its own problems; all those countries have their own problems &#8212; is the notion that somehow we can work together in concert and &#8212; contrary to what are essentially dictatorships, which a lot of countries have become &#8212; particularly, not only China, but Russia and many other countries &#8212; the Philippines.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, the point I&#8217;m making is that I spend a lot of time and put together, I think, a pretty good foreign policy team &#8212; with our Secretary of Defense, Secretary of State, National Security Advisor, et cetera &#8212; and reached out.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what happened was: Putin thought, when we got elected, that we’d &#8212; he’d easily be able to break up NATO.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what part of his objective was from the very beginning.&nbsp; And I know I&#8217;ve been saying that for eight years, but it was part of his objective.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the irony of all ironies to this &#8212; and you know from being the Ambassador to Switzerland &#8212; what happened was: He got exactly what he didn&#8217;t want.&nbsp; He was looking for the further Finlandization of Europe.&nbsp; Instead, he got Finland and the President of &#8212; the President of Finland calling, wanting to see me, wanting to join NATO, and Sweden wanting to join NATO.&nbsp; His action is generating exactly the opposite of what he intended.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not suggesting that that makes things all that easier.&nbsp; But the point is that we have a circumstance where the Ukrainian people are incredibly brave; they’re incredibly resolved &#8212; not just the military that was trained, but the American &#8212; but the people in the streets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he is making &#8212; they&#8217;re making a lie of Putin’s theory that somehow because they&#8217;re Slavic in background and spoke &#8212; many spoke Russian that somehow there would be a welcoming party.&nbsp; The exact opposite has happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The reason I bother to raise this is that it raises the issue of whether or not &#8212; what our foreign policy will be from this point on.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s occupied, Jay more of my time than I ever anticipated it would be.</p>



<p>And that, coupled with COVID, has had a phenomenal negative impact on things that relate to, basically, inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The &#8212; when you find ourselves in a situation where in &#8212; because of COVID, there&#8217;s a factory in &#8212; the factory in Vietnam or in Taiwan closes down &#8212; that was the reason why one third of all the inflation last year was the price of automobiles.&nbsp; They couldn&#8217;t get &#8212; they couldn&#8217;t get the computer chips to be able to build the automobiles.</p>



<p>We’re now in a situation where because of Russia being such a major oil producer and because Ukraine and Russia were the wheat and corn breadbaskets of the world, we see everything from the price of eggs to the price of gasoline go up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I come from a family &#8212; not a joke &#8212; where when the price of a gallon of gasoline went up, it was a conversation at our kitchen table.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And a lot of people, notwithstanding the fact that we&#8217;ve created more jobs in the first 14 months than any President in the history.&nbsp; We have provided 400- &#8212; 5- &#8212; we created 420,000 manufacturing jobs that people thought were dead in America.&nbsp; We made &#8212; brought the employment &#8212; employment rate down to 3.6 percent from over 6 percent.&nbsp; Notwithstanding all that &#8212; and wages going up &#8212; people are concerned, uncertain, and angry.&nbsp; They&#8217;re angry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>They don&#8217;t know quite what to do because, again, when gasoline goes over $4 a gallon, it&#8217;s a big deal in an awful lot of households &#8212; the vast majority of households.&nbsp; When the cost of a dozen eggs goes up.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I mean, so the two things we&#8217;ve worked on as hard as we could is dealing with the supply chains so that we&#8217;re able to &#8212; we&#8217;re able &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a law that&#8217;s been on the books since the ‘30s and it’s the “Buy America” law.&nbsp; It’s not a violation of any international group.&nbsp; As President United States these days, I get to spend and decide where we spend about $6- to $700 billion of your money.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, under the law, we&#8217;re able to insist that I can only buy &#8212; I can insist that we buy American and that the vehicles that I&#8217;m &#8212; the &#8212; whatever I&#8217;m purchasing is up to 100 percent made in America &#8212; all the &#8212; all the parts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, Buy American was viewed to be 51 percent.&nbsp; That was enough.&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s 51 percent of American product.&nbsp; It&#8217;s now 75.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But my generic point is this: We have not invested in ourselves in America &#8212; the government has not invested in America either in our education and in our &#8212; in our technology.&nbsp; We used to provide &#8212; and now you all are doing it &#8212; but we used to provide from the government &#8212; 2 percent of our GDP was invested in research and development.&nbsp; It’s less than 1 percent now.&nbsp; Less than 1 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We used to be in a situation where we had the best infrastructure in the world &#8212; our ports, airports &#8212; or just go down the road &#8212; high- &#8212; the whole deal.&nbsp; We now rank 13th in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We used to be in a situation where &#8212; if you think about it, why were we the most powerful nation in the world, beginning &#8212; in the beginning of the 21st century &#8212; the 20th century?&nbsp; Because the only nation in the world that had universal education from K through 12.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other people &#8212; they had great education systems for the elite in &#8212; throughout Europe and great universities and great, great what we would call “high school.”&nbsp; But it wasn&#8217;t universal.&nbsp; The rest of the world has caught up with us and what have we done?&nbsp; Does anybody think if, today, we said, “We&#8217;re going to have a national education system,” that we&#8217;d say 12 years is enough?&nbsp; Anybody think 12 years is enough in the 21st century &#8212; in the second quarter of the 21st century?&nbsp; What are we doing?&nbsp; We&#8217;re resisting what we know to be the case.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If in fact &#8212; all the studies have shown from the great universities of the last 10 years, if you have mandatory schooling &#8212; or schooling available for pre-K &#8212; three-, four-, and five-year-olds &#8212; you increase by over 56 percent that the child, no matter what the background they come from, is going to be able to get through 12 years of school &#8212; 12 years of schooling and go beyond.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, you all know the studies because you’re &#8212; the philanthropies you run, you&#8217;ve been involved in helping.&nbsp; You all know that, for example, a child coming from a broken home &#8212; with a mom or a dad or &#8212; where there&#8217;s a drug problem or there&#8217;s just pure poverty &#8212; that child, by the time they go to kindergarten, will have heard 1 million fewer words spoken than a child from an average middle-class home.&nbsp; Not different words, just spoken.&nbsp; Just spoken.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re in a situation where we find now, if in fact you have a circumstance where there is three- and four- and five-year-olds in school &#8212; school, not daycare &#8212; school, where they’re learning to read, write, add, and subtract, they increase exponentially their ability to learn.&nbsp; And they don&#8217;t show up &#8212; it doesn&#8217;t matter what their background they come from.&nbsp; It doesn’t matter what the background they come from.</p>



<p>Many of you know better than I &#8212; my son-in-law, who has his doctorate in neuroscience and is a reconstructive plastic surgeon in Philadelphia, talks about it.&nbsp; The brain has been rapidly advancing during that period of time.&nbsp; And it continues to grow after age 20.&nbsp; But what do we do?</p>



<p>So, for very little money, I spoke to the Fortune 500 companies, I spoke to the &#8212; actually the &#8212; when I &#8212; in Washington, we had &#8212; finally were able to gather up a larger number of people, and I spoke to the national Chamber of Commerce.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I pointed out that, when I was Vice President, President Obama asked me to deal with the Recovery Act, which was several billion dollars, and to get it working.</p>



<p>And I said one things I did was I went with the Secretary of Commerce and others to speak to a 300 &#8212; I think it was 340-some or 350 &#8212; I don&#8217;t remember the number &#8212; of the CEOs in the Fortune 500 companies.&nbsp; And I asked what they most needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It will not surprise you what the answer was: a better-educated workforce.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; The notable exceptions in this room: You all don&#8217;t pay for the better-educated workforce you have.</p>



<p>When I got elected in 1973, the DuPont &#8212; “the state of DuPont,” as I used to kid &#8212; DuPont was the eighth-largest corporation in the world, and they educated their newly hired people for the jobs they had.&nbsp; They took the time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That doesn’t happen now.&nbsp; So, I raised the question.&nbsp; I said, “Why…” &#8212; this was the national Chamber &#8212; “why are you opposed to preschool being…”&nbsp; And they all said, “I never thought of it.&nbsp; We’re not.&nbsp; We’re not.”</p>



<p>There are so many things we can do without raising taxes on &#8212; and, by the way, all of the stuff &#8212; we&#8217;ve had expensive programs: the Recovery Act, plus the infrastructure bill.&nbsp; Guess what?&nbsp; We’ve actually reduced the federal debt by $350 billion in 2021.&nbsp; And it’s projected now to be reduced by $1.3 trillion with all the growth we&#8217;re talking about.&nbsp; That’s a fact.</p>



<p>Whether we do the $1.3 trillion, we&#8217;ll see at the end of the year.&nbsp; The largest number ever in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; But my generic point is &#8212; it’s not some &#8212; what I&#8217;m trying to say is, there&#8217;s so many things we can do that don&#8217;t punish anybody and get so much done.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m a capitalist.&nbsp; I think you should be able to make a million, a billion dollars.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Whatever you can make.&nbsp; But you&#8217;re the prime example of what I&#8217;m about to say because you do it.&nbsp; Everybody has to pay a piece of &#8212; a fair share.&nbsp; The idea &#8212; the idea that we have a system now where it&#8217;s so disproportionately unbalanced &#8212; without &#8212; it won&#8217;t hurt anybody.&nbsp; No big deal &#8212; to pay for what we need.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, healthcare.&nbsp; You know, I know some of you have &#8212; I hope you have interest in some of the major drug companies in the country.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; The insulin &#8212; how many people have Stage 1 diabetes?&nbsp; Thousands of people, two hundred thousand kids in America.&nbsp; The average cost on a monthly basis: $641; as high as $1,000, as low in some places as $95.</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the deal: It cost 10 bucks to develop, at the time, that insulin vial.&nbsp; Ten dollars.&nbsp; I think we should see to it that &#8212; that unless there&#8217;s new research and development put into it to change the formulas that you can&#8217;t charge more than $35.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Imagine being the parent of a kid with Type 1 diabetes, knowing, if they go into insulin shock, what the danger is, sitting there knowing you don’t have the insurance or the wherewithal to pay for it.&nbsp; Not only is your kid in trouble &#8212; you&#8217;re stripped of your dignity.&nbsp; Everything is taken from you.</p>



<p>But what&#8217;s the big fight?&nbsp; I can&#8217;t get a single Republican to say, “That&#8217;s a good idea.”&nbsp; Everybody points out what I have is I have one Democrat that says “no.”&nbsp; Well, that&#8217;s true.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; Forty-eight of the fifty Democrats in the Senate vote with me 95 percent of the time, or over 90 percent of the time.</p>



<p>But the second point I want to make: This is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party.  This is a different deal.  Not a joke.  Not a joke.  And it&#8217;s not just Trump, it&#8217;s the MAGA crowd.  It’s all about things that have nothing to do with traditional, conservative doctrine. </p>



<p>I respect conservatives.&nbsp; There&#8217;s nothing conservative about deciding you&#8217;re going to throw Disney out of its present posture because &#8212; Mickey Mouse?&nbsp; In fact, do you think we should be not be able to say, you know, “gay”?</p>



<p>I mean, what’s going on here?&nbsp; What the hell is going on?&nbsp; And it&#8217;s just &#8212; so, I don&#8217;t believe it’s who the vast majority of American people are.</p>



<p>Another point I want to make is &#8212; and I&#8217;ll stop, I apologize, so we can get to questions &#8212; when I got elected and when I was running, I said that I was going to see to it that if I were President, my administration looked like America.</p>



<p>I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; Looked like America.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s exactly what I&#8217;ve done.&nbsp; Of all the thousand appointees I&#8217;ve had that didn’t require Senate confirmation &#8212; well over a thousand &#8212; and all those requiring confirmation, there are more women than men, by a slight margin.&nbsp; It’s not much.&nbsp; But equally as &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s no distinction in terms of qualification.&nbsp; Pick the best person.</p>



<p>I’ve appointed more Circuit Court judges to the federal Circuit Court that were Black than every other president in American history combined.&nbsp; Not because &#8212; not because to make a point, other than the point that &#8212; to let every little Black girl out there know that she could do anything any little white girl can do, given the chance.</p>



<p>You saw how Judge Brown Jackson was treated.&nbsp; The questions they asked her were humiliating.&nbsp; Humiliating.&nbsp; And now we had an event in the White House when she &#8212; on the lawn &#8212; when she was &#8212; was confirmed.&nbsp; And she had a great line she used.&nbsp; She said &#8212; she said it best.&nbsp; She said, “From segregation to the Supreme Court in one generation.&nbsp; I thank my parents.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>You should see, when I go into African American communities, or especially young African American women, they look and they see.&nbsp; Think of all of the young girls of middle-class backgrounds (inaudible) who look up there and see the women who are heading up major Cabinet positions, from the Vice President on down.</p>



<p>So, you know, I &#8212; I think that when &#8212; you&#8217;re more united and stronger than ever when we focus on what we have in common.&nbsp; And I know that sounds, you know, sort of prosaic.&nbsp; I mean &#8212; and I&#8217;ve been doing this a long time.&nbsp; I got involved in public life because of the Civil Rights Movement.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not making this &#8212; this is not a, you know, painted rosy picture.&nbsp; But we are unique in the world.&nbsp; We&#8217;re the only democracy that is as &#8212; as ethnically, politi- &#8212; excuse me &#8212; ethnically, racially so divided.&nbsp; So &#8212; and if we don&#8217;t bring it together, what in the hell are we going to do?&nbsp; What are we going to do?&nbsp;</p>



<p>So again, I&#8217;m not on a crusade; it’s just about fairness. It&#8217;s about giving people a shot.&nbsp; And like I said, you know, I think that the clear contrast with our Republican colleagues &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to have to start pointing this out.&nbsp; Everybody thinks &#8212; they always talk about the Democratic Party divided because there are two senators who occasionally don’t vote with me.</p>



<p>Well, the bad news is, when you have a 50/50 Senate, you have 51 presidents.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; It becomes a problem.&nbsp; And &#8212; and the use of the filibuster, which I think is so far out of whack, can hold up anything.&nbsp; You need 60 votes.&nbsp; That&#8217;s &#8212; I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m going on too long, but (inaudible) questions.</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the deal: One of the reasons that I&#8217;m here is we have to keep the Uni- &#8212; we have to keep the United States Senate.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t afford to lose it.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t afford to lose the House.&nbsp; And I think &#8212; what I&#8217;m concerned about is that I have been so focused on whatever the immediate emergency is, we haven&#8217;t sold the American people what we’ve actually done &#8212; what we’ve actually gotten done.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve gotten a hell of a lot done.&nbsp; A hell of a lot done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, this is what I&#8217;m here for: to ask you for your help, when it comes to this off-year election, to help keep the Democratic (inaudible) Senate and the Democratic House so that we can, in fact &#8212;</p>



<p>The la- &#8212; the act- &#8212; actual very last point I’ll make: There are a number of Republicans who are not the MAGA group &#8212; that are not.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; They&#8217;re scared to death.&nbsp;&nbsp;They know &#8212; and I know you know this, Jay, that we could privately name them off the top of our heads &#8212; there are a significant number who if they were to vote where they had voted in the past, if they vote their heart, they’d get a primary and they’ll lose a primary.&nbsp; They would lose a primary.&nbsp; It doesn&#8217;t talk about courage, but it talks about reality.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we got to make &#8212; we got to provide room by providing more Democratic votes that allow people to say &#8212;</p>



<p>You know, I remember, early on, learning a lesson from a senior senator when I got there.&nbsp; He said, “It&#8217;s one thing to cast your vote that you feel strongly about on a losing cause. It&#8217;s another thing if you vote with the side that what you care about wins.&nbsp; It ain&#8217;t worth it if you can&#8217;t win.&nbsp; You just get the downside and no upside.”</p>



<p>That’s reality.&nbsp; That’s how, I think &#8212; how human nature functions.&nbsp; And so, I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;m going to change human nature, but I think the more we are &#8212; go around the country, talking about what we&#8217;ve done, talking about what we can do, talk about the impact of the &#8212; everything from the &#8212; what we&#8217;ve done in terms of healthcare, what we&#8217;ve done in terms of the whole notion of how we&#8217;re going to deal with education, the way in which we&#8217;re going to deal with the notion of the infrastructure bill that’s going to fundamentally change &#8212;</p>



<p>Your state is going to get hundreds of millions of dollars to do good things.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; And &#8212; but I know you know, Jay.&nbsp; It really is.&nbsp; We&#8217;re talking about tens of millions of dollars.&nbsp; I was just at your airport &#8212; I mean, I was just in Portland at their airport.&nbsp; We’re talking about that whole airport facility getting close to a billion dollars.&nbsp; You&#8217;re going to be able to do the same thing here so we can once again invest in our country and our people so we can stay competitive.</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m outcompeting myself here because I&#8217;m taking up too much of your time before we get to questions.&nbsp; So, thank you very much for listening.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m prepared to take questions at the appropriate moment.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>6:58 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at a Democratic National Committee&#160;Fundraiser</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-president-biden-at-a-democratic-national-committee-fundraiser-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 01:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Portland Yacht ClubPortland, Oregon 3:38 P.M. PDT&#160;&#160;THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Well, thank you all.&#160; Joe, thank you, thank you, thank you. I &#8212; there&#8217;s a guy in here wearing a hat.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; Oh, it&#8217;s Ron Wyden.&#160; That’s who it is.&#160; Hey, Ron.&#160; Poor Ron has had to see me all day, God love him.&#160; He didn’t &#8212;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Portland Yacht Club<br>Portland, Oregon</p>



<p>3:38 P.M. PDT&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Well, thank you all.&nbsp; Joe, thank you, thank you, thank you.</p>



<p>I &#8212; there&#8217;s a guy in here wearing a hat.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Oh, it&#8217;s Ron Wyden.&nbsp; That’s who it is.&nbsp; Hey, Ron.&nbsp; Poor Ron has had to see me all day, God love him.&nbsp; He didn’t &#8212;</p>



<p>SENATOR WYDEN:&nbsp; Oh, lucky me.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Laughs.)&nbsp; Yeah.&nbsp; Well, look, first of all, Joe, thank you very, very much.&nbsp; I appreciate it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Carol and Win, I &#8212; you also supported me from the beginning.</p>



<p>It’s wonderful to be back in Portland.&nbsp; I’ll try to make this brief because you’re all standing and I don’t want to keep you on your feet that long.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But look, I’m here for a simple reason, and I mean this sincerely: to say thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So many of you were with me when I was trying to get the nomination.&nbsp; And you know that, at the time, when I came to see you, it was shortly after I decided to run.&nbsp; Because I hadn&#8217;t planned on running again.&nbsp; For real.&nbsp; I had no intention of running again.</p>



<p>And to tell you a little story, we &#8212; when I saw those folks come out of the fields down in Charlottesville, carrying those torches &#8212; literally out of the fields &#8212; with Nazi banners and chanting the same anti-Semitic bile that was chanted in the ‘30s, Gov, not a joke, that was when I decided that I thought this can&#8217;t be happening in America.</p>



<p>And then when my predecessor was asked what did he think, he said there were very good people on both sides.&nbsp; And &#8212; but I still concluded that I &#8212; you know, I didn&#8217;t want to run, but I felt like I should.&nbsp; But I just thought it was going to be a really ugly campaign because of the circumstances.</p>



<p>And we have a &#8212; we have a tradition in my family &#8212; for real: Any child can ask for a family meeting.&nbsp; I&#8217;m being deadly earnest about this.&nbsp; And I got a phone call from my eldest granddaughter, Naomi &#8212; Naomi Biden, named after my deceased daughter.&nbsp; And she was, at that time, a freshman in Columbia Law School.&nbsp; And her &#8212; and then her sister, who was at Penn, and another sister, who was in Washington and still in high school, and my deceased son Beau’s two young children.&nbsp; And they &#8212; so they said, “Okay.”&nbsp; This was on a Wednesday.&nbsp; So, we met at Wilmington &#8212; at my home in Wilmington, with Jill and I.</p>



<p>And they started off and said, “Pop, you’ve got to run.”&nbsp; And I said, “Honey, I don’t think I want to do that.&nbsp; It’s going…”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, I’m serious.&nbsp; “It’s going to be &#8212; it’s going to be just a really mean campaign, and I don’t want you guys to have to go through it.”</p>



<p>Because their whole lives, they have been &#8212; either had a grandfather who was a senator, a vice president, or a &#8212; or as a vice president.&nbsp; And one of their dads had been an attorney general for a long time as well.&nbsp; And so, they knew what it was going to be like.&nbsp; And they started off and said that, “Daddy, we want you to do it.&nbsp; We want you to do it.”&nbsp; And they made the case.</p>



<p>And my youngest &#8212; now he&#8217;s 16 years old &#8212; grandson, my son Hunter&#8217;s son &#8212; my son Beau’s son named Hunter said, “Pop…” &#8212; and he took out his cellphone and showed a picture &#8212; I hadn&#8217;t plan on saying this.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t know why I&#8217;m telling you, but Joe reminded me of it.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>He showed me a picture of coming out of mass &#8212; the memorial mass &#8212; the burial of my &#8212; of my son Beau.&nbsp; And I had my hand on the hand-draped coffin in the military funeral.&nbsp; And I had my hand around the neck of my little &#8212; then he was 14 years old &#8212; I mean, excuse me, about 12 years old &#8212; grandson.&nbsp; And &#8212; and the caption underneath the picture was, “Biden molests another child.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I said &#8212; and he said, “But, Pop, it&#8217;s okay.&nbsp; Daddy wants you to run.&nbsp; You got to run.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And when I ran &#8212; when I came out to see some of you at that time, I told you I was running for three reasons.&nbsp; I was running to restore the soul of this country &#8212; some decency and honor.&nbsp; And I meant that sincerely.&nbsp; And I remember I got widely criticized for saying it.</p>



<p>And secondly, I was going to rebuild the backbone of the country, which I consider to be the middle class.&nbsp; When the middle class does well, everybody does well.&nbsp; The poor have a way up and the wealthy still are able to do very well.</p>



<p>And lastly, I was going to try to unite America.&nbsp; Because I think in a democracy, you cannot sustain growth unless &#8212; without unity.&nbsp; It’s just not possible.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; and during the campaign, I talked about the fact that in my time as the eight years as Vice President, that I spent a fair amount of time doing foreign policy for the President and traveling around the world.&nbsp; And I spent more time with Xi Jinping than any other world leader, just in terms of raw numbers.&nbsp; I traveled 17,000 miles with him throughout Asia and the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And he’s very straightforward and blunt.&nbsp; He doesn’t think democracies can function in the 21st century.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; This is deadly earnest.&nbsp; Deadly earnest.&nbsp; Same attitude with less grace than &#8212; that Putin has and many other leaders around the world.</p>



<p>Because things are changing so rapidly, they do not believe that democracy can &#8212; that democracies can adjust.&nbsp; Because the world is changing.&nbsp; We&#8217;re at one of those inflection points in world history where, regardless who&#8217;s the head of what state, there&#8217;s fundamental change taking place.&nbsp; Whether it&#8217;s a negative pla- &#8212; place &#8212; change taking place because of climate or things that are not bad.&nbsp; But just technology changing everything.</p>



<p>And &#8212; and so, one of the things that happened was I &#8212; I found working with &#8212; and I mean it sincerely &#8212; working with Ron and &#8212; and your delegation that we all figured out we had to begin to invest in America.&nbsp; We had to invest in America.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>We used to have, for example, the number-one infrastructure in the world.&nbsp; We invested in America.&nbsp; We invest &#8212;</p>



<p>One of the reasons why we were the leading country in the world in the 20th century was because we were the best-educated country in the world.&nbsp; Others had more &#8212; more prominent education systems for the narrow minority, but we were the only country in the world that had universal education from kindergarten through high school, for 12 years, regardless.&nbsp; And it mattered.</p>



<p>And so, one of the things that we started talking about was: How do we invest in our people?&nbsp; What do we do?&nbsp; Because so many people were being left behind.&nbsp; And so, that&#8217;s what this was all about when we started.</p>



<p>And one of the things that we did to begin this administration, we found ourselves in the situation where I believe we had to have a Recovery Act that was consequential.&nbsp; And I know everybody thought it was crazy, it had nothing to do with inflation because we decided to spend $1.9 trillion investing in America.&nbsp; And we did.&nbsp; We brought the economy back.</p>



<p>And by the way, that same budget year in 2021, we reduced the federal deficit by $350 billion at the same time.&nbsp;&nbsp;(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And investing in America was investing in our infrastructure as well.&nbsp; We used to be the number-one country in the world in terms of the most modern infrastructure.&nbsp; We&#8217;re now number 13.&nbsp; Thirteen other countr- &#8212; twelve other countries have better infrastructure than we do.</p>



<p>And what the hell do you think grows the economies?&nbsp; Infrastructure grows economies, and it gives people opportunities.&nbsp; It creates good jobs.&nbsp; It creates opportunities for people to move.</p>



<p>Now, with the help of Ron and the rest of your delegation, we passed a $1.2 trillion infrastructure bill that was designed &#8212; (applause) &#8212; I hope some of you are making more than $400,000 a year, but if you made less than 400, you didn&#8217;t pay a single penny in taxes &#8212; in your taxes.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>And so, what began to happen is: We began to rebuild and invest in our people in ways we hadn&#8217;t done before.&nbsp; And the other thing I decided to do when I said “restore the soul of America,” I believe America should look like the &#8212; that my administration should look like America &#8212; look like America.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of over a thousand appointments I&#8217;ve made in the federal government and my Cabinet as well, there are slightly more women than men.&nbsp; Because &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; no, it&#8217;s important.&nbsp; No, no.&nbsp; But it really is important for all those young women out there.&nbsp; It&#8217;s critically important.</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve been able to appoint more African American Circuit Court of Appeals judges than every other president in the history of the nation combined.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Because, look, in the 21st century, we&#8217;ve got to be who we are.&nbsp; We are a multi-ethnic nation.&nbsp; But we all have one fundamental commitment we&#8217;ve all made.&nbsp; You know, we&#8217;re the only country in the world that is formed based on an idea &#8212; not geography, not ethnicity &#8212; and I’m &#8212; I&#8217;m deadly earnest about this.&nbsp; Only one.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, what is the reason why we came together?&nbsp; Because we said, “We hold these truths to be self-evident…all men and women are created equal…endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights…Life, Liberty…” &#8212; I know it sounds corny, but that&#8217;s who we are.&nbsp; No other nation in the world has been built on an idea &#8212; an idea we have never realized &#8212; we have never realized but, until the last guy came along, we have never fully walked away from.&nbsp; We’ve gradually made progress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so the point that I want to you all is: There is so much that we still have to do.&nbsp; Because, you know &#8212; and one of the things that&#8217;s changed is that &#8212; and I&#8217;ll be very brief: On foreign policy, you recall that the last administration, some &#8212;</p>



<p>By the way, I&#8217;m not just talking about former President Trump.&nbsp; We have a whole &#8212; this is not your father&#8217;s Republican Party, by any stretch of the imagination.&nbsp; This is the MAGA Party.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Think about it: This is a party that&#8217;s owned whol- &#8212; wholly by guys like the senator from Texas and others.&nbsp; I mean, really and truly, did you ever think we&#8217;d be in a circumstance where the Republican platform would be that &#8212; and they (inaudible) the guy &#8212; the head of the rec- &#8212; the head of the Senate campaign committee in the United States Senate and Republican Party put out a platform that even Republicans have walked away from, some of them, saying &#8212; what? &#8212; that every five years we should reconsider whether we keep Social Security, Medi- &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; This is the God&#8217;s truth.&nbsp; If you want a copy of it, I will send it to you.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; No, no, but this is what they&#8217;re running on.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And by the way, remember why we won &#8212; we won all those seats back in 2018?&nbsp; Because they kept, for the 500th time, trying to do away with Obamacare.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But what people didn&#8217;t know and what &#8212; my point I&#8217;m about to get to: They don&#8217;t know a lot about what we&#8217;ve already done, just like they didn&#8217;t know then because things move so quickly.</p>



<p>All we had to do &#8212; I went into 58 &#8212; 56 races as a guy who was out of office for two years, as a former Vice President.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; We &#8212; in all Republican districts &#8212; incumbent Republicans &#8212; we won 46 of them.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And here&#8217;s the deal &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, no, here’s &#8212; no, here’s what we ran on &#8212; it&#8217;s a really important point, at least from my perspective.&nbsp; We said, “Do you know why you have a preexisting condition and you can&#8217;t be no- &#8212; denied insurance? Because of Obamacare.”&nbsp; Nobody knew it.&nbsp; We won all those races.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, what I&#8217;m worried about now is that we have done one hell of a job, but the fact is that because things have moved so rapidly, so profoundly, it&#8217;s hard for people &#8212; no, let me just give you a few statistics.</p>



<p>We have created 7.9 million jobs in the first 14 months of my administration &#8212; more than any in history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have created &#8212; we said manufacturing is dead in America.&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; We&#8217;ve created 430,000 new manufacturing jobs, and it&#8217;s still climbing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We &#8212; also unemployment rate went from 3 &#8212; went from 6.4 percent to 3.6 percent &#8212; the fastest decline in American history.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re in a situation where we reduced the deficit by $350 billion in last year&#8217;s budget.&nbsp; And this year, it&#8217;s on track, literally, to reduce it by $1.3 trillion.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>All we’re saying is &#8212; I&#8217;m a capitalist; I&#8217;m a guy who thinks if you can make a million or a billion or 100 million dollars, you should do it.&nbsp; But everybody has to pay their fair share.&nbsp; Just pay a little bit.</p>



<p>Today, as Ron will point out to you &#8212; not a joke &#8212; there&#8217;s seven hundred and ninety-some &#8212; I think that&#8217;s the number &#8212; or sixty-some billionaires in America.&nbsp; Average tax paid: 3 percent.&nbsp; Okay?&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don&#8217;t want &#8212; just &#8212; just pay a little of their &#8212; I come from the corporate state of the world, Delaware.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; There are more corporations in my state registered than every other state in the nation combined.&nbsp; But guess what?</p>



<p>Of the Fortune 500 companies, 40 of them &#8212; I think a total of $40 billion &#8212; did not pay a single penny.&nbsp; Nothing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look at the firemen who come to help you out.&nbsp; Look at the cop, the school teacher, the nurse.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Yay!&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible) seven months in an ICU, when &#8212; when I had two craniotomies because of aneurisms and a major embolism.&nbsp; My son lay in a bed for 19 months.&nbsp; The doctors let you live; the nurses make you want to live.</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; Oh.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no &#8212; male and female.&nbsp; I swear to God.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Oh, I didn’t see you, Senator.&nbsp; I’m sorry.&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But here&#8217;s the deal, guys: There&#8217;s so much we can do &#8212; so much we can do.&nbsp; But what I realized is I&#8217;m making the same mistake &#8212; and I mean this as a compliment because he’s still my best buddy &#8212; that &#8212; that we made when &#8212; in the Obama-Biden administration.</p>



<p>I remember saying to Barack after we passed the Affordable Care Act, I said, “Let&#8217;s take a victory lap.”&nbsp; He said, “We don&#8217;t have time.&nbsp; We don’t have time.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>But guess what?&nbsp; No one knew what was in it.&nbsp; They didn&#8217;t know why they had what they had.&nbsp; They didn&#8217;t know why we were able to do the &#8212; people were covered when they were never covered before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, here&#8217;s what we &#8212; I have to do.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not doing a very good job because so much &#8212; it’s like &#8212; you know, I used to say in Barack&#8217;s administration, “Everything landed on his desk but locusts.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, they landed on my desk.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>So, here&#8217;s the thing &#8212; and I&#8217;m going to hush up: One of the things I was absolutely been convinced of &#8212; because I&#8217;ve been involved in American foreign policy for my whole career since I was a 29-year-old kid in the Foreign Relations Committee (inaudible) &#8212; and that is that NATO &#8212; what happens in Europe is the foundation of what we can do around the rest of the world.&nbsp; Because there&#8217;s no way we can escape the conflict that occurs in Europe.&nbsp; It&#8217;s never occurred, never happened.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, remember: The last guy treated NATO like it was a protection racket.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; “If you don&#8217;t do such and such, we&#8217;re not going to protect &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to honor Article 5.&nbsp; We&#8217;re not going to honor our commitment.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; As Ron will tell you, I was predicting that we would have serious problems and there would be an invasion of Ukraine by &#8212; by Putin.&nbsp; Well, he not only invaded Ukraine, he&#8217;s done so much more.&nbsp; He&#8217;s a butcher.&nbsp; They have an actual butcher.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;ve been to Ukraine many times.&nbsp; Folks, these &#8212; it’s just what&#8217;s happening is &#8212; is just sinful.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m not trying to be moralistic, but it’s true: It’s sinful what he&#8217;s doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But the point is: The most important thing to have happen that we&#8217;ve had to do is how do we keep NATO and Europe united &#8212; united.&nbsp; Because I guarantee you Putin has been hoping and believing that NATO would crack and we would not make any (inaudible) sacrifice to help and deal with what he was doing in &#8212; in Eastern Europe.</p>



<p>But guess what?&nbsp; I&#8217;ve had over 120 meetings and/or &#8212; and/or what &#8212; what do we call them on the &#8212; when we do the &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; Zoom.</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Zoom.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; With &#8212; with the world leaders.&nbsp; I&#8217;m serious.&nbsp; Over 120 times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A matter of fact, the press was pointing out that &#8212; I guess it was two days ago &#8212; I called all the world &#8212; the major leaders together in the world to say, “We got to stick together,” and keeping them together.&nbsp; Because if we break &#8212; if it breaks up, we got a real problem in terms of our long-term security and a lot else that’s going to happen.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, it takes time and effort.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re &#8212; I&#8217;m not going to send a single American force into Ukraine to start World War Three.&nbsp; But we&#8217;re going to give every Ukrainian military capability that they have &#8212; that they need, in order to protect themselves.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Between Ukraine and COVID, we have been really stymied in a big way.&nbsp; Look what we have.&nbsp; Although we have &#8212; although jobs are open, jobs are up, pay is up for people &#8212; the average pay has gone up.&nbsp; But guess what?&nbsp; Inflation really is killing people.</p>



<p>I came from a family that when the price of a gallon of gasoline went up, it was a topic of conversation at the kitchen table.&nbsp; I mean, for real.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, we got two bad things happening at one time.&nbsp; One, one of the major suppliers of oil and gas in the world happens to be an absolute &#8212; well, anyway.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Not a good person.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>But guess what?&nbsp; As we cut off the oil for it to slow up &#8212; slow him up and make sure that there&#8217;s a price to pay, it raises the price of &#8212; of gas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And it affects a lot of people.&nbsp; It affects, in Europe, particularly, home heating, oil, and a whole range of other things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, one of the things that we have to do is figure out how &#8212; and the second thing is &#8212; the reason why you go buy a dozen eggs and it costs more money, the reason why you buy a loaf of bread and it costs more money is because the breadbaskets of the world starts off in Ukraine, Russia, and then United States, in terms of wheat and corn.&nbsp; And so, we &#8212; we’re going to go through a tough period.</p>



<p>But the thing is that there&#8217;s nothing beyond our capacity.&nbsp; We can do all of these things if we, in fact, have the gumption and confidence of who we are.&nbsp; This is the United States of America.&nbsp; There&#8217;s not a damn thing we can&#8217;t do &#8212; nothing we can&#8217;t do.</p>



<p>And with the help of your two senators and your congressional delegation &#8212; and I&#8217;m not being solicitous, because they have been major leaders in this effort.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>We’re in a situation where we&#8217;re going to &#8212; we&#8217;re going to gain control of this.&nbsp; For example, you know, one of the reasons for inflation last year was that one third of all the inflation is because of the lack of computer chips.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’ve ever heard of a little outfit called Intel?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Well, guess what?&nbsp; The head of Intel came to see me &#8212; asked if he could come and see me.&nbsp; He&#8217;s going to invest $20 billion in new facilities (inaudible).&nbsp; And if we pass the bill that (inaudible) trying to get done (inaudible) in the United States Senate, we’re going to &#8212; he’s going to invest another $100 billion &#8212; $100 billion.</p>



<p>The United States of America invented the computer chip.&nbsp; We’re the ones who made it &#8212; who made the progre- &#8212; progressed all along.&nbsp; But we just &#8212; we just stopped investing in ourselves, so you go to Taiwan, you go to other places to get computer chips.</p>



<p>Well, because the automobile &#8212; there&#8217;s nothing, from that cellphone you have in your hand to the automobile you&#8217;re driving, that can be functioned or made without a computer &#8212; those chips.</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; The fact is that we weren’t making them in the United States.&nbsp; And so, what I decided, with the help your delegation, is that there’s &#8212; and I&#8217;ll end with this.&nbsp; I&#8217;m sorry to go on so long.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; (Inaudible)</p>



<p>I want you to know, I believe in every fiber of my being &#8212; and I&#8217;ve been doing this my whole life &#8212; we&#8217;re on the verge of such incredible breakthroughs in this country across the board.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Every &#8212; out of &#8212; my mother, God love her, she’d say, “Out of everything bad, Joey, something good will come (inaudible).”&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re in a position where, you&#8217;re going to see, we&#8217;re going to move &#8212; I was &#8212; I led the effort on COP in the &#8212; in, anyway &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; that will &#8212; what we did was we &#8212; you know, I got another 120 nations to sign a commitment that we were going to plant another trillion &#8212; a billion trees in the next year.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>(Inaudible) all the research we&#8217;re doing, in terms of breakthrough technology, that deal with &#8212; with the whole notion of climate change and what we can do.&nbsp; And now we&#8217;re in a position where we should look at it &#8212; we have no choice but to do it.&nbsp; Nations that were reluctant to &#8212; to step up and do what they had to do are now going, “We have no choice.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I guess what I&#8217;m trying to say to you all is &#8212; and I should have stuck to my speech.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; What I&#8217;m trying to say is: I just want you to know I am absolutely, positively certain that we can once again lead the world in a way that&#8217;s consistent with who we are as a people, and we can grow this country in ways where we can benefit not only ourselves but the rest of the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And all the things we&#8217;re doing on the climate change side, that’s all technologies we will be able to export and not only help the rest of the world, but make sure that we, in fact, create all these good-paying jobs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For example &#8212; I’ll end with Intel.&nbsp; Intel &#8212; they&#8217;re going to have a total of &#8212; I think it&#8217;s 13,000 jobs on this one site at $20 billion.&nbsp; Well, 7,000 of those jobs are the construction phase; there are four phases.</p>



<p>Well, guess what?&nbsp; The factor is that the remaining jobs &#8212; running the factory &#8212; you know that the average salary is going to be?&nbsp; And you can be a blue-collar worker and still make it.&nbsp; A hundred and thirty-four thousand dollars a year.</p>



<p>We are in a position like no other nation.&nbsp; And we can do it and benefit ourselves while benefiting other countries as well.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, if there was any time to be engaged, I think this is the time.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; I can&#8217;t think of any other time.&nbsp; And again, I&#8217;m a kid who got elected from a, I guess, technically lower middle class &#8212; but a middle-class household when I was 29 years old &#8212; in the United States Senate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And as my Senate colleagues may remember, I used to have the dubious distinction every year of being listed as the poorest man in Congress.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I was making a good salary because I was a senator.</p>



<p>But my generic point is: There&#8217;s nothing we &#8212; beyond our capacity.&nbsp; There really and truly isn’t.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to need your help again in this off-year election, help making sure that we keep the Senate and keep the House.&nbsp; I think we can pick up two Senate seats.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>But I admit to you, what I haven&#8217;t done &#8212; and the reason I&#8217;m getting out on the road again instead of dealing with the day-to-day emergencies in my office &#8212; is making the case of what we&#8217;ve done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I mean this sincerely: No congressional delegation has done more for the things I&#8217;m talking about than your congressmen and senators in this state.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the God’s truth.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>So, if (inaudible) knocking on your door, saying, “I’m trying to raise money to help the following people” &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; you know, just think of &#8212; just think of what our Republican colleagues would do if they win.&nbsp;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE:&nbsp; (Groans.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, no, I’m serious.&nbsp; Think of what they &#8212; and are saying.&nbsp; They’re not kidding about &#8212; and we haven&#8217;t even talked about voting rights and gun violence and criminal justice, immigration &#8212; all things.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we just have &#8212; you know, the good news is we have 50 senators and the Vice President.&nbsp; And the bad news is there are 51 presidents.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Any one can declare themselves president, as two Democrats have.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The idea that somehow we have split the Democratic &#8212; which all people read about is the Democrats are divided.&nbsp; Forty-eight members of the United States Senate have voted with me on 96 percent of the time.&nbsp; Forty-eight.&nbsp; Two have not.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But all kidding aside, think about it.&nbsp; There&#8217;s virtually no Republican support.&nbsp; My &#8212; as my colleagues can tell you &#8212; and, by the way, I&#8217;ve been a guy who&#8217;s not been one of these guys suggesting Democrats are always bad.&nbsp; I mean that sincerely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I had a reputation &#8212; I think my colleagues would tell you &#8212; in the Senate of putting these things together, Democrats and Republicans.</p>



<p>But what&#8217;s happened is that there are a number of Republicans who know better, but they&#8217;re afraid.&nbsp; I know &#8212; I won&#8217;t ask for names, but I&#8217;m sure my colleagues can tell you from the Senate at least six United States senators have come to me and said, “I know &#8212; I know I should vote for this, Joe.&nbsp; But if I do, they’ll primary me and I&#8217;ll be out.”&nbsp; It&#8217;s not very courageous, but this &#8212; the Far Right has taken over that party.</p>



<p>And it&#8217;s not even conservative in a traditional sense of conservative.&nbsp; It&#8217;s mean.&nbsp; It’s ugly.&nbsp; It’s the way &#8212; look what&#8217;s happening down in Florida.&nbsp; (Inaudible), they’re going after Mickey Mouse.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp; I mean, seriously, think about it.&nbsp; As my friend used to say (inaudible), “Who woulda thunk it?”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>Folks, look, I&#8217;ve talked &#8212; spoken too long.&nbsp; I want to thank you for all you did for me last time around.&nbsp; I’m determined to make sure we keep the House and the Senate.&nbsp; And so, thank you for the help you’ve given me before, and I hope you can help the DNC move along and raise money to help these people who are going need our help.</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; And, Governor, (inaudible).&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>4:07 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the Infrastructure Investments Made at Portland International&#160;Airport</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-infrastructure-investments-made-at-portland-international-airport/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Portland Air National Guard BasePortland, Oregon 2:35 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Please have a seat if you have one.&#160; Thank you all very much.&#160; It’s great to be back in Portland.&#160; It’s great to &#8212; and, Lauren, thank you very much for that introduction.&#160; And, Mayor Wheeler, thanks for the passport into the city.&#160; Being&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Portland Air National Guard Base<br>Portland, Oregon</p>



<p>2:35 P.M. PDT<br><br>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Please have a seat if you have one.&nbsp; Thank you all very much.&nbsp; It’s great to be back in Portland.&nbsp; It’s great to &#8212; and, Lauren, thank you very much for that introduction.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, Mayor Wheeler, thanks for the passport into the city.&nbsp; Being a mayor is the toughest job in American politics.&nbsp; They know where you live &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; and they &#8212; everything that affect them, they look to you for answers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Governor Brown, thank you for welcoming me back to Oregon.</p>



<p>And, Colonel, I want to thank you and the 142nd Wing of the Redhawks of Oregon, the Air National Guard for hosting us at the base today.&nbsp; We’re making a lot of work for you.&nbsp; I understand that.</p>



<p>I also want to thank Oregon’s outstanding members of Congress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Ron Wyden.&nbsp; Ron &#8212; Ron has been a leader in the Senate, fighting for clean energy and jobs for a long time.&nbsp; And now he’s chairman of a finance committee, which makes him the king of the Senate.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But we’re going to make sure that teachers and firefighters don’t pay a higher tax than billionaires, which, in many cases, they do.</p>



<p>We’re going to get it done, Ron.&nbsp; We’re going to get it done.</p>



<p>And Senator Jeff Merkley &#8212; a leader on climate and foreign policy.&nbsp; And, you know, we &#8212; we’ve been together &#8212; put together this Bipartisan Infrastructure bill.&nbsp; Jeff was key &#8212; a key leader in getting that done.</p>



<p>He made sure it included the money for wild- &#8212; wildfire prevention, to help prevent and respond to fires like the thousands that burned a half a million acres &#8212; a half a million acres across Oregon last year.&nbsp; All those major fires that took place since I’ve been in office with FEMA &#8212; I’ve been in a helicopter from &#8212; flying &#8212; Northern California through these &#8212; all across the Northeas- &#8212; the Northwest and into the state of Idaho.&nbsp; And it’s just devastating what’s happened, what continues to happen.</p>



<p>And Congressman Pete DeFazio, chair of the Transportation Committee.&nbsp; Pete has helped ensure that we’re going to rebuild the country and we buy American &#8212; we buy American.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, look, the union workers and U.S. steel, we’re going to miss Pete.&nbsp; We’re going to miss you, Pete.&nbsp; I don’t &#8212; I don’t know &#8212; I wish you weren’t leaving.</p>



<p>And Congressman Earl &#8212; where’s Earl?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There &#8212; Earl, thank you.&nbsp; Earl had me ride here on a bicycle.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; But I don’t mind.&nbsp; But I got a new one.&nbsp; I got a &#8212; it’s really not &#8212; anyway.&nbsp; A critical voice in Congress when it comes to investing in infrastructure, Earl helped bring together labor and business to help us get this done.</p>



<p>And Congressman Kurt Schrader, who &#8212; he’s played a key part in the progress we’ve made as a nation on jobs, economic growth, and clean energy.&nbsp; Thank you very much, pal.</p>



<p>And he’s a strong and consistent voice to make sure we modernize our infrastructure and help Oregon and everyone all across America.</p>



<p>You know, the last guy that had this job talked about “Infrastructure Week.”&nbsp; Every week, he’d talk about “Infrastructure Week.”&nbsp; It didn’t come for four years.</p>



<p>Well, I gave you “Infrastructure Decade.”&nbsp; This is for 10 years.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; One trillion four hundred billion dollars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Suzanne, who works tirelessly to ensure that we have left out &#8212; no one is left out, you know, including women and people of color.&nbsp; We’re not &#8212; we’re building a better America.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>When I got elected, I said &#8212; and I meant it &#8212; people weren’t sure I really meant it, but I said, “I want my administration to look like America &#8212; to look like America.”&nbsp; And it does.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; There are more women in my administration than men.&nbsp; There are more women in positions of consequence.&nbsp; There are more African American judges that have been appointed than every other president combined has appointed.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Folks, I want to thank you all for everything you’re doing for the people of Oregon.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re here today to talk about investments we’re making to modernize this airport and this economic engine for the entire region.</p>



<p>Though &#8212; through the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, we’re investing $25 billion to upgrade and modernize American airports, out of the money that is &#8212; the over a trillion dollars we’re spending on infrastructure.</p>



<p>Airports all across America are second rate.&nbsp; I used to tell the story that if, in fact, I dropped you in the middle of the night in an airport in China and an airport in the United States, took the blindfold off, and said, “Where are you?&nbsp; Where are you?,” you’d think the one in China was in America.&nbsp; We are &#8212; we’ve fallen behind.&nbsp; We haven’t invested in ourselves.</p>



<p>And I want to thank Ron and Jeff, Peter, Earl, Kurt, Suzanne for helping prove that America can do big things again.&nbsp; We can do anything we want to do.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>It bothers the heck out of me that there’s this belief that we can’t do big things anymore.&nbsp; But we can.&nbsp; We’re proving we can.&nbsp; And we must build a better America.&nbsp; And a good place to start is right here in Portland.</p>



<p>Folks, look, Portland International Airport is a perfect example of both the need and the opportunity and the ability to make progress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I don’t have to tell you that it’s an essential economic engine for the entire region, not just Portland.&nbsp; A lot of folks may not know it, but this airport employs 10,000 people &#8212; 10,000 people.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Every day, they show up &#8212; airline workers, technicians, retail workers, maintenance staff, and more.</p>



<p>In addition, 20 million people travel from this airport every year, bringing 330,000 metric tons of cargo in and out of this state through this airport, in the air &#8212; shipping seafood from Oregon to fishermen all across America, all across the world, quite frankly; bringing goods from every corner of the country to Oregon homes and businesses.</p>



<p>But here’s the deal.&nbsp; It’s been much too big and too long since America has invested in our own airports, our ports, and our rail.&nbsp; We haven’t done it.</p>



<p>We used to have best infrastructure &#8212; rated the best infrastructure in the world.&nbsp; This is a fact.&nbsp; We are now ranked by the international community as 13th best infrastructure &#8212; 13.&nbsp; The United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve stopped investing in ourselves.&nbsp; We stopped investing in our people.&nbsp; We stopped investing in America.&nbsp; And I know people are tired of hearing me say it, but this time, we’re going to lead the world and invest in ourselves, invest in the nation, and invest in our people.&nbsp; That’s the place to start.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>People kind of forget that America invented modern aviation.&nbsp; But like I said, we’ve allowed our airports to lag far behind our competitors.</p>



<p>I remember, when I was Vice President, I was flying into New York to make a speech.&nbsp; And I landed in New York on Air Force Two in LaGuardia Airport.&nbsp; As I was walking through the terminal to get out to the vehicles, there was a sign on an escalator going to one of the gates saying that, “Out of order.&nbsp; Fixed in two months.” &nbsp;Not a joke.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States of America, in one of the leading cities in the world, and it had a sign saying the escalator to the gate would take two months to be fixed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>At the time, I said if I took the average person, dropped them off, as I said, in LaGuardia or anywhere else, they’d wonder where in God’s name they were.&nbsp; But look, they’d probably think &#8212; they’d probably think they weren’t in America if they didn’t know better.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, folks, by the way, LaGuardia has &#8212; I caused a bit of a stir because I said it publicly, what was happening.&nbsp; And guess what?&nbsp; The governor and legislature decided they had to change things.&nbsp; And they invested $4 billion into one of the great destinations of the world, New York.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>The whole point of telling this story is &#8212; and I realize I’m preaching to the choir &#8212; is we need to invest in American airports and here in Oregon.</p>



<p>As I said earlier, through the Bipartisan Infrastructure bill &#8212; which I might add, I wrote the original one with my own paw; I wrote it.&nbsp; Sat down and wrote it because I was convinced there was no other answer other than beginning to invest in our country again.&nbsp; And we’re investing $25 billion this year to modernize American airports all across this country and across this state, not just here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that includes $211 million this year in Oregon, $42 million being delivered this year alone &#8212; not just to modernize PDX but for 50 additional airports across Oregon, because you’ve got more than one, as you all know.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that’s in addition to the $20 million we invested in PDX last year.</p>



<p>Look, here’s just some of the &#8212; what we’re &#8212; this investment will do.&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, thanks to Ron Wyden and Jeff Merkley and Earl Bam- &#8212; and Earl &#8212; excuse me &#8212;</p>



<p>AUDIENCE MEMBER:&nbsp; (Inaudible.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; I know.&nbsp; You can call me “Bid-en.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Joe Bid-en.</p>



<p>Helping deliver a more resilient, state-of-the-art runway.</p>



<p>You know, I don’t have to tell you or anyone here in Oregon, it sits on a major earthquake zone. &nbsp;And in fact, you had a 4 &#8212; a <s>.4</s> [4.0] magnitude earthquake strike not far from here just two days ago.</p>



<p>Imagine what would happen if that earthquake struck closer to the airport.&nbsp; It wouldn’t just threaten lives, it would threaten to shut down the local economy for a heck of a lot longer than the two months it takes to fix an escalator.</p>



<p>Folks, but your senators and congressmen are looking out for you.&nbsp; They fought to dedicate $3.75 million in the last month’s omnibus bill to build a resilient runway here at PDX.</p>



<p>The project is being modeled on the engineering of an airport that I happened to visit in Japan that remained operational in the face of a devastating earthquake and tsunami in 2011, successfully evacuating families and moving lifesaving supplies because their runway was resilient.&nbsp; It was built resilient in the first place.</p>



<p>Best of all, extensive research shows that every dollar we invest in our resilience of your runway will save $50 down the road by pe- &#8212; keeping this airport operational, safe, and efficient.</p>



<p>But that’s not all we’re doing.&nbsp; You’re in the midst of a $2 billion renovation to build a cutting-edge mai- &#8212; main terminal.</p>



<p>I just saw an incredible component of that terminal being constructed &#8212; 392,000 square feet of roof being built out of what’s known as “mass timber” &#8212; advanced engineering wood design that you’re pioneering right here in Oregon.&nbsp; And it won’t just stay in Oregon.</p>



<p>Almost every single piece of wood being used was substantially harvested from local forests.&nbsp; You can point to any beam, and the folks building it can tell you where it came from.</p>



<p>Best of all, this project will support more than 1,250 good-paying jobs constructing the terminal.&nbsp; Over 95 percent of the construction is being done by union workers.&nbsp; Union.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Someone criticizing me two &#8212; I guess it was now two months ago.&nbsp; They said, “You know, you &#8212; you were using the word ‘union’ more than all presidents combined.”&nbsp; Well, there’s a good reason for that: They’re the best workers in the world.&nbsp; There’s a reason why it makes sense to have a union worker.&nbsp; They train like &#8212; it’s like going to college to get that apprenticeship.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>And in addition to that, they are the &#8212; they get it done on time and with the best possible results you can get.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We already nearly have 280 contracts amounting to $80 million that have gone out to small businesses that are minority-owned and women-owned and veteran-owned, lifting up the economy for everyone.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And this is just the start.&nbsp; Because of the Infrastructure Law, we’re going to see modern baggage claim area, improved taxi-ways, and, yes, better escalators.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>And, you know, the investment all across Oregon is going to continue, like was mentioned earlier, by Coos Bay.&nbsp; You know, we’ve delivered nearly $33 million in January to modernize the main jetty, making it safer and more efficient for ships, boaters, and fishermen.</p>



<p>And improving the capacity of that port is something Ron Wyden and Pete DeFazio in particular have been fighting for for a long time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All across Oregon, we’re sending the message: These ports and airports are open for more business.&nbsp; And we’re seeing &#8212; and we’re sending the same message &#8212; the same message about your roads and your bridges.</p>



<p>Right now, there are nearly 400 bridges and about 1,300 miles of highway in poor condition just here in Oregon.&nbsp; It’s estimated that driving on those roads that need repair costs Oregon drivers an extra $256 a year in gas, repairs, and longer commute times.&nbsp; That’s a $256 hidden tax on Oregon drivers.</p>



<p>And thanks to the Infrastructure Law, we’re making the most significant investment to modernize roads and bridges in the last 70 years since Eisenhower’s Interstate Highway System.</p>



<p>This year alone, we’re delivering $662 million to fix roads and bridges in Oregon, plus an additional $53 million in dedicated funding for bridges.</p>



<p>We’re also going to start replacing 100 percent &#8212; 100 percent of the lead pipes and water serv- &#8212; and water lines that go into homes and schools in this country.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’ve got an estimated 14,000 lead service lines here in Oregon.&nbsp; Because of the Infrastructure Law, we’re getting rid of the poisonous pipes and delivering 92 million to Oregon &#8212; dollars to Oregon this year to provide clean and safe water, because every American, every child &#8212; (applause) &#8212; should be able to turn on a faucet and drink water that’s clean.&nbsp; And it’ll also create thousands of good-paying jobs for plumbers and pipefitters in the process.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, Ron and Jeff and Earl and Kurt and Suzanne, we all share a core belief that high-speed Internet is essential to success in the 21st century.&nbsp; But today, more than 1 in 10 Oregon households don’t have high-speed Internet.</p>



<p>And the law delivers &#8212; this law delivers $100 million to Oregon to make high-speed Internet affordable and available everywhere in the state &#8212; urban, suburban, and rural &#8212; (applause) &#8212; creating jobs for union technicians laying down those broadband lines.</p>



<p>Never again should a parent have to sit in their car, drive to a McDonald’s parking lot, sit there with their child to get online so they can do their homework, which was happening during the pandemic.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The law also builds up our resilience to extreme weather.&nbsp; Over the last decade, extreme weather has cost the state of Oregon at least $5 billion in damages &#8212; $5 billion.</p>



<p>Our Infrastructure Law upgrades modernizing and the strengthening of transmission lines, helping communities to deal with floods, droughts, wildfires that are only coming with more frequency and ferocity.</p>



<p>Folks, there’s so much more in this law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve made a lot of progress, and the fact is we have an incredible opportunity ahead of us.</p>



<p>But we also know that families are still struggling with higher prices.</p>



<p>I grew up in a family where, when the price of gasoline went up, it was a conversation at the kitchen table because it made a difference to my dad.&nbsp; We felt it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Let’s be absolutely clear about why prices are high now.&nbsp; Two reasons.&nbsp; First, COVID.</p>



<p>The way the global economy works: If a factory in Vietnam makes a computer chip and shuts down due to COVID in Vietnam, the ripple effect can slow down automobile manufacturing in Detroit.&nbsp; So, because of the pandemic, we’ve had disruptions in our supply of important materials, so prices went up.</p>



<p>Just look at automobiles.&nbsp; Last year, they accounted for one third of all the inflation in America.&nbsp; One third was because if automobile companies couldn’t get computer chips and the price of automobiles skyrocketed because there was fewer &#8212; significant demand because the economy was growing, but no availability.</p>



<p>So I’m calling on Congress to pass the bipartisan Innovation Bill to make more of these chips here at home and speed up the supply chains.</p>



<p>And folks, with regard to supply chains, let me say one thing: There’s a little outfit called Intel.&nbsp; The chairman of the board of Intel asked can he come and see me in Washington.&nbsp; And he said he wanted to invest $20 billion in a computer chip factory he was going to build just outside of Cleveland &#8212; $20 billion.</p>



<p>It was going to create thousands of jobs building the facility and thousands of jobs running the facility.&nbsp; Average wage once the facility was built: $132,000.&nbsp; This is &#8212; and now he’s &#8212; if you guys pass and get me that other bill on my desk, he’s prepared to invest another $100 billion &#8212; $100 billion in that same facility.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And what everybody forgets: We invented the damn thing.&nbsp; We invented the computer chip.&nbsp; Not a joke.&nbsp; And all the progress, all the change has come from American technology.&nbsp; We don’t make them any more, basically.&nbsp; But now we’re changing that.</p>



<p>The second big reason for inflation is gas prices &#8212; and it’s Vladimir Putin’s gas price increase.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Putin’s invasion in Ukraine has driven up gas prices and food prices all around the world.&nbsp; We saw that in the most recent inflation data.</p>



<p>Last month, 70 percent of the increase in inflation was a consequence of Putin’s price hike because of the impact on gas and energy prices.</p>



<p>I’m doing everything I can to bring down the price to address Putin’s price hike.&nbsp; That’s why I authorized the release of 1 million barrels per day for the next six months from our Strategic Petroleum Reserve, and I worked with oil-producing [countries] to ramp up production.</p>



<p>I coordinated the release with our partners all around the world, because I spent a lot of time with them.&nbsp; And they agreed &#8212; over 30 countries agreed to release 60 million additional barrels over the same period for another 240 million barrels over the next six months &#8212; the largest collective reserve release in history.&nbsp; Nations coming together to help deny ability to Putin to weaponize his energy resources against American families and families in Europe and around the world.</p>



<p>And Americans should be seeing some savings, which you’ve already seen in the price of gas coming down.&nbsp; But we need to do something else.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need to get off this rollercoaster of relying on oil.&nbsp; We need to declare America’s energy independence.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We need to accelerate our path to clean, renewable energy that includes adoption of electric &#8212; adaptation of electric vehicles, like cars, trains, school buses, and transit.&nbsp; We found new battery technology that is just amazing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Beyond the price &#8212; beyond gas prices, I’ve called on Congress to move immediately to lower the cost of families’ utility bills, prescription drug costs while lowering the deficit and reducing inflationary pressure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Folks, I&#8217;ll give you one example.&nbsp; There&#8217;s over 200,000 children in America with Type 1 diabetes.&nbsp; They need that vial of insulin all the time.&nbsp; If they don&#8217;t get it &#8212; you know what the average cost for that is nationwide?&nbsp; Six hundred and forty-seven dollars.&nbsp; That&#8217;s how much it costs them a month.</p>



<p>Not only is it a concern if you don&#8217;t have the insurance, you don&#8217;t have the income.&nbsp; Imagine being the parent robbed of your dignity, knowing you don&#8217;t have the ability to help your child at all and seeing what&#8217;s happening.&nbsp; You know how much it cost them to make that one vial?&nbsp; Ten &#8212; T-E-N &#8212; dollars.&nbsp; Ten dollars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With a little bit of help &#8212; and I know my colleagues support me &#8212; with a little bit of help and a few Republicans getting out of the way in the United States Congress, because none of them are helping, we can lower that price to $35 a month and they’d still make three and a half times what they paid for it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>It would make a big difference in families’ lives.&nbsp; We can do it without raising taxes a penny on anyone making under $400,000.&nbsp; No one making under 400 grand would see a penny in their taxes go up.&nbsp; That’s the best way Congress can address inflation right now: lower the cost of other things for people &#8212; everyday people working like hell just to keep food on the table.</p>



<p>Let me close with this: When I was running for office &#8212; I&#8217;m sure you’ve heard me say it a thousand times &#8212; I was going to build this economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; Because when that happens, everybody does well.&nbsp; The wealthy do very, very well.&nbsp; The poor have a way up.&nbsp; And the middle class can grow, as my dad would say, and just have a little bit of breathing room.&nbsp; Just a little bit of breathing room.</p>



<p>So we’re going to deal in the people and the places that have been left out and left behind.&nbsp; We’re making progress.</p>



<p>Over the course of my presidency, our recovery has created 7.9 million jobs &#8212; (applause) &#8212; more jobs created over the first 14 months of my presidency than any presidency in American history.</p>



<p>Over 420,000 manufacturing jobs.&nbsp; Who says we can&#8217;t manufacture our way through all of this?&nbsp; We have the best workers in the world.&nbsp; Not a joke.</p>



<p>Unemployment nationwide is at 3.6 percent, down from 6.4 percent when I took office 19 months ago &#8212; the fastest decline in unemployment at the start of a term of a President ever recorded.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Oregon, you’ve just added 122,000 jobs, and unemployment has dropped from 6.4 percent to 3.8 percent.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Last year and during all this time &#8212; don’t listen to my Republican friends in Congress &#8212; last year, we reduced &#8212; my budget reduced the &#8212; the deficit by $350 billion.&nbsp; You hear me?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; We didn’t spend &#8212; we didn’t increase the deficit a penny.&nbsp; We reduced it by $350 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And the budget that I submitted, (inaudible) getting done &#8212; this year, in 2022, we’re on track to reduce the deficit by more than $1.3 trillion &#8212; $1.3 trillion &#8212; (applause) &#8212; the largest one-year reduction in the deficit in American history.</p>



<p>This is particularly important now as we work to reduce pressure on inflation.</p>



<p>Oregon and America have gone from being on the mend to being on the move.&nbsp; We just go to get the hell out of our own way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we’re coming &#8212; we’re coming forward with challenges &#8212; challenges from strength positions that we’re in, not like we&#8217;ve been before.&nbsp; I&#8217;m more optimistic about America’s potential today than I’ve been any time in my career &#8212; and I&#8217;ve been doing this job in national politics for a long time &#8212; because I see a future that is without limit.</p>



<p>I mean, this is the United States of America, for God’s sake.&nbsp; We’re the only nation in the world &#8212; this is a fact; look it up &#8212; the only nation in the world that’s come out of every crisis stronger than when we went into the crisis &#8212; stronger every single time.</p>



<p>I was with Xi Jinping, who &#8212; I&#8217;ve traveled with 17,000 miles with him and spent more time with than any other world leader over a total of, I think &#8212; and we&#8217;re up to ni- &#8212; 90-some hours of talking or meeting together over the last six, seven years.</p>



<p>And we were in the foothills of the Tibet.&nbsp; And he asked me &#8212; he said &#8212; I had a translator and he had a simultaneous translator.&nbsp; And he said, “Can you define America for me?”&nbsp; This is a true story; he repeats it.&nbsp; I said, “Yeah, I can, in one word.”&nbsp; And he looked at me and said, “What do you mean ‘in one word’?”&nbsp; I said, “Possibilities.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Anything is possible in America.&nbsp; Anything is po- &#8212; and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re &#8212; exactly we&#8217;re going to do today: Do what we are capable of doing &#8212; stop feeling sorry for ourselves, get the hell up, and take this country back in a way that we lead the world again.&nbsp; Because we can do it, we’re on the way to doing it, and with the help of your delegation, we’re going to get it done.&nbsp; I mean it.&nbsp; (Applause.) There&#8217;s nothing beyond our capacity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>God bless you all.&nbsp; And may God protect our troops.&nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&nbsp; Appreciate it.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>3:00 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris on the Administration&#8217;s Commitment to Improve Maternal&#160;Health</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-on-the-administrations-commitment-to-improve-maternal-health/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51588</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UCSF Mission Bay Medical CenterSan Francisco, California 2:12 P.M. PDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Please, have a seat.&#160; Please, have a seat.&#160; Adrienne, thank you so very much for telling your story and for your courage and for your fortitude and all that you do.&#160; Thank you for that. I’ve spent a good deal of time&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>UCSF Mission Bay Medical Center<br><em>San Francisco, California</em></em></p>



<p>2:12 P.M. PDT<br><br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Please, have a seat.&nbsp; Please, have a seat.&nbsp; Adrienne, thank you so very much for telling your story and for your courage and for your fortitude and all that you do.&nbsp; Thank you for that.<br><br>I’ve spent a good deal of time this afternoon with many women who, really, I’ve said to you &#8212; I see many of you in the audience &#8212; your voices are so important.&nbsp; And you are speaking for women around our country, and you are bringing them here in this room as part of this conversation.&nbsp; And it’s such an important conversation to happen, not just because we’re talking about it but because we’re actually going to do something about it.<br><br>And all of this is a reminder of why this work is so essential and so urgent.&nbsp;<br><br>So, it is good to be here &#8212; to be here with the Administrator of the&nbsp;Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, Chiquita Brooks-LaSure.&nbsp; Thank you, Madam Administrator.&nbsp; As well as our Senator, Dianne Feinstein.&nbsp; It’s good to be with you.&nbsp; And our Lieutenant Governor, Eleni Kounalakis.&nbsp; Mayor London Breed is here.&nbsp; And to all the local and statewide elected leaders.&nbsp;<br><br>Thank you all for the work you do every day.<br><br><br>So, I want to also say to all the healthcare professionals: Thank you for the work you do every day.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Yes.<br><br>You know, over the course of these last two years, we have certainly thanked the healthcare professionals for the work that you have done during these most difficult days of this pandemic; and your relentlessness, your conviction to help those, many of whom are perfect strangers to you; and the risk that you have taken and that you have taken for your own self &#8212; and also a risk that it could be presented to your families &#8212; for coming to work every day to concern yourself with the health and wellbeing of so many people.<br><br>And then, in particular, to the healthcare workers who are here today who work on this important issue: You do this work every day, and it is work that protects our mothers, our sisters, our aunties, our daughters.&nbsp; And it is work that lifts up whole communities.<br><br>As Vice President of the United States, I can tell you I do believe that our nation is facing a crisis on the issue of maternal health.&nbsp; It’s real.&nbsp; And it is impacting so many women and their families and communities.<br><br>Before, during, and after childbirth, women in our nation are dying at a higher rate from pregnancy-related causes than in any other wealthy or developed nation in our world.<br><br>And we know that, for certain women, the risk is much higher, regardless of income level, regardless of education level.<br><br>Black women are three times as likely to die from pregnancy-related complications.&nbsp; Native women are more than twice as likely to die.&nbsp; And women who live in rural America, where there are many maternal care deserts, they are about 60 percent more likely to die.&nbsp;<br><br>And a big factor which continues to these outcomes, of course, is systemic inequities.&nbsp; The differences in how people are treated based on who they or where they live.&nbsp; These differences create significant disparities, then, in how women experience the healthcare system &#8212; disparities that are often a matter of life and death.<br><br>We must also recognize that when women do not get the healthcare they need, families suffer, communities suffer, and our nation suffers.<br><br>In fact, one estimate suggests that in a single year, the direct and indirect cost of poor maternal healthcare could be more than $30 billion.&nbsp; Thirty billion dollars.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>For years,&nbsp;I have worked to make sure our nation treats maternal mortality as the national crisis it is.<br><br>As a United States senator proudly representing the great state of California &#8212; (applause) &#8212; together with Congresswoman Alma Adams, I introduced one of the first bills in the history of the United States Senate to target racial disparities&nbsp;and implicit bias in the healthcare system.&nbsp; That bill we named the Maternal CARE Act.<br><br>With Congresswoman Adams and Congresswoman Lauren Underwood, I worked to improve maternal nutrition and expand affordable housing &#8212; (baby cries) &#8212; and to grow our maternal health workforce to include more doulas and midwives so that we can have babies with healthy lungs.&nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&nbsp; That’s a good sign.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>In the Senate, I introduced the Black Maternal Health Momnibus Act.&nbsp;<br><br>And I believe we must create a more community-based approach&nbsp;to maternal healthcare.&nbsp;<br><br>I also believe that we must collectively, all of us, speak and name out loud the issues that cause so many women to experience complications and, in many cases, to silently suffer &#8212; which is why I worked with Congresswoman Yvette Clarke to take on the issue of fibroids.&nbsp; Through the Uterine Fibroid Research and Education Act, we are addressing an issue that so many women &#8212; and in particular Black women in America &#8212; are dealing with every day.<br><br>As many of you know probably know, in fact, Black women are about three times more likely to be hospitalized because of fibroids.<br><br>So, all of these topics must be elevated as national priorities.&nbsp; And that is why President Joe Biden and I have waged this fight from the White House.<br><br>Last December, our administration convened the first-ever<br>White House Maternal Health Day of Action.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And we announced a $170 million investment in the private sector on the issue of maternal health.<br><br>Last week &#8212; I shared with some of you &#8212; I convened the first-ever Cabinet-level meeting on maternal health.&nbsp; And during that meeting with Secretaries who represent the biggest agencies in our federal government, we discussed the importance &#8212; the importance of seeing and treating women as whole human beings.<br><br>We must understand maternal mortality is not only a healthcare issue, it is also a housing issue, a transportation issue, an environmental issue.<br><br>Think about it: If mothers don’t have a safe and healthy place to live before and after childbirth, they will be at greater risk of adverse outcomes.<br><br>If a woman has no means of getting to the hospital for checkups, it will negatively impact her health.<br><br>And we know air pollution, water pollution, lead in pipes can be an extremely dangerous &#8212; extremely dangerous circumstance to the health of women and newborns.<br><br>If the unique challenges and stressors that women face are not addressed, it will likely increase complications during and after pregnancy.<br><br>All of this is then why our administration is taking a whole-of-government approach, including our entire Cabinet, to address this crisis.<br><br>At the regional and state-government level, our administration have given states the ability to expand Medicaid coverage &#8212; Medicaid coverage for postpartum women from what it is right now, which is 2 months after giving birth, to a full 12 months after giving birth, which means &#8212; which means that more women will have access for a longer period of time to things like pelvic examinations and vaccines and postpartum depression screening and regular checkups.<br><br>In fact, we’re pleased to announce that 11 states are now working with our CMS to expand this essential coverage.&nbsp; And we will continue &#8212; and I do it now &#8212; to call on all states to do the same thing and expand Medicaid coverage to 12 months for postpartum care.&nbsp; (Applause.)<br><br>And as we work then to expand access to healthcare, we are also working to ensure that care fits the needs of the community.&nbsp; And that is why we are here today &#8212; to lift up the tremendous work that is being done by this group of extraordinary leaders.<br><br>Here, at UCSF, at EMBRACE, you have helped build a model for culturally competent care.<br><br>You include partners and family members in perinatal care,<br>through family sessions and trainings.&nbsp; You support patients<br>for a full year after birth to ensure they are staying safe<br>and healthy.&nbsp; You have brought together a staff, who I have met &#8212; an extraordinary staff that reflects the community and understands the community you serve.<br><br>And there is so much more to do.&nbsp; Our administration<br>will continue to do everything in our power to make sure these<br>effective interventions and strategies are adopted far and wide.<br><br>And I will talk about the work that you are all doing as I travel our country as a model of what can be done.<br><br>As I mentioned to many of you this afternoon, you know, sometimes folks, well, they’re clear about what’s wrong, they’re clear about how they feel, how they’re being treated, and what’s not working.&nbsp; But the solution sometimes requires the ability to actually see what is possible to know it is possible and then to refer to it to say this is what should happen where I am and where I live.<br><br>That’s what you all are doing here in being a national model.&nbsp; This is lifting up exactly the design that is necessary to see the kind of outcomes that you all have been producing here on the ground.<br><br>So, I thank you for that.&nbsp; I’m very grateful for that.&nbsp;<br><br>And I’ll end then with this: Women are the pillars of so many families and so many communities.&nbsp; And when women then receive the care they need, by extension it makes families and communities stronger.&nbsp; And I will say to you: It makes<br>our nation stronger.&nbsp; And that will be the case for years and, with the work you are doing, for generations to come.&nbsp;<br><br>So let us all continue to work together to make sure that every woman and every mother in our nation has the care that she needs to thrive, and let us do everything in our power to lift her up knowing that is how we strengthen our entire nation.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I thank you all.&nbsp; God bless you.&nbsp; And God bless America.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 2:26 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Gaggle by Principal Deputy Press Secretary Karine Jean-Pierre, April 21,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/04/21/press-gaggle-by-principal-deputy-press-secretary-karine-jean-pierre-april-21-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aboard Air Force OneEn Route Portland, Oregon 1:32 P.M. EDT MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&#160; Good afternoon, and thanks for joining us on President Biden’s first trip to Oregon and Washington.&#160; I know you all got a background memo last night, but just a few points about this trip I wanted to highlight. The focus of the President’s&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Aboard Air Force One<br>En Route Portland, Oregon</p>



<p>1:32 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Good afternoon, and thanks for joining us on President Biden’s first trip to Oregon and Washington.&nbsp; I know you all got a background memo last night, but just a few points about this trip I wanted to highlight.</p>



<p>The focus of the President’s trip is fourfold.&nbsp; One, to underscore the historic economic growth and nearly 8 million jobs created as a result of his and congressional Democrats’ actions, including the American Rescue Plan and the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, and his administration’s work to lower costs for American families.</p>



<p>Number two, to emphasize the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s historic $25 billion investments in airports, such as Portland International Airport, which is upgrading its south runway so that the runway can survive an earth- &#8212; an &#8212; sorry &#8212; survive an earthquake.&nbsp; In 2022 alone, PDX will receive $20 million in funding from this program.</p>



<p>Number three, to mark Earth Day by speaking to the need to bolster our nation’s resilience in the face of threats like wildfire, and the need to rapidly deploy clean energy.&nbsp; We will have more details on Earth Day announcements later this evening for you all.</p>



<p>And finally, President Biden will call on Congress to pass his plan to lower healthcare and energy costs.&nbsp; He has already taken important steps to lower costs &#8212; from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve release and the extension of E15 gasoline to lower gas prices, to fixing the “family glitch” and enacting the Rescue Plan to save families that buy ACA coverage an average of $59 per person per month.</p>



<p>But he has also laid out an ambitious plan to continue to build on that work and lower the cost of healthcare, including prescription drugs.  And Congress should act on that to ensure lower premiums; close Medi- &#8212; Medicaid coverage <s>cap</s> [gaps]; cap cost-sharing for Insulin; and let Medicare negotiate the price of prescription drugs.</p>



<p>In Portland today, the President will be joined by Governor Kate Brown; Senators Ron Wyden, Jeff Merkley; Representative Earl Blumenauer, Suzanne Bonamici, Peter DeFazio, and Kurt Schrader; and Portland Mayor Ted Wheeler.</p>



<p>And in Seattle tomorrow, he will be joined by Governor Jay Inslee, Senators Pat Murray and Maria Cantwell, Congresswoman Kim Schrier, and other state and local elected officials.</p>



<p>Today, as we get closer to the hot summer months, HHS is announcing more than $385 million to all 50 states, territories, and Tribes to help families lower their home energy costs through the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program &#8212; LIHEAP.</p>



<p>Together with the billions provided in the American Rescue Plan, this brings the total funding for LIHEAP this year to over $8.3 billion &#8212; the most relief ever in the history of the program to lower out-of- &#8212; to lower out-of-pocket heating and cooling costs for hard-pressed American families.</p>



<p>As you all know, we’re headed to the Pacific Northwest, which experienced record heat last year.&nbsp; Extreme heat kills more Americans than any other weather-related event.&nbsp; Over the last 20 years, the frequency of extreme weather events, including extreme heat, has increased dramatically.</p>



<p>Today’s announcement builds on previous LIHEAP funding allocated through the American Rescue Plan, which more than doubled typical annual appropriations.&nbsp; Oregon will receive a record total of $92.6 million in LIHEAP funding, and Washington will receive a record total of $151 million.</p>



<p>This month, President Biden has taken a number of actions to lower prices, including using executive action to fix the “family glitch” in the ACA.&nbsp; And he has taken action on student debt by freezing payments through August, providing immediate student debt cancellation for at least 40,000 borrows &#8212; borrowers, and helping another 3.6 million borrowers move closer to debt relief forgiveness.</p>



<p>Okay.&nbsp; That was a lot.&nbsp; Thanks &#8212; thanks for listening through that, everybody.</p>



<p>All right, Josh.&nbsp; What you got for me? &nbsp;Why don’t you kick us off.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; Thanks, Karine.&nbsp; Two subjects.&nbsp; First, Ukraine: The President talked about military aid today, but Ukraine says it needs $5 billion a month to support its government.&nbsp; Is the U.S. and its allies going to get Ukraine that money?&nbsp; And what would that look like?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, this $500 million combined &#8212; the $500 million today that was announced, combined with the $500 million that President Biden announced in March, is targeted to meet Ukraine’s most acute needs.</p>



<p>We will also continue to work with Congress to find ways to get more resources to Ukraine and bolster their ability to fight the war and restore its economy.</p>



<p>The United States is also committed to working with other bilateral and multilateral donors.&nbsp; For example, the international community has provided and pledged considerable support exceeding $24 billion for 2022 and beyond.&nbsp; And this comes on the top of the economic support provided since 2014 until 2021, which exceeds $60 billion.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, secondly, with regard to Florida, did Governor DeSantis overstep by penalizing Disney on “Don’t Say Gay”?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, our view is this &#8212; is that the “Don’t Say Gay” bill is really crystal clear: It’s wrong.&nbsp; That’s our view: It is just wrong.</p>



<p>We oppose the governor taking action against a company because of their opposition to that bill.&nbsp; And we’re just going to leave it there for now; we’re not going to say anymore to that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, a follow-up &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, go ahead, Jeff.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Excuse me, Josh.&nbsp; A follow-up &#8212; are you sure?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, please.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You guys are so nice to each other today.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; A follow-up on Ukraine.&nbsp; The President said, in his remarks this morning, that he would be asking Congress for more money.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of what dollar figure the administration will be asking for?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Anything in particular you’re talking about?&nbsp; Just &#8212; is it the security or the economic assistance?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All of the above.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All of the above.&nbsp; Okay.&nbsp; So, you know, as the President just said today, as you mentioned: With this latest disbursement, we will have almost exhausted &#8212; as we were talking about the security assistance &#8212; almost exhausted the drawdown authority that Congress authorized for Ukraine in the bipartisan spending bill last month.</p>



<p>We are committed to continuing to provide Ukraine with weapons and equipment that they are using so effectively to defend their country.&nbsp; And the administration will be in touch with Congress, as the mention- &#8212; as the President mentioned in his speech, next week on additional resource requirements to keep weapons and ammunition flowing without interruption to Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we appreciate the bipartisan support that we have seen in Congress, we &#8212; so we have received so far, efforts to support Ukraine, and hope &#8212; and hope that continues.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So you&#8217;ll be putting in a formal ask next week, but can you give us a sense of what that dollar figure will be?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have a dollar figure for you.&nbsp; I think the President was asked this question earlier, and he said that the Department of Defense is working on that right now.&nbsp; But I don&#8217;t have a dollar figure to share with you right &#8212; at this time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; One other issue.&nbsp; Elon Musk has gotten enough &#8212; has gotten funding for his attempt to buy Twitter.&nbsp; What is the White House&#8217;s view right now on Musk and potential ownership of that company by one person?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So I&#8217;m not &#8212; I&#8217;m not &#8212; that&#8217;s something I&#8217;m &#8212; we&#8217;re not going to comment on.&nbsp; The SEC is independent and would handle any review process moving forward, but we&#8217;re not going to comment.&nbsp; That is a private investor, and so we&#8217;re not going to comment on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I do want to add one more thing because the funding information that I gave you, Jeff, was for the security component, but I just want to also give you the economic &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s the Treasury side of that as well.&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; the economic assistance to that too so we just get that on the record.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, as &#8212; what remains there &#8212; there are some funds remaining, as it relates to the economic assistance.&nbsp; And the administration is working to get those out of the door quickly.</p>



<p>The administration will also be in touch with Congress next week, as I just mentioned, on additional resource requirements to continue delivering economic assistance to the Ukrainian people.</p>



<p>Just wanted to make sure that was clear.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The Congress coming back next week &#8212; obviously, a priority for the administration is pushing for a new COVID funding bill.&nbsp; Can you give us a sense of what you&#8217;re doing on that?&nbsp; Is the ask still $10 billion?&nbsp; And is the administration open to joining that with the supplemental ask on Ukraine?&nbsp; Could it be the same funding bill?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, you know, as we have said time and time again &#8212; is, like, we can&#8217;t move forward with securing vaccine as we look at the fourth dose for all Americans.&nbsp; You know, at this time last year, we were in the process of contracting for a booster campaign in the fall.&nbsp; Now we can&#8217;t and &#8212; and risk not having adequate doses if needed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If experts decide we need different vaccines, including a variant-specific vaccine, we don&#8217;t have the funding to secure them, so our testing capacity won&#8217;t be able to support surge demand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Americans could, once again, face empty shelves, as we saw not too long ago.&nbsp; We can&#8217;t buy any more treatments, including preventative treatments for the immune compromised.&nbsp; These treatments take six months to manufacture, so we &#8212; so we&#8217;re &#8212; we risk losing out on supply that we intended to purchase.</p>



<p>So, we can&#8217;t do more to invest in the next-generation vaccines and treatments that will help us be prepared for future variants and provide more durable protection.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, we just want to be very clear: If we don&#8217;t purchase these vaccines and therapies for the American people, other countries will step in to purchase them for their citizens.&nbsp; They already are.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Without new support, we will quickly &#8212; and we will quickly find ourselves at the back of the line for future vaccines, treatments, and tests.</p>



<p>So, this is something that we&#8217;re going to continue to work with Congress on and push for that additional funding.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Do you have a view on whether it can be rolled into the supplemental as well?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Say that one more time.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Could it be packaged in the same bill with Ukraine aid?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don’t have more &#8212; I don’t have more to add.&nbsp; I &#8212; clearly, as I’ve &#8212; we’ve said, that we need more for &#8212; for the economic assistance and security assistance, as I just laid out. I don&#8217;t have anything more on how we&#8217;re going to be packaging any of that.&nbsp; What &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And part of the need is the fact that you owe $5 billion to Pfizer right now for the &#8212; to complete your purchase of Paxlovid.&nbsp; That would chew up half the $10 billion.&nbsp; Is $10 billion still the ask, or is twenty-two and a half still the ask?&nbsp; This &#8212; the USAID money &#8212; how much money are you seeking on COVID?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, are you asking about &#8212; asked me about Plaxlo- &#8212; Paxlovid as &#8212; as it related to the funding?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, you &#8212; yeah, there are 20 million courses of Paxlovid ordered right now.&nbsp; You&#8217;ve only paid for about 11 million out of that.&nbsp; Is that order at risk of going under, if we want to talk about that?&nbsp; But more broadly &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yup.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; what is the total dollar ask?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So it continues to be what we have discussed, which is $22.5 billion.&nbsp; That hasn&#8217;t changed.&nbsp; But on Paxlovid, I&#8217;ll give you an update.</p>



<p>There&#8217;s plenty of supply of Paxlovid available.&nbsp; We get more delivered each week, which we are quickly pushing out to places like pharmacies, hospitals and urgent care centers, nursing homes, and community health centers.&nbsp; There are more than 17,000 locations across the country where people can get prescription filled.&nbsp; It’s not &#8212; it&#8217;s not yet ubiquitous like vaccines are, but we&#8217;re getting there.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;re working to make sure doctors and patients know about Paxlovid.&nbsp; After it was authorized, it was in limited supply.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not &#8212; that&#8217;s not the case anymore.&nbsp; It&#8217;s widely available, and the eligibility criteria are pretty expansive.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, we&#8217;re working to make sure providers and patients know that.&nbsp; And we’re working to make it easier to access.&nbsp; One way is through our new test-to-treat program.&nbsp; It&#8217;s just about a month since the President announced this program, so we already got 2,000 locations up and running.&nbsp; We&#8217;re &#8212; continue to expand it and working our partners to improve patients&#8217; experience.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We need funding to sustain this process to &#8212; this progress and are actively working beyond these actions to increase uptake.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; The President finally was asked about Title 42 today, but he responded by talking about the mask thing.&nbsp; Can I ask the the Title 42 question again?&nbsp; Is the administration open to delaying that in order to get a COVID funding deal?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just clear &#8212; let me just kind of reiterate what the President said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We sent out &#8212; we sent out a pool note to all of you from him, which is &#8212; he &#8212; it says: “I want to clarify that in comments at the conclusion of my remarks this morning, I was referring to the CDC’s mask mandate and there is no Department of Justice action on Title 42.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And just &#8212; also wanted to just reiterate what Jen Psaki said yesterday: The CDC made a determination that it can be lifted on May 23rd.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re working hard to implement a plan to do that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>She also &#8212; she also noted that, “As we prepare for the implementation of the end of Title 42, there are a range of steps that we&#8217;ve been taking to prepare for that, including surging resources, that includes moving officer, agents, DHS Volunteer Force personnel to rapidly decompress points along the border and more effectively process migrants.</p>



<p>It also entails the deployment of COVID-19 mitigation efforts, including the use of &#8212; continued use of PPE, providing the COVID-19 vaccines.&nbsp; It also includes expanding these efforts to cover migrants in CBP custody.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, the point is there are a range of steps in this comprehensive plan that we have to be ready to go by May 23rd.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that a “no” you won’t consider extending Title 42 if that’s what it takes to get COVID money?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, I mean, extending Title 42 is not our decision.&nbsp; As Jen said yesterday, as we’ve been saying, that is Congress’s decision to make.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I have a follow-up on Title &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, go ahead.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No &#8212; I just wanted to ask about the President’s approach to masking.&nbsp; Does he still believe it should be a per- &#8212; an individual choice, even though the Department of Justice is appealing the federal judge’s ruling?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, a couple of things.&nbsp; I just want to lay this out, because I think it’s very important.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, first, you know, we’ve made a lot of progress on COVID.&nbsp; Thanks to vaccines, boosters, and treatments, severe cases of COVID and deaths are down 90 percent since the President entered office.&nbsp; Our economy is growing.&nbsp; Schools are open.&nbsp; People are getting back to work.&nbsp; We can feel much better about how things are today.&nbsp; But we know that this virus is tricky.&nbsp; It’s a tricky virus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There can be new variants, as we have seen. &nbsp;We have to be ready.&nbsp; So, we all know that airplane and train travel are different than most places.&nbsp; You are stuck next to someone for a long time, as we are currently right now.&nbsp; But we have our masks on.&nbsp; And if that person is sick &#8212; if you are sick, you can spread the virus.&nbsp; And young kids can’t get vaccinated &#8212; kids five &#8212; under five years old, as we all know.&nbsp; People with weak immune systems aren’t protected and they need to travel safely.</p>



<p>I know that masks are uncomfortable.&nbsp; We understand that.&nbsp; But masking on planes and trains is a way to protect yourself and others.&nbsp; So, as the CDC recommends, the President thinks you should mask right now, especially as they learn more about BA.2.</p>



<p>The CDC should have the time and authority to make these decisions to protect the American people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re in a much better place now with &#8212; on COVID as I just listed out.&nbsp; But if things get worse or in the event of another public health crisis, CDC must have the essential public health authority, now and in the future, and the principle that public health decisions should be made by public health authorities.&nbsp; That is what is at stake right now, and that’s what the President stands on.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, the U.S. military is sending specialized weapons that suit Ukraine&#8217;s military needs.&nbsp; We are asking for hundreds of millions of dollars in military aid to send to the Ukrainians.&nbsp; The President is using active language to describe our involvement in this war.&nbsp; “…<s>walk</s> [speak] softly and carry a <s>big</s> [large] Javelin,” he said this morning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Is this a sign that Americans are going to continue to hear from him, even on a week-by-week basis as &#8212; does this mean we&#8217;re just going to continue to escalate our involvement in this war?&nbsp; And is this something Americans should just expect, even on a weekly basis?&nbsp; Where is this going?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, let me just say a couple of things there.&nbsp; You know, the latest &#8212; the latest steps today that the President announced and talked about in his speech was to support the people of Ukraine, which is important as they&#8217;re protecting their democracy; to hold Putin accountable for the brutal and bloody war.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m just very much reiterate &#8212; reiterating what the President said today.</p>



<p>You know, Russia has launched a refocus campaign, as we have been talking about, to seize new territory in eastern Ukraine.&nbsp; And we are in a critical window that &#8212; that will set the stage for the next phase of this war, as you have heard us talk about.&nbsp; So, you know, the U.S. and our Allies and our partners are moving as fast as possible to make sure that the Ukrainian forces have the weapons and equipment to defend their nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so that is what we&#8217;re supporting &#8212; not just us alone, but in a &#8212; with our &#8212; again, our partners and Allies as we see a strong Western force here.&nbsp; And so this is why Ukraine has been able to stop &#8212; to stop Russia from taking over their country.&nbsp; This is what we have seen because we have come together &#8212; together to make sure to give them what they need.</p>



<p>And we&#8217;re not sitting on the funding that Congress is providing for us to &#8212; is providing for us to give to Ukraine.&nbsp; And so, this is &#8212; this is what we&#8217;re &#8212; this is the announcement that he made today.</p>



<p>And he was asked &#8212; the President was asked how much longer can we do this for.&nbsp; And he said, you know, we can sustain this; we can continue to do this.&nbsp; He said the most important thing is to make sure that we are continuing to be aligned with our partners and Allies.&nbsp; And so that is going to be the focus, and we&#8217;re going to continue to help the Ukrainian people &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Jake &#8212; sorry to cut you off, but Jake came out a couple of weeks ago in the briefing room, after the reports in Bucha, and talked about the evidence gathering that would be required to declare Putin a war criminal in Russia, culpable of war crimes.&nbsp; Reports of widespread rapes and sexual violence have been cropping up of &#8212; about what&#8217;s going on across Ukraine.&nbsp; Where is the evidence gathering &#8212; what&#8217;s the status of that, and what&#8217;s going on?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have that &#8212; I don’t have anything to provide to you right now.&nbsp; That&#8217;s something that the State Department clearly has the authority and is handling that process.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, as you&#8217;ve heard, the President has been very clear in calling it a war crime, and that is something that he believes.&nbsp; But I &#8212; we&#8217;re going to leave that to the State Department to go through the legal process.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, two questions for you.&nbsp; One, the President is going to Seattle later today and then to talk tomorrow about climate and his agenda.&nbsp; What is the President &#8212; or what should Americans &#8212; Democrats, voters &#8212; expect to hear from the President?&nbsp; He came into office with this expansive proposal to fight and combat climate change.&nbsp; That seems to have stalled in Congress.&nbsp; This is a big priority for many Democrats, as you outlined in some of the announcements you&#8217;re going to make.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But on the whole, the President&#8217;s climate agenda has really stalled in Congress and in the courts, and so I’m wondering what voters &#8212; Democrats, Americans &#8212; should expect to hear from the President, given that the promises and the ambition that he showed running for President and then in the early months of his administration have largely not come to fruition?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, just to &#8212; tomorrow is Earth Day, so we’ll have &#8212; we’ll provide more information on what tomorrow will look like and what the President will have to say.</p>



<p>But, look, the President is committed to doing everything he can to address &#8212; you know, to reach his climate goals.  And so he is committed and will continue to be committed.</p>



<p>You know, he has mobilized a whole-of-government effort in every sector of the economy &#8212; sorry, Jeff &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; It’s fine.</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; &#8212; taking executive actions that will reduce greenhouse gas emissions, accelerate clean energy production and deployment, and create good-paying jobs that strengthen the economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, tomorrow &#8212; I mean, today, in just &#8212; in a little bit, he&#8217;ll talk about the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, which is a big part of &#8212; which is a big part of his &#8212; you know, reaching his climate goals.</p>



<p>But the administration approved the first largescale projects identifying new and energy areas in the Atlantic and the Pacific, and holding a record-breaking $4.3 billion lease sale in a New York Bight, putting his major new industry on track to achieve the President&#8217;s bold goal of deploying 30 gigawatts of offshore and wind by 2030, all while creating good-paying union jobs up and down the supply chain.</p>



<p>We fast-tracked clean energy projects to bring jobs and savings to communities by providing record levels of solar and other renewable &#8212; renewables on public lands, helping local governments advance community solar projects and rooftop installations, and launching a new initiative to deploy distributed energy resources in disadvantaged communities.</p>



<p>President Biden rallied automakers and autoworkers around an electric transportation future, setting a national target of 50 percent electric vehicle sales share in 2030 and spurring investments in new American factories to manufacture EVs and batteries and chargers.</p>



<p>Last year, the administration also launched an EV Charging Action Plan to deploy $7.5 billion from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law, as I just mentioned, to build out a national charge network that is &#8212; that is convenient, reliable, and equitable through a new joint office of energy and transportation.&nbsp; And we finalized the strongest passenger vehicle standards in American history to increase average fuel economy to 49 &#8212; 49 miles per gallon; reduce to &#8212; reduce greenhouse gas emissions; and protect communities from pollu- &#8212; pollution; and save drivers money at the pump.</p>



<p>So, it’s &#8212; we &#8212; you know, we&#8217;re cont- &#8212; the President has climate goals, and he wants to continue to fight for climate control, and he&#8217;s going to continue to do that.  And he has used the power of his office to do that.  So we&#8217;re not going to stop at just &#8212; what I just laid out.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; No, I hear that.&nbsp; But at the same time, the administration has issued a waiver on E15, which environmentalists are &#8212; and climate groups are concerned will hamper those goals.&nbsp; The administration has opened up more leases for drilling in oil.&nbsp; And today, John Kerry told my colleagues that he doesn&#8217;t see proof that nations are following through on their commitments to slow Earth’s warming.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So are there concerns or concessions from the White House that it has not done enough to meet the ambitious climate goals that the President has set out?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; That is &#8212; that is not what we believe.&nbsp; We are going to continue to meet our climate goals.&nbsp; I mean, look, you talked about E15.&nbsp; The President is committed to doing everything that he can to address the pain Americans are feeling at the pump.&nbsp; You know, that was one of the reasons he made that announcement.</p>



<p>You know, but our &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sorry, just to &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yeah.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Is that in &#8212; is trying to ensure that people don&#8217;t feel pain at the pump, is that in conflict with the President&#8217;s climate goals?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; No, we don’t &#8212; look, our strategy from day one has been to meet folks where they are.&nbsp; It&#8217;s about delivering solutions that help people take on the real challenges of real life.&nbsp; Addressing the emergency supply crunch while accelerating clean energy efforts is fully consistent with the theory of the case and what we&#8217;re trying to do.</p>



<p>We believe we can walk and chew gum, because families need to take their kids to school and go to work, get groceries, and go about their lives.&nbsp; And sometimes that requires gas today, this month, and this year.&nbsp; But at the very same time, we must speed up, not slow down, our transition to clean energy.&nbsp; So we are &#8212; we believe we&#8217;re going to reach our goals, and we are very committed to doing that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Karine, on masks, does the Biden administration plan to ask for an emergency stay to immediately reimpose the mask mandate on public transit?&nbsp; Is that something you all are considering at this point?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, (inaudible), I don&#8217;t have “JD” at the last &#8212; at the end my name.&nbsp; I&#8217;m not a legal strategist.&nbsp; I refer you to the DOJ; that is in their purview.</p>



<p>What I&#8217;ll say is that the CDC believes masking is needed right now.&nbsp; And DOJ is appealing accordingly.&nbsp; DOJ has a duty to preserve CDC’s authority in the event of the current and future public health crisis.&nbsp; And this is a route that ensures we do both.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then, on Title 42, just to loop back to that, what is the &#8212; how is the administration going to help the smaller border towns who say they expect a large influx of immigrants crossing over the border if Title 42 is ended?&nbsp; What are they doing to help?&nbsp; Is that &#8212; is that more agents?&nbsp; Is that more money?&nbsp; What is the plan for those towns?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, as we&#8217;ve been talking about, DHS has a plan.&nbsp; DHS is implementing a comprehensive strategy to address &#8212; to address a potential increase in the number of border encounters.&nbsp; Their strategy includes acquiring and deploying resources to address increased volumes; that involves moving officers, agents, DHS Volunteer Force personnel to rapidly decompress points along the border and more efficiently process migrants.&nbsp; It also entails the deployment of COVID-19 mitigation efforts, including the continued use of PPE and providing the COVID-19 vaccines to non-citizens in ICE custody since summer of 2021.</p>



<p>Beginning March 28, 2022, DHS expanded those efforts to cover migrants in CBP custody so as to further safeguard public health and ensure the safety of border communities, the workforce, and migrants.&nbsp; And so that is what DHS has a comprehensive plan, and they&#8217;ll be executing that, and they have been.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And then last one for me &#8212; I&#8217;m sorry if this is repetitive; it&#8217;s hard to hear on the plane.&nbsp; But in terms of Ukraine, as it looks more likely that the war is going to be going on for quite some time, is there talk of allowing more complex systems like Patriot missiles that would take longer to train up but could have a bigger effect on protecting Ukraine and the airspace?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, any specific materials that you just laid &#8212; that you just mentioned, I would refer you to the Department of Defense.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t have anything here to preview on that.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; I just had another one.&nbsp; Increasingly, we&#8217;re seeing talks from Republicans directed at Democrats, allegations of grooming around LGBTQ issues.&nbsp; There was that speech that went viral from a Democrat state lawmaker in Michigan that rebutted some attacks against her of allegations of grooming.</p>



<p>From the White House&#8217;s perspective, these attacks that we&#8217;re seeing from Republicans &#8212; allegations, unsubstantiated &#8212; against Democrats, does the White &#8212; does the President plan to call out these attacks?&nbsp; Is this something that the White House is aware of, concerned about?&nbsp; Any comment that you might have on the increasing allegations that we&#8217;ve seen?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE: &nbsp;You mean like the attacks on the LGBTQ community and &#8212; in particular?&nbsp; Or &#8212;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (Inaudible) but even also broader on Democrats and allegations &#8212; again, unsubstantiated &#8212; about grooming and things of that nature, as we saw &#8212; I don&#8217;t know if you saw the video of the Michigan &#8212;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; I’d have to say, I actually have &#8212; I heard of the video, but I have not watched it in its entirety.&nbsp; I’ve only seen clips of it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, the President has always stand &#8212; stood with the LGBTQ community in supporting them and seeing them &#8212; that community.&nbsp; Clearly, any attacks or &#8212; that we are seeing &#8212; you know, I was just asked about what Governor DeSantis is doing in Florida with Disney.&nbsp; And so, we think that type of behavior is wrong.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;ve been very clear about that at the podium.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve been very clear about that anytime you all ask &#8212; ask us.</p>



<p>I have not had a conversation with the President &#8212; or we haven’t &#8212; about if he is &#8212; you know, what &#8212; if he&#8217;s going to say anything himself.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But he has put out at least &#8212; you know, behind a podium or at &#8212; you know, at a mic, but we have put out statements in his voice when it comes to attacks that we have seen in that community specifically.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;ve been very clear on that.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Just to follow up on Tyler&#8217;s question: The point is not necessarily attacks against the LGBT &#8212; the LGBT community; it&#8217;s rather Republicans accusing Democrats of being sexual predators and making that a broad strategy as an attack on the opp- &#8212; on the other party.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Well, you know, look, I asked if it was about the LGBT community.&nbsp; He said “yes.”&nbsp; But I hear your question.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, it&#8217;s &#8212; what the Republicans are doing is unfortunate.&nbsp; You know, instead of talking about the issues that&#8217;s going on currently, right now, with the pain the American families are feeling, and coming to the table and having a real discussion on how to &#8212; how to make Americans’ lives better, they want to have a culture war.&nbsp; And that &#8212; and that is unfortunate to see.&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to be steadfast and focused on what&#8217;s at &#8212; what&#8217;s at hand.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Today we&#8217;re going to be &#8212; we&#8217;re going to be in Portland, as you all know, and we’re going to talk about the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law &#8212; which, by the way, as you all know, Republicans in Congress were able to come together with Democrats and we got something done &#8212; something that was historic, something that&#8217;s going to change the lives of American people, something that&#8217;s going to create jobs, that&#8217;s going to rebuild our infrastructure deal with supply chain as we&#8217;re &#8212; as we&#8217;re trying to, you know, deal with this once-in-a-generation pandemic.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what we want to see.&nbsp; That&#8217;s what the President was elected to do &#8212; is to bring people together and get things done.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to talk about today, and that&#8217;s what we&#8217;re going to talk about tomorrow in Seattle.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; President Biden in New Hampshire and in Iowa and, perhaps today, has put his foot forward on the deficit a lot.&nbsp; He&#8217;s talking a lot more about the deficit, including touting his proposal as an immediate deficit-cutting measure.&nbsp; I wanted &#8212; I wonder if you can talk about that shift.&nbsp; BBB used to &#8212; he used to talk about it cutting the deficit in the long term, and now he talks about it in the short term.&nbsp; Seems to be an olive branch to Senator Manchin.&nbsp; How big a priority is immediate deficit reduction for President Biden?&nbsp;</p>



<p>And &#8212; because Manchin has talked about a bill that is sort of half deficit reduction.&nbsp; In other words, half the &#8212; you know, only half the new revenue would be spent and, therefore, the deficit would be immediately driven down.&nbsp; Is that something he would support?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; So, look, I &#8212; you know, as we&#8217;ve been saying for the past several months, I &#8212; we&#8217;re not just &#8212; we&#8217;re just not going to negotiate in public.&nbsp; Clearly, this is &#8212; when we think about Build Back Better &#8212; we took it &#8212; think about build &#8212; building back a better America, that is something that&#8217;s important to the President.&nbsp; And so, we&#8217;re going to continue to &#8212; continue to work towards that and continue to talk to folks on Congress, but I don&#8217;t have any specific details to share.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; He’s kind of negotiating in public though, a little bit, by telling Senator Manchin that he&#8217;s open to it.&nbsp; Isn’t he?</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; You know, I &#8212; right here, on this plane, I don&#8217;t have anything to share or any specifics (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; All right.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; All right, thanks.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Can I just ask one more, Karine, as we &#8212;</p>



<p>Sorry, a quick one.&nbsp; Does the President still have confidence that Mayor Garcetti has the support in Congr- &#8212; in the Senate to be confirmed as Ambassador to India?&nbsp;</p>



<p>MS. JEAN-PIERRE:&nbsp; Yes, he has confidence in Mayor Garcetti to &#8212; to move forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>All right.&nbsp; Thank you.&nbsp;</p>



<p> 2:05 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Letter to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and President of the Senate on Providing Notice of Intent to Designate Colombia as a Major Non-NATO&#160;Ally</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/04/21/letter-to-the-speaker-of-the-house-of-representatives-and-president-of-the-senate-on-providing-notice-of-intent-to-designate-colombia-as-a-major-non-nato-ally/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:27:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51578</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:) In accordance with section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k), I am providing notice of my intent to designate Colombia as a Major Non-NATO Ally. I am making this designation in recognition of the importance of&#160;the U.S.-Colombia relationship and Colombia&#8217;s crucial contributions&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Dear Madam Speaker: (Dear Madam President:)</p>



<p>In accordance with section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended (22 U.S.C. 2321k), I am providing notice of my intent to designate Colombia as a Major Non-NATO Ally.</p>



<p>I am making this designation in recognition of the importance of&nbsp;the U.S.-Colombia relationship and Colombia&#8217;s crucial contributions to regional and international security.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Sincerely,</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris After Air Force Two&#160;Arrival</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/04/21/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-after-air-force-two-arrival/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 20:18:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=51575</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[San Francisco International AirportSan Francisco, California Q    Two questions for you, to start. THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; (Inaudible).&#160; (Laughs.) Q&#160;&#160;&#160; Okay, two questions for you.&#160; First, do you have any reaction to the latest sanctions from Russia that would bar your entry into the country? And then, second, on Title 42, would you be in favor&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>San Francisco International Airport</em><em><br><em>San Francisco, California</em></em></p>



<p>Q    Two questions for you, to start.</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; (Inaudible).&nbsp; (Laughs.)</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Okay, two questions for you.&nbsp; First, do you have any reaction to the latest sanctions from Russia that would bar your entry into the country?</p>



<p>And then, second, on Title 42, would you be in favor of delaying the ending of it, especially as a few members of your own party have kind of pushed back?&nbsp; Is that something that’s under consideration?</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; So, let’s be very clear about where we stand in terms of Russia: As far as I’m concerned — and I think, objectively, many people will agree — that their invasion of Ukraine has not only been steeped in atrocities but will proof to be a strategic failure for Russia.</p>



<p>What we have done most recently, and the President did a speech this morning talking about what we will continue to do as a — one of our highest commitments to continue to support the Ukrainian people, President Zelenskyy with what we can in terms of economic assistance, humanitarian assistance.&nbsp; But also, with equal fervor, we are absolutely committed to continuing with the serious consequences and costs to Russia of its act of aggression and, as the President has rightly said, with its criminal conduct.</p>



<p>And so that has included what we will continue to do to issue sanctions, as we just announced, but all with an understanding that one of our highest priorities is sovereignty and territorial integrity as a — is solid principle that binds and unifies the NATO Alliance, to your point about NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so we’re going to continue to do that work, and we’re not going to give up.</p>



<p>Thank you. &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; END</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
