<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 16:34:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden During a White&#160;House Conversation on Youth Mental&#160;Health</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/18/remarks-by-first-lady-jill-bidenduring-a-white-house-conversation-on-youth-mental-health/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 16:33:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The White House, East Room 11:03 A.M. EDT THE FIRST LADY:  Okay, I guess &#8212; yes, there we go.  Thank you.  And welcome to the White House.  (Applause.)  You know, I just love seeing so many bright, young faces here.  There&#8217;s just so much energy in this room.  So, thank you for being here.  &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">The White House, East Room</p>



<p>11:03 A.M. EDT<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:  Okay, I guess &#8212; yes, there we go.  Thank you.  And welcome to the White House.  (Applause.) <br><br>You know, I just love seeing so many bright, young faces here.  There&#8217;s just so much energy in this room.  So, thank you for being here.  <br><br>You know, everyone is here today because they have a personal connection to this issue.  Right?  And our nation&#8217;s Surgeon General, Vivek Murthy, has worked hard.  (Applause.)  Yes, let&#8217;s give him a round of applause.  <br><br>So Vivek has worked hard to build a movement of support for those who struggle with their mental health.  And Selena Gomez &#8212; (applause) &#8212; has been courageously outspoken about her own challenges.  <br><br>And, Selena, I&#8217;m so glad that your mom is here!  (Laughter.)  Where are you, Mom? <br><br>MS. GOMEZ:  Where is she?  She&#8217;s over there in the corner.<br><br>THE FIRST LADY:  Oh, there she is.  (Applause.)  Mandy, you must be so proud of your daughter.  <br><br>MS. GOMEZ:  She&#8217;s crying.  (Laughter.)  <br><br>THE FIRST LADY:  And all of you on this stage and in our audience are here today because you, too, have shown incredible resilience and determination to help us find a better way forward.  And I hope you all realize, really, just how special that is.  <br><br>You know, from the schools that are reopened, to the businesses that are thriving, to unemployment that&#8217;s falling, we can just look around and see really how far we&#8217;ve come since March of 2020.  Think back of where we were back then.  <br><br>You know, our world doesn&#8217;t feel so small and dark any longer.  We&#8217;re recovering every single day, but recovery isn&#8217;t always the same as healing.  And sometimes the darkness is inside of us too.  <br><br>And over the last decade, an alarming number of young people have struggled with mental health challenges.  And the pandemic has made it so much worse, hasn&#8217;t it?<br><br>You know the isolation, the anxiety, and, yes, the grief, they are wounds that sometimes go unseen, too often cloaked in secrecy and shame.  <br><br>But young people don&#8217;t have to face these challenges alone. Right, Vivek?  No one does.  <br><br>You know, our daughter, Ashley, is a social worker.  And she comes &#8212; you know, she used to come home every day when we all lived together and tell us about her &#8212; the challenges, about the kinds of trauma that she sees in her work.  And she &#8212; but she also shares the hope she feels when she&#8217;s able to help.  And I know that there are a lot of people here today who offer that same help.  And I want to thank all of you here in the audience who do that.  So, thank you.  (Applause.) <br><br>The darkness inside of us can feel heavy at times.  But we can share the weight of it together, and we can help bring those feelings and experiences into the light.  <br><br>And that&#8217;s why I&#8217;m so grateful to all of you here.  It takes courage to, you know, be honest about the struggles that you faced and to tell your stories.  And it takes courage to understand that your voice can make a difference and to show your creativity and talents, you know, to all of the world.  <br><br>So, I&#8217;m so proud of everyone here today.  And the President is proud of you too.  In “The Hill We Climb,” the poem the &#8212; that the National Youth &#8212; Na- &#8212; Poet Laureate &#8212; you might remember this from our inauguration.  Yes, who doesn&#8217;t love Amanda Gorman?  (Laughter.)  <br><br>So, Amanda Gorman wrote, “There is always light, if we&#8217;re only brave enough to see it.  If we&#8217;re only brave enough to be it.”  And I see that illumination in each one of you.  <br><br>So, I want you to keep showing up for each other, keep being brave.  I know it&#8217;s hard.  And keep helping us find the light that we all need.  <br><br>So, thank you all &#8212; all of you.  Thank you so much for being here.  <br><br>                         END                 11:08 A.M. EDT  <br><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>White&#160;House Releases Technical Assistance Guide to Help Communities Unlock Resources From Bipartisan Infrastructure&#160;Law</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/white-house-releases-technical-assistance-guide-to-help-communities-unlock-resources-from-bipartisan-infrastructure-law/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Administration Highlights New Capacity from Philanthropic, Nonprofit &#38; Labor Organizations to Help States and Cities Respond to Once-in-a-Generation Opportunity Today, the White House released a Bipartisan Infrastructure Law technical assistance guide to help state, local, Tribal and territorial governments navigate, access, and deploy infrastructure resources that will build a better America. The Biden Administration has&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Administration Highlights New Capacity from Philanthropic, Nonprofit &amp; Labor Organizations to Help States and Cities Respond to Once-in-a-Generation Opportunity</em></p>



<p>Today, the White House released a Bipartisan Infrastructure Law <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Infrastructure-Technical-Assistance-Guide_FINAL2.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">technical assistance guide</a> to help state, local, Tribal and territorial governments navigate, access, and deploy infrastructure resources that will build a better America. The Biden Administration has identified over $700 million in dedicated funding across more than 65 technical assistance programs. In addition to highlighting federal government technical assistance, the White House Infrastructure Implementation Team has engaged with a range of external stakeholders including, philanthropic, labor and nonprofit organizations, to highlight available nongovernmental resources and create a pipeline to assist communities in quickly and equitably accessing and deploying federal infrastructure funding.<br><br>Over 90% of the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law’s historic funding will be deployed by non-federal partners. In the past, too many communities have lacked the resources to apply for and deploy transformative infrastructure opportunities. This <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Infrastructure-Technical-Assistance-Guide_FINAL2.pdf">guide</a>, building on the <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2022/01/BUILDING-A-BETTER-AMERICA_FINAL.pdf">Bipartisan Infrastructure Law Guidebook</a> and <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/build/rural/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Rural Playbook</a>, highlights programs that help communities navigate programs and resources that can help them deliver infrastructure projects.&nbsp; While some of these programs offer hands-on and intensive planning and delivery support for communities, others are more self-directed resources and tools such as webinars and websites, or funding that can support project planning.<br><br>“This technical assistance guide is just one more way we’re working to ensure state, local, Tribal and territorial governments have the tools and resources they need to take advantage of investments in President Biden’s Bipartisan Infrastructure Law,” said <strong>Mitch Landrieu, Senior Advisor &amp; Infrastructure Implementation Coordinator.</strong> “Building a better America requires that we leave no community behind. This guide aims to pull together the many different technical assistance resources available across the federal government that can help communities deliver transformative infrastructure projects. We are also grateful to the many philanthropic organizations who have stepped up to support states and local communities in ensuring we do not leave any community behind in this once-in-a-generation investment.”<br><br>In response to the Administration’s external engagement efforts, philanthropic, labor and nonprofit organizations have also committed new resources to assist communities accessing and deploying federal infrastructure funding, including:</p>



<ul><li>Bloomberg Philanthropies, Emerson Collective, Ford Foundation, and the Kresge Foundation, are launching the <a href="https://localinfrastructure.org/">Local Infrastructure Hub</a>, a national program to ensure that all U.S. cities and towns can access federal infrastructure funding to drive local recovery, improve communities, and deliver results for residents. The $50 million commitment of support for local communities in collaboration with the U.S. Conference of Mayors, National League of Cities, and Results for America, will bring together leading experts and resources to help city leaders access and ambitiously leverage funding from the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law to advance groundbreaking solutions to major challenges, especially narrowing racial wealth disparities and cutting the emissions that cause climate change.<br></li><li><a href="https://www.acceleratorforamerica.org/">Accelerator for America</a> is providing technical assistance, in-kind support for strategic planning and grant writing, communications strategy, policy research, and guides to help local government and development leaders navigate the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law and complementary funding opportunities.&nbsp; Accelerator for America is working directly with 20 cities on infrastructure projects and expanding scope and reach regularly as cities prioritize local infrastructure projects, including workforce development initiatives and project delivery support.<br></li><li>The Communities First Infrastructure Alliance is working with technical assistance providers, frontline&nbsp;communities&nbsp;and government leaders to build just,&nbsp;equitable, and more resilient communities.&nbsp;The Alliance is&nbsp;led by national equity-centered leadership groups&nbsp;and includes a national ecosystem of valued aligned partners committed to communities first. The Infrastructure Alliance members will work collectively to support communities with the resources,&nbsp;capacity and technical assistance required to actualize community-centered plans, projects, and visions to meet this moment for the movement.&nbsp;&nbsp;<br></li><li>The recently launched What Works Plus (WW+) funding collaborative coordinates efforts across philanthropy, government, and nonprofit organizations to advance racial and economic equity through more just and climate resilient infrastructure investments. The collaborative is focused on partnerships that result in better outcomes for communities, workers, and entrepreneurs.<br></li><li><a href="https://www.cjnrc.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">The Climate Jobs National Resource Center</a>&nbsp;is assisting communities and states with workforce training, including building an equitable, inclusive renewable energy economy by investing in union apprenticeship and pre-apprenticeship programs. CJNRC will be working with&nbsp;labor-led climate jobs coalitions and unions in states to support a successful implementation effort by expanding and strengthening initiatives to increase access to union climate jobs for infrastructure&nbsp;workers in under-resourced communities on the frontlines of climate change.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>The Administration welcomes additional commitments from nongovernmental stakeholders to support states and local communities access this once-in-a-generation investment.&nbsp;<br><br>Since President Biden signed the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law six months ago, the Biden-Harris Administration has hit the ground running to deliver results. <a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/16/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-hits-the-ground-running-to-build-a-better-america-six-months-into-infrastructure-implementation/">More than $110 billion </a>has been announced and allocated to states and communities from formula and competitive programs for roads and highways, bridges, ports, airports, and water systems, with another nearly $100 billion in notices of funding availability for competitive programs now underway. The historic $1.2 trillion Bipartisan Infrastructure Law is rebuilding crumbling roads and bridges, replacing lead pipes to provide clean water, delivering cleaner energy, helping provide affordable, high-speed internet to every family in America, and producing concrete results that change people’s lives for the better.&nbsp; As the Administration implements the law, it is following through on President Biden’s commitment to ensure investments advance equity and reach communities all across the country – including rural communities, communities of color, and disability communities – and strengthen the nation’s resilience to climate change.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on the Applications to NATO by Finland and&#160;Sweden</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/statement-by-president-biden-on-the-applications-to-nato-by-finland-and-sweden/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 15:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53517</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I warmly welcome and strongly support the historic applications from Finland and Sweden for membership in NATO and look forward to working with the U.S. Congress and our NATO Allies to quickly bring Finland and Sweden into the strongest defensive alliance in history. Sweden and Finland have made the important decision to seek NATO membership&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>I warmly welcome and strongly support the historic applications from Finland and Sweden for membership in NATO and look forward to working with the U.S. Congress and our NATO Allies to quickly bring Finland and Sweden into the strongest defensive alliance in history.</p>



<p>Sweden and Finland have made the important decision to seek NATO membership after thorough and inclusive democratic processes in each country. NATO guarantees the security of one billion people in Europe and North America—united by our shared commitment to democratic principles and our vision of peace and prosperity in Europe and around the world. And my commitment to NATO and Article 5 is ironclad.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finland and Sweden are longtime, stalwart partners of the United States. By joining NATO, they will further strengthen our defense cooperation and benefit the entire Transatlantic Alliance. Together with our NATO Allies, the United States will maintain its robust exercise activity and presence in the Baltic Sea region. While their applications for NATO membership are being considered, the United States will work with Finland and Sweden to remain vigilant against any threats to our shared security, and to deter and confront aggression or the threat of aggression.</p>



<p>I look forward to welcoming President of Finland Sauli Niinistö and Prime Minister of Sweden Magdalena Andersson to Washington tomorrow so that we can further consult on their NATO applications and European security.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Phone Call with Politburo Member Yang&#160;Jiechi</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-phone-call-with-politburo-member-yang-jiechi/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 14:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53509</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi by phone. This phone call, which followed their March 14 meeting in Rome, focused on regional security issues and nonproliferation. Mr. Sullivan and Director Yang also discussed Russia’s war against&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p><br>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke today with Chinese Communist Party Politburo Member and Director of the Office of the Foreign Affairs Commission Yang Jiechi by phone. This phone call, which followed their March 14 meeting in Rome, focused on regional security issues and nonproliferation. Mr. Sullivan and Director Yang also discussed Russia’s war against Ukraine and specific issues in U.S.-China relations.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement from NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Kosovo Prime Minister Albin&#160;Kurti</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/18/statement-from-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-kosovo-prime-minister-albin-kurti/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53490</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Prime Minister Albin Kurti of Kosovo. Mr. Sullivan thanked the Prime Minister for Kosovo’s willingness to host Afghan evacuees. They exchanged views on Russia’s military aggression against Ukraine, including Kosovo’s provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of Ukraine and imposition of sanctions against Russia. They also&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met yesterday with Prime Minister Albin Kurti of Kosovo. Mr. Sullivan thanked the Prime Minister for Kosovo’s willingness to host Afghan evacuees. They exchanged views on Russia’s military aggression against Ukraine, including Kosovo’s provision of humanitarian assistance to the people of Ukraine and imposition of sanctions against Russia. They also discussed stability in the Western Balkans, with Mr. Sullivan expressing U.S. support for the EU-facilitated Dialogue to reach a comprehensive normalization agreement between Kosovo and Serbia and the need for further progress on key outstanding issues. Mr. Sullivan welcomed plans by Kosovo to transition away from its dependence on lignite coal to cleaner energy and to ensure a stable supply of electricity. </p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden’s Call with New Mexico Governor Michelle Lujan&#160;Grisham</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/readout-of-president-bidens-call-with-new-mexico-governor-michelle-lujan-grisham/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 02:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden called New Mexico Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham today to discuss the wildfires that have burned hundreds of thousands of acres across the State, resulted in the evacuation of tens of thousands, and destroyed hundreds of homes.  Governor Lujan Grisham underscored the impacts of the fires on New Mexico communities and the need for&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden called New Mexico Governor Michelle Lujan Grisham today to discuss the wildfires that have burned hundreds of thousands of acres across the State, resulted in the evacuation of tens of thousands, and destroyed hundreds of homes.  Governor Lujan Grisham underscored the impacts of the fires on New Mexico communities and the need for ongoing partnership with the Federal Government as New Mexico recovers and rebuilds from some of the most devastating wildfires on record in the State.  The President reaffirmed that the people of New Mexico will have the full support of the Federal Government, and that every effort will be made to provide immediate help to people in the impacted communities and support the State throughout its recovery.  The President expressed his gratitude to all of the first responders, firefighters, and other federal, state, and local personnel who are battling the blazes and have come to the aid of those who have been impacted by the fires.<br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of President&#160;Biden call with President Guillermo Lasso of the Republic of&#160;Ecuador</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/readout-of-president-biden-call-with-president-guillermo-lasso-of-the-republic-of-ecuador/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 02:19:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53484</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden spoke today with President Guillermo Lasso of the Republic of Ecuador to discuss their vision for the Americas ahead of the Summit of the Americas and the importance of the U.S.-Ecuador relationship.  They discussed strengthening economic, security, and migration cooperation.  President Biden and President Lasso also discussed COVID-19 pandemic response and recovery and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden spoke today with President Guillermo Lasso of the Republic of Ecuador to discuss their vision for the Americas ahead of the Summit of the Americas and the importance of the U.S.-Ecuador relationship.  They discussed strengthening economic, security, and migration cooperation.  President Biden and President Lasso also discussed COVID-19 pandemic response and recovery and supporting regional priorities.  The leaders committed to upholding democratic values and advancing the Summit of the Americas objectives.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout from NSC Spokesperson Adrienne Watson on National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Meeting with Saudi Vice Minister of Defense Khalid&#160;bin Salman </title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/readout-from-nsc-spokesperson-adrienne-watson-on-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-meeting-with-saudi-vice-minister-of-defense-khalid-bin-salman/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 01:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Saudi Vice Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud.  They underscored the longstanding partnership between our two nations, as exemplified by the U.S.-Saudi Arabia Strategic Joint Planning Committee, which the Vice Minister is co-chairing this week at the Department of Defense.  Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s commitment&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan met today in Washington with Saudi Vice Minister of Defense Khalid bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al-Saud.  They underscored the longstanding partnership between our two nations, as exemplified by the U.S.-Saudi Arabia Strategic Joint Planning Committee, which the Vice Minister is co-chairing this week at the Department of Defense.  Mr. Sullivan reaffirmed President Biden’s commitment to help Saudi Arabia defend its territory, and expressed appreciation for Saudi Arabia’s leadership in securing a UN-brokered truce in Yemen.  They also discussed the importance of coordinating efforts to ensure global economic resilience.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden and Vice President Harris at a Reception to Celebrate AANHPI Heritage&#160;Month</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/17/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-at-a-reception-to-celebrate-aanhpi-heritage-month/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 22:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rose Garden 4:23 P.M. EDT THE VICE PRESIDENT:&#160; Thank you, Ambassador Tai.&#160; It is true, there is something we all know: that we must always honor the mothers, the aunties, the chithis, all of them.&#160; (Laughter.)&#160; And, of course, the husbands and the fathers and the grandfathers.&#160; (Laughter.) It is good to be with everyone.&#160;&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Rose Garden</p>



<p>4:23 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE VICE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Thank you, Ambassador Tai.&nbsp; It is true, there is something we all know: that we must always honor the mothers, the aunties, the <em>chithis</em>, all of them.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And, of course, the husbands and the fathers and the grandfathers.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>It is good to be with everyone.&nbsp; I think this is, Mr. President, one of the biggest groups that we&#8217;ve had since we&#8217;ve been in office, and it&#8217;s quite a beautiful sight to see.</p>



<p>So good afternoon to everyone.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Good afternoon.</p>



<p>And as you all know, my mother arrived in the United States at the age of 19, from India.&nbsp; And when I think about the work that we are all doing, the work we are doing as an administration, led by our President, in terms of not only living the values but standing on the shoulders of so many who imagined that we would all be here and who know that when we talk about the beauty of who we are as a nation, as the United States of America, it is represented by all of the people who are here today and all those who are proud that we stand here today together.&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Joe Biden, Dr. Jill Biden, Mr. Second Gentleman &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and members of our Cabinet, it is good again to be gathered with all of you today and to be joined by the members of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>As a former member of the caucus, I will take a few moments to talk about a friend to so many of us, a mentor to so many of us, one who helped found CAPAC and became its first chair.&nbsp; And, of course, I&#8217;m talking about the amazing Secretary Norman Mineta, who devoted his career to public service.</p>



<p>For all of those who knew Norm, he worked tirelessly to make our nation stronger, safer, and more just.&nbsp; And in so doing, he inspired a generation of leaders, including me.</p>



<p>Secretary Mineta’s family is here with us today.&nbsp; And from my family to yours, please know that he is deeply missed.</p>



<p>Today, yes, it is a great celebration for so many reasons of so many things.&nbsp; But it is also impossible to ignore that we gather mere days after a horrific act of hate in Buffalo, New York, targeting Black Americans.</p>



<p>And, you know, it was only last year, as the Ambassador said &#8212; only last year that we &#8212; that I was with the President in Atlanta, mourning the murder of eight people, including six who were Asian American women.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, sadly, what I said then remains true now: Racism is real in America. &nbsp;It has always been.&nbsp; Xenophobia is real in America. &nbsp;It has always been.&nbsp; Sexism too.</p>



<p>I said last year and I sadly say again today: We have had people in positions of incredible power in our country scapegoating, people with the biggest pulpits spreading this kind of hate.</p>



<p>This requires &#8212; these moments &#8212; sadly, tragically require us to ask, “Who are we as a nation?&nbsp; And what do we stand for?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is yet again a moment to remember and talk about and reflect on how we treat people and do we live to the greatest and best of our ideals, which means treating people &#8212; all people &#8212; with dignity and respect, remembering the history of our nation and who built our nation and honoring the diversity of all who have contributed to who we are today.</p>



<p>And, of course, that is what this month requires us to do.&nbsp; And I know, looking around at the leaders here, we remember it every day of the year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we also know in tragic moments like this that we are committed collectively to saying: A harm against any one of us, is a harm against all of us, and it is all harm against our nation.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And the President and I, and all of us as leaders, will not be silent.&nbsp; We will not stand by.&nbsp; We must always speak out against violence, against hate crime and discrimination, whenever and wherever it occurs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we must do everything in our power to end this epidemic of hate.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We feel great pride, based on good reason and fact and history, in what we celebrate today.&nbsp; And we know that those who allowed us to be here, and paved the path for us to be present at this moment, expect great things from us, including that we are not only clear-eyed but that we are optimistic about our future &#8212; collectively about our future as a nation.&nbsp; That we remain committed to the ideals that make this nation great.&nbsp; That we remain committed to the notion that a harm against any one of us is a harm against all of us.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But that is an extension of a most profound belief, which is that we are in this together as one nation undivided.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So today we celebrate all those ideals when we celebrate the great people of this nation who have paved a path for so many of us to be where we are today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, finally, to quote then a great American, Norm Mineta &#8212; I quote: “If we will act together, then we are strong enough to withstand any evil, internal or external, that threatens to unravel” &#8212; and this is key &#8212; “this beautiful tapestry that is America.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And now it is my great honor to introduce a man who ran for President because he knows that no one should be in this fight alone: President Joe Biden.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; You’ve got to admit, I have got good taste in picking people, don’t you?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; Way above my pay grade.</p>



<p>Kamala, thank you, and Ambassador Tai; and Doug, the Second Gentleman, out there hiding behind everybody out there, I know. (Laughter).&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, Jill and I are honored to welcome all of you here to celebrate the Asian American, Native Hawaiian, Pacific Islander Heritage Month here in the Rose Garden.</p>



<p>You know, it’s wonderful to see so many friends: U.S. Senator Mazie Hirono.&nbsp; Where &#8212; where’s Mazie?&nbsp; I see &#8212; was told she’s here.&nbsp; I’m looking.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;Mazie, wherever you are, you’re the best.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And Tammy Duckworth.&nbsp; Tammy &#8212; Tammy is here, I’m told.&nbsp; Or &#8212; (applause) &#8212; going to be here.&nbsp; No?&nbsp; Any rate &#8212;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And the Chair of the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus, Representative Judy Chu, is here as well.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And there’s several other representatives here today who represent the community in Congress that is growing each election.</p>



<p>As Katherine mentioned, I’m proud to have re-established</p>



<p>the White House Initiative on Asian American, Native Ameri- &#8212; Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islanders.&nbsp; Several members are here today along with members of the community across the administration at every level.</p>



<p>Also joining are mayors and local leaders, and leaders of business and philanthropy, leaders of civil rights, the arts, the fashions and culture.</p>



<p>And this is a reception that follows on the &#8212; the great honor Jill and I, Kamala and Doug had in hosting Team USA, including the Amer- &#8212; the Asian American athletes who so honorably represented America in the Olympics.</p>



<p>Not too long ago, that included one of the most decorated &#8212; the most decorated figure skater in U.S. history &#8212; (applause) &#8212; and also worked on my campaign &#8212; also worked on my campaign and is now my nominee to be Ambassador to Belize: Michelle Kwan.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Michelle, you’re the best, kid.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; You’re the best.&nbsp; You do things backward better than most people can do them forward.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp;<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; And you represent a simple truth: There is no single Asian Am- &#8212; as Jill pointed out much more articulately than I have &#8212; there is no single Asian American, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander identity.&nbsp; It doesn’t exist.&nbsp; The diversity of cultures, the breadth and achievement that has shaded and shaped so many, strengthened the fabric of this country in ways that you can’t measure.&nbsp; I don’t think &#8212; I don’t know how you can measure it.</p>



<p>The fastest-growing demographic in the United States that has also gotten us through the pandemic as frontline and essential workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you have powered our economic recovery: An unemployment rate in a community that’s fallen from 6.6 percent since we got in office to 3.1 percent &#8212; for Asian Americans.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>Entrepreneurship in the community has risen &#8212; with you all, it’s risen the fastest rate in over a decade.</p>



<p>Where members of the community were once tokenized as villains on the movie screens, you now light them up as superheroes.</p>



<p>And today, I’ll be traveling &#8212; on Thursday, excuse me, I’ll be traveling to the Republic of Korea and Japan to affirm the importance of our Indo-Pacific alliances.&nbsp; Folks &#8212; and to celebrate the indispensable partnerships that are strengthening by the deep family ties and heritage and the values reflected in the AAN- &#8212; NH &#8212; PI &#8212; aye, aye, aye, aye, aye &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; community here in the United States.&nbsp; As they say in Claymont, Delaware, “All youse guys.”&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>But, look, we know that for the generations of progress, racism, harassment, and hate crimes persist, as was pointed out by my friends behind me.&nbsp; And today we know that maybe you are one of them who don’t feel safe walking American streets.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A shooting near Atlanta a year ago is still fresh, as been mentioned, in the hearts of so many.&nbsp; And Kamala and I went to vi- &#8212; down to visit.&nbsp; Just as we’ve seen hate crime shootings in Orange County, California; Dallas, Texas, just last week.</p>



<p>Jill and I just got back from Buffalo &#8212; Buffalo, New York &#8212; where another lone gunman with a hate-filled soul shot and killed Black people at a grocery store on a Saturday afternoon.</p>



<p>You know, I probably shouldn’t be saying this now, but I’m going to say it anyway: We have to not only talk about how we’re going to end the hate, but who’s responsible for generating it.&nbsp; Who is responsible for generating it.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Look, I’ve said many times: Hate can have no safe harbor in America.&nbsp; And every person deserves to be treated with dignity and respect.</p>



<p>But, you know, you have folks on television stations talking about the “replacement theory,” scaring the living hell out of people who don’t have a whole lot of emotional stability, taking advantage of &#8212; on the Internet and other means by talking about how we’re going to be “overtaken.”<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; That’s why, one year ago, with the help of many of you, I signed into law the bipartisan COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act.&nbsp; And with your continued help &#8212; (applause) &#8212; no, with your continued help &#8212; our commitment to advance equality across the board in everything from healthcare, to education, to housing, to LGBTQ rights.</p>



<p>Look, we&#8217;re working to fix our immigration system to reflect our values and the truth that legal immigration defines who we are as a nation &#8212; who we are as a nation.&nbsp; That&#8217;s why we&#8217;re so darn strong.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Bottom line is we&#8217;re doing the work to make real the promise of America for every American &#8212; a promise that holds that every person is created equal and deserves to be treated equally throughout their lives.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We&#8217;ve never fully lived up to that promise, but we&#8217;ve never, ever before walked away from it.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve never walked away from it.&nbsp; And that&#8217;s what we acknowledge during this month: building a legacy of strength and resilience for people like you and almost all of our forebears.</p>



<p>You know, you were telling the story &#8212; Jill is going to get mad at me for &#8212; it reminded me.&nbsp; I happen to be Irish.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; That’s the problem sometimes with Jill.&nbsp; But anyway, I&#8217;m only joking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>THE FIRST LADY:&nbsp; That’s not true.&nbsp; (Laughter.)</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; No, I&#8217;m &#8212; I&#8217;m teasing.&nbsp; But my mother used to always say on birthdays, “The mother should get the gift, not the child.”&nbsp; So I didn&#8217;t realize it was both Asian and Irish &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; at least in my house.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And speaking of friends, the late Norm Mineta, whom Kamala just spoke about, was one of my close friends &#8212; for real.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As you all know, Norm was born in 1931 in San Jose, California, an immigrant &#8212; to immigrant parents from Japan.&nbsp; As an 11-year-old, he spent three years in an incarceration camp, among 120,000 Japanese Americans across the country.</p>



<p>But with every reason to be angry and resentful &#8212; with every reason to be angry and resentful, Norm chose to believe in himself, to believe in America, and to believe in his country.</p>



<p>He served in the United States Army, elected the first Asian American mayor of a major city in his hometown of San Jose.&nbsp; Elected and served two decades as a congressman.&nbsp; We were &#8212; we spent a lot of time together and traveled together, serving with pioneers and dear friends like Danny Inouye and Danny Akaka.&nbsp; They both taught me, by the way, not only about Asian Americans, they taught me that it is “Native Americans,” not “Indian Tribes.”&nbsp; “Native Americans.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>And Danny was the first guy &#8212; I don’t want to ruin his reputation, God bless his soul &#8212; but Danny was the first guy to convince me to run for president and be my national campaign chairman.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Then Norm became the first American of Asian descent to serve as a Cabinet Secretary.&nbsp; Norm passed away earlier this month, as we all know.&nbsp; In the days after, I signed a bill into law naming the U.S. Department of Transportation headquarters in his honor.</p>



<p>Today, we’re honored to be joined by two of his sons, David and Bob.&nbsp; Where are you guys?&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Come up here.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You’re a good man &#8212; you’re both good men.&nbsp; Thank you very, very much.&nbsp; And I want to tell you, he was one of hell of a man.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, let’s all follow in the power of Norm’s example.</p>



<p>I thank you all for being here, and I want you to enjoy the rest of the reception.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, though: This fight that we’re &#8212; for equality, we&#8217;re just starting here.&nbsp; It&#8217;s not just the wackos who go out there with those guns and get talked into doing something.&nbsp; It&#8217;s the people who fill their brains with false ideas.&nbsp; It’s the people who make them &#8212; convince them, for their power and their prestige and their money, to be able to go out and do these terrible things.</p>



<p>That&#8217;s not who we are.&nbsp; That&#8217;s not who we are.&nbsp; And I&#8217;ll be darned, as long as I&#8217;m President of the United States, I&#8217;m going to fight like hell, and we&#8217;re going to expose everybody.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve got to make sure that this &#8212;</p>



<p>And my &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s a &#8212; there&#8217;s a hymn in my &#8212; based on the 91st Psalm, and it says &#8212; in my church &#8212; “May He raise you up on Eagle&#8217;s wings and Bear you on the breath of dawn, and let the sun shine upon you until…”&nbsp; And then it goes on to talk about that we all &#8212; all &#8212; that God will hold you in the palm of his hand.</p>



<p>That’s how we’ve got to think about our fellow Americans.&nbsp; The reason we are strong, the reason we’re who we are is because we’re diverse with so many talents.&nbsp; So many.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I know this group will never forget it.&nbsp; But I’m going to spend the rest of my term and as long I’m in office reminding the rest of America they should understand it too.</p>



<p>God bless you all, and enjoy the night &#8212; the day.&nbsp; And thank you for being here.&nbsp; (Applause.) &nbsp;</p>



<p>4:41 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nominations and Withdrawals Sent to&#160;the Senate</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/17/nominations-and-withdrawals-sent-to-the-senate-5/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 21:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=53473</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE: &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Andrew G. Biggs, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2024, vice Lanhee J. Chen, term expired. &#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; Stacy Lynn Dean, of the District of Columbia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>NOMINATIONS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Andrew G. Biggs, of Oregon, to be a Member of the Social Security Advisory Board for a term expiring September 30, 2024, vice Lanhee J. Chen, term expired.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Stacy Lynn Dean, of the District of Columbia, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services, vice Kevin W. Concannon.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Alexis Taylor, of Iowa, to be Under Secretary of Agriculture for Trade and Foreign Agricultural Affairs, vice Ted McKinney.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Calvin Smyre, of Georgia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Commonwealth of The Bahamas.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; David Pressman, of New York, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to Hungary.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Heide B. Fulton, of West Virginia, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Oriental Republic of Uruguay.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Yohannes Abraham, of Virginia, to be Representative of the United States of America to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary.</p>



<p>WITHDRAWALS SENT TO THE SENATE:</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Alice Hill, of the District of Columbia, to be Deputy Administrator for Resilience, Federal Emergency Management Agency, Department of Homeland Security, vice Daniel J. Kaniewski, which was sent to the Senate on February 7, 2022.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Calvin Smyre, of Georgia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Dominican Republic, which was sent to the Senate on October 4, 2021.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; William J. Valdez, of Maryland, to be Under Secretary for Management, Department of Homeland Security, vice Claire M. Grady, which was sent to the Senate on July 28, 2021.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"># # #</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
