<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 20:46:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Third Round of U.S. Marshal&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/25/president-biden-announces-third-round-of-u-s-marshal-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 20:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54175</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden is announcing his third round of U.S. Marshal&#160;nominees, officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law. These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and credentials in their fields, and their dedication to pursuing equal justice for all. The President has now announced&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden is announcing his third round of U.S. Marshal&nbsp;nominees, officials who will be indispensable to upholding the rule of law.</p>



<p>These individuals were chosen for their devotion to enforcing the law, their professionalism, their experience and credentials in their fields, and their dedication to pursuing equal justice for all.</p>



<p>The President has now announced nine nominees to serve as U.S. Marshals.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center"><strong><u>U.S. Marshal Biographies</u></strong></p>



<ol><li><strong><u>Thomas E. Brown: U.S. Marshal Nominee for the Northern District of Georgia</u></strong></li></ol>



<p>Thomas E. Brown has been a business owner and consultant since 2014. He served as Sheriff of DeKalb County, Georgia from 2001 to 2016. From 1990 to 2001, he served as the Director of Public Safety for DeKalb County, where he led the Animal Control Section, Fire Bureau, Police Bureau and the 911 communications center. He also served as the Fire Chief for DeKalb County from 1985 to 1990. Mr. Brown received his B.S. from Brenau University in 1990.</p>



<p>2. <strong><u>Brian A. Kyes: U.S. Marshal Nominee for the District of Massachusetts</u></strong></p>



<p>Brian A. Kyes has served as the Police Chief for the Chelsea Police Department since 2007. He joined the department in 1987 and previously served as a Sergeant, Lieutenant, and Captain. He also currently serves as the President of the Massachusetts Major City Police Chiefs Association. Mr. Kyes received his J.D. from Suffolk University Law School in 2002, his M.A. from Anna Maria College in 1990, and his B.A. from Framingham State College in 1987.</p>



<p>3. <strong><u>Stephen D. Lynn: U.S. Marshal Nominee for the Middle District of Georgia</u></strong> </p>



<p>Stephen D. Lynn has served as the Chief of Police for the City of Perry, Georgia since 2013. From 2007 to 2013, he served as an investigator for the Houston Judicial Circuit District Attorney’s Office in Georgia. He previously served in the Warner Robins Police Department from 1981 to 2007, where he held numerous leadership positions, including Commander of the Criminal Investigation Division and Strategic Services. Mr. Lynn received his M.P.A from Georgia College &amp; State University in 1996 and his B.S. from Georgia College in 1984.</p>



<p>4. <strong><u>Roy W. Minter, Jr: U.S. Marshal Nominee for the Southern District of Georgia</u></strong></p>



<p>Roy W. Minter, Jr. has served as the Chief of Police for the Savannah Police Department since 2018.&nbsp;Mr. Minter previously served as the Chief of Police in Peoria, Arizona from 2011 to 2018. He served as the Chief of Police for the Denton, Texas Police Department from 2007 to 2011. From 1992 to 2007, Mr. Minter served in the Aurora, Colorado Police Department, where he held numerous leadership positions, including as Training Section Commander and Operations Support Section Commander. From 1982 to 1992, Mr. Minter served in the Houston Police Department. Mr. Minter received his M.A. in 1998 and his B.A. in 1996, both from the University of Phoenix.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks as Prepared for Delivery by First Lady Jill&#160;Biden at Operation Fly Formula&#160;Event</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/25/remarks-as-prepared-for-delivery-by-first-lady-jill-biden-at-operation-fly-formula-event/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 20:14:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54172</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dulles International AirportDulles, VA The sudden, senseless massacre in an elementary school—little children and their teachers, Eva and Irma. Let us pray that God cradles these broken families in the palm of his hand. But let us also pray that we use the will and courage that God gives each of us so we can&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Dulles International Airport<br>Dulles, VA</p>



<p>The sudden, senseless massacre in an elementary school—little children and their teachers, Eva and Irma. Let us pray that God cradles these broken families in the palm of his hand. But let us also pray that we use the will and courage that God gives each of us so we can act—united with common sense—to protect our children.</p>



<p>I’ve always said that food is love. But food is life, too.</p>



<p>Like all of us, I have been heartbroken to hear the stories of parents searching for formula. As a mom and a nana, it’s impossible to hear stories of children suffering and not imagine your own children in the same position. Food is the first and most important way we nurture our children.</p>



<p>Joe and his team have put solutions into place to get formula back on the shelves.</p>



<p>Thank you to Nestle and FedEx for your partnership in this. Thank you to Tarun Malkani, and Gerber, for his leadership. And I want to thank the devoted service members of U.S. Transportation Command for their critical role in Operation Fly Formula.</p>



<p>There’s more to do. We know that. Joe knows that. As Dr. Murthy said, these shipments are only one part of the strategy.</p>



<p>I am here today to say to parents: You aren’t alone. At the highest levels of Joe’s Administration, he and his team understand what you are going through. They won’t stop until every parent can get the formula their child needs.</p>



<p>Thank you.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. Approves Kansas Disaster&#160;Declaration</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/25/president-joseph-r-biden-jr-approves-kansas-disaster-declaration-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 20:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54169</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Kansas and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe winter storms and straight-line winds from March 17 to March 22, 2022. Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. declared that a major disaster exists in the State of Kansas and ordered Federal assistance to supplement state, tribal, and local recovery efforts in the areas affected by severe winter storms and straight-line winds from March 17 to March 22, 2022.</p>



<p>Federal funding is available to state, tribal, and eligible local governments and certain private nonprofit organizations on a cost-sharing basis for emergency work and the repair or replacement of facilities damaged by the severe winter storms and straight-line winds in the counties of Barton, Clark, Comanche, Edwards, Ellis, Ford, Graham, Gray, Hodgeman, Kiowa, Lane, Meade, Ness, Pawnee, Phillips, Rooks, Rush, Stafford, Trego, and Wallace.</p>



<p>Federal funding is also available on a cost-sharing basis for hazard mitigation measures statewide.</p>



<p>Deanne Criswell, Administrator, Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), Department of Homeland Security, named DuWayne Tewes as the Federal Coordinating Officer for Federal recovery operations in the affected areas.&nbsp; <strong></strong></p>



<p>Additional designations may be made at a later date if requested by the state and warranted by the results of further damage assessments. FOR FURTHER INFORMATION MEDIA SHOULD CONTACT THE FEMA NEWS DESK AT (202) 646-3272 OR <a href="mailto:FEMA-NEWS-DESK@DHS.GOV">FEMA-NEWS-DESK@FEMA.DHS.GOV</a>.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President&#160;Biden Announces Key&#160;Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/25/president-biden-announces-key-nominees-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 19:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54166</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration:  Mark W. Libby, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Azerbaijan Marie C. Damour, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Fiji, the Republic of Kiribati, the Republic of&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Joe Biden announced his intent to nominate the following leaders to serve as key leaders in his administration: </p>



<ul><li>Mark W. Libby, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Azerbaijan</li><li>Marie C. Damour, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Fiji, the Republic of Kiribati, the Republic of Nauru, the Kingdom of Tonga, and Tuvalu</li><li>Angela Price Aggeler, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of North Macedonia</li><li>Gautam A. Rana, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Slovak Republic</li><li>Sue E. Moore, Nominee for Commissioner of the U.S. Marine Mammal Commission</li><li>Andrew J. Read, Nominee for Commissioner of the U.S. Marine Mammal Commission</li></ul>



<p><strong><u>Mark W. Libby, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Azerbaijan</u></strong></p>



<p>Mark W. Libby, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, currently serves as a State Department Faculty Advisor at the National War College in Washington, D.C. Previously, he served as Deputy Chief of Mission and Chargé d’Affaires ad interim at the U.S. Mission to the European Union in Brussels. Other overseas assignments include tours in Warsaw, Nassau, Nicosia, and Baghdad, where he served as Political Counselor. His Washington assignments include tours as a watch-stander and later Deputy Director for Crisis Management in the State Department Operations Center; Deputy Director in the Office of Central European Affairs; Director of the Office of Southern European Affairs; and Director of Orientation at the Foreign Service Institute. Earlier, Libby worked on the State Department Secretariat Staff, returning later as Director. He has a Bachelor’s Degree from Tufts University in Massachusetts and also studied at the Institut des Etudes Politiques (“Sciences-Po”) in Paris; he earned a Master’s Degree from the National War College, where he was a Distinguished Graduate. He is fluent in Polish and French.</p>



<p><strong><u>Marie C. Damour, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of Fiji, the Republic of Kiribati, the Republic of Nauru, the Kingdom of Tonga, and Tuvalu</u></strong></p>



<p>Marie C. Damour is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, with the rank of Minister-Counselor.&nbsp; She currently serves as Consul General of the U.S. Consulate General in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. Previously, Damour was the Director of the Office of Maritime Southeast Asian Affairs in the State Department’s Bureau of East Asia and Pacific Affairs; Director of the Office of Policy Coordination and Public Affairs in the State Department’s Bureau of Consular Affairs; and the Deputy Chief of Mission, as well as Chargé d’Affaires ad interim at the U.S. Embassy in Wellington, New Zealand. Among her other assignments, Damour was Minister Counselor for Consular Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in Brasilia, Brazil; the Chief of Non-Immigrant Visa Services and then Chief of Visa Services at the U.S. Embassy in London, England; the Consular Chief at the U.S. Embassy in Baghdad, Iraq, and the U.S. Consulate General in Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam. Damour earned her B.A. from the College of William and Mary. She speaks French, Vietnamese, and Portuguese.</p>



<p><strong><u>Angela Price Aggeler, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Republic of North Macedonia</u></strong></p>



<p>Angela Price Aggeler, a career member of the Senior Foreign Service with the rank of Minister-Counselor, served as the Deputy Chief of Mission at the U.S. Embassy in Islamabad, Pakistan. Previously, she served as Chargé d’Affaires ad interim. Aggeler formerly served as Minister Counselor for Public Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in Paris, France; Acting Principal Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs and the Office of the Special Representative for Afghanistan and Pakistan in Washington, D.C.; and, Deputy Assistant Secretary of State for Press and Public Diplomacy in the Bureau of Press and Public Diplomacy. Earlier, she was Counselor for Public Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in Islamabad, Pakistan. Previous assignments include Public Affairs Officer at the American Embassy in Skopje, Macedonia; Cultural and Press Attaché of the U.S. Embassy in Hanoi, Vietnam; Spokesperson for the Bureau of Consular Affairs at the State Department; and assignments at the U.S. Embassy in Paris, France and U.S. Embassy in New Delhi, India. Prior to joining the Foreign Service, Aggeler worked for the State Department at U.S. Embassies in Ouagadougou, Burkina Faso and Budapest, Hungary, as well as the Consulate General in Madras, India. Earlier in her career, she worked at the National Gallery of Art in Washington, D.C. and as a Peace Corps Volunteer in the Central African Republic. Aggeler is the recipient of numerous State Department awards, including the Assistant Secretary’s Award for Excellence and the Mildred Sinclaire Award for Language. A graduate of the University of Utah, she speaks French, Macedonian, and some Hindi.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong><u>Gautam A. Rana, Nominee for Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Slovak Republic</u></strong></p>



<p>Gautam Rana is a career member of the Senior Foreign Service, with the rank of Counselor. He currently serves as Deputy Chief of Mission of the U.S. Embassy in Algeria and was the Chargé d’Affaires ad interim there from August 2020 to February 2022. Previously, he was the Deputy Chief of Mission and Chargé d’Affaires ad interim at the U.S. Embassy Ljubljana, Slovenia. Among other positions, Rana was Director for Afghanistan and Pakistan on the National Security Council staff and the Deputy Minister Counselor for Political Affairs at the U.S. Embassy in New Delhi. Rana also served as the Special Assistant to the Deputy Secretary of State, Special Assistant to the Assistant Secretary of State for European and Eurasian Affairs, and worked in Iraq, Pakistan, Afghanistan, and the UAE. Rana earned B.A. and B.S. degrees from the University of Pennsylvania, a J.D.&nbsp; from the Vanderbilt University School of Law and an M.A. from the National Defense University. He speaks Hindi, Spanish, and Gujarati.</p>



<p><strong><u>Sue E. Moore, Nominee for Commissioner of the U.S. Marine Mammal Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Sue E. Moore is a Research Scientist and Affiliate Professor at the Center for Ecosystem Sentinels in the Biology Department of the University of Washington. Moore currently serves as a Science Advisor to the U. S. Marine Mammal Commission, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Marine Mammal Unusual Mortality Event Working Group, and the Washington State Academy of Sciences. Moore previously worked for NOAA for 20 years, where she served as the Director of the NOAA National Marine Mammal Laboratory and as a Senior Scientist for the NOAA Fisheries Science &amp; Technology Marine Division. Moore also served as Chair of the Environmental Concerns Working Group of the International Whaling Commission (IWC) Scientific Committee from 2008-2012.</p>



<p>Moore has over 40 years of research experience focused on the ecology, bioacoustics, and natural history of whales and dolphins, with most of her work directed toward cetaceans in the Pacific Arctic region. She holds a B.A. in Biology from the University of California, San Diego, an M.S. in Biology from San Diego State University, and a Ph.D. in Biological Oceanography from Scripps Institution of Oceanography.</p>



<p><strong><u>Andrew J. Read, Nominee for Commissioner of the U.S. Marine Mammal Commission</u></strong></p>



<p>Dr. Andrew J. Read is the Stephen A. Toth Distinguished Professor of Marine Biology at the Nicholas School of the Environment at Duke University, and currently serves as the Director of the Duke University Marine Laboratory in Beaufort, North Carolina. He was born in Southampton, England and educated in Canada. Read received his Ph.D. from the University of Guelph in 1990 for research on the biology and conservation of harbour porpoises. Read conducted post-doctoral research at the Woods Hole Oceanographic Institution from 1990 to 1995 and then moved to the Duke University Marine Laboratory, where he remains today. He has conducted field research on marine mammals in North and South America, Europe, and the Antarctic, with a focus on conservation biology.</p>



<p>Read is active in the conservation of marine mammals at the national and international levels. He is a member of the Cetacean Specialist Group of the International Union for the Conservation of Nature, the International Committee for the Recovery of the Vaquita, and several federal marine mammal Take Reduction Teams. Read served as a member of the U.S. delegation to the Scientific Committee of the International Whaling Commission and is a past President of the Society for Marine Mammalogy. He has written more than 200 scientific papers and supervised 25 Ph.D. graduates at Duke University. Read lives in Gloucester, North Carolina with his wife.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Names Eighteenth Round of Judicial Nominees</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/25/president-biden-names-eighteenth-round-of-judicial-nominees/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 15:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The President is announcing three new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution. These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country —&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>The President is announcing three new federal judicial nominees, all of whom are extraordinarily qualified, experienced, and devoted to the rule of law and our Constitution.</p>



<p>These choices also continue to fulfill the President’s promise to ensure that the nation’s courts reflect the diversity that is one of our greatest assets as a country — both in terms of personal and professional backgrounds.</p>



<p>For example, if confirmed, Judge Doris Pryor would be the &nbsp;first judge of color to ever serve on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit from Indiana.<br><br>This is President Biden’s eighteenth round of nominees for federal judicial positions and his fifth slate of nominations in 2022, bringing the number of announced federal judicial nominees to 98.<br><br>President Biden has spent decades committed to strengthening the federal bench, which is why he continues to move rapidly to fill judicial vacancies.&nbsp;And he has won confirmation of the most lower court judges for the first year of a presidency since the Kennedy Administration.</p>



<p><strong><u>U.S. Circuit Court</u></strong></p>



<p><strong><u>Rachel S. Bloomekatz: Nominee for the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit</u></strong></p>



<p>Rachel S. Bloomekatz is a solo practitioner at Bloomekatz Law LLC, which she founded in 2019 in Columbus, Ohio. From 2016 to 2019, Ms. Bloomekatz was a principal at Gupta Wessler PLLC. She was previously an associate at Jones Day LLC in Columbus, Ohio from 2013 to 2015. Ms. Bloomekatz served as an Assistant Attorney General in the Office of the Attorney General in Boston, Massachusetts from 2010 to 2011. From 2011 to 2012, Ms. Bloomekatz served as a law clerk for Justice Stephen Breyer on the U.S. Supreme Court. From 2009 to 2010, she served as a law clerk for Chief Justice Margaret Marshall on the Massachusetts Supreme Judicial Court. From 2008 to 2009, Ms. Bloomekatz served as a law clerk for Judge Guido Calabresi on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit.</p>



<p>Ms. Bloomekatz received her J.D. from UCLA School of Law in 2008 and her A.B., <em>magna cum laude</em>, from Harvard University in 2004.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge Florence Y. Pan: Nominee for the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Florence Y. Pan has served on the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia since 2021. She previously served as an Associate Judge on the Superior Court for the District of Columbia from 2009 to 2021. From 1999 to 2009, Judge Pan served as an Assistant U.S. Attorney in the U.S. Attorney’s Office for the District of Columbia, where she also served as Deputy Chief of the Appellate Division from 2007 to 2009. From 1998 to 1999, she worked at the U.S. Department of Treasury, first as a Senior Advisor to the Assistant Secretary for Financial Markets in 1998 and then as a Senior Advisor to the Undersecretary for Domestic Finance in 1999. Judge Pan worked for the U.S. Department of Justice from 1995 to 1998, during which time she was a Bristow Fellow in the Office of the Solicitor General from 1995 to 1996 and an attorney in the Appellate Section of the Criminal Division from 1996 to 1998. She served as a law clerk for Judge Ralph K. Winter on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit from 1994 to 1995, and for Judge Michael B. Mukasey on the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York from 1993 to 1994.</p>



<p>Judge Pan received her J.D. with distinction from Stanford Law School in 1993, and her B.A. and B.S., <em>summa cum laude</em>, from the University of Pennsylvania in 1988.</p>



<p><strong><u>Judge Doris L. Pryor: Nominee for the United States Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit</u></strong></p>



<p>Judge Doris L. Pryor has served as a U.S. Magistrate Judge for the Southern District of Indiana since 2018. From 2006 to 2018, Judge Pryor served as an Assistant U.S. Attorney for the U.S. Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of Indiana. She served as National Security Chief for the office from 2014 to 2018. From 2005 to 2006, Judge Pryor served as a Deputy Public Defender for the State of Arkansas Public Defender’s Commission. Judge Pryor served as a law clerk for Judge J. Leon Holmes on the U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Arkansas from 2004 to 2005 and for Chief Judge Lavenski Smith on the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Eighth Circuit from 2003 to 2004.</p>



<p>Judge Pryor received her J.D. from the Indiana University Maurer School of Law in 2003 and her B.S. from the University of Central Arkansas in 1999.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>FACT SHEET: President&#160;Biden to Sign Historic Executive Order to Advance Effective, Accountable Policing and Strengthen Public&#160;Safety</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/25/fact-sheet-president-biden-to-sign-historic-executive-order-to-advance-effective-accountable-policing-and-strengthen-public-safety/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two years ago, the murder of George Floyd exposed for many what Black and Brown communities have long known and experienced &#8212; that we must do more to ensure that our Nation lives up to its founding promise of fair and impartial justice for all. The incident sparked one of the largest social movements this&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Two years ago, the murder of George Floyd exposed for many what Black and Brown communities have long known and experienced &#8212; that we must do more to ensure that our Nation lives up to its founding promise of fair and impartial justice for all. The incident sparked one of the largest social movements this country has ever seen, with calls from all corners to acknowledge the legacy of systemic racism in our criminal justice system and in our institutions more broadly.</p>



<p>Today, President Biden will sign a historic executive order (EO) to advance effective, accountable policing and criminal justice practices that will build public trust and strengthen public safety. Police cannot fulfill their role to keep communities safe without public trust and confidence in law enforcement and the criminal justice system. Yet, there are places in America today where the bonds of trust are frayed or broken. To heal as a nation, we must acknowledge that fatal encounters with law enforcement have disproportionately involved Black and Brown people.</p>



<p>President Biden’s EO will enhance public trust by promoting accountability, transparency, and the principles of equality and dignity in policing and the larger criminal justice system. Increased trust makes policing more effective and thereby strengthens public safety. Without that trust, victims do not call for help. Witnesses do not step forward. Crimes go unsolved. Justice is not served. The EO mandates measures for all Federal law enforcement agencies, leveraging the President’s direct authority over the executive branch. The EO also requires the use of federal tools such as guidance on best practices, training and technical assistance, and grantmaking to support reforms at State, Tribal, local, and territorial law enforcement agencies that will strengthen public trust and improve public safety across the nation.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Promotes Accountability</span></strong></p>



<p><strong>Creates a new national database of police misconduct</strong>. The EO orders the Attorney General to establish a National Law Enforcement Accountability Database, in which all Federal law enforcement agencies (Federal LEAs) must participate. The database will include records of officer misconduct (including convictions, terminations, de-certifications, civil judgments, resignations and retirements while under investigation for serious misconduct, and sustained complaints or records of disciplinary actions for serious misconduct), as well as commendations and awards.</p>



<p>The database will have due process protections for officers. All federal agencies must use the database in screening personnel, and it will be accessible to state and local LEAs, who are encouraged to enter their records as well. The Attorney General will make aggregate data, by law enforcement agency, public, and will assess what whether and in what form records from the database may be accessible to the public.</p>



<p><strong>Strengthens Pattern or Practice Investigations. </strong>The EO requires steps to improve the investigation and prosecution of criminal civil rights violations, including directing the issuance of best practices for independent investigations and improving coordination to address systemic misconduct through pattern-or-practice cases.</p>



<p><strong>Ensures timely and thorough investigations and consistent discipline</strong>. The EO requires Federal LEAs to adopt measures to promote thorough investigation and preservation of evidence after incidents involving the use of deadly force or deaths in custody, as well as to prevent unnecessary delays and ensure appropriate administration of discipline.</p>



<p><strong>Mandates the adoption of body-worn camera policies. </strong>The EO orders all Federal LEAs to adopt and publicly post body-worn camera policies that mandate activation of cameras during activities like arrests and searches and provide for the expedited public release of footage following incidents involving serious bodily injury or deaths in custody.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Raises Standards</span></strong></p>



<p><strong>Bans the use of chokeholds and carotid restraints unless deadly force is authorized, and restricts the use of no-knock entries. </strong>The EO orders all Federal LEAs to adopt policies that ban chokeholds and carotid restraints unless deadly force is authorized and restricts the use of no knock entries to a limited set of circumstances, such as when an announced entry would pose an imminent threat of physical violence.</p>



<p><strong>Requires new standards that limit the use of force and require de-escalation for all federal agencies. </strong>The EO orders all Federal LEAs to adopt use of force policies with requirements that meet or exceed those in the Department of Justice’s updated use-of-force policy, which authorizes force only when no reasonably effective, safe, and feasible alternative appears to exist; authorizes deadly force only when necessary; and emphasizes de-escalation. The policy also imposes a duty to intervene to stop excessive force and a duty to render medical aid. Federal LEAs must conduct annual training on those policies, implement risk management tools to facilitate appropriate interventions before problematic behavior escalates, and ensure accountability for policy violations. The policy is publicly available on <a href="https://www.justice.gov/ag/page/file/1507826/download#%3A~%3Atext%3DLaw%20enforcement%20officers%20and%20correctional%2Cofficer%20or%20to%20another%20person">DOJ’s website</a>.</p>



<p><strong>Restores and expands upon the Obama-Biden Administration’s restrictions on the transfer of military equipment. </strong>The EO imposes sensible restrictions on the transfer or purchase with federal funds of military equipment that belongs on a battlefield, not on our streets. The list of prohibited equipment is broader than under the Obama-Biden Administration, and the EO’s mandate is broader than the George Floyd Justice in Policing Act (GFJPA) in that it pertains to all relevant programs, not only the Defense Department’s 1033 program. The EO continues to ensure that state and local LEAs can access and use appropriate equipment for disaster-related emergencies; active shooter scenarios; hostage or search and rescue operations; and anti-terrorism efforts.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Supports Law Enforcement with Improved Systems and Training</span></strong></p>



<p><strong>Requires an updated approach to recruitment, hiring, promotion, and retention of law enforcement officers. </strong>The EO requires Federal LEAs to develop best practices to attract, support, and retain an inclusive, diverse, expert, and accountable law enforcement workforce, including by implementing screening tools to ensure that agencies do not hire or retain, or partner with on task forces, individuals who promote unlawful violence, white supremacy, or other bias on the basis of protected characteristics. The working group also will identify ways to expand mentorship and leadership opportunities, and ensure that performance evaluations and promotions are tied to an officer’s adherence to these policies.</p>



<p><strong>Reimagines Crisis Response. </strong>The EO directs the Attorney General and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to issue guidance and identify federal resources for innovative models to respond to persons in crisis, including co-responder and alternative responder models, community-based crisis centers, and post-crisis care. It also orders guidance on the use of pharmacological agents such as ketamine outside the hospital setting.</p>



<p><strong>Prioritizes Officer Wellness</strong>. The EO directs DOJ and HHS to publish best practices and standards to promote officer wellness and to identify resources to support wellness programs, and requires each Federal LEA to assess and improve its own Officer Wellness program. The Attorney General must also recommend measures to the President to help prevent officer suicide, after consultation with HHS and stakeholders.</p>



<p><strong>Requires new standards for accreditation and for accrediting bodies. </strong>The EO requires the Attorney General, after consultation with stakeholders, to formulate standards for bodies that accredit law enforcement agencies. Those standards must include that the accrediting body requires policies consistent with those of the EO, and that the accrediting body conducts independent assessments of agency compliance rather than rely on the agency’s self-certification. The Attorney General must also incentivize and support agencies in seeking and obtaining accreditation, including through grantmaking.</p>



<p><strong>Implements a new, evidence-informed annual anti-bias training requirement</strong>. The EO requires development of an evidence-informed training module for law enforcement on implicit bias and avoiding improper profiling based on the actual or perceived race, ethnicity, national origin, limited English proficiency, religion, sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity), or disability of individuals. Federal LEAs must conduct that training annually, implement procedures to respond meaningfully to complaints of bias, and reassess a 2014 guidance on use of certain protected characteristics by law enforcement.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Improves Data Transparency and Oversight of New Technologies</span></strong></p>



<p><strong>Tracks data on use of force incidents. </strong>Within six months of the date of the EO, all Federal LEAs must collect and submit on a monthly basis all data on incidents involving use of deadly force compiled by the FBI’s Use of Force Data Collection. The Attorney General must also facilitate the contribution of this data, as well as data about officers killed or assaulted, by STLT LEAs, and report to the President his plan to fully implement the Death in Custody Reporting Act.</p>



<p><strong>Studies the impact of use of force incidents on communities. </strong>The EO directs HHS to publish a nationwide review of the physical, mental, and public health effects of use of force incidents on communities, including any disparate impacts, and outline available resources to support mental health and support services. It also tasks the Attorney General to issue best practices for conducting law enforcement-community dialogues, and for ensuring timely and appropriate notification of deaths in custody.</p>



<p><strong>Safeguards the use of facial recognition technology and other sophisticated algorithmic tools. </strong>The EO directs the National Academy of Sciences to conduct and publish a study of facial recognition technology, other biometric technologies, and predictive algorithms that assesses any privacy, civil rights, civil liberties, accuracy, or disparate impact concerns with their use. This study will then be used to make any necessary changes to Federal law enforcement practices.</p>



<p><strong>Enhances data collection and data transparency. </strong>A working group will write a report to the President on how to collect and publish data on police practices (including calls for service, searches, stops, frisks, seizures, arrests, complaints, law enforcement demographics, and civil asset forfeiture), and on the practices and policies governing the acquisition and use of advanced surveillance and forensic technologies.</p>



<p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Reforms Our Broader Criminal Justice System</span></strong></p>



<p><strong>Directs a government-wide strategic plan to propose interventions to reform our criminal justice system</strong>. A new committee with representatives from agencies across the federal government will produce a strategic plan that advances front-end diversion, alternatives to incarceration, rehabilitation, and reentry. The Attorney General will also publish an annual report on resources available to support the needs of persons on probation or supervised release.</p>



<p><strong>Improves conditions of confinement. </strong>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, will update procedures as necessary to increase mitigation of Covid-19 in correctional facilities; expand the publication and sharing of vaccination, testing, infection, and fatality data disaggregated by race, ethnicity, age, sex, disability, and facility; and to identify alternatives to facility-wide lockdowns and restrictive housing to reduce the risk of transmission. The Attorney General will also report to the President on steps to limit the use of restrictive housing and improve conditions of confinement, including with respect to the incarceration of women, juveniles, and persons in recovery.</p>



<p><strong>Requires full implementation of the FIRST STEP Act. </strong>The Attorney General will update DOJ policy as necessary to fully implement the FIRST STEP Act and to report annually on implementation metrics, including an assessment of any disparate impact of the PATTERN risk assessment tool and steps to correct any such disparities.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan’s Call with National Security Advisor Kim Sung-han of the Republic of&#160;Korea</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/05/24/readout-of-national-security-advisor-jake-sullivans-call-with-national-security-advisor-kim-sung-han-of-the-republic-of-korea-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 03:13:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Republic of Korea (ROK) National Security Advisor Kim Sung-han to discuss the  Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) recent launch of three ballistic missiles. They both condemned the DPRK’s destabilizing ballistic missile tests and committed to continue building on their close coordination. Mr. Sullivan also&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>National Security Advisor Jake Sullivan spoke by phone today with Republic of Korea (ROK) National Security Advisor Kim Sung-han to discuss the  Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) recent launch of three ballistic missiles. They both condemned the DPRK’s destabilizing ballistic missile tests and committed to continue building on their close coordination. Mr. Sullivan also reaffirmed the United States’ steadfast commitment to the defense of the ROK. <br></p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on the School Shooting in Uvalde,&#160;Texas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/24/remarks-by-president-biden-on-the-school-shooting-in-uvalde-texas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 03:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54137</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Roosevelt Room 8:41 P.M. EDT THE PRESIDENT:&#160; Good evening, fellow Americans. I had hoped, when I became President, I would not have to do this again.&#160; Another massacre.&#160; Uvalde, Texas.&#160; An elementary school.&#160; Beautiful, innocent second, third, fourth graders.&#160; And how many scores of little children who witnessed what happened see their friends die as&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Roosevelt Room</p>



<p>8:41 P.M. EDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; Good evening, fellow Americans.</p>



<p>I had hoped, when I became President, I would not have to do this again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Another massacre.&nbsp; Uvalde, Texas.&nbsp; An elementary school.&nbsp; Beautiful, innocent second, third, fourth graders.&nbsp; And how many scores of little children who witnessed what happened see their friends die as if they&#8217;re on a battlefield, for God&#8217;s sake.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll live with it the rest of their lives.</p>



<p>There’s a lot we don’t know yet, but there’s a lot we do know.</p>



<p>There are parents who will never see their child again, never have them jump in bed and cuddle with them.&nbsp; Parents who will never be the same.</p>



<p>To lose a child is like having a piece of your soul ripped away.&nbsp; There’s a hollowness in your chest, and you feel like you’re being sucked into it and never going to be able to get out.&nbsp; It&#8217;s suffocating.&nbsp; And it&#8217;s never quite the same.</p>



<p>And it’s a feeling shared by the siblings, and the grandparents, and their family members, and the community that&#8217;s left behind.</p>



<p>Scripture says &#8212; Jill and I have talked about this in different contexts, in other contexts: “The Lord is near to the brokenhearted and saves the crushed in spirit.”&nbsp; So many crushed spirits.</p>



<p>So, tonight, I ask the nation to pray for them, to give the parents and siblings the strength in the darkness they feel right now.</p>



<p>As a nation, we have to ask: When in God’s name are we going to stand up to the gun lobby?&nbsp; When in God’s name will we do what we all know in our gut needs to be done?</p>



<p>It’s been 340- &#8212; 3,448 days &#8212; 10 years since I stood up at a high school in Connecticut &#8212; a grade school in Connecticut, where another gunman massacred 26 people, including 20 first graders, at Sandy Hook Elementary School.</p>



<p>Since then, there have been over 900 incidents of gunfires reported on school grounds.</p>



<p>Marjorie Stoneman Douglas High School in Parkland, Florida.&nbsp; Santa Fe High School in Texas.&nbsp; Oxford High School in Michigan.&nbsp; The list goes on and on.</p>



<p>And the list grows when it includes mass shootings at places like movie theaters, houses of worship, and, as we saw just 10 days ago, at a grocery store in Buffalo, New York.</p>



<p>I am sick and tired of it.&nbsp; We have to act.&nbsp; And don’t tell me we can’t have an impact on this carnage.</p>



<p>I spent my career as a senator and as Vice President working to pass commonsense gun laws.&nbsp; We can’t and won’t prevent every tragedy.&nbsp; But we know they work and have a positive impact.&nbsp; When we passed the assault weapons ban, mass shootings went down.&nbsp; When the law expired, mass shootings tripled.</p>



<p>The idea that an 18-year-old kid can walk into a gun store and buy two assault weapons is just wrong.</p>



<p>What in God’s name do you need an assault weapon for except to kill someone?</p>



<p>Deer aren&#8217;t running through the forest with Kevlar vests on, for God’s sake.&nbsp; It’s just sick.</p>



<p>And the gun manufacturers have spent two decades aggressively marketing assault weapons which make them the most and largest profit.</p>



<p>For God’s sake, we have to have the courage to stand up to the industry.</p>



<p>Here’s what else I know: Most Americans support commonsense laws &#8212; commonsense gun laws.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I just got off my trip from Asia, meeting with Asian leaders, and I learned of this while I was on the aircraft.&nbsp; And what struck me on that 17-hour flight &#8212; what struck me was these kinds of mass shootings rarely happen anywhere else in the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why?&nbsp; They have mental health problems.&nbsp; They have domestic disputes in other countries.&nbsp; They have people who are lost.&nbsp; But these kinds of mass shootings never happen with the kind of frequency that they happen in America.&nbsp; Why?</p>



<p>Why are we willing to live with this carnage?&nbsp; Why do we keep letting this happen?&nbsp; Where in God’s name is our backbone to have the courage to deal with it and stand up to the lobbies?&nbsp;<br><br>It’s time to turn this pain into action.</p>



<p>For every parent, for every citizen in this country, we have to make it clear to every elected official in this country: It’s time to act.</p>



<p>It’s time &#8212; for those who obstruct or delay or block the commonsense gun laws, we need to let you know that we will not forget.</p>



<p>We can do so much more.&nbsp; We have to do more.</p>



<p>Our prayer tonight is for those parents, lying in bed and trying to figure out, “Will I be able to sleep again?&nbsp; What do I say to my other children?&nbsp; What happens tomorrow?&#8221;<br><br>May God bless the loss of innocent life on this sad day.&nbsp; And may the Lord be near the brokenhearted and save those crushed in spirit, because they’re going to need a lot of help and a lot of our prayers.<br><br>God love you.</p>



<p><br>8:48 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at the Asian Pacific American Institute for Congressional Studies 28th Annual&#160;Awards</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/05/24/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-the-asian-pacific-american-institute-for-congressional-studies-28th-annual-awards/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 01:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Renaissance HotelWashington, D.C. 7:06 P.M. EDTTHE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you.  Please sit, everyone.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  Thank you. What an incredible room.  And, Judy Chu, thank you for that introduction and for your leadership on so many levels. Tonight is a rough night.  We planned for a great celebration, but I’m sure most&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Renaissance Hotel<br><em>Washington, D.C.</em></em></p>



<p>7:06 P.M. EDT<br>THE VICE PRESIDENT:  Thank you.  Thank you.  Thank you.  Please sit, everyone.  (Applause.)  Thank you.  Thank you.<br> <br>What an incredible room.  And, Judy Chu, thank you for that introduction and for your leadership on so many levels.<br> <br>Tonight is a rough night.  We planned for a great celebration, but I’m sure most of you have heard the tragic news about what has happened in Texas.<br> <br>So I had prepared comments about tonight, which I will speak, but I just first want to begin by saying a few words about the tragedy that occurred today in Uvalde, Texas.<br> <br>As many of you now, the reports are that there was a mass shooting at an elementary school, and the preliminary reports are that 14 children have been killed.  And the details are still coming in, and of course the President and I are monitoring the situation closely.<br> <br>So while we don’t know all the details yet, we do know that there are parents who have lost children, families that have lost children and their loves ones, of course, and many others who may have been injured.<br> <br>So, I would normally say in a moment like this &#8212; we would all say naturally &#8212; that our hearts break, but our hearts keep getting broken. <br> <br>You know, I think so many &#8212; there’s so many elected leaders in this room.  You know what I’m talking about.  Every time a tragedy like this happens, our hearts break, and our broken hearts are nothing compared to the broken hearts of those families.  And yet, it keeps happening.<br> <br>So, I think we all know and have said many times with each other: Enough is enough.  Enough is enough.<br> <br>As a nation, we have to have the courage to take action and understand the nexus between what make for reasonable and sensible public policy to ensure something like this never happens again.<br> <br>So, the President will speak more about this later.  But for now, I will just say to the people of Uvalde: Please know that this is a room full of leaders who grieve with you.  And we are praying for you, and we stand with you.<br> <br>And it is difficult at a time like this to think about much else, but I do look around this room and I know who is here, and I know this is a room full of American leaders who know and have the courage to take a stand. <br> <br>And so let us, tonight, as we do every time we all get together, recommit ourselves to having the courage to take action.<br> <br>And so that does bring me to the leaders who are in this room and the leaders of APAICS.  And, again, I want to thank Chairwoman Judy Chu for that kind introduction.  As a former member of CAPAC, I had the opportunity to see her leadership firsthand, and she is truly a national leader who lifts up the people of our country.<br> <br>And, of course, I’m honored tonight to be with Congresswoman Marilyn Strickland; APAICS Board Chair Susan Jin Davis; and all of the federal, state, and local elected officials who are here; and so many friends and former colleagues.<br> <br>So this is the first time APAICS has gathered without the great Secretary Norman Mineta, who I all know &#8212; I know we all miss.  And, you know, Norm showed us what a leader could be.  I loved Norm.  I knew Norm.  (Applause.) <br> <br>As a kid who group up &#8212; I think I see Norm’s family here.  There you are.  I &#8212; as a kid who grew up in the Bay Area, I was born in the Bay Area, Norm Mineta was a legend.  He was a legend.  In fact, many of you may know &#8212; his family knows &#8212; my brother-in-law Tony West, who some of you have worked with over the years, he was an intern in then-Congressman Mineta’s office when Tony was a very, very mature 11-year-old.  (Laughter.)  Because that’s the kind of leader Norm Mineta was.<br> <br>He, if he were here, would have great expectations of us in terms of what this moment requires of us as leaders.  But throughout his life, as long as any of us have known him &#8212; and we will carry our knowledge of him and memory &#8212; he never thought that anyone was too young or too small to deserve his attention and concern and investment.<br><br>That’s the kind of leader Norm Mineta was.  He was a leader who understood what is possible and a leader who understood what must be.<br><br>And as I think about it, going forward, I say that, you know, Norm is somebody who had the ability to &#8212; out of great sacrifice, out of great tragedy &#8212; always still be so optimistic about who we are as a country.<br><br>As we all know, he endured &#8212; through his own life experiences, along with approximately 120,000 other Japanese Americans &#8212; virtual incarceration.  We called it, for many years, “internment.”<br><br>But Norm &#8212; but Norm decided that he understood the power of a government; that he endured, he understood what a government could do.  And he said &#8212; because he was the kind of leader &#8212; “I’m going to go inside.  I’m going to run for office.  I’m going to hold office.  And I’m going to lead with a sense of optimism about the best of who we are.”<br><br>Norm saw America’s during one &#8212; saw America during one of our darkest hours.  And even so, he never gave up on our country.<br> <br>Instead, he chose to devote his career to public service.  And he worked tirelessly to make our nation stronger, safer, and more just.  And he was relentless in his efforts to bring together the AANHPI community in pursuit of a better future.<br> <br>As he once said &#8212; and I will quote &#8212; &#8220;If we will act together, then we are strong enough to withstand any evil, internal or external, that threatens to unravel this beautiful tapestry that is America.&#8221;  This room.<br> <br>After the events of today and the last two weeks in Buffalo, Laguna Woods, and Dallas, Norm’s words take on a new sense of urgency.<br> <br>Today, we are witnessing, again and again, the terrible consequences of hate and the consequences of violence.  But let&#8217;s not lose sight of the beautiful tapestry that Norm spoke of.<br> <br>Because I do believe our country still embodies a most profound belief: That we are in this together, as one nation undivided.  Out of many, one.<br> <br>And so, this is a moment that calls on us to take action.  A moment once again for all of us to join together in the collective fight against hate and toward a better future for all people.<br><br>And now I’m speaking specifically of the events &#8212; not today &#8212; that have occurred though, in the last couple of weeks and for years before.<br> <br>For nearly three decades, APAICS has done the outstanding work to promote AA and NHPI participation and representation in all levels of government.<br> <br>We know our country is stronger and more just when policies reflect the experiences and the perspectives of all people.<br> <br>We know that Asian Americans need to be in the rooms where decisions are being made.  (Applause.)  That Native Hawaiians and Pacific Islanders need to be in the room where decisions are made.  (Applause.)  We know and have devoted our lives to understand the words when we say, “Participation and access matter.”  It’s a lived experience for us.<br><br>And I know, of course &#8212; like so many of you &#8212; I know firsthand what it is like to be in the rooms where decisions are being made and be the only person who looks like you or who has had your life experience. <br><br>And so, I will remind us all that in those moments, we must always remember &#8212; and I will say to you, those of you especially who are starting out in your role of leadership: When you are in those rooms, please remember you are never alone.  Look around this room and hold onto the image to remember we are all in that room with you. <br> <br>And always remember, then, that what comes with that experience is also, of course, a responsibility to know and remember that we carry the voices of so many who are not in the room &#8212; and perhaps have never been in the room &#8212; to carry those voices with us and to remind each other always that we are in this together, supporting each other.<br><br>And most importantly, I believe it is very much a part of the spirit of this organization and its work to remember our collective responsibility to speak up for everyone who is not in the room, for those voices must be heard. <br><br>So this is a unique responsibility that all of us here carry.  However, it should not be ours alone.  It falls on every American, and especially all of our elected officials, regardless of their party affiliation, to fight for the promise of equal justice under law.<br><br>And it will take all of us working together to uplift our nation.  And slowly but surely, I’m confident that we, as elected leaders, are making progress.<br><br>And I know Judy mentioned it and I’ll just remind us all &#8212; think about it: Just one year ago, members of Congress from both parties came together to pass the COVID-19 Hate Crimes Act.<br> <br>It was based on a resolution that I had introduced &#8212; (applause) &#8212; right? &#8212; that I had introduced when I was senator, together with the phenomenal Mazie Hirono, the phenomenal Tammy Duckworth &#8212; (applause) &#8212; condemning the rise of anti-Asian sentiment in our country.<br> <br>And as I stood, then, later &#8212; a year later almost &#8212; as Vice President with President Joe Biden in the East Room that day, while he signed the bill into law, I looked around and I saw all the people in that room, including many of whom are here today, who fought to ensure that this law would be a significant step forward.<br><br>We have seen progress.  And that law, of course, now provides resources and training for law enforcement to accurately identify and report hate crime.  And it addresses language and cultural barriers that make it difficult for AA and NHPI communities to report those crimes.<br> <br>As of this month, hate crime resources are now available in 18 of the most commonly spoken Asian languages.  But we know we have hundreds; I know that too, so &#8212; but &#8212; (laughter) &#8212; it’s a start.<br> <br>And our administration has taken steps to address not only that which holds us back but that which moves us forward.<br> <br>We have created over 8 million jobs since taking office &#8212; a record-setting pace of job creation.  (Applause.)  We did that together.<br> <br>Together, we all passed an historic infrastructure law that is already delivering results for the American people and lowering costs for working families through initiatives like the Affordable Connectivity Program so more families can access high-speed Internet.<br> <br>And our administration is determined to increase representation.  We have appointed AA and NHPI Americans at every level in our government.  And we appointed and confirmed more AA and NHPI judges during our first year than any other administration.  (Applause.)<br> <br>So, I’ll close with this: In spite of the obstacles that we face along the way, the strength of our country has always been that we fight to move forward &#8212; from injustice to justice, from darkness to light.<br> <br>And together, in spite of whatever the challenges may be, let us remain focused on the path forward to a better future for all people.  Let us remain focused on what many of you have heard me say all the time: Let us remain focused on what can be &#8212; and our vision, collectively, of what can be &#8212; unburdened by what has been.<br><br>That is the beauty and the strength of this organization and the leaders in this room. <br><br>Thank you all.  God bless.  (Applause.)<br><br>                              END                 7:22 P.M. EDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation Honoring The Victims Of The Tragedy In Uvalde,&#160;Texas</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/05/24/a-proclamation-honoring-the-victims-of-the-tragedy-in-uvalde-texas/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 21:56:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=54123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a mark of respect for the victims of the senseless acts&#160;of violence perpetrated on May 24, 2022, by a gunman at Robb Elementary School in&#160;Uvalde, Texas, by the authority vested in me as President of the United States by the&#160;Constitution and the laws of the United&#160;States of America, I&#160;hereby order that the flag of&#160;the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>As a mark of respect for the victims of the senseless acts&nbsp;of violence perpetrated on May 24, 2022, by a gunman at Robb Elementary School in&nbsp;Uvalde, Texas, by the authority vested in me as President of the United States by the&nbsp;Constitution and the laws of the United&nbsp;States of America, I&nbsp;hereby order that the flag of&nbsp;the United&nbsp;States shall be flown at half-staff at the White&nbsp;House and upon all public buildings and grounds, at all military posts and naval stations, and on all naval vessels of the Federal Government in the District of Columbia and throughout the United&nbsp;States and its Territories and possessions until sunset, May 28, 2022.&nbsp; I also direct that the flag shall be flown at&nbsp;half-staff for the same length of time at all United States embassies, legations, consular offices, and other facilities abroad, including all military facilities and naval vessels and&nbsp;stations.</p>



<p>IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this twenty-fourth day of May, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
