<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 22:48:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
<image>
	<url>https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-cropped-wh_favicon.png?w=32</url>
	<title>Briefing Room | The White House</title>
	<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden at Endorsement Event for the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and&#160;Protection</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/10/remarks-by-president-biden-at-endorsement-event-for-the-los-angeles-declaration-on-migration-and-protection/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Los Angeles Convention CenterLos Angeles, California 1:44 P.M. PDT THE PRESIDENT: &#160;Well, hello, everyone. &#160;My problem is I’m getting to like these people too much. &#160;(Laughter.) &#160;We’re going to get one another in trouble, I’m afraid. Today, the leaders on this stage are joining together to make what &#8212; and is almo- &#8212; it’s an&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Los Angeles Convention Center<br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>1:44 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT: &nbsp;Well, hello, everyone. &nbsp;My problem is I’m getting to like these people too much. &nbsp;(Laughter.) &nbsp;We’re going to get one another in trouble, I’m afraid.</p>



<p>Today, the leaders on this stage are joining together to make what &#8212; and is almo- &#8212; it’s an overused phrase in international relations and public life: to make a historic commitment. &nbsp;Because it is a historic commitment we’re about to make. &nbsp;Twenty countries coming together to launch the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection.</p>



<p>With this declaration, we’re transforming our approach to managing migration in the Americas. &nbsp;Each of us &#8212; each of us is signing up to commitments that recognizes the challenges we all share and the responsibility that impacts on all of our nations. &nbsp;And that &#8212; that will take all of our nations &#8212; and this is &#8212; I’ve learned by significant experience &#8212; it’s going to take all of our nations working together in partnership to address this migration issue.</p>



<p>In the past few years, the global economic crisis triggered by COVID-19 pandemic, and now made worse by Russia’s war in Ukraine and the political turmoil from auto- &#8212; from aut- &#8212; excuse me, autota- &#8212; auta- &#8212; autocracies, regimes in our region, has led to record levels of migration, not just to the United States. &nbsp;Colombia has hosted millions of refugees from Venezuela. &nbsp;Right now, migrants make up as much as 10 percent of the population of Costa Rica. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And no nation should bear this responsibility alone, in my view &#8212; our view. &nbsp;The economic futures depend on one another. &nbsp;Each of our futures depend on one another. &nbsp;And our security is linked in ways that I don’t think most people in my country fully understand, and maybe not in your countries as well. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Our common humanity demands that we care for our neighbors by working together. &nbsp;</p>



<p>The Los Angeles Declaration is built around four core pillars:&nbsp;</p>



<p>First, stability and assistance: making sure the communities that are welcoming refugees can afford to care for them, to educate them in their education, medical care, shelter, and job opportunities. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Second, increasing pathways for legal migration throughout the region as well as protections for refugees. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Third, working together to implement more humane and coordinated border management systems. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And finally, making sure we are working together to respond to emergencies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, we know that safe, orderly, and legal migration is good for all our economies. &nbsp;But we need to halt the dangerous and unlawful ways people are migrating &#8212; and the dangerous ways. &nbsp; &nbsp;</p>



<p>Unlawful migration is not acceptable, and we’ll secure our borders, including through innovative, coordinated actions with our regional partners. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Working these efforts simultaneously, though &#8212; humane policies that secure borders and support people &#8212; representing ground-breaking, integrated new approaches. &nbsp;It addresses the needs of vulnerable migrants and the needs of countries hosting those migrants. &nbsp;That’s why it has the support of the United Nations High Commissioner on Refugees and the International Organization for Migration. &nbsp;And that’s why so many nations &#8212; again, 20, representing the entire migration route from Chile to Canada &#8212; were eager to sign up to be part of this shared solution and have stepped up with their own major commitments. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I particularly want to thank President Chaves of Costa Rica and President Lasso &#8212; who you’ll hear from in a minute &#8212; of Ecuador for your new commitments to support and protect migrants in your countries so you have the chance to stay and begin to rebuild your lives where they are. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And like many others, countries and the United States are stepping up with significant commitments as well. &nbsp;To help our partners in the region continue to welcome refugees and migrants, we’re providing economic support. &nbsp;</p>



<p>For example, more than $300 million in new funding for the humanitarian assistance for countries in the region so when migrants arrive on their doorstep, they can provide a place to stay, make sure migrants can see a doctor, find opportunities to work so they don’t have to undertake the dangerous journey north.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’re going to provide millions more, including through the World Bank, to support countries and communities that are carrying the greatest responsibility for migrants. &nbsp;For example, Colombia received $800 million last year &#8212; not enough, but $800 million, that &#8212; that will help respond to the influx of refugees from Venezuela. &nbsp;And there’s more we’ll do, working with the World Bank and the Inter-American Development Bank.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re also expanding opportunities for people to come to the United States lawfully. &nbsp;In the next two years, we’ll resettle 20,000 refugees from the region. &nbsp;In addition, we recently resumed the Cuban Family Reunification Program &#8212; Parole Program. &nbsp;We’re resuming increasing access to the Haitian Family Reunification Parole Program, with a goal of admitting 20,000 per year per country. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And on this jobs front, our Department of Agriculture is launching the pilot program, funded by the American Rescue Plan, to help American farmers bring in seasonal agricultural workers from northern Central America, countries under the H-2A visa program to improve conditions for all workers. &nbsp;The program was designed in cooperation with the United Farm Workers and through the close consultation with farmers, farmworkers, unions, and other stakeholders. &nbsp;</p>



<p>We’re also dedicated to an additional 11,500 H-2B non-agricultural temporary work visas to open opportunities for workers from Haiti and northern &#8212; north Central American countries. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Mexico, Guatemala, Canada, and Spain are also making commitments today to expand labor pathways to their countries as well. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>And in addition to securing our border and bringing order to the asylum processing in the United States, the Department of Homeland Security is leading a first-of-its-kind campaign to disrupt human smuggling in the region. &nbsp;</p>



<p>If you prey on desperate and vulnerable migrants for profit, we are coming for you. &nbsp;We are coming after you. &nbsp;</p>



<p>In the first two months of our anti-smuggling campaign, the United States has worked with our partner nations to raid stash houses, impound vehicles used smuggling operation &#8212; for use for smuggling operations, and we made more than 1,800 arrests. &nbsp;And as we speak, Mexico and the United States are conducting what is known as “mirror patrols” &#8212; joint operations to interdict criminals attempting to illegally move drugs and migrants across our borders.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is just a start. &nbsp;There&#8217;s &#8212; much more work remains, to state the obvious. &nbsp;Every country needs to work together to maintain a humane and orderly immigration process, to invest in securing the borders, screen and registering migrants who enter their countries, and repatriating those that do not qualify to remain. &nbsp;</p>



<p>I hope more countries will see the potential for joining the Los Angeles Declaration. &nbsp;And I want to thank all of my fellow leaders on this stage for committing to this historic new vision for our region. &nbsp;</p>



<p>And now I’d like to invite President Lasso of Ecuador to say a few words. &nbsp;And thank you all very, very much for your patience.(Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>1:52 P.M. PDT&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joint Readout of President Joe&#160;Biden &#038; Vice President Kamala&#160;Harris’ Meeting with Leaders of The Caribbean Community (CARICOM) and the Dominican&#160;Republic</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/10/joint-readout-of-president-joe-biden-vice-president-kamala-harris-meeting-with-leaders-of-the-caribbean-community-caricom-and-the-dominican-republic/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 22:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55307</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President Biden and Vice President Harris met yesterday with leaders of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM) and the Dominican Republic at the Ninth Summit of the Americas to develop a plan to partner in addressing the unique vulnerabilities and urgent economic challenges facing these countries, which are facing overlapping economic challenges stemming from the COVID-19 pandemic,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>President Biden and Vice President Harris met yesterday with leaders of the Caribbean Community (CARICOM) and the Dominican Republic at the Ninth Summit of the Americas to develop a plan to partner in addressing the unique vulnerabilities and urgent economic challenges facing these countries, which are facing overlapping economic challenges stemming from the COVID-19 pandemic, the impact of climate change, food and energy insecurity, and lack of access to financing. Seized with these challenges,&nbsp;President Biden and Vice President Harris committed to working with CARICOM and the Dominican Republic to form three high-level committees tasked with developing immediate and concrete, joint, and near-term solutions.<br><br>Building on Vice President Harris’ April 29, 2022, meeting with these Leaders, the United States&nbsp; launched the U.S.-Caribbean Partnership to Address the Climate Crisis 2030 (PACC 2030) to facilitate renewable energy infrastructure development, including by increasing access to financing, and to bolster the region’s resilience to climate based natural disasters.&nbsp; The joint effort will facilitate collaboration between the U.S. private sector and Caribbean companies to support renewable energy infrastructure project development from concept to financing, including through technical assistance and blended finance tools to create Caribbean equity in energy projects.&nbsp; Under PACC 2030 and as part of the Americas Partnership for Economic Prosperity, the United States will work with international financial institutions to develop financial tools that respond to the Caribbean’s unique challenges, including by exploring alternatives to the World Bank’s national income criteria for eligibility to concessional or grant financing.</p>



<p>In addition to the Caribbean’s vulnerability to natural disasters, rising international debt, and out-migration, food and nutrition insecurity is on the rise with approximately 67.5% of the population experiencing moderate or severe food insecurity.&nbsp; To address these challenges, the United States and CARICOM will launch a Caribbean Zero Hunger Plan to promote food and nutrition security in the Caribbean.&nbsp; President Biden also announced the United States will provide $28 million in new food security assistance to Caribbean countries.<br><br>The leaders discussed the need to strengthen security cooperation and engagement, including countering small arms trafficking.&nbsp; The United States and Caribbean countries reaffirm longstanding cooperation on core Caribbean Basin Security Initiative (CBSI) priorities and broader engagement complementary to CBSI, such as combatting trafficking in persons, cybersecurity, and cybercrime.&nbsp; The United States and CARICOM member states support the development of national action plans to counter firearms trafficking, as part of the firearms priority actions and roadmap implementation process. These national action plans can help the United States more effectively tailor our support to CARICOM member countries, to address especially the supply and flow of illegal handguns and assault weapons trafficking throughout the region.&nbsp; The leaders also applaud the work of CBSI countries and CARICOM Implementation Agency for Crime and Security (IMPACS) to implement the firearms trafficking priority actions and the road map.&nbsp; The United States and CARICOM concur on the utility of acceding to the Treaty of San José concerning illicit maritime and air narcotics trafficking. This treaty provides states with a valuable legal mechanism that facilitates international cooperation to disrupt illicit maritime trafficking and transnational criminal organizations in the Caribbean.</p>



<p>Finally, the United States and CARICOM reaffirm our commitment to promoting and defending democracy and the rule of law, as enshrined in the Inter-American Democratic Charter.  Our nations are bound together by shared values, culture, history, and family ties. As governments, we will work in partnership with civil society and the private sector to ensure that democracy delivers for all our people and to build safe, inclusive, prosperous, equitable, and climate-resilient societies.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Readout of White&#160;House Meeting with Disabled Activists on Reproductive&#160;Rights</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/10/readout-of-white-house-meeting-with-disabled-activists-on-reproductive-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55287</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, the White House Gender Policy Council and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with Disabled leaders.&#160; Participants discussed how access to reproductive health care, including abortion, is shaped by disability status and underscored the importance of bodily autonomy, self-determination and health equity, including culturally competent care.&#160; Participants discussed the disproportionate&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Yesterday, the White House Gender Policy Council and the White House Office of Public Engagement convened a meeting with Disabled leaders.&nbsp; Participants discussed how access to reproductive health care, including abortion, is shaped by disability status and underscored the importance of bodily autonomy, self-determination and health equity, including culturally competent care.&nbsp; Participants discussed the disproportionate effect that Americans with disabilities will face if <em>Roe v</em> <em>Wade </em>is overturned, and highlighted numerous barriers such as the lack of accessible facilities and transportation.</p>



<p>During the conversation, participants also raised that the right to parent is also a disability rights issue and that Disabled people have the right to access services that will ensure they are able to parent in their fullest capability.</p>



<p>Advocates stressed the importance of mobilizing the Disabled community in support of reproductive freedom. White House officials affirmed that participants were essential partners in the effort to protect reproductive rights and invited advocates into continued dialogue.</p>



<p>Participants included:</p>



<ul><li>Julia Bascom, Autistic Self-Advocacy Network</li><li>Lydia Brown, Autistic Women and Nonbinary Network</li><li>Giovanna Burno, Activist</li><li>Tory Cross, Be a Hero</li><li>Elena Hung, Little Lobbyists</li><li>Monica Porter, Bazelon Center for Mental Health Law</li><li>Leslie Templeton, Disability Policy Consortium</li><li>Maria Town, American Association of People with Disabilities</li><li>Angelica Vega, Activist</li><li>Robin Wilson-Beattie, Activist</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and&#160;Protection</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/10/los-angeles-declaration-on-migration-and-protection/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 21:11:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55304</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We, the Heads of State and Government of the Argentine Republic, Barbados, Belize, the Federative Republic of Brazil, Canada, the Republic of Chile, the Republic of Colombia, the Republic of Costa Rica, the Republic of Ecuador, the Republic of El Salvador, the Republic of Guatemala, the Republic of Haiti, the Republic of Honduras, Jamaica, the&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>We, the Heads of State and Government of the Argentine Republic, Barbados, Belize, the Federative Republic of Brazil, Canada, the Republic of Chile, the Republic of Colombia, the Republic of Costa Rica, the Republic of Ecuador, the Republic of El Salvador, the Republic of Guatemala, the Republic of Haiti, the Republic of Honduras, Jamaica, the United Mexican States, the Republic of Panama, the Republic of Paraguay, the Republic of Peru, the United States of America, and the Oriental Republic of Uruguay, gathered in Los Angeles on the margins of the Ninth Summit of the Americas, reiterate our will to strengthen national, regional, and hemispheric efforts to create the conditions for safe, orderly, humane, and regular migration and to strengthen frameworks for international protection and cooperation.</p>



<p>We embrace the need to promote the political, economic, security, social, and environmental conditions for people to lead peaceful, productive, and dignified lives in their countries of origin.&nbsp; Migration should be a voluntary, informed choice and not a necessity.</p>



<p>We are committed to protecting the safety and dignity of all migrants, refugees, asylum seekers, and stateless persons, regardless of their migratory status, and respecting their human rights and fundamental freedoms.&nbsp; We intend to cooperate closely to facilitate safe, orderly, humane, and regular migration and, as appropriate, promote safe and dignified returns, consistent with national legislation, the principle of non-refoulement, and our respective obligations under international law.</p>



<p>We acknowledge that addressing irregular international migration requires a regional approach, and that ongoing health, social, and economic challenges of the pandemic exacerbate the root causes driving irregular migration, including the vulnerabilities of many migrants and their communities.</p>



<p>We value the tradition of our region in welcoming refugees and migrants and showing solidarity with our neighbors.&nbsp; We recognize the positive contributions of refugees and migrants to the socio-economic development of their host communities.&nbsp; We recognize the sustained efforts of States in our hemisphere in hosting refugees, providing regular migration pathways, promoting local economic and social integration, facilitating safe, dignified, and voluntary return, and supporting the sustainable reintegration of returnees.</p>



<p>We remain committed to collectively leveraging the benefits of migration while addressing its challenges in countries and communities of origin, transit, destination, and return.&nbsp; We do so in a spirit of collaboration, solidarity, and shared responsibility among States and in partnership with civil society and international organizations.&nbsp; We reaffirm our shared commitment to supporting host communities; strengthening and expanding regular pathways and access to international protection; fostering opportunities for decent work; facilitating regularization and access to basic services; and promoting principles of safe, orderly, humane, and regular migration.</p>



<p>We also intend to strengthen the institutions that are responsible for migration management in our countries and exchange best practices in order to provide efficient and adequate care to migrants and access to protection for refugees.</p>



<p><strong>Promoting Stability and Assistance for Communities of Destination, Origin, Transit, and Return</strong></p>



<p>We affirm that countries of origin and countries and communities hosting large numbers of migrants and refugees may need international financing and assistance related to development, basic humanitarian needs, protection, security, public health, education, financial inclusion, and employment, among others. &nbsp;We support efforts that allow all migrants, refugees, asylum seekers, and persons in situations of vulnerability to integrate into host countries and access legal identity, regular status, dignified employment, public services, and international protection, when appropriate and in accordance with national legislation, to rebuild their lives and contribute to those communities. &nbsp;We plan to continue efforts to prevent and reduce statelessness.&nbsp; We intend to expand efforts to address the root causes of irregular migration throughout our hemisphere, improving conditions and opportunities in countries of origin and promoting respect for human rights.&nbsp; We reaffirm the importance of safe, dignified, and sustainable return, readmission, and reintegration of migrants to help them reestablish themselves in their communities of origin.&nbsp; We further reaffirm the importance of ensuring all foreign nationals receive prompt consular assistance when needed or requested, and returnees are treated humanely and in a dignified manner, regardless of their immigration status, including in the process of their repatriation and return.</p>



<p><strong>Promoting Regular Pathways for Migration and International Protection</strong></p>



<p>We affirm that regular pathways, including circular and seasonal labor migration opportunities, family reunification, temporary migration mechanisms, and regularization programs promote safer and more orderly migration.  We intend to strengthen fair labor migration opportunities in the region, integrating robust safeguards to ensure ethical recruitment and employment free of exploitation, violence, and discrimination, consistent with respect for human rights and with a gender perspective.  We intend to promote, in accordance with national legislation, the recognition of qualifications and the portability of social benefits.  We intend to pursue accountability for those who commit human rights violations and abuses.  We plan to promote access to protection and complementary pathways for asylum seekers, refugees, and stateless persons in accordance with national legislation and with respect for the principle of non-refoulement.  We seek to promote border security and management processes that respect human rights and encourage and facilitate lawful, safe, and secure travel within the region.  We commit to guarantee human rights to individuals in vulnerable situations and to provide access to international protection, as appropriate.  We further intend to provide specialized and gender-responsive attention to individuals in situations of vulnerability.</p>



<p><strong>Promoting Humane Migration Management</strong></p>



<p>Renewing our commitment to respect and ensure the human rights of all migrants and persons in need of international protection, we recognize each country’s responsibility to manage mixed movements across international borders in a secure, humane, orderly, and regular manner.&nbsp; We intend to expand collaborative efforts to save lives, address violence and discrimination, counter xenophobia, and combat smuggling of migrants and trafficking in persons.&nbsp; This includes expanded collaboration to prosecute migrant smuggling and human trafficking criminal organizations as well as their facilitators and money laundering networks.&nbsp; We commit to provide appropriate protection and assistance to victimized individuals.&nbsp; We intend, in accordance with national legislation, to improve and facilitate regional law enforcement information sharing, with the purpose of supporting the investigation and prosecution of crimes. We intend to explore new mechanisms, while preserving and leveraging existing regional, subregional, hemispheric, and global fora, to strengthen cooperation on border management and apply current mechanisms on visa regimes and regularization processes to combat exploitation by criminal groups.&nbsp; In the instance of foreign nationals without a need for international protection and without a legal basis to remain in their country of presence, we commit to conduct any returns in a manner consistent with our respective obligations under international human rights law and international refugee law, and that respects the dignity of the individual, integrates safeguards to prevent refoulement, and promotes the return of children to safe conditions.</p>



<p><strong>Promoting a Coordinated Emergency Response</strong></p>



<p>Recognizing the imperative of promoting safe, orderly, and regular migration, and the safety of migrants, refugees, and asylum seekers in the region, we intend to work to cooperate in emergency response and humanitarian assistance in situations of mass migration and refugee movements.&nbsp; We plan to strengthen existing regional coordination mechanisms and, as appropriate, the participation of civil society and international organizations to advance those aims.&nbsp; This includes strengthening information sharing, as appropriate and in accordance with national legislation, enhancing early warning systems, leveraging existing relevant fora and processes, and defining a common set of triggers that activate a coordinated response.</p>



<p><strong>A Shared Approach to Reduce and Manage Irregular Migration</strong></p>



<p>To advance the common goals laid out in this Declaration and create the conditions for safe, orderly, humane, and regular migration through robust responsibility sharing, we intend to work together across the hemisphere to:</p>



<ul><li>Convene multilateral development banks, international financial institutions, and traditional and non-traditional donors to review financial support instruments for countries hosting migrant populations and facing other migration challenges, without prejudice to existing financing priorities and programs.</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp;Improve regional cooperation mechanisms for law enforcement cooperation, information sharing, protection-sensitive border management, visa regimes, and regularization processes, as appropriate and in accordance with national legislation.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Strengthen and expand temporary labor migration pathways, as feasible, that benefit countries across the region, including through new programs promoting connections between employers and migrant workers, robust safeguards for ethical recruitment, and legal protections for workers’ rights.</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp;Improve access to public and private services for all migrants, refugees, and stateless persons to promote their full social and economic inclusion in host communities.</li></ul>



<ul><li>Expand access to regular pathways for migrants and refugees to include family reunification options where appropriate and feasible, in accordance with national legislation.</li></ul>



<p class="has-text-align-center">&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;-</p>



<p>This Declaration builds upon existing efforts and international commitments and advances the vision set forth in the Global Compact on Refugees and the Global Compact for Safe, Orderly and Regular Migration (GCM) anchored in the 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development.  We acknowledge the progress noted in the International Migration Review Forum Progress Declaration for the GCM.  We affirm the fundamental work that continues under the Comprehensive Regional Protection and Solutions Framework (MIRPS), the Regional Conference on Migration (RCM), and the South American Conference on Migration (SACM), as key regional bodies to facilitate the implementation of this Declaration, as well as the Quito Process and the Regional Inter-agency Coordination Platform for refugees and migrants from Venezuela.  The United Nations 1951 Refugee Convention; its 1967 Protocol; the Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment; the Geneva Conventions of 1949 and International Humanitarian Law; the United Nations Convention against Transnational Organized Crime; its Protocol to Prevent, Suppress and Punish Trafficking in Persons, especially Women and Children; its Protocol against the Smuggling of Migrants by Land, Sea and Air; the United Nations Convention on the Rights of the Child; the International Convention on the Protection of the Rights of all Migrant Workers and Members of their Families; as well as other international conventions, remain binding on Parties to those conventions that endorse this Declaration.  This Declaration aligns with States’ commitments in the International Labour Organization’s Declaration on Fundamental Principles and Rights at Work and its General Principles and Operational Guidelines for Fair Recruitment.  We reiterate the importance and meaning of the principle of non-refoulement as a cornerstone of the international protection of refugees.  We applaud efforts throughout the region to provide a coordinated and comprehensive response to all migrants, returnees, refugees, asylum seekers, and stateless persons.  We make this Declaration of non-legally binding commitments to enhance cooperation and shared responsibilities on managing migration and protection in ways grounded in human rights, transparency, nondiscrimination, and State sovereignty.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Remarks by President&#160;Biden on Inflation and Actions Taken to Lower Prices and Address Supply Chain&#160;Challenges</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2022/06/10/remarks-by-president-biden-on-inflation-and-actions-taken-to-lower-prices-and-address-supply-chain-challenges/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 20:59:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Speeches and Remarks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[USS IowaPort of Los Angeles Los Angeles, California 10:51 A.M. PDT      THE PRESIDENT:  As we used to say in the United States Senate, I hope you’ll excuse a point of personal privilege, but I think that Sal must be related closely to my good friend from Holy Rosary High School in Claymont, Mike DiCostanzo (ph). &#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">USS Iowa<br>Port of Los Angeles <br>Los Angeles, California</p>



<p>10:51 A.M. PDT</p>



<p>     THE PRESIDENT:  As we used to say in the United States Senate, I hope you’ll excuse a point of personal privilege, but I think that Sal must be related closely to my good friend from Holy Rosary High School in Claymont, Mike DiCostanzo (ph).  (Laughter.)  You think I’m kidding.  (Laughs.)  I’m not.</p>



<p>I tell you what &#8212; but anyway, thank you, Sal.</p>



<p>Look, everybody, before I begin, I want to say a few words very briefly about the January 6th hearings that were highlighted last night.</p>



<p>The insurrection on January 6th is one of the darkest chapters in our nation’s history.&nbsp; A brutal assault on our democracy.&nbsp; A brutal attack on law enforcement &#8212; some losing their lives.&nbsp; And we &#8212; and we heard about it last night again.</p>



<p>It’s important that the American people understand what truly happened and to understand that the same forces that led January 6th remain at work today.&nbsp; It’s about our democracy itself.</p>



<p>We have to protect our democracy.&nbsp; I know it sounds corny to say it.&nbsp; We were all raised in school that democracy &#8212; every generation has to protect it.&nbsp; I have to admit to you, I never thought that it was going to be this straightforward a challenge before.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The rule of law matters in democracies.&nbsp; And we’re seeing how the battle for the soul of America has been far from won.</p>



<p>But I know, together &#8212; and I mean this &#8212; we can unite and defend this nation, Democrat and Republican, and allow no one to place a dagger at the throat of our democracy.</p>



<p>That’s what those hearings are all about.&nbsp; You’re going to hear a lot more.&nbsp; I didn’t get to watch them last night because I was doing other business.&nbsp; But I tell you what: There’s a lot &#8212; a lot going on.</p>



<p>Now, look, to the reason I’m here.&nbsp; You know, thank you, Sal.&nbsp; And thanks to Gene and the Port of Los Angeles, as well.&nbsp; Mario, thank you, for the Port of Long Beach.&nbsp; And thank Mayor Garcetti of Los Angeles and the Mayor of Long Beach, who I suspect is soon going to be the Congressman of Long Beach, the way it looks like.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp;</p>



<p>You guys did a heck of a job when I came out here a couple years ago to try to get things moving.&nbsp; Everybody did &#8212; management, labor, the elected leaders.&nbsp; As well as, at the time, we also had Governor Newsom pushing hard as well.</p>



<p>Look, we have two excellent senators: Dianne Feinstein and Alex Padilla.&nbsp; I tell you what, Alex &#8212; (applause) &#8212; you don’t look any worse for the wear, man.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; You’re looking awful good.&nbsp; You’re looking awful good.</p>



<p>And, Nanette, I &#8212; I think you’ve always looked good, particularly compared to these guys.&nbsp; You know what I mean?&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And me.&nbsp; But seriously, thank you, Nanette, for the fire you bring.&nbsp; You bring some fire to this.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; It’s in your heart.</p>



<p>And Alan Lowenthal has been working on this for a long time.&nbsp; Alan and I just had a little meeting together.&nbsp; We got to change it, Alan.&nbsp; We’ve got &#8212; we can’t &#8212; we can’t give up.&nbsp; We got to turn this corner.</p>



<p>And, John, I can’t thank you.&nbsp; You’re &#8212; you’re the real deal.&nbsp; Anybody &#8212; well, I won’t get into &#8212; get you in trouble, but thanks for sticking up for me.</p>



<p>And, look &#8212; and we have a Labor Secretary that &#8212; I’m his translator.&nbsp; He’s “Marty Walsh from Boston.”&nbsp; (Pronounced in Boston accent.)&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; And &#8212; but if you need any- &#8212; the only thing you got to know: He always has your back.&nbsp; He always has your back.&nbsp; I had an uncle who used to say, “Joey, you’re labor from belt buckle to shoe sole.”&nbsp; Well, he’s labor from forehead to the tip of his toes.&nbsp; He used to run a labor’s outf- &#8212; union.</p>



<p>Look, folks, today I’d like to speak about my top economic priority: fighting inflation.&nbsp; I understand Americans are anxious, and they’re anxious with good reason.&nbsp; I was raised in a household when the price of gasoline rose precipitously, it was the discussion at the table.&nbsp; It made a difference when food prices went up.</p>



<p>But we&#8217;ve never seen anything like Putin&#8217;s tax on both food and gas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Americans should also understand our economy has unique strengths that we can build on.&nbsp; The job market is the strongest it’s been since World War Two, notwithstanding the inflation.&nbsp; We added another 390,000 jobs last month; 8,700,000 new jobs since I took office.&nbsp; An all-time record.&nbsp; Never that many jobs in that period of time.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>Unemployment rate is near historic lows.&nbsp; Millions of Americans are moving up to better jobs and better pay.</p>



<p>And since I took office, families are carrying less debt on average in America.&nbsp; They have more savings than they’ve had.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we’re doing it all while cutting the federal deficit by $1.7 trillion this year and $320 billion last.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>If I hear one of my MAGA friends once again talk about debt and deficits, I&#8217;m going to &#8212; anyway &#8212; I’m going to be good.&nbsp; (Laughter.)&nbsp; They increased the deficit by 2 trillion bucks.&nbsp; Anyway, that&#8217;s another story.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But, look, this is the largest decline in American history.&nbsp; Because of the progress, America can tackle inflation from a position of strength unlike any other country in the world, because every country in the world is getting a big bite and piece of this inflation &#8212; worse than we are in the vast majority of countries around the world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But make no mistake about it: I understand inflation is a real challenge to American families.</p>



<p>Today’s inflation report confirmed what Americans already know: Putin’s price hike is hitting America hard.</p>



<p>Gas prices at the pump.&nbsp; Energy and food prices account for half of the monthly price increases since May.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Inflation, outside of energy and food &#8212; what the economists call “core inflation” &#8212; moderated the last two months.&nbsp; Not enough, but it moderated; it’s come down.&nbsp; And we need it to come down much more quickly.</p>



<p>My administration is going to continue to do everything we can to lower the prices for the American people.&nbsp; And the Congress has to act, and they have been of late.&nbsp;</p>



<p>One of the key ways to fight inflation is by lowering the cost of moving goods through the supply chain.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When I first started talking about the supply chain, when I came here well over a year ago, the American people understandably wondered, “Supply chain &#8212; what…” &#8212; I mean, that’s not a usual part of their jargon every day.&nbsp; But they understand it fully now.&nbsp; They understand it.</p>



<p>If you can&#8217;t get the material needed to build a product you&#8217;re building &#8212; whether it&#8217;s an automobile or whatever it is &#8212; it makes it difficult to be able to move, and that&#8217;s called the supply chain.&nbsp; That’s why I’ve been focused on ports.</p>



<p>Last fall, ports around the world were congested due to disruption caused by the pandemic, so we brought together port operators, shipping companies, and labor and &#8212; to ease the bottlenecks.&nbsp; And as a result, over the holidays last, 97 percent of all the packages were delivered on time and on shelves when you went Christmas shopping.&nbsp; Remember, we weren&#8217;t going to have anything on those shelves.&nbsp; You all did it.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; No, no, not a joke.&nbsp; You did it on time with minimal delay.&nbsp; Delivery times were actually quicker than they were before the pandemic.</p>



<p>And today, there are about 40 percent fewer containers clogging the docks on long pe- &#8212; for long periods of time than there were last November.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This May was the strongest month in the Port of Los Angeles’s history &#8212; the strongest month in its history.&nbsp; (Applause.)</p>



<p>And we’re helping fund improvements.&nbsp; Because of what my friends in the Congress have done, we passed the &#8212; we passed the Infrastructure Bill and we&#8217;re funding major new initiatives on the docks &#8212; on-dock rail systems, the Port of Long Beach &#8212; move goods more quickly.&nbsp; And port electrification so communications near the ports can be &#8212; and communities can breathe cleaner air because they’re using electric machines that are not generating using gas, coal, et cetera.</p>



<p>And we’re continuing to expand capacity of our ports, thanks to the Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Look, this is a time &#8212; we took a different approach also to trucking.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Remember, last December, we brought together industry and labor to tackle problems facing truck drivers.&nbsp; It took the double &#8212; we had to double the number of commercial driver licenses being issued by the states in order to speed things up.&nbsp; We did it.&nbsp; We sped the creation and registration of apprenticeships, allowing aspiring drivers to earn while they were learning.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The result?&nbsp; We hit a record-setting employment in trucking earlier this year.&nbsp; And truckers’ wages went up even after accounting for inflation.&nbsp;</p>



<p><a>We’re going to keep at it with a new <s>Super</s> [Supply] Chain Envoy, General Steve Lyons.&nbsp; General Lyons is a four-star general.&nbsp; He handled the transportation of a little bit of a thing &#8212; he had Transportation Command &#8212; only tens of millions of billions of tons of things to move, from little things like tanks, and aircraft, and all of that.&nbsp;</a></p>



<p>But all kidding aside, he&#8217;s come off the sidelines.&nbsp; He&#8217;s retired.&nbsp; He&#8217;s helped us identify and get ahead of the challenges that raise &#8212; that &#8212; that arise at our ports, our railroads, and on the road.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is about reducing costs for families.&nbsp;</p>



<p>You know, I have to admit to you, a lot of us elected officials have been in office for a while.&nbsp; Every once in a while, something you learn makes you viscerally angry.&nbsp; Like if you had the person in front of you, you&#8217;d want to pop them.&nbsp; No, I really mean it.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are nine &#8212; nine major ocean line shipping companies that ship from Asia to the United States.&nbsp; Nine.&nbsp; They form three consortia.&nbsp; These companies have raised their prices by as much as 1,000 percent.&nbsp; So everything coming from Asia, they &#8212; they get 90-some percent of it &#8212; the stuff coming from Asia.&nbsp; They&#8217;ve raised it by 1,000 percent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>That&#8217;s why I called on Congress to crack down on &#8212; and they&#8217;re foreign owned &#8212; foreign-owned shipping companies that raise their prices while raking in, just last year, $190 billion in profit &#8212; a seven-fold increase in one year.&nbsp; Seven-fold increase &#8212; $190 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Senate passed legislation.&nbsp; I&#8217;m hopeful the House is going to act soon to crack down on these companies, as I&#8217;ve asked, and lower the cost.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m grateful to two Californians, Speaker Pelosi and John Garamendi, for &#8212; for leading this effort.&nbsp; Thanks, John.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; It&#8217;s a big deal.&nbsp; People at home trying to make it, you know, paycheck to paycheck are wondering, “Well, like, what in God&#8217;s name do nine” &#8212; understandably &#8212; “would nine shipping companies have to do with it?”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Well, almost everything you&#8217;re doing &#8212; everything from what you&#8217;re eating to what you’re having to drive, to what you&#8217;re &#8212; with what you need in your home is related to supply chains and what&#8217;s coming from abroad.</p>



<p>I&#8217;m doing everything in my power to blunt Putin&#8217;s price hike and bring down the cost of gas and food.&nbsp; I led the world to coordinate the largest release of global oil reserves in history &#8212; 240 million barrels &#8212; to boost supply to keep prices from rising even more.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks to America&#8217;s leadership and diplomacy, we&#8217;ve helped Europe reduce its reliance on Russian oil by tripling our natural gas systems to Europe compared to last year.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And I&#8217;m working closely with our European partners to get 20 million tons of grain locked in Ukraine.&nbsp; Already in their silos now.&nbsp; Ukraine and Russia, the two major suppliers of grain and corn, they have 20 million barrels &#8212; I mean 20 million in &#8212; in their &#8212; in their silos right now.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So we&#8217;re trying to help them to get that, and the Russians are blocking the export.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not allowed out through the Black Sea.&nbsp; And we&#8217;re trying to figure out how to get it out of the country to get he- &#8212; to &#8212; around the world.&nbsp; It will bring down prices.&nbsp;</p>



<p>But there&#8217;s more &#8212; there&#8217;s more than one way to solve this problem.&nbsp; We&#8217;re continuing working to bring down food prices and gas prices to save families mother &#8212; money by dealing with other items.&nbsp;</p>



<p>My dad used to say it&#8217;s all about the standard of living &#8212; how much you have left in the paycheck at the end of the month, how much is left to do the basic things.</p>



<p>So, if you add up all the things that people need just to do their &#8212; to do everything from take care of their kids to turn the heat on or the air conditioning on and everything in between, there&#8217;s a lot of ways we can reduce their cost, their cost of living, other than if we &#8212; while we&#8217;re trying to get at &#8212; at the grain and &#8212; and gas.</p>



<p>We laid out a plan.&nbsp; For example, lower prescription drug costs; that would fundamentally affect the wellbeing of every family.&nbsp; Those of you who know somebody who has Type 2 diabetes and has in- &#8212; has an insulin requirement monthly, you know it costs an average of $647 a month.&nbsp; It can cost as high as $1,000 in some place.&nbsp;&nbsp; You know how much it costs to make that one little vial of insulin?&nbsp; Ten dollars.&nbsp; T-E-N.&nbsp; Ten dollars.&nbsp;</p>



<p>No new research has been done since that was &#8212; was invented.&nbsp; And the charging is outrageous.&nbsp; So I think we should be able to have the Medicare do what they do when they deal with the VA.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The VA says, “We’re only going to pay you so much for this, if you don&#8217;t want to…” &#8212; and because they &#8212; Medicare negotiates the price for them.&nbsp; Well, if Medicare is able to negotiate the price on insulin, guess what?&nbsp; It comes down a whole hell of a lot.&nbsp; Outrageous numbers.</p>



<p>So we could put a cap on insulin at $35 a month and they&#8217;ll still make a significant profit.&nbsp; Ten bucks to manufacture; thirty-five bucks.</p>



<p>For example, we can begin by lowering the cost of high-speed Internet because of what y&#8217;all did dealing with the &#8212; with the Infrastructure Bill.&nbsp; Working with the service providers, we cut the price and rise &#8212; raised the speed, potentially lowering high-speed Internet bills on average, for an average family, $30 a month.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Okay, well, you made &#8212; you&#8217;re paying an extra more than $30 a month for your gas, but that still increases the money out of pocket &#8212; decreases the amount you have to put out.</p>



<p>The point is: We&#8217;re doing everything in our power to lower costs to families, but congressional Republicans, led by Senator Rick Scott, have a different approach.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And if you didn’t write it down, you’d think I was making it up, and I mean it sincerely.&nbsp; Rick Scott tried to change his words yesterday, by the way, after he introduced this legis- &#8212; he’d been campaigning.</p>



<p>He’s the guy that had the recon- &#8212; the re-election of the senators for &#8212; on the Republican side.&nbsp; He realized that raising taxes on working families is a little unpopular.&nbsp; He said, “Everybody, no matter what their station, if they don&#8217;t &#8212; if they&#8217;re on welfare &#8212; should have &#8212; pay a tax.&nbsp; Everybody should pay a tax.”</p>



<p>Well, but here&#8217;s the truth: One concrete plan that they laid out was going to raise taxes on working families an average of $1,500 a month, while we have 54 corporations out there who didn&#8217;t pay any tax for the last two years and made $40 billion.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t want to tax them at all.&nbsp; They don&#8217;t want to tax billionaires who are literally paying a lower tax rate than longshoremen are paying, literally, on a percentage basis.</p>



<p>So he hasn&#8217;t walked back from his plans.</p>



<p>On healthcare, he says what we have to do &#8212; now that we finally got the Affordable Care Act functioning and the price is down an average of 400 bucks for people, he wants to eliminate it.&nbsp; Again, we’re back at “want to eliminate it” again.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So &#8212; and, by the way, the one that&#8217;s the best thing that the Republicans are pushing now in the re-election is that they think that Medicare &#8212; I&#8217;m not making this up; go online and look &#8212; Medicare, Social Security, and Medicare &#8212; Medicaid &#8212; go on the chopping block every five years.&nbsp; What that means is: At the end of five years, they go out of existence unless they&#8217;re affirmatively voted back into existence &#8212; every five years. Medicare, Social Security, Medicaid.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they forget people paid for their Social Security.&nbsp; They paid for it.&nbsp; And you know what&#8217;s going to happen?&nbsp; People will say, “Well, they&#8217;ll never eliminate it all.”&nbsp; But they&#8217;ll &#8212; what they&#8217;ll do, they&#8217;ll be able to pick it apart.&nbsp; They&#8217;ll be able to cut it back.&nbsp; That&#8217;s the whole objective.</p>



<p>And, folks, you know, it’s not right.&nbsp; It’s simply not right.&nbsp; And I disagree.&nbsp; And that’s what &#8212; look, this is not your father’s Republican Party; this is a different deal.&nbsp; It really is.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I’ve worked with a lot of honorable Republicans &#8212; very conservative Republicans &#8212; over the years when I was a senator.&nbsp; But this is the MAGA gang.&nbsp; This is the MAGA crowd.&nbsp; I really mean it.&nbsp; They have a fundamentally different view of the role of government and who should pay what.&nbsp; And I&#8217;m going to work with anyone &#8212; Democrat, Republican, or independent &#8212; to deliver real solutions for families.</p>



<p>Look, because of the strong foundation we built, we&#8217;re better positioned than just about any country in the world to overcome global &#8212; the global inflation we&#8217;re seeing and to take the next step towards forming a historic recovery and a new moment.&nbsp; And I count “recovery” as going from where we are today, in terms of the economy, to stability &#8212; to make it stable.&nbsp; It is strong as can be but for inflation, but for gas and food.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, look, we have to keep go- &#8212; we have to keep coming together to find common ground to solve problems, like we&#8217;ve done in ports and in trucking.&nbsp; We continue to build the extraordinary progress we&#8217;ve made.&nbsp; So we got to continue building this economy from the bottom up and the middle out.&nbsp; And I mean that literally.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I am so sick and tired of trickle-down economics.&nbsp; It does not work.&nbsp; When the middle class is doing well &#8212; and they do well because of labor &#8212; when the middle class is doing well, the poor have a way up and the wealthy do very, very well.&nbsp; They have never been hurt when the middle class is doing well.&nbsp; Never.&nbsp; Never.</p>



<p>So, it&#8217;s about time we start to regather and remember who we are and get a lot of this done.&nbsp; But there&#8217;s no better place to starting it than right here in the port and letting those nine foreign shippers understand the rip-off is over.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thank you.&nbsp; (Applause.)&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; All right.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Are you going to go after Exxon’s profits, sir?&nbsp; Exxon’s profits &#8212; are you going to &#8212; are you going to go after them?</p>



<p>THE PRESIDENT:&nbsp; We&#8217;re going to make sure that everybody knows Exxon&#8217;s profits.&nbsp; Why don&#8217;t you tell them what Exxon’s profits were this year &#8212; this quarter?&nbsp; Exxon made more money than God this year.&nbsp; And, by the way, nothing has changed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And they&#8217;re not &#8212; by the way, one thing I want to say about the oil companies: They talk about how we have &#8212; they have 9,000 permits to drill.&nbsp; They&#8217;re not drilling.&nbsp; Why aren&#8217;t they drilling?&nbsp; Because they make more money not producing more oil.&nbsp; The price goes up, number one.&nbsp; And, number two, the reason they&#8217;re not drilling is they&#8217;re buying back their own stock &#8212; which should be taxed, quite frankly &#8212; buying back their own stock and making no new investments.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So I &#8212; I always thought Republicans are for investment.&nbsp; Exxon, start investing, start paying your taxes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Thanks.</p>



<p>11:11 A.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Statement by President&#160;Biden on Consumer Price Index (CPI) in&#160;May</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/10/statement-by-president-biden-on-consumer-price-index-cpi-in-may/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 17:03:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today’s report underscores why I have made fighting inflation my top economic priority. While it is good to see critical “core” inflation moderating, it is not coming down as sharply and as quickly as we must see. Putin’s Price Hike hit hard in May here and around the world: high gas prices at the pump,&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today’s report underscores why I have made fighting inflation my top economic priority. While it is good to see critical “core” inflation moderating, it is not coming down as sharply and as quickly as we must see. Putin’s Price Hike hit hard in May here and around the world: high gas prices at the pump, energy, and food prices accounted for around half of the monthly price increases, and gas pump prices are up by $2 a gallon in many places since Russian troops began to threaten Ukraine. Even as we continue our work to defend freedom in Ukraine, we must do more—and quickly—to get prices down here in the United States.</p>



<p>My Administration will continue to do everything we can to lower prices for the American people. Congress must act urgently as well. I call on Congress to pass a bill to cut shipping costs this month, and get it to my desk, so we can lower the price of goods. And, I call on Congress to pass legislation to cut costs for families like energy bills and prescription drugs. The deficit has come down more under my watch as President than at any time in history, but if Congress would pass tax reform to make the wealthiest Americans and big corporations pay their fair share, we could reduce this inflationary pressure even more. These are the most significant things Congress can do to help families now and complement the Federal Reserve’s efforts to bring inflation down.</p>



<p>Prices at the pump are a major part of inflation, and the war in Ukraine is a major cause of that. The United States is on track to produce a record amount of oil next year, and I am working with the industry to accelerate this output. But it is also important that the oil and gas and refining industries in this country not use the challenge created by the war in Ukraine as a reason to make things worse for families with excessive profit taking or price hikes.</p>



<p>We all have work to do to get inflation down. What will not help is the plan by some Republicans in Congress to raise taxes on the middle class and working families. That would be a step in the wrong direction, and I strongly oppose it.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Announces Sixth Operation Fly Formula Mission</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/10/president-biden-announces-sixth-operation-fly-formula-mission/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 16:17:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55275</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Delta Air Lines will carry more than 3.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula&#160; Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration has arranged the sixth Operation Fly Formula flight. Delta Air Lines will transport Kendamil formula free of charge from Heathrow Airport in London to Logan Airport in Boston and Detroit Metro&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center"><em>Delta Air Lines will carry more than 3.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula&nbsp;</em></p>



<p>Today, President Biden is announcing that his Administration has arranged the sixth Operation Fly Formula flight. Delta Air Lines will transport Kendamil formula free of charge from Heathrow Airport in London to Logan Airport in Boston and Detroit Metro Airport between June 20 and June 24.</p>



<p>These Operation Fly Formula flights donated by Delta will contain more than 212,000 pounds or approximately 3.2 million 8-ounce bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula and will begin shipping on June 20.</p>



<p>The Kendamil Organic and Classic formula, made available through Operation Fly Formula, will be distributed and available for purchase at select U.S. retailers nationwide, as well as online. The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) is exercising enforcement discretion so that Kendamil can import infant formula under the Kendamil brand. Kendamil will export up to at least 2 million cans of Kendamil infant formula – the equivalent of at least 54 million 8-ounce bottles to the United States. Parents can learn more about Kendamil infant formula at&nbsp;<a href="https://kendamil.com/">https://kendamil.com/</a>&nbsp;and visit the United States website at&nbsp;<a href="https://us.kendamil.com/">https://us.kendamil.com/</a>&nbsp;for updates and information on retail locations.&nbsp;<br>&nbsp;<br>President Biden launched Operation Fly Formula to speed up the importation of safe infant formula and start getting more formula to stores as soon as possible. Under Operation Fly Formula, the U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the General Services Administration (GSA), and the Department of Defense (DOD) are partnering to pick up overseas infant formula that meets U.S. health and safety standards so it can get to store shelves faster. Yesterday, Operation Fly Formula flights landed in Texas with 1.6 million bottle equivalents of Nestlé NAN SupremePro Stage 1 infant formula, and the first shipment of 3.7 million bottle equivalents of Kendamil infant formula landed in Virginia aboard a donated United Airlines flight.</p>



<p>In addition, the Biden Administration has taken a number of other important actions to ensure there is enough safe infant formula for families, including invoking the Defense Production Act, entering into a consent agreement between the FDA to reopen Abbott Nutrition’s Sturgis facility, and issuing FDA guidance so that major formula manufacturers can safely import formula that is not currently being produced for the U.S. market.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-center">###</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Proclamation on Flag Day And National Flag Week,&#160;2022</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/presidential-actions/2022/06/10/a-proclamation-on-flag-day-and-national-flag-week-2022/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 15:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Actions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55262</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160; On June 14, 1777, the Continental Congress passed a resolution adopting a flag for our new Nation &#8212; the United&#160;States of America.&#160; The resolution specified 13 alternating red and white stripes with 13 stars on a blue field.&#160; The stars represented the colonies that declared independence, and in the years since, they have grown&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; On June 14, 1777, the Continental Congress passed a resolution adopting a flag for our new Nation &#8212; the United&nbsp;States of America.&nbsp; The resolution specified 13 alternating red and white stripes with 13 stars on a blue field.&nbsp; The stars represented the colonies that declared independence, and in the years since, they have grown into 50 United States which comprise our great country today.&nbsp; For centuries, mariners looked to the stars to guide them across the seas, just as Americans and people across the globe look to our flag as a guiding symbol of freedom, opportunity, and hope. &nbsp;On Flag Day and during National Flag Week, we celebrate the journey of progress represented in our banner and pay tribute to the inspiration it gives Americans at home and abroad.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Our flag belongs to all Americans, and its red, white, and blue colors are woven into a rich tapestry of different cultures, backgrounds, and beliefs which connects us and honors our shared history. &nbsp;Old Glory has flown around the world in times of war and in times of peace. &nbsp;It has traveled to the Moon and to Mars. &nbsp;It has sailed on ships and flown on planes. &nbsp;It waves high above the White House, courthouses, post offices, schools, and homes across the Nation, and also above our embassies and military bases overseas &#8212; an enduring beacon of democracy.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; From the Revolutionary War to the modern age, American Service members have fought bravely under the symbol of our flag, and those who give the last full measure of devotion are wrapped in its broad stripes and bright stars as they are laid to rest.&nbsp; We honor those who serve our country in uniform and pay homage to those who have made that ultimate sacrifice.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Every day, the American Flag instills pride &#8212; reminding us of the ideals upon which our Nation was founded and the values for which we stand. &nbsp;As we pledge our allegiance to the Star-Spangled Banner, and the legacy it holds in our history, let us continue the work of perfecting our Union so that, together, we can deliver the promise of America for all Americans. &nbsp;</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; To commemorate the adoption of our flag, the Congress, by joint resolution approved August 3, 1949, as amended (63 Stat. 492), designated June 14 of each year as &#8220;Flag Day&#8221; and requested the President issue an annual proclamation calling for its observance and for the display of the flag of the United States on all Federal Government buildings.&nbsp; The Congress also requested, by joint resolution approved June 9, 1966, as amended (80 Stat. 194), that the President issue annually a proclamation designating the week in which June 14 occurs as &#8220;National Flag Week&#8221; and calling upon all citizens of the United States to display the flag during that week.</p>



<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; NOW, THEREFORE, I, JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR., President of the United States of America, do hereby proclaim June 14, 2022, as Flag Day, and the week starting June 12, 2022, as National Flag Week.&nbsp; I direct the appropriate officials to display the flag on all Federal Government buildings during this week, and I urge all Americans to observe Flag Day and National Flag Week by displaying the flag and honoring all of our brave service members and revering those who gave their last full measure of devotion defending our freedoms. &nbsp;I encourage the people of the United States to observe with pride and all due ceremony those days from Flag Day through Independence Day, set aside by the Congress (89 Stat. 211), as a time to honor the American spirit, to celebrate our history and the foundational values we strive to uphold, and to publicly recite the Pledge of Allegiance to the Flag of the United States of America.</p>



<p>     IN WITNESS WHEREOF, I have hereunto set my hand this tenth day of June, in the year of our Lord two thousand twenty-two, and of the Independence of the United States of America the two hundred and forty-sixth.</p>



<p class="has-text-align-right">&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; JOSEPH R. BIDEN JR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fact Sheet: The Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection U.S. Government and Foreign Partner&#160;Deliverables</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2022/06/10/fact-sheet-the-los-angeles-declaration-on-migration-and-protection-u-s-government-and-foreign-partner-deliverables/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 14:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Statements and Releases]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55254</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Today, President Biden joins leaders from across the Western Hemisphere to present the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection at the Summit of the Americas. The Declaration seeks to mobilize the entire region around bold actions that will transform our approach to managing migration in the Americas. The Declaration is organized around four key&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p>Today, President Biden joins leaders from across the Western Hemisphere to present the Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection at the Summit of the Americas. The Declaration seeks to mobilize the entire region around bold actions that will transform our approach to managing migration in the Americas. The Declaration is organized around four key pillars: (1) stability and assistance for communities; (2) expansion of legal pathways; (3) humane migration management; and (4) coordinated emergency response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In preparation for the Summit, the United States and other countries in the region developed a suite of bold new migration-related deliverables.</p>



<p><strong>Pillar I: Stability and Assistance for Communities</strong></p>



<p>Addressing the unprecedented migration crisis in the region requires us to rethink how we view multilateral development finance and how we manage the strains on our economies. Globally, International Financial Institutions (IFIs) and development assistance have been directed to poor and low-income countries, designations which no longer apply to most of Latin America and the Caribbean. The need for economic stabilization and support is particularly important in countries housing the more than six million refugees and migrants.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Belize will implement in August 2022 a program to regularize Central American and CARICOM migrants</strong> who have been living illegally in the country for a specified time.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Colombia’s leadership in responding to Venezuelan migrants and refugees with forward-leaning policies based on solidarity, humanitarian relief, and protection:</strong> Colombia reaffirms its commitment to fully implement its announcement of temporary protected status for displaced Venezuelan migrants and refugees in its territory. As of June 10, it has granted regularization documents to over 1.2 million individuals, allowing them to work legally, access public and private services, integrate successfully, and contribute to Colombia’s economy and society. Colombia further reaffirms its commitment to grant regularization permits to 1.5M Venezuelan migrants and refugees in total, by the end of August 2022.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Costa Rica commits to plan for a renewal of the special temporary complementary protection category scheme for migrants from Venezuela, Nicaragua, and Cuba</strong>, that have arrived prior to March 2020, contingent on obtaining necessary financial resources, and to convene an international task force to secure additional direct support and financial resources to support its implementation.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Ecuador issued an executive decree that creates a path to a regular migration status for Venezuelans who entered the country regularly via an official port of entry, but who are currently out of status.</strong> This process includes unaccompanied or separated migrant children and a migration amnesty. It contemplates the provision of identification documents for the regularization process, taking into account the current difficulties facing Venezuelan citizens. It intends to expand this process to include all Venezuelans.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will provide additional U.S. support for a crisis response mechanism on migration</strong>. Working with Congress, we will provide an additional <a href="https://www.state.gov/support-to-the-global-concessional-finance-facility-gcff/">$25 million</a> to the Global Concessional Financing Facility (GCFF) housed at the World Bank to prioritize countries in Latin America such as Ecuador and Costa Rica in their newly announced regularization programs for displaced migrant and refugee populations residing within their respective countries. &nbsp;The new funding would support registration processes, the extension of social services, integration programs, and would benefit host communities that have generously opened their doors to the most vulnerable.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will announce $314 million in new PRM and USAID funding for stabilization efforts in the Americas.</strong> <a href="https://www.usaid.gov/news-information/press-releases/jun-10-2022-united-states-announces-more-314-million-new-stabilization-efforts-venezuela">USAID</a> and the <a href="https://www.state.gov/additional-314-million-for-u-s-humanitarian-response-to-the-venezuela-regional-crisis/">State Department</a>’s Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration (PRM) will announce more than $314 million in new funding for humanitarian and development assistance for refugees and vulnerable migrants across the hemisphere. This includes support for&nbsp;socio-economic integration and humanitarian aid for Venezuelans in 17 countries of the region.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Pillar II: Legal Pathways and Protection</strong></p>



<p>Expanding legal pathways for protection and opportunity is at the heart of efforts to humanely address irregular migration in the Americas. The goal is to <em>change the way</em> people migrate. Countries in the region have strategically pegged priority legal pathway programs with the primary reasons for migrating: (1) jobs; (2) protection; and (3) family reunification.</p>



<ul><li><strong>Canada’s resettlement and complementary pathways initiative:</strong> Canada is welcoming record numbers of refugees and in line with Canada’s immigration levels plans.&nbsp;As part of these growing efforts, Canada will increase refugee resettlement from the Americas and aims to welcome up to 4,000 individuals by 2028, providing durable solutions to a number of refugees in the region. Canada recognizes the important support of the UNHCR and the IOM in the region. Canada will also look to promote its regular pathways in the region to help provide opportunities including to those in vulnerable situations. For example, Canada will advance a promotion and recruitment efforts related to its Francophone Immigration Program which may offer opportunities to French speaking newcomers such as Haitians with skills and experience, some of which may gave have been displaced due to the pandemic.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Canada is addressing root causes and</strong> <strong>investing&nbsp;$26.9 million, in 2022-2023, in additional funding toward migration- and protection-related capacity building in the Americas.</strong> This funding is supporting projects across Latin America and the Caribbean focused on supporting the socio-economic and labour market integration of refugees and migrants; improving border and migration management systems; contributing to the safeguarding of migrants, refugees and host communities’ rights; advancing gender equality and inclusive economic growth; and preventing and tackling migrant smuggling and trafficking in persons.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Canada expects to welcome more than 50,000 agricultural workers from Mexico, Guatemala and the Caribbean in 2022.</strong> Canada is a strong supporter of labour mobility and continues to actively promote regular pathways for migration, including temporary foreign worker programs that respond to employer labour needs, to address our labour market gaps and as alternatives to irregular migration.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Guatemala approves new legislation to promote legal labor migration programs.</strong>&nbsp;On June 1, the Government of Guatemala approved new legislation to incentivize fair recruitment and expand legal pathways for its citizens. The legislation exempts airline tickets from value-added and departure taxes for those traveling for temporary work abroad contracts obtained through the Ministry of Labor.&nbsp; The new initiative is part of a broader set of Guatemalan programs and policies to expand access to labor migration programs, ensure ethical recruitment, and promote legal protections for Guatemalan workers.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Mexico will expand the existing Border Worker Card program to include 10,000 to 20,000 additional beneficiaries.</strong> This program allows greater labor mobility to meet employer needs in Mexico, promote economic development in Central America, and provide an alternative to irregular migration.&nbsp;&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li>&nbsp;<strong>Mexico will launch a new temporary labor program providing work opportunities in Mexico for 15,000 to 20,000 workers from Guatemala per year.</strong> &nbsp;The Government of Mexico aims to expand eligibility for that program to include Honduras and El Salvador in the medium-term.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>Mexico will integrate 20,000 recognized refugees into the Mexican labor market over the next three years.</strong> With the support of UNHCR, the program would connect individuals with legal status as recognized refugees in Mexico to work opportunities in regions with labor shortages. A joint initiative with UNHCR, the private sector and the Mexican Government, both refugees and firms will benefit from successful integration into Mexico&#8217;s formal labor market.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will launch the development of a $65 million U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) pilot program to support U.S. farmers hiring agricultural workers under the H-2A program.&nbsp;</strong>In collaboration with other agencies, <a href="https://www.usda.gov/media/press-releases/2022/06/10/us-department-agriculture-invest-65-million-pilot-program">USDA</a> is exploring a multi-year pilot program funded by the President’s American Rescue Plan to provide grants to agricultural employers that hire farmworkers from Northern Central American countries under the seasonal H-2A visa program and agree to additional protections to benefit both U.S. and H-2A workers. The pilot will promote the resiliency of our food and agricultural supply chain and three major Administration priorities: (1) driving U.S. economic recovery by addressing current labor shortages in agriculture; (2) reducing irregular migration through the expansion of legal pathways; and (3) improving working conditions for U.S. and migrant agricultural workers. USDA will enter into a cooperative agreement with the United Farm Workers of America (UFW), which will work with relevant stakeholders, including farmers, farmworkers, farmworker advocates and unions, to ensure that the agency benefits from a wide range of views in designing this program.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will provide 11,500 H-2B nonagricultural seasonal worker visas for nationals of Northern Central America and Haiti. </strong>To address labor shortages in key sectors of the U.S. economy and reduce irregular migration, the <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2022/03/31/dhs-and-dol-supplement-h-2b-cap-additional-visas-second-half-fiscal-year-2022">Department of Homeland Security</a> (DHS) and Department of Labor (DOL) made an additional 11,500 H-2B visas available in late May. These visas are dedicated for nationals of the Northern Central America countries and Haiti for this fiscal year. This is combined with new employer oversight provisions.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will roll out new Fair Recruitment Practices Guidance for Temporary Migrant Workers with the cooperation of major employers, including Walmart.</strong> As the United States and various other countries expand temporary worker programs in the Western Hemisphere, President Biden recognizes the importance of safeguarding against exploitation of workers. This is why his Administration will issue first-of-its-kind “<a href="http://www.dol.gov/newsroom/releases/ilab/ilab20220610">Guidance on Fair Recruitment Practices for Temporary Workers</a>.” The guidance promotes best practices for governments seeking to increase participation in the H-2 visa programs and employers relying on these programs. The United States has also mobilized the support of major U.S. retailer Walmart, which notes the importance of H-2A migrant workers to U.S. agriculture and that the fair recruitment guidance aligns with the company’s own expectations around responsible recruitment.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will commit to resettle 20,000 refugees from the Americas during Fiscal Years 2023 to 2024.</strong> This represents a three-fold increase from this year and reflects the Biden Administration’s strong commitment to welcoming refugees. The protection needs are significant in the Western Hemisphere. More than 5 million Venezuelans have been displaced in the Americas, and hundreds of thousands more people from other countries across Latin America and the Caribbean are also displaced [across borders]. As the United States scales up its resettlement operations in the Americas, we call on other governments to do the same.&nbsp;</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will increase resettlement of Haitian refugees.</strong> Reflecting the President’s commitment to support the people of Haiti, the United States also commits to receiving an increased number of referrals to the <a href="https://www.state.gov/u-s-refugee-admissions-program/">U.S. Refugee Admissions Program</a> for Haitians. The United States encourages other governments to join us in strengthening legal pathways for protection and opportunity for Haitians and other displaced populations in the Americas.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will resume and increase participation in the Haitian Family Reunification Parole Program.&nbsp;</strong>The Department of Homeland Security will announce the resumption of the Haitian Family Reunification Parole&nbsp;Program, which&nbsp;allows certain eligible U.S. citizens and lawful permanent residents to apply for parole for their family members in Haiti. Additionally, U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services will take steps to increase participation in the program by reducing barriers to access.&nbsp;New invitations to apply under the program are anticipated to be issued in early fall 2022. &nbsp;Concurrently, the Department of State will increase efforts to process Haitian immigrant visas and reduce the existing backlog.&nbsp;State&nbsp;is in the process&nbsp;of assessing options to augment&nbsp;consular adjudicator staffing in Embassy Port-au-Prince and review additional operational efficiencies to decrease the immigrant visa backlog for Haitians.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will resume the Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program.</strong> Last month, the United States announced the resumption of operations for the Cuban Family Reunification Parole Program (CFRP). CFRP provides a safe, orderly pathway to the United States for certain Cuban beneficiaries of approved family-based immigrant petitions. <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-dhs-resumes-cuban-family-reunification-parole-cfrp-program-and-haitian">DHS</a> will resume processing cases this summer, work with the Department of State to begin interviews in Cuba by early fall, and build capacity to consider and process approved applicants, thus contributing to migration accord targets over the next two years.</li></ul>



<p><strong><em>Observer States</em></strong></p>



<ul><li><strong>Spain will double the number of labor pathways for Hondurans</strong> to participate in Spain’s circular migration programs.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Pillar III: Humane Border Management</strong></p>



<p>Securing borders with humane border management policies and practices is essential to reducing irregular migration and collaboratively managing migration across the hemisphere. The focus moving forward should be on: 1) humane border enforcement; 2) return of migrants lacking protection needs or other legal basis to remain; 3) facilitating returns to countries of most recent residence or origin; 4) support for assisted voluntary returns; and 5) strengthened bilateral and regional law enforcement information sharing and cooperation to combat migrant smuggling and human trafficking.</p>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will announce a multilateral “Sting Operation” to disrupt human smuggling networks across the Hemisphere.</strong> The President will announce a first of its kind campaign, unprecedented in scale, to disrupt and dismantle smuggling networks in Latin America. In the last two months, the United States, led by <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2022/06/09/fact-sheet-dhs-leads-first-its-kind-campaign-unprecedented-scale-foil-human">DHS</a>, has surged over 1,300 personnel throughout the region and invested over $50 million to support these activities. Through the end of May, efforts have produced approximately 20,000 total disruption actions including arrests and prosecutions, seizures of property such as houses and vehicles used to hide and smuggle people, and criminal investigations. DHS assesses that this has led to 900 fewer migrants arriving at the Southwest border each day, and we are just getting started. The U.S. will seek to expand efforts with other governments in the region to improve information sharing, build capacity, and advance criminal investigations.</li></ul>



<ul><li><strong>The United States will improve the efficiency and fairness of asylum at the border.</strong> In late May, <a href="https://www.dhs.gov/news/2022/05/26/fact-sheet-implementation-credible-fear-and-asylum-processing-interim-final-rule">DHS</a> and Department of Justice began implementing a new process that improves and expedites processing of asylum claims made by noncitizens subject to expedited removal, to ensure that those who are eligible for asylum are granted relief quickly, and those who are not are promptly removed. The new process is a further step toward a more functional and sensible asylum system that reduces the caseload in immigration courts while also providing individuals with a prompt and fair decision in their case. DHS is phasing in the implementation of this rule and when fully implemented, the rule will shorten the administrative process from several years to just several months.</li></ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Background Press Call by a Senior Administration Official Previewing the Summit of the Americas Migration Deliverables and&#160;Accomplishments</title>
		<link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2022/06/10/background-press-call-by-a-senior-administration-official-previewing-the-summit-of-the-americas-migration-deliverables-and-accomplishments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[The White House]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Press Briefings]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/?p=55234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Via Teleconference 5:05 P.M. PDT MODERATOR:&#160; Thank you so much.&#160;&#160; And hi, everyone.&#160; I appreciate you all tuning in.&#160; Before we get started, I just wanted to set the ground rules and remind you all that this call is on background, embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern.&#160; We hope to have a factsheet for you sometime&#8230;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[


<p class="has-text-align-center">Via Teleconference</p>



<p>5:05 P.M. PDT</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thank you so much.&nbsp;&nbsp; And hi, everyone.&nbsp; I appreciate you all tuning in.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Before we get started, I just wanted to set the ground rules and remind you all that this call is on background, embargoed until 5:00 a.m. Eastern.&nbsp; We hope to have a factsheet for you sometime tonight, if not the declaration language, to make sure that you guys have enough context.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And you may attribute the contents of the call to a “senior administration official.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>With that, I&#8217;ll kick it over to my colleague, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Great, thank you so much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thank you all for joining us this evening.&nbsp; We’re excited to be able to talk to you about the Los Angeles Declaration that the President will be presenting tomorrow with other heads of state.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So just to provide some background: The Western Hemisphere, as a region, is undergoing historic and unprecedented rates of irregular migration.&nbsp; Nearly every country has been impacted.&nbsp; And that is why President Biden is pursuing bold and concrete action to address hemispheric responsibility for the migration challenge the region is facing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tomorrow, President Biden, alongside fellow heads of state, will announce a regional partnership to address historic migration flows affecting every country in the region.</p>



<p>President Biden is asking all governments along the migratory route to establish and fortify asylum processing in each of their respective countries while more effectively enforcing their borders, conducting screenings, and removing those individuals who do not qualify for asylum.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Los Angeles Declaration on Migration and Protection is centered around responsibility sharing and economic support for countries that have been most impacted by refugee and migration flows.&nbsp; It sets forth a framework for a coordinated and predictable way for states to manage migration, and focuses on four main pillars: stability and assistance for communities, legal pathways, humane border management, and coordinated emergency response.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is a historic moment for our country.&nbsp; No prior administration has so assertively engaged to the region to secure concrete commitments to share responsibility and act to address this regional challenge.&nbsp; And no U.S. President has stood in solidarity with Canada, the countries of Latin America, and the Caribbean in this way.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I&#8217;d like to take a moment to share a few of the bold new migration-related deliverables that will be shared tomorrow.</p>



<p>Under the declaration, governments will commit to collectively expand temporary worker programs to address labor shortages while reducing irregular migration.&nbsp; We see this as a true win-win for countries such as the United States, Canada, and Mexico, and other countries across the Western Hemisphere that are facing massive labor shortages.</p>



<p>It will also open, expand, and reinforce other legal channels for migration &#8212; including refugee resettlement, family unification &#8212; which will also help address critical labor shortages.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And we will surge support for countries that are hosting large refugee and migrant populations, and combat and root out human smuggling networks that prey on the most vulnerable in the region.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Additionally, President Biden will announce an ambitious package of new actions to combat irregular migration in a humane and sustainable way.&nbsp; For instance:</p>



<p>Jobs.&nbsp; We’ll strengthen the U.S. economy by addressing labor shortages, again, through the expansion of labor migration pathways, while strengthening protections for workers.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Under stability and assistance, we’ll surge support to refugee- and migrant-hosting countries to stabilize populations and reduce secondary flows towards our southern border.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Refugees.&nbsp; We’ll demonstrate U.S. leadership in refugee response through our new and ambitious resettlement and funding commitments.</p>



<p>And law enforcement.&nbsp; Announcing a first-of-its-kind and unprecedented-in-scale campaign to disrupt and dismantle human smuggling networks across Latin America.</p>



<p>And last, support for Haiti.&nbsp; We will announce deliverables to help the people of Haiti, in light of the deteriorating security and humanitarian situation in the country.</p>



<p>The Los Angeles Declaration demonstrates the commitment of the entire region to step up collectively to address the challenges of historic levels of migration.&nbsp; Many countries across the region have already been absorbing millions of immigrants, migrants, and refugees, and it&#8217;s time that we work together to address this challenge.</p>



<p>Tomorrow&#8217;s announcement is a major step forward towards solving the unprecedented irregular migration challenge in the region and along our border while also focusing resources to modernize immigration and temporary worker programs to address labor shortages that are driving up prices.</p>



<p>I look forward to taking your questions.&nbsp; And back to you, [senior administration official].</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&nbsp; I guess my main question is: How is the U.S. hoping to ensure that countries who take part in this declaration actually follow through on the commitments that you just outlined, especially the commitment around making sure that folks who don&#8217;t qualify for asylum are returned to their home country, especially folks who are able to come to the U.S. and who are not able to establish a legal basis to remain here?&nbsp;</p>



<p>How are you hoping to make sure those countries actually follow through on that commitment?&nbsp; Are you providing them anything in return?&nbsp; Or can you explain that for me, please?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure, thanks so much for the question.&nbsp; And this is, I think &#8212; you know, it&#8217;ll be an ongoing dialogue.&nbsp; I think that the process of developing the declaration really helps to bring us together to work &#8212; you know, there&#8217;s been a lot of work over the course of months, at all levels, to develop the text and to come up &#8212; you know, develop consensus around these ideas.</p>



<p>And so, but this is just the beginning.&nbsp; You will see, I think, tomorrow, not only the U.S. but many countries making concrete commitments around these four pillars that I mentioned, including the one that you just highlighted about strengthening asylum systems, cross-screening people that enter one border, repatriating people that don&#8217;t qualify.&nbsp; This is really critical.&nbsp; But actions are the most important thing.</p>



<p>So I think you will see the United States continue to engage actively with all of these countries.&nbsp; We will lead by example, but we will certainly expect that all countries do their part.&nbsp; This is &#8212; you know, at its heart, at its core &#8212; is about responsibility sharing.</p>



<p>And so, we will continue to provide support to countries that are really making a strong effort to build their asylum capacity.&nbsp; There&#8217;s many countries in the region that are doing that.&nbsp; And through the State Department, we provide a lot of support, and we will continue to do so.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you so much.&nbsp; Can you provide more details about the support for Haiti that&#8217;s going to be announced tomorrow?&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks for the question.&nbsp; I don&#8217;t want to get ahead of the President, but that’s just to say that I think we recognize that &#8212; you know, the need to expand legal pathways for &#8212; just in general, but also specifically countries where we&#8217;re seeing high outflows that are directly related to humanitarian situations and security situations.</p>



<p>And so, I think the goal here is to provide legal channels so that folks don&#8217;t have to take irregular means to get to safety or to reunite with family.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; I wanted to ask about the pillar on expanding things like temporary worker programs and family reunification.&nbsp; I think, at least in the United States, that would require congressional action, and that&#8217;s something that the Biden administration already supports.&nbsp; So, what in the declaration is going to meaningfully change the situation for the United States, which as we know is taking in the vast majority of migrants in the Western Hemisphere?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We would absolutely love to see Congress act on this.&nbsp; I think we see that there&#8217;s a real opportunity to expand legal channels for migration, and that &#8212; that would be good for our economy, good for the United States, but it would also directly have an impact on reducing irregular migration.</p>



<p>We will do everything we can within our executive authority.&nbsp; So, you know, I think you&#8217;ve already seen in the last year and a half the Biden administration do everything that we can to expand access to the H-2A and H-2B program.&nbsp; We&#8217;ve seen a huge uptick in the number of people that have been able to access that program and have come on temporary work visas from Central America by the &#8212; you know, we&#8217;ve done the supplemental for H-2Bs.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We have done a lot of work &#8212; USAID, in particular &#8212; on the ground to help build the capacity of the labor ministries in the three northern Central American countries.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And then we&#8217;ve done a lot to, you know, make sure that employers are aware of how the program works and to better match workers in countries like Central America with, you know, employers that are that are seeking &#8212; that are facing labor shortages.</p>



<p>So, I think what you&#8217;ll see tomorrow are additional efforts to try to support employers in the U.S. to more easily bring in workers from the region.&nbsp; And, you know, other ways that that we&#8217;ve &#8212; coupled with worker protections &#8212; strengthening worker protections, as that&#8217;s been sort of a really important thing for us that we&#8217;re not only expanding access to work visas, but also addressing longstanding exploitation that exists in those programs.</p>



<p>So, again, we&#8217;re doing everything we can and it&#8217;s something that I think a lot of other countries are looking to do as well.</p>



<p>We will not be the only country tomorrow to announce ways in which we&#8217;re seeking to expand labor pathways.&nbsp; But you make a great point that without congressional action, there&#8217;s only so much we can do.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hello, thank you for doing this tonight.&nbsp; My question is: Does the administration trust the government of Ariel Henry to do what it should with the deliverables for Haiti?</p>



<p>And also, we&#8217;ve been getting questions from Haitian migrants about whether the administration would consider extending TPS for them.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; All I can say is that, you know, our deliverables tomorrow are focused on providing opportunities for the people of Haiti.&nbsp; Thanks.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, [senior administration official].&nbsp; Thank you so much for doing this call.&nbsp; I am wondering if you can tell us: Is every country in the Western Hemisphere expected to sign?&nbsp; What about the countries that are not present?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Thanks.&nbsp; We don&#8217;t expect every country to sign.&nbsp; And we &#8212; as we were &#8212; as we were developing the declaration and engaging with countries in the hemisphere, we were prioritizing countries that are most impacted by migration and refugee flows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And, you know, as the President has pointed out, there&#8217;s countries in the region &#8212; we&#8217;re certainly not the only one.&nbsp; And there are some countries that have been particularly impacted by the Venezuelan outflows, the Nicaraguan outflows.&nbsp; A country, you know, like Costa Rica and Panama, you know, 9, 10 percent of their population are made up of immigrants and refugees.</p>



<p>So, you know, there&#8217;s certain countries that, I think, feel the pain and recognize the value in coming together, working on responsibility sharing, and advancing &#8212; exploring new tools that we can employ to better bring the situation under control.</p>



<p>So those &#8212; we’ve sought to build consensus among those states.&nbsp; And, of course, we opened it up to any other country that wanted to join us, but we were &#8212; we were never seeking to have all countries in the Western Hemi- &#8212; we didn&#8217;t expect to have all countries in the Western Hemisphere sign.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; So, I had a question about screening people for asylum.&nbsp; If I understand you correctly, you&#8217;re hoping that other countries screen people at their border.&nbsp; Is it sort of the hope that fewer people reach the United States border and apply for asylum once they get there?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; The goal really is &#8212; I keep on saying &#8212; it&#8217;s responsibility sharing.&nbsp; You know, we want &#8212; we don’t &#8212; we want all countries to enforce their own immigration laws.&nbsp; We want those that enter international borders to have the opportunity to be screened for asylum or other forms of protection or immigration relief.&nbsp; And we want those who’d be qualified to be returned to their home country.</p>



<p>It&#8217;s (inaudible) three, four, five borders to access (inaudible).&nbsp; And we really do expect all countries to (inaudible).</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi.&nbsp; So, how many countries do you expect to sign the declaration?&nbsp; And will we see concrete numbers assigned to each country whether it’s in (inaudible)?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; We’ll be able to provide you more details on all that tomorrow.&nbsp; I think you will be pleased to see a long list of deliverables from the countries that adopt the declaration.&nbsp; You know, this is really important to the President that this not be a statement of principles &#8212; that countries come forward with something to put on the table, just as we will be doing.&nbsp;</p>



<p>And so, you know, I think there’ll be a very ambitious and concrete slate of deliverables.&nbsp; And we look forward to sharing that with you very soon.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi, thank you.&nbsp; I mean, I think I just want to second some of the questions have already been asked.&nbsp; If you all can provide any additional details on what these deliverables might look like, how many countries are signing on to the declaration, and even how many countries have agreed to provide these kinds of deliverables that we can include in our stories ahead of tomorrow&#8217;s announcement, that would be really helpful.&nbsp;&nbsp; Thank you.</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Sure.&nbsp; One piece that I realize I haven’t spoken about that might be of interest to all of you is &#8212; and this connects to the economic agenda that the President laid out on the first day of the summit, on Wednesday &#8212; is we’re really looking at ways in which we can provide more support to middle-income countries in the Western Hemisphere that are hosting large refugee and migrant populations.&nbsp;</p>



<p>I think they see that this is a region that has a long tradition of solidarity, welcoming one&#8217;s neighbors, but, you know, the impact of COVID and now the Russian aggression in Ukraine &#8212; we&#8217;re seeing countries &#8212; it&#8217;s a lot harder for countries to be welcoming and to host.&nbsp; And so that&#8217;s why we have seen, I think, a real uptick in secondary movements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, one thing that you will see tomorrow are &#8212; (audio drop) &#8212; are really strained under the weight of welcoming, you know &#8212;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; [Senior administration official]?</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &#8212; hundreds of thousands, if not millions, of additional, you know, migrants and refugees.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So, you know, work that we&#8217;ll do with the International &#8212; you know, the Inter-American Development Bank and World Bank, and other donors to provide more new sources of financing for these countries.&nbsp; And financing that will support not only the refugees and migrants, but the host communities themselves.&nbsp;</p>



<p>So that&#8217;s one more &#8212; one other area beyond what I briefed before where I think you&#8217;ll see that&#8217;s providing some specifics tomorrow.</p>



<p>Q&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Hi there.&nbsp; Just a follow-up to some of the questions that were already asked here.&nbsp; How much were the governments of Mexico and Guatemala involved in or consulted with in drafting the declaration?&nbsp; And does the administration still have faith that their commitment to this is solid, despite their absence at the summit?</p>



<p>SENIOR ADMINISTRATION OFFICIAL:&nbsp; Yeah, I can say that we have very strong bilateral cooperation with both Guatemala and Honduras on migration.&nbsp; And they&#8217;ve been &#8212; we&#8217;ve engaged with them quite a bit in the development of the declaration and have welcomed their support.&nbsp;</p>



<p>MODERATOR:&nbsp; Thanks so much, [senior administration official].&nbsp; And thanks, everyone for joining, again.</p>



<p>And sorry, we are moving, so the call dropped a few minutes.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Just as a reminder, this call is under 5:00 a.m. embargo.&nbsp; And we hope to share a draft embargo factsheet shortly.</p>



<p>Talk soon.&nbsp; Bye.</p>



<p>5:25 P.M. PDT</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
